<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت صنعتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5885</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analyzing Bullwhip Effect Sensitivity in a Four-level Supply Chain Using Average Moving Method to Forecast the Demand</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل حساسیت اثر شلاق چرمی در زنجیرۀ تأمین چهارسطحی با استفاده از روش میانگین متحرک برای برآورد تقاضا</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>43</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>58</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63874</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/imj.2017.223681.1007173</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>بنی هاشمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4676-2847</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدمحمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاجی مولانا</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In recent years, coping with a phenomenon known as bullwhip effect, has been among the most important issues in supply chain management. Bullwhip dramatically affects companies’ financial performance stating that the swing of changes in demands increases when we move from the end of the chain to the beginning of that chain. Many studies have been conducted on reducing the impact of supply chain bullwhip, each focusing on specific aspects. For this purpose in the present study, a linear four-level supply chain including store, retailer, wholesaler and factory was proposed, and the moving average method was used to predict the demand. To do so, nine different scenarios including demand changes (low, medium, high) and precautionary (low, moderate, high) were considered and the lag effect was calculated with a 95% confidence interval and throughout a one-year period. The findings showed that if we use average moving method to predict the demands, any increase in the customers’ demand change swing will result in the decrease of the whip effect on the whole chain. In addition, if the demand changes are considered as constant and fixed, any increase in precautionary saving in each part of the supply chain will increase the whip effect on the whole chain.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اثر شلاقی به‎طور شایان توجهی بر عملکرد مالی شرکت­ها و سازمان­ها اثر می­گذارد. این پدیده بیان می­کند که نوسان تغییرات تقاضا از انتهای زنجیره به ابتدای زنجیره بیشتر می‎شود. دانشمندان و محققان در زمینۀ کاهش آثار شلاقی در زنجیرۀ تأمین، مطالعات بسیاری انجام داده و جنبۀ خاصی را بررسی کرده‎اند. در این پژوهش به بررسی آثار ذخیرۀ احتیاطی و تغییرات تقاضای مشتری نهایی بر اثر شلاقی کل زنجیرۀ تأمین پرداخته شده است. به همین منظور، یک زنجیرۀ تأمین چهارسطحی خطی شامل فروشگاه، خرده­فروش، عمده­فروش و کارخانه مد نظر قرار گرفت و برای پیش­بینی تقاضا از روش میانگین متحرک استفاده شد. در این رابطه، نُه سناریوی مختلف شامل تغییرات تقاضا (کم، متوسط، زیاد) و ذخیرۀ احتیاطی (کم، متوسط، زیاد) در نظر گرفته شد و اثر شلاقی با فاصلۀ اطمینان 95درصد و دورۀ زمانی یک ساله به‎دست آمد. نتایج این تحقیق نشان داد اگر روش برآورد تقاضا در همۀ اعضای زنجیرۀ تأمین با استفاده از روش میانگین متحرک باشد، با افزایش نوسان تغییرات تقاضای مشتری نهایی، اثر شلاقی کل زنجیره کاهش می­یابد. همچنین اگر تغییرات تقاضا ثابت فرض شود، افزایش ذخیرۀ احتیاطی در هر یک از اعضای زنجیرۀ تأمین موجب افزایش اثر شلاقی کل زنجیرۀ تأمین می‎شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اثر شلاق چرمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش میانگین متحرک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنجیرۀ تأمین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاست سفارش تا سطح هدف</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://imj.ut.ac.ir/article_63874_bf8b43af364919e3070a4c144de2e698.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
