<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت صنعتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5885</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigate the barriers of implement green supply chain in Mazandaran steel industry with a combined approach BSC / BWM</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی موانع پیاده‎سازی زنجیرۀ تأمین سبز در صنایع فولاد استان مازندران با رویکرد ترکیبی BSC/BWM</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>653</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>684</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">62698</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/imj.2017.62698</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>فلاح لاجیمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکدۀ علوم اقتصادی و اداری، دانشگاه مازندران، بابلسر، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5802-4027</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>عرب</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری تخصصی تحقیق در عملیات، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5024-2177</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هوشمند</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهرام زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت صنعتی (تولید و عملیات)، دانشگاه مازندران، بابلسر، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The concept of green supply chain management formed in manufacturing industries and recently put its focus on environmental issues. Various industries are trying to identify barriers for green supply chain implementation. In the past decade, due to the continuous environmental damage such as increased pollution, exhaustion of natural resources, extinction of animal and its harmful effects on humans, the growing importance of green supply chain management exists. A great tendency can be seen in Various industries to implement green supply chain. There are many obstacles to the successful implementation of the green supply chain that The aim of this research is identifying barriers to implementation of this concept by concentrating on the green supply chain researches. In this study, the combination of the BSC / BWM used and for the first time, the barriers to green supply chain were measured in terms of the Balanced Scorecard. This obstacle identified by customization model through a number of steel industry experts ranked by utilizing the best-worst method as a novel multi-criteria decision-making method. The results showed that internal processes and lack of clear environmental objectives, Lack of customer awareness about GSCM and green products and lack of technology, materials, and processes are the most important dimensions and criteria for green supply chain in the Mazandaran province steel industry respectively. Finally, some suggestions were given to overcome these barriers and reduce their effects.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در دهۀ گذشته، مدیریت زنجیرۀ تأمین سبز با توجه به تخریب مداوم محیط زیست مانند افزایش آلودگی، اتلاف منابع طبیعی، انقراض حیوانات و آثار مضر آن بر انسان، اهمیت روزافزونی یافته است. هدف از این تحقیق، شناسایی موانع استقرار زنجیرۀ تأمین سبز با تمرکز بر تحقیقات گذشته در خصوص این مفهوم است. در این تحقیق از مدل ترکیبی BSC/BWM استفاده شده و برای نخستین بار موانع زنجیرۀ تأمین سبز در ابعاد کارت امتیازی متوازن سنجیده می‎شود. این موانع با بومی‌سازی مدل توسط تعدادی از خبرگان و کارشناسان صنعت فولاد شناسایی و با استفاده از روش بهترین ـ بدترین به‎عنوان روشی نو در تصمیم‎گیری چند معیاره، رتبه‌بندی شدند. نتایج حاکی از آن بود که بعد فرایند‎های داخلی و شاخص‌های عدم وجود اهداف مشخص زیست‎محیطی، ناآگاهی مشتری دربارۀ مدیریت زنجیرۀ تأمین سبز و محصولات سبز و کمبود تکنولوژی، مواد و فرایندها، به‎ترتیب مهم‎ترین ابعاد و شاخص‌های موجود در استقرار زنجیرۀ تأمین سبز در صنایع فولاد استان مازندران هستند. در نهایت پیشنهادهایی به‎منظور غلبه بر این موانع و کاهش آثار آن ارائه شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصمیم‎گیری چندمعیاره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش بهترین ـ بدترین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنجیرۀ تأمین سبز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">موانع</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://imj.ut.ac.ir/article_62698_936a91cac9ade643b7bc1dbdb9601e14.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
