<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت صنعتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5885</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Development of technology acceptance model in Iranian banking (Case study: Refah Bank of Semnan province)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>توسعۀ مدل پذیرش فناوری در بانکداری ایران (پژوهشی پیرامون بانک رفاه)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>471</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>490</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">50679</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/imj.2014.50679</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جعفر</FirstName>
					<LastName>رزمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مهندسی صنایع، پردیس دانشکده‎های فنی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدعبدالله</FirstName>
					<LastName>حیدریه</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>شهابی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت تکنولوژی واحد علوم و تحقیقات، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Development of new technologies is one of the key success factors in most today’s organizations. But this point must also be considered that the acceptance of new technologies does not happen at the moment; it is a process that takes shape over time, and if the usage is repeated, it can be concluded that acceptance has been successful. Besides the systematical review of the researches conducted on technology acceptance model since it’s development by Davis so far in this paper, there has been an effort regarding basic TAM model variables and adding more neglected variables including habit, the ability to use and advertisements, a technology acceptance model has been presented considering social and cultural situation in Iran. A questionnaire was designed to test the assumptions, and after being completed by the staff of information Technology action Refah bank, it was analyzed using fuzzy dematel. Research result shows the fact that continuous use of a technology (like electronic banking) leads to an increase in habit of use that itself results in an increase of usage, indeed there will be a strong reinforcing loop. On the other hand, habit of using previous system (traditional banking) is of the main obstacles to users willing to use new technologies in Iran.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سازمان‎های امروزی برای دستیابی به موفقیت و بقا به فناوری‎های نوین و استفاده از آن نیاز دارند. تلاش‎های مدیریت فناوری زمانی به نتیجه می‎رسد که مشتریان فناوری جدید را بپذیرند و به‎طور مستمر از آن استفاده کنند. علاوه‎براین، پذیرش فناوری‎های نوین در لحظه اتفاق نمی‎افتد، فرایندی است که طی زمان شکل می‎گیرد و با استفادۀ مستمر، پذیرش موفق صورت می‎گیرد. در این مقاله ضمن مرور مطالعات انجام‎گرفته در زمینۀ مدل پذیرش فناوری ارائه‎شدۀ دیویس از زمان معرفی تا کنون، تلاش شده است با در نظر گرفتن متغیرهای مدل پذیرش فناوری اولیه و افزودن متغیرهای عادت، توانایی استفاده و تبلیغات که کمتر به آن توجه شده است، مدلی از پذیرش فناوری با توجه به وضعیت اجتماعی و فرهنگی ایران معرفی شود. پس از شناسایی متغیرها، برای بررسی روابط میان آنها پرسشنامه‎ای طراحی شد و با پاسخ خبرگان بخش فناوری اطلاعات بانک رفاه به پرسشنامه، داده‎های جمع‎آوری شده به‎کمک روش دیماتل فازی تجزیه‎وتحلیل شد. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‎دهد استفادۀ مستمر از فناوری (بانکداری الکترونیکی)، عادت به فناوری را افزایش می‎دهد و هرچه عادت افزایش یابد، استفاده از فناوری بیشتر می‎شود؛ در واقع یک چرخۀ تقویتی قوی به‎وجود خواهد آمد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بانکداری الکترونیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تبلیغات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دیماتل فازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عادت به سیستم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل پذیرش فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://imj.ut.ac.ir/article_50679_11a34d9d9bcd19601e245a01a8e308e8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
