<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت صنعتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5885</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Applying Value Engineering Through Fuzzy MADM Approach to Improving Project Performance</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>به‎کارگیری مهندسی ارزش با رویکرد MADM فازی در بهبود عملکرد پروژه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>81</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>98</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22997</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اکبر</FirstName>
					<LastName>عالم تبریز</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>منیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت صنعتی دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the most effective tools for decline cost and time, quality improvement and consequently project performance enhancement especially in construction projects, is value engineering. There are linguistic judgments in many cases of value engineering studies in construction projects such as interior design, mechanical installations design, and etc. Therefore multiple attribute decision-making techniques with fuzzy approach can be used in decision-making stages in value engineering process. In this paper, value engineering is combined with fuzzy MADM techniques. In this hybrid, fuzzy AHP technique is used in order to determine the weight of evaluation criteria recommended in creativity phase and fuzzy TOPSIS is used for ranking of alternatives. This approach was applied in design phase of mechanical installations of Mouj tower project in Sadaf town, one of the under construction projects in union sector of the state. According to the paper results, estimation of value engineering team, leads to 21.45 % of decreasing in project’s costs and 17.65% of decreasing in project’s duration.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از ابزارهای قدرتمندی که امروزه در راستای کاهش هزینه، زمان، افزایش کیفیت و در نتیجه بهبود عملکرد پروژه‌ها به‎خصوص پروژه‌های عمرانی به‏کار می‌رود، مهندسی ارزش است. برای مطالعه‎های مهندسی ارزش در پروژه‌های ساختمانی در بسیاری از موارد با قضاوت‎های زبانی و غیر دقیق سروکار داریم که می‌توان از روش‎های تصمیم‌گیری چند شاخصه با رویکرد منطق فازی، به‎جای روش‎های معمول استفاده کرد. در مقاله‎ی حاضر برنامه کار مهندسی ارزش با مدل‎های MADM فازی تلفیق شده است. در این تلفیق به‎منظور تعیین وزن معیارهای ارزیابی پیشنهادهای حاصل از مرحله خلاقیت، از روش AHP فازی و به‎منظور تعیین اولویت گزینه‎ها از روش TOPSIS فازی استفاده شده است. روش فوق در طرح تأسیسات مکانیکی پروژه برج موج شهرک مسکونی صدف، یکی از پروژه‎های در دست احداث بخش تعاونی در کشور، به‏کار گرفته شده است. بر اساس برآورد تیم مهندسی ارزش، اجرای طرح پیشنهادی به‎جای طرح اولیه، کاهش45/21 درصدی در هزینه پروژه و 6/17 درصدی در زمان پروژه را در پی خواهد داشت.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تأسیسات مکانیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصمیم‎گیری چند شاخصه فازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد پروژه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارکرد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://imj.ut.ac.ir/article_22997_0fc9c7577516f54ed1ed5d9751ba5aac.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
