<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت صنعتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5885</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Decision Making Model with AHP for Choosing the Merging, Acquisition and Joint Venture Strategies in Auto Industry</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارایه یک مدل تصمیم‌گیری بر اساس الگوی سلسله مراتبی برای انتخاب راهبرد ادغام، واگذاری، همکاری مشترک در صنعت خودروسازی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">20380</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عزت الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>اصغری زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>حقیقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>بلالی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Because of heavy competition between auto manufacturer and the threats of foreign companies, they try to reduce the internal competition and costs by cooperation and merge. Estimation about the auto market is affected by supply and demand. The demand depends on two factors: need for new cars and old cars exit. And the supply depends on production capacity and export. Key factors that affected on supply are income per capita and population age average. Auto market of Iran is closing to the equilibrium point and after it depends on GDP. In this paper find a solution for being successful and effective manager in survival in this industry, the concept of merge, strategic cooperation, buyout and acquisition is explained and with studying the complex market of auto in the world, we attention to their challenges for development and survival in Iran. Then with interview with experts and using multi criterion decision making method (AHP) we analyze the strategies of this industry. In this subject the advantages of merger such as cost reduction, accessing to knowledge, technology, suppliers, shared markets and financial resources in contrast of disadvantages such as import tariff and oil subsid and environmental standards are considered. The best strategy is cooperating with auto manufacturers.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به‌دلیل رقابت سنگین بین خودروسازان و تهدیداتی که توسط رقبای خارجی برای آنها وجود دارد، آنها سعی می‌کنند با همکاری یا ادغام، موجب کاهش رقابت داخلی شده و در هزینه‌های شرکت‌های خود صرفه‌جویی نمایند. ‌برآورد حجم بازار خودرو در کشور متاثر از دو عامل تقاضا و عرضه می‌باشد. تقاضا تابعی از نیاز جدید به خودرو و میزان خروج خودروهای فرسوده است و عرضه نیز تابعی است از ظرفیت تولید و بازارهای صادراتی. عوامل کلیدی موثر برتقاضا، درآمد سرانه و میانگین سنی جمعیت می‌باشند و پیش‌بینی تقاضا حاکی از نزدیک شدن بازار خودروی ایران به مرحله تعادل می‌باشد. ‌در این مقاله به‌منظور ارایه راهکار برای موفقیت مدیران و اثربخشی تلاش‌هایی که در جهت بقا و ارتقا این صنعت صورت می‌گیرد، مفهوم راهبرد ادغام، همکاری استراتژیک و واگذاری مطرح شده و با مطالعه بازار پیچیده خودرو در دنیا و چالش‌های آنها برای بقا و رشد، وضعیت صنعت خودروسازی کشورمان مورد توجه قرار می‌گردد. سپس با مصاحبه با متخصصان و نخبگان و استفاده از روش تصمیم‌گیری چند معیاره (AHP) راهبردهای این صنعت تحلیل می‌گردد. در این مقوله مزایای ادغام چون کاهش هزینه‌ها، دسترسی به دانش، فن‌آوری، تامین کنندگان و بازارهای مشترک و نیز توان مالی بالاتر در برابر معایبی چون انحصار و دولتی شدن بیشتر بررسی می‌شود و در این بین اثر کاهش تعرفه واردات و حذف سوبسید بنزین و استانداردهای زیستی نیز در نظر گرفته می‌شود. راهبرد پیشنهادی همکاری در تولید با خودروسازان خارجی است</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ادغام</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برند</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خودروسازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عرضه و تقاضا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://imj.ut.ac.ir/article_20380_842fd0c369ddba4a37365a310ee6ee94.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
