<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت صنعتی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2008-5885</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An analysis of housing market in Tehran Province using system dynamics</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل بازار مسکن استان تهران با استفاده از رویکرد پویایی‌شناسی سیستم</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>665</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>683</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">52449</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/imj.2014.52449</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدوند</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشکدة فنی مهندسی، مؤسسة آموزش عالی ایوانکی، سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حدیثه</FirstName>
					<LastName>خدادادی ابیازنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مهندسی صنایع، دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی، مؤسسة آموزش عالی ایوانکی، سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زینب</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدیانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مهندسی صنایع، دانشکدۀ فنی و مهندسی، مؤسسة آموزش عالی ایوانکی، سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>[Naeini1]  Housing is the third top factor in human life, after food and clothing in all communities. Many variables are involved in determining housing prices and it is impossible to ignore housing feedback. One of the powerful tools to determine the impact of policies in this field is using system dynamics approach. According to this approach, the cause-and- effect diagram of factors affecting housing prices in Tehran is presented for dynamic model. To simulate the intended model Vensim software was used. Finally, scenario making was conducted to consider various policies in housing market. The results show that enhanceing other provinces&#039; facilities, increasing the supply of affordable housing by the government as well as loaning for construction decrease the housing price thereby the price would be balanced.



 </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA"> مسکن بعد از خوراک و پوشاک، مهم‌ترین جزء زندگی افراد است. در تعیین قیمت مسکن، متغیرهای زیادی دخیل­اند و نادیده­گرفتن بازخوردها در بخش مسکن، ناممکن است. یکی از ابزارهای قدرتمند برای تعیین تأثیر سیاست‌ها در این حوزه، استفاده از رویکرد پویایی‌شناسی سیستم‌هاست. با توجه به این رویکرد، نمودار علّی- معلولی عوامل مؤثر بر قیمت مسکن در استان تهران، برای مدل­سازی پویای مسئله ارائه شده است. برای شبیه­سازی مدل درنظرگرفته­شده، از نرم­افزار ونسیم استفاده شده است. در پایان، به­منظور بررسی سیاست‌های مختلف در بازار مسکن، سناریو‌بندی صورت گرفته است. نتایج حاصل نشان می‌دهد افزایش امکانات شهری دیگر استان‌های کشور و همچنین عرضة مسکن­های ارزان‌قیمت از سوی دولت و ارائة تسهیلات برای ساخت‌وساز مسکن، به تعادل در قیمت مسکن و همچنین کاهش قیمت در بازار مسکن منجر می­شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازار مسکن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پویایی شناسی سیستم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عرضه و تقاضای مسکن</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://imj.ut.ac.ir/article_52449_6c43fa5d0da6d4b7eaadc933ca9a9cae.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
