<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Significance of Translation in Documents of Ancient Iranian Languages</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اهمیت ترجمه در مستنداتِ زبان‌های ایرانی باستان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>107</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>126</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">4395</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>موسی</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمودزهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>رشته فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، گروه زبان و ادبیات انگلیسی، دانشگاه ولایت ایرانشهر، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهره‌مند</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیأت علمی گروه زبان و ادبیات انگلیسی، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ولایت، ایرانشهر، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;: &lt;/strong&gt;
Based on the existing documents remained from Iranian Languages, the present study aims at investigating the significance of translation through the three historical epochs of Achaemenid, Parthian and Sassanid dynasties in Ancient Persia. The results indicated that the geographical extension of each empire along with existence of variations in population, language and traditions as well as the diversity of economic, social and political relations had made the use of both written and oral translations inevitable for their citizens. Such documents and the historical analyses around them reveal that the majority of translations of the era were the Royal Orders, religious and scientific texts and deeds related to commerce and families to fulfill the requirements and goals of the era. Moreover, some measures taken byShapur I, Shapur II and Khosrow Ito develop translation and interpretation were so vast and influential to be named “the movements of translation”. Studying translation products made in the era also revealed that there existed several languages simultaneously but with different ranks. The results of the present study can be of use to researchers in fields such as history, history of science, archeology, historical linguistics, Iranian studies as well as Iranian Culture and Literature.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله به بررسی اهمیت ترجمه بر اساس مستندات موجود از زبان‌های ایرانی در سه دورۀ تاریخی ایرانِ باستان شامل هخامنشی، اشکانی و ساسانی پرداخته شده است. یافته‌‌ها نشان می‌‌دهد که گستردگی جغرافیایی هر کدام از این سه فرمانروایی ایرانی و تنوع و تکثر جمعیت‌‌های انسانی با زبان‌ها، آداب و رسوم، و روابط سیاسی، اقتصادی، اجتماعی متفاوت؛ ضرورت استفاده از ترجمۀ شفاهی و مکتوب را در میان مردم اجتناب‌‌ناپذیر ساخته بود. مستندات موجود و مباحث تاریخیِ پیرامون آنها، حاکی از آن است که غالبِ این ترجمه‌‌ها از نوعِ فرمان‌‌های شاهان، متون مذهبی، متون علمی، معاملات اقتصادی، و اسنادخانوادگی بود که هر کدام در جای خود هدف یا ضرورتی را در پی داشت، آن چنانکه بخشی ازاقدامات شاهان ساسانی مانند شاپور اول، شاپور دوم و خسرو انوشیروان را دراین خصوص، می‌‌توان به نام &lt;em&gt;نهضت ترجمه&lt;/em&gt; تعبیر کرد. بررسیِ این ترجمه‌‌ها نشان می‌‌دهدکه چندین زبان با درجۀ اهمیت متفاوت به صورت همزمان در این امپراتوری‌‌ها رواج داشته است. حاصل این مقاله می‌‌تواند امروز به علومی مانند تاریخ، تاریخِ علم، باستان‌‌شناسی، زبان‌‌شناسیِ تاریخی، ایران‌‌شناسی، و فرهنگ و ادبیاتِ ایرانی کمک کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایران باستان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌های ایرانی باستان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترجمه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کتیبه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زند اوستا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">متون مانوی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4395_3b6e5a6e54fb894b9bc02bc355d0199f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
