<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Literary figures in the hymns of the Iranian language Manicheans</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abbas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azarandaz</namePart>
				<affiliation>Researcher of Shahid Bahonar University of Kerman</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Much of poetry of Iran in middle period has been composed by Manicheans in middle Persian, Parthian and Sogdian languages. These poems are praise and liturgical or mystic hymns that narrate the story of strangeness of light in the prison of Matter. In the latter, because of more connection with human, the emotion and imagination element are clearer, and the poetic art can be better observed in them. The figures of speech, both figures of word and figures of thought have been greatly used in these poems. Apart from existing the figures that are expected in every poem and are in the nature of poetry, the specimens can be seen that they are correspond even with the definitions of rhetorical books in Islamic period. The figures of speech in Manichaean poems can be divided in two groups; the sound music (figures of word), and spiritual music (figures of thought). It has been used in the figures of word field, the repetition (words, sentences and phonemes); and in the figures of thought field, the figures such as antithesis, amphiboly and apostrophe. It has been attempted in this article to show the quality of use of figures of speech in Manichaean poems surviving in Middle Persian, Parthian and Sogdian languages, along with citing the specimens.   </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>26</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1904_6ab273d4d0b64664eed492e049d6bf94.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Cognitive Mechanisms and Their Role in Do’a Conceptualization</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shirin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Pourebrahim</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Linguistics department, Payame- Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Abstract Cognitive strategies, first introduced in Cognitive Semantics, are cognitive devices like conceptual metonymies, conceptual metaphors, image metaphors and schemas which structure abstract concepts in our minds and facilitate our understanding. This paper aims to study examples of these strategies in the language of Sahife Sajjadie. For this purpose, I have analyzed cases of structural, orientational, and ontological metaphors, as well as conceptual metonymies, image metaphors and image schemas in this religious text to find out two things. What is the role of these strategies in conceptualization and understanding of abstract concepts, and to find whether the analyzed language is a literary language or not. Analysis of the selected metaphorical data shows that religious abstract concepts are represented both literally and non-literally. Non-literal representations of concepts are structured by using cognitive strategies of metaphor, metonymy, image schemas and metaphors. In addition, language of Do’a in this book has used the same metaphors as ordinary conventional language, though it has used extending, elaboration, combining of metaphors, as well as personification and metaphorical images which assimilate it to a literary work.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>25</start>
					<end>44</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1905_93e5143cfb26c10f9af1b4fdd040aeb5.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>nam- and rēž-, Two Sogdian Impersonal Verbs</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jalalian Chaleshtari,</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ancient Iranian Culture and Languages
Fauculty of Persian Literature and Foreign Languages
University of Tabriz</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The Impersonal verb is a verb which is always inflected in the third singular and its logical subject does not appear in the nominative case. These verbs often express physical or mental/cognitive experiences which the logical subject experiences without having any control on them. Thus the subject in these structures is called &quot;experiencer&quot;. Another element which has a role in impersonal sentences is the source of the events, activities and experiences. It&#039;s presence in the sentence depends on the meaning of the verb. In Sogdian beside some of the modal verbs which are in accordance with the definition of impersonal verbs, there are two other verbs which are impersonal too. These are rēž- and nam-. As will be shown rēž- is appeared as an impersonal verb approximately in all the remaining evidences, but nam- has impersonal use just in one of it&#039;s evidences. In this article I will study and analyze these two verbs.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>45</start>
					<end>60</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1906_3e1ff344a691655ea1f24f2c309f5946.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Urartian Bronze Inscribed Horse Harness Disc in Eastern Azerbaijan Museum</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">dara</namePart>
				<affiliation>پژوهشکده زبان‌‌شناسی، متون و کتیبه‌‌ها</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Urartians left pieces of evidence of their domination in North West of Iran. They were extraordinary metalworkers and sometimes wrote the name of the Urartian king on their objects. They sometimes decorated or even inscribed horse equipment with short inscriptions. Some discs from horse harnesses, with or without inscriptions, are found from Urartian kingdom. A similar object exists in Eastern Azerbaijan Museum which is a bronze disc from the horse harness with the inscription of Argishti I. This disc is dedicated to the museum by a rural from Varzaghan. Although the name of the king’s father is not written but epigraphically it is from Argishti I.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>61</start>
					<end>78</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1907_70a6d4cb8197f8698f44814fdbc953e0.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The study of markedness hierarchies in nominal and pronominal morphology of modern north-western Iranian languages</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rasekh Mahand</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate professor of General Linguistics, Bu-Ali Sina University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Masoud</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadirad</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD student in General Linguistics, Bu-Ali Sina University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This paper aims to investigate markedness in nominal and pronominal morphology of modern north-western Iranian languages from a diachronic perspective based on Hawkinʼs (2004) minimized forms principle. Based on this principle marked forms ocuupy the lowest and unmarked forms the highest position in performance-based hierarchies. Forms are ranked based on their frecuency in performance-based hierarchies. The reason that there exist these different frecuensies can be attributed to communicative reasons, complixity and different occurances of linguistic units in outside world. In this paper, we have shown that markedness changes in number and gender hierarchies are in line with minimized forms principle and its predictions in the investigated languages, but there are some exceptions in case hierarchy, which is not in line minimized forms predictions.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>79</start>
					<end>112</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1908_b3fea2f5f24c512c04f37e740ab2a982.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Prepositional Phrases in Persian:A Functional Analysis</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Vali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rezai</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor,Departement of linguistics, Faculty of Foreign languages</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">homayon</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Saeidi</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A  in Teaching Persian to Non-Persian Speakers. Departement of linguistics</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Prepositional phrases have a significant place in different syntactic theories. In Role and Reference Grammar these constituents are categorized into three classes namely Adjuncts, Argument markers and Argument-adjuncts. Adjuncts PPs offer semantic information for the sentence in which they occur. They are adverbial elements modifying the event or situation described by the predicate. Argument marking PPs mark an argument of the predicate. In this class the preposition itself does not contribute semantic information. Argument- adjunct PPs contain predicative adpositions that add to the meaning of the sentence. Also, they introduce one of the participants in the event. This paper examines different PPs in Persian based on the classification of RRG. It will be demonstrated that PPs in Persian do not always function as adjuncts, but they play as markers of arguments in ditransitive clauses or even as direct objects with some predicates. To conclude we will show that RRG accounts for prepositional phrases in Persian.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>113</start>
					<end>135</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1909_6051016073da94ba3b7ff99091b892bf.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Process of Metaphor Comprehension Development in Persian-Speaking Children of 6 to 8 Years Old</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shahla</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Raghibdoust</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Linguistics, Allameh Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shohreh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sadeghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Corresponding Author: Phd Candidate of Linguistics, Allameh Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The present study, evaluated the developmental process of metaphor comprehension in Persian-speaking children of three age groups of 6, 7 and 8 years old. Some researchers believe that metaphor comprehension occurs at the beginning of adolescence. Another group believes that preschool children can understand metaphorical concepts. Cognitive linguists believe that metaphors are fundamental aspects of language and cognition, which are used innately and subconsciously, for perceiving emotions and other mental and abstract concepts. To examine the children’s metaphoric competence, a multiple-choice test of 36 metaphoric sentences, in four subtests, was designed. Based on the findings, children are able to comprehend different types of metaphors at early ages, and their interpretation of metaphors develops progressively with the increase of age and world knowledge development. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>137</start>
					<end>160</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2080_3ccccdea0367d28fec7754d000a1ef84.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Comparison of Some Meta-Linguistic Similarities Between 
Ibn Khaldoun's and Chomsky’s Views</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ruhollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sayyadi-nejad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Arabic Language and Literature from Kashan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abbas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zare&#039;i Tajareh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of English Language and Literature from Kashan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Tayyebeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bagh-chaei</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA of Arabic Language and Literature from Kashan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Human language is a very complicated system that has been studied by scholars in different centuries; among whom was, &quot;Abdul-Rahman Ibn Khaldoun&quot;, the great Muslim scholar, that discussed language faculty in his study of society and named it &quot;Al-Malakat Al-Lughawiyah&quot; (The Queen of Words), in his famous book &quot;Al- Muqaddimah&quot; (The Introduction) where he argued that, a child has an innate ability for language learning to him, this is a gradual quality that does not come about all at once. In the same vein, &quot;Chomsky&quot;, the contemporary American linguist, explored linguistic competence following “Ibn Khaldoun”. He, too, believed that, language faculty is innate, and that the mind sets parameters for universal principles. Results of this comparative study of the two scholars, highlighted differences and similarities between the two, and revealed that Chomsky’s language faculty was first introduced by &quot;Ibn Khaldoun&quot;; whom should, therefore, be accredited as the founder of this view based on the results.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>161</start>
					<end>183</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2037_1ad2d1b3fa9f57a2e20ff2dac754387e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Poetics of Literary Works
In the Account of the Fore-text, Text, and Post-Text</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Pooran (Sediqeh)</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Alipoor</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Department of Languages and Literature, Faculty of Literature and Humanities, Shahid Bahonar University of Kerman, Ira</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Poetics is the knowledge to read a literary work, not solely based on the meaning of the text, but rather based on the more abstract elements that create the literary piece. Consequently, the Poetics of a literary work can be indefinitely identified only via the structure of the work itself, based on descriptions and elicitations of how it was developed and evolved. The poetics structural format of a literary work consists of fore-text, text, and post-text, which are constantly under the influence of the process of writing in its past, present and future, as an abstract and experimental phenomenon. Poetics, according to their performance score on the analysis of literary work, can answer the question of value and status of literary works, in relevance to literary criticism.. This paper strives to explain the concepts and theories related to the topic, and analyze the Poetics elements involved in the creation of a literary piece. In conclusion, in addition to clarifying the metaphysical presence of process, the post-textual evolutionary and developmental parameters are analyzed. 
�ته این امر مسلم است که بوطیقا تنها از طریق ساختار اثر می‌‌تواند نحوۀ تحول و تکوین آن را تبیین نماید. اثر ادبی، در حوزۀ ساختار بوطیقایی‌‌اش، در سه رخداد پیشامتن، متن، و پسامتن شکل می‌‌گیرد. پس، تحت تأثیر فرایند نوشتار، بوطیقا، همواره در زمان گذشته، حال و آیندۀ خود، هم‌چون پدیده‌ای تجریدی و تجربی جریان دارد و، با توجه به عملکردش در خصوص تحلیل ساختار اثر ادبی، می‌‌تواند پاسخی بر پرسش محتوم چگونگی ارزش آن بیان کند؛ به همین دلیل، جایگاه ویژه‌‌ای در امر نقد آثار ادبی دارد. این مقاله می‌‌کوشد تا در این راستا، ضمن تشریح مفاهیم و نظریه‌‌های مرتبط با موضوع، به تحلیل حوزۀ بوطیقا در خلق اثر بپردازد. بدین‌‌ ترتیب، فرایند نوشتار را از آغاز نیت ژرف مؤلف در پیشامتن، و ،پس از آن، در گسترۀ فضامند متن و تبدیل آن به کتاب تا ادامۀ روند حیات تجریدی‌‌اش در غیاب مؤلف، کتاب، و ر‌هایی از خوانندۀ تأویل‌‌گر، بررسی نماید. در نهایت، ضمن تبیین حضور متافیزیک گونۀ فرایند، پارامترهای تعالی‌بخش پسامتنی را، تحلیل کند.
 </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>185</start>
					<end>206</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2197_65c60abe3d072200a560c1a8e3c46a03.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Prince of Darkness in Five Pits of Destruction
Identification of a Parthian Manuscript Fragment from Turfan Manichaean Collection</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">shokrifomeshi</namePart>
				<affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی، دانشگاه ادیان و مذاهب</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Identification and recognition of the Turfan Manichaean fragments belonging to the Ewangelyōnīg bāšāhs are the main aim of this article. In a codicological study the author attempts to show whether the fragment M441 is a piece of the same manuscript page from which M507 has been separated. Positive answer to this provides a new unified text which mainly contains a poetical expression of the Manichaean Creation myth and of the quarrelsome deeds of the “Prince of Darkness” (Ahriman) in Manichaeism.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>207</start>
					<end>230</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2198_8f05b1ce8a8201fe1a28f2828281d52d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Ecological Approach in Linguistic Researches</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fariba</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghatreh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Linguistics, Al-Zahra University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamideh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Poshtvan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Masters of Linguistics, Al-Zahra University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahnaz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Talebi-Datenaei</namePart>
				<affiliation>Corresponding Author: PhD Candidate of Linguistics, Al-Zahra University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Linguistic diversity, across socio-natural environments, reflects similarities and differences in ethnic groups’ views towards natural ecological phenomena. This diversity is driven by needs, cognition, culture, human-related and environmental factors. Lexicon, categorization, and classification in any given language, act differently with regard to interaction with ecology. Ecolinguistics emerged in 1990s as a new approach in language studies, which focuses on the interrelationship between a given language, and its users’ geographical and natural environment. This paper, aims to introduce Eco-linguistics, as well as its potentials in dialect-related research, highlighting the impact of natural environment on lexical, morphological, and syntactic differences among languages and dialects. The current paper, studies the relationship between Eco-linguistics approach, and Gilani and Semnani dialects from two different ecologies. The results reveal that, in the authors’ beliefs, this new approach can explain why the means of naming concepts and phenomena vary in dialects, how metaphors develop, and why regional–and local-dialects sometimes differ incredibly in terms of their lexicon and morpho-syntax. The answers eco-linguistics provides to these questions appear reasonable to a considerable extent.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>231</start>
					<end>243</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2081_b5422b526a2c7c35b2d55d9eb0847410.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>