<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>10</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analytical Approaches to the History of Zoroastrainism</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تاریخ دین زردشتی روش‌های بررسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>167</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>180</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1891</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهشید</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرفخرایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد پژوهشکدۀ زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>There appears to be virtual agreements on the date of Zoroaster and on the fact that the religion of the Achaemenian dynasts is part of the history of Zoroastrianism. The subject which remains hotly debated is the reconstruction of a pre-Zoroastrian Iranian religion. The main problem in the study of Zoroastrian history is discontinuity between three distinct corpora of textual sources, namely: the Avesta, the Old Persian inscriptions and Zoroastrian literature, since none of them reflect the religion of the ordinary people. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the academic discussions of the history of Zoroastrianism, three different approaches are observed: The first approach (fragmentizing) rejects the notion of a single Zoroastrian tradition and concentrates on the Gāthās as the only source of information for Zarathustra&#039;s teachings, and compares its notions and references with the Vedic tradition. The second approach (harmonizing) emphasizes on the combined evidence of Avesta and Pahlavi books. Its main attitude is the recognition of the fact that the three different collections basically reflect the teaching of Zarathustra and developments are not due to ruptures and breaks in the tradition or because of influence of other religions. The third approach (diversifying) regards the combined evidence of Avesta and Pahlavi books as a variegated elastic tradition rather than a strict doctrinal system, and describes the Mazdeism of Sasanian as an active efficient religion.&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">دربارة تعیین زمان زردشت و دین هخامنشیان توافق‌هایی نسبی به دست آمد، اما آن‌چه هم‌چنان مورد بحث است دین ایرانیان پیش از زردشت است. عمده‌ترین مسئله در بررسی تاریخ دین زردشتی، ناپیوستگی میان سه پیکرة اساسی منابع است که عبارت‌اند از: &lt;em&gt;اوستا&lt;/em&gt;، سنگ‌نبشته‌های هخامنشی، و ادبیات زردشتی که هیچ یک انعکاس‌دهندة دین عامة مردم نیست و گه‌گاه پاره‌ای از عقاید مردم در آن‌ها بازتاب یافته است. اما به هر حال منطقی‌تر آن است که از خلال همین آثار مبهم و غیرصریح محتوای فکری آغازین مردم ایران را، که پایه‌های اصلی دین آنان را تشکیل می‌دهند، بشناسیم. به طور کلی، در بررسی دین پیش‌زردشتی ایران سه رویکرد به نظر می‌رسد: 1. تاریخ دین را منحصراً بر اساس گاهان تعیین می‌کند و ابزار کار تفسیری است از اشارات گاهانی به‌جای‌مانده و انطباق آن‌ها بر سنت ودایی؛ 2. بر هم‌سازی و ترکیب شواهد &lt;em&gt;اوستا&lt;/em&gt; و کتاب‌های پهلوی تأکید دارد و ارزش این مواد را در آن می‌داند که بازتاب‌دهندة مجموعة آموزه‌های زردشت و نمودار روند طبیعی رشد هستند و تغییرات حاصل‌شده در آن را موجب گسست در سنت و نفوذ ادیان دیگر نمی‌داند؛ 3. شواهد ترکیب‌شده از &lt;em&gt;اوستا&lt;/em&gt; و کتاب‌های پهلوی را متنوع و انعطاف‌پذیر می‌شمارد و آن را دستگاه اعتقادی خشک نمی‌داند و مزدیسنای ساسانیان را دینی پویا و کارآمد توصیف می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تاریخ دین زردشتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دین پیش‌زردشتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنت ودایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنگ‌نبشته‌های فارسی باستان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اوستا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آثار فارسی میانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ادبیات زردشتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1891_7e38e43f34faae2ea1bc9d7dd1824854.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
