<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>16</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Introduction to the Pahlavi numeral system and an effective approach to the calculus of  Pahlavi numbers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>معرفی دستگاه عددنویسی پهلوی و رهیافتی موثر به حساب اعداد پهلوی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>27</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>53</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">3262</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری مته کلائی (آریا بزرگمهر)</LastName>
<Affiliation>فیزیک/ دانشگاه سمنان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرزانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>گشتاسب</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Pahlavi numbers written by Pahlavi alphabet and including from an impressing numeral system, although we do not have a symbol for zero and at first glance it is non-positional but writing in such a way that it’s easy to determine the order of each number. Our approach into calculus of these numbers show that in summing up these numbers do not need a especial algorithm, also the number of products which an ancient child was preserved compare with other ancient numerals was much less. Moreover some of the large numbers (greater than ten thousand) have more than one display and this indicates the ability of this system.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اعداد پهلوی برپایۀ حروف الفبای پهلوی نوشته می‌شوند و از یک دستگاه عددنویسی توانمند و درخور توجه برخوردارند، با آنکه در این عددنویسی نمادی برای صفر نداریم و در نگاه نخست، ناموضعی به نظر می‌رسد ولی شیوۀ نگارش آنها به گونه ای است که به سادگی می توان جایگاه یا مرتبۀ هر عدد را روشن ساخت. رویکرد ما به حساب این اعداد نشان می‌دهد، در جمع این اعداد نیازمند الگوریتم ویژه‌ای نیستیم، همچنین شمار حاصل ضرب‌هایی که یک کودک ایران باستان می‌بایست از بر‌می‌بوده در مقایسه با دیگر دستگاه‌های عددنویسی کهن بسیار کمتر است. افزون بر همۀ این ها برخی از اعداد بزرگ (بزرگتر از ده هزار) بیش از یک نمایش دارند و این خود توانمندی این دستگاه عدد نویسی را نشان می دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعداد پهلوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الفبای فارسی میانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">متون پهلوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حساب اعداد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دستگاه عددنویسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3262_a071d8cf3385b89918819a7152bef584.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
