<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Phonological and morphological adaptations in Azerbayjani Turkish loanwords</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ahmadkhani</namePart>
				<affiliation>زبان شناسی دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Diana</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rashidian</namePart>
				<affiliation>زبان شناسی دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This research is on the phonological and morphological shifts of Azerbaijani Turkish loanwords. Speakers of most languages in order to utilize the loan words shift and adapt them according to their native morphological and phonological system. In this research, first, the loanwords from Arabic and Persian collected, and then their phonological shifts as vowel harmony, mutation, insertion, deletion, lenition, and assimilation as well as morphological shifts such as derivation and compounding studied. The method of this research is descriptive and analytic and data are collected from Turkish dictionaries. The framework of phonological shifts is generative phonology. In this research, 704 loanwords from Arabic and Persian studied. Among phonological shifts the most frequent shift was vowel harmony and the least one is assimilation. In morphological shifts, derivation and compounding are studied. In this type of shift, the most frequent one is derivation and the least one is compounding.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>13</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>15</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2490_de3d0831a077c5f070d2045f7e961dff.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>IndefP as a New Functional Category in Persian</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hosseini-Maasoum</namePart>
				<affiliation>زبانشناسی دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mahdavy</namePart>
				<affiliation>زبان و ادبیات فارسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The so-called indefiniteness morpheme or enclitic /i:/ in Persian has been substantially studied from morphological and semantic points of view, but rarely given full analysis in syntactic surveys. Mostly considered as an affix attached to the head noun in NP/DP, it is seldom considered as independent or significant in syntactic representations. In generative syntax, especially in the Minimalist Program, functional categories have been suggested as elements which regulate the grammatical relations among lexical categories. Formerly, the functional category Ezafe has been established above nominal heads in Persian NPs. The present study, introduces IndefP as a functional category in Persian for the first time, and seeks to give structures containing the /i:/ element the fullest analysis they have ever enjoyed. Evidence is provide as to depict a full minimalist projection for this category and analyze complex structures headed by this functional item. Indefinite Phrase is shown to be a head-last projection which selects NP/DPs as its complement and accepts various structures (CPs, PPs or APs) as its adjuncts. It is further shown that this analysis is not limited to nominal structures in A-positions and is also extendable to those appearing in A-bar positions as sentence adverbs attached to the (maximal or intermediate) projection of T.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>13</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>17</start>
					<end>46</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2491_a4cadecb02cfd5ed93fe845a28d89bd4.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Urartian inscription with the cross in Maku</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Dara</namePart>
				<affiliation>پژوهشکده زبانشناسی/متون و کتیبه‌ها</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Heydari</namePart>
				<affiliation>باستان‌شناسی انستیتو خاور نزدیک  LMU مونیخ/ آلمان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Many stone blocks with the cross carved on them have been found in Armenia and Turkey. They had been inscribed with cuneiform inscriptions, especially Urartian. Some are being studied so far but no similar inscription has been found in Iran. Recently, a badly damaged cuneiform inscription with a cross on it is found in Maku being studied by the authors. The right side of the block is the end of a cuneiform inscription and the left side is broken in order to be reused. Therefore, the inscription is not complete and has a half or parts not being found yet. The obverse with a cross carved on it in an unknown period is Assyrian and only some signs have been left. There is only one sign left on the reverse. The epigraphy of the inscription shows that this inscription is written by Urartians between 800 and 700 B.C. This inscription is introduced in this paper and its epigraphy is studied and it is compared to the similar ones.
 
 </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>13</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>47</start>
					<end>57</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2492_6fa798b593e071215623e98f37a4f817.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>From Volition to Future: The Grammaticalization of "Future Tense" in Persian</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shadi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Davari</namePart>
				<affiliation>مدرس دانشکده پیراپزشکی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehrdad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Naghzguy-Kohan</namePart>
				<affiliation>هیأت علمی گروه زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>As it is generally assumed, the concept of future is not a concept of novelty. However the specialized strategies of encoding the notion are recently emerged. Typologically, the lexical units bearing the meanings of &quot;desire&quot; and &quot;volition&quot; are potentially major constructions representing the meaning of future. This embodies in the fact that intension is future projecting. The present contribution illustrates the grammaticalization of xâstan from a lexical verb to a modal auxiliary of volition and then to an auxiliary encoding the future tense. The result offers a clear picture of specialization process of using the future marker in a scheduled and  inevitable future situation.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>13</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>59</start>
					<end>87</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2493_5cd7ea4e99032926c426c58a87b85263.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Metaphor and Ecocriticism:
Case Study on two Stories 
"Gilemard" and "Az Khame Chambar"</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rakei</namePart>
				<affiliation>پژوهشکده زبان‌شناسی/ پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات‌فرهنگی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Naeimi Hashkavaee</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Environmental crises are the outcome of this thought that human being is the center of creation and the entire world is for them and for their needs. Versus this view, there is biocentric view which believes the nature is centre in the world. These two views indicate that human being effects on environment and also is influenced from it. These effects appear on mind and thought and finally represent in language of us. The aim of this paper is investigating of the effect of environment on thought which represent in metaphoric expressions.. In this paper, on the basis of Shiri(1387) classification, two climates of Iran(North and Khorasan)(Alavi and Dolatabadi) is selected. The results show that biocentric view is represented in regional novel. The writers of this kind of novel conscious or unconscious centered the nature and used the metaphor of &quot;Mother of the Nature&quot; in different forms in their novels.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>13</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>89</start>
					<end>103</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2494_3abb4ce687eb036fbca140cebb8a89a5.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Dadisho Qatraya’s Commentary on fifteenth homily of Abba Isaiah</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Niloofar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shahrokhi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه‌آزاد اسلامی/ واحد علوم تحقیقات</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Zohreh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zarshenas</namePart>
				<affiliation>هیئت علمی پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Sogdian Christian works are consisted of some parts of gospel translations, and translations of works and biographies of holy men, homilies and commentaries, acts of Christian martyrs and comments of church leaders from Syriac to Soghdian. These works are in fact a kind of ‎translating literature, which are mostly translated from Syriac to Sogdian. ‎‎&quot;Dādišo‛ Qatarāyā&#039;s commentary on the fifteenth homily of Abbā Isaiah&quot; is ‎one of these works that is studied in this paper in terms of translating from Sogdian to Persian, comparing it to Syriac translation, and comparing linguistic features of this kind of Sogdian literature with another species of Sogdian works.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>13</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>105</start>
					<end>130</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2495_416ece8628c504387c360326718c36be.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The role of anxiety in using learning strategies of Persian as a second language
In regard to the mediating role of cognitive intelligence</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mansoureh Sadat</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sadeghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>روانشناسی/پژوهشکده خانواده/ دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahinnaz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mirdehghan</namePart>
				<affiliation>زبانشناسی دانشکده ادبیات/ دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amirreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Vakilifard</namePart>
				<affiliation>آموزش زبان فارسی/دانشگاه بین‌المللی امام خمینی (ره) / قزوین</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdiye</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghanaat</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The present research is aimed to examine the role of anxiety in using learning strategies of Persian as a second languagein regard to the mediating role of cognitive intelligence.The study corpus includes 80 non-Iranian Persian learners of Imam Khomeini International University who have participated by filled out the 3 research questionnaires including Motivational strategies for learning questioner, anxiety and Cognitive Intelligence tests.The data analysis illustrates the role of anxiety in learning strategies, in both with and without its mediating role of cognitive intelligence operation.This role acts in such a way that by increasing the extent of anxiety, the level of strategy learning will be reduced. Increase in anxiety also results in the reduction of the cognitive intelligence of operation; i.e. anxiety reveals a meaningful inverse relation with the cognitive intelligence. The more increasing anxiety is associated to the more decrease in personal efficiency in the cognitive intelligence. Moreover the conclusions revealed that cognitive intelligence operation have a direct effect on application level of learning strategy in such a manner that by increasing in cognitive intelligence operation, the extent of the learning strategy application will be expanded. The results of this conclusion pointed out that not only learning strategy is under the effect of personal intelligence components but also the other psychological component such as anxiety could act as a destructive role even more than the cognitive intelligence at the level of application of these strategies. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>13</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>131</start>
					<end>149</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2496_070922fe8d9e84c3dd260df4a5582587.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/.</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>