<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>6</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Polyphony and Poly-Subjectivity in Iranian Postmodern Novel; A Study of Asfar-e Kateban by Abutorab-e Khosravi</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>چندصدایی و چندشخصیتی در رمان پسامدرن ایران با نگاهی به رمان اسفار کاتبان از ابوتراب خسروی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>85</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>120</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">678</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوبخت</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری زبان‌‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;em&gt;Asfar-e Kaateban &lt;/em&gt;by Aboutorab Khosravi&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is a polyphonic text in the light of the presence of associated and amalgamated various voices. &lt;em&gt;Polyphony &lt;/em&gt;is a term that Mikhail Bakhtin used to refer to Dostoyevsky&#039;s works, in which characters have dialogue in some manner. By means of dialogue, characters renounce the dominance of author and they can illustrate their individuality. &lt;br /&gt;In Pre-Modern works, narrator was the dominant recite in the whole text which did not authorize characters to express their impressions. In Modern era, this complete dominance of narrator is suppressing and we can identify the equality of characters&#039; authority and narrator&#039;s authority in expressing the impressions. Nowadays in Post-Modern world, this equality converts to the complete independence of characters and even they disobey narrator. Consequently, text exemplifies the presence of numerous voices, and by means of polyphony, the polarity nature of postmodern atmosphere is illustrated. Here, a question arises that how polyphony is personified, or in other words, how polyphony is textualized. The focus of this paper is on the reflex of characters&#039; psyche in their language. Therefore, the formation of embedded focalization and its affect on making polyphony is shown through the analysis of combination and competition of different characters and the presence of other characters in the mind of a character. The analysis of selected texts demonstrates that Khosravi managed to create polyphony and poly subjectivity, and consequently, the place and role of characters in the postmodern text is indicated. And it is multi-focalizer that collects other focalized in itself. Then, focalized are sometimes other person and other self of focalizer itself. In this situation, we have first person pronoun and third person pronoun that are used by focalizer to refer to it, to its subjective and objective self; me and him / her.  Therefore, different voices embody their effects in text, and the text, also manifests its polyphonic characteristic by means of poly-subjectivity, that is the resultant of these different self.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;em&gt;اسفار کاتبان&lt;/em&gt; از ابوتراب خسروی، به اعتبار حضور صداهای چندگانة شخصیت‌‌ها با‌هم و در‌هم، متنی چندصدایی تلقی می‏شود. چندصدایی اصطلاحی ‏است که باختین برای اشاره به رمان‌‌های داستایفسکی از آن استفاده کرد، که، در آن‌ها، شخصیت‌‌ها به گونه‏ای به مکالمه با هم می‌‌پردازند. در رمان‌‌های پیشامدرن، راوی گویندة مسلط در کل متن بود که اجازة هیچ‌‌گونه ابراز عقیده‌‌ای را به شخصیت‌‌ها نمی‌‌داد. در دورة مدرن، این تسلط کامل راوی از بین می‌‌رود و برابری قدرت شخصیت‌‌ها و راوی را در بیان عقایدشان شاهدیم. &lt;br /&gt;حال در دورة پسامدرن، این برابری به‏استقلال کامل شخصیت‌‌ها در متن بدل می‏شود و شخصیت‌‌ها حتی گاه از راوی/ نویسندة رمان نافرمانی می‌‌کنند. به این‏ترتیب، متن شاهد حضور آواهای متعدد می‏شود و، از طریق چندصدایی، سرشت متکثرگونة فضای پسامدرنیستی را می‌‌نمایاند. حال سؤال این ‏است که چندصدایی چگونه در متن تجسم‏ یا، به عبارتی، متنیت می‌‌یابد. بر این اساس، در این مقاله، تأکید روی بازتاب ذهنیت شخصیت‌‌ها در زبان آن‌ها‏ست. بنابراین، با بررسی ترکیب و رقابت انواع متفاوت شخصیت‌‌ها و نیز حضور دیگر شخصیت‌‌ها در ذهن ‏یک شخصیت، چگونگی شکل‌‌گیری کانونی‌‌سازی درونه‌‌گیری‌‌شده و تأثیر آن در ایجاد چندصدایی متن نشان داده خواهد شد. با توجه به متن‌‌های نمونه‌ای که در بخش تحلیل داده‌ها آورده شده، ما نه تغییر مدام زاویة دید بلکه‏ حضور کانونی‏سازهای چندگانه را شاهدیم که کانونی‌‌شونده‌های دیگر را در خود جمع می‌کند. این کانونی‌شونده‌ها گاهی افراد دیگری‌‌اند و گاهی خودِ دیگرِ کانونی‌ساز. بنابراین، هنگام بازگویی مطالب از زبان کانونی‌‌سازِ چندگانه، ضمیر‌های اول‏شخص و سوم‌شخص را می‌بینیم که از جانب خودِ کانونی‌ساز برای اشاره به خود به‌کار می‌رود: خودِ عینی و خودِ ذهنی‌اش، یعنی ضمیر‌های «من» و «او». بدین‌ترتیب، صداهای متفاوت تأثیر زبانی خود را در متن تجسم می‌بخشند و متن، به‌‌واسطة چند‌‌شخصیتیِ حاصل از این خودهای متفاوت، چندصدایی‏بودن خود را متجلی می‌سازد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پسامدرنیسم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چندصدایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چندشخصیتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اسفار کاتبان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ابوتراب خسروی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_678_a914e30b352959360e2e2cace0069e03.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
