<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>12</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Verse Poetry and Poetic Prose in Indo-European Languages</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شعر منظوم و نثر شاعرانه در زبان‌های هندواروپایی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>145</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>165</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2188</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهشید</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرفخرایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشکده زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Comparative Linguistics has two distinct approaches towards the study of languages; Typology and Generic. The aim of the former is to detect the universals, while the latter attempts to compile the history of languages. &lt;br /&gt;Comparative linguist assumes one certain principle for all languages, which is the existence of similarities among them. These similarities are by no means accidental or borrowed. Thus it is assumed that these resemblances are indicators of a common source and the existing differences are the results of their development from a common original language. The comparative method enables us to reconstruct the principle features of the grammar and lexicon of the proto-language, which is a starting point to the historical description of the related languages. According to comparative linguistics, languages possess two dimensions; descriptive or linguistic and artistic-poetic. The linguistic dimension searches for a factor to transform a linguistic message to a work of art. &lt;br /&gt;The comparison of the significant models in Indo-European languages makes it possible to reconstruct the languages to reach that common origin, and to define the verse poetry and the poetical prose, as a consistent tradition for communication among Indo-Europeans. Based on this comparison, it can be concluded that in traditional Indo-European societies, poetic language was the area of expertise of those who had poetic motivation, but in addition to the compose of poetry, had other duties such as priesthood, foretelling and eulogizing. The surviving terminologies in the branches of this language family, both in vocabulary and in the poets&#039;&#039; functional frame, are identical in west and east. Therefore, through these similarities not only can the social status of the poet be seen, but also the poetical terminology of the Indo-European family branches can be identified. &lt;br /&gt;The following study attempts to reconstruct and describe the poetic language and its initial form according to the existing data, with an emphasis on the Indo-Iranian branch of the languages.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زبان­شناسی تطبیقی برای شناخت زبان‌ها دو روش مشخص دارد: روش رده­شناختی و روش تکوینی. هدف روش نخست تثبیت ویژگی‌های همگانی زبان‌ها و هدف روش تکوینی، تدوین تاریخ زبان‌هاست.    &lt;br /&gt;زبان­شناس تطبیقی برای هر زبانی یک اصل مسلم و یک فرض دارد. اصل مسلم نزد ایشان مشابهت­های بسیار زبان‌هاست که نمی­توان آنها را حمل بر اتفاق یا وام­گیری کرد. فرض آنان بر این است که این زبان‌ها از یک اصل مشترکی منشأ گرفته‌اند و اختلافات کنونی میان آنها نتیجۀ تحولی است که زبان‌های هر گروه، پس از جدایی از نیای اصلی، پذیرفته‌اند. بررسی زبان­ها از طریق روش تطبیقی، بازسازی ویژگی­های بنیادی دستور و واژگان زبان فرضی را ممکن می­سازد، که این خود آغازی برای توصیف تاریخی زبان­های وابسته است. بر اساس مطالعات زبان­شناسی تطبیقی، زبان دارای دو بعد است، یکی توصیفی، یعنی بعد زبانی و دیگری هنری و شعری. بعد زبانی به دنبال عاملی است که یک پیام زبانی را به یک اثر هنری تبدیل می­کند. &lt;br /&gt;مقایسۀ الگوهای شاخص در زبان­های هندواروپایی امکان باسازی زبان­ها را تا رسیدن به زبان مشترک اصلی، نیز شناخت ویژگی‌های شعر منظوم و نثر شاعرانه را فراهم می­سازد. بر اساس این مقایسه می­توان دریافت که در جوامع سنتی هندواروپایی، زبان شاعرانه در صلاحیت متخصصانی بوده است که انگیزۀ شاعری داشته، امّا جز سرودن شعر، وظایف دیگری از نوع موبدی، پیشگویی و مداحی را نیز عهده‌دار بوده­اند. اصطلاحات بازمانده در برخی از شاخه­های زبانی این خانواده، هم در بُعد واژه­ها و هم در چهارچوب وظایف و خویشکاری­های شاعران، در شرق و غرب یکسان است و از خلال این مشترکات می­توان هم از پایگاه اجتماعی شاعر آگاه شد و هم اصطلاحات مربوط به شعر را در شاخه­های زبانی خانوادۀ هندواروپایی باز شناخت. &lt;br /&gt;در گفتار پیش رو کوشش شده است با تأکید بر شاخۀ هندوایرانی زبان­ها، زبان شعری و شکل آغازین آن بر اساس داده­های موجود باسازی و توصیف شود. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان هندواروپایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌شناسی تطبیقی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌شناسی درزمانی و هم‌زمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شعر منظوم و نثر شاعرانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مفاهیم شعری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ریگ‌ودا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گاهان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2188_be484b9f5bd86c4c75b1b67ef884cae7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
