<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Towards the National Language Policy</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>به سوی چارچوب سیاست زبانی ملی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>16</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">118</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طاهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدی‌پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد‌یار زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه ولی‌عصر (عج) رفسنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Persian is the only official language of our country,Iran,along with several other languages and dialects, each with some speakers. Moreover both English as an international language and Arabic as a religious one have some positions in our linguistic programs. Planning for teaching each of them are among government&#039;s political programs and therefore is among the responsibilities of a government. As the language is a cultural element for the people of each community, the policies devised for that are very important as well. In our society, Persian language has been accepted as the national language and it is used in official and social usage and education. It goes without saying that using Persian language as national language does not mean that the other languages and dialects do not deserve to be paid attention. The language policy devised and used by the government about all languages in Iran needs to guarantee the status and usage of all other languages along with Persian. The present article aims to examine the most important official documents for the state of language policy. The results show that in most of the documents some linguistic programs can be referred but in a scattered manner. The present article suggests the compilation of a deliberate and integrated policy making for all the languages and dialects in Iran. Therefore such linguistic framework can precisely reflect the state of national language (Persian), other languages, English and Arabic</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زبان فارسی تنها زبان رسمی کشور ماست و در کنار آن چندین زبان و گویش دیگر نیز وجود دارد که هر یک دارای تعدادی گویشور در نقاط گوناگون کشور است. زبان انگلیسی به‌عنوان زبان جهانی و زبان عربی به‌عنوان زبان مذهبی نیز در برنامه‌های آموزش زبانی ما جایگاهی دارند. برنامه‌ریزی در خصوص کاربرد و آموزش هریک از این زبان‌ها درحوزة برنامه‌های سیاسی دولت قرار دارد و در‌واقع از وظایف هر دولتی است. بدیهی است کاربرد زبان فارسی، به‌عنوان زبان ملی، لزوم توجه به دیگر زبان‌های موجود در کشور را محدود نمی‌نماید و در برنامه‌ریزی سیاست زبانی لازم است شأن و کاربرد دیگر زبان‌ها نیز در کنار زبان فارسی تضمین شود. طی پژوهش‌های مقالة حاضر، بررسی برخی ازمهم‌ترین اسناد دولتی، همچون قانون اساسی، سند چشم‌انداز، اساسنامة سیاست فرهنگی و فرهنگستان زبان، نشان‌داده که در اکثر این اسناد به برنامه‌های زبانی چندان اشاره نشده و سندی مشخص و مخصوص سیاست زبانی، که حاوی قوانین جامع مربوط به کاربرد و آموزش کلیة زبان‌های موجود در ایران باشد، تدوین نشده است. لذا پیشنهاد این مقاله تدوین سیاستی منسجم و سنجیده در خصوص کاربرد و آموزش همة زبان‌ها و گویش‌هایی است که ایرانیان به نوعی با آنها سروکار دارند. در این مقاله، بخش‌های گوناگون چنین سندی پیشنهاد شده است، ضمن اینکه قانون اساسی و سند چشم‌انداز مرجع شاخص‌های لازم برای تدوین این سیاست در نظر گرفته می‌شوند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاست زبانی ملی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان ملی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چند زبانگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌های قومی و محلی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_118_c3ac9e57c24fdb5f760ef27ec7ad744c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
