<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>10</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Azofa with Cinema: The Use of Films for Teaching Persian Language and Iranian Culture to Non-Persian Speakers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آزوفا سینمایی: کاربرد فیلم سینمایی در آموزش زبان و فرهنگ ایران به غیرفارسی‌زبانان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>79</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>102</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1886</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>صفارمقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار زبان‌شناسی پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آتوسا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رستم‌بیک تفرشی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار زبان‌شناسی پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present article aims at studying the feasibility of using films as a source to provide teaching material for Azofa (teaching Persian language and Iranian culture to non-Persian speakers). The question which the present article seeks to answer is how, based on an Iranian film, a syllabus may be designed which includes the linguistic and cultural points required by the Azofa program (Zoreda, 2006; Garn, 2012). This library-based research (which uses the analytical-descriptive method) assesses the possibility of teaching vocabulary and the skills of listening, speaking, reading and writing, as well as of introducing Iranian culture, to non-Persian speakers, based on the film “Colour of Paradise”, directed by Majid Majidi (1997); thus, the role of culture and the importance of intercultural competence in language teaching (Meyer, 1991; Byram, 1997) constitutes the theoretical basis for the research. Studies show that films may be properly used as a rich resource for the efficient teaching of Persian language and Iranian culture to non-Persian speakers. To this end, appropriate films and teaching approaches should be chosen with respect to the structural features and content of the films and the learners’ needs. In addition, the limited number of proficient Iranian teachers abroad and the absence of evaluated and accessible collections of Iranian films should be carefully taken under consideration when designing a film-based syllabus.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف مقالۀ حاضر بررسی و امکان‌سنجی کاربرد فیلم سینمایی به ‌عنوان منبعی برای تهیه و تدوین مواد درسی در دوره‌های آزوفا (آموزش زبان و فرهنگ ایران به غیرفارسی‌زبانان) است. در مقاله به این پرسش پاسخ داده می‌شود که چگونه می‌توان بر مبنای یک فیلم سینمایی ایرانی طرحی درسی ارائه داد که نکات زبانی و فرهنگی مورد نظر در برنامه‌های آزوفا را داشته باشد (زرودا، 2006؛ گارن، 2012). این پژوهش که از نوع کتاب‌خانه‌ای است، با استفاده از روش توصیفی ‌ـ ‌تحلیلی، امکان آموزش واژگان، مهارت‌های شنیدن، گفتن، خواندن و نوشتن و نیز معرفی فرهنگ ایرانی به غیرفارسی‌زبانان را بر اساس فیلم سینمایی &lt;em&gt;رنگ خدا&lt;/em&gt; ساختۀ مجید مجیدی (1997)، ارزیابی می‌کند. در این راستا نقش فرهنگ و اهمیت توانش بینافرهنگی در آموزش زبان (مِیِر، 1991؛ بایرام، 1997) مبنای نظری پژوهش قرار گرفته است. بررسی نشان می‌دهد که فیلم سینمایی به‌درستی می‌تواند به ‌عنوان منبعی غنی برای آموزش کارآمد زبان فارسی و فرهنگ ایرانی به غیرفارسی‌زبانان به ‌کار گرفته شود. بدین منظور، انتخاب فیلم و رویکرد آموزشی مناسب باید با توجه به ویژگی‌های ساختاری و محتوای فیلم و نیازهای زبان‌آموزان صورت پذیرد. علاوه ‌بر این، ضرورت دارد که تعداد محدود مدرسان توانای ایرانی در خارج از کشور و نبود مجموعه‌ای ارزیابی‌شده و در دسترس از فیلم‌های سینمایی ایرانی در طراحی برنامۀ درسی فیلم‌محور به‌دقت مورد توجه قرار گیرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آموزش زبان فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">غیرفارسی‌زبان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فیلم سینمایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانش بینافرهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1886_04b9f7fe7d6e30aa15faa56f33257e4c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
