<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>11</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Process of Metaphor Comprehension Development in Persian-Speaking Children of 6 to 8 Years Old</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>فرایند رشد درک استعاره در کودکان 6-8 سالۀ فارسی‌زبان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>137</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>160</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2080</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شهلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رقیب‌دوست</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه زبانشناسی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش‌جوی دکتری زبانشناسی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present study, evaluated the developmental process of metaphor comprehension in Persian-speaking children of three age groups of 6, 7 and 8 years old. Some researchers believe that metaphor comprehension occurs at the beginning of adolescence. Another group believes that preschool children can understand metaphorical concepts. Cognitive linguists believe that metaphors are fundamental aspects of language and cognition, which are used innately and subconsciously, for perceiving emotions and other mental and abstract concepts. To examine the children’s metaphoric competence, a multiple-choice test of 36 metaphoric sentences, in four subtests, was designed. Based on the findings, children are able to comprehend different types of metaphors at early ages, and their interpretation of metaphors develops progressively with the increase of age and world knowledge development. </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر توانایی درک استعاره در کودکان فارسی‌زبان از سه گروه سنی 6، 7 و 8 سال را ارزیابی کرده‌ است. گروهی از پژوهشگران‌ معتقدند که درک استعاره در اوایل دورۀ نوجوانی صورت ‌می‌گیرد. برخی دیگر از پژوهشگران بر این عقیده‌اند که کودکان در سنین پیش از دبستان قادر به فهم مفاهیم استعاری اند. زبان‌شناسان شناختی نیز معتقدند استعاره از جنبه‌های اساسی زبان و شناخت است که به ‌صورت ذاتی و ناآگاهانه برای درک احساسات و دیگر مفاهیم ذهنی و انتزاعی به ‌کار می‌رود. به ‌منظور ارزیابی توانش استعاری کودکان، آزمونی دوگزینه‌ای شامل 36 جملۀ استعاری در قالب چهار زیرآزمون تدوین‌ و اجراگردید. بر پایۀ نتایج به ‌دست ‌آمده، کودکان در سنین پایین در درک انواع استعاره چندان توانا نیستند اما، به موازات رشد سنی، تعقلی و گسترش دانش جهان‌شناختی، تفاسیر و استنباط‌های‌ آنان از استعاره‌ها، در روندی تکوینی، متکامل‌تر و پرورده‌تر می‌گردد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">: نظریۀ شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شناخت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درک استعاره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رشد زبان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کودک فارسی‌‌زبان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2080_3ccccdea0367d28fec7754d000a1ef84.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
