<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>8</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Sogdian Ancient Letter No.1</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>یک ناﻣﺔ سغدی (نامة باستانی سغدی شمارة یک)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>37</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>49</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1173</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شیما</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری دهقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد / مرکز دائرة‌المعارف بزرگ اسلامی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>  &lt;br /&gt;Ancient Iranians used letter writing as one of the most important methods of communication. The earliest surviving evidence of official correspondence in Pre&lt;span style=&quot;letter-spacing: -0.1pt;&quot;&gt;-Islamic Iran is a collection of letters from the Achaemenid period. Undoubtedly, the existence of correspondence in Iran could be studied diachronically. &lt;/span&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;letter-spacing: -0.1pt;&quot;&gt;Among the remaining texts from Middle Iranian languages, the earliest surviving evidence for correspondence in the Sogdian language is a collection of texts written in the form of correspondence. The study of such letters is significant not only because of their linguistic value but also because they are the primary source of information to study the early history of the Sogdian people. The Sogdian language was spoken in Eastern Iran, from Black Sea to Western China, from approximately 100-1200 C.E. &lt;/span&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;letter-spacing: -0.1pt;&quot;&gt;In 1907, Sir Aurel Stein found these Ancient Letters in a watchtower near the Great Wall of China. These letters, now called “The Ancient Letters”, are the oldest Sogdian document on paper. Letter number one, is from a daughter to her mother in which she has talked about her life.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;letter-spacing: -0.1pt;&quot;&gt;The aim of the current paper was to interpret and translate the Ancient Letter number one. The researcher has also carried outan etymological survey on selected words and also has analyzed the style of the letter.&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">نامه‌نگاری از دیرباز از جمله ابزارهای ارتباط انسان‌ها بوده است و ایرانیان باستان نیز از آن آگاه بودند. از جمله کهن‌ترین شواهد موجود از نامه‌نگاری در ایران متعلق به دورۀ هخامنشیان است. از دورﮤ اشکانیان نیز آثاری در دست است، اما دورﮤ ساسانی را می‌توان اوج شکوفایی نامه‌نگاری در ایران پیش از اسلام دانست. در میان آثار به‌جای مانده از دورة میانه نیز، نوشته‌هایی به زبان سغدی به شیوة نامه نگارش شده که مطالعة آن‌ها نه فقط از لحاظ زبان‌شناسی اهمیت بسیار دارد بلکه بسیاری از زوایای تاریک تاریخ اقوام شرق ایران را نیز در این دوره مشخص می‌کند. اورل استاین، در سال 1907 م، مجموعه‌ای از چند نامة سغدی را در ویرانه‌های یکی از برج‌های دیده‌بانی دیوار چین پیدا کرد. این نامه‌ها، که بعدها «نامه‌های باستانی سغدی» نامیده شدند، امروزه کهن‌ترین متون سغدی نوشته بر کاغذ شمرده می‌شوند. نامة نخست را زنی به مادرش نوشته و در آن شرح حال خود را برای مادر بازگو کرده است. در مقالة حاضر، به خوانش و ترجمة این نامه، ریشه‌شناسی واژگان و تحلیل شیوة نامه‌نویسی در آن پرداخته شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آیین نامه‌نویسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان سغدی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نامه‌های باستانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌های ایرانی میانه شرقی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1173_0d57f5cc334e0b714e796f0cb545538e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
