<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>11</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>nam- and rēž-, Two Sogdian Impersonal Verbs</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>rēž- و nam- دو فعل غیرشخصی در زبان سغدی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>45</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>60</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1906</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمّدحسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>جلالیان چالشتری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیارگروه فرهنگ و زبانهای باستانی دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The Impersonal verb is a verb which is always inflected in the third singular and its logical subject does not appear in the nominative case. These verbs often express physical or mental/cognitive experiences which the logical subject experiences without having any control on them. Thus the subject in these structures is called &quot;experiencer&quot;. Another element which has a role in impersonal sentences is the source of the events, activities and experiences. It&#039;s presence in the sentence depends on the meaning of the verb. In Sogdian beside some of the modal verbs which are in accordance with the definition of impersonal verbs, there are two other verbs which are impersonal too. These are rēž- and nam-. As will be shown rēž- is appeared as an impersonal verb approximately in all the remaining evidences, but nam- has impersonal use just in one of it&#039;s evidences. In this article I will study and analyze these two verbs.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">فعل غیرشخصی فعلی است که به صورت سوّم شخص مفرد صرف می‌شود و فاعل منطقی آن حالت غیر فاعلی دارد. این گونه افعال غالباً در بر دارندة معانی تجارب فیزیکی، ذهنی و ادراکی هستند که بر فاعل منطقی حادث می‌شوند و خارج از کنترل و ارادة  او هستند. این فاعل منطقی که همیشه جاندار است تجربه‌گر نامیده می‌شود. عنصر دیگری که در جملات غیرشخصی ظاهر می‌شود منشأ بروز واقعه یا تجربه است و حضور آن در جمله بستگی به معنای فعل دارد. در زبان سغدی در کنار برخی از افعال وجهیِ این زبان که با تعریف افعال غیرشخصی سازگارند دو فعل دیگر نیز صرف غیرشخصی دارند. این دو فعل rēž- و nam-  هستند. rēž- ظاهراً در تمامی نمونه‌های موجود و nam- تنها یک بار به صورت غیرشخصی صرف شده‌ است. بررسی و تحلیل این دو فعل موضوع این نوشتار است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فعل غیرشخصی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تجربه‌گر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سبب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پسند آمدن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پذیرفتن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آرزو کردن</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1906_3e1ff344a691655ea1f24f2c309f5946.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
