<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>11</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Cognitive Mechanisms and Their Role in Do’a Conceptualization</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سازوکارهای شناختی و نقش آنها در مفهوم سازیِ دعا</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>25</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>44</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1905</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شیرین</FirstName>
					<LastName>پورابراهیم</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه زبانشناسی، دانشکده ادبیات و زبانهای خارجی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Abstract &lt;br /&gt;Cognitive strategies, first introduced in Cognitive Semantics, are cognitive devices like conceptual metonymies, conceptual metaphors, image metaphors and schemas which structure abstract concepts in our minds and facilitate our understanding. This paper aims to study examples of these strategies in the language of Sahife Sajjadie. For this purpose, I have analyzed cases of structural, orientational, and ontological metaphors, as well as conceptual metonymies, image metaphors and image schemas in this religious text to find out two things. What is the role of these strategies in conceptualization and understanding of abstract concepts, and to find whether the analyzed language is a literary language or not. Analysis of the selected metaphorical data shows that religious abstract concepts are represented both literally and non-literally. Non-literal representations of concepts are structured by using cognitive strategies of metaphor, metonymy, image schemas and metaphors. In addition, language of Do’a in this book has used the same metaphors as ordinary conventional language, though it has used extending, elaboration, combining of metaphors, as well as personification and metaphorical images which assimilate it to a literary work.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">درمعنی‌شناسی شناختی، منظور از سازوکا‌رهای شناختی ابزارهای شناختی مثل مجازهای مفهومی، استعاره‌های مفهومی و تصویری، و طرحواره‌های تصویری هستند که در سازماندهی ودرک مفاهیم انتزاعی در ذهن انسان نقش دارند. هدف مقاله حاضر، بررسی نمونه‌هایی از این سازوکارهای شناختی است که در دعای امام سجاد علیه السلام در صحیفة سجادیه به کار‌رفته‌است. سؤالی که مقاله حاضر این است که این سازوکارهای شناختی در مفهوم‌سازی مضامین و درک مفاهیم انتزاعی دعا چه نقشی دارند. از سوی دیگر، کدام شاخص‌های شناختی، زبان دعا را از زبان عادی متمایز می‌کند؟ نتایج تحلیل نشان می‌دهد مضامین دینی موجود در این ادعیه، علاوه بر مفاهیم حقیقی، از مفاهیم انتزاعی ساخته شده‌اند که به کمک سازوکارهای شناختی استعاره، مجاز، تصویرسازی و طرحواره‌های تصویری ساختارمند می‌شوند و درک آنها تسهیل می‌شود. همچنین، زبان دعا، از نظر نوع سازوکارهای شناختی به زبان عادی نزدیک است اما از جهاتی شاهد جنبه‌های ادبی در این مفهوم‌سازی‌ها می‌باشیم. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازوکارهای شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استعارة مفهومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مجاز مفهومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استعارة تصویری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طرحوارة تصویری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان دعا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان ادبی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1905_93e5143cfb26c10f9af1b4fdd040aeb5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
