<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>15</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Comparison between the Discourse Frame of Advertisements on Internet and Persian Magazines</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مقایسه قالب گفتمانی تبلیغات در اینترنت و مجلات فارسی زبان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>39</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>56</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2843</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جلیل‌الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>فاروقی هندوالان</LastName>
<Affiliation>زبانشناسی / دانشگاه بیرجند</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>علیزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>زبانشناسی / دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نیلوفر</FirstName>
					<LastName>هاشم زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>بانشناسی / دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of the present research is a comparative analysis between the discourse frame of advertisements in Internet and Persian magazines in terms of verbal and non-verbal features.  In verbal part, more prominent syntactic and lexical features and in non-verbal part, the analysis of color, covert taxonomy technique, salience in images, paralanguage and pictorial parallelism were examined. After data analysis, it was found that the discourse frame of advertisements in the two media have differences as well as similarities. In terms of verbal features, the differences include little use of interrogatives and more use of alien and unfamiliar words in magazines’ advertisements compared to Internet advertisements. The use of imperatives, disjunctive syntax and positive adjectives were among the observed similarities in verbal section between the two kinds of media. Regarding the non-verbal features, it was observed that Internet and magazines’ advertisements are different in terms of the application of warm and cool colors and pictorial parallelism. However, both groups of the advertisements are similar in using the covert taxonomy technique, paralanguage in writing, salience in images and the technique of making eye contact with the audience to attract their attention. &lt;br /&gt; </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی و مقایسه قالب گفتمانی تبلیغات در اینترنت و مجلات    فارسی­زبان از حیث ویژگی­های کلامی و غیر کلامی می­باشد. در بخش کلامی به بررسی ویژگی­های نحوی و واژگانی مهم­تر و برجسته­تر و در بخش غیر کلامی تحلیل رنگ، تکنیک طبقه­بندی پنهان، برجسته­سازی، فرازبان، جذب مخاطب از طریق برقراری تماس چشمی و موازات تصویری در تصاویر تبلیغات صورت پذیرفت. پس از تحلیل داده­ها مشخص گردید که قالب گفتمانی تبلیغات در دو رسانه مورد نظر دارای تفاوت­ها و شباهت­هایی با یکدیگر می­باشند. از حیث ویژگی­های کلامی این تفاوت­ها شامل کاربرد اندک ساخت پرسشی و     به­کارگیری بیشتر لغات بیگانه و نامأنوس در تبلیغات مجلات نسبت به اینترنت بود. کاربرد ساخت امری، نحو گسسته، استفاده از سبک رسمی و نوشتاری و نیز به­کارگیری صفات مطلق در هر دو گروه تبلیغات مورد نظر جزو شباهت­های مشاهده­شده در قسمت ویژگی­های کلامی بودند. بر اساس ویژگی­های غیر کلامی، مشاهده گردید که تبلیغات اینترنتی و مجلات از لحاظ کاربرد رنگ­های گرم و سرد، و بهره­گیری از موازات تصویری با هم متفاوت هستند؛ اما هر دو گروه تبلیغات مورد نظر در به­کارگیری تکنیک طبقه­بندی پنهان، فرازبان در نوشتار، برجسته­سازی در تصاویر و برقراری تماس چشمی با مخاطب به طور مشابه عمل می­کنند.&lt;br /&gt;  </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گفتمان تبلیغات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اینترنت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مجلات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ویژگی‌های کلامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ویژگی‌های غیر کلامی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2843_f960f0e0105c7507f26b860f53bf7263.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
