<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Compound Sentences in Persian
(An RRG-Based Analysis)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Pahlavan Nezhad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Rassulpur</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hossein</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A. in Linguistics, Lecturer of Payame Noor University of Azar shahr</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This paper undertakes to describe “Compound Sentences” in Modern Persian (Farsi) based on Functional Syntactic theory of “Role and Reference Grammar”. First, it describes the foundation of RRG theory which is presented in 1997 by Robert D. Van Valin Jr. and Randy J. Lapolla and extended later by Van Valin in his book “Exploring the Syntax-Semantics Interface” (2005).The RRG posits three nexus relations between clauses in “Compound Sentences” (Coordination, Co subordination, Subordination) rather than the two of “Traditional”, “Structural” and “Generative” Grammar. There are three primary levels of juncture, clausal, core and nuclear and there are three possible nexus relations among the units in the juncture .All three types of nexus are possible in all three forms of juncture and this yields nine juncture-nexus types in Universal Grammar. We described two relations (Coordination, Subordination) in Compound Sentences. There are two types in Coordination and nine types in Subordination. This paper concludes that the advantage of the RRG is simultaneous exploring of three levels of “Syntactic”, “Semantics” and “Pragmatics” description.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>5</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>25</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_568_3cfc7c02bcaecdbbb226ded3513e9f7d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Comparison between the Effect of Stressor and Mental Arithmetic and Linguistic Phonemes- Phonetics Contradiction on Biomarkers Systolic Blood Pressure, Diastolic Blood Pressure Heart Rate in High School Student Girls</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fariba</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jannesari Ladani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Payame Nour University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aghayusefi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor Psychology Payame Nour University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Alipour</namePart>
				<affiliation> Professor Psychology Payame Nour University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zare</namePart>
				<affiliation> Associate Professor Psychology Payame Nour University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Background and purpose: linguistic phonemes-phonetics contradiction is one of the major factors underlying the effects of stress on students is considered ... The purpose of this research is to study the linguistic phonemes-phonetics contradiction and the mental arithmetic caused by stress effect creations on activity of autonomic nervous system (systolic blood pressure, diastolic blood pressure, heart rate) in the high school students. Methods: 30 female students from each education level of high school in one of the high schools at disrtict5 of Tehran education system were selected randomly. After ensuring of their physical and mental health they were divided to 2 equal groups In first group, linguistic phonemes-phonetics contradiction (reading of Finglish text) and in second group the mental arithmetic (PASAT test) were performed. Systolic blood pressure, diastolic blood pressure, heart rate, was measured at 3 steps. At 8-9 o’clock in the morning. Result: The two types of stress creation in mental arithmetic and linguistic phonemes-phonetics contradiction have no significant differences (p&gt;0.05) in the change of composition of the dependent variable (systolic blood pressure ,diastolic blood pressure ,heart rate in 3 steps). Indicators in two experimental groups have significant increase (p&lt;0.05) after both intervention. Conclusion: linguistic phonemes-phonetics contradiction and mental arithmetic as sources of stress creation increase systolic blood pressure .diastolic blood pressure, heart rate, in female students and this increase was same in both of experimental groups.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>5</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>27</start>
					<end>45</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_569_393294219dcec4b12ee83cb84a8b1cf6.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Sogdian ršt’wc’r</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">zohreh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">zarshenas</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor Linguistics IHCS</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Moshkriz</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D Ancient Literature and Culture</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The aim of this paper is to examine the unknown etymology of “ršt’wc’r” a Sogdian word, which literally means consolation, condolence, sympathy, based on a close comparing and studying of some Middle Iranian words in both Eastern Middle Iranian languages (e.g. Khotan-Saka and Bacterian) and Western Middle Iranian languages (e.g. Middle Persian and Parthian).</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>5</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>47</start>
					<end>52</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_582_3433647db054693095b7c4afcd6fe06f.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Study of Language Family and Effect of Disorder Articulation in Cleft Palate Persons after Surgery</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alieh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kord Zaferanloo Kamboozia</namePart>
				<affiliation> Associate Professor Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdieh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Seyyedzade Aghdam</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A Linguistics</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ferdows</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aghagolzade</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor Linguistics Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Normal speech may defect from resonance to disorders. These results from inappropriate coupling of the oral and nasal cavities which frequently occur in cleft palate and operative techniques are used to repair it. Measurement of nasalance score by modern and or exact instrument devices is an important part of the evaluation of patient with resonance disorders due to cleft palate and or velopharyngeal in sufficiency. In this study snap test and phonetic tests after palatoplasty for Persian speaking persons. Paletoplasty was done for 30 people (15 boys and 15 girls) with cleft palate between the age of 5 and 15 years old and had not any problems in hearing and hadn’t cold or any other illness which can affect voice and resonance. Snap test and phonetic test was done for them after surgery. Each of subjects produced prolonged 6 vowels (for three second) 23 consonants in syllable and 69 words (23 in first place.23 in middle place.23 in last place) and electronic system (nasometer) calculated nasalance scores of snap test for vowels and consonants and 69 words productions judging by 5 normal listener and recognizing normal articulation and disarticulation. All of the Persian vowels and consonant in cleft palate persons after palatoplasty are hyper nasal. The most mean nasalance score of vowels is for /i/ and the least mean nasalance score is for /o/ sound. The most mean nasalance score of oral consonant is for /L/ the least mean nasalance score is for /q/ sound. The most of disarticulation includes compensatory the least disarticulation includes substitution in production. The most of compensatory production includes secondary articulation. The most of secondary articulation includes glottalized. The most of obligatory production includes nasalized and omission. The findings are similar to other research’s findings. This study prepared statistical data about nasalance score of Persian sounds in cleft palate person after surgery which can be a good start for repairing surgery in order to improve speech cleft palate. Findings of this study indicates the necessity of completing them with the other studies.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>5</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>53</start>
					<end>70</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_583_6aaa2f147afe659682632090707575aa.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Analysis of Covert Linguistic Structure Expressed in Selected Persian Proverbs and Expressions</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Nahid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Moayyed Hekmat</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor Sociology IHCS</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Since language is one of the main non material cultural elements, therefore, a study of linguistic structure carried in selected Persian Proverbs and expressions can be useful for understanding a part of oral cultural elements. The present article explores the rhetorical forms, types of addresses and manners of expression of selected Persian proverbs and expressions. The research method is quantitative content analysis. This is an exploratory kind of research, whose aim is emphasis on linguistic dimension of some selected proverbs taken from some written anthologies by others. The findings show that the dominant pattern of rhetorical form is expression, the address form is indirect and the type addressing is emotional. Affectiveness is found that is the common element of all three linguistic, attitudinal an evaluative dimension of selected Persian proverbs and expressions. All that means the comprehension of linguistic structure is produced and understood through discourse analysis.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>5</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>71</start>
					<end>84</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_584_4fd2dc8f3b8e7ea6e586805d667089eb.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Case and Case Marking in Vafsi</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahinnaz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mirdehghan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor Linguistics Shahid Beheshti University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Saeedreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Yusefi</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A. Linguistics Shahid Beheshti University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Fourteen grammatical cases can be detected in Vafsi. These cases are marked by means of different types of strategies. These strategies are: 1. using morphemes in the form of suffixes, 2. using ppositions, 3. using clitics, 4. using word order, and 5. using suprasegmental features. Ergative, accusative, object of adposition, dative and genitive cases in Vafsi are marked using the portmanteau morphemes mentioned in the Table No.3. Ablative, comitative/ associative, dative, locative, allative and instrumental cases are marked using word order and the sentence structure. Only the vocative case is marked using the suprasegmental feature of the rising tone. Summary of Vafsi cases are classified in Table No. 4.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>5</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>85</start>
					<end>105</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_585_08c812b68fe4828d24f524dfa99b206e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Common Proper Names in Sogdian Inscriptions of Pakistan’s Upper Indus and Western Middle Iranian Inscriptions (Sasanid, Parthian)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Vida</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nadaf</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor Islamic Azad University of Hamedan</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The Sogdian inscriptions of the upper Indus are a corpus of more than 700 graffiti including 2 in Parthian, 2 in Middle Persian, 2 in Bactrian and the others in the Soghdian language and Some engravings carved on the boulders which litter the banks of this river; for the most part they consist of the personal names of visiting Sogdian merchants. These inscriptions belong to about the 3rd-6th centuries AD. The occurrence of Middle Persian names such as Shapur, Kartir, and Babak amongst the Sogdian names also suggests a time within the Sassanian period (i.e. 3rd-mid 7th century). In this Paper, I considered the common proper names between Sogdian and the west Middle Iranian Inscriptions, and then the similarities and differences are studied at the end.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>5</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>107</start>
					<end>124</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_586_89522bac87792f488eed2be4a8d9a3a6.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>