<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Functions of Paratactic Structures in Qabus-nameh and its Effect on Technical Prose in Creating of Prolixity</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">seyed mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">arta</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه رازی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">modaresi</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد گروه زبان و ادبیات فارسی دانشگاه ارومیه</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abdolreaz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Naderifar</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD in Persian Language and Literature Razi University of Kermanshah</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In the 12th paragraph of the 33rd Zand of Yasna, the name of the god “Bahman” has been followed by the adjective griftAr and another word whose spelling and meaning are not so clear. griftAr has been rendered “acceptor” and “recipient”. In this article, with respect to the meanings of griftan and griftAr, it is suggested that griftAr is a passive participle and its meaning is “perceivable”. The connection between this adjective and Bahman will be demonstrated by surveying sentences and phrases from Middle Persian texts. At the end, it will be proved that this word and that one which follows it, should be read griftArOmand and this latter one be rendered as “perceivable”.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>15</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>22</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2842_91fc88f16618211e1fff0445094e173e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Comparison between the Discourse Frame of Advertisements on Internet and Persian Magazines</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Jalilallah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Faroughi</namePart>
				<affiliation>زبانشناسی / دانشگاه بیرجند</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Alizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>زبانشناسی / دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Niloofar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hashemzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>بانشناسی / دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The aim of the present research is a comparative analysis between the discourse frame of advertisements in Internet and Persian magazines in terms of verbal and non-verbal features.  In verbal part, more prominent syntactic and lexical features and in non-verbal part, the analysis of color, covert taxonomy technique, salience in images, paralanguage and pictorial parallelism were examined. After data analysis, it was found that the discourse frame of advertisements in the two media have differences as well as similarities. In terms of verbal features, the differences include little use of interrogatives and more use of alien and unfamiliar words in magazines’ advertisements compared to Internet advertisements. The use of imperatives, disjunctive syntax and positive adjectives were among the observed similarities in verbal section between the two kinds of media. Regarding the non-verbal features, it was observed that Internet and magazines’ advertisements are different in terms of the application of warm and cool colors and pictorial parallelism. However, both groups of the advertisements are similar in using the covert taxonomy technique, paralanguage in writing, salience in images and the technique of making eye contact with the audience to attract their attention.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>15</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>39</start>
					<end>56</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2843_f960f0e0105c7507f26b860f53bf7263.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Linguistics of Speech Poem</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">farzad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">karimi</namePart>
				<affiliation>ندارم</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The increasing passion of poets and audiences of today Iranian poems to what is called ’’Speech poem’’ reveals the importance of study the language characteristics of this poetic style especially with the mass interacting in the critics and reading contacts of this style in the literary communications. This mass interaction makes some problems in finding the differences between Speech poem and those who use speech language in their work in any way. In this essay we will try to analysis the prominent language characteristics, the way of using speech language by the Speech poets and the language differences of this poetic style with other styles and how speech act can be substituted with speech and the effect of this substitution in the narrativity of Speech poem and also the ways of using the language coeds, and the ways of using of some language elements like modal elements and deixis.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>15</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>57</start>
					<end>81</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2844_288567ff9d7f75274f90cd8315a26c08.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Perceptual Learning Style Preferences: A Study on Adult Learners of Persian as a Foreign Language</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amirreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Vakilifard</namePart>
				<affiliation>IKIU</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Depending on language background, culture, age range and gender, language learners adopt different learning styles. Although learning styles is one of the well-studied topics in the field of foreign language learning, to our knowledge, no study has explored this topic in the context of learners of Persian as a foreign language. This study aimed to investigate the perceptual learning style preferences of 97 learners of Persian who had acquired Persian in 40 different countries. In this cross-sectional survey study, Reid’s (1997) Perceptual Learning Style Preferences Questionnaire was used for data collection. A variety of statistical tests were used to answer the research questions which related to the learning style profiles of learners of Persian as a foreign language and the learning style differences in terms of level of education, geographic location, gender and age. Results of independent samples t-test and Mann-Whitney test did not show a statistically significant difference between the average scores and learning style preferences of men and women. Kruksal-Wallis test did not indicate a significant difference between the scores and learning style preferences of different age ranges. As for geographicregion, there was a statistically significant difference between Asians and Europeans only in terms of group and haptic style scores. Theaverage scores and individual style preferences differed significantly among subjects who were at different levels of education (bachelor’s, master’s and PhD).</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>15</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>83</start>
					<end>105</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2845_db6f702c6ec0c7fb39aa31830886ba7a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Rashnu and his role in Zoroastrian religion</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">zohre</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">zarshenas</namePart>
				<affiliation>d</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rashno</namePart>
				<affiliation>پژوهشگر مرکز دایره المعارف بزرگ اسلامی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In this study, the linguistic derivation and functional role of Rashn deity in Zoroastrian religion is investigated. Rashn or Rashnu is a Zoroastrian deity which has a prominent role in Zoroastrian religion as god of justice and divine Judge. According to Middle Persian texts, Rashnu has judicial duties as a member of the spiritual court which judges the soul of the dead. In this paper, Rashnu etymological derivation is studied first and then his various functions in ancient (e.g. Old Avestan and New Avestan), and Middle Persian texts is mentioned. Finally, his similar functions in Vedic and Elamite tradition are also discussed.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>15</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>107</start>
					<end>124</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2888_6eedfc6289c2056729fd4d8d1af69c7d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Story of the Jesus’ Betrayal by Judas According to the Manichaeans</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jalalian Chaleshtari,</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ancient Iranian Culture and Languages
Fauculty of Persian Literature and Foreign Languages
University of Tabriz</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>One of the Manichaean Parthian texts consists of the passion of Christ and his crucifixion by the conspiracy of the Jews. One part of this text is about the Judas’ betrayal of Jesus and is unfortunately lost from all the existing manuscripts. Some of the previous editions of this text does not match to what the manuscripts contain in this particular point. The others which have reflected the correct reading of the manuscripts have interpreted the text in such a manner that does not have any coordination with what we know from the Christian and other Manichaean narrations of this story. In this paper, by using the linguistic potentialities of the text and considering sound changes and word formation in Iranian languages, the author will try to offer a reading which is more consistent with the above-mentioned narrations</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Language Studies</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>IHCS</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2099-8002</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>15</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>23</start>
					<end>37</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2913_800e88c816c2d61be29876ed63296a54.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>