<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>18</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>30</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Review of ac (M2 II)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بازنگری قطعۀ ac (M2 II)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>49</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>73</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">4442</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرزایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه فرهنگ و زبانهای باستانی، دانشکدۀ ادبیات فارسی و زبانهای خارجی، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In M2 II, a fragment of Manichaean Turfan texts, equivalent to the text “ac” according to the subject-matter partition created by Boyce, there are two powers named by Mani as “the Power of Light”, and “the Power of Darkness”. By giving some notes, Andreas and Henning interpreted the Power of Light as an active Power who will gain the eternal salvation, and a passive one that have to stay bogged down in Darkness forever. Though the scholar translations of the text are based on Andreas and Henning’s, they are either quiet about the Powers or some indefinite allusions are just mentioned by them. With making unnecessary changes to the scribe’s paragraphs on the one hand, and paying not much attention to the Parthian syntax rules on the other, the scholars who translated this text did suggest different translations which seem in some cases to be obscure. In this essay these items will be discussed: The idea of the active and passive Powers of Light is in the air; the scholars did not pay attention to the distinct topical divisions appeared in the scribe’s writing system; the scholar’s negative attitude to some syntactical structures is rather responsible for those obscurity.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در دست‌نویس M2 II از مجموعۀ متون تورفانی، برابر با قطعۀ ac در تقسیم‌بندی موضوعی مری بویس، به دو نیرو اشاره شده است: نیروی روشنی و نیروی تاریکی. آندرئاس و هنینگ در ترجمه و تفسیر این قطعه، نیروی روشنی را به دو بخش فعاله، که نجات خواهد یافت، و منفعله که تا ابد در ظلمت گرفتار خواهد ماند، تقسیم کرده‌اند. با آنکه محققان بعدی در ترجمۀ این قطعه متأثر از ایشان بوده‌اند، در خصوص نیروی روشنی فعال و منفعل یا سکوت کرده و یا به گونه‌ای مبهم بدان اشاره کرده‌اند. ترجمه‌های پیشنهادی محققان در موارد متعددی به دلیل عدم رعایت نحو کلام، و نیز اعمال تغییراتی در تقسیم‌بندی موضوعی پاراگراف‌های کاتب، مبهم است. در این مقاله نشان خواهیم داد که: مبحثی تحت عنوان نیروی روشنی فعاله و منفعله در کیش مانی وجود ندارد؛ محققان در تصحیح انتقادی متن توجهی به تقسیم‌بندی موضوعی کاتب نداشته‌‌اند؛ ساختار نحوی کلام ساده و روان است و علت ابهام نحوی و معنایی متن را باید در نوع برداشت محققان جست.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پهلوی اشکانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نیروی روشنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فعاله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منفعله</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4442_cc54c42d10f2959913f4c5edec903ab7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
