<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>6</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Structure of Iranian Newspaper’s Editorials
(According to 2001 Michael Hoey’s Solving-Problem Model)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ساختار متن سرمقاله‌‌های روزنامه‌‌های ایرانی (بر اساس الگوی حل مسئلة مایکل هوی 2001)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>15</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>30</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">667</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ژیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>خانجانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش‌آموختة دکترای زبان‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فردوس</FirstName>
					<LastName>آقاگل‌‌زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه زبان‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Text linguistics attends to texts and their properties. Various approaches have been put forth to explore the organization of texts and the way they are produced and comprehended. One of which is Michael Hoey’s problem-solution approach (2001). This model consists of four components including situation, problem, recycling, response and evaluation. In this approach, texts are rewritten in the form of conversations, questions and answers. We attempt to answer these questions: in what extend we can generalize this pattern to newspaper articles and by using the problem solution pattern, how we can achieve a degree of anticipation, predictiveness and quicker comprehension of narrative texts as hypotheses. To fulfill the objectives, benefiting from the problem-solution pattern (2001), 20 articles from four newspapers including E’temade and Aftabe yazd, were analyzed based on this pattern. In conclusion, the analysis revealed how newspaper articles of these groups using PS pattern. Therefore, the first hypothesis was confirmed and the relationship between components of problem-solution pattern was shortly displayed by diagrams in each article. Texts were analyzed on the bases of socio-cultural and discursive structures and also rewritten in conversations. Furthermore from data analysis via a t- test calculation, it became clear that the comprehension, anticipation, predictiveness of reader enhanced on the basis of this pattern. Consequently the second hypothesis of the current study has been confirmed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زبان‌‌شناسی متن شاخه‌‌ای از تحلیل گفتمان است که به بررسی زبان در سطح جمله و فراتر از جمله می‌‌پردازد. رویکردهای مختلفی برای تشخیص ساختار درونی متون و چگونگی تولید و درک آن‌ها ارائه شده که یکی از آن‌ها رویکرد حل ‌مسئله مایکل هوی است. این رویکرد دارای چهار رکن است: موقعیت، مسئله، پاسخ‌، و ارزیابی. در تحقیق حاضر، سعی بر آن است تا، با استفاده از زبان‌‌شناسی متن، این رویکرد توضیح و به این پرسش‌‌ها پاسخ داده شود که ساختار متن سرمقالة روزنامه‌‌های ایرانی تا چه میزان بر اساس الگوی مایکل هوی ‌تعمیم‌پذیر است و چگونه می‌‌توان میزان انتظار وقایع آن را توسط خوانندگان با استفاده از این الگو مشخص کرد. بر این اساس، در تحقیق حاضر، تعداد 20 متن سرمقاله‌‌ (سخن سردبیر)های روزنامه‌‌های ایرانی از دو روزنامة سراسری کشور، &lt;em&gt;اعتماد&lt;/em&gt; و &lt;em&gt;آفتاب یزد&lt;/em&gt;، انتخاب و بررسی شده است. تحلیل داده‌‌ها بر اساس این رویکرد حاکی از این امر است که ساختار تولید متن روزنامه‌‌های بررسی‌شده تا حد زیادی با چهار رکن الگوی حل ‌مسئلۀ مایکل هوی یعنی موقعیت، مسئله، پاسخ و ارزیابی منطبق است و با استفاده از این الگو میزان انتظار و ضریب پیش‌‌بینی و درنتیجه درک سریع‌‌تر متن روایی عرضه‌شده به خواننده مشخص می‌‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌‌شناسی متن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل گفتمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی حل ‌مسئله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساختار متن</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_667_d6da8a021ec3988f58f77fcbc35a3bca.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
