<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>14</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Anger metaphors in the language of absolute congenital blind in comparison with their sighted counterpart based on Forceville Model</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>استعاره‌های خشم در زبان نابینایان مطلق مادرزاد در مقایسه با همتایان بینا بر مبنای انگارۀ فورسیول (2005)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>65</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>78</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2510</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهناز</FirstName>
					<LastName>طالبی دستنایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه الزهراء</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آزیتا</FirstName>
					<LastName>افراشی</LastName>
<Affiliation>زبانشناسی/  پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فریده</FirstName>
					<LastName>حق‌بین</LastName>
<Affiliation>زبانشناسی / دانشگاه الزهراء</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The conceptual metaphor program firstly launched by Lakoff and Johnson (1980) in Metaphors We Live By book. The theory attempt to describe conceptual metaphors as mental chart that idealize in the language metaphorically. Most of the studies of conceptual metaphors are limited to speech and writing. However studying of conceptual metaphors especially emotional metaphors in pictures can expand the conceptual metaphor model. Forceville (1996, 1999, and 2002) for the first time studied metaphor mapping in images and movies. The current paper analyzes anger metaphors in 10 congenital blinds’ language metaphors in comparison with their sighted peers based of Forceville model. According to the result, there are some differences and similarities in understanding of anger and anger metaphors in the language of two groups. one can see the effect of language on shaping the mental images of the absolute congenital blind that do not have any visual notion of their environment. &lt;br /&gt; </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">نظریۀ استعارۀ مفهومی اولین بار توسط لیکاف و جانسون,1980) Lakoff &amp;Johnson)، در کتابی با نام &lt;em&gt;استعاره‌هایی که ما با آنها زندگی‌می‌کنیم&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Metaphors We Live B&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;) &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;مطرح شد. بر اساس این نظریه، استعارۀ مفهومی، امری تصوری و ذهنی است که در زبان به صورت استعاری تجلی می‌یابد. بیشتر مطالعه‌ها در مورد  استعاره‌های مفهومی منحصر به گفتار و نوشتار است، در صورتی‌که بررسی استعاره‌های مفهومی مخصوصاً استعاره‌های عواطف در تصاویر می‌تواند به گسترش الگوی استعاره‌های مفهومی کمک کند. فورسیول (Forceville 1996, 1999, 2002,2005 ( برای اولین بار به مطالعۀ وجود نگاشت‌های استعارۀ خشم در تصاویر و فیلم‌ها پرداخت. مقالۀ حاضر  استعاره‌های خشم در گفتار و نوشتار 10 نابینای مطلق مادرزاد و 10 همتای بینا را بر اساس انگارۀ فورسیول (2005) بررسی می‌کند. شباهت‌ها و تفاوت‌هایی در درک دو گروه از خشم و استعاره‌های خشم طبق این الگو مشهود است. می‌توان تأثیر زبان را در شکل‌گیری تصاویر ذهنی یک نابینای مطلق مادرزاد که هیچ تصور دیداری از محیط پیرامون ندارد را مشاهده کرد. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استعارۀ مفهومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استعارۀ عواطف</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استعارۀ خشم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انگاره فورسیول</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گفتارگرایی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2510_75c1bf2cabc9fa3195e1cb815f875c1e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
