<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>15</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Rashnu and his role in Zoroastrian religion</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ایزد رشن و جایگاه او در دین زرتشتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>107</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>124</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2888</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>زرشناس</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیئت تحریریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>رشنو</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگر مرکز دایره المعارف بزرگ اسلامی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In this study, the linguistic derivation and functional role of Rashn deity in Zoroastrian religion is investigated. Rashn or Rashnu is a Zoroastrian deity which has a prominent role in Zoroastrian religion as god of justice and divine Judge. According to Middle Persian texts, Rashnu has judicial duties as a member of the spiritual court which judges the soul of the dead. In this paper, Rashnu etymological derivation is studied first and then his various functions in ancient (e.g. Old Avestan and New Avestan), and Middle Persian texts is mentioned. Finally, his similar functions in Vedic and Elamite tradition are also discussed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در پژوهش حاضر به بررسی زبانشناختی و کارکردی ایزد رشن در دین زرتشتی پرداخته شده است. رشن یا رشنو یکی از ایزدان زرتشتی است که در متون فارسی میانه نقش برجسته‌ای به عنوان یکی از سه ایزد داوری روان بر عهده دارد. رشنو در نوشته‌های پارسی میانه به صورت «رشن» با صفت «راست» آمده است. در این مقاله ابتدا اشتقاق ریشه‌شناختی رشنو مورد بررسی قرار گرفته و در ادامه به کارکردهای گوناگون این ایزد و سایر ایزدان همکار او در اوستا و متون فارسی میانه اشاره شده است. برای ارائه تصویری جامع‌تر از این ایزد به کارکردهای مشابه با رشن در سنت ودایی و عیلامی/ایلامی نیز توجه شده و در پایان به نمونه‌هایی از کاربرد نام این ایزد در ادبیات فارسی اشاره شده است.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رشنو</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رشن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رشن یشت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">داوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عدالت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرجام‌شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2888_6eedfc6289c2056729fd4d8d1af69c7d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
