<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Continence according to Buddha teaching in a Khotanese language text</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>خویشتن‌داری بنابر آموزه بودا در متنی به زبان ختنی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>41</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>61</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">4392</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سارا</FirstName>
					<LastName>روحانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری، رشته فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران، ایران،</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهشید</FirstName>
					<LastName>میر فخرایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشکده زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>30</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The book of “Zambasta” is a long poem in ancient a khotanese language, a branch of middle Eastern Iranian language. This book , containing wide set of common concepts and various aspects of Buddhism. Chapter 12 of this book is educational and includes a set of goodness and badness. The stanza which translated from Khotanese language into Persian in this article, includes the first 52 paragraph of this chapter that allocated to the description of Saṃvara(=continence, moral continence or stopping the effects of karmas or human beings previous actions). Saṃvara which considered as one of the most important steps to reach knowledge of continence and is like a guard trying continually to take man away from everything that is wrong and disagreeable, and to help him in order to reach Nirvānā(=salvation). Under the etymology of the word of Saṃvara, philosophical view about Saṃvara, steps of achievement, commitment ceremonies and conditions that lead to the loss of Saṃvara, are investigated.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کتاب زَمبَستَه منظومه­ای طولانی به زبان ختنی قدیم از شاخه زبان­های ایرانی میانه شرقی است. این کتاب، مجموعه­ای وسیع از مفاهیم رایج آئین بودایی و جنبه­های گوناگون دین بودا است. فصل دوازدهم این کتاب فصلی آموزه­ایو شامل مجموعه­ای از شایست­ها و نشایست­هاست. قطعه­ای که در این گفتار برگردان آن از زبان ختنی به فارسی آمده، شامل 52 بند نخستین همین فصل است که به شرح و توصیف سَموَرَ(saṃvara= خودداری،خویشتن­داری اخلاقی یا  متوقف ساختن تأثیرات کَرمَه­ها یا اعمال پیشین انسان) اختصاص دارد. سَموَرَ یکی از مهم­ترین مراحل رسیدن به فضیلت پرهیزگاری به شمار می­آید و همانند نگهبانی است که پیوسته می­کوشد تا انسان را از هر آنچه که ناشایست و ناپسند است، دور دارد و او را در جهت رسیدن به نیروانه (= نجات و رستگاری) یاری رساند. در زیر ریشه­شناسی واژه سَموَرَ، دیدگاه فلسفی درباره سَموَرَ، مراحل دستیابی، مراسم تعهد و شرایطی که به از دست دادن سَموَرَ می­انجامد، مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌های ایرانی میانه شرقی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ختن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان ختنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کتاب زَمبَستَه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آئین بودا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سَموَرَ</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4392_169ad9463409b4c7f59de3c60081eabf.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
