<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>8</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Relation between Language and Thought in Auditory Verbal Hallucination and Delusional Speech of Schizophrenic Patients: The Analytic Philosophy Perspective</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطة زبان و تفکر در توهم‌ شنیداری کلامی و گفتار هذیانی بیماران مبتلا به اسکیزوفرنی از دیدگاه فلسفة تحلیلی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>165</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>178</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1179</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرشته</FirstName>
					<LastName>مومنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد چالوس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شهلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رقیب‌دوست</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;letter-spacing: -0.1pt;&quot;&gt;The relation between language and thought has been studied from different perspectives. Analytic philosophy with language as its core subject, considers the mentioned relation as the main subject of analysis, which is clearly traceable in the speech of the individuals who have deficiency either in their thought or in their language. Hence, the speech of those schizophrenic patients who have no problem in their language, but have thought disorders could be an appropriate choice. This paper was aimed to present an analysis based on analytic philosophy, on the relation of language and thought in such patients, indicative in their Auditory Verbal Hallucinations (AVHs) and delusions. The framework was the philosophy of mind, which considers the nature, state and functions of mind, and also discusses the foundation of the Theory of Mind (ToM). Disorders of ToM will lead to auditory verbal hallucinations and delusional speech, both based on inner speech.&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ارتباط زبان و تفکر موضوع مورد مطالعه از دیدگاه علوم گوناگون است. فلسفة تحلیلی، که زبان، اصلی‌ترین موضوع آن است، از جمله به چگونگی چنین رابطه‌ای می‌پردازد. یکی از بهترین نمایه‌های مطالعة این رابطه گفتار افرادی است که یا زبانشان دچار مشکل است یا تفکرشان. بنابراین، گفتار هذیانی آن دسته از بیماران مبتلا به اسکیزوفرنی، که هیچ مشکل زبانی ندارند و فقط دچار اختلال فکر هستند، از بهترین موارد برای این منظور به شمار می‌آید. هدف مقالة پیشِ رو ارائة تحلیلی بر پایة فلسفة تحلیلی از رابطة زبان و تفکر چنین بیمارانی است که در توهم شنیداری کلامی و گفتار هذیانی آنان آشکار می‌شود. در چهارچوب فلسفة تحلیلی، فلسفة ذهن به حالات و کارکردهای ذهن می‌پردازد و، در آن، نظریة ذهن مطرح‌ می‌‌شود که اختلال، در آن، هم به توهم می‌تواند بینجامد، هم به هذیان. توهم شنیداری کلامی و هذیان، که هر دو ساختار گفتاری دارند، ناشی از پدیدة گفتار درونی هستند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اسکیزوفرنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان و تفکر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توهم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هذیان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریة ذهن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تخلیة تبعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1179_135387ac77654b2bda98754382bbfd98.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
