<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A suggestion for re-interpretation of GWDAN Mint Marks on Arab -Sassanian Coins.</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>پیشنهادی درباره ی قرائت علامت اختصاری GWDAN برروی سکه های عرب ساسانی و شناسایی محل ضرب این سکه ها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>21</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">5065</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>انصاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیارفرهنگ و زبانهای باستانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد بوشهر</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The buried remains of the ruins of Sar-Mashhad represent a great city that belonged to the Sassanian-Islamic era. In 1979, Whitcomb succeeded in identifying the ruins of the ancient city ofGhandijan in the south of Kazeroon and the historic route of Shiraz to Tawwaj. Today, it is definitely clear that Ghandijan is the same as Sar-Mashhad, which is 84km. south of Kazeroon. Considering the remains of the ancient site, it seems that this city had thrived during the Sassanid era, at the beginning of the Islamic era, and during the second and third centuries, but was emptied during the seventh and eight centuries. The purpose of this article is to provide another interpretation of the mint mark GWDAN on a number of Arab-Sassanian coins dating back to the reign of Calipha Umar ibnUbayd Allah ibnM’mar.. However, if this mint mark instead signifies GNDAN, then it would correspond to the ancient city of Ghandijan according to linguistic and archaeological evidences, which is located in the Pars province near the city of Tawwaj.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ویرانه های به جا مانده در سر مشهد نشان دهنده شهری بزرگ مدفون شده ساسانی ـ اسلامی است. در سال ۱۹۷۹ ویتکام ( Whitcomb) موفق به شناسایی ویرانه های شهر باستانی غندیجان در جنوب کازرون و در مسیر تاریخی شیراز به توج نایل گردید. امروز به طور قطع مشخص است که غندیجان همان سر مشهد امروزی است که در ۸۴ کیلومتری جنوب کازرون است. با توجه به آثار باقی مانده از این محوطه باستانی به نظر می رسد که این شهر در دوران ساسانی از رونق زیادی برخوردار بوده است و در اوایل دوره اسلامی یعنی قرن دوم و سوم از رونق آن کاسته و در قرن هفتم و هشتم از سکنه خالی شده است.
هدف از نوشتن این مقاله ارائۀ قرائتی برای علامت اختصاری GWDAN  منقور بر روی تعدادی از سکه های عرب ساسانی متعلق به خلیفه عمربن عبیدالله بن معمر ضرب شده، می باشد. این علامت اختصاری اگر به صورت  GNDAN خوانده شود می تواند با توجه به شواهد زبانشناسی و باستانشناسی با شهر باستانی غندیجان که در ایالت پارس و درنزدیکی شهر توج واقع شده انطباق داده شود.
 </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سکه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساسانیان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عرب ـ ساسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پهلوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">غندجان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عمربن عبیدالله معمر</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_5065_33777d3cb0dc8281d606daa4b3deded5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
