<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Argument Structure of the Persian Derivational Words</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ساخت موضوعی کلمات مشتق در زبان فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>57</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>74</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">107</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد‌مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>واحدی لنگرودی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد‌یار دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>قادری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبانشناسی همگانی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Argument Structure (AS) of a Predicate is a list of its arguments. For example the Persian verb xord (ate) in &quot;Ali sib ra xord.&quot; Has two arguments, while the verb dād (gave) in &quot;Ali sib rā be Zahrā dād.&quot; has three arguments: Ali, Sib, and Zahrā. The argument structure of a verb is usually changed by affixation, so that the argument structure of a derived word is different form that of the stem. This paper intends to study the argument structure of Persian verbal derivations and the effect of affixation on the argument structure of the base. The theoretical framework of this paper is Lieber&#039;s view (1992) which states that the argument structure of each word is a projection of the Lexical Conceptual Structure (LCS) of that word. So the Study of AS of a word and the changes made in it must be done according to the LCS and the changes made in it. This paper studies the effect of affixation on the argument structure of a word through the changes it may have on the LCS of that word. It will also illustrate that only those affixes that changes the LCS of the word will affect the AS of the base; it means the affixes which do not have any effects on the LCS of a word have no changes on its AS.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ساخت موضوعـی بـه فهرست موضوع‌هـای یک محمـول اطلاق می‌شود. مثلاً، فعل «خورد» دو موضوع و فعل «داد» سه موضوع در ساخت موضوعی خود دارد. معمولاً ساخت موضوعی افعال پس از افزوده‌شدن یک وند اشتقاقی به آنها تغییر می‌کند، به‌گونه‌ای که ساخت موضوعی مشتق حاصله با ساخت موضوعی کلمۀ پایه متفاوت است. در مقالة حاضر، ساخت موضوعی مشتقات فعلی زبان فارسی و تأثیر وند افزایی بر ساخت موضوعی کلمة پایه را مطالعه می‌کنیم. چارچوب نظری این مقاله نظریة لیبر است که ساخت موضوعی هر کلمه را فرافکنی از ساختار معنایی ـ واژگانی آن می‌داند و معتقد است که، برای مطالعة ساخت موضوعی هر کلمه یا تغییرات وارده بر آن، باید ساختار معنایی‌ـ واژگانی آن را مطالعه کرد. ما نیز تأثیر وندافزایی بر ساخت موضوعی کلمة پایه را از طریق بررسی تأثیر آن بر ساختار معنایی‌ـ واژگانی آن کلمه مطالعه می‌کنیم و نشان می‌دهیم که فقط وندهایی ساخت موضوعی کلمة پایه را تغییر می‌دهند که در ساختار معنایی ـ واژگانی آن کلمه تغییری ایجاد کرده باشند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساخت موضوعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساختار معنایی ـ واژگانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">موضوع</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتقاق</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_107_f3ca61e2824df929245c65dd12b9187c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
