<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>12</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Language Speakers and Collocations</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>گویشوران زبان و باهم‌آیی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>63</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>74</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2185</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منیژه</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهبودی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی ـ واحد تهران جنوب</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Combining words appropriately in a target language is one of the most difficult tasks for foreign/second language learners. By contrast, native speakers have extensive knowledge about which words should be used together, and they can accurately form the combinations of diverse words. Such knowledge is one of the vital competencies of native speakers. These combinations of words are referred to as “collocation”. &lt;br /&gt;The proper use of collocations is crucial to sound like a native speaker, yet it is not so easy for non-native speakers of a Target language. Therefore, they should be taught systematically. However, “it is largely unclear how and which collocations should be taught”. Errors in vocabulary use can be caused by the differences between learners’ L1 and target language. &lt;br /&gt;It is helpful for learners to be aware of the causes of possible errors while learning collocations. This article has an attempt to introduce collocations which are likely to cause learners to make errors due to differences their L1 and target language.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به‌کارگیری واژه‌های متناسب در کنار هم، یکی از مشکل‌ترین وظایف زبانی زبان‌آموزان دوم/خارجی است. درمقابل، گویشوران بومی، در این باره که کدام واژه‌ها را باید در کنار هم به‌کار برد، دانش گسترده‌ای دارند؛ و آنها می‌توانند واژه‌های مختلف را به‌درستی در کنار هم قرار دهند. این دانش، یکی از توانایی‌های اساسی گویشوران بومی است. درکنارهم‌قرارگرفتن واژه‌ها را «باهم‌آیی» می‌نامند. &lt;br /&gt;کاربرد خاصِّ باهم‌آیی‌ها به شکلی همانند گویشوران بومی، مسئله‌ای حساس است؛ اما این وظیفه برای گویشوران غیربومی آسان نیست. بنابراین، در این زمینه باید به آنان آموزش داد؛ با این حال، «به‌طور کلی مشخص نیست که کدام باهم‌آیی‌ها را باید آموزش داد و چگونه». خطاهایی که در استفاده از واژه‌ها رخ می‌دهد، ممکن است به‌دلیل تفاوت‌هایی باشد که بین زبان‌های مبدأ و مقصد وجود دارد. &lt;br /&gt;آگاهی از دلایل بروز خطاهای احتمالی به‌هنگام یادگیری باهم‌آیی‌ها، برای زبان‌آموزان بسیار مفید است. در این مقاله سعی شده است باهم‌آیی‌هایی معرفی شود که(به‌دلیل تفاوت در دو زبان مبدأ و مقصد) احتمال زیادی دارد زبان‌آموزان در به‌کارگیری آنها دچار اشتباه شوند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">باهم‌آیی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گویشور بومی/غیربومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌آموز دوم/خارجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان مبدأ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان مقصد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آموزش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">یادگیری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2185_46c31b85068fcec7e848ae4a31442657.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
