<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Stylistic Differences of Hafez and Salman Savoji’s Ghazals 
(Based on Verb)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تفاوت‏های سبکی غزل‏ حافظ و سلمان ساوجی از نظر کاربست فعل</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>17</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">4390</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طاهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>ایشانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیارزبان و ادبیات فارسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The literary and artistic beauty of Hafez&#039;s sonnets is obvious to everyone but these beauties become more apparent when compared to the other poets&#039; poems and especially the ghazals that he was interested in. Such studies may partially reveal why the lovers&#039; ghazas receive more enjoy by readings of Hafez&#039;s ghazals incomparison with the similar ghazals of others. Systemic functional linguistics, which has been shown to be effective in analyzing literary texts, can help in answering this question. In Haliday&#039;s systematic, experiential metafunction represent human experience from the outside and inside world, and in fact expresses the content of the clause that is expressed by the main verb and referred to as the process. hence, in the present study, using descriptive - analytical and statistical method, we seek to answer the question of what differences exist, and what effect these differences have, or effects on the ghazal style of the two poets, and their literary enjoyment of their poetry. The results of this research suggest that although both of these works have been written in a common genre (ghazal) and have a roughly similar background, the verbal choices differ from their language. Hafiz has paid more attention to the use of &quot;mental and emotional&quot; processes and &quot;material transformation&quot; processes, and the distinction of the style of the ghazals in comparison with Salman’s ghazals is in the emotional color and smell of his sonnets, as well as the dynamics of his ghazals.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زیبایی‏های ادبی و هنری غزل حافظ بر همگان مبرهن است؛ امّا این زیبایی‏ها زمانی بیشتر آشکار می‏شود که با غزل‏های دیگر شاعران و بویژه غزل‏هایی که مورد توجّه وی بوده و در استقبال از آن اشعار، غزل‏هایی هم‏زمینه سروده؛ بررسی مقایسه‏ای گردد. چنین بررسی‏هایی تا حدّی می‏تواند این امر را محرز کند که چرا غزل‏دوستان از خوانش غزل حافظ در مقایسه با غزل‏هایی با همان زمینه؛ حظّی وافرتر و متفاوت‏تر دریافت می‏کنند. زبان‏شناسی نقش‏گرای هلیدی که در تحلیل متون ادبی کارآمد نشان داده شده؛ در پاسخ به این پرسش می‏تواند کمک نماید. در این رویکرد، فرانقش تجربی که به بازنمایی تجربه‌های انسان از جهان بیرون و درون می‌پردازد؛ بیانگر محتوای گزاره‌ای بند است که به‌وسیلة فعل اصلی بیان می‌شود و به آن فرایند می‌گویند. در جستار پیشِ رو، با بهره‏گیری از روش توصیفی‏تحلیلی و آماری، در پی پاسخ به این پرسش‏ هستیم که غزل حافظ و سلمان از نظر کاربست انواع فرایندها چه تفاوت‏هایی با هم دارند و این تفاوت‏ها چه تأثیراتی بر سبک غزل این دو شاعر و به تبع آن التذاذ ادبی شعر آنان دارد. نتایج این پژوهش حاکی از این است اگرچه هر دوی این آثار در یک ژانر مشترک (غزل) نوشته شده‌اند و دارای زمینة تقریباً مشابهی هستند؛ امّا گزینش‏های فعلی انگیخته از زبان آنان متفاوت است. حافظ به بهره‏گیری از فرایندهای «ذهنیِ آرزویی و عاطفی»، و فرایندهای «مادّیِ تبدیلی» توجّه بیشتری نشان داده و تمایز سبکیِ غزلیّات هم‏زمینة او نسبت به غزل‏های سلمان در رنگ و بوی عاطفی و همچنین پویایی غزل وی نهفته است</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حافظ شیرازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سلمان ساوجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‏شناسی نظام‏مند نقش‏گرا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرانقش تجربی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فعل</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4390_89af4659e67398b000dd3036786156b6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
