<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Rustam, Mithraʼs Soldier</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رستم، سرباز مهر</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>19</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">5066</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>نظری فارسانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه فرهنگ و زبانهای باستانی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The narration collection which has been mentioned in Iranian national book is divided to the three main periods: myth, epic and historical. Rustam is the main hero in epic period of Shahnameh. His principal work is guardedness and maintenance to Iranian kingdom. Numerous valuable researches about various aspects of this deep character are done, but there is ambiguousness and questions about some of Rustamʼs characteristics, meaning of his name, some of his epithets, and some of his weapons, yet. In this paper a few of Rustamʼs characteristics and of his works is studied in epic and myth and linguistic sphere, and with pay attention to Rustam is a Scythian according to Shahnameh, his name and his tāj-baxš epithet and his armor named as babr i bayān is studied on the basis of Scythian language vocabulary. In addition, it is shown that Rustam has no relation and connection with Indra and Apām Napāt, but with Mithra.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مجموعه روایت‌هایی که درحماسه ملّی ایران،شاهنامه، بیان شده‌اند به سه دورة عمدة اساطیری، حماسی و تاریخی تقسیم شده‌اند.رستم بزرگ‌ترین پهلوان دورة حماسی شاهنامهاست. کار برجستة او حمایت و پاسداری از شهریاری ایران است.گرچه دربارة ابعاد مختلف این شخصیت ژرف و پهلوان محبوب ایرانیان پژوهش‌های ارزشمند پرشماری انجام شده است، هنوز ابهامات و پرسش‌هایی در خصوص برخی ویژگی‌هایشخصیتی رستم، معنی نام او، برخی از صفات او، و همچنین بعضی از ابزارهایش وجود دارد. در مقالة حاضر به شخصیت و برخی اعمال رستم از دید زبانی و اسطوره‌ای و حماسی می‌نگریم، و با توجه به این که رستم سکایی است، و در شاهنامه به این نکته تصریح شده است، نام این پهلوان و صفت «تاج‌بخش» و تن‌پوش موسوم به «ببر بیان» او را بر اساس گنجینة واژگانی زبان سکایی بررسی می‌کنیم.همچنین نشان می‌دهیم که رستم نه با ایندره و اپام نپات، بلکه پیوند نزدیکی با ایزد میثره دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">:رستم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مهرپرستی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان سکایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تاج‌بخش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ببر بیان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سکیسران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_5066_297d529c3a80f6730167d574485dc96e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
