<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Rapitwin Gāh, the Ideal Time in
Mazdayasni Religion</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>گاهِ رَپیتوین، زمان آرمانی در دین مزدیسنی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>25</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>37</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">457</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرزانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>گشتاسب</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار پژوهشکدة زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The “&lt;em&gt;Rapitwin&lt;/em&gt;” is considered as a highly important &lt;em&gt;yazata&lt;/em&gt; (adorabale one) within the Zoroastrian religion. He is the lord of that portion of a day which is called “&lt;em&gt;Rapitwin gāh”. &lt;/em&gt;In Zoroastrian mythology, the&lt;em&gt; Rapitwin gāh&lt;/em&gt; signifis a quality of time which can be interpreted as “the ideal time”. This &lt;em&gt;gāh&lt;/em&gt; is considered to represent either the beginning of creation, the moment of resurrection and also is supposed to be the period during which the &lt;em&gt;saošyant&lt;/em&gt;s will appear. The material symbol of the “&lt;em&gt;Rapitwin gāh&lt;/em&gt;” is noontime. The myth of &lt;em&gt;Rapitwin &lt;/em&gt;has brought about wonderful and impressive rituals amongst the Zoroastrian ceremonies. Special rituals are celebrated for this lord to bid him farewell, when he goes underground, in order to protect the roots of vegetation, which is at the beginning of the great winter, a hundred days before the first day of the new year and again at the time of his return over the ground, on the new year&#039;s day. The ritual for &lt;em&gt;Rapitwin, &lt;/em&gt;at the first day of &lt;em&gt;Farvardin&lt;/em&gt;, may be considered as the festival of the &quot;seventh creation&quot; which is fire. The “&lt;em&gt;Jašn-e Sade&lt;/em&gt;”, the festival which is observed on the occasion of the discovery of fire, and the prayers and rituals for the lord of &lt;em&gt;Rapitwin &lt;/em&gt;support this opinion.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ایزد رَپیتْوین یکی از ایزدان بسیار مهم دین زرتشتی است. این ایزد موکل بخشی از زمان است که آن را «گاه ‌رَپیتوین» می‌نامند. گاه‌ رَپیتوین در اساطیر زرتشتی بیان‌گر کیفیتی از زمان است که می‌توان آن‌ را وضیعت آرمانی نامید. این گاه هم لحظة آغازین آفرینش است و هم لحظة انجامین رستاخیز؛ و هم لحظه‌ای است که سودرسانان موعود (سوشیانت‌ها) ظهور می‌کنند. نماد این‌جهانی گاه ‌رَپیتوین، هنگام ظهر و یکی از بخش‌های پنج‌گانة روز است. اسطورة ایزد رَپیتوین در مناسک زرتشتی بازتابی روشن و شگفت به‌جای گذاشته ‌است. برای بدرقة او در آغاز زمستان بزرگ، صد روز پیش از بازگشت او به روی زمین و نیز اول فروردین، که هنگام بازگشت دوبارة اوست، آیین‌هایی برای این ایزد برگزار می‌شود. مراسم رَپیتوین در اول فروردین را می‌توان جشن بزرگ‌داشت هفتمین آفرینش یعنی جشن پیدایش آتش نامید. «جشن‌ سده»، که به پیشواز بازگشت رَپیتوین می‌رود و به مناسبت کشف آتش برگزار می‌شود، و دیگر نیایش‌ها و آیین‌های مربوط به ایزد رَپیتوین این نظریه را تقویت می‌کنند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رَپیتوین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جشن سده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زمان آرمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آیین‌های زرتشتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_457_726f93df8bf188738b3ff9e12fc0552a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
