<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Nature of Epenthetic Vowel in English Loanwordes In Persian Based on Optimality Theory</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ماهیت واکۀ درج‌شده در وام‌واژه‌های انگلیسی در زبان فارسی بر مبنای نظریۀ بهینگی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>69</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>97</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">123</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بتول</FirstName>
					<LastName>علی‌نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد‌یار زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ملیحه</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحیمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present paper studies breaking of initial consonant clusters of English loanwordes which results in changing of syllable structure in Persian. The research data were collected from three famous dictionaries -Anvari (1386), Moshiri (1371), Zomorrodian (1384). The theoritical framework of the present research is Optimality Theory, a constraint based approach, which was presented in Generative Grammar in 1993 by Prince and Smolensky . In this research, we are going to answer the question: How can Optimality Theory analyzes the changing of syllable structure of loanwords in Persian? The results show that Persian language follows a series of faithfulness and markedness constraints to obtain optimal outputs and by vowel epenthesis (initial and mediate), breakes the consonant clusters and changes the syllable structure.The main reason of vowel epenthesis in the present paper has been considered assimilation process.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقالۀ حاضر به بررسی شکسته‌شدن خوشه‌های همخوانیِ آغازین وام‌واژه‌های انگلیسی در زبان فارسی، که منجر به تغییر هجا می‌شود، می‌پردازد. داده‌های پژوهش از سه فرهنگ معتبر، انوری (1383)، مشیری (1371) و زمردیان (1384)، جمع‌آوری شده‌است. چارچوب این پژوهش نظریۀ بهینگی ـ یکی از رویکرد‌های محدودیت بنیاد ـ است که پرینس و اسمولنسکی در سال 1993 آن را در چارچوب مکتب زایشی مطرح کردند. در این پژوهش، در پی پاسخ به این سؤال هستیم که نظریۀ بهینگی چگونه می‌تواند تغییر و تحولات خوشه‌های همخوانی آغازین وام‌واژه‌ها را، که منجر به تغییر ساخت هجا در زبان فارسی می‌گردند، تجزیه و تحلیل کند؟ پاسخ مقالۀ حاضر به سؤال مذکور این است که زبان فارسی برای دستیابی به برون‌داد‌های بهینه به تعارض محدودیت‌های نشانداری و پایایی در نظریۀ بهینگی پرداخته، با فرایند درج واکه (میانجی و آغازی) خوشه‌های همخوانی را می‌شکند و تغییری در ساخت هجا پدید می‌آورد. علت اصلیِ درجِ واکه همگونی در نظر گرفته شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریۀ بهینگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وام‌واژه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محدودیت پایایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محدودیت نشانداری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_123_9c7b11bb4538a05324e8ba620f040afc.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
