<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>5</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Common Proper Names in Sogdian Inscriptions of Pakistan’s Upper Indus and Western Middle Iranian Inscriptions (Sasanid, Parthian)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نام‌ها‌‌ی خاص مشترک در کتیبه‌های سغدی سند علیای پاکستان و کتیبه‌های ایرانی میانة غربی (ساسانی ـ پهلوی اشکانی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>107</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>124</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">586</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ویدا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نداف</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The Sogdian inscriptions of the upper Indus are a corpus of more than 700 graffiti including 2 in Parthian, 2 in Middle Persian, 2 in Bactrian and the others in the Soghdian language and Some engravings carved on the boulders which litter the banks of this river; for the most part they consist of the personal names of visiting Sogdian merchants. These inscriptions belong to about the 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt;-6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; centuries AD. The occurrence of Middle Persian names such as Shapur, Kartir, and Babak amongst the Sogdian names also suggests a time within the Sassanian period (i.e. 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt;-mid 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century). In this Paper, I considered the common proper names between Sogdian and the west Middle Iranian Inscriptions, and then the similarities and differences are studied at the end.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کتیبه‌‌های سغدی سند علیا مجموعه‌‌ای است شامل بیش از 700 سنگ‌نوشته به زبان‌‌های پارتی (2 مورد)، فارسی میانه (2 مورد)، بلخی (2 مورد)، و بقیه به زبان سغدی و نیز نقش برجسته‌هایی، که بر روی سنگ‌‌هایی در کنارة این رودخانه کنده شده‌‌اند. بر روی بیش‌تر این سنگ‌نوشته‌‌ها، نام بازرگانان سغدی حک شده است که زمانی از این مکان دیدار کرده‌‌اند. این کتیبه‌‌ها متعلق به قرن سوم تا ششم میلادی است. وجود نام‌ها‌‌ی فارسی میانه نظیر شاپور، کرتیر، و پاپک در میان نام‌ها‌‌ی سغدی زمانی نزدیک به دورة ساسانی (نیمة قرن سوم تا هفتم میلادی) را تأیید می‌‌کند. &lt;br /&gt;در این مقاله، ابتدا نام‌ها‌‌ی خاص مشترک بین کتیبه‌‌های سغدی و کتیبه‌‌های ایرانی میانة غربی (پهلوی ساسانی ـ پهلوی اشکانی) مشخص شده، و سپس شباهت‌‌ها و ناهمانندی‌ها در پایان هر نام آورده می‌‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کتیبه‌‌های سغدی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سند علیای پاکستان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کتیبه‌‌های ساسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کتیبه‌‌های اشکانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_586_89522bac87792f488eed2be4a8d9a3a6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
