<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>5</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Compound Sentences in Persian
(An RRG-Based Analysis)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>جملات مرکب در زبان فارسی تحلیلی بر پایة نظریة دستور نقش و ارجاع</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>25</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">568</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>پهلوان‌نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>رسول‌پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبان‌شناسی و مدرس دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This paper undertakes to describe “Compound Sentences” in Modern Persian (Farsi) based on Functional Syntactic theory of “Role and Reference Grammar”. First, it describes the foundation of RRG theory which is presented in 1997 by Robert D. Van Valin Jr. and Randy J. Lapolla and extended later by Van Valin in his book “Exploring the Syntax-Semantics Interface” (2005).The RRG posits three nexus relations between clauses in “Compound Sentences” (Coordination, Co subordination, Subordination) rather than the two of “Traditional”, “Structural” and “Generative” Grammar. There are three primary levels of juncture, clausal, core and nuclear and there are three possible nexus relations among the units in the juncture .All three types of nexus are possible in all three forms of juncture and this yields nine juncture-nexus types in Universal Grammar. We described two relations (Coordination, Subordination) in Compound Sentences. There are two types in Coordination and nine types in Subordination. This paper concludes that the advantage of the RRG is simultaneous exploring of three levels of “Syntactic”, “Semantics” and “Pragmatics” description.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله، ساختار جملات مرکب زبان فارسی بر پایة نظریة «دستورِ نقش و ارجاع» بررسی می‌شود. این نظریه را، در سال 1997، رابرت دی. ون ولین و رندی جی. لاپولا مطرح کردند و، در سال 2005، ون ولین نسخة نهایی آن را ارائه داد. دستور حاضر سه نوع رابطه را با عنوان «هم‌پایگی»، «ناهم‌پایگی» و «هم‌وابستگی» بین جملات مرکب مطرح می‌سازد و سه سطحِ اولیة پیوند را «بند»، «کانون»، و «هسته» می‌داند. سه نوع رابطة احتمالی بین «واحدها» برقرار است. بنابراین، از ترکیب سطوحِ اولیة پیوند و روابط احتمالی، نُه رابطه در «دستور همگانی» این نظریه قابل تصور است؛ که الزاماً تمامیِ آن‌ها در همة زبان‌ها یافت نمی‌شود. در این مقاله، جملات مرکب زبان فارسی را تحت دو رابطة کلیِ هم‌پایگی و ناهم‌پایگی بررسی نموده و دو نوع رابطه را برای هم‌پایگی و نُه رابطه را برای ناهم‌پایگی معتبر دانسته‌ایم؛ که با ارائة مثال‌ها و نمودارهایی تبیین شده‌اند. مزیت تحلیل‌های زبانیِ این دستور نسبت به سایر نظریه‌های دستوری را می‌توان توجهِ هم‌زمان به سه سطح «نحوی»، «معنایی»، «کاربردشناختی» دانست. امری که در نظریه‌های دستوری دیگر مستلزم پژوهش‌های جداگانه‌ای است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نقش‌گرایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دستور نقش و ارجاع</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساخت‌های نحوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معنایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">و کاربردشناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جملات مرکب فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هم‌پایگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ناهم‌پایگی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_568_3cfc7c02bcaecdbbb226ded3513e9f7d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
