<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Adjective Predicates in Persian language</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>محمول صفتی در زبان فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>111</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>125</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">4989</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ازاده</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرزایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>There are two main approaches to the predicative function of the adjectives that precede the verb ‘to be’ and it`s equivalences; one which considers these adjectives as a non-verbal element of the compound verb and the other one assumes them as the subject complement. Studying the behavior of the adjectives in the Persian Proposition Bank and Persian Syntactic Dependency Treebank show that the adjectives that accompany the verbs ‘to be’ and it`s equivalences are generally divided into two categories: 1- Adjectives that take argument structure and can be called adjective predicates; 2. Adjectives that do not take argument structure. This study assumes that only the second group of adjectives is the subject complement. To prove this claim, two substitution and coordination tests were used to identify whether this adjective is an autonomous constituent or a part of a whole. Also, considering the semantic role of the subject in the sentences containing this group of adjectives and based on the list of compound verbs in the Persian language, the hypothesis of this study was tested. Accordingly, about half of the approximately eleven thousand subject complements reported in the Persian Syntactic Dependency Treebank should be viewed as the non-verbal element of the-compound-verb.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در ارتباط با نقش محمولی صفت در جایگاه پیش از فعل‌های «بودن» و معادل‌های آن، دو رویکرد عمده وجوددارد؛ یک دیدگاه صفت را در این جایگاه، جزء غیرفعلیِ فعل مرکب می‌داند و رویکرد دیگر آنرا مسند فرض‌می‌کند. بررسی رفتارصفت‌ها در پیکرۀ وابستگی نحوی زبان فارسی و پیکرۀ گزاره‌های معنایی زبان فارسی نشان‌می‌دهد، صفاتی که در جایگاه پیش از فعل‌های «بودن» و معادل‌های آن قرارمی‌گیرند، به طور کلی به دو دسته تقسیم‌می‌شوند، 1-صفت‌هایی که ساخت ظرفیتی دارند و به اصطلاح می‌توان آنها را محمول صفتی نامید و 2-صفت‌هایی که ساخت ظرفیتی ندارند. فرض این پژوهش بر این است که تنها صفت‌های گروه دوم مسند هستند. در این پژوهش برای اثبات این ادعا از دو آزمون جایگزینی و همپایه‌سازی در تشخیص سازه‌های جملهاستفاده‌شده‌است. نقش معنایی فاعل در جملات حاوی این گروه از صفت‌هاو استناد به فهرست افعال مرکب زبان فارسی، شواهدی دیگری هستند که بر اساس آنها می‌توان بر درستی فرضیۀ این پژوهش صحه گذاشت.بر این اساس از حدود یازده هزار مسند‌ گزارش‌شده در پیکرۀ وابستگی نحوی زبان فارسی، نیمی از آنها باید به عنوان جزء فعلی فعل مرکب درنظر گرفته شوند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صفت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مسند</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محمول</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فعل مرکب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4989_0ad11ce7268d822b3cc9cb199d40b1b9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
