<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>13</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Phonological and morphological adaptations in Azerbayjani Turkish loanwords</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بومی سازی واجی و صرفی وام‌واژه‌ها در زبان ترکی آذربایجانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>15</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2490</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدخانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>زبان شناسی دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>دیانا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رشیدیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>زبان شناسی دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This research is on the phonological and morphological shifts of Azerbaijani Turkish loanwords. Speakers of most languages in order to utilize the loan words shift and adapt them according to their native morphological and phonological system. In this research, first, the loanwords from Arabic and Persian collected, and then their phonological shifts as vowel harmony, mutation, insertion, deletion, lenition, and assimilation as well as morphological shifts such as derivation and compounding studied. The method of this research is descriptive and analytic and data are collected from Turkish dictionaries. The framework of phonological shifts is generative phonology. In this research, 704 loanwords from Arabic and Persian studied. Among phonological shifts the most frequent shift was vowel harmony and the least one is assimilation. In morphological shifts, derivation and compounding are studied. In this type of shift, the most frequent one is derivation and the least one is compounding.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این تحقیق بررسی تغییرات واجی و صرفی وام­واژه­ها در زبان ترکی آذربایجانی می­باشد. سخن­گویان هر زبانی برای استفاده از وام واژه ها، آنها را در دستگاه صرفی و واجی بومی خود تغییر می­دهند. در این پژوهش ابتدا واژگانی که از زبانهای فارسی و عربی وارد این زبان شده مشخص گردیده سپس به بررسی تغییرات واجی مانند هماهنگی واکه­ای ،ابدال، درج، حذف، نرم­شدگی، همگونی و تغییرات صرفی از جمله ترکیب و اشتقاق پرداخته شده است. در این پژوهش از روش توصیفی و تحلیلی  و به منظور جمع آوری داده­ها از فرهنگهای لغت ترکی- فارسی استفاده شده است. در حوزه واج شناسی چارچوب نظری واج شناسی زایشی است. در این پژوهش 704 وام­واژه از زبانهای فارسی و  عربی بررسی شدند. در این پژوهش مشخص گردید که از میان فرایندهای واجی فرایند هماهنگی واکه­ای بیشترین بسامد را دارا بوده وکمترین بسامد مربوط به فرایند  همگونی است. در حوزه صرف فرایند اشتقاق و ترکیب مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. بیشترین بسامد مربوط به اشتقاق و کمترین بسامد مربوط به ترکیب می­باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرایندهای واجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرایندهای صرفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وام‌واژه‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترکی آذربایجانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2490_de3d0831a077c5f070d2045f7e961dff.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
