<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>9</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Two decades of Conferences in Iranian Linguistics; A Scientometric Study</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی دو دهه همایش در زبان‌شناسی ایران؛ یک مطالعۀ علم‌سنجی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>103</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>123</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1437</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>قلی‌فامیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه زبان‌شناسی و زبان‌های خارجی، دانشگاه‌ پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Scientometrics is a field of study that analyzes the quantitative parameters involved in science publication and expansion. Taking seven scientometric parameters into account, the present paper investigates 411 articles presented in eight linguistic conferences held in Iran between 1991 and 2013. The findings indicate that the frequency of syntax is higher than other sub-fields of linguistics followed respectively by discourse analysis and morphology. Among 70 universities participating in the eight conferences under study, the students and members of faculty in Allame Tabataba’i University have been the most active scholars. Likewise, 202 articles dealt with a special language or dialect and with 152 counts, Persian has been the most frequent language. The results show that the tendency towards the group work in research and article writing, the number of female article writers, the average of length of article titles, and the frequency of citation have increased throughout the time.        </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">علم‌سنجی حوزه‌ای است که به سنجش شاخص‌های کمّی مؤثر در نشر علوم می‌پردازد. در پژوهش حاضر، 411 مقالۀ ارائه‌شده در 8 همایش زبان‌شناسی ایران از سال 1369 تا 1391 با توجه به هفت شاخص علم‌سنجی بررسی شده است. یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد که فراوانی مقالات در زیرشاخۀ نحو بیش از سایر زیرشاخه‌‌های زبان‌شناسی است و دو زیرشاخۀ تحلیل‌ گفتمان و ساخت‌واژه در رتبه‌های دوم و سوم قرار دارند. از میان 70 دانشگاه و مرکز علمیِ شرکت کننده در همایش‌های مورد مطالعه، دانشجویان و اعضای هیئت علمیِ دانشگاه‌ علامه‌ طباطبایی بیش‌ترین سهم را در ارائۀ مقالات داشته‌اند. از مجموع مقالاتِ ارائه‌شده، 202 مقاله به زبان یا گویشی خاص پرداخته است و زبان فارسی با 152 مقاله رتبۀ نخست را به خود اختصاص داده است. هم‌چنین گرایش به کار گروهی در انجام دادن پژوهش و تألیف مقاله، سهم زنان در ارائۀ مقالات، میانگین طول عنوان مقالات و نیز استناد به منابع در طول زمان افزایش یافته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">علم‌سنجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همایش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مقاله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عنوان مقاله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استناد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1437_4be18c67cf645175640c23595c75187c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
