<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Formulaic Language and its Role in Persian Language Teaching</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>زبان فرمولواره‌ای و نقش آن در آموزش زبان فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>81</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>106</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">4394</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>کاوه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی (نویسنده مسئول)،</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آزیتا</FirstName>
					<LastName>افراشی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This descriptive study investigates formulaic language in Persian. There are two types of formulae: prefabricated (situation-bound) formulae (PFF); and semi-prefabricated formulae (SPFF); they have fixed elements as well as open slots to be occupied with words of given lexical categories. The data is taken from linguistic corpora, soap operas, personal observations, and web materials. This study addresses these questions: 
a.            What contexts are formulae used in?
b.            What socio-cultural meanings do formulae convey? 
c.             How can learning formulae help overcome the problem of fluency of Persian language learners?
 Formulaic sequences are used in all socio- cultural contexts and mostly in idiomatic meaning. To analyze the data, the author used his own intuition as well as other native speakers’ along with consulting various dictionaries. In the following ‘dual process model’ is employed to demonstrate the interaction of PFF and SPFF as well as novel language. The implications in teaching involve that introducing the situation and meaning of PFF to learners helps them produce idiomatic native like expressions in a given situation and analyzing the  SPFF and identifying their underlying formula, meaning, and restrictions (deductively) and presenting different examples (inductively)to learners  they can generate infinite number of native like  expressions  in Persian.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این جستار پژوهشی است توصیف‌بنیاد که به معرفی، توصیف، و تحلیل عبارت‌های فرمولواره‌ای و انواع اصلی آن در فارسی می‌پردازد. فرمولواره‌ها دو گونه‌ی اصلی دارند؛ فرمولواره‌های ثابت (پیش‌ساخته) توالی‌هایی هستند که به‌طور یکجا فراگرفته، به‌طور یکجا ذخیره می‌شوند و به‌طور یکجا بکار می‌روند. دیگری، فرمولواره‌های زایا (نیمه‌پیش‌ساخته) هستند که هم دارای عناصر ثابت و هم برخی جایگاه‌های تُهی هستند که توسط عناصری از مقوله واژگانی مشخص پُر می‌شوند. داده‌های پژوهش از پایگاه داده‌های زبان فارسی، وِب‌گردی، زنجیره‌های تلویزیونی، و مشاهدات شخصی گردآوری‌شده است. این پژوهش به سؤالاتی از این قبیل می‌پردازد که فرمولواره‌ها در چه بافت‌هایی، و با چه معنایی بکار می‌روند و فراگیری آن‌ها چگونه می‌تواند به رفع مشکل روانی گفتار فارسی‌آموزان بیگانه کمک کند. گوناگونی داده‌ها نشان می‌دهد فرمولواره‌ها تقریباً در تمامی بافت‌های اجتماعی-فرهنگی و غالباً در معنای اصطلاحی بکار می‌روند. در ادامه بر مبنای انگاره پردازش دوسطحی به چگونگی پردازش فرمولواره‌ها پرداخته‌ایم. پس از تحلیل ساختار درونی و ارائه نمونه‌های متعدد از فرمولواره‌ها و دسته‌بندی جایگاهشان در گفتمان ، به توصیفی دست‌یافتیم که راه را برای فراگیری آن‌ها در آموزش زبان فارسی هموار می‌کند. ازآنجایی‌که بر مبنای هر فرمولواره زایا می‌توان بی‌نهایت عبارت جدید خلق کرد بنابراین فراگیری آن‌ها می‌تواند کمک شایانی به سلاست گفتاری زبان‌آموزان کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان فرمولواره‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عبارت‌های فرمولواره‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرمولواره‌های ثابت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرمولواره‌های زایا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توصیف ساختاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توصیف معنایی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4394_7f667846c83e1056073c940b4c2478f9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
