<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>9</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Instance of Umlaut in the Historical Studies of Balochi Language
(Historical Change of /ū/ into /ī/)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نمونه‌ای از فرایند پیشین‌شدگیِ واکه‌ای در مطالعاتِ تاریخیِ زبان بلوچی (تبدیلِ تاریخیِ ū به ī)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>171</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>185</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1440</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>موسی</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمودزهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The sounds of languages undergo changes under the effects of certain linguistic factors through the historical changes of languages from one form into another. Studying 100 Balochi—an Iranian language—words, it was found that the vowel /ū/ in Old Iranian has changed into /ī/ in some parts of Iranian Baluchistan including southern and central areas, currently being common in a free variant of two forms as /ū/ and /ī/ in these areas. In addition, investigating the phenomenon in some other Iranian languages from the most eastern (Pamir territory) to the most western (Kurdish and Bakhtiari territories), it was found that this historical change has occurred, and it can be considered a general and widespread phenomenon among Iranian languages. Finally, the study of this phenomenon in the Balochi language can be useful from some aspects such as typology and linguistic description and historical studies of Balochi language and its dialects and accents.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در تحول تاریخیِ زبان‌ها، اصواتِ آن‌ها تحتِ تأثیر عواملِ زبانیِ خاصی تغییر می‌کنند و از صورتی به صورتِ دیگر درمی‌آیند. در این مقاله، با بررسیِ 100 واژه در زبانِ بلوچی، یکی از زبان‌هایِ ایرانی، معلوم شد که واکۀ /ū/ در ایرانیِ قدیم، تحت تأثیر فرایند پیشین‌شدگیِ واکه‌ای، در بخشی از بلوچستانِ ایران، از جمله نواحیِ جنوبی و مرکزی، به /ī/ تبدیل شده و، در حالِ حاضر، در این مناطق به صورت گونۀ آزادِ دوگانه‌ای به دو صورتِ /ū/ و /ī/ رایج است. به‌علاوه، با بررسیِ این پدیده در بعضی از دیگر زبان‌هایِ ایرانی از شرقی‌ترین نواحی(حوزۀ پامیر) تا غربی‌ترین نواحی(حوزه‌های کُردی و بختیاری)، معلوم شد که این تحولِ تاریخی در آن زبان‌ها نیز اتفاق افتاده است و می‌توان آن را یک پدیدۀ گسترده و عمومی در زبان‌های ایرانی به حساب آورد. در نهایت این‌که بررسی این پدیده در زبانِ بلوچی در زمینه‌هایی مانند رده‌بندی، توصیف‌هایِ زبانی و مطالعاتِ تاریخی زبانِ بلوچی و گویش‌ها و لهجه‌های آن قابل استفاده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌های ایرانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بلوچستانِ ایران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبانِ بلوچی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیشین‌شدگیِ واکه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گونه‌های آزادِ واکه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1440_6b5f9d5753ff58f1203269e42c80ac6c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
