<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1391</YEAR>
<VOL>3</VOL>
<NO>6</NO>
<MOSALSAL>6</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>170</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تغییرات واژگانی در جامعة زبانی شهر گرگان بر اساس متغیرهای اجتماعی سن، جنسیت، و تحصیلات</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Study of Lexical Changes in Gorgan Language Society, According to Social Varieties, Age, Gender and Education</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زبان پدیده‌‌ای است اجتماعی که پیدایش آن به زمان نخستین اجتماعات انسانی باز می‌‌گردد و همچون «‌‌نهادی انسانی‌‌« و متعلق به جامعه، در ارتباط با تحولات اجتماعی و تاریخی جوامع بشری، شکل می‌‌گیرد. مطالعات جامعه‌‌شناختی زبان نشان داده است که ساخت و کاربرد زبان بی‌تأثیر از عوامل اجتماعی و متغیرهای غیر‌زبانی، مانند جنسیت، سن، تحصیلات، قومیت، طبقة اجتماعی و غیره نیست. بررسی گویش‌‌های شهری و تحولات آن نیز یکی از زیر شاخه‌‌های جامعه‌‌شناسی زبان محسوب می‌‌شود. اما پیش‌تر، در مطالعات گویشی، محققان اغلب به بررسی گویش‌‌های روستایی می‌‌پرداختند و به تبع آن گویش‌‌های شهری مورد غفلت قرار می‌‌گرفت. این امر خود بدان دلیل بود که، در بررسی‌‌های گویش‌‌شناسی، نیروهای محرک بر فیلولوژی تطبیقی استوار بود و شهرها، به علت مهاجرت افراد از روستاها، اهمیت خود را به لحاظ فیلولوژی از دست می‌‌دادند. زمانی که تأکید بر این امر (فیلولوژی‌‌) در بررسی‌‌های زبان‌‌شناختی تغییر یافت، تمایل به مطالعات شهری افزون گردید. در پژوهش حاضر، نگارندگان به بررسی تغییرات واژگانی در جامعۀ زبانی شهر گرگان، با توجه به عوامل سن، جنسیت و تحصیلات، پرداخته و هم‌بستگی میان تغییرات واژگانی براساس متغیرهای اجتماعی مذکور را، با بهره‌‌گیری از روش میدانی و انتخاب جمعیت نمونه، ارزیابی کرده‌اند. نتایج حاصل از این پژوهش نشان دادند که متغیر اجتماعی سن مهم‌ترین عامل در تغییر واژه محسوب می‌شود و متغیرهای جنس و تحصیلات نقش کمرنگ‌‌تری ایفا می‌‌کنند. همچنین این متغیر در تغییرات واجی و آوایی در این جامعة زبانی نقشی عمده دارد. بنابراین متغیر سن مهم‌ترین شاخص این تغییرات محسوب می‌‌گردد و می‌‌تواند خطری در راستای از میان‌رفتن گویش اصیل این جامعة زبانی باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Language is a social phenomenon, which emersion goes back to the emersion of the first human societies. Such a phenomenon is the same as a human inclination, owned by society which is formed in accordance with societies’ social and historical evolution. The sociolinguistics studies has already indicated that the infrastructure and application of the language is inseparable from the social factors such as gender, age, education, tribal bias, social levels, etc. Meanwhile, the study of urban dialectology considers as a part of sociolinguistics, which has been ignored regarding to scientists’ intention toward rural dialects. Rural dialectology is basically founded on comparative philology, therefore cities which were faced a huge emigration from variety of regions have lost their philological values. However, the focus on philology is changed in the recent studies and the study of urban areas drew the attentions toward itself. In this paper, the author&#039;s focus is on the lexical changes in Gorgan’s urban society, regarding to three social factors: age, gender and education. In the other words, the paper mainstream is on the correlation between lexical changes and social variables which is assessed by using the field method, asking randomly from the statistical society. The results of the research has shown that the age is the major factor of lexical changes in Gorgan and other variables, gender and education, stand at the second and third position respectively. The age variable also plays a significant role in phonological changes in the mentioned language society. All in all, it seems that age is the most important changing factor in the Gorgan language society, which considers as a warning about the gradual death of the dialect.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>14</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>یدالله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پرمون</Family>
						<NameE>Yadollah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Parmoon</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار زبان‌‌شناسی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار زبان‌‌شناسی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>yadollahparmoon@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ندا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ازکیا</Family>
						<NameE>Neda</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Azkiya</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکترای زبان‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکترای زبان‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>n_azkia@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهناز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کربلائی صادق</Family>
						<NameE>Mahnaz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Karbalayi Sadegh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری زبان‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران‌‌</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری زبان‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mahnaz_ks@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جامعه‌شناسی شهری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>متغیر زبانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جنسیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>باطنی، محمدرضا (1374). مسائل زبان‌شناسی نوین، تهران: آگاه.##ترداگیل، پیتر (1376). زبان‌شناسی اجتماعی، درآمدی بر زبان و جامعه، ترجمة محمد طباطبایی، تهران: آگاه.##زنده‌دل، حسن (1379). مجموعه راهنمای جامع ایرانگردی، استان گلستان، تهران: ایران‌گردان.##کالوه، لویی ژان ( 1379). درآمدی بر زبان‌شناسی اجتماعی، ترجمة محمد‌جعفر پوینده، تهران: نقش جهان.##مدرسی، یحیی (1368). درآمدی بر جامعه‌شناسی زبان، تهران: مؤسسۀ مطالعات فرهنگی.##مهدی‌پور، مرجان (1378). «بررسی قدرت در گفتار زنان و مردان فارسی‌زبان»، پایان‌نامة کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.##وود، جیمز (1369). دیدگاه‌های نوین جامعه‌شناسی، ترجمة مصطفی ازکیا، تهران: کیهان.##Chambers, J. K. and Peter Trudgill (1980). Dialectology, London: Cambridge University Press.##Cheshire, J. (1987). Age and Generation, Specific Use of Language, London: Edward Arnold.##Fasold, R. (1984). The Sociolinguistics of Society, Oxford: Basil Blackwell.##Gordon, E. (1997).‘Sex, Speech and Stereo Type why Women Use More Prestige Speech Forms More than Men?’, Language in society, 26,47-63.##Hudson, R. (1980). Sociolinguistics, London: Cambridge University press.##Jespersen, O. (1922). Language: It&#039;s nature, development and origin, London: George Allen and Uhwin.##Labov, W. (1972). Sociolinguistics patterns, Philadelphia: University of Pensylvania press.##Lakoff, R. (1973). The logic of politeness: Minding your psqs, Chicago linguistics society.##Macaulay, R. K. S. (1977). Language Social and Education, A Glasgow study. Edinburg university press.##Trudgill, P. (1972). Sex, covert prestige and linguistic change in the urban British of Norwich, Cambridge University press.##Versteegh, K. (1997). Landmarks in linguistic thought: the Arabic linguistic tradition, Routledge.##Wardhaugh, R. (1992). An introduction to sociolinguistics, Oxford: Blackwell.##Weatherall, A. (2002). Gender, Language and Discourse, Routledge.##Wolfram, W. (1969). A Sociolinguistics is description of Detroit negro speech, Washington D.C: Center for applied linguistics.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ساختار متن سرمقاله‌‌های روزنامه‌‌های ایرانی (بر اساس الگوی حل مسئلة مایکل هوی 2001)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Structure of Iranian Newspaper’s Editorials
(According to 2001 Michael Hoey’s Solving-Problem Model)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زبان‌‌شناسی متن شاخه‌‌ای از تحلیل گفتمان است که به بررسی زبان در سطح جمله و فراتر از جمله می‌‌پردازد. رویکردهای مختلفی برای تشخیص ساختار درونی متون و چگونگی تولید و درک آن‌ها ارائه شده که یکی از آن‌ها رویکرد حل ‌مسئله مایکل هوی است. این رویکرد دارای چهار رکن است: موقعیت، مسئله، پاسخ‌، و ارزیابی. در تحقیق حاضر، سعی بر آن است تا، با استفاده از زبان‌‌شناسی متن، این رویکرد توضیح و به این پرسش‌‌ها پاسخ داده شود که ساختار متن سرمقالة روزنامه‌‌های ایرانی تا چه میزان بر اساس الگوی مایکل هوی ‌تعمیم‌پذیر است و چگونه می‌‌توان میزان انتظار وقایع آن را توسط خوانندگان با استفاده از این الگو مشخص کرد. بر این اساس، در تحقیق حاضر، تعداد 20 متن سرمقاله‌‌ (سخن سردبیر)های روزنامه‌‌های ایرانی از دو روزنامة سراسری کشور، اعتماد و آفتاب یزد، انتخاب و بررسی شده است. تحلیل داده‌‌ها بر اساس این رویکرد حاکی از این امر است که ساختار تولید متن روزنامه‌‌های بررسی‌شده تا حد زیادی با چهار رکن الگوی حل ‌مسئلۀ مایکل هوی یعنی موقعیت، مسئله، پاسخ و ارزیابی منطبق است و با استفاده از این الگو میزان انتظار و ضریب پیش‌‌بینی و درنتیجه درک سریع‌‌تر متن روایی عرضه‌شده به خواننده مشخص می‌‌شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Text linguistics attends to texts and their properties. Various approaches have been put forth to explore the organization of texts and the way they are produced and comprehended. One of which is Michael Hoey’s problem-solution approach (2001). This model consists of four components including situation, problem, recycling, response and evaluation. In this approach, texts are rewritten in the form of conversations, questions and answers. We attempt to answer these questions: in what extend we can generalize this pattern to newspaper articles and by using the problem solution pattern, how we can achieve a degree of anticipation, predictiveness and quicker comprehension of narrative texts as hypotheses. To fulfill the objectives, benefiting from the problem-solution pattern (2001), 20 articles from four newspapers including E’temade and Aftabe yazd, were analyzed based on this pattern. In conclusion, the analysis revealed how newspaper articles of these groups using PS pattern. Therefore, the first hypothesis was confirmed and the relationship between components of problem-solution pattern was shortly displayed by diagrams in each article. Texts were analyzed on the bases of socio-cultural and discursive structures and also rewritten in conversations. Furthermore from data analysis via a t- test calculation, it became clear that the comprehension, anticipation, predictiveness of reader enhanced on the basis of this pattern. Consequently the second hypothesis of the current study has been confirmed.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>15</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>30</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ژیلا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خانجانی</Family>
						<NameE>Zhila</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khanjani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش‌آموختة دکترای زبان‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش‌آموختة دکترای زبان‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>j.khanjani@srbiau.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فردوس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آقاگل‌‌زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Ferdows</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aghagolzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه زبان‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه زبان‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان‌‌شناسی متن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل گفتمان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی حل ‌مسئله</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساختار متن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آقاگل‌‌زاده، فردوس (1385). تحلیل گفتمان انتقادی، تهران: علمی و فرهنگی.##آقاگل‌زاده، فردوس و علی افخمی (1383). «زبان‌شناسی متن و رویکردهای آن»، مجلة زبان‌شناسی، س 19، ش 1.##آقاگل‌‌زاده، فردوس و شیرین ممسنی (1386). «تحلیل زبان‌‌شناختی سازمان متن روایی تنگسیر در چهارچوب الگوی حل مسئلة مایکل هوی»، فصل‌‌نامة علمی ـ پژوهشی انجمن زبان و ادبیات فارسی، س 4، ش 15.##یارمحمدی، لطف‌‌الله (1383). گفتمان‌‌شناسی رایج و انتقادی، تهران: هرمس.##Aghagolzadeh, F. (2004). ‘Problem Solution Pattern in Text Analysis’, TarbiatModares International Journal of humanities, 11 (1).##Coulthard, M. (1994). Advances in Written Text Analysis, London: Routledge.##Emmott, C. (1994). ‘Frames of reference: contextual monitoring and the interpretation of narrative discourse’, in Coulthard, M. (ed.), Advances in written text analysis, 157 - 167.##Fasold, R. )1990(. The Sociolinguistics of Language, Cambridge.##Gavins, J. (2007). Text World Theory, Edinburg University Press.##Hoey, M. (1983). On the Surface of Discourse, London: Allen and unwin.##Hoey, M. (2001). Textual Interaction; an Introduction to Discourse Analysis, London: Rutledge.##Lucena, M. I. P. (2000). ‘Situation-problem-solution-evaluation: Recognizing how these functions are signaled in a text’, UESC, Universidade Estadual de Santa Cruz 18.##Salkie, R. (1995). Text and Discourse Analysis, London: Routledge.##Shiro, M. (1994). ‘Inferences in Discourse Comprehension’, Advances in written text analysis, Coulthard, M. (ed.).##Tadros, A. (1994). ‘Predictive categories in expository text’, Advances in written text Analysis, Coulthard, M. (ed.).##Ze-sheng, Y. (2007). ‘Development of reading and writing abilities by teaching textual patterns’, Sino-US English Teaching David publishing Company, USA. 7 (12).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>جلوه‌‌های بلاغت در دو سرود منسوب به مانی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Rhetorical Aspects in Two Hymns Attributed to Mani</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مانی از پدر و مادری ایرانی در بابِل، که از استان‌‌های حکومت اشکانی بود، زاده شد. به گواهی تاریخ، ایرانیان مردمانی بلیغ بوده‌‌اند و بین‌‌النهرین محل تلاقی عقاید، افکار، و اساطیر گوناگون محسوب می‌‌شد. تبار ایرانی و پرورش در بابل زمینه‌‌های رشد و تعالی اندیشه و هنر را در مانی مهیا ساخت. بی‌‌شک جنبه‌‌ای از بلاغت ایرانیِ پیش از اسلام در اشعار او تجلی ‌‌یافته بود که نمونه‌‌های بازمانده به زبان فارسی میانه و پارتی پیروان او بخش کوچکی از این گنجینۀ پربار گذشته است. این اشعار گوشه‌‌ای از تصرفات ایرانیان در حوزۀ خیال و برخی سنت‌‌ها و ویژگی‌‌های شعری آن دوره را نشان می‌دهد. در این مقاله، دو سرود یکی، به زبان فارسی میانه و دیگری، به زبان پارتی، که اصل آن‌ها منسوب به مانی است، به دلیل تنوع استفاده از صُوَر خیال و جلوه‌‌های بلاغی پیشرفته، بررسی و تحلیل زیبایی‌شناختی می‌شوند. از آرایه‌‌های ادبی در این دو سرود کوتاه، به تشبیه، استعاره، مجاز، کنایه، تکرار، مراعات‌‌نظیر، حس‌آمیزی، ایهام، و ایهام تناسب باید اشاره کرد که ظرافت و ذوق به‌‌کاررفته در برخی از آن‌ها از دست‌یابی شاعران آن دوره، به نوعی کمال در حوزۀ خیال شاعرانه حکایت می‌‌کند، موضوعی که از لحاظ تاریخ ادبی ایران بسیار مهم است. در این اشعار، امکانات ادبی و بلاغی در خدمت اندیشه‌‌های مانی درآمده است که، به مناسبت، دربارۀ این عقاید توضیح داده شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Mani was born from the Persian parents in Babylonia, which was a part of the province of Asoristan in the Parthian empire. According to the Historical evidences, Iranians have been eloquent people, and Mesopotamia was consideredas the confluence of the various ideas, thoughts and myths. Being in an Iranian family and training in Babylonia caused to improve mani&#039;s thought and art Undoubtedly, we can find in his poetry, an aspect of pre-Islamic Iranian rhetoric which is survived in middle Persian and parthian hymns. Part of Iranians&#039; attainments in the field of poetical imagination are displayed in these hymns. In this article two hymns, attributed to mani, one in the middle Persian and the other in the Parthian language, have been studied from aestethical point of view. The rhetorical speeches used in these two hymns such as, simile, metaphor, metonymy, kenning, repetition, taxis, synesthesia, amphiboly and opacity can display a kind of excellent achievement in poetic imagination that is very important in the history of Persian literature in Iran. In these hymns, literary and rhetorical features have been applied to express Mani’s thoughts that, if necessary, have been explained too.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>31</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>43</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زرشناس</Family>
						<NameE>Zohre</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zarshenas</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zzarshenas@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عباس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آذرانداز</Family>
						<NameE>Abbas</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Azarandaz</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری فرهنگ و زبان‌‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری فرهنگ و زبان‌‌های باستانی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abbasazarandaz@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شعر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فارسی میانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پارتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بلاغت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آرایه‌‌های ادبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>کلیم کایت، هانس یواخیم (1384). هنر مانوی، ترجمۀ ابوالقاسم اسماعیل‌‌پور، تهران: اسطوره.##محمدی ملایری، محمد (1384). فرهنگ ایرانی پیش از اسلام، تهران: توس.##همایی، جلال‌‌الدین (1373). معانی و بیان، تهران: مؤسسة نشر هما.##Asmussen. Jes. P. (1975). Manichaean literature, New York: Scholars’ Facsimiles and reprints.##Boyce, M. (1954). The Manichaean Hymn Cycles in Parthian, London.##Boyce, M. (1975). A Reader in Manichaean Middle Persian and Parthian (Acta Iranica 9), Leiden, Téhéran and Liège.##Boyce, M. (1977). A word List of Manichaean Middle Persian and Parthian, (Acta Iranica 9a), Leiden, Téhéran and Liège.##Holman, C. Hugh (1985). A Handbook to Literature, Indiana: ITT bobs-Merrill Educational Publishing Company, Inc.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>گونه‌های گفتاری و نوشتاری در زبان‌های انگلیسی و فارسی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Spoken and Written Variants in Teaching
Persian Language to non-Persian Speakers</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مهم‌ترین تمایز کاربردی زبان، که از وسیلۀ بیان ناشی می‌شود، تمایز گفتار و نوشتار است. این تمایز دو گونۀ گفتاری و نوشتاری زبان را پدید می‌آورد که در همۀ زبان‌ها کم و بیش به‌چشم می‌خورد. تفاوت‌های دو گونه به دوری یا نزدیکی صورت‌های گفتاری از صورت‌های نوشتاری بستگی دارد. به دلیل اختلافات بارز گفتار و نوشتار در زبان فارسی، آموزش این زبان به‌عنوان زبان خارجی دشواری‌ فراوانی برای زبان‌آموزان به همراه دارد. این دشواری زمانی محسوس‌تر می‌شود که غیر ایرانی بودن بسیاری از مدرسان این رشته، تخصص مدرسان ایرانی در رشته‌های جدا از آموزش زبان، محیط زبانی نامأنوس و بیگانه، ضعف عوامل انگیزشی در زبان‌آموزان، و، درنهایت، عدم دسترسی به منابع آموزشی صوتی نیز در مد نظر قرار گیرد. در آغاز مقاله، ضمن اشاره به نحوة شکل‌گیری مطالعات گفتاری ـ نوشتاری، وضعیت کلی آموزش زبان فارسی به غیر فارسی‌زبانان به‌اختصار مطرح گردیده، سپس به توضیح تفاوت‌های عمدة‌ ساختاری در دو گونۀ گفتاری و نوشتاری پرداخته شده است. شرح مجموعۀ تفاوت‌های این دو، بر مبنای پژوهش‌های نوین زبان‌شناختی، بخش اصلی مقاله را تشکیل می‌دهد. طرح مبانی نظری، به شرحی که خواهد آمد، می‌تواند اساس ارائة راهکار مناسب برای آموزش تفاوت‌ها در برنامه‌های فارسی‌آموزی قرار گیرد و در کسب مهارت‌های گفتاری زبان‌آموزان مفید واقع شود و، درنهایت، به ارتقای دانش زبانی آنان و جایگاه زبان فارسی بینجامد. طرح مقاله از شناخت و تجربۀ نگارنده در آموزش زبان فارسی به غیر فارسی‌زبانان نشئت گرفته و داده‌های آن به روش اسنادی از آثار محققان نام‌دار زبان‌شناسی تأثیر پذیرفته است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The most important practical distinction of language derived from the medium of expression is that of speech and writing which produces the spoken and written variants, observed more or less in all the languages. The differences of the two variants depend on the distance or proximity of the spoken from the written forms. Owing to the conspicuous differences of speech and writing in the Persian language, learning Persian as a foreign language accompanies abundant difficulties for the learners. The difficulties become more noticeable when we consider that most teachers in the field are non-Iranians, Iranian teachers have specialties other than language teaching, students learn the language in alien linguistic environment, they feel poor stimulation for language learning and, finally, learners are deprived of audio visual sources. Referring to the formation of spoken-written studies at the start of the article, the general situation of teaching Persian to non-Persian speakers has been briefly introduced and, then, the chief structural differences of the spoken and written variants have been discussed. An analysis of the differences, based on recent linguistic researches, forms the main part of the article. The theoretical principles may be used as the basis for presenting appropriate tactics to teach the differences in Persian syllabuses, prove useful to language learners in acquiring spoken skills, and finally, end in the promotion of their language knowledge and the status of the Persian language. The article is derived from the writer’s knowledge and experience in teaching Persian to non-Persian speakers, the data being influenced by the works of prominent linguistics researchers on a documentary basis.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>45</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>68</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صفارمقدم</Family>
						<NameE>Ahmad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Saffar Moghadam</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار آموزش زبان و فرهنگ ایران به غیر فارسی‌زبانان، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار آموزش زبان و فرهنگ ایران به غیر فارسی‌زبان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>as_moqaddam@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مطالعات گفتاری ـ نوشتاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آموزش زبان فارسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گونة گفتاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گونة نوشتاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تفاوت‌های گفتاری ـ نوشتاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>حسنی، حمید (1384). واژه‌های پرکاربرد فارسی امروز، تهران: کانون زبان ایران.##Kucera, Henry and W. Nelson Francis (1961). The Brown University Corpus, Rhode Island: www.helsinki.fi/varieng/CoRD/corpora/BROWN/index.html.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اخلاق و آداب سخن‌دانی در اندرزنامه‌های فارسی میانه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Speech&#039;s Etiquette in Middle Persian Advices (Andarznameh)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>سخن و آداب آن از موضوعاتی است که در متون ادبی و اندرزنامه‌های فارسی میانه همواره به آن توجه شده است. برای بیان آداب سخن‌دانی و اهمیت آن در متون این دوره می‌توان آن‌ها را به چند موضوع کلی تقسیم‌بندی کرد. در این گزارش، ابتدا در مقدمه‌ای کوتاه به اهمیت سخن در ادبیات ایران باستان پرداخته شد؛ سپس آداب سخن‌دانی در متون ادبی و اندرزنامه‌های فارسی میانه در قالب موضوعات «راست‌گویی و دوری از دروغ»، «با اندیشه سخن‌گفتن»، «میانه‌روی در گفتار»، «سنجش زمان و سخن»، «نرمی و ادب در گفتار» و غیره بررسی شد. در این نوشتار، همچنین سعی شده است برخی از این اصطلاحات در متون نظم و نثر فارسی و نیز برخی از گویش‌ها بررسی شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Speech and its etiquette have always been noticed in Middle Persian literary texts and texts on the advice (Andarznameh) as well. To express the etiquette of speech and its weight in the texts of this period, they can be divided into several general subjects. In this report, firstly, a short introduction about the importance of speech in ancient Persian an is given and then the etiquette of speech in Middle persian literature texts (Andarznameh) is elaborated. This etiquette consists of ‘truthfulness and avoiding lying’, ‘wisely spoken speech’, ‘equilibrium in speech’, ‘measurement of location and time of speaking’, ‘softness and politeness in speech’ and ... . It has also been tried in this paper to investigate some of the terminology in poetry and prose texts, and also in some dialects.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>69</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>84</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فرزانه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گشتاسب</Family>
						<NameE>Farzaneh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Goshtasp</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>f_goshtasb@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نادیا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حاجی‌پور</Family>
						<NameE>Nadia</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>hajipour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سخن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سخن‌وری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فارسی میانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>متون ادبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آموزگار، ژاله (1387 الف). «سنت شفاهی در ایران باستان»، زبان، فرهنگ و اسطوره، تهران: معین.##آموزگار، ژاله (1387 ب). «جادوی سخن در اساطیر ایران»، زبان، فرهنگ و اسطوره، تهران: معین.##ارداویراف‌نامه ← ژینیو 1382.##اندرز اوشنر دانا ← رشید یاسمی 1313؛ Dhabhar 1930.##پورداوود، ابراهیم (1356). یسنا، 2 ج، تهران: دانشگاه تهران.##تفضلی، احمد (1379). مینوی خرد، تهران: توس.##جاماسب‌آسانا، جاماسب‌جی منوچهر (1371). متون پهلوی، ترجمة سعید عریان، تهران: کتاب‌خانۀ ملی جمهوری اسلامی ایران.##ماتیکان هزار داتستان ← Perikhanian 1980.##دهخدا، علی‌اکبر (1373). لغت‌نامه، تهران: دانشگاه تهران.##دینکرت ششم ← Shaked 1979؛ Madan 1911.##دینکرت هفتم ← راشدمحصل 1389؛ Madan 1911.##راشدمحصل، محمدتقی (1389). دینکرد هفتم، تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##رشید یاسمی، غلامرضا (1313). «اندرز اوشنر دانا»، مهر، س 2، ش 7، صص 718 - 722؛ ش 8، صص 839 - 842؛ ش 9، 937 - 942.##روایت پهلوی ← میرفخرایی 1390؛ Dhabhar 1913 .##ژینیو، فیلیپ (1382). ارداویراف‌نامه، ترجمه و تحقیق ژاله آموزگار، تهران: معین.##سروشیان، جمشید (1356). فرهنگ بهدینان، به کوشش منوچهر ستوده، تهران: دانشگاه تهران.##عنصرالمعالی، کیکاووس (1375). قابوس‌نامه، تصحیح غلامحسین یوسفی، تهران: علمی و فرهنگی.##فرهنگ اویم ← Reichelt 1899-1901؛ Asha 2009.##فره‌وشی، بهرام (1386). فرهنگ زبان پهلوی، تهران: دانشگاه تهران.##کیا، صادق (1390). واژه‌نامۀ شصت و هفت گویش ایرانی، تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##متون پهلوی ← جاماسب آسانا 1371؛ Jamasp-Asana 1897.##میرفخرایی، مهشید (1390). روایت پهلوی، تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##مینوی خرد ← تفضلی 1379؛ Anklesaria, 1913##واژه‌نامۀ پهلوی← فره‌وشی 1386؛ MacKenzie, 1986.##Anklesaria, T. D. (1913). Dânâk-u Mainyô-I Khard, Bombay.##Asha, R. (2009). Avesta Glossary, A Glossary of Avesta words and their Pārsīg equivalents, based on the Zand, the so-called Frahang ī ōim:ēk, Bombay.##Dhabhar, B. N. (1913). The Pahlavi Rivâyat, Bombay##Dhabhar, B.N. (1930). Andarj-i Aōshnar-i Dānāk, Bombay.##Jamasp-Asana, J.M. (1897). Pahlavi Texts, Bombay.##MacKenzie, D.N. (1986). A Concise Pahlavi Dictionary, London.##Madan, D. M. (1911). Pahlavi Dinkard, part I, II. Bombay.##Perikhanian, A. (1980). The Book of A Thousand Judgment, California and New York.##Reichelt, H. (1899-1901). ‘Der Farhang i oīm’, Wiener Zeitschrift für die Kunde des Morgenlandes, 1899: pp. 178; 1901: pp. 117-186.##Shaked, S. (1979). The Wisdom of the Sasanian Sages, (Dēnkart VI), (Persian Heritage Series, 34). Colarado.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>چندصدایی و چندشخصیتی در رمان پسامدرن ایران با نگاهی به رمان اسفار کاتبان از ابوتراب خسروی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Polyphony and Poly-Subjectivity in Iranian Postmodern Novel; A Study of Asfar-e Kateban by Abutorab-e Khosravi</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>اسفار کاتبان از ابوتراب خسروی، به اعتبار حضور صداهای چندگانة شخصیت‌‌ها با‌هم و در‌هم، متنی چندصدایی تلقی می‏شود. چندصدایی اصطلاحی ‏است که باختین برای اشاره به رمان‌‌های داستایفسکی از آن استفاده کرد، که، در آن‌ها، شخصیت‌‌ها به گونه‏ای به مکالمه با هم می‌‌پردازند. در رمان‌‌های پیشامدرن، راوی گویندة مسلط در کل متن بود که اجازة هیچ‌‌گونه ابراز عقیده‌‌ای را به شخصیت‌‌ها نمی‌‌داد. در دورة مدرن، این تسلط کامل راوی از بین می‌‌رود و برابری قدرت شخصیت‌‌ها و راوی را در بیان عقایدشان شاهدیم. حال در دورة پسامدرن، این برابری به‏استقلال کامل شخصیت‌‌ها در متن بدل می‏شود و شخصیت‌‌ها حتی گاه از راوی/ نویسندة رمان نافرمانی می‌‌کنند. به این‏ترتیب، متن شاهد حضور آواهای متعدد می‏شود و، از طریق چندصدایی، سرشت متکثرگونة فضای پسامدرنیستی را می‌‌نمایاند. حال سؤال این ‏است که چندصدایی چگونه در متن تجسم‏ یا، به عبارتی، متنیت می‌‌یابد. بر این اساس، در این مقاله، تأکید روی بازتاب ذهنیت شخصیت‌‌ها در زبان آن‌ها‏ست. بنابراین، با بررسی ترکیب و رقابت انواع متفاوت شخصیت‌‌ها و نیز حضور دیگر شخصیت‌‌ها در ذهن ‏یک شخصیت، چگونگی شکل‌‌گیری کانونی‌‌سازی درونه‌‌گیری‌‌شده و تأثیر آن در ایجاد چندصدایی متن نشان داده خواهد شد. با توجه به متن‌‌های نمونه‌ای که در بخش تحلیل داده‌ها آورده شده، ما نه تغییر مدام زاویة دید بلکه‏ حضور کانونی‏سازهای چندگانه را شاهدیم که کانونی‌‌شونده‌های دیگر را در خود جمع می‌کند. این کانونی‌شونده‌ها گاهی افراد دیگری‌‌اند و گاهی خودِ دیگرِ کانونی‌ساز. بنابراین، هنگام بازگویی مطالب از زبان کانونی‌‌سازِ چندگانه، ضمیر‌های اول‏شخص و سوم‌شخص را می‌بینیم که از جانب خودِ کانونی‌ساز برای اشاره به خود به‌کار می‌رود: خودِ عینی و خودِ ذهنی‌اش، یعنی ضمیر‌های «من» و «او». بدین‌ترتیب، صداهای متفاوت تأثیر زبانی خود را در متن تجسم می‌بخشند و متن، به‌‌واسطة چند‌‌شخصیتیِ حاصل از این خودهای متفاوت، چندصدایی‏بودن خود را متجلی می‌سازد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Asfar-e Kaateban by Aboutorab Khosravi is a polyphonic text in the light of the presence of associated and amalgamated various voices. Polyphony is a term that Mikhail Bakhtin used to refer to Dostoyevsky&#039;s works, in which characters have dialogue in some manner. By means of dialogue, characters renounce the dominance of author and they can illustrate their individuality. In Pre-Modern works, narrator was the dominant recite in the whole text which did not authorize characters to express their impressions. In Modern era, this complete dominance of narrator is suppressing and we can identify the equality of characters&#039; authority and narrator&#039;s authority in expressing the impressions. Nowadays in Post-Modern world, this equality converts to the complete independence of characters and even they disobey narrator. Consequently, text exemplifies the presence of numerous voices, and by means of polyphony, the polarity nature of postmodern atmosphere is illustrated. Here, a question arises that how polyphony is personified, or in other words, how polyphony is textualized. The focus of this paper is on the reflex of characters&#039; psyche in their language. Therefore, the formation of embedded focalization and its affect on making polyphony is shown through the analysis of combination and competition of different characters and the presence of other characters in the mind of a character. The analysis of selected texts demonstrates that Khosravi managed to create polyphony and poly subjectivity, and consequently, the place and role of characters in the postmodern text is indicated. And it is multi-focalizer that collects other focalized in itself. Then, focalized are sometimes other person and other self of focalizer itself. In this situation, we have first person pronoun and third person pronoun that are used by focalizer to refer to it, to its subjective and objective self; me and him / her.  Therefore, different voices embody their effects in text, and the text, also manifests its polyphonic characteristic by means of poly-subjectivity, that is the resultant of these different self.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>85</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>120</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نوبخت</Family>
						<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nobaxt</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری زبان‌‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری زبان‌‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nobaxt@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پسامدرنیسم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چندصدایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چندشخصیتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اسفار کاتبان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ابوتراب خسروی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آلن، گراهام (1386). بینامتنیت، ترجمة پیام یزدان‏جو، تهران: نشر مرکز.##تسلیمی، علی (1383). گزاره‏هایی در ادبیات معاصر ایران (داستان)، تهران: اختران.##تودورف، تزودان (1377). منطق گفت‌وگویی میخائیل باختین، ترجمة داریوش کریمی، تهران: نشر مرکز.##تولان، مایکل (1386). روایت‏شناسی: درآمدی زبان‏شناسی ـ انتقادی، ترجمة سیده فاطمه علوی و زهرا نعمتی، تهران: سمت.##خسروی، ابوتراب (1379). اسفار کاتبان، تهران: آگه و نشر قصه.##خسروی، ابوتراب (1384). اسفار کاتبان، تهران: آگه و نشر قصه.##کریستوا، ژولیا (1381). «کلام، مکالمه، رمان»، به سوی پسامدرن: ساختارگرایی در مطالعات ادبی، ترجمة پیام یزدان‏جو، تهران: نشر مرکز.##Bakhtin, M. (1984). Problem of Dostoevsky’s Poetics, ed and rtans, C. Emerson Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press.##Benfild, A. (1982). Unspeakable Sentences, New York: Routledge and Kegan Paul.##Jahn, M. (1996). ‘Window of Focalization: Deconstructing and Reconstructing a Naratological Concept’, Style (30) 2.##Lodge, David (1990). After Bakhtin, London and New York: Routledge.##McHale, B. (1987). Postmodernist Fiction, New York: Methune.##Moriss, R. (2003). Realism, London: Routledge.##Teranishi, Masayuki (2007). ‘AStylistic Analysis of Soul Bellow’s Hersog: a Mode of postmodern Polyphony’, Language and Literature, London, Los Angeles. New Delhi and Singapore. Vol 16 (1).##Toolan, Micel (2001). Narrative: A Critical Linguistic Introduction, 2ed. London: Rotledge.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ریشه‌شناسی چند لغت در ترجمه‌ای از عهد عتیق</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Etymology of Some Words in a Translation
of the Old Testament</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>اسفار خمسة لندن تنها ترجمة تاریخ‌دار فارسی ـ عبری از اسفار خمسه است. این متن در 1319 میلادی مطابق 719 هجری قمری کتابت شده است. همة محققان، به پیروی از نظر لازار، این متن را متعلق به جنوب غربی ایران می‌دانند. اما باید توجه داشت که برخی لغات شرقی (مانند لغات حوزة ماوراءالنهر و هرات) نیز در آن دیده می‌شود. در این مقاله، به ریشه‌شناسی تعدادی از لغات این متن خواهیم پرداخت. این لغات عبارت‌اند از: b’z sknydn, bγr’wydn, bγr’w/bγr’y, br ryšydn/wr ryšydn, bprčn-, dr gwrx’nydn, jng k’rydn, snyl, syl, m’rh, mwžndh/mwzydg’r, nwxrys/nwxrys’nydn, wysh.. در نهایت، خواهیم دید که اغلب این لغات در زبان‌های شرقی ایران ریشه دارند یا در گونه‌های زبانی فارسی شرقی به‌کار می‌روند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Pentateuch of London is the only dated translation of Torah in Judaeo-Persian or Hebrew-Persian. The text has written in 1319 AD, according to 719 AH. All of researchers follow up Lazar (1968) and attribute the text to the southwest of Iran. But it should be noted that some Eastern words (eg: the words of Transoxiana or Herat area) is also seen. In this article we will deal with the root of the following words in this text: b’z sknydn, bγr’wydn, bγr’w/bγr’y, br ryšydn/wr ryšydn, bprčn-, dr gwrx’nydn, jng k’rydn, snyl, syl, m’rh, mwžndh/mwzydg’r, nwxrys/nwxrys’nydn, wysh. Finally, we will see that most of these words in the Eastern kinds of Persian Language.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>121</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>153</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حامد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نوروزی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamed</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Noroozi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه زبان و ادبیات فارسی دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه زبان و ادبیات فارسی دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hd_noruzi@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اسفار خمسة لندن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فارسی ـ عبری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ریشه‌شناسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فارسی جنوب غربی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فارسی شرقی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آذرلی، غلامرضا (1387). فرهنگ واژگان گویش‌های ایران، تهران: هزار.##احمد جام نامقی، ابونصر (1355). روضةالمذنبین و جنّةالمشتاقین، به تصحیح علی فاضل، تهران: بنیاد فرهنگ ایران.##اسدی طوسی، ابومنصور علی بن احمد (1319). لغت فرس، به تصحیح عباس اقبال، تهران: چاپ‌خانة مجلس.##اسماعیل جرجانی (2535 ش.ش.). ذخیرۀ خوارزمشاهی، به کوشش سعیدی سیرجانی، تهران: بنیاد فرهنگ ایران.##امیرمعزی (1318). دیوان امیرالشعراء محمد بن عبدالملک نیشابوری متخلص به معزی، به تصحیح عباس اقبال، تهران: کتاب‌فروشی اسلامیه.##انجو شیرازی، میرجمال‌الدین حسین بن فخرالدین (1354). فرهنگ جهانگیری، 3 جلد، به تصحیح رحیم عفیفی، مشهد: دانشگاه فردوسی.##بخشی از تفسیری کهن (1375). به تصحیح آیت‌الله‌زاده، تهران: میراث مکتوب.##ترجمۀ تفسیر طبری (1339 - 1343). 7 جلد، به تصحیح حبیب یغمایی، تهران: دانشگاه تهران.##ترجمۀ کتاب مقدس (عهد عتیق و عهد جدید که از زبان‌های اصلی عبرانی و کلدانی و یونانی ترجمه شده است) (1920). دارالسلطنۀ لندن.##ترجمه و قصه‌های قرآن از روی نسخة موقوفه بر تربت شیخ جام (1338). به تصحیح یحیی مهدوی و مهدی بیانی، تهران: دانشگاه تهران.##تفسیر شنقشی، گزاره‌ای از بخشی از قرآن کریم (1355). به تصحیح محمدجعفر یاحقی، تهران: بنیاد فرهنگ ایران.##تفسیری بر عشری از قرآن کریم (1352). به تصحیح جلال متینی، تهران: بنیاد فرهنگ ایران.##جمال‌الدین محمد بن عبدالرزاق اصفهانی (1320). دیوان، به تصحیح حسن وحید دستگردی، تهران: کتاب‌فروشی ابن‌ سینا.##جهان‌ملک خاتون (1374). دیوان کامل جهان‌ملک خاتون، به تصحیح پوراندخت کاشانی راد و کامل احمدنژاد، تهران: زوّار.##حسن‌دوست، محمد (1383). فرهنگ ریشه‌شناختی زبان فارسی، ج 1: آ- ت، زیر نظر بهمن سرکاراتی، تهران: فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی.##حسن‌دوست، محمد (1390). فرهنگ تطبیقی ـ موضوعی زبان‌ها و گویش‌های ایرانی نو، 2 جلد، تهران: فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی.##خرگوشی، ابوسعید عبدالملک بن ابوعثمان محمد واعظ (1361). شرف‌النّبی، ترجمۀ نجم‌الدین راوندی، به تصحیح محمد روشن، تهران: بابک.##دهخدا، علی‌اکبر (1358). لغت‌نامه، تهران: موسسۀ لغت‌نامة دهخدا.##رضایی باغ بیدی، حسن (1390). «دربارة چند مهرنوشته و سکه‌نوشتة ساسانی و عرب ساسانی»، آیینة میراث، پیاپی 48.##رواقی، علی و مریم میرشمسی (1381). ذیل فرهنگ‌های فارسی، تهران: هرمس.##زوزنی، ابوعبدالله حسین بن احمد (1339). کتاب المصادر، به اهتمام تقی بینش، مشهد.##سروری، محمدقاسم بن حاجی محمد کاشانی (1338). مجمع الفرس، 3 جلد، تهران: علمی.##سروشیان، جمشید سروش (1370). فرهنگ بهدینان، به کوشش منوچهر ستوده، تهران: دانشگاه تهران.##سعدی، ابو عبدالله شیخ مشرف‌الدین (1381). بوستان، سعدی‌نامه، به تصحیح غلامحسین یوسفی، تهران: خوارزمی.##صادقی، علی‌اشرف (1380). مسائل تاریخی زبان فارسی، تهران: سخن.##صادقی، علی‌اشرف (1391). تحقیق در کتاب المصادر ابوبکر بُستی، تهران: میراث مکتوب.##طوسی، محمد بن محمود احمد (1382). عجایب‌المخلوقات و غرایب‌الموجودات، به تصحیح منوچهر ستوده، تهران: علمی و فرهنگی.##عثمان مختاری (1341). دیوان، به تصحیح جلال‌الدین همایی، تهران: بنگاه ترجمه و نشر کتاب.##عوفی، محمد (1335). لباب الالباب، به کوشش سعید نفیسی، تهران: کتاب‌خانة ابن سینا، حاج علی علمی.##فردوسی، ابوالقاسم (1387). شاهنامه، 7 جلد، به تصحیح جلال خالقی مطلق و محمود امید سالار و ابوالفضل خطیبی، تهران: مرکز دایرةالمعارف بزرگ اسلامی.##فرهنگ‌نامۀ قرآنی (1389). 5 جلد، با نظارت محمدجعفر یاحقی، مشهد: بنیاد پژوهش‌های اسلامی آستان قدس رضوی.##قاسمی، مسعود (1388). «ذیلی بر ذیل فرهنگ‌های فارسی»، نشر دانش، س23، ش 1.##قرآن قدس (1364). به تصحیح علی رواقی، تهران: مؤسسة فرهنگی شهید محمد رواقی.##قریب، بدرالزمان (1383). فرهنگ سغدی، تهران: فرهنگان.##قواس غزنوی، فخرالدین مبارکشاه (1353). فرهنگ قواس، به تصحیح نذیر احمد، تهران: بنگاه ترجمه و نشر کتاب.##کردی نیشابوری، ادیب یعقوب (2535/ 1355). کتاب البلغة، به تصحیح مجتبی مینوی و فیروز حریرچی، تهران: بنیاد فرهنگ ایران.##کرمینی، علی بن محمد بن سعید الادیب (1385). تکملةالاصناف، 2 جلد، به تصحیح علی رواقی با همکاری سیّده زلیخا عظیمی، تهران: انجمن آثار و مفاخر فرهنگی.##کمال‌الدین، حازم‌علی (2008). معجم مفردات المشترک السامی فی اللغة العربیة، لبنان: مکتبة الآداب.##لازار، ژیلبر (1384). شکل‌گیری زبان فارسی، تهران: هرمس.##محمد پادشاه (1335). آنندراج، 7 جلد، به تصحیح محمد دبیرسیاقی، تهران: کتاب‌خانة خیام.##محمدحسین بن خلف تبریزی (1376). برهان قاطع، 5 جلد، به تصحیح و تحشیۀ محمد معین، تهران: امیرکبیر.##ملیکیان، گورگین (2001). نامۀ آفرینش، قدیم‌ترین ترجمۀ فارسی به خط عبری، ایروان.##ناصر خسرو قبادیانی (1353). دیوان، به تصحیح مجتبی مینوی و مهدی محقّق، تهران: دانشگاه تهران.##نفیسی، علی‌اکبر (2535/ 1355). فرهنگ نفیسی، 5 جلد، تهران: کتاب‌فروشی خیام.##Asmussen, J. P. (1969). A Selected List of Words from the Vatican Judaeo Persian Pentateuch (Genesis), Reprinted from k. R. Cama Oriental Institute Golden Jubilee Volume, Bombay.##Asmussen, J. P. and H. Paper (1977). The Song of Songs in Judeo-Persian, Introduction, Texts, Glossary, Kobenhaven.##Bacher, W. (1896). ‘Ein Hebraisch-Persisches Worterbuch aus dem 15 Jahrhundert’, Zeitschrift fur die Alttestamentlische Wissenschaft 16.##Bailey, H. W. (1933-35). ‘Iranian Studies II’, BSOAS, Vol. VII.##Bailey, Harold Walter (1979). Dictionary of Khotan Saka, Cambridge (etc.): Cambridge University Press.##Boyce, M. (1977). A Word-list of Manichaean Middle Persian and Parthian (AcIr 9a, 3e Serie, Vol. 2, Supplement), Leiden, etc.: Brill.##Cheung, Johny (2007). Etymological Dictionary of the Iranian Verb, Boston: Leiden.##Dagmar, S. Wodtko, Britta Irslinger, and Carolin Schneider (2008). Nomina im Indogermanischen Lexikon, Universitätsverlag Winter Heidelberg.##Durkin-Meisterernst (2004). Dictionary of Manichaean Texts, Vol. III: Texts from Central Asia and China,  Nicholas Sims-Williams (ed.), Part 1: Dictionary of Manichaean Middle Persian and Parthian, Turnhout (Belgium): Brepols.##Gindin, T. E. (2003). ‘The Tafsir of Ezekiel: Four Copyist or Four Authors?’, Persian Origins, Early Judaeo-Persian and the Emergence of New Persian, Collected Papers of the Symposium, Gottingen 1999, Paul Ludwig (ed.), Wiesbaden, 2003.##Gindin, T. E. (2007). The Early Judaeo-Persian Tafsirs of Ezekiel: Text, Translation, Commentary, Vol. I: Text (Veroffentlichungen zur Iranistik), Austrian Academy of Sciences.##Gindin, T. E. (forthcoming). The Early Judaeo-Persian Tafsirs of Ezekiel: Text, Translation, Commentary, Vol. III: Grammar.##Henning, W. B. (1940-42). ‘Sogdian Loan-Words in New Persian’, Bsoas, Vol. X.##Horn, P. (1892). Grundriss der Neupersischen Etymologie (Sammlung Indogermanischer Worterbucher, IV), Strassburg: Karl J. Trubner.##Horn, p. (1901). ‘Neupersische Schriftsprache’, Grundriss der Iranischen Philologie, II band, Herausgegeben von wilh, Geiger und Ernest Kuhn, Strassburg, 1895-1901.##Hübschmann, H. (1895). Persische Studien, Strassburg: Verlage Von Karl J. Trübner.##Kellens, Jean (1995). Liste du Verbe Avestique, Avec un Appendice sur l’orthographe des Racines Avestiques par Eric Pirart, Wiesbaden: Reichert.##Kent, R. G. (1953). Old Persian: Grammar, Texts, Lexicon, New Haven: Connecticut.##Lazard, G. (1968). ‘La Dialectologie du Judeo-Persan’, Studies in Bibliography and Booklore, Spring, Paris.##Mackenzie, D. N. (1968). ‘An Early Jewish-Persian Argument’, Bsoas, Vol. XXXI, Part 2.##Mackenzie, D. N. (1971). A Concise Pahlavi Dictionary, London.##Mainz, E. (1977). ‘Vocabulaire Judeo-Persan’, Studia Iranica, Tome 6, faciculer.##Mayerhofer, Manfred (1992). Etymologisches Wörterbch des Altindoarischen, Vol. I: A-DH.##Mayerhofer, Manfred (1996). Etymologisches Wörterbch des Altindoarischen, Vol. II: N-H.##Mayerhofer, Manfred (2001). Etymologisches Wörterbch des Altindoarischen, Vol. III: Vorbemerkungen, Jünger Sprache, Register.##Morgenstierne, Georg (1927). An Etymological Vocabulary of Pashto (Skrifter Utgitt av det Norske Videnskapsakademi i Oslo, No. 3, Historisk-filosofiskKlasse), Oslo: Dybwad.##Paper, H. H. (1965 a). ‘The Vatican Judeo-Persian Pentateuch: Genesis’, Acta Orientalia, xxvIII 3-4.##Paper, H. H. (1965 b). ‘The Vatican Judeo-Persian Pentateuch: Numbers’, Acta Orientalia xxIx, 3-4.##Paper, H. H. (1965-66). ‘The Vatican Judeo-Persian Pentateuch: Exodus and Leviticus’, Acta Orientalia, xxIx, 1-2.##Paper, H. H. (1967). ‘Judeo-Persian Deverbatives in-šn and–št’, IIJ, x.##Paper, H. H. (1972). A Judeo-Persian Pentateuch, The Text of the Oldest Judeo-Persian Pentateuch Translation, British Museum Ms. Or. 5446, Jerusalem and Leiden.##Pokorny, J. (1994). Indogermanisches Etymologisches Wörterbuch. 2 Bände, Francke Verlag, Tübingen/ Basel.##Seligsohn, M. (1903). ‘The Hebrew-Persian MSS. of the British-Museum’, The Jewish Qarterly Report 15.##Shaked, Sh. (2003). ‘Early Judaeo-Persian Texts. With Notes on a Commentary to Genesise’, in Persian Origins, Early Judaeo-Persian and the Emergence of New Persian, Collected Papers of the Symposium, Gottingen 1999, Paul Ludwig (ed.), Wiesbaden.##Szemerenyi, O. (1977). Studies in the Kinship Terminology of the Indo-European Languages, Varia (AcIr 16).##Tregelles, S. P. (1907). Hebrew and Chaldee Lexiconto the Old Testament Scriptures, Samuel Bagster &amp; Sons, London.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				