<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>8</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Locating the Sassanid Mint Houses in the Province of Fars</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بازجستن ضراب‌خانه‌های ساسانیان در فارس</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>25</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>36</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1172</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>انصاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار/دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد بوشهر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>زرشناس</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;letter-spacing: -0.1pt;&quot;&gt;Being a hub of theological, political, economic, and business opportunities, the province of Pars in Southern Iran was considered as the most important province in Iran during Sassanid period (226–651). Its proximity to the Persian Gulf made Pars an important zone for transportation and trade by both land and sea, and its main products such as cotton and silk fabrics, hand-woven carpets, and pearls used to be exported to China and other distant countries. In addition, the high volume of coins found in this province has demonstrated the importance of mint houses in this region. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;letter-spacing: -0.1pt;&quot;&gt;The current paper has studied the mint houses of Pars region in Sassanid period. The findings of the current study confirmed the speculations about WLC designation. According to most coin experts WLC has remained unknown to date; however it has been suggested that it may refer to the city of “Borazjan” in Southern Fars; the idea that has been confirmed by the current paper.&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">استان پارس، در جنوب ایران، به لحاظ نقش خاستگاهی، مرکزیت دینی، سیاسی و موقعیت اقتصادی و تجاری، مهم‌ترین ایالت شاهنشاهی ساسانیان (226 - 651 م) محسوب می‌شد. تولیدات انبوه این ایالت، همچون پارچه‌های کتانی و ابریشمی یا فرش و مروارید که تا چین و سایر نواحی دوردست نیز صادر می‌شد و موقعیت جغرافیایی آن، در پس کرانۀ خلیج فارس، آن‌جا را به مکان مهمی برای حمل و نقل و تجارت زمینی و دریایی تبدیل کرده بود. رونق تجارت با سایر سرزمین‌ها موجب افزایش میزان ضرب سکه در آن ایالت شده بود و بسیاری تعداد سکه‌های مکشوفه در این ایالت حکایت از کثرت ضراب‌خانه‌هایی دارد که در این منطقه قرار داشته‌اند. در این پژوهش ضراب‌خانه‌های منطقة پارس در دورة ساسانیان بر اساس سکه‌های نبشته‌دار ساسانی بررسی شده‌اند و بر پایة شواهد موجود پیشنهادشده علامت اختصاری WLC، که به گفتة اکثریت سکه‌شناسان تاکنون ناشناس باقی مانده است، اشاره به شهر برازگان (برازجان) در جنوب ایالت پارس دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساسانیان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پارس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برازگان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضراب‌خانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خط پهلوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">علامت اختصاری شهرها</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1172_3fdc41601d21e560971de2d790d467ad.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
