<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>AZOFA: A New Approach to Teaching Persian to 
Non-Persian Speakers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آزوفا: رویکردی جدید در آموزش زبان فارسی به غیرفارسی‌زبانان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>51</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>70</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">112</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>صفاری‌مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present article refers to the writer’s twenty years of experience at the Institute for Humanities and Cultural Studies in the field of teaching Iranian language and culture to non-Persian speakers. The writer has set his teaching missions to Bosnia and South Korea universities as a basis for related research and has proceeded to put forth the principal problems and shortcomings of the field by studying the situation of teaching Persian language and positive outcome of responsible organizations. Then the formation of Azofa group during the recent years and the new approach of the Institute in the field has been propounded. According to the new approach, it is required in the first place that instruction of Persian language to non-Persian speakers and Iranian younger generation abroad be promoted vigorously by relying on modern pedagogic methods and cooperating with responsible organizations. In the second place, the propagation of Iranian culture and civilization which is part of the human cultural legacy should be defined as the more valuable target of instruction.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقالة حاضر به بیست سال تجربة نگارنده در پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی در حوزة ‌آموزش زبان و فرهنگ ایران به غیرفارسی‌زبانان پرداخته است. نگارنده مأموریت‌های آموزشی خود در دانشگاه‌های بوسنی و کرة ‌جنوبی را پایة تحقیقات مربوط قرار داده و، با بررسی وضعیت آموزش زبان فارسی و عملکرد مثبت نهادهای متولی، به طرح مسائل و کاستی‌های عمده پرداخته؛ آنگاه شکل‌گیری بخش آزوفا در سال‌های اخیر و رویکرد جدید پژوهشگاه در این حوزه را مطرح ساخته است. براساس این رویکرد، اولاً لازم است که سطح آموزش زبان فارسی به غیرفارسی‌زبانان و فرزندان ایرانی دور از وطن، با تکیه بر روش‌های نوین آموزشی و همکاری با نهادهای متولی، به‌طور جدی ارتقا داده شود و، ثانیاً، ترویج جذابیت‌های فرهنگی و تمدنی ایرانیان به‌عنوان بخشی از میراث فرهنگ بشری هدف والاتر آموزش زبان تعریف شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">: آموزش زبان فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">میراث فرهنگی ایران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نهادهای متولی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شیوه‌های آموزشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جذابیت‌های صوتی‌تصویری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_112_ca9311410686f982ecda7156da832568.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
