<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>11</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Ecological Approach in Linguistic Researches</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رویکرد زیست‌محیطی در پژوهش‌های زبان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>231</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>243</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2081</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فریبا</FirstName>
					<LastName>قطره</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی گروه زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه الزهرا، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمیده</FirstName>
					<LastName>پشتوان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش‌آموخته رشته زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه الزهرا تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهناز</FirstName>
					<LastName>طالبی دستنایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری رشته زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه الزهرا تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Linguistic diversity, across socio-natural environments, reflects similarities and differences in ethnic groups’ views towards natural ecological phenomena. This diversity is driven by needs, cognition, culture, human-related and environmental factors. Lexicon, categorization, and classification in any given language, act differently with regard to interaction with ecology. Ecolinguistics emerged in 1990s as a new approach in language studies, which focuses on the interrelationship between a given language, and its users’ geographical and natural environment. This paper, aims to introduce Eco-linguistics, as well as its potentials in dialect-related research, highlighting the impact of natural environment on lexical, morphological, and syntactic differences among languages and dialects. The current paper, studies the relationship between Eco-linguistics approach, and Gilani and Semnani dialects from two different ecologies. The results reveal that, in the authors’ beliefs, this new approach can explain why the means of naming concepts and phenomena vary in dialects, how metaphors develop, and why regional–and local-dialects sometimes differ incredibly in terms of their lexicon and morpho-syntax. The answers eco-linguistics provides to these questions appear reasonable to a considerable extent.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">گوناگونی زبان‌‌شناختی محیط‌های طبیعی ـ اجتماعی منعکس‌کنندة شباهت‌ها و تفاوت‌های نگرش جامعه‌های زبانی مختلف به پدیده‌های طبیعی است و برآمده از شناخت، نیازها، فرهنگ و عوامل زیست‌محیطی و انسانی است. واژگان، مقوله‌بندی، و طبقه‌بندی‌  در هر زبانی در تعامل با محیط طبیعی آن زبان به شیوه‌ای متفاوت عمل می‌کنند. در این راستا، زبان‌‌شناسی زیست‌‌محیطی از دهة ١٩٩٠ به‌ عنوان یکی از گرایش‌‌های کاربردی در مطالعات زبان‌شناختی مطرح شد. این گرایش به بررسی روابط متقابل میان یک زبان خاص و محیط طبیعی ـ اجتماعی گویشوران آن زبان می‌‌پردازد. در این مقاله، برآنیم، ضمن معرفی زبان‌‌شناسی زیست‌‌محیطی، توان‌مندی بالقوة این رویکرد را در پژوهش‌های گویش‌محور نشان دهیم و تأثیر محیط زیست بر تفاوت‌‌های نحوی، صرفی و واژگانی میان زبان‌ها و گویش‌‌ها را بررسی کنیم. مقالة حاضر، با رویکرد مقایسه‌ای، به بررسی ارتباط زیست‌محیط با دو گویش گیلانی و سمنانی،‌ از دو اقلیم متفاوت، می‌پردازد. نتایج حاصل از این پژوهش نشان می‌‌دهد بسیاری از ویژگی‌‌های زبان، از جمله نام‌‌گذاری مفاهیم و پدیده‌‌ها و چگونگی شکل‌‌گیری استعاره‌‌ها و هم‌چنین تفاوت‌های موجود در گویش‌های منطقه‌ای (و حتی محلی)، از منظر زبان‌شناسی زیست‌محیطی، قابل توضیح است و این رویکرد نو می‌تواند پاسخ قابل قبولی برای تفاوت‌های صرفی-نحوی و واژگانی گویش‌های منطقه‌ای و محلی ارائه نماید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌شناسی زیست‌محیطی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محیط زیست طبیعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گویش منطقه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شناخت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صرف زیست‌محیطی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2081_b5422b526a2c7c35b2d55d9eb0847410.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
