<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>13</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>IndefP as a New Functional Category in Persian</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>معرفی یک گروه نقشی جدید در نحو زبان فارسی؛ گروه نقشی نکره</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>17</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>46</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2491</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی معصوم</LastName>
<Affiliation>زبانشناسی دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>مهدوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>زبان و ادبیات فارسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The so-called indefiniteness morpheme or enclitic /i:/ in Persian has been substantially studied from morphological and semantic points of view, but rarely given full analysis in syntactic surveys. Mostly considered as an affix attached to the head noun in NP/DP, it is seldom considered as independent or significant in syntactic representations. In generative syntax, especially in the Minimalist Program, functional categories have been suggested as elements which regulate the grammatical relations among lexical categories. Formerly, the functional category Ezafe has been established above nominal heads in Persian NPs. The present study, introduces IndefP as a functional category in Persian for the first time, and seeks to give structures containing the /i:/ element the fullest analysis they have ever enjoyed. Evidence is provide as to depict a full minimalist projection for this category and analyze complex structures headed by this functional item. Indefinite Phrase is shown to be a head-last projection which selects NP/DPs as its complement and accepts various structures (CPs, PPs or APs) as its adjuncts. It is further shown that this analysis is not limited to nominal structures in A-positions and is also extendable to those appearing in A-bar positions as sentence adverbs attached to the (maximal or intermediate) projection of T.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">عنصر /i:/ که در فارسی به عنوان تکواژ یا واژه­بست نکره شناخته می­شود در پژوهش­های مختلف ساختواژی و معناشناختی بررسی شده­است. امّا در تحلیل­های نحوی جایگاه خاصی برای آن درنظر گرفته نمی­شود. در دستور زایشی، مقوله­های نقشی به عنوان عناصری که جایگاه و ارتباط دستوری میان مقوله­های واژگانی را مشخص می­کنند مطرح شده­اند. پیشتر گروه اضافه به عنوان یک گروه نقشی در بالای اسم در فارسی مطرح شده است. در این پژوهش برای نخستین بار تحلیل کاملی از عملکرد عنصر نکره به عنوان یک گروه نقشی مبتنی بر برنامه کمینه­گرا ارائه و استدلال می­شود که می­توان بسیاری از سازه­های اسمی (NP/DP) را به عنوان گروه نقشی نکره (IndefP) نمایش داد. بر این اساس، مقوله یادشده یک مقوله نقشی هسته­پایانی در زبان فارسی است که اسم یا گروه­های اسمی را به عنوان متمّم و انواع سازه­های وصفی (بند موصولی، گروه حرف­اضافه­ای، گروه صفتی) را به عنوان ادات می­پذیرد. گروه نقشی نکره علاوه بر جایگاه­های موضوع، خود می­تواند در جایگاه غیر موضوع و به عنوان ادات به گروه (بیشینه یا درونی) زمان T افزوده شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نکره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مقوله نقشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گروه اسمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گروه حرف تعیین</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2491_a4cadecb02cfd5ed93fe845a28d89bd4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
