<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1389</YEAR>
<VOL>1</VOL>
<NO>1</NO>
<MOSALSAL>1</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>107</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>سنگ نبشتة شیلهَک ـ این شوشینَک از سولقان شهرکرد</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Inscription of Shilhak- inshushinak Suleghan, Shahr-e Kord</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در این مقاله، متن سنگ‌نبشته‌ای از شیلهک-این‌شوشینک، فرمانروای بزرگ ایلام (حدود 1150 تا 1120 پ م)، ارائه شده است. در این سنگ‌نبشتة 28 سطری، همانند دیگر نوشته هایش، وی نخست خود و خانواده‌اش را معرّفی کرده و از بهر همگی تندرستی و زندگانی دیر پایی را آرزو می کند. سپس از برپایی این سنگ نبشته، نوشتن نام خود بر آن، بخشش زمینی به کسی که آیین ویژة دینی را برای او انجام داده است، سخن می گوید و سرانجام هزینه‌های برپایی آیین را بر می شمارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The text of the Inscription by Shilhak-inshushinak, the great ruler of Elam (c.1150- 1120 BC), is presented in this paper. In this 28-line inscription, as in his other inscription, the Ruler, introducing himself and his family, wishes them good health and long life. The text then explains the cause of the making of the inscription, granting a land to a person who has performed ritual service for him, and finally the expenditure of this ceremony.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>10</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عبد‌المجید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ارفعی</Family>
						<NameE>abdolmajid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Arfaie</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>پژوهشگر فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی آسیای غربی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>پژوهشگر فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی آسیای</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.majid@arfaee.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سنگ‌نبشته</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ایلامی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شیلهک ـ این‌شوشینک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شکل‌هجا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی چند اصطلاح فارسی میانه دربارة خانواده</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Study of Some Family Terms in Middle Persian</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در نوشته‌های فارسی میانه زردشتی یا پهلوی، چند واژه دربارة خانواده محل بحث و جدل است. در مقالة زیر، طرحی برای بررسی آنها و ارتباط این واژه‌ها با یکدیگر و با ساحت خانوادة ساسانی می‌آید.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In Zoroastrian and Pahlavi texts of the Middle Persian, there are some family words that have been the subject of much controversy. This paper suggests a pattern to examine them as well as their relation with each other and with the family structure.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>11</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>22</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>کتایون</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مزداپور</Family>
						<NameE>katayoun</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mazdapour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mazdapour@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دوده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دوده‌مان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دوده‌سالار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پادشاه زنی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چکرزنی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خانوادة دوران ساسانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>کتیبه‌ای سُغدی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Sogdian Inscription</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در فاصلة سال‌های 1966-1967 از چند دیوارنگاره در کنار کاودیوار (تاقچة محرابی) در تالار اصلی اتاق1، ‌بخش 22، در پنجکنت پرده برداشته شد. در این دیوارنگاره‌ها، بخش‌هایی از قصه‌ای ناشناخته در صحنه‌های متوالی به تصویر درآمده است. در صحنۀ‌ نهایی، پیروزی قهرمان داستان در برابر دروازۀ دژی ترسیم شده است. روی این دژ، کتیبه‌ای به زبان سغدی، مشتمل بر 12 سطر نوشتة عمودی، قرار دارد. متن کتیبه در شرح ماجرای قصه است که به احتمال بسیار به حلقۀ داستانی ذِوِنک تعلق دارد. در این پژوهش، پس از قرائت متن سغدی این کتیبه، آوانوشت و برگردان فارسی آن ارائـه خواهـد شد. در پایان، سبـک خاص دیـوارنگاره‌های سـغدی به‌اجمال بررسی می‌شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>During 1966-67, some murals were unveiled in Panjkant, beside the altar niche of the room 1, the major hall, section 22. Parts of an unknown story are serially illustrated on this wall, ending with the victory of the hero in the gate of the fortress. A Sogdian Inscription with 12 vertical lines in the fortress refers to the content of the story that most probably belongs to the circle Thewenak stories. In this research paper, after reading the text of this Sogdian Inscription, the writer gives its transcription as well as its Persian translation. The paper concludes with the studying of the mural’s style.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>23</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>36</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زرشناس</Family>
						<NameE>zohreh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zarshenas</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان سغدی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کتیبه‌</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دیوارنگاره</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هنرنگارگری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>‌ ادبیات شفاهی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی متون مانوی دربارة مدت آتش‌سوزی در پایان جهان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Time of the Doomsday Fire According to Manichaean Literature</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در اسطورۀ آفرینش مانوی رقم 1468 سال، که مدت آتش‌سوزی در پایان جهان مانوی را نشان می‌دهد، رقمی نجومی است که مانی، با آگاهی از اطلاعات نجومی زمان خود، به احتمال زیاد، آن را معادل یک دورۀ خورشیدی به‌حساب آورده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In Manichaean Myth of Creation, the figure 1486 is the year of the Fire at the End of the Universe. This figure, which was found out by Mani from the astrological information, is possibly equal to a Sun Period.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>37</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>42</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زنده‌یاد احترام‌السادات</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسینی</Family>
						<NameE>ehteramsadat</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hoseyni</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد‌یار سابق سازمان اسناد و کتابخانه ملی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد‌یار سابق سازمان اسناد و کتابخانه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مانویت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اسطورۀ مانوی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نجوم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رقم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>قاعده‌کاهی در نثر گلشیری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Rule Reduction in Golshiri’s Writing</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>توجه به ادبیات داستانی معاصر و نقد و بررسی آن به کمک شیوه‌هایی به‌جز نقد سنتی که تا به امروز بیشتر مورد توجه بوده است، دریچه‌های تازه‌ای را بر روی ادب‌دوستان می‌گشاید. در این مقاله، نظریات مکتب فرمالیسم روس و لیچ، زبان‌شناس انگلیسی، مـورد توجـه قرار گرفته است، کـه از دیدگـاه ادبـی و زبان‌شناسی به آثار ادبی نگاه می‌کنند، چند اثر از هوشنگ گلشیری، نویسندۀ معاصر، پژوهش و بررسی شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The recent approach of criticism in the Iranian contemporary literature, based on new methods of criticism, opposite to that of traditional one, has brought a new literary outlook. Drawing on the views of the Russian Formalists and G.Leech, English linguist, who use linguistic values in dealing with literature, the writer studies the linguistics characteristics of some works of Houshang Golshiri.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>43</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>56</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>گلریز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صالح</Family>
						<NameE>golriz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Saleh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>golriz_s@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرمالیسم روس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خود کاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>برجسته سازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قاعده‌کاهی (هنجارگریزی ) قاعده‌افزایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ساخت موضوعی کلمات مشتق در زبان فارسی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Argument Structure of the Persian Derivational Words</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>ساخت موضوعـی بـه فهرست موضوع‌هـای یک محمـول اطلاق می‌شود. مثلاً، فعل «خورد» دو موضوع و فعل «داد» سه موضوع در ساخت موضوعی خود دارد. معمولاً ساخت موضوعی افعال پس از افزوده‌شدن یک وند اشتقاقی به آنها تغییر می‌کند، به‌گونه‌ای که ساخت موضوعی مشتق حاصله با ساخت موضوعی کلمۀ پایه متفاوت است. در مقالة حاضر، ساخت موضوعی مشتقات فعلی زبان فارسی و تأثیر وند افزایی بر ساخت موضوعی کلمة پایه را مطالعه می‌کنیم. چارچوب نظری این مقاله نظریة لیبر است که ساخت موضوعی هر کلمه را فرافکنی از ساختار معنایی ـ واژگانی آن می‌داند و معتقد است که، برای مطالعة ساخت موضوعی هر کلمه یا تغییرات وارده بر آن، باید ساختار معنایی‌ـ واژگانی آن را مطالعه کرد. ما نیز تأثیر وندافزایی بر ساخت موضوعی کلمة پایه را از طریق بررسی تأثیر آن بر ساختار معنایی‌ـ واژگانی آن کلمه مطالعه می‌کنیم و نشان می‌دهیم که فقط وندهایی ساخت موضوعی کلمة پایه را تغییر می‌دهند که در ساختار معنایی ـ واژگانی آن کلمه تغییری ایجاد کرده باشند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Argument Structure (AS) of a Predicate is a list of its arguments. For example the Persian verb xord (ate) in &quot;Ali sib ra xord.&quot; Has two arguments, while the verb dād (gave) in &quot;Ali sib rā be Zahrā dād.&quot; has three arguments: Ali, Sib, and Zahrā. The argument structure of a verb is usually changed by affixation, so that the argument structure of a derived word is different form that of the stem. This paper intends to study the argument structure of Persian verbal derivations and the effect of affixation on the argument structure of the base. The theoretical framework of this paper is Lieber&#039;s view (1992) which states that the argument structure of each word is a projection of the Lexical Conceptual Structure (LCS) of that word. So the Study of AS of a word and the changes made in it must be done according to the LCS and the changes made in it. This paper studies the effect of affixation on the argument structure of a word through the changes it may have on the LCS of that word. It will also illustrate that only those affixes that changes the LCS of the word will affect the AS of the base; it means the affixes which do not have any effects on the LCS of a word have no changes on its AS.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>57</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>74</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد‌مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>واحدی لنگرودی</Family>
						<NameE>mohammad mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Vahedi Langrudi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد‌یار دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد‌یار دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قادری</Family>
						<NameE>mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghaderi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد زبانشناسی همگانی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد زبانشناسی همگانی، دانشگاه تربیت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ghaderim@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساخت موضوعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساختار معنایی ـ واژگانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>موضوع</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اشتقاق</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی عوامل برون‌زبانی مؤثر بر پذیرش نوواژه‌ها</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Effect of Non-linguistic Factors on the Acceptance of Neologisms</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مقالۀ حاضر گزارشی است از نتایج یک بررسی دربارۀ پذیرش نوواژه‌های عمومی، مصوب فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی، با همکاری 450 پاسخگو در سه استان (تهران ،اصفهان وکرمان). مبنای نظری این بررسی الگوی انتشار نوآوری‌های رابرت ال. کوپر است که به حوزۀ برنامه‌ریزی زبان مربوط می‌شود. پژوهشی میدانی درمورد مهم‌ترین عوامل غیرزبانی است که بر انتشار نوواژه‌های مصوب فرهنگستان اثر می‌گذارد. فرض بر این است که، در جامعۀ آماری مورد نظر، به‌عنوان مخاطبان نوواژه‌های مصوب فـرهنگستـان، بین سطوح پیشنهادی کـوپـر دربارۀ نوآوری‌های ارتباطی، که عبارت‌اند از: آگاهی، ارزیابی، دانش و کاربرد، رابطه وجود دارد. چگونگی این روابط از طریق شیوه‌های آماری توصیفی و استنباطی گوناگون و با استفاده از پرسشنامه به‌دست آمد. بر پایۀ نتایج به‌دست آمده، بین دو عامل آگاهی و دانش پاسخگویان و نیز بین دو عامل ارزیابی و کاربرد نوواژه‌ها همبستگی مثبت دیده شد. علاوه بر این، بین دو عامل آگاهی و سن و نیز دو عامل دانش و تحصیلات پاسخگویان همبستگی معنی‌دار مثبت وجود دارد. در این مقاله، با کشف و توصیف این روابط، راهکارهایی برای کمک به تسریع فرایندهای پذیرش و انتشار نوواژه‌ها پیشنهاد می‌شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>This study aims to examine the most important non-linguistic factors influencing the acceptance of neologisms approved by Academy of Persian Language and Literature, called Farhangestan, among Persian speakers in Iran. The theoretical basis used for this research was the diffusion of innovation model devised by Robert Leon Cooper.To get the goal, the criterion variables of adoption in the speech community were evaluated by questionnaire in three provinces.The different descriptive and inference statistics were used to determine the correlation between the mentioned variables: awareness, evaluation, knowledge and usage, in relationship to each other and to background ones: age, sex and education. The main results gained in this study show that there is a positive significant correlation between the awareness and knowledge and between evaluation and usage as well along with some other subordinate results. Above all, We came to this conclusion that Farhangestan , as the greatest language planner in Iran, can influence the awareness variable so that the proficiency and knowledge of using their neologisms by the potential adopters can be monitored. On the other hand, it can put effect on evaluation to promote frequent usage of neologisms. All these lead to diffusing the linguistic innovations, that is, the approved neologisms.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>75</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>107</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>طاهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>احمدی‌پور</Family>
						<NameE>tahereh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ahmadipour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد‌یار زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه ولی‌عصر (عج) - رفسنجان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد‌یار زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه ولی‌عص</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>tahereh_ahmadipour@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>برنامه‌ریزی زبان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوواژه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پذیرش نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انتشار نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرهنگستان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				