<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>9</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study of Simin Daneshvar’s Stylistic and Personality Features 
From SFL Perspective</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی ویژگی‌‌های سبکی و شخصیتی سیمین دانشور با رویکرد زبان‌‌شناسی نقش‌‌گرا</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>19</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>34</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1434</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">.</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طاهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>ایشانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار زبان و ادبیات فارسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the important issues in systemic functional linguistics is metafunction. In this viewpoint, all of languages have been formed by three broad metafunctions: ideational, interpersonal and textual. The ideational metafunction is divided into two functions: experiential and logical. In experiential function, experiences of the world are represented through the language. In SFL view, a component of the ideational metafunction is transitivity as a property of clauses. It is used to specify the different types of processes in clauses. So, as transitivity encodes our experiences, by studying and inquiring processes existing in the text and their frequency, we can understand thought, experiences and inner world of an author. Then, in this paper, in addition to inquiring the processes of some short stories of Simin Daneshvar, frequency and percentage of all kinds of processes will be demonstrated as a stylistic indicative of her work and also considering these frequencies, her personality will be revealed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از مباحث مهمی که در زبان‌‌شناسی نظام‌‌مند نقش‌‌گرا مطرح می‌‌شود «فرانقش» است. در این رویکرد، همۀ‌‌ زبان‌‌ها حول دو محور اساسیِ معنایی، یعنی معنای اندیشگانی و معنای بینافردی، شکل گرفته‌‌اند. از سوی دیگر، فرانقشِ اندیشگانی به دو کارکرد تجربی و منطقی تقسیم می‌‌شود. در کارکرد تجربی، کاربرِِ زبان تجربیات دنیای بیرونِ خود را از طریق زبان بیان می‌کند. محصول این کارکرد، در جمله، گذرایی است که مؤلّفه‌‌ای از فرانقشِ اندیشگانی و مشخصه‌‌ای از جمله است و برای مشخص کردن انواع متفاوت فرایندها در جمله به کار می‌‌رود. بنابراین، باتوجه به این‌که گذرایی، براساس زبان‌‌شناسی نقش‌‌گرای هلیدی، رمزگذاری تجربیات ما از فرایندهاست و هم‌چنین، از آن‌‌جا که ارتباط تنگاتنگ ذهن و زبان بر کسی پوشیده نیست، می‌‌توان، با بررسی انواع فرایندهای موجود در افعال و تعیین بسامد و تکرار آن‌‌ها، تا حدودی از افکار و دنیای درون صاحبان آثار ادبی آگاه شد. به همین دلیل، در مقالۀ حاضر، ضمن بررسی افعال موجود در داستان‌‌های کوتاه سیمین دانشور، با این رویکرد و با روش تحلیلی ـ آماری، بسامد و درصد انواع فرایندها، به عنوان شاخصی سبکی، نشان داده‌‌ شده و هم‌چنین، با تکیه بر این بسامدها، طرز تفکر و نگرش این نویسنده‌‌ مشخص شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌‌شناسی نظام‌‌مند نقش‌‌گرا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرانقش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گذرایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">داستان کوتاه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیمین دانشور</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1434_d0b2c3572fe2a4b86a7ed60e9559d6fa.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
