<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1393</YEAR>
<VOL>5</VOL>
<NO>10</NO>
<MOSALSAL>10</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>220</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>فایل کامل مجله شماره 10 (تمام مقالات)‌پاییز و زمستان 93</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Full text of Magazine (include of all article) .No.10</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>224</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>استعاره‌های مفهومی در حوزۀ شرم با استناد به شواهدی از شعر کلاسیک فارسی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Conceptual Metaphors of Shame in Persiam Classic Poetry</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مقالۀ حاضر تحلیلی از استعاره‌های مفهومی شرم، با استناد به اشعار کلاسیک فارسی قرن ششم تا دهم قمری، به دست می‌دهد. چهارچوب نظری این پژوهش، کتاب استعاره و عواطف: تأثیر زبان، فرهنگ و بدن در احساس نوشتة زولتان کووچش (2010) است. سؤال اصلی مقاله این است که در زبان فارسی استعاره‌های مفهومی شرم بر مبنای کدام حوزه‌های مبدأ ساخته می‌شوند؟ هدف از پاسخ‌گویی به این سؤال، یافتن مفهوم کانونیِ شرم در زبان فارسی با استناد به شواهدی از شعر کلاسیک فارسی است. به این منظور، ابتدا، دُرج 3 (کتاب‌خانۀ الکترونیک شعر فارسی)، «پیکرۀ زبانی گروه فرهنگ‌نویسی فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی»، و تارنمای گنجور (آثار سخن‌سرایان پارسی‌گو) با کلیدواژه‌های «شرم» و «حیا» جست‌وجو شد. در نتیجۀ این جست‌وجو ابیاتی که در آن‌ها مفهوم شرم در قالب استعارۀ مفهومی دریافت می‌شد گردآوری گردید. بر اساس روشی که توضیح داده شد، 220 شاهد به دست آمد. در مرحلۀ بعد، با تحلیل استعاره‌های مفهومی حوزه‌های مبدأ استخراج شد. در نتیجۀ این بررسی، ده اسم‌نگاشت برای استعارۀ مفهومیِ شرم به دست آمد که در قالب یک شبکه با هم در ارتباط‌اند و مفهوم شرم را در زبان فارسی می‌سازند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>This paper surveys the conceptual metaphors of shame in Persian classical poetry of Iraqi style. The theoretical framework of this research is based on Metaphor and Emotion: Language, culture and body in human feeling (Kovecses 2010). Main question of the research is: What are the source domains of the conceptual metaphors of shame in Persian? The research aim is to find the core metaphor of shame in Persian with reference to Persian classical poetry. In doing so the DORJ 3 and Language Corpus of the Department of Lexicography in the Academy of Language and Literature were searched with the keywords of “sharm” and “haya”. Instances of Persian classical Poetry were found in which “shame” was understood in a conceptual metaphor. In this way 220 metaphorical structures were found and analyzed. As the result 10 name of the mappings were found for the conceptual metaphor of shame and a network was presented which apparently constitutes the concept of shame in Persian.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>20</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آزیتا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>افراشی</Family>
						<NameE>Azita</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Afrashi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.afrashi.ling@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدمهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مقیمی‌زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammadmahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moghimizadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکترای زبان و ادبیات فارسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکترای زبان و ادبیات فارسی، پژوهشگاه علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.moghimizadeh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>استعاره‌های مفهومی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حوزۀ عواطف</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شرم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شعر کلاسیک فارسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نگاشت استعاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>افراشی، آزیتا، تورج حسامی، و بئاتریس سالاس (1391). «بررسی استعاره‌های جهتی در زبان‌های اسپانیایی و فارسی»، مجلۀ پژوهش‌های زبان و ادبیات تطبیقی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، دورة سوم، ش 4.##Afrashi, A. (2011). “Semantic Analysis of Shame in Persian: A cognitive and Cultural Perspective”, Emotion, Cognition, Communication conference, 23-25 June, University of Cyprus and Sorbonne Nouvelle, Nicosia.##Allan, K. (2008). Metaphor and Metonymy: A diachronic approach, Uk: Wiley-Blackwell, Philsoc Society.##Benedict, R. (1946). The Chrysanthemum and the sword: patterns of Japanese culture, Boston: Houghton Mifflin.##Buck, C. D. (1971 [1949]). A Dictionary of Selected Synonyms in Principal Indo-European Languages, A Contribution to the History of Ideas, Chicago: University of Chicago Press.##Eisenberg, N. (2000). “Emotion, Regulation and moral development”, Annual Review of Psychology, 51.##Emanatian, M. (1995). “Metaphor and the expression of emotion: The value of cross-cultural perspectives”, Metaphor and symbolic activity, 10.##Geeraerts, D. and Stefan Grondelaers (1995). “Looking back at anger: Cultural traditions and Metaphorical patterns”, in J. Taylor and R. McAaury (eds.), Language and the Cognitive Construal of the World, Berlin: Gruyter.##Gevart, C. (2001 a). “Anger in old and middle English: a hot topic?”, Belgian Essays on Language and Literature.##Gevart, C. (2001 b). “The Anger is Heat Question: detecting cultural influence on the conceptualization of anger through diachronic corpus analysis”, Proceedings of the self meeting.##Gibbs, R. W. Jr. (1994). The Poetics of Mind: Figurative Thought, Language and Understanding, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Goddard, C. (2011). Semantic Analysis: A Practical Introduction, Oxford: Oxford University Press.##Grady, J. E. (2007). ”Metaphor“, in The Oxford Handbook of Cognitive Linguistics, ed. Dirk Geeraerts and Hubert Cuyckens, Oxford: Oxford University Press.##Holland, D. and Andrew Kipnis (1995). ‘‘The not-so-egotistic aspects of American self’’, in J. A. Russell et al. (eds.), Everyday conceptions of emotion.##Huang, Sh. (2002). “Tsou is different: A Cognitive perspective on language, emotion and body”, Cognitive Linguistics, 13-2.##Johnson, Mark (1987). The body in the mind: The bodily basis of meaning, imagination, and reason, Chicago: The University of Chicago Press.##Johnson, Mark (1993). Moral Imagination, Chicago: The University of Chicago Press.##Karen Caplovitz Barretta, Carolyn Zahn-waxlerb and Pamela M. Cole. (1993). “Avoiders versus amenders: Implications for the investigation of guilt and shame during toddlerhood”, Cognition and Emotion, 7.##King, B. (1989). The conceptual structure of emotional experience in Chinese, Unpublished doctoral dissertation, The Ohio State University.##Kovecses, Zolta´n (1986). Metaphors of anger, pride, and love: A lexical approach to the structure of concepts, Amsterdam: John Benjamins.##Kovecses, Zolta´n (1988). “The language of love: The semantics of passion”, in convers ational English, Lewisburg, PA: Bucknell University Press.##Kovecses, Zolta´n (1990). Emotion concepts, New York: Springer-Verlag.##Kovecses, Zolta´n (1991). “A linguist’s quest for love”, Journal of Social and Personal Relationships, 8.##Kovecses, Zolta´n (1995). Anger: Its language, conceptualization, and physiology in the light of cross-cultural evidence, in J. Taylor and R. E. MacLaury (eds.), Language and the cognitive construal of the world, Berlin: Mouton de Gruyter.##Kovecses, Zolta´n (2000). Metaphor and Emotion, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Kovecses, Zolta´n (2008). “Universality and Variation in the use of Metaphor”, Selected papers from the 2006 and 2007 Stockholm Metaphor Festivals, eds. N. L. Johannesson &amp; D. C. Minugh, Stockholm University, Department of English.##Kovecses, Zolta´n (2010). Metaphor and Emotion: Language Culture and Body in Human Feeling, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Lakoff, George (1993). The contemporary theory of metaphor, in A. Ortony (ed.), Metaphor and thought, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Lakoff, George and Mark Johnson (1980). Metaphors we live by, Chicago: The University of Chicago Press.##Lakoff, George and Mark Turner (1989). More than cool reason: A field guide to poetic metaphor, Chicago: The University of Chicago Press.##Lakoff, George and Zolta´n Kovecses (1987). “The cognitive model of anger inherent in American English”, in D. Holland and N. Quinn (eds.), Cultural models in language and thought, New York: Cambridge University Press.##Lakoff, George. (1987). Women, fire, and dangerous things: What categories reveal about the mind, Chicago: The University of Chicago Press.##Langacker, Ronald (1991). Foundations of cognitive grammar: Practical applications, Vol. 2, Stanford: Stanford University Press.##Langacker, Ronald. (1987). Foundations of cognitive grammar: Theoretical prerequisites, Vol. 1, Stanford: Stanford University Press.##Lascaratou. C. (2007). The Language of Pain, Amesterdam: John Benjamins Publications.##Matsuki, K. (1995). Metaphors of anger in Japanese, in J. Taylor and R. E. MacLaury (eds.), Language and the cognitive construal of the world, Berlin: Mouton de Gruyter.##Nubiola, J. (2000). ”El valor cognitivo de las metáforas“, Pamplona: P. Pérez-Ilzarbe y R. Lázaro, eds., Verdad, bien y belleza. Cuando los filósofos  hablan de los valores, Cuadernos de Anuario Filosófico, No. 103.##Ortiz Díaz Guerra, María Jesús (2009). La Metáfora Visual Incorporada: Aplicación de la Teoría Integrada de la Metáfora Primaria a un corpus audiovisual, Alicante: Universidad de Alicante, Departamento de Comunicación y Psicología Social.##Pape, Christina (1995). Die konzeptuelle Metaphorisierung von Emotionen: Untersuchtam Beispiel von shame and embarrassment im Amerikanischen Englisch, Unpublished master’s thesis, University of Hamburg.##Sweetser, Eve. (1990). From etymology to semantics, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Taylor, John R. and Thandi G. Mbense (1998). Red dogs and rotten mealies: How Zulus talk about anger. in Angeliki Athanasiadou and Elzbieta Tabakowska (eds.), Speaking of emotion: Conceptualisation and expression, Berlin: Mouton de Gruyter.##Turner, Mark. (1987). Death Is the Mother of Beauty, Mind, Metaphor, Criticism, Chicago: The University of Chicago Press.##Wierzbicka ,A (1993) “Reading human faces: emotion components and universal semantics”, Pragmatics and Cognition, 1.##Wierzbicka, A (1990). “The semantics of emotions: fear and its relatives in English”, Australian Journal of Linguistics (special issue on the semantics of emotions) 10 (2)##Wierzbicka, A. (1986). “Human emotions: universal or culture-specific?”, American Anthropologist, 88. 3.##Wierzbicka, A. (1994). “Emotion, language, and ‘cultural scripts’”, in Shinobu Kitayama and Hazel Rose Markus, eds. Emotion and culture: Empirical studies of mutual influence. Washington, DC: American Psychological Association.##Wierzbicka, A. (1995). “Emotion and facial expression: a semantic perspective”, Culture and Psychology, 1 (2).##Wierzbicka, A. (1999). Emotion across Languages and Cultures: Diversity and Universals, Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Yu, Ning (1995). “Metaphorical expressions of anger and happiness in English and Chinese”, in Metaphor and Symbolic Activity, Psychology Press, Vol. 10, 2.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نگاهی تازه به کتیبة پهلوی آذرشب مشهور به نیروگاه سیکل ترکیبی (کازرون چهارده)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Fresh Look on the Pahlawi Inscription of Azarshab
Known as Niroogahe Sicle Tarkibi (Kazeroon fourteen)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>کتیبة پهلوی «آذرشب»، مشهور به «نیروگاه سیکل ترکیبی (کازرون چهارده)»، یکی از سنگ مزارهای بازمانده از اواخر دورۀ ساسانی (یعنی سال 6 یزدگردی برابر با ششمین سال جلوس یزدگرد، آخرین شاه ساسانی) است که در سال 1384، هنگام خاک‌‌برداری از اطراف برج نیروگاه سیکل ترکیبی در شرق کازرون، کشف شد. محتوای این گونه کتیبه‌ها بیش‌تر معرفی آرامگاه یا دخمۀ درگذشته و ذکر نام او و پدر او یا کسی که دخمه را برای او سفارش داده و نیز طلب آمرزش برای متوفا است. کتیبۀ مذکور به شکل ستونی مکعب مستطیلی است و نوشته‌های پهلوی در دو طرف ستون و در عرض آن نگاشته شده است. در این مقاله، پیش‌نهادی تازه برای عنوان کتیبه (آذرشب به جای سیکل ترکیبی!) و خوانش و ترجمۀ آن ارائه شده است. هم‌چنین، خوانشی برای چند واژه که پیش از این خوانده نشده پیش‌نهاد شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The Pahlawi Inscription of Azarshab known as Niroogahe Sicle Tarkibi (Kazeroon fourteen) is one of the late Sasanian gravestones (iethe year 6 of Yazdgerdi, according to the sixth year of Yazdegerd reign,the last Sassanid king). It have been discovered in the year 1384 (H.) during the excavation near the combined cycle power plant tower In East Kazeroon. The content of the such inscriptions are to in troduce the Dakhma orgravestonesof the deceased and his father and the name of person who ordered to build the gravestones and asked forgiveness for the deceased. The inscription is in the form of a rectangular cube of side columns and the Pahlawi text is written on either side of it. In this paper, first I have proposed a new reading for the title &quot;Azarshab&quot; instead Sicletarkibi!, then I have suggeste dreading of a few words that were not previously read.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>21</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>29</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جعفری دهقی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahmoud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jaafari Dehaghi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، دانشکدة ادبیات و علوم انسانی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، دانشکدة</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mdehaghi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کتیبه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سنگ مزار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پهلوی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آذرشب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کازرون چهارده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ابراهیمی، آزاده (1387). «بررسی کتیبه‌های سنگ مزار پهلوی»، پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه تهران.##استروناخ، دیوید (1379). پاسارگاد، ترجمۀ حمید خطیب شهیدی، تهران: سازمان میراث فرهنگی.##بریان، پی‌یر (1378). تاریخ امپراتوری هخامنشیان، ترجمۀ مهدی سمسار، تهران: علمی.##محمدحسین بن خلف تبریزی (1362). برهان قاطع، تصحیح محمد معین، تهران: امیرکبیر.##بویس، مری (1381). زردشتیان: باورها و آداب دینی آن‌ها، ترجمۀ عسکر بهرامی، تهران: ققنوس.##بویس، مری و فرانتز گرنر (1375). تاریخ کیش زردشت، جلد سوم: پس از اسکندر گجسته، ترجمۀ همایون صنعتی‌زاده، تهران: توس.##تفضلی، احمد (1376). تاریخ ادبیات ایران پیش از اسلام، تهران: سخن.##رضائی باغ‌بیدی، حسن (1384). «کتیبۀ پهلوی ـ کوفی برج لاجیم»، نامۀ ایران باستان 7، س 4، ش 1.##شرف‌الدین، سعیده (1379). چگونگی تدفین مردگان در عصر آهن در فلات مرکزی ایران، تهران: مؤسسۀ فرهنگی انتشاراتی زهد.##طلایی، حسن (1374). باستان‌شناسی و هنر ایران در هزارة قبل از میلاد، تهران: سمت.##قریب، بدرالزمان (1345). «کتیبه‌ای به خط پهلوی در چین»، مجلۀ دانشکدة ادبیات دانشگاه تهران، ج 14، ش 1.##کامبخش فرد، سیف‌الله (1377). گورخمره‌های اشکانی، تهران: مرکز نشر دانشگاهی.##مجیدزاده، یوسف (1370). تاریخ و تمدن ایلام، تهران: مرکز نشر دانشگاهی.##مزداپور، کتایون (1384). زردشتیان، تهران: دفتر پژوهش‌های فرهنگی.##نصرالله‌زاده، سیروس (1380). «کتیبه‌های یادبود و سنگ‌مزار پهلوی ساسانی (2)»، نامۀ پارسی 23، س 6، ش 4.##نصرالله‌زاده، سیروس و محسن جاوری (1381). «مزارنوشته‌هایی نویافته به پهلوی ساسانی از چشمه ناز سمیرم»، نامۀ ایران باستان 4، س 2، ش 2.##نصرالله‌زاده، سیروس (1385). کتیبه‌های پهلوی کازرون، کازرون: کازرونیه.##Frye R.N. (1970). “Funerary inscriptions in Pahlavi from Fars”, in M. Boyce and I. Gershevitch (eds.), W. B. Henning Memorial Volume, London: Asia Major Library, Lund Humphries.##Gignoux, Philippe (1972). Glossaire des Inscriptions Pehlevieset Parthes, London: Corpus Inscriptionum Iranicarum.##Gignoux, Philippe (1986). Iranisches Personen namenbuch, Band II, Wien: Mittel iranische Personennamen.##Godard, A. (1936). “Les tours de Ladjimet de Resget”, Athār-é Iran, I.##Daneshmand, Parsa (2015). “New Phraseology and Literary Style in the Babylonian Version of the Achaemenid Inscriptions”, in: Tradition and Innovation in the Ancient Near East, Proceedings of the 57th Rencontre Assyriologique International at Rome 4–8 July 2011, Edited by: alfonso a RCHIin collaboration with Armando Bramanti.##DeBlois, F. (1990). “The Middle Persian Inscription from Constantinople: Sasanian or Post-Sasanian?”, StudiaIranica, 19.##De Blois, F. (1993). “Middle-Persian Funerary Inscription from South-Western Iran”, Medioiranica: Proceedings of the International Colloquium Organized by the Katholieke Universiteit Leuven from the 21st to the 23rd of May 1990, ed. W. Skalmowski and A. Van Tongerloo, Leuven.##Stronach, D. (1978). Pasargadae, Oxford.##Tafazzoli, A. (1997). “Persian Translation of Pahlavi Inscription of Sange Mazar (Parishan Lake)”, Kelk 80/83.##Tafazzoli, A. (1991a). “Inscription de Takht-e Tāvus IV”, in Studia Iranica, 20.##Tafazzoli, A. (1991 b). “L’inscription funeraire de Kāzerun II (Parīšān)”, Studia Iranica, 20.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی کاربرد زبان‌های مازندرانی و فارسی در شهر جویبار</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Study of the Use of Mazandarani and Farsi in Jouybar</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی کاربرد زبان‌‌های فارسی و مازندرانی در بافت‌‌های تعاملی مختلف در میان گویش‌وران مازندرانی شهر جویبار است. پرسش اصلی این است که کاربرد زبان مازندرانی و فارسی، با توجه به متغیرهای سن و جنسیت در بافت‌‌های مختلف اجتماعی، چه تفاوت‌هایی دارند. نمونة آماری پژوهش حاضر 100 گویش‌ور جویباری (50 مرد و 50 زن) می‌باشند که خود به دو گروه 25 نفره، والدین (میانگین سنی 39 سال) و فرزندان (میانگین سنی 16 سال)، تقسیم و به روش نمونه‌‌گیری در دسترس انتخاب شده‌‌اند. داده‌های پژوهش با استفاده از پرسش‌نامة محقق‌ساخته در سال 1388 گردآوری شده و از آزمون‌‌های آماری غیر‌‌پارامتریک «کولموگورف ـ اسمیرنوف» و «خی‌دو» برای مقایسه استفاده شده است. بررسی پاسخ‌‌های ارائه‌شده نشان می‌دهد که به طور کلی گرایش به کاربرد زبان فارسی در میان مادران بیش‌تر از پدران و در میان دختران بیش‌تر از پسران است. بررسی تأثیر متغیر جنسیت در مجموع داده‌ها با استفاده از آزمون آماری خی‌‌دو نشان می‌‌دهد که تفاوت بین مردان و زنان در کاربرد زبان فارسی و مازندرانی در سطح P≤0/001 است. تفاوت کاربرد فارسی و مازندرانی بین والدین و فرزندان در سطح P≤0/001 معنادار است. در نمونۀ مورد بررسی در این پژوهش، تأثیر بافت بر کاربرد زبان معنادار نیست.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>This study aimes at investigating the use of Jouybari Dialect, a local dialect of Mazandarani, and Farsi among Parents and Children in different social contexts. The effect of gender and age on the use of these languages has been studied. The informants were 100 Jouybari parents and children (50 parents and 50 children), each group consisted of two subgroups (25 males and 25 females), whom were selected through convenience sampling. A researcher-made questionnaire was used for data gathering. Non-parametric analyses (Kolmogorov-Smirnov and Chi-Square were used to compare the data. Findings show that in general the use of Persian among female members of each group is more than males, and Chi-Square analysis shows that the difference between males and females is meaningful (P≤0/001). Also, regarding the age variable the analysis reveals that the difference in language use between parents and children is meaningful (P≤0/001). The context does not have any significant effect on language use.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>31</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>50</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رمضانی</Family>
						<NameE>Ahmad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ramezani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار پژوهشگاه مطالعات آموزش و پرورش</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار پژوهشگاه مطالعات آموزش و پرورش</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ahmaderamezani@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آتوسا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رستم‌بیک تفرشی</Family>
						<NameE>Atoosa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rostambeik Tafreshi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار پژوهشکدة زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار پژوهشکدة زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>atoosa.rostambeik@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>خدیجه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>واسو جویباری</Family>
						<NameE>Khadijeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Vasoo Jouybari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد زبان‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه الزهرh</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد زبان‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه الزهرh</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>vasoo52@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان مازندرانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان فارسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بافت اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جنسیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شهر جویبار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کاربرد زبان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>امام، عباس (1377). «جنبه‌‌هایی از تفاوت رفتار کلامی زن و مرد در ایران (یک طرح اولیه)»، رشد آموزش زبان و ادب فارسی، ش 46.##بشیرنژاد، حسن (1379). «بررسی جای‌گاه و کاربرد زبان فارسی و مازندرانی در میان معلمان و دانش‌‌آموزان متوسطة شهرستان آمل»، پایان‌‌نامة کارشناسی ‌‌ارشد زبان‌‌شناسی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، دانشکدة ادبیات و زبان‌های خارجه.##بشیرنژاد، حسن (1383). «زبان‌‌های محلی ایران و خطر انقراض»، فرهنگ مردم ایران، ش 5 و 6.##پاک نهاد، مریم (1381). فرادستی و فرودستی در زبان، تهران: گام نو.##ترادگیل، پیتر (1376). درآمدی بر زبان‌‌شناسی اجتماعی، ترجمة محمد طباطبایی، تهران: آگاه.##دایرةالمعارف فارسی (1381). به سرپرستی غلامحسین مصاحب، ج 1، تهران: امیرکبیر.##رجب‌زاده، علی‌‌اصغر (1383). «برخورد زبانی میان فارسی و مازندرانی و ترکی در شهرستان گلوگاه»، پایان‌‌نامة کارشناسی ارشد زبان‌‌شناسی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و زبان‌‌های خارجه.##رضایی باغ‌بیدی، حسن (1380). «زبان‌های غیرایرانی»، دایرةالمعارف بزرگ اسلامی، ج 10، زیر نظر کاظم موسوی بجنوردی، تهران: مرکز دایرةالمعارف بزرگ اسلامی.##سیگل، سیدنی (1372). آمار غیرپارامتری، ترجمة یوسف کریمی، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.##شکری، گیتی (1374). گویش ساری (مازندرانی)، تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##عموزاده، محمد (1381). «هم‌گرایی و دوزبان‌گونگی در گویش مازندرانی»، پژوهش‌نامة علوم انسانی و اجتماعی، س 2، ش 6 و 7.##فخر‌‌روحانی، محمد‌‌رضا (1375). «نفی در گونة شرقی گویش مازندرانی»، پایان‌‌‌نامة کارشناسی ارشد زبان‌‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##مدرسی، یحیی (1368). درآمدی بر جامعه‌‌شناسی زبان، تهران: مؤسسة مطالعات و تحقیقات فرهنگی.##مشایخ، طاهره (1381). «بررسی کاربرد فارسی و گیلکی در میان دانش‌‌آموزان دورة پیش‌‌دانشگاهی و والدین آن‌‌ها در شهر رشت»، پایان‌‌نامة کارشناسی ارشد زبان‌‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##واسو جویباری، خدیجه (1385). «بررسی تفاوت بین نسلی در کاربرد واژه‌‌های مازندرانی جویباری»، پایان‌‌نامة کارشناسی ارشد زبان‌‌شناسی، دانشگاه الزهرا، دانشکدۀ ادبیات، زبان‌‌ها و تاریخ.##Borjian, M. (2005). “Bilingualism in Mazandaran: Peaceful Coexistence with Persian”, Languages, Communities, and Education, Vol. 2.##Childs, Becky, Gerard Van Herk, and Jennifer Thorburn (2007). “The effects of urbanization and social orientation: Locally salient variables as indicators of linguistic change”, Available online at http://www/ling.upenn.edu/nwav/abstracts.##Fischer, John L. (1958). “Social influences on the choice of a linguistic variant”, Word, 14.##Frye, Richard N. (1975). The Golden Age of Persia: The Arabs in the East, London: Weidenfeld and Nicolson.##Kerswill, Paul (2006). “Migration and language”, in Klaus Mattheier, Ulrich Ammon and Peter Trudgill (eds.), Sociolinguistics/Soziolinguistik, An international handbook of the science of language and society, Vol. 3, Berlin: De Gruyter.##Labov, W. (1988). “Some sociolinguistic principle”, in ch. Bratl. Paulston and G. Richard Tucker (eds.), Sociolinguistics: the Essential Reading, Blackwell Publishing.##Lakoff, R. T. (1973). “Language and Woman&#039;s Place”, Language in Society, Vol. 2, No. 1, Cambridge University Press Stable URL: http://www.jstor.org/stable/4166707.##Lakoff, R. T. (1975). Language and woman&#039;s place, Vol. 56, New York: Harper &amp; Row.##Lakoff, R. T. (2004). Language and woman&#039;s place [electronic resource]: text and commentaries, Vol. 3, Oxford University Press.##Lewis, M. Paul (ed.) (2009). Ethnologue: Languages of the World, Dallas, Tex.: SIL International, Online version: http://www.ethnologue.com.##Nemati, A. and J. M. Bayer (2007). “Gender Differences in the Use of Linguistic Forms in the Speech of Men and Women: A Comparative Study of Persian and English”, Language in India, 7.##Newman, M. L., C. J. Groom, L. D. Handelman, and J. W. Pennebaker (2008). “Gender differences in language use: An analysis of 14,000 text samples”, Discourse Processes, 45 (3).##Payne, John (1992). “Iranian Languages”, International Encyclopedia of Linguistics, edited by William Bright , Oxford: Oxford University Press , Vol. 2.##Trudgill, P. (1972). “Sex, covert prestige and linguistic change in the urban British English of Norwich”, Language in society, 1(2).##Wardhaugh, Ronald (1986). An Introduction to Sociolinguistics, Oxford: Blackwell.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>پیشینۀ نمایش در ایران باستان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Background of Drama in Ancient Iran</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>ایران و هند تمدن‌هایی کهن با ریشه‌های عمیق و مشترک‌اند، که بی‌شک حضور و گستردگی آیین‌ها در این دو تمدن نقش مهمی ایفا می‌کند. دربارۀ پیدایش خاستگاه نمایش در ایران پیش از اسلام تا کنون بحث‌ها و نظریات مختلفی بیان شده است. در میان نظریات مختلف در این باب، دیدگاه خاستگاه آیینی اساس نظرگاه ما را در این بحث تشکیل خواهد داد. در این پژوهش، ابتدا به‌اختصار، نظر این گروه از پژوهندگان بیان می‌شود. آن‌گاه با فرض پیشینگی خیمه‌شب‌بازی بر نمایش انسانی و با اتکا به شواهد باستان‌شناختی از تمدن‌های کهن جیرفت و شهر سوخته و مقایسۀ آن‌ها با یافته‌های مشترک از تمدن کهن سند، و امتزاج وسیع فرهنگی در این مناطق، در هزارة سوم پیش از میلاد، دیدگاه نگارندگان دربارۀ منشأ نمایش در ایران ارائه خواهد شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> 
 Many theorists hold that theater derives from rituals.  Iran and India are two ancient civilizations with deep and joint origins in which rituals have an important role. There are many debates about the origins of drama in ancient Iran. In this research we will concentrate on a view which holds &quot;ritual origin&quot; for drama. First we will shortly introduce the related theories .Then according to the theory of puppetry&#039;s priority over drama and depending on the archeological evidences from ancient civilizations of Jiroft and Shahr-I Sukhta and comparing them with similar findings from the civilization of Indus valley and their broad intercultural relations during the third millennium BC, we will express a new perspective about the background of drama in Iran.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>51</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>77</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زرشناس</Family>
						<NameE>Zohreh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zarshenas</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zzarshenas@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فاطمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شمسی</Family>
						<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shamsi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ft.shamsi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نمایش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عروسک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ایران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هاراپا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رقص</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آیین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>افشار، آرزو (1388). درآمدی بر رقص و حرکت، تهران: نشر افراز.##آنانواکوماراسوآمی، آناندا (1382). مقدمه‌ای بر هنر هند، ترجمۀ امیرحسین ذکرگو، تهران: نشر روزنه.##بابک، هومن (1385). نمایش عروسکی در هند، تهران: نمایش.##بویس، مری و فارمر، هنری جورج (1368). دو گفتار دربارۀ خنیاگری و موسیقی ایران، ترجمۀ بهزاد باشی، تهران: آگاه.##بهار، مهرداد (1387). پژوهشی در اساطیر ایران، تهران: نشر آگه.##بهنام، عیسی (1352). «شهر سوخته»، هنر و مردم، ش 126.##بیضایی، بهرام (1341). «خیمه‌شب‌بازی در ایران»، آرش، ش 3.##بیضایی، بهرام (1344). نمایش در ایران، تهران: بی‌نا.##پازوکی، شهاب (1389). نمایش در ایران، تهران: دانشگاه پیام نور.##ثمینی، نغمه و محمد خزایی (1382). «آیین و ادبیات مقدمه‌ای بر خاستگاه هنر نمایش»، کتاب ماه هنر، فروردین و اردیبهشت.##دانش‌نامۀ دانش گستر (1389). زیر نظر: علی رامین، کامران فانی، محمدعلی سادات، ج 3، تهران: مؤسسة علمی فرهنگی دانش گستر.##دیمز، اورلی (1388). تندیس‌گری و شمایل‌نگاری در ایران پیش از اسلام، ترجمة علی‌اکبر وحدتی، تهران: نشر ماهی.##ذکاء، یحیی (1342). «رقص در ایران پیش از تاریخ»، مجلة موسیقی، ش 79-80.##ذکاء، یحیی (1343). «سرگذشت رقص در ایران»، مجلة موسیقی، دورة سوم، ش 86.##ذکاء، یحیی (1357). «تاریخ رقص در ایران»، هنر و مردم، ش 189 و 190.##ساویتیری، شیوا لینگاپا (1337). عروسک‌های خیمه‌شب‌بازی و نقش آن‌ها در اجتماع، ترجمة علی آقابخشی، تهران: مرکز اسناد فرهنگی آسیا.##ستاری، جلال (1387). زمینة‌ اجتماعی تعزیه و تئاتر در ایران، تهران: نشر مرکز.##سرسنگی، مجید (1376). «مقدمه‌ای بر نمایش‌های سنتی و آیینی در ایران»، نامة فرهنگ، ش 26.##سهرابی، امیر (1391). عروسک پشت پرده و خیمه‌شب‌بازی در اصفهان و نائین، تهران: نمایش.##سیدسجادی، سیدمنصور (1388). باستان‌شناسی‌ شبه قارة هند، تهران: سمت.##شاتوک، سی بل (1381). دین هندو، ترجمة حسن افشار، تهران: نشر مرکز.##شفیعی کدکنی، محمدرضا (1384). «پیشینة هنر تئاتر در ایران»، بخارا، ش 41.##عاشورپور، صادق (1389). نمایشه‌ای ایرانی، نمایشه‌ای آیین مزدیسنا، ج 3، تهران: سورة مهر.##کیندرمان، هاینتس (1365). تاریخ تئاتر اروپا، ج 3، تئاتر قرون وسطی، ترجمة سعید فرهودی، تهران: مؤسسة مطالعات و تحقیقات فرهنگی.##گلریز، محمدعلی (1368). تاریخ و جغرافیای تاریخی قزوین، تهران: انتشارات طه با هم‌کاری میراث فرهنگی قزوین.##گوردن، چایلد (1354). انسان خود را می‌سازد، ترجمة احمد کریمی حکاک و محمد هل اتائی، تهران: انتشارات کتاب‌های جیبی.##گیرشمن، رومن (1350). هنر ایران در دوران پارتی و ساسانی، ترجمة بهرام فره‌وشی، تهران: بنگاه ترجمه و نشر کتاب.##مجمل التواریخ و القصص (1318). به تصحیح ملک الشعرا بهار، تهران: بی‌نا.##مجیدزاده، یوسف (1368). آغاز شهرنشینی در ایران، تهران: مرکز نشر دانشگاهی.##مجیدزاده، یوسف (1383). جیرفت کهن‌ترین تمدن شرق، تهران: وزارت فرهنگ و ارشاد اسلامی.##مددپو، محمد (1373). تجدد و دین‌زدایی در فرهنگ و هنر منورالفکری ایران از آغاز پیدایی تا پایان عصر قاجار، تهران: دانشگاه شاهد.##ناظرزاده کرمانی، فرهاد (1383). درآمدی به نمایش‌نامه‌شناسی، تهران: سمت.##میرشکرایی، محمد (1357). «پایگاه اجتماعی نمایش‌های عامیانه در مازندران و گیلان»، هنر و مردم، ش 193.##نگهبان، عزت‌الله (1351). راهنمای موزه و حفاری هفت‌تپه، تهران: انتشارات ادارة کل موزه‌ها، وزارت فرهنگ و هنر.##یغمایی، پیرایه (1390). «خیمه‌شب‌بازی و پیشینة آن»، سایت انسان شناسی و فرهنگ، http://anthropology.ir/node/12124 (تاریخ رجوع: 15/6/1393).##Boyce, Mary (1957). “The Parthian Gōsān and the Iranian Minstrel Tradition”, Journal of the Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland, No. 1 &amp; 2.##Danino, Michel (2003). “The Harappan Heritage and the Arian Problem”, Man and Environment, Vol. XXVIII, No. 1.##Floor, Willem (2005). The history of theater in Iran, Washington DC: Mage.##Lochtefelf, G. J. (2002). The Illustrated Encyclopedia of Hinduism, Vol. 1-2, New York: The Rosen Publishing GroupInc.##Rao, L. S. (2007). “A Note on Dancing Girl from Bhirana, District Fatehabad, Haryana”, Man and Environment Journal, Volume XXXII, No.1, the journal of the Indian Society for Prehistoric and Quaternary Studies, Pune, ISSN: 0258-0446.##Mallory, J. P. and Q. Adams Douglas (1997). “Armenian Language”, in Encyclopedia of Indo-European Culture, London: Fitzroy Dearborn.##McIntosh, Jane R. (2008). The ancient Indus Valley: new perspectives, Understanding ancient civilizations series, USA: ABC-CLIO. Inc.##Shirazi, R. (2007). “Figurines anthropomorphes Du Brunze Ancient De Shahr-I Sokhta, Période II (Séistan, Sud-East Du L`Iran): Approche Typologioue”, Paléorient Journal, Vol. 33, Issue. 2, France: CNRS Éditions.##Subramanian, T. S. (2008). “Harappan link”, Frontline, V. 25, Issue 02, 1, India: The Hindu publishers.##The Circle of Ancient Iranian Studies, Iranian Music: Tanbur (Guitar), Retrieved 05/05/2008.##www.cais-soas.com/CAIS/Music/tanbur.htm&gt;.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>آزوفا سینمایی: کاربرد فیلم سینمایی در آموزش زبان و فرهنگ ایران به غیرفارسی‌زبانان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Azofa with Cinema: The Use of Films for Teaching Persian Language and Iranian Culture to Non-Persian Speakers</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف مقالۀ حاضر بررسی و امکان‌سنجی کاربرد فیلم سینمایی به ‌عنوان منبعی برای تهیه و تدوین مواد درسی در دوره‌های آزوفا (آموزش زبان و فرهنگ ایران به غیرفارسی‌زبانان) است. در مقاله به این پرسش پاسخ داده می‌شود که چگونه می‌توان بر مبنای یک فیلم سینمایی ایرانی طرحی درسی ارائه داد که نکات زبانی و فرهنگی مورد نظر در برنامه‌های آزوفا را داشته باشد (زرودا، 2006؛ گارن، 2012). این پژوهش که از نوع کتاب‌خانه‌ای است، با استفاده از روش توصیفی ‌ـ ‌تحلیلی، امکان آموزش واژگان، مهارت‌های شنیدن، گفتن، خواندن و نوشتن و نیز معرفی فرهنگ ایرانی به غیرفارسی‌زبانان را بر اساس فیلم سینمایی رنگ خدا ساختۀ مجید مجیدی (1997)، ارزیابی می‌کند. در این راستا نقش فرهنگ و اهمیت توانش بینافرهنگی در آموزش زبان (مِیِر، 1991؛ بایرام، 1997) مبنای نظری پژوهش قرار گرفته است. بررسی نشان می‌دهد که فیلم سینمایی به‌درستی می‌تواند به ‌عنوان منبعی غنی برای آموزش کارآمد زبان فارسی و فرهنگ ایرانی به غیرفارسی‌زبانان به ‌کار گرفته شود. بدین منظور، انتخاب فیلم و رویکرد آموزشی مناسب باید با توجه به ویژگی‌های ساختاری و محتوای فیلم و نیازهای زبان‌آموزان صورت پذیرد. علاوه ‌بر این، ضرورت دارد که تعداد محدود مدرسان توانای ایرانی در خارج از کشور و نبود مجموعه‌ای ارزیابی‌شده و در دسترس از فیلم‌های سینمایی ایرانی در طراحی برنامۀ درسی فیلم‌محور به‌دقت مورد توجه قرار گیرد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The present article aims at studying the feasibility of using films as a source to provide teaching material for Azofa (teaching Persian language and Iranian culture to non-Persian speakers). The question which the present article seeks to answer is how, based on an Iranian film, a syllabus may be designed which includes the linguistic and cultural points required by the Azofa program (Zoreda, 2006; Garn, 2012). This library-based research (which uses the analytical-descriptive method) assesses the possibility of teaching vocabulary and the skills of listening, speaking, reading and writing, as well as of introducing Iranian culture, to non-Persian speakers, based on the film “Colour of Paradise”, directed by Majid Majidi (1997); thus, the role of culture and the importance of intercultural competence in language teaching (Meyer, 1991; Byram, 1997) constitutes the theoretical basis for the research. Studies show that films may be properly used as a rich resource for the efficient teaching of Persian language and Iranian culture to non-Persian speakers. To this end, appropriate films and teaching approaches should be chosen with respect to the structural features and content of the films and the learners’ needs. In addition, the limited number of proficient Iranian teachers abroad and the absence of evaluated and accessible collections of Iranian films should be carefully taken under consideration when designing a film-based syllabus.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>79</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>102</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صفارمقدم</Family>
						<NameE>Ahmad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Saffar Moqaddam</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار زبان‌شناسی پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار زبان‌شناسی پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>as_moqaddam@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آتوسا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رستم‌بیک تفرشی</Family>
						<NameE>Atoosa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rostambeik Tafreshi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار زبان‌شناسی پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار زبان‌شناسی پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>atoosa.rostambeik@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آموزش زبان فارسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>غیرفارسی‌زبان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فیلم سینمایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرهنگ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توانش بینافرهنگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>اردکانی، فاطمه، فرانک فتوحی، و جمال رضایی نور (1392). «بررسی و ارزیابی طراحی بازی‌های چندرسانه‌ای زبان در محیط آموزش سیار»، پنجمین کنفرانس ملی مهندسی برق و الکترونیک ایران، برخط: http://www.civilica.com/Paper-ICEEE05-ICEEE05_608.html&gt;.&lt;##تانن، دبورا (1375). منظورم این نبود: تفاوت‌های کلامی میان زن و مرد، ترجمة مهدی قراچه‌‌داغی و زهره فتوحی، تهران: نشر اوحدی.##حیدری، غلام‌حسین، یاسمن مدانلو، مرضیه نیازآذری و عبدالله جعفری گلوچه (1389). «مقایسۀ تأثیر تدریس زبان انگلیسی با نرم‌افزار آموزشی و شیوۀ سنتی بر پیش‌رفت تحصیلی دانش‌آموزان»، فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات در علوم تربیتی، س 1، ش 1.##رستم‌‌بیک، آتوسا و احمد رمضانی (1391). «نقش فرهنگ در آموزش زبان خارجی»، پژوهش‌‌نامۀ انتقادی متون و برنامه‌‌های علوم انسانی، س 12، ش 1.##صفارمقدم، احمد (1391). مجموعۀ زبان فارسی برای غیرفارسی‌‌زبانان، تهران: شورای گسترش زبان و ادبیات فارسی و پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##صفارمقدم، احمد (1392). «تفاوت‌‌های گفتار و نوشتار در آموزش مهارت گفتاری زبان فارسی به غیرفارسی‌‌زبانان»، زبان‌شناخت، س 14، ش 2.##صفارمقدم، احمد (1394). «مجموعۀ فارسی گفتاری برای غیرفارسی‌‌زبانان»، طرح پژوهشی پایان‌‌یافته و آمادۀ چاپ، تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##عبدالهی، لیدا، حسن رستگارپور، لیلا عبدالهی، و بهنام عبدالهی (1391). «بررسی رویکردهای طراحی چندرسانه‌ای تعاملی برای آموزش و یادگیری زبان»، اولین همایش میان‌رشته‌‌ای آموزش و یادگیری زبان، دانشگاه فرهنگیان، پردیس بنت‌الهدی صدر سنندج، برخط:&gt; &lt;http://confbank.um.ac.ir##فاطمی جهرمی، سیدابوالقاسم (1383). «استفاده از تکنولوژی در آموزش زبان دوم»، پژوهش‌نامۀ علوم انسانی، ش 43-44.##مدرسی، یحیی (1380). فارسی در گفتار، تهران: شورای گسترش زبان و ادبیات فارسی.##یارایی شهمیرزادی، دانیال و طیبه اعتمادی‌نسب و سیدمحمودحسینی اشلقی (1392). «مقایسۀ تأثیر نرم‌افزار چندرسانه‌ای با روش سنتی بر آموزش زبان و گفتار کودکان آسیب‌دیدۀ شنوایی»، فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات در علوم تربیتی، دورۀ سوم، ش 4، پیاپی 12.##American Council on the Teaching of Foreign Languages, Executive Summary of the Standards for Foreign Language Learning in the 21st Century (2006).##Atay, D., G. Kurt, Z. Çamlibel, P. Ersin, and Ö. Kaslioglu (2009). “The role of intercultural competence in foreign language teaching”, Inonu University Journal of the Faculty of Education, 10(3).##Berk, R. A. (2009). “Multimedia teaching with video clips: TV, movies, YouTube, and mtvU in the college classroom”, International Journal of Technology in Teaching and Learning, 5(1).##Block, D. &amp; D. Cameron (eds.) (2002). Globalization and language teaching, Routledge.##Bolton, G. (1993). “A brief history of classroom drama”, in Towards Drama as a Method in the Foreign Language Classroom, edited by M. Schewe and P. Shaw. Frankfurt/Main: Verlag Peter Lang Publishing.##Boswood, T. (1997). “New Ways of Using Computers in Language Teaching, New Ways in TESOL Series II. Innovative Classroom Techniques”, TESOL, 1600 Cameron Street, Suite 300, Alexandria, VA 22314-2751##Bredella, L. (2003). “For a flexible model of intercultural understanding”, Intercultural experience and education.##Byram, M. (1997). Teaching and Assessing Intercultural Communicative Competence, Clevedon: Multilingual Matters.##Byram, M., B. Gribkova, and H. Starkey (2002). Developing the intercultural dimension in language teaching, A practical introduction for teachers, Strasbourg: Council of Europe.##Cakir, I. (2006). “The Use of Video as an Audio-visual Material in Foreign Language Teaching Classroom”, The Turkish Online Journal of Educational Technology, 5(4).##Chan, D. Herrero C. (2010). Using films to teach languages: teachers’ toolkit, Cornerhouse, online: &lt; www.cornerhouse.org/wpcontent/.../TeachersToolkit_Jun2010.pdf&gt;.##Davies, P. (1990). “The use of drama in English language teaching”, TESL Canada Journal, 8(1).##Fotos, S. (ed.). (1996). Multimedia language teaching, Logos International.##Garn, R. (2012). “Teaching the Five C’s with Cinema”, Journal of the National Council of the Less Commonly Taught Languages, Vol. 12.##Higgins, J. (1983). “Computer assisted language learning”, Language Teaching, 16(02).##Kagan, O., M. Kashper, and Y. Morozova (2013). Cinema for Russian Conversation, Vol. 1, Hackett Publishing.##Kenning, M. M. (1990). “Computer-assisted language learning”, Language Teaching, 23(02).##King, J. (2002). “Using DVD feature films in the EFL classroom”, Computer Assisted Language Learning, 15(5).##Merrill, J., Mikhailova, J., and Alley, M. (2009). Animation for Russian Conversation, Focus Publishing.##Meyer, M. (1991). “Developing transcultural competence: Case studies in advanced language learners”, Mediating Languages and Cultures: Towards an Intercultural Theory of Foreign Language Education, eds. D. Buttjes and M. Byram. Clevedon: Multilingual Matters.##Pichugina, V. (2005). Advanced Russian through film: a collection of transcripts and exercises, Hermitage.##Qian-hong, L. O. N. G. (2003). “A Study on Teaching English Listening and Speaking Through Films [J]”, Media in Foreign Language Instruction, 3, 013.##Rice, A. (2009). “Implementing a Curriculum Built Around Film”, in Workshop on Teaching Language and Culture with Film, University of California-Berkeley.##Ronke, A. (2005). “Drama and theater as a method for foreign language teaching and learning in higher education in the United States”, Doktorin der Philosophie genehmigte Dissertation. Fakultät I – Geisteswissenschaften der Technischen Universität Berlin [Electronic resource]. Berlin.##Sercu, L. et al. (2005). Foreign language teachers and intercultural competence: an international investigation, Vol. 10, Multilingual Matters.##Shea, D. (1995). “Whole movies and engaged response in the Japanese university ESL classroom”, in C. Casanave and Simons (eds.), Pedagogical perspective on using films in foreign language classes, Keio University SFC Monograph #4.##Wang, Li (2005). “The Advantages of Using Technology in Second Language Education: Technology Integration in Foreign Language Teaching Demonstrates the Shift from a Behavioral to a Constructivist Learning Approach”, The Journal (Technological Horizons in Education), 32, No. 10: 38.##Warschauer, M. (1995). E-Mail for English Teaching: Bringing the Internet and Computer Learning Networks into the Language Classroom, Teachers of English to Speakers of Other Languages (TESOL), Inc., 1600 Cameron St., Suite 300, Alexandria, VA 22314.##Warschauer, M. and R. Kern (2000). Network-based language teaching: concepts and practice, Cambridge university press.##Webb, S. (2010). “A corpus driven study of the potential for vocabulary learning through watching movies”, International Journal of Corpus Linguistics, 15(4).##Weyers, J. R. (1999). “The effect of authentic video on communicative competence”, Modern language journal.##Wierzbicka, A. (1994). “Cultural Scripts: A New Approach to the Study of Cross Cultural Communication”, in Language Contact and Language Conflict, M. Pütz (ed.), Amsterdam: John Benjamin&#039;s Publishing Company.##Xinghui, D. (2003). “Multimedia in Foreign Language Teaching [J]”, Foreign Languages and Their Teaching, 9.##Zhen, M. (2006). “On multimedia foreign language learning and teaching” [J], Foreign Language World, 6.##Zoreda, M. (2006). “Intercultural moments in teaching English through film”, Reencuentro, 47.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>واحدهای سنجش طول در اوستا</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Avestan Units of Length Measurement</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>دربارة واحد‌های اندازه‌گیری در ایران باستان اطلاعات کمی در دست است. مهم‌ترین متنی که از ایران باستان باقی مانده است، یعنی اوستا، آگاهی چندانی در این باره به دست نمی‌دهد. خوش‌بختانه یکی از فصول فرهنگ‌نامه‌ای کهن، مشتمل بر واژه‌های اوستایی و ترجمة پهلوی آن‌ها، دربردارندة تعدادی از واحدهای سنجش طول در دوران باستان است. در فصل بیست و هفتم فرهنگ اویم، نام واحدهای اندازه‌گیری طول و نسبت آن‌ها با یک‌دیگر به زبان اوستایی و پهلوی آمده است. نام برخی از این مقیاس‌ها در متون اوستایی تک‌آمدند و تنها در این فرهنگ باقی مانده است. به این ‌ترتیب، می‌توان این متن را مهم‌ترین منبعی دانست که دربارة واحدهای اندازه‌گیری در ایران باستان اطلاعاتی به دست می‌دهد. در این مقاله، واحدهای اندازه‌گیری طول، که در فصل بیست و هفتم فرهنگ اویم نام برده و تعریف شده است، به کمک بخش‌های دیگر اوستا و منابع پهلوی و زند طبقه‌بندی و بررسی شده است. نتیجۀ این بررسی و طبقه‌بندی را می‌توان به صورت زیر خلاصه کرد: uz-ašti = 8 ǝrǝzu, dišti = 10 ǝrǝzu, paδa = 16 ǝrǝzu, vībāzu = 2 frabāzu = 4 frarāθni = 8 vitasti  = 96 ǝrǝzu, vībāzu = 2 gāiia = 4 frarāθni, gāiia = 3 paδa = 4 vitasti = 48 ǝrǝzu , yujiiasti = 2 daxšmaiti = 4 snaiiasti = 8 tacar = 16 hāθra.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>There is little information about the units of measurement in ancient Iran. From Avesta, the most important text of ancient Iran, we can’t deduce so much information about this subject. Fortunately, one of the chapters of an old Avestan-Pahlavi lexicon i.e. Farhang ī Ōim includes a list of measurement units. We can find the name of the units of length measurement in chapter 27 of the lexicon. Some of these names are hapax legomenon and are only preserved in Farhang ī Ōim. In this paper these units of length, are studied and compared according to the other parts of Avesta and the Pahlavi texts. These results can be summarized as follows: uz-ašti = 8 ǝrǝzu, dišti = 10 ǝrǝzu, paδa = 16 ǝrǝzu, vībāzu = 2 frabāzu = 4 frarāθni = 8 vitasti  = 96 ǝrǝzu, vībāzu = 2 gāiia = 4 frarāθni, gāiia = 3 paδa = 4 vitasti = 48 ǝrǝzu , yujiiasti = 2 daxšmaiti = 4 snaiiasti = 8 tacar = 16 hāθra. uz-ašti = 8 ǝrǝzu, dišti = 10 ǝrǝzu, paδa = 16 ǝrǝzu, vībāzu = 2 frabāzu = 4 frarāθni = 8 vitasti  = 96 ǝrǝzu, vībāzu = 2 gāiia = 4 frarāθni, gāiia = 3 paδa = 4 vitasti = 48 ǝrǝzu , yujiiasti = 2 daxšmaiti = 4 snaiiasti = 8 tacar = 16 hāθra.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>103</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>118</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فرزانه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گشتاسب</Family>
						<NameE>Farzaneh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Goshtasb</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>f_goshtasb@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرهنگ اویم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>واحدهای اندازه‌گیری طول</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هاسر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>بندهش ← بهار، 1369.##بهار، مهرداد (1369). بندهش، تهران: توس.##حسن‌دوست، حسن (1391). فرهنگ تطبیقی ـ موضوعی زبان‌ها و گویش‌های ایرانی نو، 2 ج، تهران: فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی.##داعی‌الاسلام، سیدمحمدعلی‌حسنی (1361). وندیداد، حصه سوم کتاب اوستا، تهران: دانش.##راشدمحصل، محمدتقی (1385). وزیدگی‌‌های زادسپرم، ج 2، تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم‌انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##روایت امید اشوَهیشتان ← صفای اصفهانی، 1376.##شایست ناشایست ← مزداپور، 1369.##صفای اصفهانی، نزهت (1376). روایت امید اشوَهیشتان، تهران: نشر مرکز.##فرهنگ اویم ← Asha, 2009 Klingenschmitt, 1968; Reichelt, 1966;.##کریمی، اصغر (1353). «واحدهای اندازه‌گیری در ایل بختیاری و حساب سیاق»، مردم‌شناسی و فرهنگ عامة ایران، ش 1.##گزیده‌های زادسپرم ← راشدمحصل، 1385.##مزداپور، کتایون (1369). شایست ناشایست، تهران:‌ مؤسسة مطالعات و تحقیقات فرهنگی.##وندیداد ← داعی‌الاسلام، 1361؛ Jamasp, 1907.##هنینگ، والتر برونو (1375). «فصل نجومی بندهش»، ترجمة همایون صنعتی‌زاده، میراث جاویدان، س 4، ش 3 و 4.##هیربدستان، نیرنگستان ← .Kotwal and Kreyenbroek, 1992-2003##هینتس، والتر (1388). اوزان و مقیاس‌ها در فرهنگ اسلامی، تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##Asha, R. (2009). Avesta Glossary, A Glossary of Avesta words and their Pārsīg equivalents, based on the Zand, the so-called Frahang ī ōim:ēk, Bombay.##Bartholomae, Ch. (1961). Altiranisches Wörterbuch, Berlin.##Henning, W. B. (1942). “An Astronomical Chapter of the Bundahishn”, Journal of the Royal Asiatic Society.##Henning, W. B. (1948). “Oktō(u)”, Transactions of the Philological Society, Vol. 47.##Jamasp, H. (1907). Vendidâd, Avesta Text with Pahlavi Translation and Commentary, and Glossarial Index, With the Assistance of M. M. Gandevia, Vol. I: The Texts, Bombay.##Kotwal, F.M. and P.G. Kreyenbroek (2003). The Hērbedestān and Nērangestān. vol.3, Paris.##Klingenschmitt, G. (1968). Farhang-i ōīm, Edition und Kommentar, Ph.D Diss, University of Erlangen.##MacKenzie, D.N. (1971). A Concise Pahlavi Dictionary, London.##Madan, D. M. (1911). The Complete Text of the Pahlavi Dinkard, 2 vol, Bombay.##Reichelt. H. (1966). “Der Frahang i oīm (Zand-Pahlavi Glossary)”, I: Einleitung, Wiener Zeitschrift für die Kunde des Morgenlandes (WZKM), XIII (1899), II: Index der Awestawörter, WZKM, XV (1901).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>توصیف واکه‌های ساده در گویش لکی نورآبادی در قیاس با زبان فارسی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Comparative Descriptive Analysis of Simple 
Vowels in Laki Nurabadi and Persian</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مقالۀ حاضر با هدف توصیف واکه‌های ساده در گویش لکی نورآبادی در تقابل با فارسی نوشتاری معیار نگاشته شده است. بر این مبنا، به دنبال مقدمه‌ای کوتاه مشتمل بر جای‌گاه این گویش در خانوادة زبان‌های ایرانی، به ارائۀ مجموعه‌ای از تحلیل‌های ساختاری در آن می‌پردازیم. تحلیل فوق، با تأکید بر نقش واجی کشش واکه‌ای در گویش، واکه‌های ساده در آن را در چهار دسته: 1. پسین و گرد [/u/, /:ɔ/, /ɔ/, /:ɑ/, /ɑ/]، 2. پیشین و گسترده [/i/, /:I/, /I/, /ε/, /a:/, /a/]، 3. پیشین و گرد [/У/, /:ø/, /ø/] و 4. مرکزی [/ә/, /ɜ/] ارائه و توصیف می‌‌‌نماید. تقسیم‌بندی فوق مجموعه‌ای مشتمل بر 16 واکۀ ممیز را در نظام واکه‌ای گویش در مقابل نظام 6 واکه‌ای فارسی برمی‌شمرد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The present research is aimed to present a description of the Monophtongs in the dialect of Laki Nurabadi in comparison to that of Standard written Persian language. Accordingly, following a brief dialectal introduction including the typological classification of the dialect within the Iranian language family, vocalic structural analyses of the two systems have been presented comparatively, in regard to the research topic; i.e monophtongs. The investigation is made with an emphasis on the distinctive function of vowel length, and the analysis results classify Laki simple vowels into four types of, 1. back and round [/u/, /:ɔ/, /ɔ/, /:ɑ/, /ɑ/], 2. front and spread [/i/, /:I/, /I/, /ε/, /a:/, /a/], 3. front and round [/У/, /:ø/, /ø/], and 4. central [/ә/, /ɜ/] vowels. The matter illustrates an inclusion of sixteen simple vowels within the dialectal vocalic system, in comparison to that of Persian’s system containing six vowels. ri;mso-bidi-language:FA&#039;&gt;ɜ/] ارائه و توصیف می‌‌‌نماید. تقسیم‌بندی فوق مجموعه‌ای مشتمل بر 16 واکۀ ممیز را در نظام واکه‌ای گویش در مقابل نظام 6 واکه‌ای فارسی برمی‌شمرد.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>147</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>166</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهین‌ناز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>میردهقان</Family>
						<NameE>Mahinnaz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mirdehghan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار زبان‌شناسی، گروه زبان‌شناسی، دانشکدة ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار زبان‌شناسی، گروه زبان‌شناسی، دانشکدة</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mahinnaz.mirdehghan@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نوری</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nuri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mo.norizadeh@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نیلوفر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسینی‌کارگر</Family>
						<NameE>Niloufar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hoseini Kargar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مطالعات هند، دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مطالعات هند، دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>niloofar_hoseinikargar@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گویش لکی نورآبادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظام واکه‌‌ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>طبقه‌‌بندی واکه‌ها</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کشش واکه‌ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>واکه‌های ساده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>امیدی، عباس (1388). «نظام ‌‌آوایی گویش ‌‌لکی‌‌ دلفان در چهارچوب واج‌شناسی‌‌ زایشی»، پایان‌‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد زبان‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.##ایزدپناه، حمید (1367). فرهنگ لکی، تهران: مؤسسۀ فرهنگی جهانگیری.##تفرجی یگانه، مریم (1385). «بررسی ساختمان گروه فعلی در زبان کردی (ایلامی)»، پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد زبان‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی.##ثمره، یدالله (1378). آواشناسی زبان فارسی، تهران: مرکز نشر دانشگاهی.##حق‌شناس، علی‌محمد (1378). آواشناسی، تهران: مؤسسۀ انتشارات آگاه.##دیهیم، گیتی (1358). درآمدی بر آواشناسی عمومی، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه ملی ایران.##عالی‌پور خرم‌‌آبادی، کامین (1384). دستور زبان لکی: ضرب‌‌المثل‌‌ها و واژه‌‌نامه‌‌ها، خرم‌آباد: افلاک.##کاظمی، فروغ (1384). «بررسی خطاهای نحوی لک‌‌زبانان در یادگیری و کاربرد زبان فارسی»، پایان‌‌نامۀ کارشناسی ‌‌ارشد زبان‌‌‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.##مشکوة‌الدینی، مهدی (1370). دستور زبان فارسی بر پایۀ نظری گشتاری، مشهد: انتشارات دانشگاه فردوسی.##مشکوة‌الدینی، مهدی (1374). ساخت آوایی زبان، مشهد: انتشارات دانشگاه فردوسی.##مک موان، ام. کی. سی. (1373). آواشناسی و واج‌‌شناسی، ترجمۀ اریک فیوج، محمد فایز و جواد نصرتی‌‌نیا، تهران: روایت.##میرچراغی، سیدفرهود (1369). بررسی ساختمان دستوری گویش لکی «خواجوندی» کلاردشت، تهران: پرهام نشر.##ناطوری، مهرناز (1383). «نظام آوایی گویش لکی هرسین از دیدگاه انگارة واج‌‌شناسی زایشی استاندارد»، پایان‌‌‌‌نامۀ کارشناسی ‌‌ارشد زبان‌‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تهران مرکز.##یارمحمدی، لطف‌الله (1373). درآمدی به آواشناسی، تهران: انتشارات مرکز نشر دانشگاهی.##Ladefoged, P. (2006). A Course in Phonetics, Boston: Thomson Wadsworth.##dir=RTL&gt;/ɜ/] vowels. The matter illustrates an inclusion of sixteen simple vowels within the dialectal vocalic system, in comparison to that of Persian’s system containing six vowels.##ri;mso-bidi-language:FA&#039;&gt;ɜ/] ارائه و توصیف می‌‌‌نماید. تقسیم‌بندی فوق مجموعه‌ای مشتمل بر 16 واکۀ ممیز را در نظام واکه‌ای گویش در مقابل نظام 6 واکه‌ای فارسی برمی‌شمرد.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ساختار تکیه و آهنگ زبان شمس تبریزی در مقالات</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Structure of Stress and Intonation in 
Shams-e Tabrīzī’s Maghālāt</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تکیۀ واژه برجستگی‌‌ای است که به یکی از هجاهای واژه داده می‌‌شود. تکیه، در زبان فارسی، با برخورداری از ابزار لازم (شدت، زیر و بمی) و جای‌گاه دستوری خاص، در جهت تبیین و تفهیم مطالب نقش دارد و در کنار آهنگ حاصل از برجستگی نمود خاص می‌‌یابد. آهنگ از تکیه جدا نیست. هر جا که تکیه هست ارتفاع صوت بیش‌تر می‌‌شود و در هیچ موردی یکی را جدای از آن دیگری نمی‌‌توان یافت. مقالات شمس تبریزی به عنوان مجموعه‌‌ای ارزنده از گفتارها و خطابه‌‌های شمس تبریزی دربردارندۀ مطالب گرانبهایی است که درک و تفهیم آن تا حدی با دشواری همراه است. نگارندگان به بررسی تکیه و آهنگ به عنوان ویژگی دستوری خاص گفتار و خطابه، که در سخنان شمس نمود بارزی دارد، پرداخته و نشان داده‌اند که توجه به این عامل سهولت درک و تفهیم مطالب این مجموعۀ باارزش را در پی دارد و نیز این امر نشان از آن دارد که شمس در مقالات، که مجموعه‌‌ای از سخنان خطابی و تعلیمی است، از تکیه و آهنگ به عنوان عوامل آوایی سخن، به منظور تأثیر بر مخاطب، به نحو احسن بهره برده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Stress is the prominence given to a particular syllable in a word. In Persian language, stress, benefiting from intensity and pitch, once used in the appropriate part of speech, clarifies the purpose and along with intonation, produced by prominence, becomes distinguished. Both, stress and into nation, normally come together as stress creates a high pitch and consequently derives attention. Maghālāt-e-Shams-e-Tabrīzī, comprising Shams’ acclaimed speeches, is difficult to understand to a certain extent. This article is engaged with discussing how Shams has devised the stress and intonation as a special grammatical character in Maghālāt, a compilation of his sermons and educational advice, to strongly influence his audience.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>119</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>130</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فاطمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مدرسی</Family>
						<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Modarresi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد زبان و ادبیات فارسی، دانشگاه ارومیه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد زبان و ادبیات فارسی، دانشگاه ارومیه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>fatemeh.modarresi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فرزانه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>وزوایی</Family>
						<NameE>Farzaneh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Vezvaee</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی پژوهشکدة زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی پژوهشکدة زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>farzaneh_vm@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ثانیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مخبر</Family>
						<NameE>Saniyeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mokhber</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد زبان و ادبیات فارسی، دانشگاه ارومیه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد زبان و ادبیات فارسی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>f.mokhber@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شمس تبریزی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مقالات</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تکیه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آهنگ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ابوالقاسمی، محسن (1380). تاریخ زبان فارسی، تهران: سمت.##بهار، ملک‌‌‌الشعرا (1375). سبک‌‌شناسی، تهران: امیرکبیر.##غلامعلی‌‌‌زاده، خسرو (1374). ساخت زبان فارسی، تهران: احیای کتاب.##مدرسی، فاطمه (1387). از واج تا جمله (فرهنگ زبان‌شناسی ـ دستوری)، تهران: نشر چاپار.##معین، محمد (1383). تاریخ زبان فارسی، تهران: فرهنگ.##موحد، محمدعلی (1369). مقالات شمس تبریزی، تهران: خوارزمی.##ناتل خانلری، پرویز (1375). تاریخ زبان فارسی، تهران: بنیاد فرهنگ ایران.##نجفی، ابوالحسن (1373). مبانی زبان‌شناسی و کاربرد آن در زبان فارسی، تهران: نیلوفر.##وحیدیان، کامیار و غلامرضا عمرانی (1383). دستور زبان فارسی (1)، تهران: سمت.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نشان‌گرهای زبانی‌ ساخت‌های کذب در فارسی: یک پژوهش زبانی ـ اجتماعی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Lying Structures in Persian Language 
as a Socio-Lingual Behavior</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف اصلی پژوهش حاضر بررسی و تحلیل ساخت‌های دروغ در زبان فارسی است و در این راستا، به بررسی رابطۀ بین میزان استفاده از «نشان‌گرهای احتیاط»، «نشان‌گرهای نفی»، «کلمات حسی»، «کلمات مجزاگر» و «ضمایر» با کذب جملات پرداخته ‌شده است. این پژوهش با روش توصیفی ـ تحلیلی در یک جامعۀ آماری فارسی‌زبان شامل 28 نفر مرد و زن و در دو گروه سنی به انجام رسیده و برای نشان دادن معناداری ارقام از آزمون‌های ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و تی استفاده ‌شده است. نتایج این پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که بین میزان استفاده از «نشان‌گرهای احتیاط» و «کلمات مجزاگر» با کذب جملات رابطه‌ای معکوس و معنادار برقرار است، بدین سان که هر چه میزان استفاده از «نشان‌گرهای احتیاط» و «کلمات مجزاگر» در جملات بیش‌تر باشد، احتمال کذب جملات کاهش می‌یابد. از سوی دیگر، بین میزان استفاده از «نشان‌گرهای نفی»، «کلمات حسی» و «ضمایر» با کذب جملات رابطه‌ای مستقیم و معنادار برقرار است؛ بدین معنا که هر چه میزان استفاده از «نشان‌گرهای نفی»، «کلمات حسی» و «ضمایر» در جملات بیش‌تر باشد، احتمال کذب جملات نیز افزایش می‌یابد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>People lie in their everyday life, and this is a deniable fact. Like any other language, Persian has true and false structures. This research aims to study and analyze lying structures in Persian language. For this purpose, the relation of the application rate of “caution markers”, “negation markers”, “emotional words and verbs”, “exclusive words” and “pronouns” with the falsehood of sentences is studied. For this purpose, a descriptive-analytical research design has been employed, and a sample of 28 male and female Persian-speaking individuals has been taken from the statistical population. To study the significance of the relation, Pearson correlation coefficient (PCC) and T-test have been applied. The results of this research show that there is a reverse and significant relation between the use of caution markers, and exclusive words and the falsehood of sentences. That is, the more the number of caution markers, and exclusive words in a sentence is, the probability of the falsehood of that sentence is decreased. However, the relation of the negation markers, sense words and verbs, and pronouns with the falsehood of the sentences is direct and of significance. That is, the increase in the use of negation markers, sense verbs and words, as well as pronouns in a sentence increases its falsehood.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>131</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>146</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>یحیی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مدرسی</Family>
						<NameE>Yahya</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Modarresi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ymodarresi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ندا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اسدی</Family>
						<NameE>Neda</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Asadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش‌جوی کارشناسی ارشد، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش‌جوی کارشناسی ارشد، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>neda.asadi61@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلمات حسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جملات کذب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ضمایر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلمات مجزاگر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نشان‌گر احتیاط</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نشان‌گر نفی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>جمال‌زاده، محمدعلی (۱۳۴۵). خلقیات ما ایرانیان، ژنو: انتشارات مجلة مسائل ایران، شمارة 4.##عزیزی، سیروس و نگار مؤمنی (۱۳۹۱). زبا‌‌ن‌شناسی حقوقی (درآمدی بر زبان، جرم و قانون)، تهران: سازمان انتشارات جهاد دانشگاهی.##مدرسی، یحیی (۱۳۶۸). درآمدی بر جامعه‌شناسی زبان، تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##نراقی، حسن (۱۳۸۲). جامعه‌شناسی خودمانی، تهران: نشر اختران.##Adams, S. (2002). “Communication under Stress: Indicators of Veracityand Deception inWritingNarratives”, Ph.D Dissertation, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University.##Baumeister, R. F., E. Bratslavsky, M. Muraven, and D. M. Tice (1998). “Ego depletion: Is theactive self a limited resource?”, Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 74.##Borstal, B. and B. Schrank (2011). “Telling It Like It Is (and Isn&#039;t)”, Brno Studies in English, Vol. 37, Issue 2, 173.##Buller, D. and J. Burgoon (1996). “Interpersonal Deception Theory”, Communication Theory, Vol. 6, Issue 3.##DePaulo, B. M., D. A. Kashy, S. E. Kirkendol, M. Wyer and J. Epstein (May 1996). “Lying in everyday life”, Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, Vol. 70(5).##DePaulo, B. M., J. I. Stone, and G. D. Lassiter (1985a). “Deceiving and detecting deceit”, in B. R. Schlenkar (ed.), The self and Social life (323-370), NewYork: McGraw-Hill##DePaulo, B. M., J. I. Stone, and G. D. Lassiter (1985b). “Telling ingratiating lies: Effects of target sex and target attractiveness on verbal and non-verbal deceptive success”, Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 48.##Ekman, P. (2001). Telling Lies: Clues to Deceit in the Marketplace, Politics, and Marriage, New York: W.W. Norton.##Epstein, J.A., B. M. DePaulo and M. M. Wyer (1993). “Sex differences in lying: How women and men deal with the dilemma of deceit”, in M. Lewis and C. Saarni (eds.), Lying and deception in everyday life (126-147), Newyork: Guliford Press.##Frederking, R. E. (1996). “Grice&#039;s Maxims: Do the Right Thing”, Stanford: Presented at the Computation alImplicature Workshop at the AAAI-96 Spring Symposium Series.##Fuller, G. M., Biros, D. P., Delen, D. (2008). “Exploration of Feature Selection and Advanced Classification Models for High-Stakes Deception Detection”, Proceedings of the 41st Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences.##Goldweber, A. (2005). The Language of Lying, College of Agriculture and Life Sciences at Cornell University.##Grice, P. (1989). Studies in the Ways of Words, Cambridge, Mass: Harvard University Press.##Hancock, J. T., Curry, L., Goorha, S., and Woodworth, M. (2005). An automated linguistic analysis of deceptive and truth ful synchronous computer-mediated communication, Proceedings, 38th Hawaii international conference on system science.##Hirschberg, J., Benus, S., Brenier, J., Enos, F., Friedman, S., et al. (2005). ”Distinguishing Deceptive from Non-Deceptive Speech”, Proceedings of Interspeech-Eurospeech, 9th European Conference on Speech Communication and Technology, pp. 1833-1836. Bonn: ISCA.##Keila, P. S. and D. B. Skillicorn (2005). “Detecting unusual and Deceptive Communication in E-mail”, External technical report, school of computing, Queen’s university, Kingston, Ontario, Canada.##Larcker, D. F. (2012). “Detecting deceptive discussions in conference calls”, Journal of Accounting Research, Vol. 50, Issue 2.##Mihalcea, Rada and Carlo Strapparava (2009). “The Lie Detector: Explorations in the Automatic Recognition of Deceptive Language”, ACL/AFNLP (Short Papers).##Minkin, A. and D. Mosher (2008). “EDD showcase: Don’t be deceived”, Technology News, Vol. 14, No. 8.##Muraven, M., R. F. Baumeister, , and Tice, D. M. (1998). “Self-control as a limited resource: Regulatory depletionpatterns”, Journal of personality and social psychology, 74.##Newman, M. L., J. W. Pennebaker, D. S. Berry and J. M. Richards (2003). “Lying words: Predicting deception from linguistic styles”, Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin, 29.##Nyberg, D. (1993). The Varnished Truth, Chicago: The university of Chicago Press.##Pennebaker, J.W. and L. A. King, (1999). Linguistic styles: language use as an individual difference, J. Personal.soc.psychol, 77; 1296-312.##Porter, S., John C. Yuille (1996). “The language of deceit: An investigation of the verbal clues todeception in the interrogation context”, Law and Human Behavior, 20(4).##Saeed, J. (2008). Semantics (Introducing Linguistics series), 3rded., Oxford: Wiley-Blackwell,32.##Skillicorn, D. B. and P.S. Keila (June 2005). Detecting Unusual and Deceptive Communication in Email; External Technical Report, School of Computing, Queen&#039;s University, 2-12.##Tannen, D. (1990). “Sex, Lies and Conversation; Why Is It So Hard for Men and Women to Talk to Each Other?”, The Washington Post, June 24, 19.##Toma, Catalina, L., and J. T. Hancock (2010). Reading between the lines: linguistic cues to deception in online Dating Profiles, Proceedings of the ACM conference on computer-supported cooperative work (CSCW 2010), 5-8##Vrij, A. (2000). Detecting lies and deceit: The psychology of lying and its implications for professional practice, Chichester: John Wiley and Sons.##Vrij, A., K. Edward, K. P. Roberts, and R. Bull (2000). “Detecting Deceit via analysis of verbal and nonverbal behavior”, Journal of Nonverbal Behavior, 24.##Yule, G. (1947). Pragmatics, Oxford University Press.##Zhou, L., J. K. Burgoon, D. Twitchell, T. Qin and J. F. Nunamaker (2004). “A comparison of classification methods for predicting deception in computer-mediated communication”, Journal of Management Information Systems, 20.##Zhou, L., J. K. Burgoon, J. F. Nunamaker and D. Twitchell (2004). Automating linguistics-based cues for detecting deception in asynchronous computer-mediated communications, Group Decision and Negotiation, 13.##Zhou, L., J. K. Burgoon, Jay F. Jr. Nunamaker, and D. P. Twitchell (2004). ”AutomatedLinguistics Based Cues for Detecting Deception in Text-Based Asynchronous Computer-MediatedCommunication: An empirical investigation”, Group Decision and Negotiation, 13(1), January 2004, 23.##Zuckerman, M., B. M. DePaulo, and R. Rosenthal (1981). “Verbal and nonverbal communication of deception”, In L. Berkowitz (ed.), Advances in Experimental social psychology, Vol. 14, Newyork: Academic Press.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تاریخ دین زردشتی روش‌های بررسی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Analytical Approaches to the History of Zoroastrainism</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>دربارة تعیین زمان زردشت و دین هخامنشیان توافق‌هایی نسبی به دست آمد، اما آن‌چه هم‌چنان مورد بحث است دین ایرانیان پیش از زردشت است. عمده‌ترین مسئله در بررسی تاریخ دین زردشتی، ناپیوستگی میان سه پیکرة اساسی منابع است که عبارت‌اند از: اوستا، سنگ‌نبشته‌های هخامنشی، و ادبیات زردشتی که هیچ یک انعکاس‌دهندة دین عامة مردم نیست و گه‌گاه پاره‌ای از عقاید مردم در آن‌ها بازتاب یافته است. اما به هر حال منطقی‌تر آن است که از خلال همین آثار مبهم و غیرصریح محتوای فکری آغازین مردم ایران را، که پایه‌های اصلی دین آنان را تشکیل می‌دهند، بشناسیم. به طور کلی، در بررسی دین پیش‌زردشتی ایران سه رویکرد به نظر می‌رسد: 1. تاریخ دین را منحصراً بر اساس گاهان تعیین می‌کند و ابزار کار تفسیری است از اشارات گاهانی به‌جای‌مانده و انطباق آن‌ها بر سنت ودایی؛ 2. بر هم‌سازی و ترکیب شواهد اوستا و کتاب‌های پهلوی تأکید دارد و ارزش این مواد را در آن می‌داند که بازتاب‌دهندة مجموعة آموزه‌های زردشت و نمودار روند طبیعی رشد هستند و تغییرات حاصل‌شده در آن را موجب گسست در سنت و نفوذ ادیان دیگر نمی‌داند؛ 3. شواهد ترکیب‌شده از اوستا و کتاب‌های پهلوی را متنوع و انعطاف‌پذیر می‌شمارد و آن را دستگاه اعتقادی خشک نمی‌داند و مزدیسنای ساسانیان را دینی پویا و کارآمد توصیف می‌کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>There appears to be virtual agreements on the date of Zoroaster and on the fact that the religion of the Achaemenian dynasts is part of the history of Zoroastrianism. The subject which remains hotly debated is the reconstruction of a pre-Zoroastrian Iranian religion. The main problem in the study of Zoroastrian history is discontinuity between three distinct corpora of textual sources, namely: the Avesta, the Old Persian inscriptions and Zoroastrian literature, since none of them reflect the religion of the ordinary people. In the academic discussions of the history of Zoroastrianism, three different approaches are observed: The first approach (fragmentizing) rejects the notion of a single Zoroastrian tradition and concentrates on the Gāthās as the only source of information for Zarathustra&#039;s teachings, and compares its notions and references with the Vedic tradition. The second approach (harmonizing) emphasizes on the combined evidence of Avesta and Pahlavi books. Its main attitude is the recognition of the fact that the three different collections basically reflect the teaching of Zarathustra and developments are not due to ruptures and breaks in the tradition or because of influence of other religions. The third approach (diversifying) regards the combined evidence of Avesta and Pahlavi books as a variegated elastic tradition rather than a strict doctrinal system, and describes the Mazdeism of Sasanian as an active efficient religion.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>167</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>180</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهشید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>میرفخرایی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahshid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mirfakhraie</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد پژوهشکدۀ زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد پژوهشکدۀ زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mahshidmirfakhraie@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تاریخ دین زردشتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دین پیش‌زردشتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سنت ودایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سنگ‌نبشته‌های فارسی باستان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اوستا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آثار فارسی میانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ادبیات زردشتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>بنونیست، امیل (1350). دین ایرانی، ترجمة بهمن سرکاراتی، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##بویس، مری (1374). تاریخ کیش زردشت، ج 1، ترجمة همایون صنعتی‌زاده، تهران: توس.##بویس، مری (1375). تاریخ کیش زردشت: هخامنشیان، ج 2، ترجمة همایون صنعتی‌زاده، تهران: توس.##بویس، مری (1375). تاریخ کیش زردشت، ج 3: پس از حملة اسکندر گجسته، ترجمة همایون صنعتی‌زاده، تهران: توس.##بویس، مری (1381). زردشتیان، باورها و آداب‌ دینی آن‌ها، ترجمة عسگر بهرامی، تهران: ققنوس.##تفضلی، احمد (1376). تاریخ ادبیات ایران پیش از اسلام، تهران: سخن.##شاکد، شائول (1387). تحول ثنویت، تنوع آرای دینی در عصر ساسانی، ترجمة احمدرضا قائم‌مقامی، تهران: نشر ماهی.##کلنز، ژان (1386). «زردشت و اوستای قدیم»، مقالاتی دربارة زردشت و دین زردشتی، ترجمة احمدرضا قائم‌مقامی، تهران: فرزان روز.##کلنز، ژان (1386). «دین هخامنشیان؛ سؤالات اولیه»، مقالاتی دربارة زردشت و دین زردشتی، ترجمة سیداحمد قائم‌مقامی، تهران: فرزان روز.##نیبرگ، ساموئل (1359). دین‌های ایران باستان، ترجمة سیف‌الدین نجم‌آبادی، تهران: مرکز مطالعة فرهنگ‌ها.##نیولی، گراردو (1381). زمان و زادگاه زردشت، ترجمة سیدمنصور سیدسجادی، تهران: مؤسسة نشر آگه.##نیولی، گراردو (1387). آرمان ایران، جستاری در خاستگاه نام ایران، ترجمة سیدمنصور سیدسجادی، تهران: مؤسسة فرهنگی و هنری پیشین‌پژوه.##ویدن‌گرن، گئو (1377). دین‌های ایران، ترجمة منوچهر فرهنگ، تهران: آگاهان ایده.##Boyce, M. (1970). “Zoroastre the Priest”, BSOAS, 33.##Gershevitch, I. (1995). “Approaches to Zoroaster&#039;s Gathas”, Iran, 33.##Humbach, H. (1991). The Gathās of Zarathustra, part I, Heidelberg: Universitätsverlag C.Winter.##Jong, A. (1997). Traditions of the Magi, Netherlands: Brill.##Kent, R. G. (1953). Old Persian Grammar-Texts-Lexicon, New Haven: American Oriental Society.##Lommel, H. (1930). Die Religion Zarathustras. Nach dem Awesta dargestellt, Tübingen: Mohr.##Molé, M. (1963). Cult, mythe et cosmologie dans l&#039;Iran ancient, Paris: Presses Universitaires de France.##Widengren, G. )1954-1955.( “Stand und Aufgaben der Iranischen Religiongeschichte”, Numern 1, 2.##Wikander, S. (1941). Vayu. Texte und Untersuchungen zur Iranischen Religiongeschichte, T. I, Lund.##Wikander, S. (1946). Feuerpriester in Kleinasien und Iran, Lund.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>پهلویات کتیبه‌ای 2 : (1) کتیبة سنگ‌مزار حاجی‌آباد استخر (نقش رستم 1) و بازخوانی کتیبة تنگ جلو (سمیرم 1)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Isncriptions Pahlavica 2: Funarary Inscription Haji-ābād, Estaxr (Naqš-e Rostam 2)
 and the Revising of Tang-e Jelo Inscription (Semirom 1)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>کتیبة حاضر از مجموعه کتیبه‌های مزارنوشته به خط و زبان پهلوی ساسانی است. این کتیبه در مأموریت اینجانب به سال 1382 در حوالی روستای حاجی‌آباد، حد فاصل میان تخت جمشید و نقش رستم، در استخر باستانی دیده شده بود. این کتیبه در ۷ سطر نوشته شده است و بر بالای آن هم دخمه یا استودانی وجود دارد که محل دفن صاحب قبر بوده است. در آغاز، تصور بر این بود که کتیبه تازه یافته شده است اما، در جست‌وجوهای نگارنده، مشخص شد که هرتسفلد این کتیبه را دیده و از آن قالب هم تهیه کرده بود. این کتیبه از آنِ شخصی به نام «پورگ» پسر «روشن ـ آدُر» است. در این مقاله، بازخوانی تازه‌ای هم از کتیبة «تنگ جلو» (سمیرم ۱) شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The present inscription is among funerary inscriptions in Pahlavi language of the Sasanids. This inscription had caught my attention during a duty trip in 1382š. To and around Haji-ābād village, located in a district between Taxt-e Jamšid (Persepolis) and Naqš-e Rostam in ancient Estaxr. The inscription appears in 7 lines and over it there stands a Astōdan/ Daxmag which had been the resting place of its proprietor. At first it was believed that the inscription had been newly discovered but as further research was performed, it was revealed that Ernest Herzfeld had had already seen this inscription and had even prepared a mold of it. This inscription belonged a person called Pūrag son of Rōšn-Ādur. In this paper also appears a new revising of Tang-e Jelo Inscription (Semirom 1). سانی است. این کتیبه در مأموریت اینجانب به سال 1382 در حوالی روستای حاجی‌آباد، حد فاصل میان تخت جمشید و نقش رستم، در استخر باستانی دیده شده بود. این کتیبه در ۷ سطر نوشته شده است و بر بالای آن هم دخمه یا استودانی وجود دارد که محل دفن صاحب قبر بوده است. در آغاز، تصور بر این بود که کتیبه تازه یافته شده است اما، در جست‌وجوهای نگارنده، مشخص شد که هرتسفلد این کتیبه را دیده و از آن قالب هم تهیه کرده بود. این کتیبه از آنِ شخصی به نام «پورگ» پسر «روشن ـ آدُر» است. در این مقاله، بازخوانی تازه‌ای هم از کتیبة «تنگ جلو» (سمیرم ۱) شده است.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>181</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>195</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سیروس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نصراله‌زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Cyrus</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nasrollahzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار و عضو هیئت علمی پژوهشکدۀ زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار و عضو هیئت علمی پژوهشکدۀ زبان‌شناسی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>cyrusnasr@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سنگ‌ مزار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حاجی‌آباد استخر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تخت جمشید</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تنگ جلو</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دخمه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ترومپلمن، لئو (1376). «قبور و آیین تدفین در دورة ساسانی»، ترجمة مولود شادکام، مجلة باستان‌شناسی و تاریخ، س 8، ش 1.##تفضلی، احمد (1376). تاریخ ادبیات ایران پیش از اسلام، تهران: سخن.##فرای، ریچارد (1352). «دخمه‌های اصطخر و کوه نقش رستم»، سی و چهار خطابه، سومین کنگرة تحقیقات ایرانی، ج 1، تهران: انتشارات بنیاد فرهنگ ایران.##مصطفوی، محمدتقی (1343). اقلیم پارس، آثارتاریخی و اماکن باستانی فارس، تهران: انجمن آثار ملی.##نصراله‌زاده، سیروس (1385). کتیبه‌های پهلوی کازرون، تهران: کازرونیه.##نصراله‌زاده، سیروس (1387). «پهلویات کتیبه‌ای 1: مروری بر کتیبة ابنون در برم دلک از دورة شاپور اول»، جشن‌نامة دکتر بدرالزمان قریب، به کوشش زهره زرشناس و ویدا نداف، تهران: طهوری.##نصراله‌زاده، سیروس و عمادالدین شیخ‌الحکمایی (1391). «گورنوشتة پهلوی سنگ زین (کازرون 16)»، زبان‌ها و گویش‌های ایرانی، دورة جدید، ش 1، تهران: فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی.##نصراله‌زاده، سیروس و محسن جاوری (1381). «مزارنوشته‌هایی نویافته به پهلوی ساسانی از چشمه‌ناز سمیرم»، نامة ایران باستان، س 2، ش 2.##نصراله‌زاده، سیروس و همت محمدی (1390). «گورنوشته‌ای دیگر از کازرون، کتیبة بُخُنگ (کازرون 15)»، زبان‌شناخت، دورة دوم، ش 4، تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##Boyce, Mary (1998). “Eṣṭaḵr, ii. as a Zoroastrian Religious Center”, Encyclopedia Iranica, Vol. VIII, Fasc. 6, pp. 643-646, available online at&gt; http://www.iranicaonline.org/articles/estakr-#ii##de Blois, F. (1993). “Middle-Persian Funerary Inscriptions from South-Western Iran”, Medioiranica: Proceedings of the International Colloquium Organized by Katholieke Universiteit Leuven from the 21st to the 23rd of May 1990, ed. W. Skalmowski and A. Van Tongerloo, Leuven (= Orientalia Lovaniensia Analecta).##Farjmirad, Mahdokht (2013). Mortuary Practice in Ancient Iran from the Achaemenid to the Sasanian Perids (mid sixth c. BC to mid seventh c. AD), Universiteit Gent. Part I. Text, Part II. Catalogue.##Gignoux, Ph. (1984-85). “Religions de L‘ Iran Ancient, I. Épigraphie Sasanide&quot;, Conférence de M. Philippe Gignoux, in: École pratique des hautes éeudes, section des sciences religieuses. Annuaire. Tome 93, &gt;http://www.persee.fr/web/ouvrages/home/prescript/article/ephe_0000-0002_1984_num_97_93_16183#&lt;##Gignoux, Ph. (1986). Noms propres Sassanides en moyen–perse épigraphique, Iranisches Personennamenbuch, Band II, Faszikiel 2, Wien.##Gignoux, Ph. (1986-2001. Supplement). Noms propres sassanides en moyen- perse epigraphique, Iranisches Personennamenbuch, Band II, Faszikiel 3, Wien.##Gignoux, Ph. and Ch. Jullien, Jullien Florence (2009). Noms Propres Syriaques d’Origine Iranienne, Iranisches Personennamenbuch, Band VII, Faszikeil 5, Wien.##Gropp, Gerd (1970). &quot;Bericht über eine Reise in West- und südiran&quot;, Archaeologische Mitteilungen aus Iran 3.##Huff, Dietrich (1999). “Fārs, v. Monuments”, Encyclopedia Iranica, Vol. IX, Fasc. 4, available online at&gt; http://www.iranicaonline.org/articles/fars-v##Skjærvø, P. O (2003). “Herzfeld, Ernest iv. Herzfeld and The Paikuli Inscription”, Encycolopedia Iranica, Vol. XII, Fasc. 3, pp. 298-300, available on line at &lt;http://www.iranicaonline.org/articles/herzfeld-ernst-iv&gt;, (accessed online at January 18, 2013).##Skjærvø, P. O. (2005). “Herzfeld and Iranian Studies”, in Ann C. Gunter and Stefan R. Hauser, eds., Ernst Herzfeld and the Development of the Near Eastern Studies, 1900-1950, Brill.##Tafazzoli, Ahmad (1991). “L&#039;inscription Funeraire de Kāzerūn (Paršiān)”, Studia Iranica 20, f. 2.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تغییرات معنایی واژه در زبان‌های فارسی و روسی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Study on Lexical Semantic Changes in Russian and Persian</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تغییر معنایی واژه‌ها، ضمن غنی‌سازی گنجینة لغات هر زبان، به شعرا و ادبا این امکان را می‌دهد که به کلمات جان ببخشند و ابداع و خلق هنرمندانه‌ای از خویش باقی گذارند. غنی‌سازی گنجینة لغات زبان‌ها و از جمله زبان‌های روسی و فارسی به شیوه‌های گوناگون انجام می‌پذیرد. بر این اساس، در این نوشتار سعی بر آن است که با روش تحلیلی به این پرسش پاسخ داده شود که چه فرایندهایی در روند تغییر معنایی واژگان در مفهوم‌سازی و غنی‌سازی گنجینة لغات در زبان روسی و فارسی وجود دارد؟ بررسی نمونه‌های موجود مؤید آن است که، استفاده از ابزارها (پیشوند‌گذاری، پسوند‌گذاری، ترکیب ریشه‌ها و غیره) و عناصر گوناگون، یعنی تکواژ‌ها، بر اساس الگوهای مشخص در واژه‌سازی، یکی از مهم‌ترین شیوه‌ها در این روند است. افزون‌ بر شیوة اصلی واژه‌سازی، کلماتِ موجود در زبان، در روند استفاده‌، به غیر از مفهوم اولیة خود برای بیان مفاهیم دیگر نیز استفاده می‌شوند. گاه تغییراتی نیز، به دلیل هم‌نشینی و مجاورت تکواژ‌های زبان، در زمان واژه‌سازی‌سازی، در کلمات ایجاد می‌شود. در نتیجه مفهوم‌سازی و غنی‌سازی گنجینۀ لغات در زبان فقط معلول خلق واژه نیست بلکه، با کمک واژه‌های موجود در زبان، گویشو‌ر می‌تواند نیاز واژگانی خود را با تغییرات معنایی واژه‌های موجود برطرف کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Semantic changes in words, enriching the vocabulary of each language, make it possible for poets and literary experts to enliven the lexis and create an artistic piece of work. Enriching the vocabulary of languages, including Russian and Persian, is done in different ways, one of the most important one being the use of tools such as suffixing, prefixing, root combinations, etc., based on the specific patterns of word-making in the language. In addition to this main method, the lexis of a language can be used for other concepts apart from its original meaning. (cf. Bear: Animal; Bear: Human, Irony of the clumsy). Due to the proximity and juxtaposition of morphemes in word-making, some changes may occur in words. Accordingly, in this article, by analyzing semantic changes in lexis in Russian and Persian, it is established that conceptualization and enrichment of a vocabulary is due not only to the effect of word creations, but also to the help of lexis in language, by which speakers can take care of their needs for words by semantic changes of the lexis. ect the teaching of Zarathustra and developments are not due to ruptures and breaks in the tradition or because of influence of other religions. The third approach (diversifying) regards the combined evidence of Avesta and Pahlavi books as a variegated elastic tradition rather than a strict doctrinal system, and describes the Mazdeism of Sasanian as an active efficient religion.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>197</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>212</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شهرام</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>همت‌زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Shahram</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hemmatzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه زبان روسی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه زبان روسی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sh_hematzadeh@sbu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مداینی اول</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Madayeni Aval</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه زبان روسی، دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه زبان روسی، دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amadayen@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تغییرات معنایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>واژه‌سازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مجاز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>استعاره</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مجاز مرسل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بلاغت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ارسطو (1337). فن شعر، ترجمۀ عبدالحسین زرین‌کوب، تهران: بنگاه ترجمه و نشر کتاب.##افراسیابی، غلامرضا، سیدمحمد مهدی جعفری و حسین بحتویی (1385). «جستار دربارة مجاز مرسل»، مجلۀ علوم اجتماعی و انسانی شیراز، دورة بیست و پنجم، ش 3.##اوشاکوف، واژه‌نامه: http://www.svetozar.ru/index/id/38481/index.html##ایرج میرزا (1353). دیوان اشعار، به اهتمام محمدجعفر محجوب، تهران: گلشن.##جرجانی، شیخ عبدالقاهر (1368). اسرارالبلاغه، ترجمۀ جلیل تجلیل، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##دبیرسیاقی، محمد (1370). پیش‌آهنگان شعر فارسی، تهران: آموزش انقلاب اسلامی.##شفیعی کدکنی، محمدرضا (1380). صور خیال در شعر فارسی، تهران: آگاه.##شقاقی، ویدا (1389). مبانی صرف واژه، تهران: سمت.##شمیسا،‌ سیروس (1381). بیان، تهران: فردوس.##شمیسا، ‌سیروس (1383). نقد ادبی، تهران: فردوس.##صفوی، کوروش (1386). هفت گفتار دربارۀ ترجمه، تهران: نشر مرکز.##فالر، راجر، رمن یاکوبسن و دیوید لاج (1369). زبان‌شناسی و نقد ادبی، ترجمۀ محمد خوزان و حسین پاینده، تهران: نشر نی.##کمالی روستا، حبیب (1386). «مجازها در زبان و ادبیات آلمانی و فارسی»، پژوهش‌های زبان‌های خارجی، ش 42.##کزازی، میرجلال‌الدین (1375). زیباشناسی سخن پارسی 1، بیان، تهران: نشر مرکز.##کزازی،‌ میرجلال‌الدین (1368). بیان، تهران: نشر مرکز.##هاکس، ترنس (1377). استعاره، ترجمۀ فرزانه طاهری، تهران: نشر مرکز.##مداینی اول، علی (1391). واژه‌شناسی زبان روسی، تهران: سمت.##Шайкевич, А.Я. (1995). Введение в лингвистику, Москва.##Кобозева, И. М. (2007). Лингвистическая семантика. Москва.##Лекант, П. А. (2004). Современный русский язык, Москва.##Розенталь Д.Э., Голуб И.Б., Теленкова М.А. (1991). Современный русский язык, Москва: Высшая школа.##Виноградов, В.В. Избранные труды: Лексикология и лексикография.##Виноградов, В.В. (1959). Основные типы лексических значений слова: Лексикология и лексикография, Москва.##Энциклопедия для детей, Т.(1999). 10: Языкознание. Русский язык. Москва.##Шанский Н.М., Боброва Т.А. (1994). Этимологический словарь русского языка. Москва.##Розенталь Д. Э., Теленкова М. А. (1985). Словарь-справочник лингвистических терминов. Москва. С. 139.##Розенталь Д. Э. и Теленкова М. А. Словарь-справочник лингвистических терминов. Пособие для учителей. Изд. 2-е, испр. и доп. Москва.(1976). “Просвещение”, 543 с.##Фасмер М.(1986), Этимологический словарь русского языка, Москва.##Даль, В.(1869). Толковый словарь живого великорусского языка, Санкт-Петербург.##Ушаков, Д.Н.(1940). Толковый словарь русского языка, Москва.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				