<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>12</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Conceptual metaphors in Persian: A cognitive perspective and a corpus driven Analysis</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>استعاره‌های مفهومی در زبان فارسی؛ تحلیلی شناختی و پیکره‌مدار</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>39</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>61</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2184</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آزیتا</FirstName>
					<LastName>افراشی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زبانشناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>عاصی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زبانشناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کامیار</FirstName>
					<LastName>جولایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>زبانشناسی-  پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی، تهران،</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present thesis studies conceptual metaphors in a representative corpus of Persian texts. Exploiting the Persian Linguistic Database (PLDB), we sampled a corpus of contemporary written texts, based on their similarity to the colloquial language of the Persian speakers, and then tried to identify and extract the relevant conceptual metaphors. The sample corpus contains of 10 texts of contemporary Iranian writers, naming Hedayat, Jamalzadeh, Daneshvar, Aale -Ahmad….et al. Analyzing the corpus, the writer managed to extract nearly 2000 conceptual metaphors in the form of 600 name of the mappings. Then the conceptual metaphors classified according to the Lakoff and Johnson classification (1980) as ontological, structural and orientational, and a class of conceptual metaphors that Lakoff and turner (1989) presented as image metaphors. &lt;br /&gt;As the next step we tried to determine the proportion of these classes comparing with each other. We concluded that the Persian speakers make use of ontological metaphors in their daily language, more than the other classes. Then we tried to determine which conceptual mappings and source domains are the most common ones in each class. &lt;br /&gt; Due to the corpus driven approach in the analysis of metaphors, considerable results obtained. For example it was observed that the abstract concepts as life, emotions or time are understood via some concrete domains as, objects, containers and personification. In addition, ideas about adopting a corpus driven approach in analyzing the conceptual metaphors, and extending the sampled corpus findings to large corpora were discussed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر به بررسی استعاره‌های مفهومی در پیکره‌ای نمونه از زبان فارسی می‌پردازد. در این پژوهش تلاش شده است تا با بهره‌گیری از پایگاه داده‌های زبان فارسی، پیکره‌ای از متون نوشتاری زبان فارسی معاصر که شباهت بیشتری به زبان روزمره سخنوران دارد، نمونه‌گیری و استعاره‌های مفهومی نهفته در آن استخراج گردد. سپس این استعاره‌ها براساس طبقه‌بندی لیکاف و جانسون Johnson, 1980) &amp; (Lakoff ، در قالب استعاره‌های «ساختاری»، «هستی‌شناختی»، «جهتی» و نیز طبقه‌ای از استعاره‌های مفهومی که لیکاف و ترنر(Lakoff &amp; Turner,1989)، تحت عنوان «استعاره‌های تصویری» معرفی کردند، دسته‌بندی شدند. در گام بعدی نسبت بسامد هریک از این استعاره‌ها در مقایسه با یکدیگر تعیین شد و تلاش شد تا پر بسامدترین حوزه‌های مبدأ در طبقه استعاره‌های هستی شناختی تعیین گردد و در مجموع با توجه به یافته‌های پیکره‌ای مشخص گردد که فارسی زبانان بیشتر از چه حوزه‌های مبدأیی برای بیان مفاهیم انتزاعی بهره می‌برند. در خلال این پژوهش، نگارندگان به دلیل بهره‌گیری از پیکره دریافتند که طبقه‌بندی لیکاف و جانسون(1980) از انواع استعاره‌های مفهومی، ملاک دقیقی برای محک یافته‌ها در یک پژوهش پیکره مدار نمی‌باشد و همچنین یافته‌های پیکره‌ای در زبان فارسی در مواردی اصل یکسویگی در نظریه استعاره ‌مفهومی را نقض می‌کنند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استعاره مفهومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌شناسی پیکره‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معنی‌شناسی شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل پیکره‌مدار</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2184_3641ded0cc9b58bf8d6a2eba500cf15e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
