<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>7</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Manichaean Parable Based on the Pattern of Cosmogony
in Middle Persian</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تمثیلی مانوی بر اساس الگوی اسطورۀ آفرینش به زبان پارسی میانه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>15</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>28</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">866</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امید</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهبهانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This paper first familiarizes the reader with some general information about&lt;br /&gt;Manichaeism and Manichaean cosmogony. Then, after defining “parable” as a literary&lt;br /&gt;genre, the whole Manichaean myth of creation is considered as a parable. At the next&lt;br /&gt;stage, the role of parable is emphasized as a tool to facilitate the understanding of&lt;br /&gt;religious, philosophical, and moral doctrines for the masses. After defining, and&lt;br /&gt;establishing the functional capability of parable, a Manichaean Middle Persian parable&lt;br /&gt;is studied and analyzed, according to the pattern of the Manichaean myth of creation.&lt;br /&gt;At the end, a comprehensive comparison is made between the characters and elements&lt;br /&gt;of the Manichaean myth of creation and the Middle Persian parable.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این جُستار خواننده نخست با کلیاتی دربارۀ مانویت و اسطورۀ آفرینش در کیش مانی آشنا می‌شود. آن‌گاه نگارنده، با تعریف نوع ادبی تمثیل و داستان تمثیلی، اسطورۀ آفرینش مانویت را به مثابۀ داستانی تمثیلی در نظر می‌گیرد و بر نقش تمثیل، در جایگاه یکی از ابزار‌های فن بلاغت در آسان ‌فهم‌کردن اصول دینی، فلسفی و اخلاقی برای تودة مردم، تأکید می‌کند. با این مقدمات، تمثیلی مانوی به زبان پارسی میانه بر اساس الگوی اسطورۀ آفرینش مانی بررسی و تحلیل می‌شود. این داستان با بیانی نمادین به اسارت نخستین انسان در زندانِ ماده اشاره دارد. بررسی حاضر به یاری مقایسۀ شخصیت‌ها و عناصر سازندۀ اسطورۀ آفرینش مانی با این داستان تمثیلی صورت می‌گیرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مانویت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اسطورة آفرینش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">داستان تمثیلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فن بلاغت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان پارسی میانه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_866_7f6770583417705c95d9877b145f100d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
