<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Cognitive Approach to Surveying Child Literary Texts</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل متون داستانی کودک با رویکردِ شعرشناسی‌شناختی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>25</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">109</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آزیتا</FirstName>
					<LastName>افراشی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد‌یار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>نعیمی حشکوانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبان‌شناسی پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the interdeciplenaries that applies cognitive linguistics is cognitive poetics. Cognitive poetics deals with the relationship between mind and literary texts. In this approach, literature is not separate from language, and understanding literature is based on our knowledge from the real world. Cognitive approach to literature studies how literary mind understands events. Present research tries to explain parabolic projection through the concept of literary and parabolic mind theory of Turner (1996) and to answer how our mind and literary texts are being related. Emphasizing on the relationship between mind and language, cognitive linguistics approach confirms that the best exemplar for cognitive analysis comes from early stages of language development. This analysis provides important evidences for cognitive poetics. Therefore in this research we selected and analyzed two child stories. Data analysis on schema projection shows that representation of these schemata in Persian child stories are below the anticipated level. But with regard to semantic fields, the research results confirm the hypotheses presented.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از میان رشته‌هایی که امروزه دستاوردهای زبان‌شناسیِ‌شناختی را به کار می‌گیرد مطالعات ادبی با رویکردِ شناختی است که اصطلاحاً به آن شعرشناسیِ‌شناختی گفته می‌شود. شعرشناسیِ‌شناختی به رابطۀ ذهن انسان با متون ادبی می‌پردازد. در این رویکرد، نظام ادبیات جدا از نظام زبان نیست و درک زبانِ ادبیات بر پایۀ دانش ما از دنیای اطراف صورت می‌گیرد. رویکرد شناختی به ادبیات چگونگی درک رویدادها را به وسیلة آنچه در این رویکرد اصطلاحاً ذهنِ ادبی نامیده می‌شود بررسی می‌کند. در میان رویکردهای موجود نسبت به تحلیل آثار ادبی، جدیدترین دیدگاه برای تحلیل ادبیات از منظر زبان‌شناسی، همین رویکرد شعرشناسی‌شناختی است. در تحقیق حاضر سعی بر آن است تا با استفاده از نظریۀ ذهن ادبی و قصه‌مدارِ ترنر (M.Turner 1996) مفهوم فرافکنی قصه‌مدار توضیح و به این پرسش پاسخ داده شود که چگونه ذهن انسان با متون ادبی رابطه برقرار می‌کند. تأکید بر پیوند ذهن و زبان در نگرش زبان‌شناسی‌شناختی مؤید این نکته است که بهترین نمونه‌ها برای تحلیل‌های شناختی از مراحل اولیۀ رشد زبانی به دست می‌آید. تحلیل متون ادبیات کودک می‌تواند شواهد با ارزشی برای شعرشناسی‌شناختی به دست دهد. بر این اساس، در پژوهش حاضر، دو داستان کودک از کتاب‌های برگزیده انتخاب و بررسی شد. تحلیل داده‌ها در مورد فرافکنی دانش طرحواره‌ای حاکی از این امر است که بازنمود این سازه‌ها در متون داستانی کودک در ایران موفق نبوده است اما، در مورد واحدهای هم‌حوزه، نتایج تحلیل با فرضیۀ تحقیق هم‌سویی نشان می‌دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌شناسی‌شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شعرشناسی‌شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ذهن ادبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قصه‌مداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طرحوارۀ تصوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_109_b68592dab9d0819acbe1e1504f0e2f96.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Manušcihr ī Jawānjamān’s Report on the 
Rain Making Tištar According
 to the Middle Persian Text, Dādestān ī Dēnīg</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>گزارش منوچهر جوان جم از تیشتر باران‌ساز در متن فارسی میانة دادستان دینی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>27</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>38</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">110</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمود</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری دهقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Rain is an Ahuric phenomenon in Iranian myth. It seems that the rise of this myth is caused by the weather conditions in the Iranian plateau. “Tištar”, the myth of rain is mentioned in Avesta and most of the Middle-Persian texts but none of these texts have ever referred to Dādestān ī Dēnīg. The opinion of Manuchehr, the son of Jawān-Jam and the author of Dādestān ī Dēnīg on myth of rain and the role of “Tištar” is stated in this article.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">باران در اساطیر ایران پدیده‌ای اهورایی است. پیدایی این اسطوره به‌واسطۀ ویژگی‌های آب و هوایی فلات ایران امری منطقی است. اسطورۀ باران‌سازی «تیشتر» در اوستا و غالب متون فارسی میانه آمده است اما هیچ یک از این منابع اشاره‌ای به دادستان دینی نکرده‌اند. در این مقاله، گزارش منوچهر جوان جم، مؤلف دادستان دینی، دربارة اسطورۀ باران و نقش «تیشتر» در ایجاد این پدیده بررسی شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اسطوره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">باران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ابر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تیشتر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اپوش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_110_05d0cfc6605c099ff07f14d73b050dd5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Sibawayhi and the Beginnings of Arabic Grammar</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سیبویه و سرآغاز دستورنویسی زبان عربی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>39</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>50</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">111</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ژیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>خانجانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی دانشگاه پیام‌نور مرکز الیگودرز لرستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this brief research is to study the viewpoints and opinions of Sibawayhi, one of the most illustrated Muslim thoughtfuls,about language and linguistics. He was the leader of the Basran school, his one work is known as &quot;sibawayhi&#039;s Book&quot;, Kitaab Sibawayhi. It is, in fact, one of the earliest books in Arabic at all, and was probably dictated informally to Sibawayhi&#039;s principal pupil al-Akhfas, who then issued it as a book after his master&#039;s death. His personal insight into the nature of language and his analytical genius alone enabled him to create an exhaustive Arabic grammatical system which has been the reference point for all subsequent grammatical speculation to this day, and for which it very soon became known as the “Quran of grammar&quot;. In this paper, we&#039;ll try to mention syntax, morphology and lastly phonology, reflecting Sibawayhi&#039;s own notion of appropriate sequence for linguistic analysis.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله، آرای سیبویه ـ دانشمند مسلمان و ایرانی ـ دربارۀ زبان و زبان‌شناسی بررسی شده است. این عالم بزرگ ایرانی، که از رهبران نحلۀ بصره نیز بود، در نحو زبان عربی به کمال رسید. کتاب او با عنوان الکتاب از معروف‌ترین و معتبرترین کتاب‌ها در زمینۀ نحو است. الکتاب طرز توصیف دستور زبان عربی را تعیین و تثبیت کرد. تصویری که او از دستور زبان عربی رسمی و کتابتی ترسیم نمود به‌ذات همان است که امروزیان از آن زبان در ذهن دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مکتب کوفه و بصره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اجزای سخن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رسایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اِعراب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">افعال‌شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استعمال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الغا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_111_dd4f0143251fef1300a8658f10a66080.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>AZOFA: A New Approach to Teaching Persian to 
Non-Persian Speakers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آزوفا: رویکردی جدید در آموزش زبان فارسی به غیرفارسی‌زبانان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>51</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>70</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">112</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>صفاری‌مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present article refers to the writer’s twenty years of experience at the Institute for Humanities and Cultural Studies in the field of teaching Iranian language and culture to non-Persian speakers. The writer has set his teaching missions to Bosnia and South Korea universities as a basis for related research and has proceeded to put forth the principal problems and shortcomings of the field by studying the situation of teaching Persian language and positive outcome of responsible organizations. Then the formation of Azofa group during the recent years and the new approach of the Institute in the field has been propounded. According to the new approach, it is required in the first place that instruction of Persian language to non-Persian speakers and Iranian younger generation abroad be promoted vigorously by relying on modern pedagogic methods and cooperating with responsible organizations. In the second place, the propagation of Iranian culture and civilization which is part of the human cultural legacy should be defined as the more valuable target of instruction.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقالة حاضر به بیست سال تجربة نگارنده در پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی در حوزة ‌آموزش زبان و فرهنگ ایران به غیرفارسی‌زبانان پرداخته است. نگارنده مأموریت‌های آموزشی خود در دانشگاه‌های بوسنی و کرة ‌جنوبی را پایة تحقیقات مربوط قرار داده و، با بررسی وضعیت آموزش زبان فارسی و عملکرد مثبت نهادهای متولی، به طرح مسائل و کاستی‌های عمده پرداخته؛ آنگاه شکل‌گیری بخش آزوفا در سال‌های اخیر و رویکرد جدید پژوهشگاه در این حوزه را مطرح ساخته است. براساس این رویکرد، اولاً لازم است که سطح آموزش زبان فارسی به غیرفارسی‌زبانان و فرزندان ایرانی دور از وطن، با تکیه بر روش‌های نوین آموزشی و همکاری با نهادهای متولی، به‌طور جدی ارتقا داده شود و، ثانیاً، ترویج جذابیت‌های فرهنگی و تمدنی ایرانیان به‌عنوان بخشی از میراث فرهنگ بشری هدف والاتر آموزش زبان تعریف شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">: آموزش زبان فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">میراث فرهنگی ایران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نهادهای متولی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شیوه‌های آموزشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جذابیت‌های صوتی‌تصویری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_112_ca9311410686f982ecda7156da832568.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Old Iranian hu- in Iranian Dialects</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحول - hu̯ ایرانی باستان در گویش‌های ایرانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>71</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>86</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">113</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اسفند‌یار</FirstName>
					<LastName>طاهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد‌یار دانشگاه بوعلی‌سینای همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Old Iranian (OIr.) hu- has developed in Iranian dialects in different form. This paper deals with development of OIr. hu- in Iranian and West middle Iranian languages, the development of this cluster is described in New Northwestern and Southwestern Iranian dialects. OIr. hu- has changed in five form xw- , x- , h- , w- and f- in Iranian dialects. And these changes can be classified in two groups: 1. hu- &gt; xw- &gt; x-&gt; h- 2. hu- &gt; wh- &gt; w- &gt; f- . Northwestern dialects show both changes groups, and show all of five developments, whereas Southwestern dialects show more similarity, and all of them have developed in first way. At the end of this paper Iranian dialects are classified according to this cluster change</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">خوشۀ همخوانی hu̯– ایرانی باستان در گویش‌های ایرانی به شکل‌های مختلفی تحول یافته است. در این مقاله، پس از شرح مختصر پیشینۀ تحول hu̯– ایرانی باستان در زبان‌های ایرانی دورۀ باستان و ایرانی میانۀ غربی، چگونگی تحول آن در گویش‌های نو شمال غربی و جنوب غربی بررسی شده است. hu̯– ایرانی باستان به پنج صورت تحول یافته و دو روند کلی را پیموده است: روند نخست: hu̯– &gt; xw– &gt; x– &gt; h–، روند دوم: hu̯– &gt; wh– &gt;w– &gt; f– . گویش‌های شمال غربی روند یکسانی را نشان نمی‌دهند و، در آنها، هر دو روند تحول و هر پنج دگرگونی اصلی را می‌بینیم. اما در گویش‌های جنوب غربی هماهنگی بیشتری دیده می‌شود و همۀ این گویش‌ها روند نخست تحول را پیموده‌اند. در پایان این مقاله، گویش‌های ایرانی، بر اساس نوع تحول hu̯– ایرانی باستان در آنها، دسته بندی شده‌اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گویش‌های ایرانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">hu̯– ایرانی باستان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گویش‌های شمال غربی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گویش‌های جنوب غربی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_113_363b3679442a459c63d771e457125b63.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Stylistics of Web Writing in Persian</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سبک‌شناسی وبلاگ‌نویسی به زبان فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>87</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>98</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">115</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید‌مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>عاصی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>مسگر‌خویی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری زبان‌شناسی پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In this paper, the characteristics of the Persian web writings are explored, regarding to the use of special style. This research shows that the web writings and their development, especially between youth and future generation, and the use of special kind of the language in this web writings can have extensive effects on the change of Persian language, especially formal writings, Persian script, and the other hand, on the globalization of the language. So accidental samples are collected and after subjective classification, their linguistic characteristics are explored from their point of view of the linguistics. As a consequence, a kind of linguistics style which is like to informal spoken Persian is used in these web writings the style has unique characteristics while it reserves some characteristics of the formal writings. Finally the linguistics characteristics of the style are explored.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله، ویژگی‌های زبانی وب‌نوشت‌های فارسی از جهت استفاده از سبک خاصی از زبان بررسی خواهد شد. در این بررسی نشان داده می‌شود که ادامة روند وبلاگ‌نویسی و گسترش فزایندة آن، به خصوص در بین نسل جوان امروزی و نسل‌های آتی، و استفاده از نوع خاصی از زبان در این وبلاگ‌ها ممکن است تأثیرات قابل توجهی در تغییر زبان فارسی، به خصوص نوشتار رسمی، خط زبان فارسی و، از سوی دیگر، جهانی کردن این زبان بگذارد. برای این منظور، نمونه‌هایی تصادفی از بین هزاران وبلاگ فارسی جمع‌آوری شد و، پس از طبقه‌بندی موضوعی آنها، ویژگی‌های زبانی سبک این وبلاگ‌ها از دیدگاه زبان‌شناختی بررسی شد. آنگاه این نتیجه به ‌دست آمد که نوعی سبک زبانی نزدیک به فارسی گفتاری غیررسمی در این وب‌نوشت‌ها به چشم می‌خورد که ویژگی‌های منحصربه‌فردی دارد، اما برخی ویژگی‌های نوشتار رسمی را نیز حفظ کرده است. در پایان، ویژگی‌های زبانی این سبک بررسی و توصیف شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سبک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سبک‌شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جامعه‌شناسی زبان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سبک‌شناسی اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وب‌نوشت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_115_c69f51169b0be80b56dd824f87b9aa84.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Stōš in Middle Persian Texts and Zoroastrian Rituals</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ستوش در متون فارسی میانه و آیین‌های زرتشتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>99</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>105</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">116</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرزانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>گشتاسب</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد‌یار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Stōš is a ritualistic word which is used in several meanings in Middle Persian texts. In this article, the different meanings of this word is investigated, the present ritual remaining of Stōš is described and finally a new etymology for this word is proposed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">واژة آیینی «ستوش/ سدوش» به چند معنا در متون فارسی میانه به کار رفته است. در این مقاله معانی گوناگون این واژه بررسی شده است، به مراسمِ بازمانده از آیین ستوش اشاره و در پایانِ مقاله اشتقاقی نو برای واژة ستوش پیشنهاد شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ستوش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سدوش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آیین‌های پس از مرگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پادافره سه‌شبه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هماگ‌دین</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_116_f3d37a98c6841602ab9b779b0ab641e8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Structure of Nutrition in the Myth of &quot;Mashi and Mashyaneh&quot;</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ساختار تغذیه در اسطورة مشی و مشیانه براساس متون زبان‌های باستانی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>107</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>120</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">117</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهار</FirstName>
					<LastName>مختاریان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد‌یار دانشگاه هنر اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In this article the writer has depicted the role of the nourishment in the formation of the culture by investigating the Persian mythology of the first human beings, Mashia and Mashianeh. By comparing the narration of this mythology with the similar ones, the author has shown that the vegetarianism is the ideal form of nourishment in the Iranian culture, while the carnivorism is the contrasting lowest form and eating milk and eggs is a phase in between.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله، اسطورة ایرانی نخستین جفت انسان، مشی و مشیانه، بررسی و نقش تغذیه در این اسطوره در شکل‌گیری فرهنگ و ارزش‌گذاری مربوط به آن توضیح داده می‌شود. با مطابقة صورت‌های مختلف، نشان می‌دهیم که صورت آرمانی تغذیه، در فرهنگ ایران پیش از اسلام، تغذیة گیاهی و صورت متقابل و اسفل آن تغذیة گوشتی است. واسطه‌ای که میان این دو صورت متضاد در نظر گرفته شده است، تغذیه با شیر و تخم‌مرغ است که نه غذایی گیاهی‌اند نه غذایی گوشتی. بررسی منطقی که این اسطوره در شکل دادن این روند به‌کار می‌گیرد هدف مقاله است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اسطوره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جفت آغازین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تغذیه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منطق</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_117_3880b216e316c1638d4a87f37d56caf9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
