<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>16</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>impact of social situation of Sassanid era on the formation of religious advices</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تاثیر اوضاع اجتماعی دوران ساسانی بر شکل گیری اندرزهای دینی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>55</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>77</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">3284</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نسرین</FirstName>
					<LastName>اصلانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>زرشناس</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیئت تحریریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Ardeshir Babakan, the founder of Sassanid Empire, established a government in Iran in place of the feudal Parthian empire, which brought about the concentration in government, unity throughout the parts of Iran and determination of Zoroaster as the Iranians official religion. &lt;br /&gt;In this research, it has been tried to investigate the literature and advices related to Sassanid era, following the study of Sassanid society structure in terms of social and religious factors. Additionally, it is intended to explore the contents of religious advices and Persian practical wisdom during the mid- Sassanid using examples, and the relation and effect of Sassanid kings and priests on the type and content of advices as well. Methodology of this research is Documentary – Library and the sample volume includes all the advices in Sassanid- Pahlavi language from which a number of samples were selected and translated. This article aims to prove the effect of Sassanid religious based society on the type of advices related to this era.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اردشیر بابکان پایه گذار سلسله ساسانی، به جای حکومت ملوک الطوایفی اشکانی، حکومتی را در ایران بنا نهاد که تمرکز در حکومت، وحدتِ تمام بخش­های ایران و برقراری دین زردشتی به عنوان کیش رسمی ایرانیان را با خود به­همراه داشت.  در پژوهش حاضر کوشیده شده است پس از بررسی ساختار جامعه ساسانی از لحاظ اجتماعی و مذهبی، ادبیات و اندرزهای آن دوره مورد مطالعه قرار گیرد و با ذکر نمونه­، محتوای اندرزهای دینی و حکمت عملی و تجربی فارسی میانه عهد ساسانی بررسی شده و به ارتباط و تاثیر اوضاع اجتماعی پادشاهان ساسانی و موبدان بر نوع و محتوای اندرزها پرداخته شود. روش تحقیق در این مقاله، کتابخانه­ای- اسنادی است و حجم نمونه، تمام اندرز های زبان پهلوی ساسانی را شامل می­شود که چند نمونه از آن­ ها برگزیده و سپس ترجمه شده­اند. هدف از نگارش این مقاله اثبات تاثیر جامعه دین محور ساسانی بر نوع اندرزهای این دوره است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جامعه ساسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دین محوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">متن‌های اندرزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اندرزهای دینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اندرزهای حکمت عملی و تجربی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3284_4f9f66e99fdf7cca9c688f8b8df62263.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
