<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Stylistic Differences of Hafez and Salman Savoji’s Ghazals 
(Based on Verb)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[ishany, tahereh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[IHCS]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Hafez Shirazi]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Salman Savoji]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Systemic Functionla linguistics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[experiential metafunction]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[verb]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The literary and artistic beauty of Hafez's sonnets is obvious to everyone but these beauties become more apparent when compared to the other poets' poems and especially the ghazals that he was interested in. Such studies may partially reveal why the lovers' ghazas receive more enjoy by readings of Hafez's ghazals incomparison with the similar ghazals of others. Systemic functional linguistics, which has been shown to be effective in analyzing literary texts, can help in answering this question. In Haliday's systematic, experiential metafunction represent human experience from the outside and inside world, and in fact expresses the content of the clause that is expressed by the main verb and referred to as the process. hence, in the present study, using descriptive - analytical and statistical method, we seek to answer the question of what differences exist, and what effect these differences have, or effects on the ghazal style of the two poets, and their literary enjoyment of their poetry. The results of this research suggest that although both of these works have been written in a common genre (ghazal) and have a roughly similar background, the verbal choices differ from their language. Hafiz has paid more attention to the use of "mental and emotional" processes and "material transformation" processes, and the distinction of the style of the ghazals in comparison with Salman’s ghazals is in the emotional color and smell of his sonnets, as well as the dynamics of his ghazals.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4390_89af4659e67398b000dd3036786156b6.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Language Studies]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[QalaichiBukan Aramaic Stele: A Local or Transferred Inscription?]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[dara, maryam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[IHCS]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mana]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[QalaichiBukan]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Assyrian]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Urartian]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[North of Syria]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stele]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[QalaichiBukan Aramaic Stele is considered to be Manneaen. Many scholars have studied its text most of which based on that the stele was discovered inside the walls of the temple. But, according to the evidence, there are doubts about the inscription text and its discovery. Therefore, there are doubts about its origin of its being Manneaen. It is the aim of the author to mention different ideas about the stele. The relation of the text and Qalaichi temple and the beliefs reflected from the text are also mentioned. According to the pieces of evidence the Mannaean origin of the stele is doubtful. It is not Assyrian norUrartian. It is possible that the stele is brought to this site in an unknown era. It is also possible that the stele of QalaichiBukan is not a treaty but a triumph text.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4391_8582979e9cb3e93224814763737396c8.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Language Studies]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Continence according to Buddha teaching in a Khotanese language text]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[rouhani, sarah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[mirfakhrai, mahshid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[IHCS]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[The middle east Iranian language]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Khotanese language]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Book of Zambasta]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Buddhism]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Saṃvara]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The book of “Zambasta” is a long poem in ancient a khotanese language, a branch of middle Eastern Iranian language. This book , containing wide set of common concepts and various aspects of Buddhism. Chapter 12 of this book is educational and includes a set of goodness and badness. The stanza which translated from Khotanese language into Persian in this article, includes the first 52 paragraph of this chapter that allocated to the description of Saṃvara(=continence, moral continence or stopping the effects of karmas or human beings previous actions). Saṃvara which considered as one of the most important steps to reach knowledge of continence and is like a guard trying continually to take man away from everything that is wrong and disagreeable, and to help him in order to reach Nirvānā(=salvation). Under the etymology of the word of Saṃvara, philosophical view about Saṃvara, steps of achievement, commitment ceremonies and conditions that lead to the loss of Saṃvara, are investigated.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4392_169ad9463409b4c7f59de3c60081eabf.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Language Studies]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Radial Categories of Persian Preposition /be/ within the Framework of Cognitive Semantics with Emphasis on Shahnameh Ferdowsi]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[alinezhad, maryam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[arianpoor, mahla]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[IHCS]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Persian Preposition /be/]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Radial categories]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[semantic network]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[cognitive semantics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Shahnameh Ferdowsi]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Preposition /be/ is one of the most widely used prepositions in Persian with a variety of meanings. The purpose of the present descriptive-analytical research is to study the radial categories of /be/ within the framework of Cognitive Semantics with emphasis on Shahnameh Ferdowsi. The data have been collected from one of the stories of Shahnameh titled "Bijan and Manijeh". This research aims to study the radial categories of semantic network of this preposition and also its semantic changes. For this purpose, the Tyler and Evans′s principled polysemy approach (2003) were used. Findings indicate that /be/ has been used with a frequency of 789 in total of 631 verses, so that its different meanings are systematic and has been placed in coherent semantic network in radial form. Ferdowsi has used its "affixation" meaning as a prototype meaning with high frequency. All other meanings such as "to address","assistance","causation" and "association" have been placed and used around its prototype meaning. Ferdowsi is also used of some distinctive meaning of /be/ out of its semantic clusters.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4393_59cd2986f399bf37c2a5923b5144e6e9.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Language Studies]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Formulaic Language and its Role in Persian Language Teaching]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[kaveh, Mojtaba]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Afrashi, Azita]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[IHCS]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[formulaic language]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[fixed formulae]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[semi-prefabricated formulae]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[structural description]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[semantic descriptions]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This descriptive study investigates formulaic language in Persian. There are two types of formulae: prefabricated (situation-bound) formulae (PFF); and semi-prefabricated formulae (SPFF); they have fixed elements as well as open slots to be occupied with words of given lexical categories. The data is taken from linguistic corpora, soap operas, personal observations, and web materials. This study addresses these questions: 
a.            What contexts are formulae used in?
b.            What socio-cultural meanings do formulae convey? 
c.             How can learning formulae help overcome the problem of fluency of Persian language learners?
 Formulaic sequences are used in all socio- cultural contexts and mostly in idiomatic meaning. To analyze the data, the author used his own intuition as well as other native speakers’ along with consulting various dictionaries. In the following ‘dual process model’ is employed to demonstrate the interaction of PFF and SPFF as well as novel language. The implications in teaching involve that introducing the situation and meaning of PFF to learners helps them produce idiomatic native like expressions in a given situation and analyzing the  SPFF and identifying their underlying formula, meaning, and restrictions (deductively) and presenting different examples (inductively)to learners  they can generate infinite number of native like  expressions  in Persian.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4394_7f667846c83e1056073c940b4c2478f9.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Language Studies]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Significance of Translation in Documents of Ancient Iranian Languages]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mahmoudzehi, Mousa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bahremand, Alireza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[IHCS]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ancient Iran]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ancient Iranian Languages]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Translation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Epigraphy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Zend]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Manichean Texts]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[: 
Based on the existing documents remained from Iranian Languages, the present study aims at investigating the significance of translation through the three historical epochs of Achaemenid, Parthian and Sassanid dynasties in Ancient Persia. The results indicated that the geographical extension of each empire along with existence of variations in population, language and traditions as well as the diversity of economic, social and political relations had made the use of both written and oral translations inevitable for their citizens. Such documents and the historical analyses around them reveal that the majority of translations of the era were the Royal Orders, religious and scientific texts and deeds related to commerce and families to fulfill the requirements and goals of the era. Moreover, some measures taken byShapur I, Shapur II and Khosrow Ito develop translation and interpretation were so vast and influential to be named “the movements of translation”. Studying translation products made in the era also revealed that there existed several languages simultaneously but with different ranks. The results of the present study can be of use to researchers in fields such as history, history of science, archeology, historical linguistics, Iranian studies as well as Iranian Culture and Literature.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4395_3b6e5a6e54fb894b9bc02bc355d0199f.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Language Studies]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Investigation of “Float Words” or Mofradāt in Sheikh Hossein Khwarizmi’s Iršād al- Morīdīn]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khani, Azar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[modarresi, fatemeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[nozhat, bahman]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[IHCS]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Persian Grammar]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[The float words (Mofradāt)]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Kamal-al- Din Hossein Khwarizmi]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Iršād al- Morīdīn]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The float words or Mofradāt is a class of words that they haven’t fix morphological labels. In other words, these words are placed between morphology and syntax. On the other hand, they are words and on the other hand, the determination of their exact meanings is depended on consideration syntactic relations and their places. So, they are morphological-syntactic categories. Therefore, they must be measured in terms of other words of the sentence to attribute to one of the syntactic categories in Persian grammar. This article –by descriptive-analytical method- tries to explore these words in Kamal al-Din Hossein Khwarizmi’s Iršād al- Morīdīn. The results of this research show that the float words of this text are: “bas / basi”, tā, čand/ čandīn, čonīn/ čonān, čo/hamço, čoon/hamčoon, če, degar/digar, ke, magar, ham, hame, and hīč. Many of these words have grammatical functions such as adverb (interrogative, cause, conditional, exceptional, uncertainty, increasing, negative and arrangement), adjective (quantity, interrogative, indefinite and exclamatory), preposition, subject, conjunction, pronoun (indefinite, interrogative, non-interrogative and numeration). Meanwhile, “ke” is the most usable float words in this text. The next clauses of it have the functions of non-interrogative pronoun, conjunction, subject, adjective, object, time and condition adverb.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4453_1adbfa379d529872a36fe09a600e3587.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Language Studies]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>