<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی ومطالعات فرهنگی</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان‌شناخت</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2099-8002</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>6</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Speech&#039;s Etiquette in Middle Persian Advices (Andarznameh)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اخلاق و آداب سخن‌دانی در اندرزنامه‌های فارسی میانه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>69</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>84</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">677</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرزانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>گشتاسب</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نادیا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاجی‌پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Speech and its etiquette have always been noticed in Middle Persian literary texts and texts on the advice (Andarznameh) as well. To express the etiquette of speech and its weight in the texts of this period, they can be divided into several general subjects. In this report, firstly, a short introduction about the importance of speech in ancient Persian an is given and then the etiquette of speech in Middle persian literature texts (Andarznameh) is elaborated. This etiquette consists of ‘truthfulness and avoiding lying’, ‘wisely spoken speech’, ‘equilibrium in speech’, ‘measurement of location and time of speaking’, ‘softness and politeness in speech’ and ... . It has also been tried in this paper to investigate some of the terminology in poetry and prose texts, and also in some dialects.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سخن و آداب آن از موضوعاتی است که در متون ادبی و اندرزنامه‌های فارسی میانه همواره به آن توجه شده است. برای بیان آداب سخن‌دانی و اهمیت آن در متون این دوره می‌توان آن‌ها را به چند موضوع کلی تقسیم‌بندی کرد. در این گزارش، ابتدا در مقدمه‌ای کوتاه به اهمیت سخن در ادبیات ایران باستان پرداخته شد؛ سپس آداب سخن‌دانی در متون ادبی و اندرزنامه‌های فارسی میانه در قالب موضوعات «راست‌گویی و دوری از دروغ»، «با اندیشه سخن‌گفتن»، «میانه‌روی در گفتار»، «سنجش زمان و سخن»، «نرمی و ادب در گفتار» و غیره بررسی شد. در این نوشتار، همچنین سعی شده است برخی از این اصطلاحات در متون نظم و نثر فارسی و نیز برخی از گویش‌ها بررسی شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سخن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سخن‌وری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فارسی میانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">متون ادبی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://languagestudy.ihcs.ac.ir/article_677_9a78f01fdd4868c8174e1b69c1a33090.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
