<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1397</YEAR>
<VOL>9</VOL>
<NO>18</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ساختار افعال‌ سببی ‌تالشی از چشم انداز زبانشناسی تاریخی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>.</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>افعال‌ سببی در زبان ‌تالشی در اشکال ‌گوناگون پدیدار می‌شوند‌. برخی‌ از این افعال ‌تنها دارای ‌گردش ‌واکه‌ای هستند اما گروهی ‌دیگر که در این پژوهش ‌مورد بررسی‌ قرارگرفته‌اند، جدای‌ از گردش واکه‌ای،پسوندهایی‌ همچون_nəste, _āvnəste_āvniye, _āvəndeمی‌‌‌گیرند. این دسته از افعال‌زبان تالشی را می‌توان برمبنای قواعد آواییِ افعالِ سببی در زبان‌های ایرانی ‌باستان، در ‌دو گروه بخش نمود. در این[1] مقاله تلاش ما بر این خواهد بود که اجزای سازندۀستاک‌هایحالِ سببیِزبان تالشی را با نگاه به زبان‌های ایرانی باستان و میانه توجیه کنیم. همچنین‌ پیشینه‌ای ‌تاریخی برای پسوندهای‌ مصدر‌ساز این ‌افعال (əste_(_de, _iye,بدست دهیم. در ادامه دگرگونی‌های ‌آوایی ‌از جمله‌ تبدیل همخوانm &gt;v در افعالی‌ که دارای ‌پسوند_ām(ə)nو_āv(ə)nهستند مورد مطالعه‌ قرار می‌گیرد.همگی ‌تحلیل‌ها در این ‌مقاله ‌برمبنای ‌دانش ‌زبانشناسی ‌تاریخی‌خواهد بود.


 </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>14</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زرشناس</Family>
						<NameE>zohre</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>zarshenas</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>ستاد فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>ستاد فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zzarshenas@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نیما</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عاصفی</Family>
						<NameE>nima</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>asefi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی، (نویسندۀ مسئول)</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nima.asefi.ym@gmial.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فعل‌ سببی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>صفت فاعلی مضارع ناگذر‌ِ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ایرانی‌باستان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اوستایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پهلوی‌اشکانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فارسی‌میانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آصفی، نیما (1397). مقایسۀ تاریخی-تطبیقی نظام واجی گویش تالشی و منابع برجای مانده از گویش آذری‌کهن،##پایان نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##ابوالقاسمی،محسن(1393).دستورتاریخیزبانفارسی،تهران:سمت.##حسن‌دوست،محمد (1389).فرهنگتطبیقی _ موضوعیزبا‌‌‌‌ن‌هاوگویش‌هایایرانی ‌نو،تهران:فرهنگستانزبانوادبفارسی.##حسن‌دوست،محمد(1393).فرهنگریشه‌شناختیزبانفارسی،تهران:فرهنگستانزبانوادبفارسی.                                       رضائی باغ بیدی،حسن(۱۳۸۱). راهنمای زبان پارتی، فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی.##رضایتی کیشهخاله،محرم (1385) «مصدر و ساخت آن در گویش تالشی»،ویژه نامۀ فرهنگستان،دورۀ سوم شماره اول ودوم .##سبزعلیپور،جهاندوست(1391).تاتی تالشی گیلکی، رشت: انتشارات دانشگاه گیلان.                    .کلنز،ژان(1394). فهرست فعل‌های اوستایی،ترجمه مرادیان، بهمن‌وکرمی، محبوبه،تهران:انتشارات فروهر.##یارشاطر، احسان (1371).«آذری»،زبان فارسی در آذربایجان، بنیاد موقوفات دکتر افشار.##منابع غیر فارسی:##-Henning, w, b. (1933). Das Verbum des Mittelpersischen der Turfantexte, ZII 9.##-Jackson.a.v.w.(1982). An Avesta Grammer,Stuttgart.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی بیان کودکان پیش‌دبستانی از درک طنز تصویری براساس نظریه عدم‌تجانس</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Study of pre-school children’s Explanation of pictorial humor Appreciation on the basis of Incongruity Theory</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>چکیده هدف این مطالعه بررسی درک طنز در کودکان پیش‌دبستانیاز طریق ارائه تصویر به آن‌ها و تحلیل توضیحات زبانی‌شانبرمبنای نظریه عدم‌تجانس است.دراین پژوهش که از نوع توصیفی است در طی مصاحبه‌های نیمه ساختارمنداز شرکت‌کننده‌های این تحقیق که 50کودک پیش‌دبستانی4 -6 ساله بودند خواسته شد تا دو محرک بصری خاص را مشاهده کنند و بگویند آیا تصویر مشاهده شده از نظر آنها خنده‌دار بوده است یا خیر و اگر خنده‌دار بوده، به چه دلیلی است. این پژوهش علاوه بر نظریه عدم‌تجانس، با معرفی مراحل پیشرفت طنز مک‌گی و طبقه‌بندی‌های براون از طنز تصویری به دنبال پاسخ به این پرسش اساسی است که: بیانکودکان پیش‌دبستانی از درک تصویر طنز بر اساس نظریه عدم تجانس چگونه صورت می‌گیرد؟یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد که کودکان 4-6 ساله مورد بررسی در این تحقیق قادر به تشخیص مفاهیم طنز در تصاویر هستند. عدم‌تجانس در یک تصویر طنز را درک می‌کنند، به آن می‌خندند و می‌توانند دلیل خنده‌شان را توضیح دهند.آنها می‌توانند از طریق مقایسه تصویر با طرحواره‌هایی که در ذهنشان دارند به درک عدم‌تجانس‌های اصلی و فرعی یک تصویر خنده‌دار دست یابند. این موضوع نشان می‌دهد که توانایی شناختی کودکان در تشخیص عدم‌تجانس‌های مفهومی با مرحله سوم مراحل پیشرفت طنز مک­گی که به تخطی از نمودهای مفهومی می‌پردازد مطابقت دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Abstract The objective of the present study is to investigate the appreciation of humor in pre-school children on the basis of Incongruity Theory, by presenting them the picture and analyzing their oral Explanations. In the present study which is methodologically descriptive, through semi-structured interviews of the participants, including 50 four to six year-old pre-school children , they were asked to observe two special visual stimuli, and say that weather they were funny or not and if yes, explain the reason of funniness. In this investigation in addition to incongruity theory, representing McGee’s stages of humor development and Brown&#039;s categories of pictorial humor, we were seeking the answer for this fundamental question that: How is the pre-school children’s explanation of humorous picture appreciation on the basis of Incongruity Theory? Findings revealed that 4-6 year-old children in this study were able to recognize humorous contents in the pictures. They appreciate incongruity in the humorous picture, laugh at it, and explain their reason for their laughter. They were also able to distinguish the major and minor incongruities of a picture through the comparison of the picture with their own mental patterns. This shows that children&#039;s cognitive ability to identify conceptual incongruities is corresponded to the third stage of the McGee’s stages of humor development that notice violations of perceptual appearances of things.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>15</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>38</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سریرا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کرامتی یزدی</Family>
						<NameE>sarira</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>keramati yazdi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری زبان‌شناسیدانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری زبان‌شناسیدانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sarira.keramatiyazdi@mail.um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شهلا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شریفی</Family>
						<NameE>shahla</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>sharifi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد (نویسنده مسئول</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد (نویسنده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sh-sharifi@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>علیزاده</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Alizadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>alalizadeh@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عطیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کامیابی گل</Family>
						<NameE>Atiye</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>KamyabiGol</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار زبانشناسی دانشگاه فردوسی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار زبانشناسی دانشگاه فردوسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>atiyeh_kamyabi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلیدواژه‌ها:طنز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>درک طنز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظریه عدم‌تجانس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کودکان پیش‌دبستانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>طنز تصویری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Attardo, Salvatore (1994).linguistic Theories of Humor, New York: Mouton de Gruyter.##Banas, A. J., N. Dunbar, D. Rodriquez &amp; S. J.Liu. (2010). &quot;A review of humor in educational setting:Four decades of research&quot;,Communication Education, 60(1), 115–144.##Bariaud, F. (1989).&quot;Age differences in children’s humor&quot;. In P.E,McGhee(Ed.), Humor and children’s development, A guide to practical applications (pp. 15-45). New York: the Haworth Press.##Berlyne, Daniel E. (1960). Conflict, arousal, and curiosity. New York: McGraw-Hill.##Booth-Butterfield, Melani&amp; Melissa Wanzer,(2010).Humorous communication as goal-orientedcommunication. In Deanna Fassett&amp; John T. Warren (eds.), SAGE Handbook ofCommunication and Instruction, 221–240. Thousand Oaks CA: Sage.##Brown, Ivan. (1990). Responses of adults with developmental disabilities to cartoon riddle humor. Unpublished manuscript, Ontario institute for studies in education.University of Toronto.##Brown, Ivan. (1993). &quot;Young children’s explanation of pictoral humor: A preliminary study&quot;. EarlyChild Development and Care 93.35–40.##Crain, W.(1992).theories of development, Concepts and applications. New Jersey: prentice Hall.##Guo, J., X. Zhang &amp; A. Xeromeritou.(2011). &quot;Humor among Chinese and Greek preschool childrenin relation to cognitive development&quot;,International Journal of Elementary Education 3(3).153–170.##Kiken, Mark E.(1977).The Grammar of Humor (Ann Arbor, MI: University Microfilms International)##Kuchner, J.F.(1991).&quot;the humor of young children&quot;,the meeting of the National Association for the Education of Young children Uniondale.NY.##Latta, Robert (1999).The Basic Humor Process: A Cognitive-Shift Theory and the Case Against Incongruity, Berlin: Mouton de Gruyter.##Loizou, Eleni. (2005). &quot;Infant humor: The theory of the absurd and the empowerment theory&quot;,International Journal of Early Years Education 13(1). 43–53.##Loizou, Eleni. (2006). &quot;Young children´s explanation of pictorial humor&quot;,Early Childhood EducationJournal 33(6).425–431.##Loizou, Eleni. (2011).&quot;Disposable cameras, humor and children’s abilities&quot;, contemporary Issues in Early Childhood 12(2), 148-162.##Loizou, Eleni&amp;Kyriakou, Maria (2016).&quot;Young children’s appreciation and Production of Verbal and Visual humor&quot;, Humor, 29(1): 99-124.##Martin, Rod A. (2007). The psychology of humor: An integrative approach. Oxford: ElsevierAcademic Press.##Makins, Marian (ed.) (1979).Collins English Dictionary, Glasgow.##McGhee, Paul. E. (1979).Humor: Its origin and development. San Francisco: Freeman.##McGhee, Paul. E. (1984).Play, Incongruity and humor. In T. D. Yawkey, &amp; A. D. Pellegrini (Eds.), Child’s play: developmental and applied, 219-236. Mahwah, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.##Morreall, J.(1983). Taking laughter seriously, Albany: SUNY.##Morreall, John. (1987). Taking laughter seriously, Albany, NY: State University of New York.##Pien, D. ,&amp;Rothbart, M. K. (1980). Incongruity humor, play, and self- regulation of arousal in young children, In P. E. McGhee, &amp; A. J. Chapman (Eds.), children’s humor 1-21, New York: John Wiley and Sons.##Pitri, Eliza. (2011). &quot;Children’s funny art and the form it can take over time&quot;,International Journal ofEducation through Art 7(1). 81–96.##Rothbart, M. K., &amp;Pien, D. (1977). Elephants and marshmallows: A theoretical synthesis of Incongruity-Resolution and arousal theories of humor. In A. J. Chapman, &amp; H. C. Foot (Eds), it’s a funny thing, humor (pp. 37-41). Oxford, UK: pergamon Press.##Sezgin, ElifYalcintas&amp;Hatipoglu, Recep (2017).&quot;The study of the 5-6 year-old children’s Appreciation the humor at preschool Education&quot;, universal Journal of Educational Research 5(11): 1902-1911.##Shultz, T. R. (1970).cognitive factors in children’s appreciation of cartoons: Incongruity and its resolution, unpublished doctoral dissertation, Yale University.##Shultz, Thomas R. (1972). &quot;The role of incongruity and resolution in children’s appreciation ofcartoon humor&quot;,Journal of Experimental Child Psychology 13(3). 456–477.##Shultz, Thomas R. (1974). &quot;Development of the appreciation of riddles&quot;,Child Development 45. 100–105.##Shultz, T. R. (1976). A cognitive-developmental analysis of humour. In A. J. Chapman &amp; H. C. Foot (Eds.), Humor and laughter: Theory,research, and applications (pp. 11–36). London, UK: Wiley.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>پیشنهادی دربارۀ خوانش فعل ناشناختۀ غئضتدر درخت آسوریگ</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A new suggestion for transcribing of the unknown verb “غئضت” in Draxt-iĀsurīg.</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در متندرخت آسوریگ‌ شش بار فعلی با صورت نوشتاری غئضتآمده که هنوز خوانش درستی از آن به دست داده نشده است. بافت عباراتی که این فعل در آن‌ها آمده است نشان می‌دهد که این فعل، باید معادل ast باشد. پژوهشگران بر سر خوانش این فعل اختلاف دارند و آن را به صورت‌های ast/ hast، est، ēst و āsēd خوانده‌اند. در این مقاله کوشش می‌شود با توجه به صورت فعلی و‌‌سذصتدر همین متن و صورت‌های ایذ/ اید در گونۀ فارسی هروی و هی در زبان کهن گرگانی، پیشنهادی تازه دربارۀ خوانش این فعل داده شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In a Middle Iranian text, Draxt-iĀsurīg, we face an ambiguous verb six times, which is writtenغئضت and no one has proposed any convincing transcription for that. The phrases before and after of this word show that the function and the meaning of this verb must be equivalent to “ast” (=is). The researchers have not accede to a same reading about this verb and have suggested different transcription such as “ast/ hast”, est” “ēst”, āsēd”. In this article, we try to propose a new suggestion for reading غئضت, according to another written form of this verb “و‌‌سذصت” in Draxt-iĀsurīg, and the words “ایذ/ اید” in Heravi dialect and “هی” in the old dialect of Gorgan.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>39</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>47</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فرزانه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گشتاسب</Family>
						<NameE>farzaneh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>goshtasb</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی(نویسنده مسئول)</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>f.goshtasb@ihcs.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>میثم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Meysam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammdi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری/ گروه فرهنگ و زبانهای باستانی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری/ گروه فرهنگ و زبانهای باستانی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>narisafyazd@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دستور تاریخی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پهلوی اشکانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>درخت آسوریگ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گونۀ فارسی هروی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان کهن گرگان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فعل ahēd</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>انصاری هروی، خواجه عبدالله بن محمّد، 1386، طبقات الصوفیه، تصحیح محمدسرور مولایی، تهران: توس.##بخشی از تفسیری کهن به پارسی، 1375، تحقیق و تصحیح سید مرتضی آیۀ الله‌زاده شیرازی، تهران: دفتر نشر میراث مکتوب، مرکز فرهنگی نشر قبله.##رواقی، علی، 1375، «مقدمه بر بخشی از تفسیری کهن به پارسی»، تحقیق و تصحبح سید مرتضی آیۀ الله‌زاده شیرازی، تهران: دفتر نشر میراث مکتوب، مرکز فرهنگی نشر قبله، صص سی و سه تا شصت و شش.##عریان، سعید، 1367، «درخت آسوری»، چیستا، شمارۀ 52، آبان، 166-178.##کیا، صادق، 1391، واژه‌نامۀ گرگانی، تهران: دانشگاه تهران.##مزداپور، کتایون، 1384، «دندان گرگ و می کنیز»، یشت فرزانگی (جشن‌نامۀ دکتر محسن ابوالقاسمی)، به اهتمام سیروس نصرالله‌زاده و عسکر بهرامی، تهران: هرمس، 449-471.##مقامات حریری، ترجمۀ فارسی، 1365، پژوهش علی رواقی، تهران: مؤسسۀ فرهنگی شهید محمد رواقی.##میبدی، ابوالفضل رشیدالدین، کشف الاسرارو عُدَّۀ الابرار، معروف به تفسیر خواجه عبدالله انصاری، 10 ج، به سعی و اهتمام علی اصغر حکمت، تهران: امیرکبیر.##ناتل خانلری، پرویز، 1392، تاریخ زبان فارسی، تهران: نشر نو.##نوابی، ماهیار، 1386، درخت آسوریگ، متن پهلوی و آوانوشت، ترجمۀ فارسی، فهرست واژه‌ها و یادداشت‌ها، تهران: فروهر.##Benveniste, Emile. 1930, “Le Texte du DraxtAsūrīk, et la Versification Pehlevie”, JOURNAL ASIATIQUE, 218, pp. 193-225.##Durkin-Meisterernst, Desmond. 2004, Dictionary of Manichaean Middle Persian and Parthian, Turnhout (Belgium): Brepols.##Durkin-Meisterernst, Desmond. 2014, Grammatik des Westmitteliranischen (Parthisch und Mittelpersisch), Wien: Verlag.##Gignoux, Philippe, 1972, Glossaire des inscriptions pehleviesetparthes(Corpus InscriptionumIranicarum. Supplementary Series, Vol. I). London: LundHumphries.##Henning, Walter Bruno, 1950, “A Pahlavi Poem”, BSOAS, 13, pp. 641-648.##Jamasp-Asana, J.M. 1913. Pahlavi Texts. Bombay.##MacKenzie,David Neil, 1971, A concise Pahlavi dictionary. London: Oxford University Press.##Tafazzoli, Ahmad, 1995, “Draxt ī Asūrīg”, EncyclopaediaIranica, VII, Costa Mesa, California, 547-549.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بازنگری قطعۀ ac (M2 II)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Review of ac (M2 II)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در دست‌نویس M2 II از مجموعۀ متون تورفانی، برابر با قطعۀ ac در تقسیم‌بندی موضوعی مری بویس، به دو نیرو اشاره شده است: نیروی روشنی و نیروی تاریکی. آندرئاس و هنینگ در ترجمه و تفسیر این قطعه، نیروی روشنی را به دو بخش فعاله، که نجات خواهد یافت، و منفعله که تا ابد در ظلمت گرفتار خواهد ماند، تقسیم کرده‌اند. با آنکه محققان بعدی در ترجمۀ این قطعه متأثر از ایشان بوده‌اند، در خصوص نیروی روشنی فعال و منفعل یا سکوت کرده و یا به گونه‌ای مبهم بدان اشاره کرده‌اند. ترجمه‌های پیشنهادی محققان در موارد متعددی به دلیل عدم رعایت نحو کلام، و نیز اعمال تغییراتی در تقسیم‌بندی موضوعی پاراگراف‌های کاتب، مبهم است. در این مقاله نشان خواهیم داد که: مبحثی تحت عنوان نیروی روشنی فعاله و منفعله در کیش مانی وجود ندارد؛ محققان در تصحیح انتقادی متن توجهی به تقسیم‌بندی موضوعی کاتب نداشته‌‌اند؛ ساختار نحوی کلام ساده و روان است و علت ابهام نحوی و معنایی متن را باید در نوع برداشت محققان جست.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In M2 II, a fragment of Manichaean Turfan texts, equivalent to the text “ac” according to the subject-matter partition created by Boyce, there are two powers named by Mani as “the Power of Light”, and “the Power of Darkness”. By giving some notes, Andreas and Henning interpreted the Power of Light as an active Power who will gain the eternal salvation, and a passive one that have to stay bogged down in Darkness forever. Though the scholar translations of the text are based on Andreas and Henning’s, they are either quiet about the Powers or some indefinite allusions are just mentioned by them. With making unnecessary changes to the scribe’s paragraphs on the one hand, and paying not much attention to the Parthian syntax rules on the other, the scholars who translated this text did suggest different translations which seem in some cases to be obscure. In this essay these items will be discussed: The idea of the active and passive Powers of Light is in the air; the scholars did not pay attention to the distinct topical divisions appeared in the scribe’s writing system; the scholar’s negative attitude to some syntactical structures is rather responsible for those obscurity.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>49</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>73</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>میرزایی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mirzaie</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه فرهنگ و زبانهای باستانی، دانشکدۀ ادبیات فارسی و زبانهای خارجی، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه فرهنگ و زبانهای باستانی، دانشکدۀ ادبیات</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mohsen311@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پهلوی اشکانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نیروی روشنی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فعاله</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>منفعله</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ابوالقاسمی، محسن (1379). مانی به روایت ابن ندیم، تهران: طهوری.##ابوالقاسمی، محسن (1383). دین‌ها و کیش‌های ایرانی در دوران باستان به روایت شهرستانی، تهران: هیرمند.##بهار، مهرداد و اسماعیل‌پور، ابوالقاسم (1394). ادبیات مانوی، تهران: کارنامه.##تقی‌زاده، سید حسن (1383). مانی‌شناسی، به کوشش ایرج افشار، تهران: توس.##رضایی باغ‌بیدی، حسن (1388). راهنمای زبان پارتی، چ. 2، تهران: ققنوس.##Andreas, F.C. and Henning, W.B. (1934). “Mitteliranische Manichaica aus Chinesisch-Turkestan”, III, SPAW 1934, pp. 846-912.##Asmussen, J.P. (1975). Manichaean Literature, New York: Scholars’ Facsimiles &amp; Reprints.##Boyce, M. (1954). The Manichaean Hymn-Cycles in Parthian, London: Oxford University Press. Boyce, M. (1975). A Reader in Manichaean Middle Persian and Parthian, Téhéran-Liège: Bibliothèque Pahlavi 1975 (Acta Iranica 9). Boyce, M. (1977). A Word-List of Manichaean Middle Persian and Parthian, Téhéran-Liège: Bibliothèque Pahlavi 1977 (Acta Iranica 9a). Brunner, Ch.J. (1977). A Syntax of Western Middle Iranian, New York: Caravan Books. Colditz, I. (2009). “Manichaean Time-Management: Laymen between Religious and Duties”, New Light on Manichaeism, BeDuhn, J.D. (ed.), Leiden-Boston: Brill, pp. 73-99.##Durkin-Meisterernst, D. )2004(, Dictionary of Manichaean Middle Persian and Parthian, Turnhout: Brepols Publishers.##Durkin-Meisterernst, D. (2014). Grammatik des Westmitteliranischen (Parthisch und Mittelpersisch), Wien: Österreichische Akademie der Wissenschaften.##Gardner, I. (1995). The Kephalaia of the Teacher, Leiden, New York, Köln: Brill.##Jackson, A.V.W. (1932). Researches in Manichaeism, New York: Columbia University Press.##Klimkeit, H.J. (1993). Gnosis on the Silk Road: Gnostic Texts from Central Asia, San Francisco: Harper.##Skjærvø, P.O. (2009). “Middle West Iranian”, The Iranian Languages, G. Windfuhr (ed.),  London and New York: Routledge, pp. 196-278. Sundermann, W. (1973). Mittelpersische und Partische Kosmogonische und Parabeltexte der Manichäer, Berlin: Akademie-verlag. Sundermann, W. (1998). “Manichaean Eschatology”, (Last Updated: January 19, 2012), http://www.iranicaonline.org/articles/eschatology-ii Sundermann, W. (2002). “The Manichean Pantheon”, (Last Updated: July 20, 2002), http://www.iranicaonline.org/articles/manicheism-ii-the-manichean-pantheon  ##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نمود آخرین صورت ادبیات فارسی میانه‌ی ساسانی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The last display of Sassanid Middle Persian literature</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مقاله­ی حاضر با معرفی انواع نامه­های فارسی میانه­ی سده­ی هفتم شامل پاپیروس و پوست­نوشته در مصر، در زمان چیرگی ارتش خسرو دوم (618- 628 م.)، به بررسی نوع خط، سبک نگارش و ادبیات این اسناد خواهد پرداخت که به خط تحریریِ شکسته­ای نوشته شده که می­تواند به عنوان آخرین گونه کاربردی خط در دوره ساسانی شناخته شود. در عین حال این نامه­ها نمایانگر فعالیت­های چندجانبه­ی ایرانیان در مصر  هستند. مکاتبات یادشده، تنها میان ایرانیان رد و بدل نمی­شده؛ بلکه مابین ایرانیان و کارمندان و صاحب­منصبان مصری هم، که قبل از ورود ایرانیان، با نظام دیوانی روم آشنایی کافی داشتند، بوده است که نشان تعامل اجتماعی و به ویژه اقتصادی میان دو گروه و تأثیرپذیری آنها از هم نیز هست. این نامه­ها به لحاظ زبان­شناسی، ادبی و تاریخی  قابل بررسی هستند.  پاپیروس و پوست­نوشته­های یاد شده، در بعد واژگان، نحو و سبک نگارش با نوشته­های فارسی میانه­ی کتابی  تفاوت­هایی دارند که  از خلال آنها، تحول خط از صورت کتیبه­ای به شکسته بررسی می­شود. ادبیات این پاپیروس­ و پوست­نوشته­ها، به ویژه در بخش نامه­های رسمی به عنوان نمود کلی مکاتبه دوره­ی ساسانی،  به نحوی است که سعی شده از  طریق ریختارها و الگوهای ثابت، موجز اما گویا و مؤثر باشد</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Introducing a variety of seventeenth-century Middle Persian forms of letters including papyrus and parchments, found in Egypt during the time of   Khosrow II army’s domination (618-628 CE.), the present article is going to study script, composition style and literature of these documents written in a cursive script which can be regarded as the last practical variation script in Sasanian era. Also, these letters represent the multilateral activities of Iranians in Egypt. These letters were not only shared among Iranians, but also between Iranians and Egyptian officials who, prior to the arrival of Iranians, had a good knowledge of the Roman ministerial system, which indicated the social interaction, and particularly the economic interrelationbetween the two groups and their mutual impact.  These letters will be studied in terms of lexicon, historical and literary aspects.Papyri and Parchment writings, mentioned here, differ from Book Pahlavi in vocabulary, syntax and style.Through studying these differences, it is possible to investigate the evolution procedure during which lapidary script developed to cursive.  Literature applied in these Papyri and parchments, particularly official letters, as Sassanian typical correspondence in the time mentioned, had a tendency to follow fixed patterns, and seem to be concise and effective enough.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>75</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>105</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سیروس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نصرالله زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Cyrus</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nasrollahzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>cyrusnasr@googlemail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فریبا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ناصری کوهبنانی</Family>
						<NameE>Fariba</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Naseri Kouhbanani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکترای فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی ،</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکترای فرهنگ و زبان‌های باستانی، پژوهشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>daaryan.fa@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پاپیروس‌های فارسی میانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خط شکسته</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نامه‌های شخصی و رسمی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ادبیات</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مجموعه‌های پاپیروس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF> ابوالقاسمی، محسن  1373. تاریخ زبان فارسی، تهران، انتشارات سمت.##آموزگار، ژاله و تفضلی، احمد 1380. زبان پهلوی، ادبیات و دستور آن. چاپ سوم، تهران، انتشارات معین.##بختیاری، آرمان  1391. پاپیروس­های پهلوی . نامه فرهنگستان، ش. 1، 75 -88.##دریایی، تورج 1387. تاریخ و فرهنگ ساسانی. ترجمه مهرداد دیزچی. تهران، انتشارات ققنوس.##دریایی، تورج 1392. ساسانیان. ترجمه شهرناز اعتمادی. تهران، انتشارات توس.##فرای، ریچارد 1380. تاریخ باستانی ایران. ترجمه مسعود رجب نیا. شرکت انتشارات علمی و فرهنگی.##کرامتی، یونس 1393. پاپیروس. دایره­المعارف بزرگ اسلامی، ج.13، 498-499.##گیرشمن، رومن1380: ایران از آغاز تا اسلام. ترجمه محمد معین. شرکت انتشارات علمی و فرهنگی.##گیزلن، ریکا 1384. چهار سپاهبد شاهنشاهی ساسانی، بر اساس شواهد مهرشناسی. ترجمه سیروس نصراله­زاده. سازمان میراث فرهنگی و گردشگری.##نصراله­زاده، سیروس. زیرچاپ. کتیبه­های خصوصی دوره­ی ساسانی. پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##هویسه، فیلیپ 1393. ادبیات کتیبه‌ای در زبان‌های ایرانی باستان ومیانه. ادبیات ایران پیش از اسلام.  جلد هفدهم (پیوست 1) . ترجمه سیروس نصراله‌زاده. انتشارات سخن.##Azarpay, Guitty et al. 2002. Analysis of Writing Materials in Middle Persian Documents. Bulletin of the Asia Institute, New Series, Vol. 16: 181-187.##Azarpay, Guitty et al. 2003. New Information on the Date and Function of the Berkeley MP Archive. Bulletin of the Asia Institute, New Series, Vol. 17: 17-29.##Bailey, W. and Abaev, V. I. 1985. Alans . Encyclopaedia Iranica,Vol. I, Fasc. 8: 801-803.##Cereti, C.G. 2008. On the Pahlavi Cursive Script and the Sasanian Avesta . Studia Iranica, Tome 37, fas.2: 175-196.##Daryaee, Turaj. 2003. Middle Persian Papyri from the Sasanian Occupation of Egypt in the Seventh Century (I).www.sasanika.org##­­­­­­­­­­­ Daryaee, Turaj.2004. Middle Persian Papyri, Ostraca and Parchments . Middle Persian Documents: 1-2.##De Menasce,Jean. 1957. Pahlavi inscriptions. Ostraca and papyri.Corpus Inscriptionum Iranicarum(CII), Part III: Pahlavi Inscriptions, Vol.IV: Ostraca,Vol.V:  Papyri . London.## De Menasce,Jean. 1985. Rechercher de Papyrologie Pehlevie . Studia Iarnica, cahier 3:163-175.##Gadjiev, Murtazali. 2016. DARBAND EPIGRAPHY i. MIDDLE PERSIAN INSCRIPTIONS. Encyclopædia Iranica, online edition. available at www.iranicaonline.org.##Geignoux, Philip. 1999. Ostraca, Papyri et Parchemins. Dossiers d&#039;Archéologie, Cote: 044.34: 24-25. Geignoux, Philip.2010. Un Nouvel Ouverage de Reference de la Papyrologue Pehlevie: Note de Laecture . Studia Iranica, Vol. 39:111-120.##Geignoux, Philip. 2012.Un Archive Post-sassanide du Tabaristan(1), Les Orientals, Vol. XXI:.29-97.##Gyselen, Rika.1999. Monnaies et Sceaux Sassanides. Dossiers d&#039;Archéologie, Cote: 044.34: 26-29.##Gyselen, Rika.2007. Sasanian Seals and Sealings in the Saeedi Collection. Acta Iranica 44.##Gyselen, Rika. 2012. Scellements dans l&#039;Archive Post-Sassanide de Tabaristan(1). Res Orienrales,Objects et Documents Inscrits en Parsig. Vol.XXI: 97-108.##Gzella, Holger.2015. A Cultural History of Aramaic, From the Beginnings to the Advent of Islam. Boston.##Hansen, O. 1938. Die Mittelpersischen Papyri der Papyrussammlung der Staatlichen Museen zu Berlin. Berlin (APAW 1937, Nr. 9).##Jalalipour, Saeid. 2014. Persian Occupation of Egypt 619-629: Politics and Administration of Sasanians  . e-Sasanika Graduate paper 10 :1-16.##Kent, Roland. 1953. Old Persian (Grammar, Texts, Lexicon). New Haven.##Sänger, Patrick. 2011.The Administration of Sasanian Egypt: New Masters and Byzantine Continuity. Greek, Roman, and Byzantine Studies 51: 653–665.##Tafażżolī , Ahmad. 1993. Correspondence i. In pre-Islamic Persia. Encyclopaedia Iranica.Vol. VI, Fasc. 3: 287-290.##Weber, Dieter. 1983. Die Pehlevi fragmente der Papyrussammlung der Österreichischen Nationalbibliothek in Wien . Festschrift Papyrus Erzherzog Rainer (P. Rainer Cent.): 215-28.##Weber, Dieter.1984. Pahlavi Papyri und Ostraca: Stand der Forschung. Middle Iranian Studies, Proceedings of the International Symposium organized by the Katholieke Universiteit Leuven from the 17th to the 20th of May 1982, ed. by W. Skalmowski and A. van Tongerloo, Leuven (= Orientalia Lovaniensia Analecta, 16): 25–43.##Weber, Dieter .1991. Ein bisher unbekannter Titel aus spätsassanidischer Zeit?. Corolla Iranica (Papers in honour of Prof. Dr. D. N. MacKenzie). ed. by R. E. Emmerick and D. Weber: 228–236.##Weber, Dieter.1992. Ostraca, Papyri und Pergamente. Corpus Inscriptionum Iranicarum, vol.IV.Ostraca and Vol.V. Papyri. London.##Weber, Dieter. 2002. Eine spätsassanidische Rechtsurkunde aus Ägypten . TYCHE 17:  185–192.##Weber, Dieter. 2003. Remarks on the development of the Pahlavi script in Sasanian times. Religious Texts in Iranian Language :185–195.##Weber, Dieter. 2005. Pahlavi Papyri . Encyclopaedia Iranica online.##Weber, Dieter. 2007a. Writing Exercises in Late Sassanian Times, A Contribution to the Culture of Writing Pahlavi. Ancient and Middle Iranian Studies: 255–263.##Weber, Dieter. 2007b. The Vienna Collection of Pahlavi Papyri. Akten des 23. Internationalen Papyrologenkongresses,(Geichische Akademie der Wissenschaften, Phil.-Hist. Kl., Kommission für Antike Rechtsgeschichte): 725–738.##Weber, Dieter. 2008a. Berliner Pahlavi-Dokumente, Zeugnisse spätsassanidischer Breif und Rechtskultur aus frühislamischer Zeit. Wiesbaden.##Weber, Dieter.2008b. Sassanidische Briefe aus Ägypten . Asiatische Studien/##Études Asiatiques LXII/3: 803–826.##Zeini, Arash. 2015: Preliminary remarks on Middle Persian in the Pahlavi documents.   Studies on the Iranian World I. Before Islam: 67–73.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر جنسیت بر بازنمود زبانی نگرش جامعه‌ی فارسی زبان به خارجی‌ها</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Linguistic Representation of the Attitude of Persian Speakers towards“Foreigners”, and it’s Relation to Gender</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف اصلی این پژوهش بررسی بازنمود زبانی نگرش جامعه‌ی فارسی زبان به مقوله‌ی خارجیو تأثیر متغییر اجتماعی جنسیت بر این بازنمود است. این پژوهش در چارچوب نظری زبان‌شناسی اجتماعی-شناختی انجام می‌گیرد و مبتنی است بر تحلیل کمی داده‌های به دست آمده از شیوه‌ی پیمایشی به وسیله‌ی پرسش‌نامه از یک سو و مقایسه‌ی این یافته‌ها با داده‌های به دست آمده از تحلیل کیفی که خود بر مبنای گفتگو بنا شده‌اند. در این پژوهش در مجموع 412 نسخه پرسش‌نامه به شیوه‌های مذکور جمع‌آوری شده و با استفاده از آزمون‌های آماری (شامل آزمون تی تک‌متغیره و آزمون تی دو متغیر مستقل) به این نتیجه رسیده‌ایم که به طور کلی بازنمودهای زبانی نشان می‌دهند نگرش چندان مثبتی در جامعه‌ی هدف نسبت به خارجی‌ها وجود ندارد و پیش‌فرض‌های نه چندان مثبت، حتی از سوی زنان بیشتر از مردان هستند.در طراحی پرسش‌نامه‌های این پژوهش از یک آزمون زبان‌شناختی به نام آزمون اما استفاده شده و در نهایت به این نتیجه رسیده‌ایم که آزمون مذکور می‌توانددر بررسی نگرش‌های زبانی مورد نظر مابه کار رود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The study aims to investigate the linguistics representation of Persian speaker society attitude towardsforeigners and impact of gender on this attitude. The study is generally in the framework of recent theories in cognitive sociolinguistics.Methodology of this research is of two kind: survey (questionnaireform) and qualitative (dialogue).Totally 412 questionnaireforms have been collected and extracted data from this data collection has been investigated by statistical tests.These statistical tests are including One Sample t Test and Two Independent Samples t Test. Themain resultsinclude:1) target society has no positive attitude on foreigners. 2) Women have more negative attitude towards foreigners.A linguistic toolcalledBut Testhas been used in our study.Finally,one of our results is that But Testcan investigate our target attitudes.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>107</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>129</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احسان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نظری باوندپور</Family>
						<NameE>Ehsan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nazari Bavandpour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری پژوهشکده‌ی زبان‌شناسی / پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی / تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری پژوهشکده‌ی زبان‌شناسی / پژوهشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ehsan.nazari@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>یحیی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مدرسی</Family>
						<NameE>yahya</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>modaressi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد پژوهشکده زبان‌شناسی/پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی/تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد پژوهشکده زبان‌شناسی/پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ymodarresi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آزیتا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>افراشی</Family>
						<NameE>Azita</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Afrashi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.afrashi.ling@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جامعه‌ی فارسی زبان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازنمود زبانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جنسیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان‌شناسی اجتماعی-شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آزمون اما</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>داوری اردکانی، نگار، محمدرضا رضائیاندلوئی و حسینمغانی. 1389. &quot;مطالعه‌یتطبیقینگرش‌هایزبانیفارسی‌زبانان به دو زبان فارسی و انگلیسی با توجه به موضوع جهانی شدن&quot;. فصلنامه‌ی مطالعات ملی، 42، سال یازدهم، شماره‌ی 2: 104-81.##سوسور، فِردینان دو. 1392. دوره‌ی زبان‌شناسی عمومی. ترجمه‌ی: کورش صفوی. تهران: هرمس.##صفار مقدم، احمد و آتوسارستم‌بیکتفرشی. ١٣٩٦. &quot;بررسیادراکگویشورانفارسی زبان از تنوعسبکی در زبان فارسی&quot;. جستارهایزبانی. پیاپی ٤٢ ، د ٨. ش7: 314-291.##قلیفامیان، علیرضا. 1395. &quot;گویش‌شناسی ادراکی؛مطالعه‌ای موردی از ترکی آذری در شهرستان شبستر&quot;. جستارهای زبانی، دوره 7، شماره 6 (پیاپی 34)، ویژه نامه پاییز، آذر و دی 1395، صفحه 73-96.##کرامر، دانکن. 1384. درآمدی بر کاربرد آمار در تحقیقات اجتماعی. ترجمه‌ی: یحیی علی‌بابایی و امیر ملکی. تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##کوچش، زولاتان. 1395. زبان، ذهن و فرهنگ: مقدمه‌ای مفید و کاربردی. ترجمه‌ی: جهانشاه میرزابیگی. تهران: انتشارات آگاه.##لیکاف، جورج. 1395. قلمرو تازه‌ی علوم شناختی: آن‌چه مقوله‌ها درباره‌ی ذهن فاش می‌کنند، کتاب یکم. ترجمه‌ی: جهانشاه میرزا بیگی. تهران: انتشارات آگاه.##مظفری، شراره. ١٣٩٣. نگرش گویشوران استان فارس نسبت به گونه‌یشیرازی و گونه‌یمعیارفارسی:پژوهشیاجتماعی-شناختیدرباره‌ی تنوعات گونه‌های (لکتال) فارسیرساله‌یدکتری به راهنمایی:یحییمدرسی. تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##نظری باوندپور، احسان. 1397. . پایان‌نامه‌ی کارشناسی ارشد، به راهنمایی: یحیی مدرسی. تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##وارداف، رونالد. 1393. درآمدی بر جامعه‌شناسی زبان. ترجمه‌ی: رضا امینی. تهران: بوی کاغذ.##Bakar, Kesumawati A. 2014. “ATTITUDE and Identity Categorizations: A Corpus-based Study of Gender Representation”. Social and Behavioral Sciences, 2014 (112) 747-756.##Bendix, Edward H. 1966. Componential Analysis of General Vocabulary: The Semantic Structure of a Set of Verbs in English, Hindi, and Japanese. The Hague.##Bickel, Balthasar. 2000. “Grammar and social practice: On the role of ‘culture’ in linguistic relativity”. In Susanne Niemeier and Rene´ Dirven (eds.): Evidence for linguistic relativity. Amsterdam: John Benjamins, 161–91.##Croft, William and D. Alan Cruse. 2004. Cognitive Linguistics. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Cruse, Alan D. 1986. Lexical Semantics. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Dirven, Rene´, Hans-georg Wolf and Frank Polzenhagen. 2007. “Cognitive Linguistics and Cultural Studies”. In Dirk Geeraerts and Hubert Cuyckens (eds): Cognitive Linguistics. New York: Oxford University Press, 1203-1221.##Evans, Vyvyan and Melanie Green. 2006. Cognitive Linguistics an Introduction. Edinburgh: Edinburgh University Press.##Geeraerts, Dirk. 2018. Ten Lectures on Cognitive Sociolinguistics. Leiden/Boston: Brill.##Geeraerts, Dirk and Hubert Cuyckens. 2007. “The Oxford Handbook of Cognitive Linguistics”. New York: Oxford University Press.##Gibbs, Raymond W. Jr. 1990. “Psycholinguistic Studies on the Conceptual Basis of Idiomaticity”. Cognitive Linguistics (includes Cognitive Linguistic Bibliography), Volume 1, Issue 4, 417-452. Walter de Gruyter.##Gibbs, Raymond W. Jr. 2017. Metaphor Wars. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Gueunier, N. 2003. “Attitudes and representations in sociolinguistics: theories and practice”. International Journal of the Sociology of Language, 2003(160), 41-62.##Hellinger, Marlis and HadumodBußmann. 2001. Gender Across Languages. Amsterdam: John Benjamins.##Ianos, Maria Adelina. 2014. Language attitudes in a multilingual and multicultural context: The case of autochthonous and immigrant students in Catalonia. Doctoral Dissertation, Coordinated by: JuditJanés and CecilioLapresta. Lleida:University of Lleida.##Katz, Jerrold J. 1967. “Some Remarks on Quine on Analyticity”, Journal of Philosophy. Volume 64, 36-52.##Krauss, Robert M. and Chi-Yue Chiu. 1998. “Language and Social Behavior”. In D. Gilbert, S. Fiske &amp; G. Lindsey (Eds.), Handbook of social psychology (4h ed.), Vol. 2. 41-88. Boston: McGraw-Hill.##Krejcie Robert V. and Daryle W. Morgan. 1970. “Determining Sample Size for Research Activities”. Educational and Psychological Measurement. Volume 30, Issue 3, 607-610. SAGE.##Lakoff, George. 1987. Women, Fire and Dangerous Things: What Categories Reviled about the Mind. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.##Levon, Erez. 2014. “Categories, stereotypes, and the linguistic perception of sexuality”. Language in Society, 2014 (43), 539–566.##Lipka, Leonhard. 1972. Semantic Structure and Word-Formation. München: Wilhelm Fink Verlag.##Moreno-Fernández, Francisco. 2017. A Framework for Cognitive Sociolinguistics. New York/London: Routledge.##Samarina V. V. and T. L. Poliakova. 2018. “Linguistic representation of gender stereotypes in English advertising texts”. Science and Education a New Dimension. Philology, VI(47), Issue: 160, 2018, 56-58.##Speelman, Dirk, AdriaanSpruyt, Leen Impe, and Dirk Geeraerts. 2013. “Language Attitudes Revisited: Auditory Affective Priming”. Journal of Pragmatics, Volume 52, June 2013, 83-92.##Weinreich, Uriel. 1966. “Explorations in Semantic Theory”. in Thomas A. Sebeok (ed.): Myth: A Symposium (A Midland Book).Indiana University Press, 395-477.##Windfuhr, Gernot and John R. Perry. 2009. “PERSIAN AND TAJIK”. In Gernot Windfuhr (ed.): The Iranian Languages. Oxon: Routledge.##https://www.amar.org.ir/##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				