<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Seismotectonic and  seismic hazard analysis in Dezful and Susa cities</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل لرزه زمین ساخت و خطر زلزله در محدوده شهرهای دزفول و شوش</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>272</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>283</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15062</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28986.1963</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>چرچی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز ، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید ساجدالدین</FirstName>
					<LastName>موسوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز ، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2794-985X</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهزاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>شاه آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز ، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This research focuses on seismotectonic setting and seismic risk analysis of Dezful and Susa cities for 50 km radius. It helps to the safety of critical structures, and optimum siting of new projects in these cities. Results of the study lead to protect lives and decrease economic risks when a probable earthquake will occur in the area. For these purposes, geological investigations, and recognition of faults, as well as their geometry in this region carried out. Moreover, the seismic background of these cities evaluated. The ground motion parameters estimate by probabilistic seismic hazard analysis in defferent probability. For return periods of 25, 50, 100, and 200 years, results show that the maximum magnitude of design base earthquake (DBE) is 5.4, 5.6, 5.9, 6.1 Richter, respectively. For Dezful city, the maximum acceleration of design base earthquake and maximum credible earthquake calculate 0.22 and 0.33g, respectively, using Donovan equation. In addition, these parameters, for Susa city, estimate equal to 0.24 and 0.36g. The seismic zonation maps revealed that the highest risk of the area located in middle and northern parts. Therefore, it is necessary to retrofit the historical and worn-out urban structures.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این تحقیق وضعیت لرزه‌زمین‌ساخت و تحلیل خطر زمین‌لرزه شهرستان‌های دزفول و شوش تا شعاع 50 کیلومتری مورد توجه قرار گرفت. این موضوع می-تواند به ایمن‌سازی سازه‎های مهم و مکان‌یابی مناسب تاسیسات و سازه‌های جدید در سطح این شهرستان‌ها کمک کند. به همین دلیل در این تحقیق با بررسی شرایط زمین شناسی منطقه اقدام به شناسایی گسل‌های محدوده مطالعاتی و تعیین ابعاد و هندسه آنها شده است. هم‌چنین، پیشینه لرزه‌خیزی این منطقه مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفت. در این مقاله برآورد پارامترهای جنبش زمین به روش آماری-احتمالاتی و در سطوح احتمال وقوع مختلف انجام شده است. نتایج نشان می-دهند که بیشینه بزرگی زلزله مبنای طرح (احتمال 64 درصد) برای دوره های بازگشت 25، 50، 100 و 200 ساله در این منطقه بترتیب 4/5، 6/5، 9/5 و 1/6 ریشتر برآورد شد. نتایج حاصل از رابطه میرایی دانووان موید آن است که بیشینه شتاب قابل انتظار و مبنای طرح برای شهر دزفول بترتیب 22/0 و g 33/0 است. این مقدار برای شهر شوش بترتیب 24/0 و g 36/0 است. نقشه‌های پهنه‌بندی تهیه شده مبین آن است که، بخش‌های شمالی و میانی گستره مورد مطالعه از بیشترین خطر برخوردار می باشند. بنابراین، باید نسبت به مقاوم‌سازی و تقویت بافت‌های فرسوده و تاریخی اقدام نمود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لرزه زمین ساخت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل احتمالاتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خطر زلزله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دزفول</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شوش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15062_8934877b81198b283dc04ef32b919854.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
