<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Comparison of geology, petrography, geochemistry and petrogenesis of ignimbrite in Sabalan and Sahand volcanoes</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مقایسه زمین‌شناسی، پتروگرافی، زمین‌شیمی و منشأ ایگنیمبریت در آتشفشان‌های سبلان و سهند</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>17</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>24</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14868</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.27148.1893</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جلیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>قلمقاش</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی پژوهشکده علوم زمین-سازمان زمین شناسی و اکتشافات معدنی کشور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>کتابی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد-پژوهشکده علوم زمین-سازمان زمین شناسی و اکتشافات معدنی کشور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهام</FirstName>
					<LastName>اصفهانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد- پژوهشکده علوم زمین- سازمان زمین شناسی و اکتشافات معدنی کشور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید زاهد</FirstName>
					<LastName>موسوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی مشکین شهر</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In the present work, the ignimbrites of Sabalan and Sahand volcanoes have been studied. The geological, petrographic, and geochemical properties of Sabalan and Sahand ignimbrites presented here. Sabalan ignimbrites contain plagioclase, amphibole, pyroxene, biotite phenocrysts and rock fragments. The rock fragments are mostly pumice and obsidian. Sahand ignimbrites have plagioclase, sanidine, quartz, hornblende and biotite glassy groundmass. Sieve texture in plagioclase crystals and corrosion of the margin of some minerals in Sabalan and Sahand ignimbrites indicate that primary magma is affected by contamination and mixing before eruption. The Sabalan and Sahand ignimbrites have composition range of trachy- dacite to rhyolite and dacite to rhyolite, respectively. In the trace elements normalized diagrams, these rocks are enriched in LREE and LILE relative to HREE and HFSE, respectively. High content of Sr/Y-Y and La/Yb-Yb indicate that these rocks have high SiO2 adakites nature. The Sabalan and Sahand ignimbrites were sourced from the partial melting of lower crust with garnet amphibolite composition. The degree of partial melting in the primary magma of sabalan ignimbrites appear to be higher than that of Sahand ignimbrites.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در مطالعه حاضر نهشته‌های ایگنیمبریتی سبلان و سهند مورد مطالعه و نمونه برداری قرار گرفته اند. هدف از این مطالعه بررسی ویژگیهای زمین شناسی، پتروگرافی و زمین‌شیمیایی این ایگنیمبریتها است. ایگنیمبریت‌های سبلان دارای درشت بلورهای پلاژیوکلاز، آمفیبول، پیروکسن، بیوتیت و قطعات سنگی از نوع پومیس و ابسیدین هستند. در صورتی که قطعاتی از درشت بلورهای پلاژیوکلاز، سانیدین، کوارتز، هورنبلند و بیوتیت در متن ایگنیمبریت‌های سهند به همراه شیشه وجود دارد. بافت غربالی در بلورهای پلاژیوکلاز و خوردگی حاشیه برخی از کانی‌ها در ایگنیمبریت‌های سبلان و سهند نشان می‌دهد که ماگمای اولیه تحت تأثیر فرایندهای ماگمایی از جمله آلودگی و اختلاط ماگمایی قرار گرفته است. از نظر زمین‌شیمیایی ایگنیمبریت‌های سبلان و سهند به ترتیب ترکیب تراکی‌داسیتی- ریولیتی و داسیتی - ریولیتی دارند. این سنگ‌ها در نمودارهای عناصر کمیاب به‌هنجار شده، دارای غنی‌شدگی از LREE و LILE به ترتیب نسبت به HREE و HFSE هستند. مقادیر بالای Sr/Y-Y و La/Yb-Yb نشان می‌دهد که این سنگ‌ها ماهیت آداکیتی سیلیس بالا دارند. با توجه به این ویژگیهای زمین شیمیایی و بر اساس نمودارSm/Yb دربرابر La/Yb ایگنیمبریت‌های سبلان و سهند از ذوب‌بخشی پوسته‌ قاره‌ای پایینی با ترکیب آمفیبولیت گارنت‌دار ایجاد شده‌اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایگنیمبریت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سبلان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سهند</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آداکیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آمفیولیت-گارنت دار</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_14868_b49b88ae78b850dd28a8e0b9cd0c5504.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
