<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" "journalpublishing3.dtd">
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11571_88ac69d3dd66325547b07602c384c8b8.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>مدیریت کمی و کیفی آبخوان دشت رامهرمز با استفاده از مدل ریاضی در MODFLOW و MD3DMS</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>چیت سازان</surname>
			            <given-names>منوچهر</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>موسوی</surname>
			            <given-names>سیده فاطمه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد هیدروژئولوژی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>میرزائی</surname>
			            <given-names>سید یحیی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رستگار زاده</surname>
			            <given-names>سعادت</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2012</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>1</fpage>
			      <lpage>8</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>08</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2011</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>30</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2012</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2012, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2012</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11571.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11571.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>      مدلسازی یکی ازروشهای غیر مستقیم مطالعه منابع آبهای زیرزمینی است که بعلت کارایی بالا و هزینه کمتر نسبت به روشهای دیگر در حال حاضر توجه زیادی رابه خود جذب نموده است. مطالعه حاضربا استفاده ازنسخه مادفلویPMWIN 5.3  در دشت رامهرمز در استان خوزستان صورت گرفته است. منطقه مورد مطالعه 267 کیلومتر مربع است که به یک لایه با 7735سلول تقسیم شده است. نتایج اندازه­گیری سطح ایستابی و غلظت نیترات، داده­های لیتولوژیکی، پارامترهای هیدروژئولوژیکی وداده­های بارندگی در مدل مورد استفاده قرار گرفتند و با مدلهای MODFLOW و MT3DMS واسنجی و صحت­سنجی گردیدند. برای حصول به مقادیر بهینه هدایت هیدرولیکی، جریان مرزی، آبدهی ویژه و نفوذ ناشی ازبارندگی و آب برگشتی ازچاه­ها، مدل جریان از مهر 1388 تا شهریور 1389 به مدت یک سال واسنجی و از مهر 1389 تا آخر اسفند 1389 به مدت شش ماه صحت­سنجی شد. پس از واسنجی و صحت­سنجی مدل جریان، مدل انتقال آلودگی نیترات به مدت شش ماه از خرداد 1389 تا آبان 1389 واسنجی و طی یک دوره دو ماهه در مهر و آبان 1389 صحت­سنجی شد. نتایج حاصل از بیلان مدل کمی تحت سناریوهای مدیریتی مختلف نشان داد که آبخوان قابلیت تحمل تنش­های شدید را داراست و با مدیریت صحیح می­توان از آب آبخوان جهت توسعه کشاورزی منطقه استفاده کرد. از نظر کیفی نیز آبخوان در مرحله گذر از خط 50 درصد آلودگی است که با توجه به سناریوهای مختلف و با برنامه­ریزی مناسب می­توان طی طولانی مدت آبخوان را پاکیزه کرد. .</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کلمات کلیدی: رامهرمز</kwd>
						<kwd>مدلسازی</kwd>
						<kwd>MODFLOW</kwd>
						<kwd>MD3DMS</kwd>
						<kwd>آبخوان</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>پیر هادی.ع.، 1377، مطالعه منابع آب دشت رامهرمز و بررسی گزینه های مختلف مدیریتی با استفاده از مدل ریاضی، پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>چیت سازان.م. و ساعت ساز.م.، 1384، کاربرد مدل ریاضی MODFLOW در بررسی گزینه­های مختلف مدیریت منابع آب دشت­رامهرمز، مجله علوم دانشگاه شهیدچمران اهواز، شماره14، ص:1 -15.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>چیت سازان.م. و صدقی.م،م.،1383، تعیین شرایط مرزی مناسب برای مدل جریان آبهای زیرزمینی دشت ارسنجان، بیست و سومین گردهمایی علوم زمین، تهران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>لاله­زاری.ر.، 1387، بررسی تأثیر آبخوان شهرکرد بر انتشار نیترات با استفاده از مدل MT3D، پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه شهرکرد، ص1-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>موسوی.س.ف.،1390 شبیه سازی کمی و کیفی منابع آب دشت رامهرمز با استفاده از مدل ریاضی تفاضل محدود، پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه شهید چمران، اهواز.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>موسوی.ع.، 1389، شبیه سازی کمی آبخوان دشت شبستر با استفاده از مدل ریاضی. پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تبریز.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>ناصری.ح.ر. و ندافیان.ح.، 1387، مدل سازی انتقال آلاینده نیترات آب های زیرزمینی در محدوده چاه های آب شرب همدان، فصلنامه زمین شناسی ایران، سال دوم، شماره6، ص 87-98.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>وزارت نیرو.، 1388، راهنمای تهیه مدل ریاضی آب های زیرزمینی، دفتر مهندسی و معیار های فنی آب و آبفا، معاونت امور آب و آبفا، نشریه شماره 337-الف. ص 110-1.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Almasri. M.N. and Kaluarachchi. J.J, 2007, Modeling nitrate contamination of groundwater in agricultural watersheds,  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>   Journal of Hydrology, 343, 211-229.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Don. N.C., Araki. H., Yamanishi. H. and Koga, K, 2005, Simulation of groundwater flow and environmental effects resulting</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>   from pumping, Environmental Geology, 47:361-374.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Jerome. M. and Chantal. G.O, 2002, Modeling flow and nitrate transport in groundwater for the prediction of water travel</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>   time and of consequences of land use evolution on water quality, Hydrological Processes, 16(2):479-492.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>   model, U. S. Geological Survey, Open-file report 83-875. Chapter A1.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Zheng. C. and Wang. P.P, 1999, A modular three-dimensional multispecies transport model for simulation of advection,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>   dispersion and chemical reaction of contaminant in groundwater systems, Documentation and User’s Guide, Department of  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>   Geology and Mathematics, University of Alabama, pp: 202.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11572_bfbb992218934a7d7471e1249cb59544.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>زمین شناسی اقتصادی کانسار اسکارن آهن چنار علیا با تکیه بر بررسی میان بارهای سیال، شمال غرب همدان</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>زمانیان</surname>
			            <given-names>حسن</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی دانشکده علوم دانشگاه لرستان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>دولتشاهی</surname>
			            <given-names>سمیه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی دانشکده علوم دانشگاه لرستان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>زارعی سهامیه</surname>
			            <given-names>رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی دانشکده علوم دانشگاه لرستان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2012</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>9</fpage>
			      <lpage>19</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2012</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>31</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2012</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2012, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2012</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11572.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11572.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>      کانسار آهن چنار علیا در استان همدان و 24 کیلومتری شمال شهر اسد آباد قرار دارد. این کانسار در انتهای بخش شمال غربی زون ساختاری سنندج - سیرجان واقع شده است. نفوذ توده کوارتز سینیتی آلموقلاق بدرون سری آتشفشانی- رسوبی  سنقر با سن  تریاس- ژوراسیک باعث نهشته شدن این کانسار شده است. کانی سازی در منطقه به دو صورت توده ای و رگه ای است. کانی اصلی این کانسار مگنتیت است و هماتیت به عنوان دومین کانی آهن دار نهشته شده است. پیریت عمده ترین فاز سولفیدی  در این کانسار است. میانبارهای سیال نمونه های کوارتزی این کانسار بیشتر دو فازی و غنی از مایع با اشکال کشیده می باشند. مطالعات میکروترمومتری این  میانبارها نشان می دهد که میانگین شوری و دمای پیدایش این کانسار به ترتیب در محدوده 5.15- 5.2 درصد وزنی نمک طعام و 170-165 درجه سانتیگراد قرار می گیرد. چگالی میانبارهای سیال نمونه های کوارتزی کانسار آهن چنار علیا از 89/0 تا 02/1 متغیر است، عمق به دام افتادن سیالات درگیر کانسار چنار علیا در حدود 100 متر و در نزدیکی سطح زمین بوده است، همچنین فشار حاکم در طی تشکیل سیالات در حدود 50 بار بدست آمده است. نهشت آهن در منطقه پیامد تحرک مجدد سیالات متاسوماتیسم کننده، در راستای پهنه های برشی، مرزهای گسل خورده و شکستگی های سطحی است. مطالعات کانی شناسی، میزان شوری و دمای همگن شدگی میانبارهای سیال نشان دهنده این است که کانی زایی در کانسار آهن چنار علیا در مرحله تأخیری اسکارن صورت پذیرفته است.
 </p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کلمات کلیدی: کانسار چنار علیا</kwd>
						<kwd>مگنتیت</kwd>
						<kwd>کانی شناسی</kwd>
						<kwd>میانبارهای سیال</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>اشراقی، س.،1380، نقشه زمین شناسی100000/1 تویسرکان، انتشارات سازمان زمین شناسی و اکتشافات معدنی کشور.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>توکلی، ح.،1383، کانی شناسی، ژئوشیمی و خاستگاه کانسارهای آهن شمال غرب همدان، پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران، 154 ص.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>رستمی پایدار، ق.، لطفی، م.، قادری، م.، امیری. ا.، عابدینی، م.،1389، یافته های جدید کانه نگاری و شیمی بلور مگنتیت و پیریت درکانسارهای آهن باباعلی وگلالی، باختر همدان، ایران، مجله علوم زمین، شماره 77، صفحه 121- 130.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>شرکت ایران کانش.، 1379، طرح اکتشاف مقدماتی سنگ آهن چنار علیا، اداره کل صنایع و معادن استان همدان، 88 ص.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Bodnar. R. J., 1993, Revised  equation and table for determining the freezing point depression of H2O-NaCl solution, Geochim .Cosmochim .Acta, Vol: 57, p: 683-684.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Craij. J. R., Vaughan. D. J., 1981, Ore microscopy and ore petrography, Copyright by John Wiley and sons, 406p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Drummond. S. E., Ohmoto. H., 1985, chemical evolution and mineral deposition in boiling hydrothermal systems, Economic Geology, Vol: 80, p: 126-147.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Einaudi. M. T., Meinert. L. D., Newberry. R. J., 1981, Skarn deposits, Economic Geology, p: 317–391.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Eugster. H. P., 1986, Minerals in hote water, Am. Mineral, Vol: 71, p: 655-673.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Hass. J. I., 1971, The effect of salinity on the maximum thermal gradient of a hydrothermal system at hydrostatic pressure, Economic Geology, Vol: 66, p: 940-946.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Kwak. T. A. P., Tan. T. H., 1981, The geochemistry of zoninig in the skarn mineral at the at the King Island_Dolphine mine, Economic Geologyv, Vol: 76, p: 468-497.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Lingang.  Xu.,et al., 2010, Geology geochemistry and age constrains on the Mengku skarn iron deposite in Xinjiang Altai, NW China, jornal of Asian Earth Sciences, Vol: 39, No: 5, p: 423-440.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Meinert. L. D., 1992, Skarn zonation and fluid evalution in the Groundhog Mine,Central Mining District , New Mexico, Economic Geology, Vol: 82, p: 523-545.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Mikucki. E. J., Groves. D. I., 1990, Genesis of primary gold deposits:gold transport and depositional models, Geol.Dep.and Uni.Extension, The Uni.of Western Aus, Vol: 20, p: 212-220.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Pirajno.  F., 1992, Hydrothermal Mineral Deposits – Principles and fundamental concepts for the Exploration Geologist, Springer, 709p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Ramdohr. P.,1980,The ore minerals and their intergrowths, Sec. Edition, English translation of the 4th. Edition. Two valumes, pergamon press, 1205p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Roedder.  E., 1984, Fluid Inclusions, Rev. Mineralogy, Mineral. Soc. Am, p: 12-644.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Scott. A. M., Watanabe. Y ., 1998, ((Extreme boiling)) model for variable salinity of the Hokko low- sulfidation epithermal Au prospect,southwestern Hokkaido, Japan Mineralium Deposita, Vol: 33, p: 568-578.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Shepherd. T. J., Ranbin. A. H., Alderton D .H. M., 1985, A Practical Guide to fluid inclusion studies, Blackie, Glasgow, 239p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Singoyi. B., Zaw. K., 2001, A petro logical and fluid inclusion of magnetite scheelite skarn mineralization at Lara, northwestern Tasmania: implications for ore genesis, Chemical geology, Vol: 173, p: 239 – 253.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Wang. Y., Sasaki. M., Sasada.  M., Chen. C. H., 1999, Fluid inclusion studies of the Chinkuashin high –sulfidation gold – copper deposits in Taiwan, Chemical Geology, Vol: 154, p: 155-167.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Wilkinson.  J. J., 2001, Fluid inclusions in hydrothermal ore deposits, Lithos, Vol: 25, p: 229- 279.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Zamanian.   H . ,2003, Iron mineralization related to the Almoughlagh and south Ghorveh batholiths, western Iran, with a specific refrence to the Baba Ali and Gelali deposits, thesis sbmitted for the degree of PhD, Univercity of Pune, 215p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation> Zhou. T., Yang.  F., Yuc.  S., Liu.  X., Zhang.  X., Fan. Y., 2007, Geochemistry and evolution of ore- forming fluids of the Yueshan Cu-Au skarn and vein- type deposits, Anhui province, south China, Ore Geology reviews, Vol: 31, p: 279-303.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11573_fa344cdc526836f62318b18cfe36bab5.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی الگوی دگرشکلی با استفاده از تحلیل استرین نهایی و عدد تاوایی جنبش شناختی در پهنه دگرشکل شده چشمه سفید، کمربند دگرگونی سنندج-سیرجان</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>سامانی</surname>
			            <given-names>بابک</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی دانشکده علوم دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>چرچی</surname>
			            <given-names>عباس</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی دانشکده علوم دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فقیه</surname>
			            <given-names>علی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>بخش علوم زمین دانشگاه شیراز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2012</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>20</fpage>
			      <lpage>26</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>09</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2011</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>09</day>
			          <month>12</month>
			          <year>2012</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2012, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2012</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11573.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11573.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>      کنگلومرا و میکروکنگلومرای دگرشکل شده مزوزوئیک در کمربند دگرگونی سنندج- سیرجان یکی از بهترین نشانگرهای جنبش شناختی برای  مطالعات استرین می باشد. در بررسی استرین دوبعدی با استفاده از روش Rf/Ø بیشترین مقدار استرین تکتونیکی (Rs=5.4) در صفحه XZ بیضوی استرین در مقایسه با صفحات XY و YZ بدست آمد. ترسیم مقادیر میانگین هماهنگ نسبت ابعادی قلوه های کنگلومرا بر روی نمودار فلین نشان دهنده تغییرات پارامتر شکل بیضوی استرین (K) بین 6/0 تا 9/0 می باشد. تحلیل تاوایی پورفیروکلاستهای دگرشکل شده نشان دهنده تغییرات عدد تاوایی (Wk) بین 43/0 تا 63/0 بوده که  نشان دهنده عملکرد هر دو مولفه های برش ساده و محض در منطقه مورد مطالعه است. بر اساس تحلیل  عدد تاوایی جنبش شناختی مقادیر درصدی برش ساده و محض (30% &gt;برش ساده&gt; 42% ) و(58% &gt;برش محض&gt; 70% )تعیین گردید. این نتایج ماهیت استرین با غلبه برش محض حاصل از حرکات همگرایی بین صفحات آفرو-عربی و صفحه ایران را آشکار می سازد. با استفاده از نتایج حاصل از تحلیل استرین و تاوایی، مقادیر کوتاه شدگی در صفحه XZ بیضوی استرین در منطقه مورد مطالعه بین 42% تا 50% محاسبه گردید. 
 </p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کلمات کلیدی: استرین نهایی</kwd>
						<kwd>عدد تاوایی</kwd>
						<kwd>بیضوی استرین</kwd>
						<kwd>الگوی دگرشکلی</kwd>
						<kwd>کنگلومرا</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Alavi, M., 1994. Tectonics of the Zagros orogenic belt of Iran: new data and interpretations. Tectonophysics 229, 211-238.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Alavi, M., 2004.Regional stratigraphy of the Zagros fold-thrust belt of Iran, and its proforeland evolution. American Journal of Science 304, 1–20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Bailey, C.M., Gilmer, A.K., Marquis, M.N., 1999. A tale of two shear zones: the vorticity and strain path of two greenschist facies shear zones. Geological Society of America Abstracts with Programs 31 (7), 59.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Berberian, M., King, G.C.P., 1981. Towards a paleogeography and tectonic evolution of Iran. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences 18, 210–265.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>De Paor, D.G., 1988. R/ strain analysis using an orientation net. Journal of Structural Geology 10, 323–333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Dewey, J.F., Pitman, W.C. III, Ryan, W.B.F., Bonnin, J., 1973. Plate tectonics and the evolution of the Alpine System. Geological Society of America Bulletin 84, 3137–3180.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Eshraghi, S.A., Roshan Ravan, J., Sabzehei, M., 1999. Geological map of the Quatruyeh area, scale 1:100,000. Geological Survey of Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Fort, A.M., Bailey, C.M., 2007. Testing the utility of the porphyroclast hyperbolic distribution method of kinematic vorticity analysis. Journal of Structural Geology 29, 983–1001.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Law, R.D., Searle, M.P., Simpson, R.L., 2004. Strain, deformation temperatures and vorticity of flow at the top of the Greater Himalayan Slab, Everest Massif, Tibet. Journal of the Geological Society, London 161, pp. 305–320.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Lin, S., Jiang, D., Williams, P.F., 1998. Transpression (or transtension) zones of triclinic symmetry: natural example and theoretical modelling. In: Holdsworth, R.E., Strachan, R.A., Dewey, J.F. (Eds.), Continental Transpressional and Transtensional Tectonics. Special Publication of the Geological Society, London 135, pp. 41–57.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>McClay, K.R., Whitehouse, P.S., Dooley, M and Richards, M., 2004. 3D evolution of fold and thrust belts formed by oblique convergence. Marine and Petroleum Geology 21, 857-877.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Mc Quarrie, N., 2004. Crustal scale geometry of the Zagros fold–thrust belt, Iran. Journal of Structural Geology 26, 519–535.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Means, W.D., Hobbs, B.E., Lister, G.S., Williams, P.F., 1980. Vorticity and noncoaxiality in progressive deformations. Journal of Structural Geology 2, 371–378.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Meere, P.A., Mulchrone, K.F., 2003. The effect of sample size on geological strain estimation from passively deformed clastic sedimentary rocks. Journal of Structural Geology 25, 1587-1595.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Mohajjel, M., Fergusson, C.L., 2000.  Dextral transpression in Late Cretaceous continental collision, Sanandaj–Sirjan Zone, western Iran. Journal of Structural Geology, 22, 1125-139.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Passchier, C. W., Trouw, R. A. J., 2005. Microtectonics. Springer-Verlag, Berlin. 336p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Ramsay, J.G., Huber, M.I., 1983. The Techniques of Modern Structural Geology, Volume 1. Strain Analysis. Academic Press, London.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Ramsay, J.G., Wood, D.S., 1973. The geometric effects of volume change during deformation processes. Tectonophysics 16, 263-277.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Samani, B., 2010. Finite strain and deformation flow geometry in the Sanandaj-Sirjan HP-LT metamorphic belt, Iran. Ph.D thesis, Shiraz University, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Sarkarinejad, K., 1999. Tectonic finite strain analysis using Ghuri deformed conglomerate, Neyriz area Southwestern Iran. Iranian Journal of Science and Technology 23, 351–363.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Sarkarinejad, K., Azizi, A., 2008. Slip partitioning and inclined dextral transpression along the Zagros Thrust System, Iran. Journal of Structural Geology 30, 116–136.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Sarkarinejad, K., Faghih, A., Grasemann, B., 2008. Transpressional deformations within the Sanandaj-Sirjan Metamorphic Belt (ZagrosMountains, Iran). Journal of Structural Geology 30, 818–826.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Sarkarinejad, K., Samani, B., Faghih, A., Grasemann, B., Moradipoor, M., 2010. Implications of strain and vorticity of flow analyses to interpret the kinematics of an oblique convergence event (Zagros Mountains, Iran). Journal of Asian Earth Sciences 38, 34–43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>25       </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Sheikholeslami, M.R., Pique, A., Mobayen, P., Sabzehei, M., Bellon, H., Hashem Emami, M., 2008. Tectono-metamorphic evolution of the Neyriz metamorphic complex, Quri-Kor-e-Sefid area (Sanandaj-Sirjan Zone, SW Iran). Journal of Asian Earth Sciences 31, 504–521.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Simpson, C., De Paor, D. G. 1997. Practical analysis of general shear zones using porphyroclast hyperbolic distribution method: an example from the Scandinavian Caledonides. In: SENGUPTA, S. (ed) Evolution of Geological Structures in Micro- to Macro-scales. Chapman and Hall, London, 169–184.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Stocklin, J. 1968. Structural history and tectonics of Iran. A review. American Association of Petroleum Geologists Bulletin 52, 1229-1258.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Treagus, S.H., Treagus, J.E., 2002. Studies of strain and rheology of conglomerates. Journal of Structural Geology 24, 1541-1567.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Truesdell, C., 1953. Two measures of vorticity. Journal of Rotational Mechanical Analysis 2, 173-217.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Wallis, S.R., 1992. Vorticity analysis in a metachert from the Sanbagawa belt, SW Japan. Journal of Structural Geology 14, 271-280.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Wallis, S., 1995. Vorticity analysis and recognition of ductile extension in the Sanbagawa belt, SW Japan. Journal of Structural Geology 17, 1077–1093.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Wallis, S. R., Platt, J. P., Knott, S. D. 1993. Recognition of syn-convergence extension in accretionary wedges with examples from the Calabrian Arc and the Eastern Alps. American Journal of Science, 293, 463–495.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Xypolias, P., 2010. Vorticity analysis in shear zones: A review of methods and applications. Journal of Structural Geology 32, 2072–2092.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11574_481c32ecd60e48570ef962203a55aee7.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>زمین شیمی و چینه‌نگاری سکانسی سازند پابده در میدان نفتی منصوری، جنوب‌غرب ایران</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>علیزاده</surname>
			            <given-names>بهرام</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین شناسی دانشکده علوم  زمین دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز و مرکز پژوهش زمین شناسی و زمین شیمی نفت</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>جنت مکان</surname>
			            <given-names>ندا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناسی ارشد گروه زمین شناسی دانشکده علوم زمین  دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>قلاوند</surname>
			            <given-names>هرمز</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>مدیر اکتشافات شرکت ملی نفت ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>غبیشاوی</surname>
			            <given-names>علی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>اداره زمین شناسی شرکت ملی مناطق نفت خیز جنوب</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2012</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>27</fpage>
			      <lpage>40</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>03</day>
			          <month>12</month>
			          <year>2011</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>16</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2012, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2012</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11574.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11574.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>هدف از این مطالعه ارزیابی پتانسیل هیدروکربوری سازند پابده میدان منصوری به عنوان سنگ­منشاء احتمالی در چهارچوب چینه­نگاری سکانسی است. قالب چینه­نگاری سکانسی سازند پابده با استفاده از لاگ GR چاه­های مورد مطالعه در نرم­افزار Cyclolog 3.2 تهیه و واحدهای رسوبی هم­زمان در این سازند مشخص گردیدند. جهت تعیین سیستم­تراکت­های نهشتی و ارزیابی پتانسیل هیدروکربوری سازند پابده از داده­های ژئوشیمی­آلی استفاده شد. مطالعه حاضر وجود دو سکانس رسوبی رده 2 را در سازند پابده نشان داد؛ سیستم تراکت پسرونده سکانس اول در زمان پالئوسن پسین تا ائوسن میانی نهشته شده و سکانس دوم در زمان ائوسن بصورت سیستم تراکت پیشرونده شکل گرفته ­است. وجود شیل­های قهوه­ای و بکارگیری مقایسه نمودار فیتان/پریستان ـ اندیس هموفان C35 نیز افزایش سطح آب دریا و وجود پیشروی را در این زمان تأیید می­کند. در نهایت در بخش فوقانی این سازند سیستم تراکت پسرونده سکانس دوم با سن الیگوسن پیشین تشخیص داده شد. بررسی­های انجام شده نشان داد که سازند پابده از نظر پتانسیل هیدروکربوری یکنواخت نبوده و می­توان آن را به سه بخش تقسیم نمود. ارتباط خوبی بین تغییرات نسبی سطح آب و تغییرات پتانسیل هیدروکربوری دیده شد. در بخش میانی (زمان ائوسن پسین) در زمان بالا بودن سطح نسبی تراز آب دریا مقدار TOC حدوداً تا %5 افزایش یافته است. در این بخش، مواد­آلی عمدتاً کروژن نوع II بوده و توانایی تولید نفت را دارد. در حالیکه در بخش­های زیرین و فوقانی با توجه به پایین­تر بودن سطح نسبی تراز آب در مقایسه با بخش میانی، مقدار TOC حدوداً %2 ـ 5/0 بوده و مواد­آلی عمدتاً کروژن نوع III است. همچنین این بخش­ها در سازند پابده پتانسیل تولید گاز را دارند. با استفاده از تطابق چینه­نگاری سکانسی و زون­بندی انجام شده سازند پابده در چاه 6 منصوری، در سایر چاه­های 31، 27، 21، 16، 14، 25، 15، 20 و 28 که داده ژئوشیمی وجود نداشت دنبال شده و توزیعشان در سرتاسر میدان منصوری پیش­بینی شد. صحت­سنجی نتایج نیز این روش را تأیید نمود. درنهایت آشکار شد که زون دارای پتانسیل تولید بالاتر در بخش میانی سازند پابده در کل میدان منصوری قرار دارد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کلمات کلیدی: سازند پابده</kwd>
						<kwd>میدان نفتی منصوری</kwd>
						<kwd>راک­ایول</kwd>
						<kwd>چینه­نگاری سکانسی</kwd>
						<kwd>Cyclolog 3.2</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>امینی.ع.، 1388، مبانی چینه نگاری سکانسی، انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>سراج.م.، 1384، تحلیل ساختاری مقدماتی میادین نفتی مناطق نفتخیز جنوب (محدوده فروافتادگی دزفول شمالی)، بایگانی شرکت ملی مناطق نفتخیز جنوب، گزارش شماره پ-5613.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>References:</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Behar.F., Beamont.V., Penteodo.H., 2001, Rock-Eval6 Technology performance and developments, Oil &amp; Gas Science and  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>   Technology-Rev. IFP, Vol: 56, p: 111-134</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Catuneanu. O., 2006, Principles of sequence stratigraphy, Elsevier, 375 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Catuneanu.O., Bhattacharya.J.P., Blum.M.D., Dalrymple.R.W., Eriksson.P.G., Fielding.C.R., Fisher.W.L., Galloway.W.E.,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>   Gianolla.P., Gibling.M.R., Giles.K.A., Holbrook..M., Jordan.R., Kendall.C.G.St.C., Macurda.B., Martinsen.O.J., Miall.A.D.,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>   Nummedal.D., Posamentier.H.W., Pratt.B.R., Shanley.K.W., Steel.R.J., Strasser.A., Tucker.M.E., 2010, Sequence  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>   stratigraphy: common ground after three decades of development, Vol: 28, p: 21-34</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Creaney.S., Passey.Q.R., 1993, Recurring Patterns of  total organic carbon and source rock quality within a sequence</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>   stratigraphic framework, American Association of Petroleum Geologists Bulletin, Vol: 77, No: 3, p: 386-40</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Embry.A., 2002, Transgressive-regressive (T-R) sequence stratigraphy, in Armentrout and N. Rosen, eds., Gulf coast SEPM</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>   Conference proceedings, Houston, p: 151-172</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Embry.A., Johannessen.E., 1992, T-R sequence stratigraphy, facies analysis and reservoir distribution in the uppermost</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>   Triassic-lower Jurassic succession, western Sverdrup Basin, Arctic Canada, in T. Vorren et al., eds., Arctic geology and</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>   Petroleum potential: Norwegian Petroleum Society Special Publication 2, p: 121-146</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Fleck.S., Michels.R., Ferry.S., Malartre.F., Elion.P., Landaise.P., 2002, Organic geochemistry in a sequence stratigraphic</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>   framework. The siliciclastic shelf environment of cretaceous series, SE France, p: 1533-1557</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Goddard.D.A., Mancini.E.A., Talukar.S.C., Horn.M., 1997, Bossier – Hanesvill shale,  North Louisian salt basin:  Lousiana  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>   State University,  Baton  Rouge,  Louisiana,  center for energy, pdf file, www. api. ning. com/files</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Hunt.J., 1996, Petroleum Geochemistry and Geology. 2nd Edition. W.H. Freeman and Company, New York, 743 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Katz.B.J., Pratt.L., 1991, Source Rocks within a sequence stratigraphic framework, American Association of Petroleum</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>   Geologists studies in Geology, p: 35-47</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Landais.P., Connan. J., Dereppe. J.M., George.E., Meunier.J.D., Monthioux.M., Pagel.M., Pironon.J., Poty.B., 1985, Alteration</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>   of organic matter; a clue for uranium or genesis uranium, III, p: 307-342</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Meijun.L., Yunlog.J., Liguo.H., 2003, Geochemical – Sequence stratigraphy and its Application prospects in lake basins,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>   Chines Journal of Geochemistry, Vol: 22</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Pasley.M., Gregory.W., Hart.G.F., 1991, Organic matter variations in trans-gressive and regressive shales, Org. Geochem, p:</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>   483-509</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Peters.K.E., Cassa.M.R., 1994, Applied source rock geochemistry, in: Magoon. L,B., Dow. W.G., (eds),The petroleum system</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>   from source to trap, AAPG memoir. Vol: 60, p:93-120</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Stoneley.R., 1990, The Arabian continental margin in Iran during the late cretaceous, In: Roberston.A.H.F., searl.M.P.,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>   Ries.A.C., Eds., The geology and tectonics of the Oman Region, Geol. Soc. London, spec, p: 787-795</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Tissot.B.P., Durand.B., Espitalie.J., Combaz.A., 1974, Influence and nature of diagenesis of organic matter in formation of</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>   petroleum, AAPG Bulletin, Vol: 58, p: 499-506</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Van Wagoner.J.C., Mitchum.R. M., Campion.K. M., Rahmanian.V. D., 1990, Siliciclastic sequence stratigraphy in well logs,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>   cores, and outcrops: concepts for high-resolution correlation of time and facies, AAPG, Methods in exploration series, 7,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>   Tulsa, 55pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Wynd.J.G., 1965, Biofacies of the Iranian Oil consortium Agreement Area, NIOC, Unpubl, Report, 1082 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11575_f79d156b4d3a74bbf66bba6975a23a25.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی مناطق دارای پتانسیل مواد اولیه آجر به منظور رفع مشکلات زیست محیطی در استان اصفهان</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>طباطبایی</surname>
			            <given-names>سید حسن</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده مهندسی دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>اسدی هارونی</surname>
			            <given-names>هوشنگ</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده مهندسی معدن دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>آیتی</surname>
			            <given-names>فریماه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه پیام نور ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2012</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>41</fpage>
			      <lpage>58</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>21</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2012</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>16</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2012, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2012</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11575.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11575.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>      استان اصفهان از دیرباز بعنوان قطب آجر ایران محسوب می شده است. قرارگیری کارخانه های تولید آجر در حوالی اصفهان و مصرف بالای رس مناسب زمین های کشاورزی، مشکلات زیست محیطی زیادی در محدوده ای به وسعت 20 کیلومترمربع در استان به وجود آورده است. با توجه به اهمیت این موضوع، در این تحقیق مواد اولیه آجر‌های رسی، شیلی و مارنی در محدوده‌ای به وسعت 12500 کیلومتر مربع دراستان اصفهان با کمک داده‌های ماهواره‌ای و نقشه‌های زمین‌شناسی 1:100000و کنترل زمینی شناسائی شدند. با انجام آزمایشات لازم بر روی نمونه های مناطق شناسائی شده مشخص گردید که با اختلاط بهینه مواد رس و شیل می توان به آجری استاندارد با مقاومت فشاری و جذب آب مناسب دست یافت. از طرفی با شناسائی و اولویت بندی مناطق دارای پتانسیل بالای مواد اولیه آجر در خارج از محدوده شهری اصفهان، می توان کارخانه‌های آجرنزدیک شهر را در آینده به این مناطق تغییر مکان داد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کلمات کلیدی: آجر</kwd>
						<kwd>مواد اولیه</kwd>
						<kwd>استان اصفهان</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>کریم پور ، م.ح.، 1385، کانی ها و سنگهای صنعتی، انتشارات دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، 397 صفحه.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>کباری، س.، 1387، مصالح شناسی، انتشارات دانش و فن، 262 صفحه.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>ایرانمنش، ح.، 1367،گزارش مختصر رس دشت آزادگان و شیل های زاگرس برای تولید آجر، سازمان زمین شناسی کشور.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>مهندسین مشاور اپال، 1377،گزارش مطالعه و تحقیق در مورد آجرهای شیلی و مارنی استان چهار محال و بختیاری.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>مالمیران،ح.، 1379، اصول مبانی سنجش از دور و تعبیر و تفسیر تصاویر هوایی و ماهواره ای، انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>اسدی هارونی، ه.، طباطبایی، ح.، 1386، کاربرد داده های ماهواره ای لندست  +ETM برای شناسائی مواد اولیه آجر و بلوکهای سفالی رنگی و خاک نسوز در  زاگرس مرتفع، مجموعه مقالات اولین همایش آجر و بلوکهای سفالی، دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Asadi, H., Hale, M., 1999, Integrated analysis of aeromagnetic, Landsat TM and mineral occurrence data for epithermal gold exploration in northwest Iran,Proceedings of the thirteenth International Conference on Applied Geologic Remote Sensing,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>   Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, 1-3 March, 8 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Crosta, C. R., 2003,Targeting key alteration minerals in epithermal deposits in Patagonia - Argentina using ASTER imagery and</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>   principal component analysis, Geosciences Institute, University of Campinas.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11576_b867ccd0bf102ebe78a2c78dc1602be5.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>شناسایی پدیده های طیفی ناشناخته از داده های تلفیقی تصاویر ماهواره ای ALI+ASTER و ابر طیفی Hyperion بر مبنای روش ضریب همبستگی:مطالعه موردی محدوده معدنی مس سرچشمه</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نجفیان</surname>
			            <given-names>طاهر</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناس ارشد مهندسی اکتشاف معدن دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فتحیان پور</surname>
			            <given-names>نادر</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده مهندسی معدن دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رنجبر</surname>
			            <given-names>حجت اله</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>بخش مهندسی معدن دانشگاه باهنر کرمان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بخش پور</surname>
			            <given-names>رامین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناس ارشد مهندسی نساجی دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2012</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>59</fpage>
			      <lpage>68</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>21</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2012</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>16</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2012, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2012</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11576.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11576.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>      یکی از مسائل مهم در بکارگیری تصاویر ماهواره ای چند طیفی و ابرطیفی، شناسایی و تشخیص رفتارهای طیفی متفاوت و  به تصویر کشیدن الگوی رفتاری آنها می باشد. که این امر تنها از طریق الگوریتم­های شناساگر که قادر به تشخیص شباهت­های طیفی مشاهدات آزمایشگاهی و یا صحرایی با داده های ماهواره ای می باشد، امکان پذیر است. در این تحقیق سعی شده تا بوسیله توسعه الگوریتمی مبتنی بر تصویر کردن طیف کانی­ها و مقایسه آنها با روش ضریب همبستگی، طیف ناشناسی را که از تصاویر ماهواره ای (چند طیفی و ابر طیفی) بدست می­آید با طیف­های کتابخانه­ای مرجع مقایسه و بر اساس شباهت طیفی، امکان تعلق آن به مجموعه کانی­های موجود در بانک کتابخانه طیفی محاسبه و کانی دارای حداکثر شباهت به کانی ناشناس مشخص گردد. در ابتدا و به منظور ارزیابی عملکرد الگوریتم از طیف­های کتابخانه­ای مرجع که توسط سازمان زمین شناسی آمریکا (USGS) ارائه شده است، استفاده گردید. نتایج حاصل از اجرای الگوریتم بر روی داده­های کتابخانه­ای حاکی از تشخیص دقیق طیف­های ناشناس می­باشد. همچنین ارزیابی و صحت سنجی عملکرد الگوریتم فوق بر روی داده­های تصاویر ماهواره­ای مربوط به دگرسانی فیلیک در منطقه­ی معدنی مس دره زار واقع در جنوب معدن مس سرچشمه، حداکثر شباهت را به طیف کتابخانه ای مسکویت که مشخصه دگرسانی فیلیک می­باشد، نسبت داد. از این روش همچنین می توان جهت شناسایی کانی­ها با استفاده از طیف­های اندازه گیری شده توسط دستگاه اسپکترورادیومتر استفاده نمود.     </p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کلمات کلیدی: سنجش از دور</kwd>
						<kwd>ضریب همبستگی</kwd>
						<kwd>دگرسانی فیلیک</kwd>
						<kwd>کتابخانه طیفی USGS</kwd>
						<kwd>طیف ناشناس</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>بابایی، م. ، 1388، استفادهازروشهایچندمتغیرهپیشرفتهجهت مدلسازیاکتشافیمنطقهسرچشمهوکوهپنجکرمان، پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد رشته مهندسی معدن، گرایش اکتشاف، دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>نجفیان، ط. ، 1389، نقشه برداری از کانی های مناطق دگرسان شده منطقه سرچشمه استان کرمان با استفاده از داده های چندطیفی و ابرطیفی ، پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد رشته مهندسی معدن، گرایش اکتشاف، دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>نجفیان، ط. ، رنجبر، ح. ، فتحیان­پور، ن. ، 1390، بررسی قدرت تفکیک آلتراسیونهای مرتبط با کانسارهای مس پورفیری با استفاده از تجمیع طیفی داده های ALI و ASTER ، اولین کنگره­ی جهانی مس، تهران، ص 109-120.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Center for the Study of  Earth from Space (CSES), 1992, SIPS User's Guide, Spectral Image Processing System, Version 1.2,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>   Center for the Study of Earth from Space, Boulder, CO, p. 88.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Clark, R. N., Gallagher, A. J., and Swayze, G. A., 1990, Material absorption band depth mapping of imaging spectrometer data</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>   using the complete band shape least-squares algorithm simultaneously fit to multiple spectral features from multiple materials, in</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>   Proceedings of the Third Airborne Visible/Infrared Imaging Spectrometer (AVIRIS) Workshop, JPL Publication 90-54, pp. 176 –  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>   186.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Clark, R. N., Swayze, G. A., Gallagher, A., Gorelick, N., and Kruse, F. A., 1991, Mapping with imaging spectrometer data using  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>   the complete band shape least-squares algorithm simultaneously fit to multiple spectral features from multiple materials, in</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>   Proceedings, 3rd Airborne Visible/Infrared Imaging Spectrometer (AVIRIS) workshop, JPL Publication 91-28, pp. 2-3.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Clark, R. N., Swayze, G. A., Gallagher, A. J., King, T. V. V., and Calvin, W. M., 1993, The U. S. Geological Survey, Digital</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>   Spectral Library, Version 1: 0.2 to 3.0 microns. U.S. Geological Survey Open File Report 93-592, 1340 pages.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation> Crowley, J. K., and Clark, R. N., 1992, AVIRIS study of Death Valley evaporite deposits using least-squares band-fitting methods,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>   in Summaries of the Third Annual JPL Airborne Geoscience Workshop, JPL Publication 92-14, v 1, pp. 29-31.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Elvidge, C. D., 1990, Visible and infrared reflectance characteristics of dry plant materials, International Journal of Remote</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>   Sensing, v. 11(10), pp. 1775 - 1795.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Gersman, R., Ben-Dor, E., Beyth, M., Doavigad, Abraha, M. &amp; Kibreab, A., 2008. Mapping of hydrothermally altered rocks by the</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>   EO-1 Hyperion sensor,Northern Danakil Depression, Eritrea, International Journal of   Remote Sensing, 29, 3911–3936.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Goetz, A. F. H., Vane, G., Solomon, J. E., and Rock, B. N., 1985, Imaging spectrometry for earth remote sensing, Science, v. 228,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>   pp. 1147 - 1153.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Grove, C. I., Hook, S. J., and Paylor, E. D., 1992, Laboratory reflectance spectra for 160 minerals 0.4 - 2.5 micrometers, JPL</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>   Publication 92-2.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Gupta, R., 2003. Remote sensing geology, Springer, 655p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Hubbard, B. E. , Crowley, J. K. , Zimbelman, D. R. , 2003 “Comparative Alteration Mineral Mapping Using Visible to Shortwave</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>   Infrared (0.4–2.4 µm) Hyperion, ALI, and ASTER Imagery”,  Geoacience and Remote Sensing, Vol. 41, NO. 6, 1401-1410.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Hubbard, B.E. &amp; Crowley, J.K., 2005  Mineral mapping on the Chilean–Bolivian Altiplano using co-orbital ALI, ASTER and</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>   Hyperion imagery: Data dimensionality issues and solutions, Remote Sensing of Environmen, 99, 173–186.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Korb, A. R., Dybwad, P., Wadsworth, W., and Salisbury, J. W., 1996, Portable FTIR spectrometer for field measurements of</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>   radiance and emissivity, Applied Optics, v. 35, pp. 1679-1692.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation> Kruse, F. A., A. B. Lefkoff, J. B. Boardman, K. B. Heidebrecht, A. T. Shapiro, P. J. Barloon, and A. F. H. Goetz, 1993, The</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>   Spectral Image Processing System (SIPS) - Interactive Visualization and Analysis of Imaging spectrometer Data, Remote Sensing</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>   of the Environment, v. 44, p. 145 - 163.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Mazer, A. S., Martin, M., Lee, M., and Solomon, J. E., 1988, Image Processing Software for Imaging Spectrometry Analysis,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>   Remote Sensing of the Environment, v. 24, no. 1, p. 201-210.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Montgomery,  D. , 2003, Applied Statistics and Probability for Engineers,  3rd ed., Wiley.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Salisbury, J. W., D'Aria, D. M., and Jarosevich, E., 1991a, Midinfrared (2.5-13.5 micrometers) reflectance spectra of powdered</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>   stony meteorites. Icarus, v. 92, pp. 280-297.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Salisbury, J. W., Wald, A., and D'Aria, D. M., 1994, Thermal-infrared remote sensing and Kirchhoff's law 1. Laboratory</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>   measurements, Journal of Geophysical Research, v. 99, pp. 11,897-11,911.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Salisbury, J. W., Walter, L. S., Vergo, N., and D'Aria, D. M., 1991b, Infrared (2.1- 25 micrometers) Spectra of Minerals. Johns</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>   Hopkins University Press, 294 p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Simon, K., Beckmann, T. &amp; Beckmann, T., 2002, Hyperion  Level 1GST (L1GST) Product output  Files Data Format Control Book</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>   (DFCB), Earth Observing-1 (EO-1), USGS, EO1-DFCB-0003 ,Version 1.0.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Stephen, G. U., Pearlman, J. S., Mendenhall, J. A., Reuter, D., 2003. Overview of the Earth Observing One (EO-1) Mission, IEEE   </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>   41, 1148-1159.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Swayze, G. A., and Clark, R. N., 1995, Spectral identification of minerals using imaging spectrometry data: evaluating the effects</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>   of signal to noise and spectral resolution using the Tricorder Algorithm, in Summaries of the Fifth Annual JPL Airborne Earth</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>   Science Workshop, JPL Publication 95-1, pp. 157 - 158.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Yuan, J., Niu, Z., 2008. Evaluation of Atmospheric Correction Using FLAASH, International Workshop on Earth Observation and</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>   Remote Sensing Applications (IEEE), Beijin, 1–6.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11577_332378f7e652e970deb50916d9941573.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی کانی‌شناسی و زمین‌شیمی معدن بنتونیت چاه گلستان سرایان، خراسان جنوبی</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نماینده</surname>
			            <given-names>علی رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناس ارشد زمین شناسی اقتصادی دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مدبری</surname>
			            <given-names>سروش</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار زمین شناسی اقتصادی دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رنجبران</surname>
			            <given-names>محسن</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار رسوب شناسی دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2012</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>69</fpage>
			      <lpage>79</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>08</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2012</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>16</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2012, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2012</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11577.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11577.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>      معدن بنتونیت چاه گلستان در شهرستان سرایان خراسان جنوبی قرار دارد. در این پژوهش با استفاده از مطالعات کانی­شناسی و زمین­شیمیایی شرایط تشکیل و زایش این معدن مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. روشهای تجزیه ای شامل تجزیه پراش پرتو X (XRD ) و تجزیه شیمیایی (XRF و ICP- MS) بنتونیتها و سنگ دورنگیرشان می شود. کانی اصلی بنتونیت در این معدن، مونت­موریلونیت سدیمی است. همچنین کانیهایی مانند آلبیت، کریستوبالیت، کلسیت، کوارتز، هالیت و ارتوکلاز نیز حضور دارند. بر اساس داده های زمین­شیمیایی ماگمای مادر ریولیتی، سری ماگمایی به وجود آورنده بنتونیتها، آهکی _ قلیایی و محیط زمین ساختی کمان آتشفشانی همزمان با برخورد صفحات است. این معدن در یک فرآیند دیاژنتیکی بوسیله دگرسانی شیشه آتشفشانی در یک لاگون بوجود آمده است. برخی از شواهد موجود شامل چینه کران بودن کانیها، مقدار بالای مونت­موریلونیت، حضور لایه های ژیپس که به صورت بین لایه ایی با بنتونیت وجود دارند، فقدان دگرسانی هیدروترمال و .... می شود.
 </p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کلمات کلیدی:  بنتونیت</kwd>
						<kwd>چاه گلستان</kwd>
						<kwd>ماگمای ریولیتی</kwd>
						<kwd>کانی­شناسی</kwd>
						<kwd>زمین­شیمی</kwd>
						<kwd>سرایان</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation> آقا نباتی س. ع، زمین شناسی ایران(1365)، انتشارات سازمان و اکتشافات معدنی کشور، ص 619</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation> حجازی. م، قربانی. م(1373) بنتونیت – زئولیت ، سازمان زمین شناسی کشور، ص 67</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation> نادری میقان. ن(1379) نقشه 100000:1 آیسک، سازمان زمین شناسی کشور</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Abedini, A. Calagari, A.A , and Akbari,M., 2009. Geochemistry and genesis of Mehredjan bentonite deposit, Suthest of Khoor, Isfehan province. JGeope, p. 47 -58</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Berkley, J.L., and Baird, G.C., 2002. Calcareous K-bentonite deposits in the Utica shale and Trenton Group (Middle Ordovician), of the Mohawk Valley, New York State. Physics and Chemistry of the Earth, 27, p.265–278</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Christidis G. , and Scott P. 1993. Laboratory evaluation of bentonites. Industrial Minerals, 311, 51_57.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Christidis G., Scott P., and Marcopolos T., 1995. "Origin of the bentonite deposits of Eastern Milos, Aegean",Greece: Geological, Mineralogical and Geochemical evidence, Clays and Clay Minerals, 43(1), 63-77.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Christidis, G.E., 2001. Geochemical correlation of bentonites from Milos Island, Aegean, Greece. Clay Minerals, 36, p.295-306</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Dibble Jr., W. E., and Tiller., W 1981. Kinetic model of zeolite paragenesis in tuffaceous sediments. Clays and Clay Minerals. 29: 323-330.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Foreman B.Z., Rogers R.R., Deino A.L., Wirth K.R. &amp; Thole J.T., 2008. Geochemical characterization of bentonite beds in the Two Medicine Formation (Campanian, Montana), including a new 40Ar/39Ar age. Cretaceous Research, 29, 373_385.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Foreman, B.Z., Rogers, R.R., Deino, A.L., Wirth, K.R., Thole, J.T., 2007. Geochemical characterization of bentonite beds in the Two Medicine Formation (Campanian, Montana), including a new 40Ar/39Ar age. Cretaceous Research, 93, p. 1-13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Grim R.E,. 1962. Applied Clay Mineralogy. International Series in Earth Sciences. McGraw- Hill Book Co. Inc., New York.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Grim, R.G. and Guven, N., 1978. Bentonites—Geology, Mineralogy, Properties and Uses. Elsevier, Amsterdam, 256pp</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Harben, P. W., and R. L. Bates., 1990. Geology of the Nonmetallics. New York: Metal Bulletin Inc. 62-89.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Hartwell, J.M.,1965. The diverse uses ofmontmorillonite.Clay Miner. 6: 111-1</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Hay, R. L., and Sheppard, R. A., 1977. Zeolites in open hydrologic systems. In Reviews in Mineralogy, Vol. 4. Mineralogy and Geology of Natural Zeolites. F. A. Mumpton, ed. Washington, D.C.: Mineral. Soc. Am., 93-102.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Hay, R. L., and Guldman. S. G., 1987. Diagenetic alteration ofsilicic ash in Searles Lake, California. Clays and Clay Minerals. 35: 449-457.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Hess, P.C., 1966. Phase equilibria of some minerals in the K20, Na:O, A12Os, SiO2, H20 system at 25~ and 1 atmosphere. Am. J. Sci. 264: 289-309.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Hints, R., Kirsimäe, K., Somelar, P., Kallaste, T. and Kiipli, T., 2008. Multiphase Silurian bentonites in the Baltic Palaeobasin. Sedimentary Geology, 209, p. 69–79.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Hosterman J.W., and Patterson S.H., 1992. Bentonite and fuller's earth resources of the United States. US Geological Survey Professional Paper, 1522, 45 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Huff W.D., Merriman R.J., Morgan D.J. and Roberts B., 1993. Distribution and tectonic setting of Ordovician K-bentonites in the United Kingdom. Geological Magazine, 130, 93_100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Huff, W., 2008. Ordovician K-bentonites: Issues in interpreting and correlating ancient tephras. Quaternary International, 178, p. 276–287.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Irvine T. N., Baragar W.R.A., 1971. "A guide to the chemical classification of the common volcanic rock, Canadian Journal of Earth Science", 8, p.523-548.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Keith, K.S. and Murray, H.H., 1994. Clay liners and barriers. Chapter in Industrial Minerals and Rocks, 6th Edition. Carr, D.D., ed. Society for Mining, Metallurgy and Exploration, Littleton, CO, pp. 435–462</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Kolarikova, I., Hanus, R., 2008. Geochemistry and mineralogy of bentonites from Ishirini (Libya). Chemie der Erde- Geochemistry, 68, p.61–68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Mariner R.H., and Surdam R.A.,1970. Alkalinity and formation of zeolites in saline alkaline lakes. Science, 170, 977_980.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Muchangos, A.C., 2006. The mobility of rare-earth and other elements in process of alteration of rhyolitic rocks to berntonite (Lebombo Volcanic Mountainous Chain, Mozambigue). Journal of Geochemical Exploration, 88, p.300-303.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Murray, H.H., 2007. Applied clay mineralogy occurrances, processing and application of kaolines, bentonites, palygoreskite, and common clays, p. 12- 13</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Patterson, S. H., and H. H. Murray.,1983. Clays. In Industrial Minerals and Rocks. S. J. Lefond, ed. New York: Am.Inst. Mining Engineers, 519-585.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Pearce J. A., Harris N. B. W., Tindle A. G., 1984. "Trace element discrimination diagrams for the tectonic interpretation of granitic rocks, Petrology", 25, Part 4, 956-983.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Pellenard, P., Deconinick, J.F., Huff, W.D., Thierry, J., Marchand, D., Fortwengler, D., Trouiller, A., 2003. Characterization and correlation of Upper Jurassic (Oxfordian) bentonite deposits in the Paris Basin and the subalpine basin, France. Sedimentology, 50, p. 1035-1060.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Roberts B. &amp; Merriman R.J. ,1990. Cambrian and Ordovician metabentonites and their relevance to the origins of associated mudrocks in the northern sector of the Lower Paleozoic Welsh marginal basin. Geological Magazine, 127, 31_43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Savage, D., Walker, C., Arthur, R., Rochelled, C., Odae, C.,Takase, H., 2007. Alteration of bentonite by hyperalkaline: A review of the role of secondary minerals. Physics and Chemistry of the Earth, 32, p. 287–297</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Senkayi A.L. Dixon J.B. Hossner L.R. Abder-Ruhman M., and Fanning D.S. ,1984. Mineralogy and genetic relationship of tonstein, bentonite and lignitic strata in the Eocene Yegna Formation of East-Central Texas. Clays and Clay Minerals, 32, 259_271.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Sheppard, R. A., and Gude A. J., 1973. Zeolites and associated authigenic silicate minerals in tuffaceous rocks on the Big Sandy Formation, Mohave County, Arizona. U.S. Geol. Surv. Prof. Paper No. 830: 36p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Shiraki, R., and T. Iijama., 1990. Na-K ion exchange reaction between rhyolitic glass and (Na, K) Cl solution under hydrothermal conditions. Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta 54: 2923-2931.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Slaughter M. &amp; Earley J.W.,1965. Mineralogy and geological significance of the Mowry bentonites, Wyoming. Geological Society of America, Special Paper, 83, 95 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Spears, D.A., Kanaris-Sotirios, R., Riley, N., Krause, P., 1999. Namurian bentonites in the Pennine basin, UK-origin and magmatic affinities. Sedimentology, 46, p. 385-401.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Steefel C.L., and van Cappellen P., 1990. A new kinetic approach to modelling water-rock interaction: The role of nucleation, precursors and Ostwald ripening. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, 54, 2657_2677.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Takagi T., Koh S. M., Song M. S., Itoh M., Mog K., 2005. "Geology and properties of the Kawasaki and Dobuyama bentonite deposits of Zao region in northeastern Japan", Clay Minerals, 40, 333-350.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Taylor M.W., and Surdam R.C., 1981. Zeolite reactions in the tuffaceous sediments at Tells Marsh, Nevada. Clays and Clay Minerals, 29, 341_352.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>White A.F., 1983. Surface chemistry and dissolution kinetics of glassy rocks at 25"C. Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta 47: 805-815.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>White, A. F., and Claasen. H. C., 1980. Kinetic model for the short-term dissolution of a rhyolitic glass. Chem. Geol. 28: 91-109.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Winchester J. A., Floyd P. A., 1977. "Geochemical discrimination of different magma series and their differentiation products using immobile elements", Chemical Geology, 20, 325-343.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Yalcin H., and Gumuser G., 2000. "Mineralogical and geochemical characteristics of late Cretaceous</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>       bentonite deposits of the Kelkit Valley region", northern Turkey, Clay minerals, 35, 807- 825.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Yildiz A., and Kuscu M., 2004. "Origin of the Basoren (Kutahya W Turkey) bentonite deposits", Clay Minerals, 39, 219-231</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Yildiz A., Dumlupunar I., 2009. Mineralogy and  geochemical affinities of bentonites from KapIkaya(Eskisehir, western Turkey), clay minerals, 44, 339- 360</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11578_4781b61be81b210293dec02eb4459545.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>معرفی توف‌های آهکی به عنوان منابع جدید پوزولان: بر اساس مطالعه توف‌های سازند کرج در جنوب غرب بلده</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مسعودی</surname>
			            <given-names>فریبرز</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده علوم زمین دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>خادمی پارسا</surname>
			            <given-names>مهناز</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده علوم زمین دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فاطمی عقدا</surname>
			            <given-names>سید محمود</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده علوم دانشگاه خوارزمی و مرکز تحقیقات راه مسکن و شهرسازی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>پرهیزکار</surname>
			            <given-names>طیبه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>مرکز تحقیقات راه مسکن و شهرسازی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2012</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>80</fpage>
			      <lpage>88</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>15</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2012</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>16</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2012, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2012</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11578.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11578.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>پوزولان طبیعی سنگ‌های آتشفشانی هستند که در تولید سیمان‌های آمیخته استفاده می‌شوند. این سنگ‌ها به‌صورت گرد نرم در مجاورت رطوبت و در دمای معمولی با هیدروکسید کلسسیم واکنش نشان داده و ترکیباتی با خواص سیمانی بوجود می‌آورند. توف‌های آهکی ترکیب شیمیایی استانداردهای بین المللی را نشان نمی­دهند، و از این رو  به عنوان پوزولان استفاده نمی شوند. میزان سیلیس آنها کمتر از حد معرفی شده و میزان کلسیم آنها بیشتر از حد مجاز استانداردهای بین المللی است. اما بر اساس مطالعات صورت گرفته در این تحقیق بخشی از توف‌های آهکی سازند کرج در منطقه جنوب غرب بلده قابلیت کاربرد به عنوان پوزولان طبیعی را دارا می باشند. توف‌های آهکی مورد مطالعه دارای سیلیس به صورت آذر آوارهای شیشه‌ای هستند. این توف‌ها فعالیت پوزولانی خوبی را نشان می‌دهند. درصد بالای کلسیم در نمونه‌های پوزولانی باعث می‌شود تا مدت زمان رسیدن به فعالیت پوزولانی مطلوب افزایش یابد. علاوه بر معرفی توف‌های آهکی به‌عنوان منابع جدید پوزولان، بر اساس نتایج حاصل از مطالعات پتروگرافی، آنالیزهای ICP-MS و نتایج آزمایش‌های تعیین فعالیت پوزولانی، این تحقیق نشان داد که تنها ویژگی‌های شیمیایی برای تعیین کیفیت سنگ‌های آتشفشانی به‌عنوان پوزولان‌های طبیعی کافی نبوده و مطالعات پتروگرافی نیز در این راستا لازم می‌باشد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کلمات کلیدی: پوزولان</kwd>
						<kwd>توف آهکی</kwd>
						<kwd>آذر آوار شیشه‌ای</kwd>
						<kwd>سازند کرج</kwd>
						<kwd>بلده</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>حاجی محمدی، ف.، 1380، بررسی پتروگرافی و پترولوژی سنگ‌های آتشفشانی و آتشفشانی- رسوبی منطقه بلده، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، پژوهشکده علوم زمین.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>خادمی پارسا، م.، مسعودی، ف.، پرهیزکار، ط.، پورخورشیدی، ع.، 1389، پتروگرافی سنگ‌های جنوب غرب بلده با نگرشی بر قابلیت کاربرد پوزولان، اولین همایش پترولوژی کاربردی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی خوراسگان.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>خادمی پارسا، م.، 1390، پترولوژی سنگ‌های آتشفشانی جنوب غرب بلده (البرز مرکزی)، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی‌ارشد، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>رحیم زاده، ب.، 1388، پترولوژی سنگ‌های آتشفشانی شرق قزوین با نگرشی بر امکان وجود پوزولان، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>سعیدی، ع.، 1372، تهیه نقشه 1:100000 بلده، سازمان زمین‌شناسی و اکتشافات معدنی کشور.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>قریشوندی، ح.، 1389، پتروگرافی و پترولوژی سنگ‌های آذرین منطقه جام(سمنان) با نگرشی بر امکان وجود پوزولان، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>نوری زاده، ح.، 1381، بررسی پترولوژی و ژئودینامیک خروج گنبدهای آتشفشانی و سایر توده های نیمه عمیق جوان منطقه بلده، پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد، پژوهشکده علوم زمین.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Mehta, P.K., 1989, “Pozzolanic and Cementitious By -Product in Concrete- Another Look”, Silica Fume, Slag and</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>   Natural Pozzolan in Concrete Proc, 3rd International Conference, Trondheim, Norway.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Fisher, R.V., 1966, Mechanism of deposition from Pyroclasic flows, Am. Sci.,Vol:264, P:350-363</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Habert, G., Choupay, N., Montel, J.M., Guillaume, D., Escadeillas, G., 2008, Effects of the secondary minerals of the natural</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>   pozzolans on their pozzolanic activity, Cement and Concrete Research, Vol: 38, P:963–975.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Rodriguez-Camacho, R.E., Uribe-Afif, R., 2002, Importance of using the natural pozzolans on concrete durability, Cement  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>   Concrete Research, Vol: 32 P: 1851– 1858.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Shannag, M.J., Yeginobali, A., 1995, Properties of Pastes, Mortars and Concrete Containing Natural Pozzolan, Cement and  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>   Concrete Research, Vol:25, P:647-657.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Shi, C., Day, R.L., 2000,Pozzolanic reactions in the presence of chemical activators part I: reaction kinetics, Cement and</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>   Concrete Research, Vol:30,P:51–58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Shi, C., 2001, An overview on the activation of reactivity ofnatural pozzolans, Can. J. Civ. Eng., Vol: 28, P:778–786.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Shi, C., Krivenko, P.V., Roy, D., 2006, Alkali –Activated Cement and Concrets, Taylor &amp; Francis, P: 376.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Turkmenoglu, A.G., Tankut,  A., 2002, Use of tuffs from central Turkey as admixture in pozzolanic cements; Assessment of</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>   their petrographical properties, Cement and Concrete Research, Vol:32, P:629–637.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11579_e353c779a1372aa9dbd953add2fa05a1.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>نقش توزیع فرکتالی سیلیس در تغییرات بافتی سامانه های اپی ترمال (مقایسه کانه زایی آرموداغ با ذخایر طلای کوئینزلند)</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مهرنیا</surname>
			            <given-names>سید رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار دانشگاه پیام نور</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2012</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>89</fpage>
			      <lpage>99</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>26</day>
			          <month>08</month>
			          <year>2012</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>16</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2012, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2012</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11579.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11579.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>             شواهد اکتشافی بدست آمده از ناحیه آرموداغ ، بیانگر فعالیت های پساماگمایی سنوزوئیک در یک سامانه اپی ترمال است که بر اساس سوابق زمین شیمیایی و مطالعه سیالات درگیر با شکل گیری رخساره آدولاریایی در ارتباط می باشد. مطالعه تغییرات بافتی در مناطق کانه دار آرموداغ موید الگوی ناحیه بندی منظم و در عین حال منحصر بفردی است که در مطابقت با سازوکار تحولات بافتی شناخته شده در ذخایر کوئینزلند است. با توجه به نمونه های کوارتزی بدست آمده از ناحیه آرموداغ، توزیع پذیری غیر خطی سیلیس توسط توابع فرکتال بررسی و متعاقبا رابطه پیدایش بافت کلوفرم با فرآیند کانه زایی طلا استنتاج گردیده است. در عمل پس از نمونه برداری از رگه های طلادار این منطقه، تحولات خاص کانیایی با هدف شناسایی الگوی توزیع نمایی سیلیس و شکل گیری کمیت های متناظر بافتی بررسی شده اند. بدین ترتیب برخی از تحلیل های بافتی مرتبط با رخنمون های طلا دار آرموداغ با نتایج به دست آمده از  تحولات بافتی کوئینزلند مقایسه گردیده و معیار جدیدی برای پی جویی ذخایر پنهان و احتمالی طلا در آذربایجان شرقی ایران معرفی شده است.
 </p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کلمات کلیدی:  اکتشاف طلا</kwd>
						<kwd>توزیع سیلیس</kwd>
						<kwd>سامانه اپی ترمال</kwd>
						<kwd>فرکتال</kwd>
						<kwd>ناحیه بندی بافتی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>مهرنیا ، س. ر. ، 1383،  نحوه پیدایش طلا و ترکیبات وابسته به آن در ماگماتیسم سنوزوئیک چهارگوشه میانه - استان آذربایجان شرقی، پایان نامه دوره دکترای تخصصی ، دانشگاه شهید .بهشتی، دانشکده علوم زمین ،  200ص.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>مهرنیا ، س. ر. ، 1389، توزیع پذیری غیرخطی سیلیس ، روش نوینی برای شناسایی الگوی ناحیه بندی بافتی در اندیس های طلادار استان آذربایجان شرقی ، مجله علوم دانشگاه تهران، جلد 36، شماره1، ص82-69.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Lescuyer J., 1978, Petrology &amp; petrography of Cenozoic volcanism in Mianeh area, Ph.D Thesis, Submitted to GSI, 420 p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>    Aleaster M., 2001, Armudaq license Report within Mianeh quadrangle prosspects, Eastern Azerbaijan, Iran, Report for  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>    Karand Co. ltd. 40 p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Morrison G., Guoyi D., 2001, AMIRA Project, Preliminary Report: Textural Zoning in Epithermal Quartz veins, J.C Univ.,  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>    Queensland, 129 p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation> Morison G, , 2003, AMIRA Project, Revised version : Evaluating of Gold Mineralization Potentials in Queensland Epithermal     Systems, Queensland J.C Univ. press, Queensland, Australia, 249 p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Guoyi, D., 2002, AMIRA Project, Final Report: Epithermal gold deposit in Queensland, J.C Univ. Queensland, Australia, 245      p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Hedenquist J. W. and White N.C., 2008, Epithermal gold deposits and Characteristics for  Exploration Guides, Society of  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>     Resource Geology, 62 p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Mandelbrote B., 2010, Fractal Geometry of Nature, 23st Edition (Revised &amp; Updated), W.H Freeman &amp; Company, New York:       433 p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation> Mehrnia S. R., 2012, Using Multifractal Peculiarities of ETM Spectrums for Realizing Gold Mineralization Potentials in</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>     Eastern Azerbaijan, NW of Iran, 6th SASTECH Int. Conference, Kuala lumpur, Malaysia, Paper ref. code: 6-13-11-0135, p147 – 155.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11580_d641cbe8168774caec75ecc592f2ef07.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی زیست محیطی پسماندهای حفاری: مطالعه موردی پسماندهای چاه شماره 449 میدان نفتی اهواز</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فرهادیان بابادی</surname>
			            <given-names>مهین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناسی ارشد زمین شناسی ژئوشیمی دانشگاه خوارزمی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مسعودی</surname>
			            <given-names>فریبرز</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه شهید بهشتی تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>زراسوندی</surname>
			            <given-names>علیرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2012</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>100</fpage>
			      <lpage>110</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>01</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2012</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>16</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2012, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2012</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11580.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_11580.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>      در این تحقیق، تاثیر مواد افزودنی گل­ و سازندهای حفاری شده در غلظت فلزات پسماندهای حفاری چاه 449 میدان نفتی اهواز مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. نمونه­برداری از مواد افزودنی گل، گل­های حفاری، پسماند (گل+خرده) سازندهای حفاری شده و همچنین خاکهای اطراف منطقه حفاری صورت گرفت. پس از آماده­سازی نمونه­ها، برای تعیین غلظت فلزات از روشهای ICP-MS و ICP-OES استفاده شد.
نتایج نشان می­دهد که باریت منشا فلزات Cu, Zn, Ag، بنتونیت منشا فلزات Ni, V, Zn، فروبار منشا فلزات Zn, V, Ni, Cr، گل پایه آبی سنگین منشا فلزات Cu, Ag، شیل­ها منشا فلزات Cr, Zn, V، شیل­های بیتومینه منشا فلزات Cd, Cr, Zn, V و سنگ­آهک منشا فلز Ba در سازند پابده، ماسه­سنگ منشا فلز Cr، مارن­خاکستری منشا فلزات Cr, Cu, V و آهک منشا فلز Sr در سازند آسماری، مارن­خاکستری آهکی و آهک­های شیلی گورپی منشا فلز Cu، سنگ­آهک سازند ایلام منشا فلزات Cu, Ag، و سنگ­آهک سازند سروک منشا فلز Ba هستند. این تحقیق نشان داد که علاوه بر گل حفاری، سنگ­های حفاری شده نیز منبع فلزات هستند و در مواردی موجب افزایش غلظت فلزات در پسماندهای حفاری شده­اند.پسماندهای حفاری چاه 449 اهواز براساس بررسی­های زیست محیطی نسبت به فلزات Cu و Ag آلودگی متوسط تا شدید، نسبت به Cd نسبتا آلوده، نسبت به Sr و Ba غیرآلوده تا نسبتا آلوده هستند و نسبت به دیگر فلزات آلوده نیستند.
 </p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کلمات کلیدی: چاه شماره 449 میدان نفتی اهواز</kwd>
						<kwd>مواد افزودنی گل حفاری</kwd>
						<kwd>پسماندهای حفاری</kwd>
						<kwd>بررسی زیست محیطی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Abrahim. G.M.S., Parket. R.J., 2008, Assessment of heavy metal enrichment factors and the degree of contamination in marine     sediments from Tamaki Estuary, Auckland, New Zealand, Estuar. Coast. Shelf Sci. 136 227-238.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>API (American Petroleum Institute), 1978, API recommended practice. Standard procedure for testing drilling mud, API,  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>    Washington D.C, pp:35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Candler. J.E., 1995, Sea floor monitoring for synthetic based mud discharged in the Western Gulf of Mexico, presented at  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>    society of professional engineers, Houston, Texas, March.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Crecelius. E., Trefry. J., McKinley. J., Lasorsa. B., Trocine. R., 2007, Study of barite solubility and the release of trace  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>    components to the marine environment. New Orleans (LA): US Department of the Interior Minerals Management Service, Mexico Region. OCS Study MMS 2007–061. Accessed on 10 December 2008 at    </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>    ttp://www.gomr.mms.gov/PI/PDFImages/ESPIS/4/4289.pdf.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Christophoridis. C., Dedepsidis. D., Fytianos. K., 2009, Occurrence and distribution of selected heavy metals in the sediments</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>   of Thermaikos Gulf, N. Greece. Assessment using pollution indicators Journal of Hazardous Materials.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Darley. H.C.H., Gray. G.G., 1988, Composition and properties of drilling and completion fluids. Fifth Edition. Gulf Pulishing</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>   Co., Houston, TX. 643 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Eaton. A.D., Clesceri. L., Greenbery. A.E., 1998, Standards methods for  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>   the examination of water and wastewater, 20th ed., APHA-AWWA-</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>   WEF.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Gettleson. D.A., 1980, Effects of oil and gas drilling operations on the marine environment. in Marine Environmental</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>   Pollution, 1: Hydrocarbons (R. A. Geyer, Ed.), pp. 371–411, Elsevier Scientific, Amsterdam.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Govindaraju. K., 1994, Compilation of working values and sample description for 383 geostandards. Geostand Newsletters,  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>   Special Issue 18:1–158.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Grow Cock. F.B., Curtis. G.W., Hoxha. B., Broo. W.S., Candler. J.E., 2002, Designing invert drilling fluids to yield</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>   environmentally friendly drilled cuttings. IADC/SPE 74470, IADC/SPE drilling conference, Dallas, Tx, Feb 26-28.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Hastings. L., Cooper. G.P., Burg. W., 1984, Human sensory response to selected petroleum hydrocarbons. In: Advances in  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>   modern environmental toxicology.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Hernandez. L., Probst. A., Probst. J. L., Ulrich. E., 2003, Heavy metal distribution in some French forest soils: evidence for</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>   atmosphere contamination. The Science of Total Environment, 312, 195-210.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Insalaco, E., Virgone, A., Courme, B., Gaillot, J., Kamali, M., Moallemi, A., Lotfpour, M., Monibi, S., 2006, Upper Dalan</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>   Member and Kangan Formation between the Zagros Mountains and offshore Fars, Iran: depositional system, biostratigraphy  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>   and stratigraphic architecture: Bahrain, Gulf PetroLink, GeoArabia, 11(2), 75-176.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Kabata-Pendias. A., Pendias. H., 1984, Trace element in soil and plant. CRC press, Booca Raton, Fla.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Kabata-Pendias, A., Pendias, H., 1992, Background levels and environmental influences on trace metals in soils of the  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>    temperate humid zone of Europe. In: Adriano DC (ed) Biogeochemistry of trace metals. Lewis Publ, Boca Raton, pp 19–60.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Krauskopf. K., Dannis. B., 1995, Introduction to geochemistry . Third edition, McGraw-Hill.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Leuterman. A., Still. I., Christie. J., Butcher. N., 1997, A study of trace metals from barites: Their concentration,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>   bioavailability, and potential for bioaccumulation. In: Proceedings of the Offshore Mediterranean Conference and Exhibition,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>   OMC97; 1997 March 19-21: Ravenna, Italy. Ravenna (IT): OMC. P 357-396.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Lindsay. W.L., 1979, Chemical equilibria in soils. John Wiley and Sons. New York.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>McGrath. S.P., Smith. S., 1990, Chromium and nickel. In heavy metals in soils. B.J. Alloway (ed.). Blackie and Son, Ltd.,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>109       </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>   Bishopbriggs, Glasgow. pp 151-176.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Monaghan. P.H., McAuliffe. C.D., 1980, Environmental aspects of drilling fluids and cuttings from oil and gas operation in</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>   offshore and coastal waters. Marine Environmental Pollution 1: Hydrocarbons. Elsevier Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Muller. G., 1979, Schwermetalle in den sediment des Rheins-Veranderungen seitt 1971. Umschan 79, 778-783.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>NRC (National Research Council), 1983, Drilling Discharges in the Marine Environment. National Academy Press,</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>   Washington. 180 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Neff. J.M., Mckelvie. S., Ayers. R.C., 2000, Environmental Impacts of Synthetic Based Drilling Fluids. OCS Study MMS</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>   2000-64. U.S.Dept. of the Interior, Minerals Management Service, Gulf of Mexico OCS Program, New Orleans, LA, LA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>  118 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson. D.W., Liu. S.L., Sommers. L.E., 1984, Extractability and plant uptake of trace elements from drilling fluids. J.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>   Environ. Qual. 13:562-566.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>OGP (International Association of oil &amp; Gas Producers), 2003, Environmental aspects of the use and disposal of non aqueous</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>   drilling fluids associated with offshore oil &amp; gas operations. Report 342 from OGP, London, England. 103 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Paradias. S., Simandl. G.L., MacIntyre. D., Orris. G.J., 1997, Sedimentary-hosted, stratiform barite. B.C, Mineral Deposit.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Patin. S.A., 1999, Environmental Impact of Offshore Oil &amp; Gas Industry. New York: Eco Monitor Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Ravichandran. M., Baskaran. M., Santschi. P.H., Bianchi. T.S., 1995, History of Trace Metal Pollution in Sabine-Neches</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>   Estuary, Beaumont, Texas. Environ. Sci. Tech., 29, 1495–1503.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Scholten. M.C.Th., Karman. C.C., Huwer. S., 2000, Exotoxicological risk assessment related to chemicals and pollutants in</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>   off-shore oil production. Toxicology Letters 112-113, 283-288.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Stow. D., 1987, South Atlantic organic rich sediments: Facies, Processes, and Environments of Deposition”, GSSP, No.26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Susich. M.L., 2000, Onshore drilling waste management: Beneficial reuse of cuttings. Marathon Oil Company. Max W.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>   Schewenne, OASIS Environmental, Inc.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Sutherland. R.A., 2000, Bed sediment-associate trace metals in an urban stream, Oahu, Hawaii. Environ. Geol. 39 (6), 611.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Tisdale. S.L., Nelson. W.L., Beaton. J.D., 1985, Soil Fertility and Fertilizers. 4th ed.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Trefry. J.H., Trocine. R.P., Metz. S., Sisler. M.A., 1986, Forms, reactivity and availability of trace metals in barite, Report to the offshore operators committee, task force on environmental science, New Orleans, LA, 1986, P 1-50.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Trefry. J.H., Smith. J.P., 2003, Forms of mercury in drilling fluid barite and their fate in the marine environment. A review and  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>   synthesis. SPE 8o571. SPE/EPA/DOE exploration and production Environmental conference, San Antonio, TX. Richardson</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>   (TX): Society of petroleum Engineers. P 1-10.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>U.S EPA, 1992, Behavior of metals in soils. U.S Environmental Protection Agency. Office of solid waste and emergency</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>   response, EPA/540/S-92/018. </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>U.S EPA, 1988, 53 Federal Register, 41356-383.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>WHO (World Health Organization), 2001, Concise International Chemical Assessment Document 33: Barium and Barium</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>   Compounds. Accessed on 12 December 2008 at http://www.inchem.org/documents/cicads/cicads/cicad33.htm.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>