<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of Chahak Fault Activity by Seismic Analysis and Tectonic Morphology (West Aryanshahr - South Khorasan)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی فعالیت گسل چاهک به روش تحلیل لرزه خیزی و ریخت زمین‌ساختی (غرب آرین شهر – خراسان جنوبی )</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15491</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.31040.2039</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>نواصری</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه بیرجند</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>موسوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه بیرجند</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خطیب</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه بیرجند</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>غلامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه بیرجند</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The presence of active and Quaternary (young) faults in the eastern part of Iran has made this area a seismically active area. There are many ways to identify and evaluate seismic hazard for a range. In this study, two methods of seismic analysis have been used for statistical analysis and tectonic morphological indices and neo-tectonic evidence of Chahak fault activity and seismicity located 30 km from Arianshahr (South Khorasan). Compare these two methods. Finally, by studying and calculating the tectonic indices S, BS, AF, T and Smf that their numerical averages are 1, 1.88, 59, 0.40, 1 and combining them and obtaining the Active tectonic index (Iat) equal to 1.94 as well as seismic survey of Chahak Fault revealed that Chahak Fault has relatively high activity in the study area and it can be said that seismic analysis by statistical method and tectonic morphological analysis is a suitable tool. To estimate the amount of tectonic movements and earthquake hazards are in range to identify and analyze seismic hazard areas as well as seismic springs. To reduce the casualties and financial losses during the earthquake, we can make the most of the benefits of the earthquake and change our view of the earthquake.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">وجود گسل‌های فعال و کواترنری (جوان) در خاور ایران باعث شده تا این گستره از دیدگاه لرزه‌خیزی یکی از مناطق فعال در نظر گرفته شود . روش‌های زیادی برای شناسایی و ارزیابی میزان خطرزمین‌لرزه برای یک گستره وجود دارد. دراین پژوهش سعی شده به دو روش تحلیل لرزه‌خیزی به روش آماری و بررسی شاخص‌های ریخت زمین‌ساختی و شواهد نوزمین ساختی میزان فعالیت و لرزه‌خیزی گسل‌چاهک که در 30 کیلومتری آرین‌شهر (خراسان جنوبی) واقع شده است پرداخته شود و نتایج حاصل از این دو روش را با هم مقایسه گردد. درانتها با بررسی و محاسبه شاخص‌های ریخت زمین ساختی S ، BS ، AF ، T و Smf که میانگین عددی آن‌ها به ترتیب 1 ، 88/1 ، 59 ، 40/0 ، 1 و تلفیق آن‌ها و بدست آوردن شاخص زمین ساخت فعال (Iat) که برابر با 94/1 و همچنین بررسی لرزه خیزی گسل‌چاهک مشخص شد که گسل‌چاهک دارای فعالیت نسبتا بالایی در منطقه مورد مطالعه می‌باشد و می‌توان گفت که تحلیل لرزه‌خیزی به روش آماری و بررسی ریخت زمین‌ساختی ابزار مناسبی برای برآورد میزان تحرکات تکتونیکی و خطرزمین‌لرزه در یک گستره هستند تا به واسطه آن‌ها بتوان مناطق با خطر زمین لرزه و همچنین چشمه‌‌های لرزه‌زا را شناسایی و تحلیل نمود . تا در هنگام وقوع زمین‌لرزه شاهد کاهش تلفات جانی و خسارات مالی باشیم و بتوانیم بیشتر از فواید وقوع زمین‌لرزه استفاده کنیم و دید خود را نسبت به وقوع زمین‌لرزه تغییر دهیم.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لرزه‌خیزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ریخت زمین‌ساخت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تکتونیک‌فعال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گسل‌چاهک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خاورایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
