<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Compression classification methods (MLC, SAM and SID) to provide the best geologic map and using A Spectral Analysis and MTMF Method for enhancing of alteration zones</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مقایسه سه روش طبقه بندی(MLC، SAM و SID) جهت تهیه بهترین نقشه سنگ شناسی و استفاده از طیف سنجی و روش MTMF به منظور بارزسازی مناطق دگرسانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>77</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>87</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14829</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.27532.1900</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هوشنگ</FirstName>
					<LastName>پورکاسب</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کاظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>رنگزن</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سمیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>بیرانوند</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>زراسوندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حجت اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>رنجبر</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Due to improvements in remote sensing techniques and available analyzes it is now possible to prepare maps of lithology and alteration of an area. In this study, Aster image as well as several image classification (Maximum likelihood(MLC), Spectral Angle Mapper(SAM) and Spectral Information Divergence(SID)) were used to provide lithology maps and spectrum of minerals has been applied for the enhancing of alterations. To evaluate the accuracy of the prepared geologic maps were used. The classification results showed that the MLC method has the highest accuracy and the classified image using this method is acceptable. Also, spectrum of minerals which obtained by FieldSpec3 Analytical Spectral Device (ASD) were utilized to prepare the alteration map using Mixture Tuned Matched Filtering (MTMF) method. The presence of sericite and chlorite minerals were confirmed by examination of thin sections. The obtained lithological and alteration maps represent that the phyllic zone associated with granite and granodiorite rocks, while argillic and propylitic zones are mostly accompanied with andesitic rocks of study area.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به علت بهبود در روش های سنجش از دور و تجزیه و تحلیل های موجود، تهیه نقشه سنگ شناسی و دگرسانی یک منطقه امکان پذیر می باشد. در این مطالعه جهت تهیه نقشه سنگ شناسی روش های طبقه بندی شامل روش های بیشترین احتمال(MLC)Maximum likelihood ، زاویه طیفی (SAM) Spectral Angle Mapper و اطلاعات طیفی واگرایی (SID)Spectral Information Divergence ، مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. به منظور ارزیابی صحت نقشه های تهیه شده، از نقشه زمین شناسی منطقه استفاده گردید. نتایج بارزسازی سنگ شناسی منطقه نشان داد که روش طبقه بندی (MLC) دارای بیشترین دقت بوده و تصویر طبقه بندی شده از این روش قابل قبول می باشد. همچنین با استفاده از طیف های به دست آمده از نمونه های سنگی توسط دستگاه FieldSpec3Analytical Spectral Device (ASD) و روش ((MTMF Mixture Tuned Matched Filtering نقشه دگرسانی ها تهیه گردید. بررسی مقاطع نازک میکروسکوپی حضور کانی های سرسیت و کلریت را در نمونه های مورد مطالعه تایید نمود. نقشه های سنگ شناسی و دگرسانی بدست آمده مشخص کردند که زون فیلیک با سنگ های گرانیتی وگرانودیوریتی و زون آرژیلیک و پروپلیتیک با سنگ های آندزیتی موجود در منطقه در ارتباط هستند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنگ شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طیف سنجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">MTMF</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زون های دگرسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ASTER</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_14829_861ab821f49f0e4b3f19833de51ad630.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
