<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Bioavailability and bioaccumulation of heavy metals in the sediment-plant system of Shadegan Wetland, Khuzestan Province</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>زیست‌دسترس‌پذیری و زیست‌انباشت فلزات سنگین در سیستم رسوب-گیاه تالاب شادگان، استان خوزستان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>392</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>406</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15073</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28736.1947</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نسرین</FirstName>
					<LastName>یاورعشایری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0328-5051</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهنام</FirstName>
					<LastName>کشاورزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زمین شناسی زیست محیطی دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرید</FirstName>
					<LastName>مر</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Shadegan Wetland is one of the most important and valuable aquatic habitats in the country that has great importance in terms of biological and ecological in the region&#039;s Wildlife. In order to evaluate plant species as an indicator organism of heavy metal pollution in biomonitoring studies of the aquatic ecosystem, the levels of heavy metal accumulation (Mo, Cu, Pb, Zn, As, Se, Hg, Ni, Co, Cd, Cr, V, Mn, Al and Fe) in shoot and root of the macrophytes Typha latifolia, Halocnemum strobilaceum, Aeluropus lagopoides, Phragmites australis and Scripus maritimus was determined. All five species exhibited significantly higher concentrations of metals in roots than in aboveground organs. These species are therefore suitable for use as indicators of the presence and level of heavy metal contaminants in wetlands. Selenium was the most mobile element through the plant tissues with an average bioaccumulation factor exceeds 1. Selenium concentration in the plants was more than levels detected in sediments. Translocation factor values for Phragmites australis were all below 1, suggest-ing low-efficiency plants for metal translocation from roots to shoots. Sequential extractions of sediment samples indicated that three elements including Pb, Ni, and Zn had the most bioavailability.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تالاب شادگان یکی از مهمترین و ارزشمندترین زیستگاه‌های آبی کشور است که از نظر زیست‌شناختی و بوم‌شناختی اهمیت زیادی در حیات‌وحش منطقه دارد. به منظور ارزیابی گونه‌های گیاهی به عنوان اندامگان نشانگر آلودگی فلزات سنگین در مطالعات زیست‌پایشی بوم‌سامانه آبی، در این پژوهش انباشت فلزات سنگین(مولیبدن، مس، سرب، روی، آرسنیک، سلنیم، جیوه، نیکل، کبالت، کادمیم، کروم، وانادیم، منگنز، آلومینیم و آهن) در ریشه و اندام هوایی ماکروفیت‌های نی(Phragmites australis)، لوئی(Typha latifolia)، چمن‌شور(Aeluropus lagopoides)، باتلاقی‌شور(Halocnemum strobilaceum) و جگن(Scripus maritimus) تعیین شد. غلظت‌ فلزات سنگین در ریشه‌ی هر پنج گونه از اندام‌هوایی بیشتر بود که بیانگر مناسب بودن این گونه‌ها به عنوان نشانگرهای حضور و میزان آلودگی فلزات سنگین در تالاب‌ها هستند. بیشترین مقدار ضریب زیست‌انباشت مربوط به عنصر سلنیم می‌باشد. همچنین غلظت سلنیم در گیاهان از رسوب بیشتر است. ضریب انتقال کمتر از یک برای تمام عناصر در گیاه نی نشان‌دهنده توانایی کم گونه گیاهی نی برای انتقال ‎عناصر از ریشه به اندام‌های هوایی است. طبق نتایج استخراج گزینشی سه عنصر سرب، نیکل و روی بیشترین زیست‌دسترس‌پذیری را دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زیست‌دسترس‌پذیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زیست‌انباشت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ماکروفیت‌های آبزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فلزات سنگین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تالاب شادگان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15073_a5e23ab121e16fe5e80b69e475257500.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
