<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Hydrogeochemical study and determination of Pollution Source of Dehloran Sargrou Spring</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی هیدروژئوشیمیایی و تعیین منشاء آلودگی چشمه سرگرو دهلران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>357</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>373</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15057</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28116.1917</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید یحیی</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرزائی ارجنکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7470-6784</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منوچهر</FirstName>
					<LastName>چیت سازان</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>پیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حاجی</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایلام، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Groundwater salinity and contamination, especially in carbonate formations, are one of the most important challenges of water resources management in Iran. The study of contamination sources shows that sometimes, tectonic conditions caused interference and adjacent salinity sources with karst waters resources. Therefore, recognizing the contamination and understanding the mechanism of this process can help to determine the location of the contamination mixing point and provide a solution for the discharge of water before contamination. Sergrou is one of the famous springs of Dehloran which due to the high salinity and the presence of some pollutants is not exploited. In the spring water flow path, Sergrou spring Water contributes to pollution of surface water and groundwater of the region. In order to hydrochemical investigation of the spring, in a 10-year period, the hydrochemical data were collected as well as four data sampling steps were performed to complete the available data. Graphical methods, composite diagrams, ion ratios, ion exchange diagrams and also salinity ratios were used to analyze the data. The results of the study showed that spring water is unusable for drinking and agricultural usage. Analysis of ion ratios and ion exchanges showed that chlorine molar concentration is higher than sodium at all times, as well as other ion ratios, reversed ion exchange represents the interactions or interactions between deep Oilfield brines. The determination of the amount of bromine and iodine and their relative weight with chlorine also confirms the mixing of Oilfield brines with spring water.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">آلودگی و شوری آب‌های زیرزمینی خصوصاً در سازند های کربناته از جمله چالش‌های مهم مدیریت آب می‌باشد. بررسی منابع آلاینده نشان می‌دهد شرایط تکتونیکی می تواند باعث تداخل منابع الاینده با آب‌های کارستی گردد. لذا شناخت آلودگی‌ها همچنین درک مکانیسم حاکم بر این فرایند کمک زیادی به تعیین محل تداخل و ارائه راهکار جهت خروج آب قبل از آلودگی می‌نماید. چشمه سرگرو یکی از چشمه‌های مهم دهلران می‌باشد که به دلیل کیفیت پایین مورد بهره‌برداری قرار نمی‌گیرد به منظور بررسی‌های هیدروشیمیایی، در یک بازه 10 ساله، داده‌های کیفی چشمه جمع‌آوری شد همچنین جهت تکمیل داده‌ها چهار مرحله نمونه برداری در منطقه صورت پذیرفت. جهت تحلیل داده‌ها از روش های گرافیکی، نمودارای ترکیبی، نسبت‌های یونی، نمودارهای تبادل یونی همچنین روابط تعیین کننده شوری استفاده گردید. نتایج بررسی‌ها نشان داد آب چشمه از لحاظ شرب و کشاورزی غیر قابل مصرف می‌باشد. بررسی نسبت های یونی و تبادلات یونی نشان داد مقادیر غلظت مولی کلر در تمامی دوره با سدیم تطابق نداشته همچنین سایر نسبت های یونی در منطقه موید تبادل یونی معکوس و یا تداخل شورابه عمیق نفتی می‌باشد. بررسی میزان برم و ید اندازه‌گیری شده و نسب وزنی آنها با کلر نیز تایید کننده اختلاط شورابه نفتی با آب چشمه می‌باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چشمه سرگرو</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شورابه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نسبت یونی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تبادل یونی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارستی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15057_3a8e41c32a0e00be121ecf9167765069.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
