<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Hydrocarbon continuity investigation of Sarvak and Ilam reservoirs in Azadegan oilfield using integration of geochemical, geological and reservoir engineering data</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی پیوستگی هیدروکربنی مخازن سروک و ایلام در میدان نفتی آزادگان با استفاده از تلفیق داده‎های ژئو‌شیمیایی، زمین‌شناسی و مهندسی مخزن</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>195</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>206</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15017</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28061.1915</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهرام</FirstName>
					<LastName>علیزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز
مرکز تحقیقات زمین‌شناسی و زمین‌شیمی نفت، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8033-4080</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهراب</FirstName>
					<LastName>رشیدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز
اداره مطالعات و تحقیقات ژئوشیمی، مدیریت اکتشاف شرکت ملی نفت ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2682-3518</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>زراسوندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز
مرکز تحقیقات زمین‌شناسی و زمین‌شیمی نفت، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9821-6747</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید رسول</FirstName>
					<LastName>سیدعلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز
مرکز تحقیقات زمین‌شناسی و زمین‌شیمی نفت، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9668-0711</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>علیئی</LastName>
<Affiliation>اداره ژئوفیزیک، مدیریت اکتشاف شرکت ملی نفت ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Azadegan oilfield, located in Abadan Plain, is considered as one of the largest undeveloped oilfields in Iran. The carbonate Sarvak (Middle Cretaceous) and Ilam (Upper Cretaceous) reservoirs have been completely separated by the shaly Lafan Formation in this oilfield. Here, in order to investigate the connectivity between the oils of the mentioned reservoirs, organic geochemical data were integrated with the geological and reservoir pressure information. Geochemical data show that the oils of Sarvak and Ilam reservoirs have a common genetic family, originated from a marine source rock, and their geochemical characteristics are identical. Also, they have a same thermal maturity in the range of middle oil generation window. However, two distinct and unrelated oil groups were identified in these reservoirs based on the results of C7 light hydrocarbons, confirmed by the reservoirs’ pressure data. This is due to stratigraphic situation of the thin impermeable shaly Lafan Formation related to the studied reservoirs, disconnecting the hydrocarbon connectivity between them. Based on the results obtained from this study, geochemical investigation of hydrocarbon reservoirs can be appropriately used for assessment of reservoir connectivity and would improve the reservoir models which in turn plays a crucial role in reducing the risk of the field’s development and production programs.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">میدان آزادگان واقع در دشت آبادان بعنوان یکی از بزرگترین میادین نفتی توسعه نیافته ایران محسوب می‌شود. مخازن کربناته سروک (کرتاسه میانی) و ایلام (کرتاسه بالایی) در این میدان توسط سازند شیلی لافان از یکدیگر جدا گردیده‎اند. در این تحقیق به منظور بررسی نحوه ارتباط نفت این مخازن با یکدیگر، داده‌های ژئو‌شیمیایی آلی با اطلاعات زمین‌شناسی و فشار مخزن ادغام گردید. بر اساس نتایج به‌دست آمده از داده‌های ژئو‌شیمیایی، نفت‌های این مخازن از لحاظ زایشی به یک خانواده نفتی با منشأ مشترک دریایی تعلق دارند و دارای خصوصیات ژئوشیمیایی و بلوغ یکسان در حد اواسط زون نفت‌زایی می‌باشند. با این‌حال، دو گروه نفتی متفاوت و غیر مرتبط در این مخازن بر اساس مطالعه ترکیبات هیدروکربوری سبک C7 تشخیص داده شد که اطلاعات فشار مخازن نیز آن را تائید می‌نماید. این امر به دلیل عملکرد سازند کاملاً شیلی لافان است که علی‌رغم ضخامت کم بعنوان یک لایه ناتراوا عمل نموده و ارتباط مخازن سروک و ایلام را قطع نموده است. بر اساس نتایج حاصله، مطالعه ژئو‌شیمیایی مخازن هیدروکربوری می‌تواند به خوبی در تعیین پیوستگی مخازن مورد استفاده قرار گیرد و سبب بهبود مدل‌های مخزنی که نقش تعیین‌کننده‌ای در کاهش ریسک برنامه‌های توسعه و تولید میدان دارند، گردد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ژئوشیمی مخزن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیوستگی مخزن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مخازن کرتاسه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دشت آبادان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">میدان نفتی آزادگان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15017_4f5ae3602174c39e5f6b45408aceee93.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
