<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Enhancing iron containing minerals (Gossan Zone) using satellite images and spectroscopy technique (Case study: North Saveh)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بارزسازی کانی های آهن دار (زون گوسان) با استفاده از تصاویر ماهواره ای و فن طیف سنجی (مطالعه موردی: شمال ساوه)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15538</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.31975.2067</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کاظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>رنگزن</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سمیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>بیرانوند</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هوشنگ</FirstName>
					<LastName>پورکاسب</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>زراسوندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حجت ا...</FirstName>
					<LastName>رنجبر</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه معدن، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Extensive volcanic rocks with phyllic, argillic and propylitic alterations have outcrops in the north of Saveh. This area is considered as the an important region for Cu mineralization (e.g., porphyry and manto-types). Given that iron minerals could be formed during the supergene alteration in the upper parts of porphyry Cu systems, the Thematic Mapper (TM), the plus Enhanced Thematic Mapper (ETM+) and landsat8 images were utilized for the enhancement of these minerals in the study area. The TM3/TM1. TM4/TM1 band ratio (BR) on the TM image, 3/1 band ratio on the ETM+ image and 4/2 band ratio on the Landsat8 image were applied to identify iron mineral zones in the study area. The rock samples were collected in the study areas. The FieldSpec3 device and the Spectral Geologist (TSG) 7.1.0.073 techniques were used for detection of iron mineral types. Then the spectra obtained from the FieldSpec3 device were entered into the spectral analysis software (TSG). The FieldSpec3 and TSG identified hematite and goethite minerals in the rock samples. Because the sampling points are most consistent with the band ratio method in the TM image and the spectroscopy technique confirms the results of this method, in this study, enhancing of the iron containing minerals using band ratio method in the TM image was identified as a suitable method in the North Saveh.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سنگ های ولکانیکی گسترده ای همراه با دگرسانی های فیلیک، آرژیلیک و پروپلیتیک در شمال ساوه رخنمون دارند. این منطقه از مناطق مهم به جهت کانه زایی مس (پورفیری و مانتو) قلمداد می شود و از آنجاییکه کانی های آهن دار می توانند طی فرایند های دگرسانی سوپرژن در بخش های بالای سیستم های مس پورفیری تشکیل کلاهک آهنی (زون گوسان) دهند، در این مطالعه به بررسی بارزسازی کانی های آهن دار (زون گوسان) در منطقه شمال ساوه پرداخته شده است. به این منظور از تصاویر TM، ETM+، Landsat8، روش نسبت گیری باندی TM3/TM1. TM4/TM1 بر روی تصویر TM و روش نسبت باندی1/3 و ۲/۴ به ترتیب بر روی تصاویر  ETM+و Landsat8 استفاده شده است. از مناطق بارزسازی شده نمونه های سنگی جمع آوری و طیف نمونه ها توسط دستگاه FieldSpec3 استخراج گردید. در ادامه از نرم افزار تحلیل طیف The Spectral Geologist 7.1.0.073 (TSG) استفاده و طیف های به دست آمده از دستگاه  FieldSpec3به این نرم افزار وارد شدند. روش های FieldSpec3 و TSG، کانی های هماتیت و گوتیت در نمونه های سنگ شناسایی نمود. با توجه به اینکه نقاط نمونه برداری بیشترین انطباق را با روش نسبت گیری باندی در تصویر TM دارند و فن طیف سنجی نتایج این روش را تایید می کند، در این مطالعه بارزسازی کانی های آهن دار با روش نسبت گیری باندی، به عنوان روشی مناسب جهت بارزسازی کانی های آهن دار در شمال ساوه شناخته شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"بارزسازی کانی های آهن دار"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"تصاویر TM"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"ETM"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"Landsat8"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">" فن طیف سنجی FieldSpec3 و TSG"</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
