<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study the different phases of sulphur in the soil around the gas refinery and their relationship with other soil characteristics, an example from the NE Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی شکل‌های مختلف گوگرد در خاک اطراف پالایشگاه گاز و ارتباط آن با سایر ویژگی‌های خاک، مثالی از شمال شرق ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>14</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15068</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28141.1919</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>تاج بخشیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم ، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">137513751375</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمودی قرائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اسداله</FirstName>
					<LastName>محبوبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>موسوی حرمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>To study soil quality in Shahid Hashemi Nezhad gas refinery region in view of pollution level of produced sulfur in this industrial unit, 22 soil samples collected from inside and adjacent areas of the refinery. Sulfate content of soil was extracted in three phases water soluble, absorbed, and occluded with carbonates by deionized water, 0.032 M NaH2PO4 and 1 M HCl, respectively. The concentration of total sulfate was determined by soil complete digestion with a mixture of HF, HCl and HNO3. The content of organic matter and CO32- and HCO3- anions concentrations in the soil samples were measured using titration method. Organic, occluded with carbonates, water soluble and absorbed sulfate had the maximum concentration in the soil samples respectively, that inside refinery samples had more concentration than the other samples regarding all these phases. Water soluble sulfate had a reverse correlation with soil pH that showed sulfate occurrence could slightly oxidize sulfur and its compounds and acidic environment dominance in the soil.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">برای بررسی کیفیت خاک در منطقه پالایشگاه گاز شهید هاشمینژاد از نظر سطح آلودگی به گوگرد تولیدی در این واحد صنعتی، 22 نمونه خاک از مناطق مجاور پالایشگاه و داخل آن برداشت شد. مقدار سولفات خاک در سه شکل قابل‌حل در آب، جذب شده و متصل به کربنات‌ها بهترتیب توسط آب دیونیزه، محلول M 032/0 NaH2PO4 و M 1 HCl استخراج شد. غلظت سولفات مجموع به روش هضم کامل خاک توسط مخلوطی از HF، HCl و HNO3 تعیین شد. مقدار ماده آلی و غلظت آنیون‌های کربنات و بیکربنات موجود در نمونه‌های خاک به روش تیتر کردن تعیین شد. در تمام نمونه‌های خاک برداشت شده، به ترتیب سولفات آلی، متصل به کربنات‌ها، قابل‌حل در آب و در نهایت جذب شده بیشترین غلظت را داشتند، که درمورد نمونه‌های خاک داخل پالایشگاه نه تنها این امر مشخص بود، بلکه از نظر تمامی این اشکال سولفات، غلظت بیشتری را نسبت به سایر نمونه‌ها نیز نشان دادند. شکل سولفات قابل‌حل در آب رابطه معکوسی با pH خاک داشت که نشان داد وجود سولفات توانسته تا حدودی موجب اکسیداسیون گوگرد و ترکیبات آن و غلبه محیط اسیدی در خاک شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پالایشگاه گاز شهید هاشمی نژاد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هضم کامل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ماده آلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سولفات جذب شده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ژیپس و انیدریت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15068_060baab5dbbdd384072002e7dae0e4d8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
