<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1398</YEAR>
<VOL>9</VOL>
<NO>2</NO>
<MOSALSAL>2</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>119</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تحلیل استرین نهایی با استفاده از پورفیروکلاستهای سازند گچساران، مطالعه موردی درتاقدیس رامهرمز</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Finite Strain analysis using Gachsaran formation porphyroclasts, case study in Ramhormoz Anticline</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در این پژوهش با استفاده از مطالعات بافت ساختاری و تحلیل استرین نهایی به بررسی تغییرات کمی استرین در واحدهای سنگی سازند گچساران در بخش فرا دیواره گسل راندگی رامهرمز پرداخته شده است. در مقطع عمود بر امتداد گسل و در طول ترانشه طبیعی موجود در منطقه تعداد 13 نمونه سنگی مورد بررسی قرار گرفت.  پورفیروکلاستهای موجود در نمونه ها بعنوان نشانگر جهت مطالعه استرین مورد تحلیل قرار گرفت. نتایج مطالعات بافت ساختاری حاکی از وجود یک مؤلفه برش راستگرد در منطقه می­باشد. نتایج حاصل از تحلیل استرین حاکی از وجود رابطه نسبی بین مقادیر استرین و فاصله از گسل است. تحلیل سه بعدی بیضوی استرین نشان دهنده شکل بیضوی استرین بصورت بیضوی کشیده شده سه محوری می­باشد. تحلیل مقادیر عدد تاوایی جنبش شناحتی در صفحه XZ بیضوی استرین نشان دهنده دامنه تغییرات پارامتر تاوایی بین  0.39&lt;Wk&lt;0.85 و عملکرد مولفه های استرین برش محض و برش ساده و رخداد پدیده توزیع استرین در منطقه است. نتایح حاصل از مقادیر درصدی مولفه های برش محض و برش ساده نشان دهنده وجود مولفه استرین برشی عمومی با غلبه مولفه برش محض می باشد.
 </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>1-Introduction
 
In this research with application of petrofabric studies and finite strain analysis quantitative changes of strain have been evaluated in the Gachsaran rock units in the hanging wall of Ramhormoz thrust fault. Thirteen samples were selected for strain analysis in the normal section to the Fault strike along natural trench in the study area. Porphyroclasts have used as strain markers for future strain studies. The results of petrofabric studies reveal a dextral component of shear in the study area. Results of strain analysis show relative relationship between amounts of strain and distance from the fault. Three dimensional analysis of strain ellipsoid shows three axial oblate ellipsoid shape for strain ellipsoid. Kinematic vorticity analysis in the XZ principal plane of strain ellipsoid shows 0.39&lt;Wk&lt;0.85 and operation of both simple and pure shear components of shear strain and occurrence of strain partitioning in the study area. Percentage amounts of simple and pure shear components of strain reveal general shear with pure shear dominated component of strain.               
 
2-Methodology
 
In this research chalk porphyroclasts of Gachsaran Formation have been used as strain markers. Gachsaran Formation in the hanging wall of Ramhormoz fault has conserved the deformation characteristics of shear movements during the deformation history. Shear sense indicators and other strain markers such as porphyroclasts have been evaluated in this formation. These porphyroclasts have made a good fortune for quantitative strain studies in this area. In this research the strain ratios of porphyroclasts were calculated in the XZ principal plane of strain ellipsoid. With application of EllipsFit software the amounts of tectonic strain and long axis orientation of strain ellipsoid were determined using Rf/Ø and polar methods. With using the amounts of tectonic strain and orientation of the long axis of strain ellipsoid and application of (K-γ-θ-Rxz) nomogran (Fossen, 2010) the amounts of shear strain and strain ellipsoid shape factor were determined. Also with application of (Rxz-θ) nomogram (Bailey et al., 1999) the amounts of kinematic vorticity number were calculated for understanding the nature of deformation and percents amounts of pure and simple shear.                  
 
3-Results and discussion
 
The study area has been located in the Rmhormoz Anticline in the 75km NW of Ahvaz city. Structural studies show development two main joint sets that both of them are approximately parallel to the Ramhormoa main thrust fault. According to the petrofabric studies all shear sense indicators such as secondary antitaxial veins, σ type and δ type structures reveal a dextral sense of shear in the area. Using Rf/Ø and polar methods strain analysis have been made in thirteen locations of anticline based on shape factor of chalk porphyroclast. The amounts of strain tectonic in the XZ principal plane of strain ellipsoid were calculated. Also orientations of long axis of strain ellipsoid were determined in each sample. For this aim the horizontal line has used as reference line. Results show relative relationship between amounts of strain and distance from the main thrust fault. With application of (K-γ-θ-Rxz) nomogran (Fossen, 2010) the amounts of shear strain and strain ellipsoid shape factor (K) were determined. Results show 1.3&lt;K&lt;1.7. Therefore according to the amounts of K factor, the general shape of strain ellipsoid is three axial prolate. Kinematic vorticity (Wk) is a dimensionless measure of rotation relative to strain and characterizes the amount of shortening proportional to displacement. Wk was originally defined as an instantaneous rotation relative to the instantaneous stretching at a point (Means et al. 1980). Kinematic vorticity is measured on a scale between 0 (pure shear) and 1 (simple shear). General shear is the term used for flows between pure and simple shear (1&gt;Wk&gt;0) (Passchier and Trouw 2005). Pure and simple shearing components contribute equally to the instantaneous flow at Wk=0.71 (Law et al. 2004). There are several methods for determination of the kinematic vorticity number. In this research kinematic vorticity analysis was made based on Rxz-θ nomogram (Bailey et al., 1999). Rxz and θ are strain ratio in the XZ principal plane of strain ellipsoid and the angle between long axes of the strain ellipsoid related to the reference line, respectively. Results show 0.39&lt;Wk&lt;0.85 and operation of both component of pure shear and simple shear in the area.
 
4-Conclusion
 
Strucrural and petrofabric studies reveal operation of both ductile and brittle deformation in the study area. According to the study of shear sense indicators, results show a main dextral sense of shear in the area. Results of strain analysis show greater amounts of Rs near the main thrust and lower amount Rs far from the main thrust fault. 3d shape of strain ellipsoid is mainly three axial prolate shape. Results of kinematic vorticity analysis show the occurrence of general shear with operation of both pure and simple shear component of deformation. The amounts of kinematic vorticity number reveals strain partitioning in the area. This strain partitioning mainly is due to oblique convergence between Iranian and Arabian plates.   
 
 </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>113</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>119</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بابک</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سامانی</Family>
						<NameE>Babak</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Samani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه شهید</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>samani.babak@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عادل</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ساکی</Family>
						<NameE>Adel</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Saki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده علوم زمین دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده علوم زمین دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>saki.a@scu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>هدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مختاربند</Family>
						<NameE>Hoda</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mokhtarband</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده علوم زمین دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده علوم زمین دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mokhtarband.h@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بیضوی استرین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>استرین نهایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عدد تاوایی جنبش شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گسل رامهرمز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توزیع استرین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Alavi, M., 1994. Tectonics of the Zagros orogenic belt of Iran: new data and interpretations. Tectonophysics 229, 211-238.##Alavi, M., 2004. Regional stratigraphy of the Zagros fold-thrust belt of Iran, and its proforeland evolution. American Journal of Science 304, 1–20.##Bailey, C.M., Gilmer, A.K., Marquis, M.N., 1999. A tale of two shear zones: the vorticity and strain path of two greenschist facies shear zones. Geological Society of America Abstracts with Programs 31 (7), 59.##Bailey, C.M., Eyster, E.L., 2003. General shear diformation in the Pinaleno Mountains metamorphic core complex, Arizona. Journal of Structural Geology 25, 1883–1893.##Berberian, M., King, G.C.P., 1981. Towards a paleogeography and tectonic evolution of Iran. Canadian Journal of Earth Sciences 18, 210–265.##Fort, A.M., Bailey, C.M., 2007. Testing the utility of the porphyroclast hyperbolic distribution method of kinematic vorticity analysis. Journal of Structural Geology 29, 983–1001.##Fossen, H., 2010. Structural geology. Cambridge University Press, 481p.##Fossen, H., 2016. Structural geology second edition. Cambridge University Press, 520p.##Means WD, Hobbs BE, Lister GS, Williams PF .,1980. Vorticity and noncoaxiality in progressive deformations. J Struct Geol 2:371–378.##Passchier, C.W., Trouw, R.A.J., 2006. Microtectonics. Springer Verlag, Berlin-Heidelberg– New York.##Ramsay, J.G., Huber, M.I., 1983. The Techniques of Modern Structural Geology. Strain Analysis, Academic Press, London, 1: 307p.##Simpson, C., De Poar, D.G., 1997. Strain and kinematic analysis in general shear zones. Journal of Structural Geology, 15: 1–20.##Vitale S, Mazzoli S., 2008. Heterogeneous shear zone evolution: the role of shear strain hardening/softening. J Struct Geol 30:1383–1395.##Vollmer, F.W., 2011. EllipseFit 2.0. http://www.frederickvollmer.com/ellipsefit/.##Wallis, SR., 1995. Vorticity analysis and recognition of ductile extension in the Sanbagawa belt, SW Japan. J Struct Geol 17:1077–1093.##Xypolias, P., 2010. Vorticity analysis in shear zones: Areview of methods and applications. Journal of Structural Geology. 42, 1-21.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>زمین شیمی، خاستگاه و بررسی رفتار عناصر کمیاب در لاتریت نیکل چاه غیب، قادر آباد، استان فارس</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Geochemistry, genesis and behavior of the rare elements in Chah-Gheib laterite deposit, Ghader Abad, Fars Province</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>کانسارلاتریت چاه غیب تحت‌ تأثیر فرایندهای هوازدگی پریدوتیت‌های سرپانتینی شده مربوط به مجموعه افیولیتی- رادیولاریتی نیریز تشکیل شده است که در بخش زیرین آهک دولومیتی جهرم به سن ائوسن قرار دارد. از پایین به بالا شامل پریدوتیت‌های سرپانتینی، زونهای انتقالی، لیمونیت، هماتیت و لاتریت میباشد. بر اساس نتایج کانی شناسی، XRD و EPMA کانیهای هماتیت، گوتیت، کوارتز، مونت موریلونیت، پالیگورسکیت و الیوین از کانیهای اصلی سازنده این کانسار میباشند. همچنین با مطالعه EPMA مشخص شد، طلا در زون لیمونیت به همراه کانیهای سیلیس شناسایی شده است. بر اساس نتایج آزمایشات ژئوشیمیایی (ICP-MS)، بیشترین مقدار نیکل (ppm) 10870 در زون لاتریت و کمترین مقدار (ppm) 2066 در زون انتقالی می‌باشد. بررسی همبستگی بین عناصر نشان میدهد که نیکل دارای همبستگی مثبت قوی با عنصر آهن می‌باشد که خود گواهی بر حضور عنصر نیکل در اکسید های آهن بوده است. بر اساس نمودار سه تاییAl2O3-Fe2O3-SiO2 درصد هوازدگی در کانسار چاه غیب درجه قوی تا متوسط میباشد. مقدار عناصر نادر خاکی از سرپانتینیت (سنگ منشا) (8.97 ppm) به سمت زون لاتریت 18.41ppm)) روند افزایشی را نشان میدهند.. مقدار Ce/Ce* از 0.65 درزون سرپانتینیت تا 1.56 در زون لاتریت تغییر میکند که نشان دهنده اکسیدی و اسیدی بودن محیط تشکیل لاتریت میباشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The Chah-Gheib laterite deposit is formed as a result of the weathering of serpantinized peridotite of the radiolarite-ophiolite Neyriz complex. occurs in the lower part of the dolomitic limestone of the Eocene Jahrum Formation which from the bottom to top includes; serpantinized peridotite transitional, limonite, hematite and laterite zones. Based on the mineralogical investigations coupled withXRD and EPMA results, the main minerals consist of hematite, goethite, quartz montmorillonite, palygorskite and olivine. . Based investigations EPMA results Gold is accompanied with silica minerals in the limonite zone. Based on the geochemical analysis (ICP-MS), the highest content of nickel is 10870 (ppm), which is related to the laterite zone and lowest one is 2066 (ppm), related to the transitional zone. There is a positive correlation coefficient between nickel and iron, which reflecting the presence of nickel in iron oxides. Based on Al2O3-Fe2O3-SiO2 diagram, the weathering in the Chah-Gheib laterite deposit ranges from strong to middle. Based on the geochemical analysis and correlation coefficient The rare earth elements show an increasing trend from serpentinite (8.97 ppm) to the laterite zones (18.41ppm. The amounts of Ce/Ce* range from 0.65 to 1.56 in the serpentinite and laterite zones, respectively. This indicates oxidized acidic conditions for the laterite zone. The Eu/Eu* increases from serpentines (0.13) to laterite zone (0.98) ref</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>120</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>132</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شیرین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خدیور</Family>
						<NameE>Shirin</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khadivar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>علوم زمین، علوم، شیراز، شیراز، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>علوم زمین، علوم، شیراز، شیراز، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khadivar.shirin@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بتول</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تقی پور</Family>
						<NameE>Batoul</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Taghipour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه علوم زمین، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه شیراز، شیراز، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه علوم زمین، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه شیراز،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>taghipour@shirazu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>افیولیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نی ریز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>لاتریت نیکل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عناصر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کمیاب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aleva, G.J.J., 1994. Laterites: concepts, geology, morphology, and chemistry. International Soil Reference and Information Center, 169 pp.##Elias, M., 2002. Nickel laterite deposits, Geological overview, resources and exploration. Special Publication 4, p: 205–220.## Freyssinet, P., Butt, C.R.M., Morris, R.C., Piantone, P., 2005. Ore-forming processes related to laterite weathering. Economic Geology, 100th Anniversary Volume, p: 681–722.##Lelong, F., Tardy, Y., Grandin, G., Trescases, J.J., Boulange, B., 1976. Pedogenesis, chemical weathering an processes of formation of some supergene ore deposits, in Wolf K.H., ed., Supergene and surficial ore deposits- Texture and fabrics of Handbook of strata-bound and stratiform ore deposits. Amsterdam, Elsevier 3, p: 93–133.##Taylor, S.R., McLennan, S.M., 1985. The continental crust: its composition and evolution. Blackwell. Oxford, 312p.                                                                                                                                                       ##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تعیین ارتباط هیدرولیکی چشمه‌های تاقدیس کینو (استان خوزستان) با استفاده از داده‌های هیدروشیمیایی، روش تحلیل مؤلفه اصلی (PCA) و خوشه‌ سلسله مراتبی (HCA)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Determination of the hydraulic Connection between the Ķīno anticline springs (Khuzestan province) using hydrochemical data, principal component analysis (PCA) and hierarchical cluster (HCA)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در یک دهه اخیر مدیریت منابع آب کارستی به دلیل نقش ویژه آن‌ها در تامین آب‌شرب، مورد توجه قرارگرفته‌است. در این راستا این تحقیق به بررسی ویژگی‌های هیدروشیمیایی چشمه‌های واقع در تاقدیس کینو در استان خوزستان می‌پردازد هدف این تحقیق تعیین ارتباط هیدرولیکی وعوامل مؤثر بر کیفیت شیمیایی چشمه‌ها با به‌کارگیری داده‌های هیدروشیمیایی و بهره‌گیری از روش‌های تحلیل‌ مؤلفه‌ اصلی(PCA) و خوشه‌ سلسله‌ مراتبی(HCA) می‌باشد. نتایج روش تحلیل مؤلفه‌های‌اصلی نشان‌داد، دوعامل بیش‌ترین تاثیر را برکیفیت شیمیایی چشمه‌های تاقدیس دارند. عامل اول شامل متغیرهای منیزیم، بی‌کربنات، سدیم، کلر، کل مواد جامد محلول و هدایت الکتریکی که خصوصیات کیفی چشمه‌های آب سرده و موری تحت تاثیر این عامل قراردارد. جهت بررسی ارتباط هیدرولیکی چشمه‌ها از روش تحلیل‌خوشه‌سلسله‌مراتبی در حالت Q-mode استفاده‌گردید. براساس نتایج این تحلیل چشمه‌های تاقدیس کینو در دو خوشه اصلی قرار می‌گیرند که نشان دهنده ارتباط هیدرولیکی بین این چشمه‌ها در هر خوشه می‌باشد. نتایج روش تحلیل‌خوشه‌ای در حالت R-mode نیز تایید کننده روش Q-modeمی‌باشد. جهت بررسی و شناخت فرایندهای شیمیایی موجود در چشمه ها از نمودار پایپر و نسبت‌های‌ یونی استفاده‌شد. نتایج این بررسی نشان‌داد چشمه‌ S1 با S2 و چشمه‌ S3 با S4 دارای ارتباط هیدرولیکی می باشد</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In the last decade, the management of karst water resources has been considered because of its particular role in supplying potable water. In this regard, this research studies the hydrochemical characteristics of springs located at the Ķīno anticline. The purpose of this research is to determine the hydraulic relationship and effective factors on the chemical quality of the springs by applying the hydrochemical data and using the main component analysis and hierarchical cluster analysis methods. The results of the analysis of the main components method show that the two components have the most impact on the chemical quality of springs. The first factor consists of magnesium, bicarbonate, sodium, chlorine, Total Dissolved Solids, and electrical conductivity, which is influenced by the quality characteristics of Absard and Mourei springs. The second factor is calcium ions, sulfate, which play the most role in the chemical quality of Susan and Tangsard springs. To investigate the hydraulic connection of the springs, the hierarchical cluster analysis method was used in “Q-mode” mode. According to the results of this analysis, the data of the Ķīno anticline springs are split into two major clusters, which indicate the hydraulic connection between these springs in each cluster. The results of cluster analysis in “R-mode” mode are also validated by the Q-mode method. The Piper diagram and ion ratios were used to study the chemical processes in the springs. The results of this study showed that the S1 spring with S2 and the S3 spring with S4 have a hydraulic connection.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>133</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>141</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید یحیی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>میرزائی ارجنکی</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Yahya</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mirzaee</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین شناسی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین شناسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>yahya2010@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>منوچهر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>چیت سازان</Family>
						<NameE>Manouchehr</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Chitsazan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز ک</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز ک</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.chitsazan@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زهرا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>چغازردی</Family>
						<NameE>Zahra</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Chaghazardi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش آموخته گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش آموخته گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>chaghazardi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آمار چندمتغیره</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پارامتر‌های کیفی آب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تاقدیس کینو</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>Q - mode</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>R - mode</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مکان‌یابی محل دفن پسماند جامد شهرهای جنوبی استان خوزستان با استفاده از منطق فازی و تحلیل سلسله مراتبی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Landfills site selection in southern cities of Khuzestan province with using fuzzy set and AHP method</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>دفن غیربهداشتی پسماند جامد شهری و اثرات منفی زیست‌محیطی آن، موجب شده که روش‌های علمی و صحیح، جایگزین روش‌های سنتی شوند. یکی از مهم‌ترین مراحل دفن بهداشتی پسماندها انتخاب مکان مناسب است، به طوری که اثرات نامطلوب زیست‌محیطی، اجتماعی و اقتصادی حداقل شود. هدف از این مطالعه تعیین مکان مناسب جهت دفن پسماند جامد شهرهای شهرستان‌های خرمشهر، آبادان، شادگان و ماهشهر است. عوامل تأثیرگذار در سه شاخص زیست‌محیطی (آب‌های سطحی، سواحل دریا، مناطق حساس و حفاظت شده، گسل، کاربری اراضی و شرایط اقلیمی)، اجتماعی (سکونتگاه‌ها، مراکز تجاری، صنعتی، تفریحی و تاریخی، راه‌آهن و فرودگاه‌ها) و اقتصادی (دسترسی به جاده و مکان دفن، شیب زمین) بررسی شدند. برای تحلیل و ادغام شاخص‌ها از سیستم اطلاعات جغرافیایی و روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی همراه با ارزش‌گذاری فازی معیارها و شاخص‌ها استفاده گردید. نتایج نشان داد که بخش وسیعی از منطقه برای دفن نامناسب است. منطقه به خصوص از نظر زیست‌محیطی جهت دفن زباله شهری بسیار حساس است و انتخاب مکان دفن باید با دقت و بررسی زیادی انجام شود. در نهایت نقشه مکان‌های مناسب جهت دفن زباله بر اساس ارزش عضویت فازی تهیه گردید که می‌تواند در راستای مدیریت مؤثر و کاربردی پسماند شهری مفید باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Non-sanitary landfill of solid municipal waste and its negative environmental impacts have made traditional methods to be replaced by appropriate and scientific methods. One of the most important phases of sanitary landfill is selecting the best spatial location to minimize environmental, social and economic impacts. The purpose of this study is to determine the proper location for solid landfills in Khorramshahr, Abadan, Shadegan and Mahshahr cities. The effective criteria have been evaluated in three categories including environmental criteria (surface waters, coastal zones, sensitive and protected areas, faults, land uses, vegetation and climatic conditions), social criteria (settlements, commercial, industrial, tourism and historical areas, railways and airports) and economic criteria (access to road and landfill, and slope). Geographic information systems (GIS), Analytical Hierarchy Process (AHP), and fuzzy logic have been used to analyze and integrate all criteria. The results showed that a large part of the area is inappropriate for landfill. In addition, the area is very sensitive to landfill environmentally and landfill site selection should be studied carefully. Finally, a map of suitable landfill sites has been prepared based on the fuzzy membership value that can be useful in municipal solid waste management in the mentioned cities.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>142</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>155</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>چابک</Family>
						<NameE>Majid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Chabok</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مهندسی بیوسیستم، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز/ اهواز، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مهندسی بیوسیستم، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>majid_chabok@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>هوشنگ</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بهرامی</Family>
						<NameE>Houshang</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bahrami</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مهندسی بیوسیستم، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مهندسی بیوسیستم، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>bahrami16@scu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عباس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عساکره</Family>
						<NameE>Abbas</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Asakereh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مهندسی بیوسیستم، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه شهید چمران اه.واز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مهندسی بیوسیستم، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.asakereh@scu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نعمت الله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جعفرزاده حقیقی فرد</Family>
						<NameE>Nemat allah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jaafarzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مرکز تحقیقات و فناورزی های محیط زیست، دانشگاه علوم پزشکی جندی شاپور اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مرکز تحقیقات و فناورزی های محیط زیست، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>jaafarzadeh-n@ajums.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>Economic Factors</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>Fuzzy set</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>Khuzestan</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>Municipal Solid Waste</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>social factors</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Alavi, N., Goudarzi, G., Babaei, A. A., Jaafarzadeh, N., Hosseinzadeh. M., 2013. Municipal solid waste landfill site selection with geographic information systems and analytical hierarchy process: a case study in Mahshahr County, Iran. Waste Manage Research 31, 98–105.##Chang, K.H., Cheng, C.H., Chang, Y.C., 2008. Reliability assessment of an aircraft propulsion system using IFS and OWA tree. Eng Optim 40, 907–921.##Eskandari, M., Homaee, M., Mahmoodi, S., Pazira, E., Van Genuchten, M.T., 2015. Optimizing landfill site selection by using land classification maps. Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res 22, 7754–7765.##Gorsevski, P.V., Donevska, K.R., Mitrovski, C.D., Frizado, J.P., 2012. Integrating multicriteria evaluation techniques with geographic information systems for landfill site selection: A case study using ordered weighted average. Waste Manage 32, 287–296.##Kahraman, C., Cebi, S., Onar, S.C., Oztaysi, B., 2018. A novel trapezoidal intuitionistic fuzzy information axiom approach: An application to multicriteria landfill site selection. Engineering Applications of Artificial Intelligence 67, 157-172.##Kumar, S., Mohammad, I.H., 2013. Selection of a landfill site for solid waste management: An application of AHP and spatial analyst tool. J. Indian Soc. Remote Sens 41, 45–56.##Melo, A.L.O., Calijuri, M.L., Duarte, I.C.D., Azevedo, R.F., Lorentz, J.F., 2006. Strategic decision analysis for selection of landfill Sites. J. Surv. Eng. 132, 83–92.##Rahmat, G.Z., Vosoughi Niri, M., Alavi, N., Goudarzi,G., Babaei, A., Baboli, Z., Hosseinzadeh, M., 2017. Landfill site selection using GIS and AHP: a case study: Behbahan, Iran. KSCE Journal of Civil Engineering 21, 111-118.##Ramjeawon, T., Beerachee, B., 2008. Site selection of sanitary landfills on the small island of Mauritius using the analytical hierarchy process multi-criteria method. Waste Manage. Res 26, 439–447.##Sener, S., Sener, E., Nas, B., Karaguzel, R., 2010. Combining AHP with GIS for landfill site selection: a case study in the Lake Beyşehir catchment area (Konya, Turkey). Waste management 30, 2037-2046.##Shahabi, H., Keihanfard, S., Ahmad, B.B., Amiri, M.J.T., 2014. Evaluating Boolean, AHP and WLC methods for the selection of waste landfill sites using GIS and satellite images. Environ. Earth Sci 71, 4221–4233.##Uyan, M., 2014. MSW landfill site selection by combining AHP with GIS for Konya, Turkey. Environ. Earth Sci 71, 1629–1639.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی آلودگی و منشأ فلزات سنگین و هیدروکربن های آروماتیک چندحلقه ای (PAHs) در رسوبات سطحی رودخانه قره سو شهرستان کرمانشاه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating contamination and sources of heavy metals and polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) in surface sediment of Qarasoo River, Kermanshah</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>ویژگی‌های فیزیکوشیمیایی، و آلودگی فلزات سنگین (Cu, Pb, Zn, Fe, Al, V, Ni) و ترکیبات PAH در رسوبات رودخانه قره‌سو کرمانشاه مطالعه شد. نتایج شاخص آلودگی (CF)، شاخص بار آلودگی (PLI) و ضریب غنی‌شدگی بیانگر آلودگی شدید رسوبات به ویژه درمورد عناصر سرب، روی و مس در مقاطعی از رودخانه بود. همچنین ایستگاه‌های نزدیک به شهر کرمانشاه مانند پالایشگاه نفت و شهرک صنعتی آلودگی بسیار بالاتری از PAH نسبت به بالا دست نشان دادند. براساس شاخص هم‌ارز سمناکی و مقایسه غلظت‌PAHها با محدوده اثر پایین (ERL) بیانگر وضعیت نامناسب رسوب قره سو بود. در بین انواع ترکیبات، گونه غالب، ترکیبات PAH سه حلقه‌ای است که بالاترین آلودگی آن نیز مانند فلزات سنگین مربوط به ایستگاه پالایشگاه نفت کرمانشاه بود. بر اساس تحلیل مولفه اصلی (PCA) و شاخص‌های زمین شیمیایی پساب خروجی پالایشگاه نفت کرمانشاه منبع اصلی آلودگی ترکیبات PAH سبک با منشأ نفت‌زاد و عناصری مانند مس، وانادیم و نیکل محسوب می‌شود. علاوه براین عناصر، مواد آلی و pH نیز همراهی قوی با این مولفه نشان داده که تصدیقی بر نقش پالایشگاه در افزایش آنها در رودخانه قره‌سو است. از دیگر منابع انسان‌زاد نیز می‌توان به پساب صنعتی و شهری، ترافیک و دفع غیرقانونی پسماند در حاشیه رودخانه اشاره کرد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Contamination of seven heavy metals (Cu, Pb, Zn, Fe, Al, V, Ni) and PAH compounds, and physicochemical characteristics were studied in sediments of Qarasoo River, Kermanshah. The results of contamination factor (CF), pollution load index (PLI) and enrichment factor indicated severe contamination of sediments, particularly for lead, zinc and copper in some segments of the river. Also, sampling stations near the city including oil refinery and industrial town had much higher PAH concentrations than the upstream. Based on toxic equivalency factor (TEF) and comparison of PAHs concentration with effect range low (ERL) revealed inappropriate situation of Qarasoo sediments. Among the various compounds, 3-rings PAHs are dominant with maximum concentration, same as heavy metals, in oil refinery station. Based on principal component analysis (PCA) and geochemical indices effluents of Kermanshah oil refinery are the main source of contamination of low molecular weight PAHs with petrogenic origin and copper, vanadium and nickel. In addition, organic matter and pH have also shown strong correlation with this component, confirming the role of the refinery in increasing their concentration in the Qarasoo River. Other important anthropogenic sources in the Qarasoo River include urban and industrial effluent, traffic and illegal waste disposal in the river margins.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>156</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>167</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>میثم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رستگاری مهر</Family>
						<NameE>Meisam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rastegari Mehr</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه آموزشی زمین شناسی کاربردی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگته خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه آموزشی زمین شناسی کاربردی، دانشکده علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rastegar.m@khu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عدنان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>دشه ئی</Family>
						<NameE>Adnan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Deshaee</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه آموزشی زمین شناسی کاربردی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه آموزشی زمین شناسی کاربردی، دانشکده علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>adnandeshaee@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عطا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شاکری</Family>
						<NameE>Ata</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shakeri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه آموزشی زمین شناسی کاربردی، دانشکئه علوم زمین، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه آموزشی زمین شناسی کاربردی، دانشکئه علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>atashakeri@khu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فلزات سنگین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>PAH</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رودخانه قره‌سو</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رسوب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کرمانشاه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Amin, A., Fazal, S., Mujtaba, A., Singh, S.K., 2014. Effects of land transformation on water quality of Dal Lake, Srinagar, India. Journal of the Indian Society of Remote Sensing 42, 119-128.##Chen, Z., Saito, Y., Kanai, Y., Wei, T., Li, L., Yao, H., Wang, Z., 2004. Low concentration of heavy metals in the Yangtze estuarine sediments, China: a diluting setting. Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science 60, 91-100.##Gautam, S.K., Sharma, D., Tripathi, J.K., Ahirwar, S., Singh, S.K., 2013. A study of the effectiveness of sewage treatment plants in Delhi region. Applied Water Science 3, 57-65.##Keshavarzi, B., Mokhtarzadeh, Z., Moore, F., Mehr, M.R., Lahijanzadeh, A., Rostami, S., Kaabi, H., 2015. Heavy metals and polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in surface sediments of Karoon River, Khuzestan Province, Iran. Environmental Science and Pollution Research, 22, 19077-19092.##Kumar, N., Singh, S.K., Srivastava, P.K., Narsimlu, B., 2017. SWAT Model calibration and uncertainty analysis for streamflow prediction of the Tons River Basin, India, using Sequential Uncertainty Fitting (SUFI-2) algorithm. Modeling Earth Systems and Environment, 3(1), p.30.##Lepane, VV., Heonsalu, A., 2007. Sedimentary record of heavy metals in Lake Rouge Liinjarv, southern Estonia. Journal of Estonian Earth Science 56, 221–232.##Narsimlu, B., Gosain, A.K., Chahar, B.R., Singh, S.K., Srivastava, P.K., 2015. SWAT model calibration and uncertainty analysis for streamflow prediction in the Kunwari River Basin, India, using sequential uncertainty fitting. Environmental Processes, 2, 79-95.##Rastegari Mehr, M., Keshavarzi, B., Moore, F., 2012. Investigation of hydrogeochemistry and source of potentially toxic metals (Cu, Pb, Zn, Cd, Cr, Ni) in Zayandehrud River. Journal of Advanced Applied Geology 1, 82-97.##Singh, S.K., Srivastava, P.K., Gupta, M., Thakur, J.K., Mukherjee, S., 2014. Appraisal of land use/land cover of mangrove forest ecosystem using support vector machine. Environmental earth sciences, 71, 2245-2255.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی پتانسیل و مقادیر واقعی تغذیه درآبخوان مناطق شهری و مکان یابی مناطق مستعد تغذیه مصنوعی با استفاده از GIS و AHP (مطالعه موردی: آبخوان شهری ارومیه)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The potential and actual urban aquifer recharge and site selection for artificial recharge using GIS and AHP methods
 (Case Study: Urmia urban aquifer)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>توسعه مناطق شهری تاثیر بسزایی بر روی چرخه آب داشته بطوریکه گسترش سطوح نفوذناپذیر باعث کاهش نفوذ، افزایش رواناب، و تغییر در مقدار و منشأ تغذیه آبخوان شده است. هدف از این تحقیق، برآورد تغذیه آبخوان، تعیین مناطق مستعد برای پخش سیلاب‌های شهری جهت تغذیه مصنوعی آبخوان در شهر ارومیه میباشد. برای این منظور ابتدا مدل تغذیه آبخوان و نقشه های پتانسیل تغذیه و تغذیه واقعی تهیه و سپس بر اساس معیار های تاثیر گذار، نقشـه نهـایی مناطق مستعد پخش سیلاب شهری در جهت تغذیه آبخوان تهیه گردید. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که پتانسیل تغذیه آبخوان به دلیل افزایش سطوح نفوذناپذیر کاهش‌یافته و تغذیه از طریق نشت از شبکه آب شرب ، چاه‌های جذبی و آب برگشتی آبیاری بیشترین سهم تغذیه آبخوان را دارد. مقدار تغذیه واقعی با توجه به کاربری‌های مختلف، بین 0 تا 28 و پتانسیل تغذیه بین 4 تا 262 میلی متر در سال تغییر می نماید. مهمترین فاکتورهای موثر بر مکانیابی پخش سیلاب های شهری کاربری اراضی، تاثیر زون غیراشباع و شبکه زهکشی بوده و مناطق مناسب برای تغذیه ، اراضی بایر و کشاورزی با شیب کمتر از 5 درصد، مناطقی با ضخامت زیاد زون غیر اشباع با رسوبات دانه درشت و نفوذپذیر درحاشیه شهر می باشند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Development of urban areas has a significant impact on the natural water cycle. Expansion of impermeable surfaces caused reduce infiltration, increase runoff volume and changes in the amount and source of aquifer recharge. The purpose of this study was to present the aquifer recharge model to determine suitable areas for urban runoff dispersal with artificial aquifer recharge approach in Urmia city. To this purpose, first groundwater recharge model was implemented. Afterwards, the potential and actual recharge map was estimated. Also, the suitable areas map for urban storm water spreading for groundwater recharge was proposed.  The result shows that due to the expansion of urban areas and the increment of impermeable surfaces, the potential of direct aquifer recharge has decreased. The most aquifer recharge is through leakage from urban drinking water network, sewage wells and irrigated water returns. The actual recharge has changed according to different land use and it was between 0-28 mm/y. The greatest potential recharge was related to, bare land, open spaces, parks and agricultural land and various between 4-262 mm/y. The results indicated that in the study area, land use, impact of aeration zone and drainage net are the most important factors that affects site selection for flood spreading. Barren and agricultural land with a slop of less than 5%, areas with high thickness of aeration zone, coarse sediment and high permeable in suburban area are suitable site for groundwater artificial recharge.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>168</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>179</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نصرت</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آقازاده</Family>
						<NameE>Nosrat</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aghazadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه عمران-مدیریت منابع آب،دانشکده فنی و مهندسی، واحد ارومیه، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، ارومیه، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه عمران-مدیریت منابع آب،دانشکده فنی و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nosrataghazadeh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>منوچهر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>چیت سازان</Family>
						<NameE>Manochehr</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Chitsazan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت تحریریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت تحریریه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>chitsazan_m@scu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>یحیی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>میرزائی</Family>
						<NameE>Yahya</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mirzaee</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mirzaee_y@scu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>&quot;ارومیه&quot;</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>&quot; مدل تغذیه آبخوان&quot;</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>&quot; مناطق شهری&quot;</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>&quot; سیلاب شهری&quot;</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>&quot; AHP&quot;</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aghazadeh, N., Mogaddam, A.A., 2006. Evaluation effects of road deicing salts and saline water on groundwater system in the Orumieh plain aquifer. 9th Congress of Geological Society of Iran.##Aghazadeh, N., Nojavan, M., Mogaddam, A.A., 2010. Effects of road-deicing salt (NaCl) and saline water on water quality in the Urmia area, northwest of Iran. Arab J Geosci. 2010565-570.##Aronica, G., Lanza, L.G., 2005. Drainage efficiency in urban area: A case study. Hydrological Processes 19,1105-1119.##Broomandnasab, S., Jallalvand, A., 2012.  Urban hydrology, hydraulics and storm water quality. Shahid Chamran University Press, 350pp (In Persian).##Chitsazan, M., Aghazadeh, N., Mirzaee, Y., Golestan, Y., Mosavi, S., 2017. Hydrochemical characteristics and quality assessment of urban groundwater in Urmia City, NW Iran. Water Science and Technology: Water Supply, DOI: 10.2166/ ws. 2017. 039##Chowdhury, A., Jha, M.K., Chowdary, V.M., 2010. Delineation of groundwater recharge zones and identification of artificial recharge sites in West Medinipur district, West Bengal, using RS, GIS and MCDM techniques. Environmental Earth Sciences 59, 1209-1222.##Ehsan, S., 2013. Utilization of Storm Runoff for Groundwater Recharge in Urban Areas- A Case Study of Gujranwala City in Pakistan. Journal of river engineering 1, 1-10.##Gogate, N.G, Rawal, P.M., 2015. Identification of Potential Storm Water Recharge Zones in Dense Urban Context: A Case Study from Pune city. Int. J. Environ. Res 9,1259-1268.##Grischek, T., Nestler, W., Piechniczek, D., Fischer, T., 1996. Urban groundwater in Dresden, Germany. Hydrogeology Journal 4, 48-63.##Howard, K.W., 2015. Sustainable cities and the groundwater governance challenge. Environ Earth Sci 73, 2543–2554.##Islam, S., Singh, R.K., Abad Khan, R., 2016. Methods of Estimating Ground Water Recharge. International Journal of Engineering Associates 5, 6-9.##Kruse, E., Carol, E., Mancuso, M., Laurencena, P., Deluchi, M., Rojo, A., 2013. Recharge assessment in an urban area: a case study of La Plata, Argentina. Hydrogeology Journal 21, 1091–1100.##Kumar, M., Rao, S., Kumar, B., Ramanathan, A., 2011. Identification of aquifer-recharge zones and sources in an urban development area (Delhi, India), by correlating isotopic tracerswith hydrological features. Hydrogeology Journal 19, 463–474.##Lerner, D.N., 2002. Identifying and quantifying urban recharge: a review. Hydrogeology Journal 10, 143–152.##Lodwick, W.A., Munson, W.N.A., Svoboda, L., 1990. Attribute error and sensitivity analysis of map operations in geographical information systems: suitability analysis. International Journal of Geographic Information Systems 4, 413-428.##Mafi, E., Moradi, G., Hayati, S., Khayampour, R., 2014. Management and Disposal of Urban Runoff Using Geographic Information System and River Tools Techniques (Case Study: District 1 of Ahwaz City). Journal of Geography and Regional Development 12, 1-15 (In Persian)##Minnig, M., Moeck, C., Radny, D., Schirmer, M., 2018. Impact of urbanization on groundwater recharge rates in Dübendorf, Switzerland. Journal of Hydrology  563, 1135–1146.##Naik, P.K, Tambe, J.A., Dehury, B.N., Tiwari, A.N., 2008. Impact of urbanization on the groundwater regime in a fast growing city in central India. Environmental Monitoring Assessment 146, 339-373.##Sharp, J.M.J., 2010. The impacts of urbanization on groundwater systems and recharge. AQUAmundi, DOI 10.4409/Am-004-10-0008.##Singh, S., Samaddar, A.B., Srivastava, R.K, Pandey, H.K., 2014. Ground Water Recharge in Urban Areas – Experience of Rain Water Harvesting. Journal geological society of India 83, 295-302.##Tama, V.T, Ngab, T.V., 2018. Assessment of urbanization impact on groundwater resources in Hanoi,Vietnam. Journal of Environmental Management 227, 107–116.##Tavasoli, A., Vafakhah, M., Hoseniya, A., 2008. Determine watercourse storage areas by application of GIS techniques in Mashhad. 3th Congress of Water Resource Management, Tabriz University (In Persian).##Tubau, I., Vázquez-Sune, E., Carrera, J., Valhondo, C., Criollo, R., 2017. Quantification of groundwater recharge in urban environments. Science of The Total Environment 592, 391-402.##Vazquez-Sune, E., Carrera, J., Tubau, I., Sanchez-Vila, X., Soler, A., 2010. An approach to identify urban groundwater recharge. Hydrol. Earth Syst. Sci 14, 2085–2097.##Wakode, H.B., Baier, K., Jha, R., Azzam, R., 2018. Impact of urbanization on groundwater recharge and urban water balance for the city of Hyderabad, India. International Soil and Water Conservation Research 6, 51–62.##Yousefi, H., Noorallahi, Y., Soltani, K., Javadzadeh, Z., 2015. The Management Strategies to Reduce the Vulnerability of Flood in Tehran (Case Study: District 1 and 3). Eco hydrology 1, 181-193 (In Persian).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی عملکرد روش‌های تخمین زمین‌آماری غیرخطی در تخمین عیار- تناژ کانسار سنگ آهن چاه ‏باشه، استان یزد</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluation of performance of non-linear geostatistical estimation methods to estimate tonnage-grade of the Chah-‎bashe iron deposit, Yazd province‎</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در پژوهش حاضر عیار و ذخیره کانسار آهن چاه باشه یزد با استفاده از روش‌های زمین‌آماری لاگ کریجینگ معمولی بلوکی، کریجینگ شاخص و شبیه‌سازی متوالی ‏گوسی و نیز روش آماری عکس مجذور فاصله (برای مقایسه)، ارزیابی شده است. برای این منظور ابتدا مطالعات آماری داده‌های عیارسنجی گمانه‌های اکتشافی از طریق ‏تعیین آماره‌های توصیفی مختصر، ترسیم هیستوگرام و نمودار فراوانی تجمعی داده‌ها صورت گرفت. همچنین برای مدل‌سازی کانسار، از طریق ترسیم واریوگرام‌های ‏امتدادی مختلف با استفاده از نرم‌افزار ‏SGeMS، توابع موجود در نرم‌افزار ‏MATLAB‏ و کدنویسی‌های کوتاه در این محیط، واریوگرافی و تجزیه و تحلیل ساختار ‏فضایی انجام شد. سپس مدل‌سازی سه‌بعدی بلوکی کانسار، تعیین متوسط عیار، تخمین میزان ذخیره و ترسیم نمودارهای عیار- تناژ، با استفاده از نرم‌افزار ‏Datamine‏ ‏صورت گرفت. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهند که روش‌های شبیه‌سازی متوالی گوسی، کریجینگ شاخص، لاگ کریجینگ معمولی و عکس مجذور فاصله به‌ترتیب دارای ‏کمترین مقدار واریانس تخمین می‌باشند. اگرچه تمام روش‌های انتخاب شده از دقیق‌ترین روش‌های تخمین زمین‌آماری هستند، اما نتایج روش شبیه‌سازی متوالی ‏گوسی با اعمال فیلترهای مختلف بر روی داده‌ها همانند استفاده از نقشه‌های باقیمانده، دقیق‌ترین بوده و از درجه اعتبار بیشتری برخوردار است. ‏</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In this research, non-linear geostatistical methods containing block ordinary log-kriging, indicator kriging and sequential ‎gaussian simulation as well as inverse squared distance from statistical methods (for comparison) have been employed ‎to evaluate grade and ore reserve of the Chah-bashe iron deposit, Yazd provice. To achieve this goal, first statistical ‎studies of assay data of exploratory boreholes were performed through determination of descriptive statistics, drawing ‎the histograms and cumulative probability distribution diagrams of the data. For modeling the deposit, variography ‎was also carried out through drawing various directional variograms using SGEMs software, MATLAB functions and ‎short programming in this environment. Afterward, 3-D block modeling of the deposit, determination of average grade, ‎ore reserve estimation and plotting tonnage-grade diagrams were performed using Datamine software. The results of ‎the research show that sequential gaussian simulation, indicator kriging, ordinary log-kriging, and inverse squared ‎distance‏ ‏methods have the minimum estimation variance, respectively. Although all selected methods are the most ‎accurate geostatistical methods, however the results of sequential gaussian simulation method by applying various ‎filters on the data such as using residual maps, is most highly accurate and more reliable so has more validity. ‎</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>180</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>194</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>احمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ahmadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه صنعتی اراک</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه صنعتی اراک</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rezahmadi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فریدونی</Family>
						<NameE>Hosein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Fereidooni</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکترای دانشکده مهندسی معدن دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکترای دانشکده مهندسی معدن دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>fereydoonihosein@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>لاگ کریجینگ معمولی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کریجینگ شاخص</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبیه‌سازی متوالی گوسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نرم‌افزار ‏Datamine</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کانسار آهن چاه باشه یزد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ahmadi, R., 2010. Application of statistical patterns for ore reserve estimation emphasis to Ali-abad, Yazd copper mine. Arak University of Technology, Vice Chancellor for Research, Arak, 102 pp.##Bohling, G., 2007. SGeMS Tutorial Notes, 26 pp.##Hassani-Pak, A.A., Sharafodin, M.S., 2001. Exploration data analysis. Tehran University Press, 987 pp.##Rendu, J.M., 1981. An introduction to geostatistical methods of mineral evaluation, South African Institute of Mining and Metallurgy monograph series, Johannesburg, 84 pp.  ##Yousefi, M., Jaafarzadeh, A.O., Karami, A. and Fereidooni, H., 2013. Detailed exploration report of the region of Chah-bashe deposit, Iran Minerals Supply and production Co., Tehran, 125R4-02, 67 pp.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی پیوستگی هیدروکربنی مخازن سروک و ایلام در میدان نفتی آزادگان با استفاده از تلفیق داده‎های ژئو‌شیمیایی، زمین‌شناسی و مهندسی مخزن</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Hydrocarbon continuity investigation of Sarvak and Ilam reservoirs in Azadegan oilfield using integration of geochemical, geological and reservoir engineering data</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>میدان آزادگان واقع در دشت آبادان بعنوان یکی از بزرگترین میادین نفتی توسعه نیافته ایران محسوب می‌شود. مخازن کربناته سروک (کرتاسه میانی) و ایلام (کرتاسه بالایی) در این میدان توسط سازند شیلی لافان از یکدیگر جدا گردیده‎اند. در این تحقیق به منظور بررسی نحوه ارتباط نفت این مخازن با یکدیگر، داده‌های ژئو‌شیمیایی آلی با اطلاعات زمین‌شناسی و فشار مخزن ادغام گردید. بر اساس نتایج به‌دست آمده از داده‌های ژئو‌شیمیایی، نفت‌های این مخازن از لحاظ زایشی به یک خانواده نفتی با منشأ مشترک دریایی تعلق دارند و دارای خصوصیات ژئوشیمیایی و بلوغ یکسان در حد اواسط زون نفت‌زایی می‌باشند. با این‌حال، دو گروه نفتی متفاوت و غیر مرتبط در این مخازن بر اساس مطالعه ترکیبات هیدروکربوری سبک C7 تشخیص داده شد که اطلاعات فشار مخازن نیز آن را تائید می‌نماید. این امر به دلیل عملکرد سازند کاملاً شیلی لافان است که علی‌رغم ضخامت کم بعنوان یک لایه ناتراوا عمل نموده و ارتباط مخازن سروک و ایلام را قطع نموده است. بر اساس نتایج حاصله، مطالعه ژئو‌شیمیایی مخازن هیدروکربوری می‌تواند به خوبی در تعیین پیوستگی مخازن مورد استفاده قرار گیرد و سبب بهبود مدل‌های مخزنی که نقش تعیین‌کننده‌ای در کاهش ریسک برنامه‌های توسعه و تولید میدان دارند، گردد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Azadegan oilfield, located in Abadan Plain, is considered as one of the largest undeveloped oilfields in Iran. The carbonate Sarvak (Middle Cretaceous) and Ilam (Upper Cretaceous) reservoirs have been completely separated by the shaly Lafan Formation in this oilfield. Here, in order to investigate the connectivity between the oils of the mentioned reservoirs, organic geochemical data were integrated with the geological and reservoir pressure information. Geochemical data show that the oils of Sarvak and Ilam reservoirs have a common genetic family, originated from a marine source rock, and their geochemical characteristics are identical. Also, they have a same thermal maturity in the range of middle oil generation window. However, two distinct and unrelated oil groups were identified in these reservoirs based on the results of C7 light hydrocarbons, confirmed by the reservoirs’ pressure data. This is due to stratigraphic situation of the thin impermeable shaly Lafan Formation related to the studied reservoirs, disconnecting the hydrocarbon connectivity between them. Based on the results obtained from this study, geochemical investigation of hydrocarbon reservoirs can be appropriately used for assessment of reservoir connectivity and would improve the reservoir models which in turn plays a crucial role in reducing the risk of the field’s development and production programs.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>195</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>206</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهرام</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>علیزاده</Family>
						<NameE>Bahram</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Alizadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز
مرکز تحقیقات زمین‌شناسی و زمین‌شیمی نفت، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>alizadeh@scu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهراب</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رشیدی</Family>
						<NameE>Mehrab</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rashidi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز
اداره مطالعات و تحقیقات ژئوشیمی، مدیریت اکتشاف شرکت ملی نفت ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehrab_rashidi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زراسوندی</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zarasvandi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز
مرکز تحقیقات زمین‌شناسی و زمین‌شیمی نفت، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zarasvandi_a@scu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید رسول</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سیدعلی</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Rasoul</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Seyedali</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز
مرکز تحقیقات زمین‌شناسی و زمین‌شیمی نفت، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sr.seyedali1993@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>علیئی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hasan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aliee</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>اداره ژئوفیزیک، مدیریت اکتشاف شرکت ملی نفت ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>اداره ژئوفیزیک، مدیریت اکتشاف شرکت ملی نفت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>alieemh@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ژئوشیمی مخزن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پیوستگی مخزن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مخازن کرتاسه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دشت آبادان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>میدان نفتی آزادگان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>AbdollahieFard, I., Braathen, A., Mokhtari, M., Alavi, S.A., 2006. Interaction of the Zagros Fold-Thrust belt and the Arabian-type, deep-seated folds in the Abadan Plain and the Dezful Embayment, SW Iran. Petroleum Geoscience, 12:347-362.##Alizadeh,B., Sarafdokht, H., Rajabi, M., Opera, A., Janbaz, M., 2012. Organic geochemistry and petrography of Kazhdumi (Albian-Cenomanian) and Pabdeh (Paleogene) potential source rocks in southern part of the Dezful Embayment, Iran. Organic Geochemistry, 49: 36-46.##Alizadeh,B., Saadati,H.,  Rashidi,M. and Kobraei,M., 2016 .Geochemical investigation of oils from Cretaceous to Eocene sedimentary sequences of the Abadan Plain, Southwest Iran. Marine and Petroleum Geology, 73:609-619.##Connan, J., 1984. Biodegradation of crude oils in reservoirs, In: Brooks, J., Welte D.H. (eds.), Advances in Petroleum Geochemistry. Academic Press, London.##Du, Y., Chen, J., Cui, Y., Xin, J., Wang, J., Li, Y.Z., Fu, X., 2016. Genetic Mechanism and development of the unsteady Sarvak play of the Azadegan oil Field, Southwest of Iran, Petroleum Science 13: 34-51.##England, W.A., 2007. Reservoir geochemistry-A reservoir engineering perspective. Journal of Petroleum Science and, 58:344-354.##Sofer, Z., 1984. Stable carbon isotope compositions of crude oils: application to source depositional environments and petroleum alteration. AAPG Bulletin, 68:31-49.##Grantham, P. J. and Wakefield, L. L. 1988. Variations in the Sterane Carbon Number Distributions of Marine Source Rock Derived Crude Oils through Geological Time. Organic Geochemistry, 12: 61-73.##Halpern, H.I., 1995. Development and application of light-hydrocarbon-based star diagrams. AAPG Bulletin, 79: 801-815.##Moldowan, J. M., Seifert, W. K. and Gallegos, E. J., 1985. Relationship between Petroleum Composition and Depositional Environment of Petroleum Source Rocks. American Association of Petroleum Geology Bulletin, 69: 1255-1268.##Paez, R.H., Lawerence, J.J., Zhang, M., 2010. Compartmentalization or gravity segregation? Understanding and predicting characteristics of near- critical petroleum fluids. In: Jolley, S.J., Fisher, Q.J., Ainsworth, R.B., Vrolijk, P., Delisle, S. (eds.), Reservoir Compartmentalization. Geological Society, London, Special Publications, 43-53.##Peters, K.E., Walters, C.C., Moldowan, J.M., 2005. The biomarker guide. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge.##Sofer, Z., 1984. Stable carbon isotope compositions of crude oils: application to source depositional environments and petroleum alteration. AAPG Bulletin, 68:31-49.##Thompson, K.F.M., 1979. Light hydrocarbons in subsurface sediments. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, 43: 657-672.##Thompson, K.F.M., 1983. Classification and thermal history of petroleum based on light hydrocarbons. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta, 47: 303-316.##Thompson, K.F.M., 1987. Fractionated aromatic petroleums and the generation of gas-condensates. Organic Geochemistry, 11: 573-590.##Thompson, K.F.M., 1988. Gas condensate migration and petroleum fractionation in deltaic systems. Marine and Petroleum Geology, 5: 237-246.##Thompson, K.F.M., 2006. Mechanisms controlling gas and light end composition in pyrolysates and petroleum: applications in the interpretation of reservoir fluid analyses. Organic Geochemistry, 37: 798-817.##Tissot, B.P., Welte, D.H., 1984. Petroleum formation and occurrence. Springer-Verlag, Berlin.##Volkman, J.K., Maxwell, J.R., 1986. Acyclic isoprenoids as biological markers. In: Johns, R.B. (ed.), Biological markers in the sedimentary record. Elsevier, Amsterdam, 1-46.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				