<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Detection of mine tailing dam using ASTER in AnguranPb-Zn mine, SW Zanjan</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آشکارسازی سدهای باطله معدنی با استفاده از تصاویر چندطیفی سنجنده استر، مطالعه موردی: معدن سرب-روی انگوران، جنوب غرب زنجان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>110</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>120</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15070</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28325.1934</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نازی</FirstName>
					<LastName>مظهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرجان</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز-دانشکده علوم بخش علوم زمین</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پروین</FirstName>
					<LastName>بیات</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدصالح</FirstName>
					<LastName>برومند</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the main purposes of geological remote sensing is trying to improve mapping methods of various rock and minerals. In recent decades, with the development of Remote Sensing, this technology has been proposed as an effective method for mapping of rock units. remote Sensing technology has been very helpful by using satellite data to control and monitor various pollutions in managing different sources and also its economical to use these data to identify enviromental pollution caused by unlimited mining activities and with fast detection of these kind of pollution, it has been very useful for solving enviromental problems. Undoubtedly the use of this technology in exploratory studies, natural and environmental resources not only increases the speed of studies, but is also much more efficient in terms of accuracy and cost and manpower. The purpose of this study is mine tailings detection of the Anguran Pb-Zn mining area using false color combination (R:1,G:6,B:3), principal component analysis (PCA), and band ratios [R3/2,G5/3,B8/4]. The use of the first three PC and the evaluation of the eigenvector shows that the fifth and ninth components with eigenvectors of 0.72 and 0.65 indicate the spectral behavior of carbonate and clay minerals in bands 8 and 6. image processings validated by the USGS library spectra, the Resampled USGS library spectra and Z-Profile images.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی ازاهداف سنجش از دور زمین شناختی، تلاش برای بهبود روش های نقشه برداری انواع سنگ ها و کانی هاست. شناسایی آلودگی‌های زیست محیطی ایجاد شده در اثر فعالیت‌های نامحدود معدنی با استفاده از این داده‌ها از لحاظ اقتصادی و زمانی مقرون به-صرفه بوده ‌است. بارزسازی هر چه سریعتر این آلودگی‌ها در زمینه حل مشکلات زیست محیطی گام مهمی برداشته خواهد شد. بدون شک استفاده از این فناوری در مطالعات اکتشافی ، منابع طبیعی و زیست محیطی نه تنها سرعت انجام مطالعات را بیشتر می‌کند، بلکه از نظر دقت، هزینه و نیروی انسانی نیز بسیار با صرفه‌تر است. هدف از این تحقیق، بارزسازی باطله‌های معدنی سرب-روی انگوران با استفاده از داده‌های استر می‌باشد. بررسی رفتار سنگ‌ها و کانی‌های و استفاده از روش‌های ترکیب رنگی کاذب (R:1,G:6,B:3)، تحلیل مولفه‌های اصلی و نسبت‌گیری باندی به صورت ترکیب رنگی کاذب (R3/2,G5/3,B8/4) موجب نقشه برداری باطله‌های معدن گردید. استفاده از سه PC اول و بررسی مقدار ویژه بردار نشان می‌دهد که مولفه‌های پنجم و نهم با مقادیر ویژه بردار 72/0 و 65/0 دلالت بر رفتار طیفی کانی‌های کربناته و رسی در باندهای 8 و 6 دارد. اعتبارسنجی پردازش‌های انجام شده در نهایت از طریق طیف‌های کتابخانه‌ای، طیف‌های بازنویسی شده و طیف تصویر صورت گرفت.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معدن سرب-روی انگوران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنجنده استر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترکیب رنگی کاذب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل مؤلفه اصلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نسبت‌گیری باندی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15070_6887b3cc25925d54f7e6d16f224b3820.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
