<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Comparison accuracy of Fuzzy-GAMMA and analytical hierarchy process (AHP) two methods with the potential detection of Cu metal in Malayer-Aligoudarz-Esfahan metallogenic zone</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مقایسه دقت دو روش فازی گاما (Fuzzy-GAMMA) و تحلیل سلسله مراتبی (AHP) با هدف پتانسیل‏ یابی فلز مس در زون فلززایی ملایر-الیگودرز-اصفهان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15341</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.30222.2011</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدامین</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجو کارشناسی ارشد، دانشکده زمین‌شناسی، پردیس علوم، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احد</FirstName>
					<LastName>نظرپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی اهواز- گروه زمین شناسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>کنعانیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Malayer-Aligoudarz-Isfahan metallogenic belt is located in the Sanandaj-Sirjan Zone, which hosts a large number of metal deposits. In this study, using Fuzzy-GAMMA method and analytic hierarchy process (AHP) based on weighting to exploratory layers were used Cu metal modeling in the studied area. First, all exploration layers and substrates, including lithology, geochemistry and fault density, they were weighted by Fuzzy-GAMMA method and were in the range of 0 to 1. Then fuzzy layers are then integration according to the weights assigned with 0.9 gamma (γ) value and Potential maps of Cu metal in the study area were obtained by Fuzzy-GAMMA method. Subsequently, using analytic hierarchical process Method (AHP), and forming appropriate matrix for the exploration layers, the layers were weighted and the potential map of Cu metal was obtained. Finally, the location of the Cu deposits and indices in the region was used to compare the accuracy of the applied methods. The results showed that (AHP) method compared with Fuzzy-GAMMA method determine more anomaly and the obtained anomalies by this method more consistent with existing Cu deposits in the region.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کمربند فلززایی ملایر-الیگودرز-اصفهان با قرار گرفتن در زون سنندج-سیرجان میزبان تعداد زیادی از ذخایر فلزی می باشد. در این پژوهش با استفاده از روش های منطق فازی (Fuzzy-GAMMA)، تحلیل سلسله مراتبی (AHP) و بر اساس وزن دهی به لایه های اکتشافی، مدل سازی فلز مس در منطقه مورد مطالعه صورت گرفت. ابتدا تمام لایه ها و زیرلایه های اکتشافی شامل لیتولوژی، زمین شیمی و چگالی گسل ها با استفاده از روش منطق فازی (Fuzzy-GAMMA) وزن دهی و در دامنة 0 تا 1 قرار گرفتند. سپس لایه های فازی سازی شده طبق وزن های اختصاص یافته با مقدار گامای (γ) 9/0 با یکدیگر تلفیق و نقشه های پتانسیل یابی فلز مس در منطقه مورد مطالعه بر اساس روش منطق فازی (Fuzzy-GAMMA) حاصل شد. پس از آن با استفاده از روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی (AHP) و با تشکیل دادن ماتریس مناسب برای لایه های اکتشافی، لایه ها وزن دهی شدند و نقشة پتانسیل یابی فلز مس بدست آمد. نتایج حاصل نشان داد روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی (AHP) در مقایسه با روش منطق فازی (Fuzzy-GAMMA) آنومالی های بیشتری را مشخص کرده و آنومالی های بدست آمده از این روش انطباق بیشتری با معادن مس موجود در منطقه نشان می دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پتانسیل یابی مس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سینگولاریتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منطق فازی (Fuzzy-GAMMA)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل سلسله مراتبی (AHP)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ملایر-الیگودرز-اصفهان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
