<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Genetic classification and geochemical evaluation of oil families in the South ‎Dezful Embayment, southwest of Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تعیین خانواده های نفتی و توصیف ژئوشیمیایی آن ها در فروافتادگی دزفول جنوبی، جنوب غربی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15334</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.31504.2053</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهرام</FirstName>
					<LastName>علیزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8033-4080</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیرعباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>جهانگرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه&amp;lrm; &amp;lrm;زمین شناسی،&amp;lrm; &amp;lrm;دانشکده&amp;lrm; &amp;lrm;علوم&amp;lrm; &amp;lrm;زمین،&amp;lrm; &amp;lrm;دانشگاه&amp;lrm; &amp;lrm;شهید&amp;lrm; &amp;lrm;چمران&amp;lrm; &amp;lrm;اهواز</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0542-6313</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>علیپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده علوم زمین-گروه زمین شناسی-دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3759-993X</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>گندمی ثانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>اداره مطالعات و تحقیقات دیرینه شناسی و ژئوشیمی، مدیریت اکتشاف، شرکت ملی نفت ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The occurrence of barren anticlines in the vicinity of major hydrocarbon fields producing from individual ‎reservoirs in the south of the Dezful Embayment unveils the structural complexity of the area and the ‎intricacy of the processes of hydrocarbon generation, migration and entrapment. In this study, we ‎investigate the possible genetic relationships between the Jurassic-Lower Cretaceous reservoirs on one ‎hand, and the Upper Cretaceous-Tertiary reservoirs on the other. A comprehensive geochemical approach ‎is undertaken to identify genetic oil families in the study area and throw some light on the existing ‎petroleum systems. Bulk geochemical properties and molecular fingerprints support the existence of two ‎distinct oil families within the Khami Group (Jurassic-Lower Cretaceous) and the Asmari-Sarvak (Upper ‎Cretaceous-Tertiary) reservoirs. Source and maturity related biomarker parameters well suggest differing ‎source rocks for these oil families. Oils in the Asmari-Sarvak family indicate a uniform thermal maturity ‎equivalent to the middle oil window. These oils have originated from a marly-carbonate source rock with ‎mixed marine-terrigenous organic matter input that was deposited under anoxic to semi-anoxic ‎conditions. The oils in the Khami Group family are derived from an older Early Cretaceous source rock ‎deposited under dysoxic to semi-anoxic conditions that could receive significant inputs of terrigenous ‎organic matter. These oils are most likely generated at the peak of oil generation window from their ‎parent source rock. Data from this study suggest that the immature Pabdeh Formation is a subordinate ‎source rock of the Asmari-Sarvak oil family that could play a minor impregnating role.‎</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در بخش جنوبی فروافتادگی دزفول، وجود ساختارهای نفتی متعدد و مخازن هیدروکربنی در افق‌های مختلف در مجاورت ساختارهای فاقد ‏هیدروکربن نشان‌دهنده پیچیدگی ساختاری و فرآیندهای زایش، مهاجرت و به تله افتادگی هیدروکربن در این ناحیه است. بر همین اساس به منظور ‏تبیین ارتباط ژنتیکی بین خانواده‌های نفتی و روشن‌تر ساختن وضعیت سیستم‌‌های نفتی فعال در منطقه، با بکارگیری روش‌‌های ژئوشیمیایی، ‏ارتباط بین نفت‌های مخازن ژوراسیک با مخازن کرتاسه-ترشیری مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. ویژگی‌‌های کلی نفت و اثرانگشت‌های نفتی، وجود دو ‏خانواده نفتی مجزا در مخازن آسماری-سروک و مخازن گروه خامی در منطقه مورد مطالعه را محتمل جلوه می‌دهد. تمایزات بیومارکری وابسته به ‏منشاء و بلوغ به‌خوبی سنگ‌های منشاء متفاوتی را برای نفت‌های موجود پیشنهاد می‌کنند. نفت مخازن آسماری-سروک دارای بلوغی در محدوده ‏اواسط پنجره نفتی هستند و هیدروکربن‌ آن‌ها از منشاء یکسان و از نوع کربناته-مارنی با مشارکت مواد آلی دریایی-تخریبی مشتق شده است. شرایط ‏رسوبگذاری سنگ منشاء این گروه عمدتاً احیایی تا نیمه احیایی بوده است. خانواده نفتی گروه خامی از سنگ منشاء قدیمی‌تر به سن کرتاسه زیرین ‏و در شرایط رسوبگذاری نیمه‌اکسیدی-نیمه‌احیایی و با غلبه مواد آلی با منشاء تخریبی زایش یافته است. بلوغ سنگ منشاء این گروه از نفت‌ها در ‏محدوده پیک زایش هیدروکربن قرار دارد.‏</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فروافتادگی دزفول جنوبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مخازن نفتی آسماری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بنگستان و خامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خانواده نفتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ژئوشیمی نفت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
