<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Faulting and morphotectonic in the Bakharden-Quchan zone</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>گسلش و مورفوتکتونیک در زون بخاردن-قوچان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>58</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>65</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14827</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.27146.1892</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>بیگلری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شاهرود گروه زمین شناسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>کنگی</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیئت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شاهرود</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفریان</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیئت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شاهرود</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;1-Introduction&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;In this paper fundamental goal is discussed about tectonic activities and survey role of different factors of forming and deformations to understand better about origin of morphotectonic of land forms occurring to reveal geomorphological patterns in the Bakharden-Quchan zone in the context of Arabia-Eurasia collision (Berberian, 1976; Lybris and Manby, 1999; Shabanian, 2009). &lt;br /&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2-Methodology&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;This paper uses of satellite images observations from Landsat 7, topographic data (SRTM), GIS and GPS data, geology and topographic maps, field observations of the morphotectonic landforms to clarify the active tectonics in the Bakharden-Quchan zone. &lt;br /&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3-Results and discussion&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;In this zone there is an array active right lateral-strike slip fault that they obliquely have cut the range and produced offsets of several Kms in the geological structures. These faults have identifiable ends, where they turn into thrust and link to blind faults mechanism changing of faults to revers have caused shortening by thrusting in their ends bending. Through convergence of Arabia-Eurasia plates have put constantly under neotectonic activities this zone since last phase of Alpine orogeny. Morphotectonic features have revealed by uplifts, deformations, ruptures and incision of late Quaternary traces, displacement of channel this sections, shear and displacement of Quaternary alluvial fan deposits. There faults have rotated anti clockwise around their vertical axes to cause several Kms of NS shortening. They also require of several Kms along strike extension that is taken by the westward component of motion between south Caspian Sea basin, Shahrood Fault system and both Eurasia and central Iran (Hollingsworth, 2006: Bretis and Conrady, 2012). &lt;br /&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4-Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;The most important results of this paper is the identification of an array of active right lateral-strike slip faults which are almost certainly responsible for major destructive earthquakes in both historical and modern. All of these faults have ended where they turn into thrusts and link to blind faults. Mechanism changing of these faults to reverse of caused to increase stress, shortening by thrusting in their ends bending and their neotectonic activities create different morphotectonic features in Bakharden-Quchan zone particulary along the Qhuchan and Baghan-Garmab faults that there are enough morphotectonic evidences (Tchalenko, 1975; Masson et al., 2007; Shabanian, 2009). &lt;br /&gt; </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زون گسل بخاردن-قوچان در فاصله 150 کیلومتری شمال شرق مشهد از برجسته ترین چهره های توپوگرافی-ساختمانی مرکز کپه داغ در بین شهرهای قوچان، ‏شیروان و بجنورد است. مجموع گسل های امتداد لغز-راستگرد قوچان، باغان-گرماب، شیروان و غلامان-سومبار با روند شمالغرب-جنوبشرق از مهم ترین گسل های ‏این زون بوده که فعالیت نوزمین ساختی آنها در نهشته های کواترنری قابل ردیابی است. انتهای این گسل ها به صورت رورانده است. طبق شواهد دورسنجی و میدانی ‏این جنبش ها می توان در ایجاد پدیده های مورفوتکتونیکی مانند برخاستگی و برش پادگان های رودخانه ای، جابجایی ابراهه ها و تقطیع، برش و جابجایی رسوبات ‏کواترنری مخروط افکنه ای مشاهده نمود. تراکم بالای پراکنده ای زمین لرزه ها در پایانه گسل های قوچان و باغان و گرماب می باشد. ‏</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زون تکتونیکی بخاردن-قوچان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تکتونیک فعال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گسلش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مورفوتکتونیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ژئومورفولوژی.‏</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_14827_b3c86d272b2b3b23b09e2db2d086badb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
