<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Biostratigraphy and paleoecology of Paleocene-Eocene deposits in Kuh–e-Ketabi section (West of Rafasanjan)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>زیست‌چینه‌نگاری و بوم‌شناسی دیرینه نهشته‌های پالئوسن-ائوسن در برش کوه کتابی (غرب رفسنجان)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>423</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>439</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15066</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28036.1914</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طیبه</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدی ابراهیم آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه زمین شناسی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Abstract. &lt;br /&gt; The biostratigraphy and paleoecology of Paleocene - Early Eocene deposits in the west of Rafsanjan city (Kerman Province) were studied for the first time. The Kuh – e - Ketabi sequence, the measured profile has about 161 m thick, mainly consists of limestone, dolostone, marl, shale, dolomitic limestone, and calcareous sandstone. Based on lithological characteristics, the studied section could be divided into 5 informal rock units. Forty genera and species of benthonic and planktonic foraminifera have been obtained from the section. One planktonic biozone (Morozovella angulata Lowest occurrence zone) and three shallow-water Tethyan foraminiferal biozones (SBZ4 – SBZ6) have been recognized based on the foraminiferal distribution in the stratigraphic column. From the view of abundance, diversity and distribution of foraminifera the Late Paleocene - Early Eocene part of the studied section is comparable with an equivalent sequence of the Tethyan Basin. Also, environmental depth changes are discussed based on faunal changes.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">نهشته‌های پالئوسن -ائوسن پیشین در غرب شهرستان رفسنجان (استان کرمان) برای اولین بار از دیدگاه زیست‌چینه‌ای و بوم شناسی دیرینه مورد بررسی قرار گرفته‌اند. رخنمون کوه کتابی با ستبرای 161 متر به طور عمده از سنگ آهک، دولومیت، شیل، مارن و ماسه سنگ‌های آهکی تشکیل شده و بر اساس ویژگی‌های سنگ شناسی به پنج واحد رسوبی قابل تقسیم است. چهل جنس و گونه از روزنبران کف‌زی و شناور از توالی این برش بدست آمد که بر پایه توزیع عمودی آنها یک زون زیستی بر اساس روزنبران شناور (Morozovella angulata Lowest occurrence zone) و سه زون زیستی از زون-های کف‌زی کم ژرفا حوضه تتیس (SBZ4-SBZ6 Biozones) براساس روزنبران کف‌زی شناسایی گردید. توالی بررسی شده در برش کتابی از نظر تغییرات فراوانی، تنوع و نحوه پراکندگی روزنبران در فاصله زمانی پالئوسن پسین- ائوسن پیشین با نهشته‌های معادل در حوضه تتیس قابل مقایسه است. همچنین تغییرات ژرفای محیط نهشتگی در ارتباط با تغییرات نوع فونا نیز مورد بحث قرار گرفته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پالئوسن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ائوسن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روزنبران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تتیس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفسنجان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15066_e1e6c78aae3fc285866bc7c66534004c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
