<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Mineralogical Investigation and Water Absorption of Bentonites in Momen Abad Area, to be Used in Pelletizing Industry and a Comparison with Some Other Bentonite Mines in Eastern Iranian Bentonite Zone</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی کانی‌شناسی و جذب آب بنتونیت‌های منطقه مؤمن ‌آباد به منظور کاربرد در صنایع گندله سازی و مقایسه با برخی معادن زون بنتونیت خاور ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15344</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.29487.1982</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سحر</FirstName>
					<LastName>طربی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، باشگاه پژوهشگران جوان و نخبگان، تهران،  ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سروش</FirstName>
					<LastName>مدبری</LastName>
<Affiliation>رئیس انجمن زمین شناسی ایران
هیئت علمی دانشکده زمین شناسی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Momen Abad Mining area is a part of the Eastern Iranian Bentonite Zone. Mineralogical studies revealed the presence of cristobalite and smectite as the main phases and plagioclase, feldspar and amorphous silica occur as the minor phases and this mineralogy favors the application of this mineral assemblage in pelletizing industry of iron concentrate. Scanning Electron Microscopy of bentonite clumps indicates that smectite clays show wavy sheet like morphology with overgrowth of cristobalite and bentonite sheet grains occur as aggregates with flocculated appearance and spherical and angular grains with popcorn texture. Based on the Na and Ca contents it was found out that the bentonites are compositionally Na members. Water absorption tests on 104 samples indicate that the Momen Abad samples from trenches shallower than 15m are not favorable for pelletizing however deeper samples show acceptable parameters for this purpose. In addition, the results obtained from comparison of eight mines indicate that Momen Abad and Deheshk mines with absorption of higher than 600 are more convenient than samples from Sanajan, Tighab, Khosh’hal, Ebrahimi, Mortezanejad, and Shirazi mines.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">منطقه معدنی مؤمن ‌آباد بخشی از زون بنتونیتی خاور ایران است. نتایج کانی‌شناسی نشان می‌دهد کریستوبالیت و اسمکتیت به عنوان کانی‌ اصلی و پلاژیوکلاز، ‌فلدسپار، کانی‌های شکل‌دار مانند سیلیس و ... به عنوان فاز فرعی می‌تواند زمینه را برای کاربرد بهتر در صنعت گندله آهن ایجاد کند. تصاویر SEM بیان می‌کند که رس‌های اسمکتیتی، مرفولوژی ورقه‌ای موجدار با رورشدی کریستوبالیت نشان می‌دهد و ذره‌های صفحه‌ای بنتونیت، انبوهه‌هایی را با ظاهری لخته شده و به صورت کروی و زاویه‌دار با بافت دانه‌ذرتی نشان می‌دهند. براساس میزان Na و Ca بنتونیت‌ها، سدیمی هستند. آزمون‌ جذب آب بر روی 104 نمونه نشان می‌دهد که معدن مؤمن ‌آباد برخلاف ویژگی‌های کانی‌شناسی قابل قبول، در عمق کمتر از 15 متر میزان جذب آب غیر قابل قبولی دارند، اما در نمونه‌های با عمق بیشتر از 15 متر با توجه به ماهیت زمین‌شناسی و ارتباط مستقیم جذب آب با عمق، مناسب کاربرد در گندله‌سازی هستند. مقایسه هشت معدن از زون بنتونیتی خاور ایران نشان می‌هد که معدن دهشک و مؤمن ‌آباد نسبت به معادن سناجان، تیغاب، قله‌گل‌کن، خوشحال، ابراهیمی، مرتضی‌نژاد و شیرازی جذب آب بالای 600 را نشان می‌دهند و ویژگی مناسب‌تری برای گندله‌سازی آهن دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جذب آب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گندله‌سازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بنتونیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مؤمن ‌آباد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خاور ایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
