<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Application of structural data, chemistry of sulfide minerals and fluid inclusion in mineralization type determination of Zn-Pb carbonate hosted Gardaneshir ore deposit in Southwest Ardestan</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کاربرد داده‌های ساختاری، شیمی‌کانی‌های سولفیدی و میان‌بارهای سیال در تعیین تیپ کانه‌زائی کانسارهای روی-سرب منطقه معدنی گردنه‌شیر با سنگ میزبان کربناته در جنوب باختر اردستان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15342</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.29813.1997</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفر کوپائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد گروه زمین‌شناسی اقتصادی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>راستاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیئت علمی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>معدنی پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه تکتونیک دانشگاه تربیت مدرس تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سجاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>مغفوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیئت علمی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Gardeneh-Shir zinc and lead deposit is located at 38 km southwest of Ardestan in Central Iran. The host rocks of this deposit includes carbonates of Middle Triassic Shotory Formation juxtaposed over Upper Triassic Naiband Formation by thrust faulting. The mineralization in these deposits is in the form of vein-veinlet, breccia and filling of karstic cavities with dolomitization and silicification and mainly controlled by Strike-slip faults with the normal component and normal faults with strike slip component those are cross cutting older generation of thrust faults. The results of fluid inclusion studies of on quartz and dolomite in Gardeneh-Shir deposits Area show a fluid with a salinity of 23.2-18.6% by weight of salt, temperature range of homogeneity between 91 -162 ° C and a density of 1.09-1.056 g/cm3. The combination of fluid inclusion and EPMA analysis of Zn / Cd (879%) elemental ratios in sphalerite mineral has confirmed low temperature generation of Gardeneh Shir deposit. According to the results of our studies including host rock type, mineralogy, mineralization control structures, salinity and temperature it can be considered that the mineralization of zinc and lead are the mining region of Gardeneh-Shir deposits in the category of MVT type deposits</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">منطقه معدنی روی-سرب گردنه‌شیر در جنوب باختری اردستان در کربنات‌های سازند شتری به سن تریاس میانی که بر روی سازند نایبند به سن تریاس بالایی رانده شده است تشکیل گردیده. کانه‌زائی در این کانسارها به صورت رگه-رگچه‌ای، برشی و پرکننده حفرات کارستی بوده که با دگرسانی‌های دولومیتی و سیلیسی همراهی می-گردد. کنترل کننده کانه‌زائی این منطقه معدنی گسل‌های نرمال با مولفه امتداد لغز و گسل‌های امتداد لغز با مولفه نرمال قطع کننده گسل‌های راندگی می‌باشد. نتایج مطالعات میان‌بارهای سیال کانی‌های کوارتز و دولومیت مرتبط با کانه‌زائی در منطقه معدنی گردنه‌شیر نشان از سیال کانه‌ساز با شوری معادل 6/18-2/23 درصد وزنی نمک طعام، دامنه دمایی همگن شدن بین C° 91-162 و چگالی g/cm³ 056/1-09/1 دارد. نتایج آنالیز دستگاهی EPMA و مقایسه نسبت‌های عنصری Zn/Cd (879 درصد) در کانی اسفالریت نیز تاییدی بر پایین بوده دمای تشکیل این کانی‌ها در محدوده دمای کانسارهای نوع MVT می‌باشد. با توجه به نتایج مطالعات صورت گرفته و بر اساس نوع سنگ میزبان، کانی‌شناسی، ساختارهای کنترل کننده کانه‌زائی، شوری و دمای میان‌بارهای سیال و مقایسه آنها با ویژگی‌های تیپ‌های کانساری سرب و روی با میزبان رسوبی می‌توان کانه‌زائی روی و سرب در منطقه معدنی گردنه‌شیر را در رده کانسارهای تیپ MVT در نظر گرفت.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کانه زائی سرب-روی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساختارهای راندگی و نرمال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تیپ MVT</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گردنه‌شیر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایران مرکزی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
