<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Geochemistry, Mineralogy, and Genesis of Darbe Behesht Iron- Copper deposit, Dehaj-Sardoiye subzone, Kerman province, Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>زمین‌شیمی، کانی‌شناسی و زایش کانسار آهن- مس درب بهشت، زیرپهنه دهج ـ ساردوئیه، کرمان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15229</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.15229</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>قدرت‌اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>رستمی پایدار</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، واحد اهواز، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8406-6688</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منصور</FirstName>
					<LastName>عادل پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;
Darbe Behesht Iron- copper deposit is located in the Dehaj-Sardoiye subzone of Uromieh-Dokhtar Magmatic Arc (UDMA) in Kerman region. The UDMA zone is often composed of calc-alkaline intrusive and volcanic rocks and associated pyroclastic materials (Alimohammadi et al., 2015). Tectonic features of this volcano-plutonic belt discussed by many authors (eg., Shahabpour, 2005 and 2007). Most of the copper deposits are located in the southern part of the arc, known as the Dehaj-Sarduiyeh arc or the Kerman copper belt (Mirzababaei et al., 2011 and 2016; Shafiei et al., 2009). This study investigates the geochemistry, tectonic position of volcanic rocks containing Eocene Fe-Cu mineralization, paragenesis, and alteration. So we focus to the field observations, lithology and ore characterization of Darbe Behesht as a prominent example of the IOCG deposits in the southern part of the Dehaj-Sardoiye Belt in Iran.
 
 
&lt;strong&gt;Methodology&lt;/strong&gt;
During field surveys, geological and structural framework of the area were reviewed as well as the relationship between mineralization and intrusive rocks. The samples were collected from the study area focusing on identifying some characteristics of the host rock and ore textures (13 thin sections and 12 polished sections). Ten samples were analyzed for major elements using x-ray fluorescence (XRF) in the Zar-Azma Laboratory, Mashhad, Iran. Ten samples were sent to the WestLab, Australian Laboratory for trace and rare earth elements (REE) analysis using Inductively- Coupled Plasma-Mass spectrometry (ICP-MS).
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Results and Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;
The area is covered by Eocene volcanic rocks composed mainly of andesite, trachy-andesite, basalt and pyroclastic rocks (various types of tuffs and agglomerate). Based on major, trace and REE elements, these rocks are very similar to calc-alkaline lava with metaluminous to peraluminous nature. Enrichment of LILE (Such as K, U, Sr, Rb, Th, Pb and Ba) and LREE relative to HFSE (Such as Zr, Y, Ti and Nb) and HREE, high ratios of K&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O/Rb and FeO/Mg reveal that the rocks under study were originated in an active continental margin subduction-related tectonic setting. Volcanic rocks affected by hydrothermal fluids which lead to the occurrence of propylitic alteration, silicification with skarn alteration. propylitic alteration comprises dominant alteration in the area and is characterized by epidote, chlorite and calcite mineral assemblages. Silicification is mainly cropped out in both adjacent to mineralized veins, and to a lesser amount, as pervasive silica. Argillic alteration is locally present within the surface outcrops. Mineralization is mainly controlled by a system of extensional faults and joints. In most cases, mineralization is hosted by pyroclastic units (especially agglomerate) or in the contact between agglomerate and andesitic rocks. The presence of granodiorite intrusive masses in the area containing large amounts of hydrous mafic minerals (including amphibole and less biotite) and the presence of skarn zone produced by magmatic fluids indicate that the mineralization event related to the injection of granodiorite intrusive into country rocks. Magnetite and chalcopyrite are the main ore minerals. Secondary minerals from weathering are goethite, hematite, limonite, malachite and azurite. The ore textures and structures are open space-filling, disseminated, vein-veinlet and replacement. Fluid fluxes into faults, fractures, and weaknesses of the rock units have caused ore mineralization in the specified trends as same as normal faults systems.
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;
According to the tectonic setting, geochemical study, and the extensional fault mechanisms which are lucid together extensional back-arc basin in the Dehaj-Sardoiye subzone within UDMA subduction zone. Two important stages could be separated for mineralization. The first one is the hypogene mineralization phase and the other one is the supergene phase. The first stage is accompanied by the generation of magnetite in volcanic and pyroclastic rocks and second ones related to reduction fluids that caused copper mineralization. Based on geology, mineralization, geochemistry data and the presence of skarn, mineralization mechanism of the Darbe Behesht area is comparable with the North Semnan deposits and we can be classified as a proximal subclass of calc-alkaline type of IOCG deposits, eg. skarn. Detailed studies including the fluid inclusion, electron microprobe, and stable isotopic investigations can be further applied to examine the type of mineralization in the Darbe Behesht area.
 
 &lt;strong&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/strong&gt;
The authors are grateful to the Journal of Advanced Applied Geology reviewers and editor are also thanked for their constructive suggestions on the manuscript.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA"> کانسار آهن-مس درب بهشت در زیرپهنه دهج- ساردوئیه از کمان ماگمایی ارومیه-دختر در ناحیه کرمان واقع شده است. سنگ­های میزبان ­­کانسار درب بهشت به سن ائوسن، شامل تناوبی از­گدازه­ها (آندزیت، تراکی­آندریت، تراکی‌آندزیت-بازالت و بازالت) و مواد ­آذرآواری (انواع توف وآگلومرا) هستند. این سنگ­ها، بر اساس داده‌های زمین‌شیمیایی عناصر اصلی، کمیاب و عناصر نادر خاکی (REE)، شباهت زیادی به­گدازه­های کالک­آلکالن دارند. تمامی نمونه­ها دارای ماهیت متاآلومین تا پرآلومین هستند. غنی­شدگی عناصر ­لیتوفیل با شعاع ­یونی بالا (LILE) (Rb, Sr, K, U, Th، Pb و Ba) و LREE نسبت به عناصر با میدان پایداری بالا (HFSE) (Zr، Y، Ti و Nb) و HREE و نسبت­های بالای­K&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O/Rb  وFeO/MgO  نشان‌دهنده پیدایش این سنگ­های آذرین در پهنه زمین‌ساختی وابسته به فرورانش حاشیه فعال قاره­ای است. سنگ­های­ آتشفشانی منطقه­ درب بهشت تحت تأثیر محلول­های گرمابی قرار­گرفته و دگرسان شده­اند، دگرسانی اسکارنی، اپیدوتی‌ و سیلیسی مهمترین نوع دگرسانی می­باشند. کانی­سازی آهن و مس در اثر عملکرد سیالات­گرمابی­ که در امتداد­ گسل­ها در­ حرکت بوده ایجاد شده است. ساخت و بافت ماده معدنی به صورت پرکننده فضای خالی، دانه‌پراکنده، رگه-رگچه‌ای و جانشینی است. محیط زمین­ساختی کانسار درب بهشت با توجه به بررسی‌های زمین‌شیمیایی صورت گرفته یک محیط کششی است که همزمان با رخداد فرورانش در پشت کمان زیرپهنه دهج-ساردوئیه تشکیل شده است. دو فاز مهم برای رخداد کانه‌زایی در این کانسار قابل جدایش است. فاز اول شامل فرآیندهایی است که سبب تشکیل مگنتیت در سنگ‌های آتشفشانی و آذرآواری شده و فاز دوم مربوط به ورود سیالات احیایی است که کانه‌زایی مس را به­ وجود آورده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زمین‌شیمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کانی‌شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آهن- مس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درب بهشت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کرمان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
