<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The concentration and health risk assessment of potentially toxic elements in agricultural soils of the Aleshtar plain, Lorestan province.</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی غلظت و ارزیابی ریسک سلامتی عناصر بالقوه سمّی در خاکهای کشاورزی دشت الشتر، استان لرستان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15079</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.29590.1988</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>گیتی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرقانی تهرانی</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>شیخی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of the present study was to assess the health risk imposed by toxic metals present in agricultural soils of the Aleshtar plain. The average concentration of Cd, As, Sb, Zn, Ni, Fe, Mn, Cr, Ag, Co, Th and U in the studied samples were higher than corresponding values in world average soils. Based on geochemical indices calculations, the samples are highly polluted by Ag, Sb, As and Ni. Health risk assessment indicates that the hazard quotient for As via ingestion for children is higher than 1; therefore, there were adverse non-carcinogenic health effects of arsenic for this age group. The results showed that carcinogenic risk imposed by arsenic via ingestion for both adult and children age groups. Cr is carcinogenic for children via dermal contact and ingestion; whereas it is carcinogenic for adults through ingestion. The intake of Ni via ingestion by adults and via dermal contact by children would be associated with carcinogenic risk. The results indicated that Cd is carcinogenic for children through the ingestion route. The obtained results in this study show that agricultural activity has considerably increased the concentration of As, Cr, Ni and Sb in the Aleshtar agricultural soils. Regarding the probable negative effects of metal accumulation on public health status, the management of agricultural practice in the study area is of crucial importance.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این تحقیق، بررسی ریسک سلامتی عناصر سمّی در خاک‌های کشاورزی دشت الشتر می‌باشد. میانگین غلظت کادمیم، آرسنیک، آنتیموان، روی، نیکل، آهن، منگنز، کروم، نقره، کبالت، توریم، اورانیم در نمونه‌ها، از غلظت متناظر آنها در خاک‌های جهانی میانگین بالاتر است. محاسبه ضرایب ژئوشیمیایی نشان‌‌دهنده‌ آلودگی قابل توجه نمونه‌ها به نقره، آنتیموان، آرسنیک و نیکل است. ارزیابی ریسک سلامتی نشان می‌دهد که مقدار ضریب ریسک آرسنیک از طریق مسیر بلع برای خردسالان بالاتر از یک می‌باشد، که نشانگر احتمال رخداد اثرات نامطلوب غیرسرطانی مرتبط با آرسنیک برای خردسالان در منطقه است. برای عنصر آرسنیک، ریسک سرطانزایی در کودکان و بزرگسالان از طریق مسیر بلع وجود دارد. عنصر کروم، از طریق مسیر تماس پوستی برای خردسالان و از طریق مسیر بلع برای بزرگسالان و خردسالان دارای ریسک سرطانزایی است. دریافت عنصر نیکل از طریق بلع برای بزرگسالان و از طریق تماس پوستی برای خردسالان با ریسک سرطان‌زایی همراه است. کادمیم از طریق بلع برای خردسالان دارای ریسک سرطانزایی است. بر اساس نتایج به دست آمده، فعالیت‌ کشاورزی، تأثیر قابل‌توجهی در تجمع آرسنیک، کروم، نیکل و آنتیموان در خاک‌های دشت الشتر داشته است و با توجه به خطرات احتمالی تجمع این عناصر برای سلامت جامعه انسانی، مدیریت کشاورزی در این منطقه ضروری است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عناصر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خطر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خاک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الشتر</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
