<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Mineralogy, texture and structure, and formation stages of the Golijeh intermediate-sulfidation epithermal deposit in Tarom subzone of western Alborz – Azerbaijan zone</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کانی‌شناسی، ساخت و بافت، و مراحل تشکیل کانسار اپی‌ترمال سولفیداسیون حدواسط گلیجه در زیرپهنه طارم از پهنه البرز غربی- آذربایجان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>9</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>20</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14227</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2018.24286.1802</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>خدابنده‌لو</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد گروه زمین‌شناسی اقتصادی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>قادری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زمین‌شناسی اقتصادی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>راستاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زمین‌شناسی اقتصادی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The Golijeh base metal - silver deposit in northeast Zanjan is located in the Tarom subzone of western Alborz – Azerbaijan structural zone. Lithologic units in the area are volcanic-pyroclastic rocks of Eocene age with a composition of crystalline tuff, lithic tuff, volcanic breccia and andesitic lavas of the Kordkand member of Karaj Formation. The subvolcanic body of gabbro-diorite porphyry with a post-Eocene age has intruded these units. Mineralization has occurred in the form of vein-veinlets in the andesitic unit and, to a lesser extent, in the pyroclastic units. The main ore minerals include chalcopyrite, pyrite, galena, and iron-poor sphalerite together with lesser amounts of Ag-bearing tetrahedrite- tennantite. The alteration at Golijeh can be distinguished as two groups of mineralization-related alteration (silica-sulfide, phyllic, silica-carbonate and carbonate-sulfide) and non-mineralization-related general alteration (propylitic and argillic). The major ore textures and structures are, respectively, vein-veinlet, brecciated, open space filling and replacement. The intrusion of the subvolcanic gabbro-diorite porphyry body and the occurrence of faults are the factors controlling mineralization in the area. Considering the main properties of mineralization at Golijeh including mineralogy, metal content, vein-veinlet shape and the occurred alteration, the Golijeh mineralization can be classified as an intermediate-sulfidation epithermal deposit.
 
 </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کانسار فلزات پایه- نقره گلیجه در شمال‌شرق زنجان در زیرپهنه طارم از پهنه البرز غربی- آذربایجان قرار دارد. واحدهای سنگ‌شناسی در محدوده، سنگ‌های آتشفشانی- آذرآواری با سن ائوسن و با ترکیب کریستال توف، لیتیک توف، برش ولکانیکی و گدازه‌های آندزیتی بخش کردکند سازند کرج هستند که توده نفوذی نیمه‌عمیق گابرودیوریت پورفیری با سن پس از ائوسن، این واحدها را قطع کرده است. کانه‌زایی به شکل رگه- رگچه‌ای در واحد آندزیتی و به مقدار کمتر در واحدهای پیروکلاستیک روی داده است. کانه‌های اصلی کانسنگ شامل کالکوپیریت، پیریت، گالن و اسفالریت فقیر از آهن همراه با مقادیر کمتری تتراهدریت- تنانتیت حاوی نقره هستند. دگرسانی در گلیجه را می‌توان در دو گروه دگرسانی‌های مرتبط با کانه‌زایی (دگرسانی‌های سیلیسی- سولفیدی، فیلیک، سیلیسی- کربناته و کربناته- سولفیدی) و دگرسانی‌های فراگیر غیرمرتبط با کانه‌زایی (دگرسانی‌های پروپیلیتیک و آرژیلیک) قرار داد. عمده‌ترین ساخت و بافت‌های مربوط به ماده معدنی به‌ترتیب شامل رگه- رگچه‌ای، برشی، پرکننده فضای خالی و جانشینی است. نفوذ توده نیمه‌عمیق گابرودیوریت پورفیری و رخداد گسل‌ها از عوامل کنترل‌کننده کانه‌زایی در این محدوده است. با توجه به ویژگی‌های اصلی کانه‌زایی گلیجه از جمله کانی‌شناسی، محتوای فلزی، شکل رگه- رگچه‌ای و دگرسانی‌های رخ‌داده، می‌توان آن را در رده کانسارهای تیپ اپی‌ترمال سولفیداسیون حدواسط قرار داد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کانی‌شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اپی‌ترمال سولفیداسیون حدواسط</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دگرسانی گرمابی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زیرپهنه طارم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فلزات پایه- نقره</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_14227_64cad40de75aacf65800c822836b4d94.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
