<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of sedimentary environment and reservoir quality of the Burgan Formation in one of the oil fields of Abadan plain</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی محیط رسوبی و کیفیت مخزنی سازند بورگان در یکی از میادین نفتی ناحیه دشت آبادان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15490</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.31561.2055</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آراد</FirstName>
					<LastName>کیانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مهندسی نفت دانشگاه سمنان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>صابری</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه اکتشاف نفت، دانشکده مهندسی نفت</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهمن</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارع نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مهندسی شیمی، نفت و گاز دانشگاه سمنان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهام</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسدی مهماندوستی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده علوم زمین دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نسیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>شرکت متن</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The Kazhdumi Formation is a Middle Cretaceous whose base in the Abadan plain is composed of sandstone, shale and limestone, and is equivalent to the Burgan Formation in Arab countries. In this study, we investigated the reservoir quality of one of the major oilfields of the Abadan plain using thin sections, core data such as hydrocarbon impregnation, porosity, permeability, and well logs. According to petrographic studies, 4 sedimentary microfacies and 5 lithofacies have been identified in the Burgan Formation deposited in the carbonate ramp to the Delta. Diagenesis processes include dissolution, fracture, cementation, dolomitization, condensation, glaconite, hematite and pyrite occurring in three marine, meteoric and burial environments. Among the diagenesis processes, dissolution and fracture have had a special role in enhancing reservoir quality, and cementation, dolomitization and compaction have been the most important determinants of reservoir quality studied. Core studies and wellbore diagrams show that the sandstone and carbonate facies have the highest and the lowest amount of porosity, permeability and hydrocarbon impregnation, respectively, and the Chilean facies is in terms of reservoir quality between these two facies. Quartz Arenite rock facies was identified as the main reservoir zone in the studied oil field.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سازند کژدمی به سن کرتاسه میانی می باشد که قاعده آن در ناحیه دشت آبادان دارای ترکیب سنگ شناسی ماسه سنگ، شیل و سنگ آهک و معادل سازند بورگان در کشورهای عربی است. با توجه به مطالعات پتروگرافی 4 ریزرخساره رسوبی و 5 رخساره سنگی در سازند بورگان شناسایی شد که در محیط رمپ کربناتی به سمت دلتا نهشته شده است. از جمله فرآیندهای دیاژنزی می توان به انحلال، شکستگی، سیمانی شدن، دولومیتی شدن، تراکم، گلاکونیتی شدن، هماتیتی شدن و پیریتی شدن اشاره کرد که در سه محیط دریایی، متئوریک و تدفینی به وقوع پیوسته اند. از میان فرآیندهای دیاژنزی انحلال و شکستگی نقش ویژه ای در افزایش کیفیت مخزنی داشته اند و سیمانی شدن، دولومیتی شدن و تراکم مهمترین عوامل کاهش کیفیت مخزنی سازند مورد مطالعه بوده اند. مطالعات مغزه و نمودارهای چاه پیمایی نشان می دهند که رخساره ماسه سنگی و کربناتی به ترتیب بیشترین و کمترین مقدار تخلخل، تراوایی و آغشتگی به هیدروکربور را داشته اند و رخساره شیلی از لحاظ کیفیت مخزنی در میان این دو رخساره قرار گرفته است. رخساره سنگی کوارتز آرنایت به عنوان زون اصلی مخزنی در میدان نفتی مورد مطالعه شناسایی شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازند کژدمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کمربندهای رخساره ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرآیندهای دیاژنزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پتروگرافی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زاگرس</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
