<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Employing support vector machine, statistical and geostatistical methods ‎to design the detailed exploration grid of Khomein-Robat Pb-Zn deposit</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بکارگیری روش‌های ماشین بردار پشتیبان، آمار کلاسیک و زمین آماری به منظور ‏طراحی شبکه اکتشاف تفصیلی کانسار سرب و روی رباط خمین ‏</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15076</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.29369.1977</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه صنعتی اراک</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In current research, primary classification of Khomein-Robat-Arregijeh Pb-Zn deposit has been ‎carried out first, using support vector machine (SVM) method. To achieve this goal, 548 ‎available multivariate data point comprising 337 induced polarization (IP) and resistivity (Rs) ‎geophysical data, 211 rock type and Pb-Zn assay data from outcrops, trenches and test pits, ‎three variables IP, Rs and rock type were considered as predictive variables as well as Pb-Zn ‎assay as target variable. Afterward through designing and training an SVM model, on the basis ‎of three cut off grade 1.5, 2 and 3 percent, the deposit was classified to two classes: high-grade ‎zone or anomaly (above the cut off grade) and low-grade zone or background (lower than cut ‎off grade). Then exploratory boreholes scattered in the region, were drilled in the locations ‎known as high-grade zone as well as anomalies of the geophysical pseudo-sections. In the next, ‎using all exploration information, designing the detailed exploration grid of the deposit was ‎performed through statistical and geostatistical methods. A rectangular grid with dimensions of ‎‎36*35m was obtained by analytical method based on classical statistics. Employing geostatistical ‎method and 3-D variography for Pb-Zn assays of the boreholes using SGEMS software ‎concluded a square grid with dimensions of 55*55m. According to the results of the research, ‎semi-deep exploration activities are suggested at the nodes of the new exploration grid, designed ‎by geostatistical method due to more accuracy of the method.‎</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در پژوهش حاضر طبقه‌بندی اولیه کانسار اره گیجه رباط خمین توسط روش ماشین بردار پشتیبان انجام شد. برای این منظور از 548 داده چندمتغیره شامل ‏‏337 داده ژئوفیزیکی ‏Ip‏ و ‏Rs، 211 داده نوع‎‌‎سنگ و عیارسنجی مجموع سرب و روی نمونه‎‌‎های دستی، ترانشه‌ها و چاهک ها، سه متغیر ‏Ip، ‏Rs‏ و ‏نوع‌سنگ به‌عنوان متغیرهای پیش‌بین و عیار مجموع سرب و روی، به‌عنوان متغیر هدف انتخاب شد. سپس طبقه‌بندی توده کانسار براساس سه عیار حد ‏مجموع سرب و روی 5/1، 2 و 3 درصد، به دو طبقه بی‌هنجاری و زمینه صورت گرفت. در ادامه در موقعیت‌های شناخته شده به عنوان بی هنجاری، گمانه های ‏اکتشافی بطور پراکنده در سطح محدوده، حفاری شد. در مرحله بعد طراحی شبکه اکتشاف تفصیلی با دو روش آمار کلاسیک و زمین آماری انجام شد که با ‏روش تحلیلی شبکه مستطیلی به ابعاد 35×36 متر به دست آمد. بکارگیری روش زمین‌آماری داده های عیارسنجی مجموع سرب و روی گمانه ها با نرم افزار ‏SGeMS، شبکه اکتشاف مربعی شکلی به ابعاد 55×55 متر را نتیجه داد. براساس نتایج پژوهش، در مرحله بعد حفر کارهای اکتشافی نیمه عمیق در موقعیت ‏گره های شبکه اکتشافی طراحی شده با روش زمین آماری به واسطه دقت بیشتر این روش، پیشنهاد می شود.‏</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کانسار سرب و روی رباط خمین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ماشین بردار پشتیبان ‏‎(SVM)‎</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طراحی شبکه اکتشاف</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش کلاسیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش زمین آماری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
