<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Mineralization, structure and texture and genesis of Halab gold occurrence, southwest of Dandy, Zanjan Province</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کانه زایی، ساخت و بافت و ژنز رخداد معدنی طلای حلب، جنوب باختر دندی، استان زنجان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15343</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.29775.1995</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رحیمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>نفیسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>کوهستانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیات علمی دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3031-9042</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میر علی اصغر</FirstName>
					<LastName>مختاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیأت علمی گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مارتیا</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>سازمان زمین شناسی سوئد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Mineralization in the Halab occurrence occurs as Au-bearing silicified-sulfidic zone within Precambrian mafic schist sequence. Ore minerals include arsenopyrite, sphalerite, pyrite, chalcopyrite, pyrrhotite and gold, and quartz, actinolite, clinopyroxene, and chlorite are present as gangue minerals at Halab. The ore minerals show banded, laminated, disseminated, veinlet, brecciated, vug infill, colloform, replacement, and relict textures. Alteration are consist of actinolitization, silicification, and chloritization. Four stages of mineralization can be distinguished at Halab. Gold mineralization is related to hydrothermal stage (stage 3) accompanied with arsenopyrite. Field and analytical results reveal that primary mineralization at Halab occurs as sub-economic stratiform and startabound, laminated and disseminated Zn‒Cu mineralization coeval with the deposition of the volcano-sedimentary units which that overprinted during later metamorphic-deformation process. This primary Zn‒Cu mineralization is comparable with metamorphosed and deformed laminated and disseminated parts of the Besshi type massive sulfide deposits. Gold mineralization is related to late hydrothermal phase which is thought to be result of Miocene magmatism in the Takab–Takht-e-Soleyman–Angouran zone. Investigation of alteration zones within Precambrian metamorphosed units which have spatial relationship with Miocene magmatism, is, therefore, of major importance in exploration of this type of gold mineralization at the Takab–Takht-e-Soleyman–Angouran zone.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کانه‌زایی در رخداد معدنی حلب به‌صورت یک پهنه سیلیسی- سولفیدی طلادار درون توالی شیست‌های مافیک پرکامبرین رخ داده است. آرسنوپیریت، اسفالریت، پیریت، کالکوپیریت، پیروتیت و طلا، کانی‌های معدنی و کوارتز، اکتینولیت، کلینوپیروکسن و کلریت، کانی‌های باطله در حلب هستند. بافت‌ کانسنگ شامل نواری، &lt;br /&gt; لامینه‌ای، دانه‌پراکنده، رگچه‌ای، بِرشی، شکافه پُرکن، گل‌کلمی، جانشینی و بازماندی است. دگرسانی‌ها شامل اکتینولیتی‌، سیلیسی‌ و کلریتی‌شدن است. چهار مرحله کانه‌زایی در حلب قابل تفکیک است. کانه‌زایی طلا مربوط به مرحله گرمابی (مرحله سوم) هم‌‌زمان با تشکیل آرسنوپیریت می‌باشد. نتایج مطالعات صحرایی و آزمایشگاهی نشان می‌دهد کانه‌زایی در حلب ابتدا به‌صورت کانه‌زایی غیراقتصادی روی- مس با ژئومتری نواری- لامینه‌ای، دانه‌پراکنده و چینه‌سان-چینه‌کران هم‌زمان با فعالیت‌های آتشفشانی- رسوبی تشکیل شده است که طی فرایندهای دگرگونی-دگرشکلی بعدی، رونقش شده است. مقایسه ویژگی‌های این کانه‌زایی اولیه با انواع کانسارهای روی- مس نشان می‌دهد این کانه‌زایی معادل دگرگون- دگرشکل‌شده بخش‌های لایه‌ای و افشان کانسارهای سولفید توده‌ای آتشفشان‌زاد نوع بشی است. کانه-زایی طلا در ارتباط با یک فاز گرمابی تأخیری در ارتباط با نفوذ فازهای ماگمایی میوسن در پهنه تکاب-تخت‌سلیمان-انگوران می‌باشد. بررسی پهنه‌های دگرسانی در واحدهای دگرگونه پرکامبرین که ارتباط فضایی نزدیکی با فازهای ماگمایی میوسن دارند، کاربرد فراوانی در اکتشاف این تیپ از &lt;br /&gt; کانه‌زایی‌های طلا در پهنه کانه‌دار تکاب-تخت‌سلیمان-انگوران دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کانه‌زایی طلا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تکاب- تخت‌سلیمان- انگوران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنندج- سیرجان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حلب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنجان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
