<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Morphotectonic analysis of Aghajari fault</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل ریخت زمین ساختی گسل آغاجاری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15081</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.29656.1991</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بابک</FirstName>
					<LastName>سامانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>چرچی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی گروه زمین شناسی دانشکده علوم دانشگاه  شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شیما</FirstName>
					<LastName>ناظمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده علوم زمین دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The Geomorphic indices including mountain front sinuosity (Smf), valley floor width to valley height ratio (Vf), basin shape index (Bs), and stream length–gradient index (SL) have been calculated for determination of various tectonic activities along the Aghajari fault. The mountain front sinuosity (Smf) index was calculated about 1.007 to 1.58 respectively in the active and inactive parts of the Aghajari fault. The basin shape (Bs) index has been calculated between 7.83 for the very active parts and, 1.18 for the low active parts of the fault. The amounts of valley floor width to valley height ratio (Vf) index show the range between 0.21 to 5.29 in the active parts with V shape valley morphology and inactive parts with U shape valley morphology respectively. The stream length–gradient (SL) index was calculated between 1414.58 in the high active tectonic and 385.14 in the low active tectonic parts of the study area. With application of the GIS techniques and the overlaying the Smf, Bs, Vf and SL data layers the area was divided into three different tectonic zones and quantitative active tectonic zoning map was prepared for the study area. In this active tectonic map, classes 1 to 3 respectively show the highest to lowest tectonic activity along the Aghajari fault. Results reveal that the Aghajari fault in the central and southeastern parts except for some small areas shows the medium tectonic activity and in the northwestern parts shows the low tectonic activity manner.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">برای تشخیص و ارزیابی فعالیت‌های تکتونیکی گسل آغاجاری، شاخص‌های مورفوتکتونیکی پیچ وخم پیشانی کوهستا‌ن (Smf)، شکل حوضه(Bs) نسبت پهنای کف دره به ارتفاع دره (Vf)، و گرادیان–طول رودخانه (SL) محاسبه گردید. مقدار شاخصSmf از 007/1 در مناطق بسیار فعال تا 58/1 در مناطق با فعالیت متوسط تکتونیکی متغیر می‌باشد. مقدار شاخص Bs از 83/7 در مناطق بسیارفعال منطقه تا مقدار 18/1 در مناطق با فعالیت تکتونیکی کم متغیر می‌باشد. مقدار شاخص Vfاز 21/0 در مناطق فعال با دره های V شکل تا 29/5 در مناطق غیرفعال با دره‌های U مانند تغییر می کند. شاخص SL از 58/1414 در مناطق بسیارفعال منطقه تا مقدار14/385 در مناطق با فعالیت تکتونیکی کم متغیر است. با استفاده از تکنیک‌های سنجش از دور و رویهم‌اندازی (overlay) لایه‌های‌ اطلاعاتی Smf، Bs ، Vf و SL منطقه به سه ناحیه تکتونیکی رده‌بندی شد و نقشه پهنه‌بندی تکتونیک فعال بصورت کمی برای منطقه تهیه گردید. در این نقشه رده‌های 1 تا 3 به ترتیب نشانگر بیشترین تا کمترین فعالیت‌های تکتونیکی میباشند. نتایج نشان میدهد که گسل آغاجاری در بخش‌های مرکزی و جنوب شرقی به جز چند محدوده کوچک دارای فعالیت با رده تکتونیکی متوسط بوده و در بخش های شمال غربی دارای فعالیت با رده تکتونیکی پایین میباشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گسل آغاجاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فروافتادگی دزفول</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نو زمین ساخت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تکتونیک جنبا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص‌های مورفوتکتونیکی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
