<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Enrichment, origin, and health risks of heavy metals in rice farms, case study: Ahwaz and Bavi counties</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>غنی شدگی، منشا، و خطر سلامتی فلزات سنگین در مزارع برنج: مطالعه موردی شهرستانهای اهواز و باوی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>75</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>84</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14873</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28395.1935</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>راست منش</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسنا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>زراسوندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9821-6747</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of this study is to investigate heavy metal concentrations in the Paddy farms of Ahwaz and Bavi counties and determine anthropogenic or natural sources of heavy metals, using statistical methods. 14 farms were chosen in Ahwaz and Bavi counties.After preparing samples, ICP-MS and ICP-OES devices were used to determine the concentration of heavy metals in soil and rice samples, respectively. Average concentration of Ag, As, Cd and Sb is higher than that of standard crust. Based on average environmental risk assessment indices, the highest contamination was related to Ag, As, Cd and Sb, which indicates the anthropogenic input to agricultural soil such as using pesticides and chemical fertilizers in the study area. Cr, Fe, Pb, Ni, and V have natural source; Sb and Cd anthropogenic source; As and Mo both anthropogenic and natural sources; and Ag anthropogenic source. Health risk due to As and Pb is probable through rice consumption. The highest mean concentration of metals in the rice samples was measured for Pb and the lowest for V. Pb concentration in the rice samples was higher than, and As concentration is close to the WHO standard. Non-carcinogenic risk for adults and children due to As and Pb is medium.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از این مطالعه ارزیابی غلظت فلزات سنگین در خاک و برنج مزارع شهرستان‌های اهواز و باوی و شناسایی منابع فلزات سنگین است. 14 نمونه خاک و برنج جمع آوری شد. پس از آماده سازی، به منظور تعیین غلظت فلزات سنگین در نمونه‌های خاک و برنج به ترتیب از دستگاه‌هایICP-MS وICP-OES استفاده شد. میانگین غلظت نقره، آرسنیک، کادمیم و آنتیموان از استاندارد پوسته بالایی بیشتر است. براساس میانگین شاخص‌های ارزیابی ریسک زیست محیطی بیشترین آلودگی مربوط به نقره، آرسنیک، کادمیم و آنتیموان است که بیانگر ورودی‌های انسانزاد به خاک کشاورزی همچون استفاده از کود‌های شیمیایی و آفت‌کش‌ها در منطقه مورد مطالعه، می‌باشد. فلزات کروم، آهن، سرب، نیکل و وانادیم دارای منشا طبیعی، آنتیموان و کادمیم دارای منشا انسانزاد، آرسنیک و مولیبدن هم دارای منشا طبیعی و انسانی می‌باشند و نقره دارای منشا انسانزاد است.. احتمال خطر سلامتی ناشی از سرب و آرسنیک با مصرف برنج در منطقه وجود دارد. بیشترین میانگین غلظت فلزات در نمونه‌های برنج مربوط به سرب و کمترین مربوط به وانادیم است. سرب نمونه‌های برنج از استاندارد WHO مقادیر بیشتری ‌را نشان داد و آرسنیک نیز نزدیک به مقدار استاندارد WHOاست. میزان خطر غیرسرطانی در بزرگسالان و کودکان برای آرسنیک و سرب خطر متوسط است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برنج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فلزات سنگین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضریب غنی شدگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اهواز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">باوی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_14873_b46f45bb7eb7c2d4ec3e7fc8aa0e1ded.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
