<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The efficiency of Data-Driven Models for Months ahead Groundwater Level Forecasting Using a Hybrid Gamma Test and Genetic Algorithm Model</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی عملکرد مدل های داده مبنا در شبیه سازی گام‌های مختلف زمانی سطح آب زیرزمینی با استفاده از روش تلفیقی آزمون گاما و الگوریتم ژنتیک</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>62</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>72</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14233</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.25611.1843</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرعربی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی معدنی و آب، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>ناصری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>نخعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه خوارزمی تهران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4823-5197</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرشاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>علیجانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی- دانشکده علوم زمین - دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In order to implement sustainable groundwater resources management, it is necessary to model the behavior of groundwater level. Groundwater is a nonlinear and complex system which Data-driven models can be modeled this system without approximation and simplification. This study evaluates the performances of data-driven models (Support Vector Regression (SVR) and Artificial Neural Network (ANN)) for forecasting groundwater levels of Hashtgerd plain at 1, 2 and 3 months ahead. One of the most important steps in constructing data-driven models is determining the optimal combination of input variables. In this paper, the optimal composition was determined using the hybrid of gamma test and genetic algorithm, also the optimal length of input composition in teaching period was determined using the M-test method. The results of this study showed that the models for 1 month ahead performed better than for 2 and 3 months ahead forecasts and the accuracy of the models decreased as months ahead increased. The Developed Discrepancy Ratio (DDR) was applied to evaluate the efficiency of models. The results showed that the ANFIS model had the best performance for one month ahead groundwater level forecasting. Also, the results demonstrated that the ANFIS and MLP models were able to provide better performance in groundwater levels forecasting for a shorter-time period (e.g., 1 month ahead). The performance of the SVR model for a longer-time period (e.g., 3 month ahead) was superior to the MLP and ANFIS models.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به منظور مدیریت پایدار منابع آب زیرزمینی، تعیین رفتار سطح آب زیرزمینی ضروری است. نوسانات سطح آب زیرزمینی فرآیندی غیرخطی و پیچیده است که مدل-های هوش محاسباتی داده مبنا قادر هستند بدون تقریب و ساده‌سازی به مدل‌سازی آن بپردازند. در این مطالعه میزان دقت و کارایی هر یک از مدل‌های داده مبنا هوش مصنوعی پرسپترون چند لایه (MLP)، استنتاجی فازی عصبی (ANFIS) و رگرسیون بردار پشتیبان(SVR) در شبیه‌سازی سه افق زمانی پیش‌رو (t+2, t+1 و t+3) سطح آب زیرزمینی دشت هشتگرد مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفت. در این راستا از قابلیت‌های روش آزمون گاما و تلفیق آن با الگوریتم ژنتیک (GA-GT) بمنظور انتخاب ترکیب ورودی بهینه و نیز روش M-Test در تعیین طول بهینه داده‌های آموزش مدل استفاده شد. نتایج مشخص کرد که دقت مدل‌های داده مبنا در شبیه سازی افق زمانیt+1 سطح آب زیرزمینی بیشتر از افق زمانی t+2 و t+3 است. بمنظور تعیین میزان عملکرد و کارایی مدل‌ها، نتایج براساس شاخص DDR مورد تحلیل قرار گرفت که محاسبات نشان داد مدل ANFIS در شبیه‌سازی افق زمانی اول بهترین عملکرد و کارایی را داشته است. همچنین استنباط شد که مدل MLP و ANFIS در شبیه‌سازی افق‌های ماهانه نزدیک‌تر و SVR در افق‌های ماهانه دور‌تر کاربرد بهتری دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سطح آب زیرزمینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گاما تست</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شبکه عصبی مصنوعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رگرسیون بردار پشتیبان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوریتم ژنتیک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_14233_150865426b81769297d36a12ae512b67.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
