<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation of Makran seismicity in southeast Iran, before and after 2011 Dalbandin earthquake of Pakistan with Mw: 7.2</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی لرزه خیزی مکران در جنوب شرق ایران قبل و پس از زمین لرزه 2011 دالبندین پاکستان با بزرگی 7.2</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15493</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.30494.2024</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>آق آتابای</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه گلستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرشته</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه گلستان، گرگان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>عظیم محسنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه آمار، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه گلستان، گرگان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>From 2011 to 2013, several major earthquakes occurred in the Makran Seismotectonic zone (Iran and Pakistan). The low event interval of these earthquakes in a tectonic zone may indicate their interaction. In this paper, the interactions between 2011 Dalbandin earthquake of Pakistan, 2013 Saravan and Goharan earthquakes of Makran seismotectonic zone in SE Iran was investigated by calculating the Coulomb stress changes. Maps and cross sections of coseismic stress changes show that Saravan and Goharan earthquakes have occurred in the stress enhanced areas indicating the positive effect of Dalbandin earthquake on trigerring the mentioned events. In order to quantify the seismicity level changes, statistical parameters including b-value, seismicity rate and temporal changes of local standard deviation of gradient (lsd) were calculated over a 10 year period (5 years before and after the Dalbandin earthquake).The results show that the seismicity rate of Makran seismotectonic zone has significantly increased after this event. The temporal variation graph of lsd parameter also decreases at the time of the Dalbandin earthquake event, indicating an increase in seismicity rate in the region. In overall, the results indicate that the Dalbandin earthquake is the beginning of an active seismic period in the Makran subduction zone on which the peak of activity occurred in 2013 with two years delay.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در سالهای 2011 تا 2013 چند زمین‌لرزه بزرگ در ایالت لرزه‌زمین‌ساختی مکران (ایران و پاکستان) اتفاق افتاد. فاصله زمانی کم رویداد این زمین‌لرزه‌ها در یک زون زمین‌ساختی می‌تواند بیانگر درهم‌کنش آنها باشد. در این مقاله، درهم کنش زمین‌لرزه 2011 دالبندین پاکستان و زمین‌لرزه‌های 2013 سراوان و گوهران در مکران در جنوب شرق ایران، با محاسبه تغییر تنش کولمب مطالعه شد. نقشه‌ها و نیم‌رخ‌های تغییر تنش نشان می‌دهند که زمین‌لرزه‌های سراوان و گوهران در محدوده‌های افزایش تنش روی داده‌اند که حاکی از تاثیر مثبت زمین‌لرزه دالبندین بر تحریک حوادث مذکور می‌باشد. جهت کمی نمودن میزان تغییرات سطح لرزه‌خیزی، پارامترهای آماری شامل b-value، نرخ لرزه‌خیزی و تغییرات زمانی انحراف استاندارد موضعی (lsd) گرادیان پارامترهای لرزه‌ای در یک دوره 10 ساله (5 سال قبل و بعد از زمین‌لرزه دالبندین) محاسبه شد. نتایج نشان دادند که نرخ لرزه‌خیزی ایالت لرزه‌زمین‌ساختی مکران بعد از این حادثه بطور قابل توجهی افزایش یافته است. نمودار تغییرات زمانی پارامتر lsd نیز در زمان رویداد زمین‌لرزه دالبندین کاهش نشان می‌دهد که بیان‌گر افزایش نرخ لرزه‌خیزی در منطقه است. بیشترین میزان کاهش پارامتر lsd (افزایش سطح لرزه‌خیزی) دو سال پس از زمین‌لرزه دالبندین اتفاق افتاده است. در مجموع نتایج این تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که زمین لرزه دالبندین شروع یک دوره فعال لرزه‌خیزی در زون فرورانش مکران است که اوج فعالیت دوره فعال با تاخیر دو ساله در سال 2013 و رویداد زمین‌لرزه‌های بزرگ اتفاق افتاده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مکران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زمین‌لرزه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نرخ لرزه‌خیزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تغییر تنش کولمب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پارامتر آماری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
