<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation of cu vein of the Shurk and associated gossan zone (North West of Birjand) based on alteration, mineralization, geochemistry and fluid inclusion</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی مس رگه ای شورک و زون گوسان همراه (شمال غرب بیرجند) بر اساس دگرسانی، کانی سازی، زمین شیمی و سیالات درگیر</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>316</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>340</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15056</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.26285.1864</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>جاویدی مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریم پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم، گروه پژوهشی اکتشاف ذخایر معدنی شرق ایران، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آزاده</FirstName>
					<LastName>ملکزاده شفارودی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم، گروه پژوهشی اکتشاف ذخایر معدنی شرق ایران، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The Shurk area located in the west of Birjand city is a part of the Lut Block volcanic-plutonic belt. Preliminary prospecting in the area using ASTER satellite data processing in method of spectral angle mapper enhanced propylitic, argillic alteration and iron oxides. The area comprises outcrops of Eocene volcanics, which was intruded by subvolcanic intrusions with gabbro to diorite composition. The vein mineralization was formed in two stages, including: 1) quartz-pyrite-chalcocite-chalcopyrite-bornite-fahlore-sphalerite that are associated with argillic-silicified alteration and 2) quartz-chalcocite-sphalerite accompained with silicified-carbonate alteration. Primary fluid inclusions of quartz in paragnesis with minealization in the first and second stages of vein mineralization, have an average of homogenization temperatures 267°C and 215 °C respectively. Based on freezing studies, the average of final ice melting temperature (Tfmice) equals to 19.4 and 11.1 wt.% NaCl respectively. Mixing, dilution with meteoric water and boiling have been effective during the evolution of hydrothermal fluids and the formation of ore-bearing veins. Based on evidences such as structural control of mineralization, the type of alteration, simple mineralogy of ore and thermometric data, the Shurk deposit is similar to those of epithermal deposits. The presence of numerous Cu veins on a large scale indicates significant economic potential of area.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">محدوده شورک بخشی از پهنه آتشفشانی-نفوذی در بلوک لوت، شمال‌غرب‌ شهر بیرجند است. طی پی‌جویی اولیه در این منطقه توسط پردازش داده‌های ماهواره‌ای آستر به روش نقشه برداری زوایای طیفی، دگرسانی‌های پروپلیتیک، آرژیلیک و اکسیدهای آهن بارزسازی شدند. این گستره‌ شامل برونزدهایی از سنگ‌های آتشفشانی (با ترکیب آندزیتی تا ریولیتی) بوده که واحد‌های نیمه‌عمیق و عمیق با ترکیب گابرویی تا دیوریتی در آنها نفوذ نموده‌اند. کانی‌سازی رگه‌ای در دو مرحله شکل گرفته که شامل، 1. کوارتز-پیریت-کالکوسیت-کالکوپیریت-بورنیت±فاهلور±اسفالریت همراه با دگرسانی آرژیلیکی- سیلیسی و 2. کوارتز-کالکوسیت-گالن±اسفالریت همراه با دگرسانی سیلیسی-کربناتی می‌باشد. مطالعه سیالات درگیر اولیه در بلورهای کوارتز همزمان با مرحله اول و دوم کانی‌سازی رگه‌ای، متوسط دمای همگن شدن به ترتیب 267 و 215 درجه سانتی‌گراد را نشان می‌دهند. بر پایه مطالعات سرمایش، میانگین دمای ذوب آخرین قطعه یخ (Tfmice) در این دو مرحله به ترتیب برابر با 4/19 و 1/11 درصد وزنی نمک طعام است. اختلاط، رقیق شدگی توسط آب‌های جوی و جوشش طی تحول سیالات گرمابی و شکل-گیری رگه‌ها موثر بوده است. بر پایه شواهدی چون کنترل ساختاری کانی‌سازی، نوع دگرسانی، کانی‌شناسی ساده ذخیره و داده‌های دماسنجی، کانسار شورک مشابه کانسارهای اپی‌ترمال می‌باشد. حضور متعدد رگه‌های اپی‌ترمال مس در مقیاس وسیع نشان دهنده پتانسیل اقتصادی بالای این محدوده می‌باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کانی‌سازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیالات درگیر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اختلاط</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اپی‌ترمال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شورک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15056_b8b1645b2e69355c6959ebfd9fa33f01.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
