<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Optimum route selection for Pole Zal - Khorram Abad highway using GIS and environmental consideration</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مسیریابی بهینه آزادراه پل زال-خرم آباد با استفاده ازسنجش از دور و GIS و ملاحظات زیست محیطی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>284</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>299</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15058</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28145.1920</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کاظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>رنگزن</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه سنجش از دور و GIS، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید ساجدین</FirstName>
					<LastName>موسوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین‌شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز ، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2794-985X</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عظیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>صابری</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه سنجش از دور و GIS، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، اهواز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سهیلناز</FirstName>
					<LastName>درویشی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه سنجش از دور و GIS، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Highways are one of the most important of lifelines in society. On the other hand, road constructions have unfavorable effects on the environment in each region. In spite of abundant benefits, Pole Zal-Khorram Abad highway from southwestern Iran had various geohazards and environmental impacts on this area such as landslides, land use change, and decreasing the population of fauna and flora species. The optimum route selection is a complex multi criteria problem with conflicting objectives that need balancing. For the reason, the aim of this study was to find the optimum route based on environmental considerations. For this purpose, eight effective factors were selected, including slope angle, stratigraphy, proximity to streams, proximity to faults, land use, vegetative cover, elevation, as well as protected areas. Then, the analytic hierarchy process (AHP) and fuzzy systems were applied to standardize each effective factor using Expert Choice 11 software as engineering geological, environmental and economic viewpoint. The results showed that protected area, stratigraphy, vegetative cover, and land use were the most effective factors in recently highway route selection with a weight equal to 0.166, 0.165, 0.147, and 0.123, respectively. Afterward, the suggested route was selected by the combination of the factors based on relative weight in GIS. The selected road is 15 km shorter than existent highway. Also, the recent route has less geological hazards and negative environmental impacts. Therefore, it is recommended that this method, for decreasing environmental impacts, apply to constructed and constructing highways.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">آزادراه‌ها یکی از مهمترین شریانهای حیاتی جامعه بوده که نقش مهمی را در تخریب محیط‌زیست داشته و از معضلات اساسی در حفظ و تنوع زیستی هستند. آزادراه پل زال-خرم آباد در جنوب غربی کشور علیرغم داشتن مزایای اقتصادی فراوان، مخطرات زمین‌شناسی و مشکلات عدیده‌ای را برای محیط‌زیست بصورت زمین‌لغزشها، تغییر کاربری اراضی و کاهش جمعیت گونه‌های جانوری و گیاهی داشته است. به همین دلیل در این پژوهش، تعیین مسیر بهینه بر مبنای ملاحظات زیست‌محیطی مدنظر قرار گرفته است. هشت عامل شیب، چینه‌شناسی، گسل، فاصله از آبراهه، پوشش گیاهی، ارتفاع، کاربری اراضی و مناطق حفاظت شده از منظر زمین‌شناسی مهندسی، زیست‌محیطی و اقتصادی به روش فازی و AHP استانداردسازی شده‌اند. این تحقیق نشان می‌هد که عوامل مناطق حفاظت شده، چینه‌شناسی، پوشش گیاهی و کاربری اراضی با وزن 166/0، 165/0، 147/0و 123/0 بیشترین تاثیر در انتخاب مسیر جدید دارند. در نهایت، این عوامل براساس وزن نسبی در محیط GIS با یکدیگر ترکیب شده و مسیر پیشنهادی انتخاب گردید. این مسیر نسبت به مسیر فعلی 15 کیلومتر کوتاهتر و مخاطرات زمین‌شناسی و اثرات زیست‌محیطی کمتری دارد. بنابراین، توصیه می‌شود که این فرآیند برای سایر آزادراه‌های احداث شده و یا در حال احداث به منظور کاهش پیامدهای زیست محیطی پروژه بکار گرفته شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ملاحظات زیست محیطی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنجش از دور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مسیر بهینه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آزادراه پل زال-خرم آباد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فازی و AHP</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15058_e0ef9d0d0fb4a1c93a3314bbcfd6e884.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
