<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating contamination and sources of heavy metals and polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) in surface sediment of Qarasoo River, Kermanshah</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی آلودگی و منشأ فلزات سنگین و هیدروکربن های آروماتیک چندحلقه ای (PAHs) در رسوبات سطحی رودخانه قره سو شهرستان کرمانشاه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>156</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>167</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15014</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28511.1940</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میثم</FirstName>
					<LastName>رستگاری مهر</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه آموزشی زمین شناسی کاربردی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگته خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عدنان</FirstName>
					<LastName>دشه ئی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه آموزشی زمین شناسی کاربردی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عطا</FirstName>
					<LastName>شاکری</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه آموزشی زمین شناسی کاربردی، دانشکئه علوم زمین، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Contamination of seven heavy metals (Cu, Pb, Zn, Fe, Al, V, Ni) and PAH compounds, and physicochemical characteristics were studied in sediments of Qarasoo River, Kermanshah. The results of contamination factor (CF), pollution load index (PLI) and enrichment factor indicated severe contamination of sediments, particularly for lead, zinc and copper in some segments of the river. Also, sampling stations near the city including oil refinery and industrial town had much higher PAH concentrations than the upstream. Based on toxic equivalency factor (TEF) and comparison of PAHs concentration with effect range low (ERL) revealed inappropriate situation of Qarasoo sediments. Among the various compounds, 3-rings PAHs are dominant with maximum concentration, same as heavy metals, in oil refinery station. Based on principal component analysis (PCA) and geochemical indices effluents of Kermanshah oil refinery are the main source of contamination of low molecular weight PAHs with petrogenic origin and copper, vanadium and nickel. In addition, organic matter and pH have also shown strong correlation with this component, confirming the role of the refinery in increasing their concentration in the Qarasoo River. Other important anthropogenic sources in the Qarasoo River include urban and industrial effluent, traffic and illegal waste disposal in the river margins.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ویژگی‌های فیزیکوشیمیایی، و آلودگی فلزات سنگین (Cu, Pb, Zn, Fe, Al, V, Ni) و ترکیبات PAH در رسوبات رودخانه قره‌سو کرمانشاه مطالعه شد. نتایج شاخص آلودگی (CF)، شاخص بار آلودگی (PLI) و ضریب غنی‌شدگی بیانگر آلودگی شدید رسوبات به ویژه درمورد عناصر سرب، روی و مس در مقاطعی از رودخانه بود. همچنین ایستگاه‌های نزدیک به شهر کرمانشاه مانند پالایشگاه نفت و شهرک صنعتی آلودگی بسیار بالاتری از PAH نسبت به بالا دست نشان دادند. براساس شاخص هم‌ارز سمناکی و مقایسه غلظت‌PAHها با محدوده اثر پایین (ERL) بیانگر وضعیت نامناسب رسوب قره سو بود. در بین انواع ترکیبات، گونه غالب، ترکیبات PAH سه حلقه‌ای است که بالاترین آلودگی آن نیز مانند فلزات سنگین مربوط به ایستگاه پالایشگاه نفت کرمانشاه بود. بر اساس تحلیل مولفه اصلی (PCA) و شاخص‌های زمین شیمیایی پساب خروجی پالایشگاه نفت کرمانشاه منبع اصلی آلودگی ترکیبات PAH سبک با منشأ نفت‌زاد و عناصری مانند مس، وانادیم و نیکل محسوب می‌شود. علاوه براین عناصر، مواد آلی و pH نیز همراهی قوی با این مولفه نشان داده که تصدیقی بر نقش پالایشگاه در افزایش آنها در رودخانه قره‌سو است. از دیگر منابع انسان‌زاد نیز می‌توان به پساب صنعتی و شهری، ترافیک و دفع غیرقانونی پسماند در حاشیه رودخانه اشاره کرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فلزات سنگین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">PAH</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رودخانه قره‌سو</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رسوب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کرمانشاه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15014_fbea03dad42c1832e18aa605e4d7d671.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
