<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Application of elemental analysis in distincting of dolomitization model of Sormaq and Abadeh Formations in Hambast section , Abadeh area , Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کاربرد آنالیز عنصری در تعیین مدل دولومیتی شدن سازند های سورمق و آباده در برش همبست ، ناحیه آباده ، ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15496</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.29977.2006</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بیژن</FirstName>
					<LastName>یوسفی یگانه</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی ، گروه زمین شناسی د انشگاه لرستان ،</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیما</FirstName>
					<LastName>شاهین فر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری ، گروه زمین شناسی ، دانشگاه لرستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سکینه</FirstName>
					<LastName>عارفی فرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی ، گروه زمین شناسی ، دانشگاه لرستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The study area is located 60 km southeast of Abadeh city in the northeastem part of Mountain Hambast .In the concerned area there exists complete outcrops from the Middle to the Upper Permian , and has two stratigraphic sections in the Hambast valley as was based on field evidence , petrography and geochemical analysis based on elemental analysis of (EDS) and (EPMA) methods. Two main groups of dolomite minerals including primary dolomite and secondary dolomite were identified .The Primary dolomitic group (called dolomicrites) show mosaic texture and are more anhedral , The second group (dolomicrosparites ) are subhedral. The dolosparites are often subhedral and uhedral.In dolomicrites , Mg is lower than other dolomites due to the highe Ca content.In general , the amount of Sr in the dolomites studied decreases from dolomicrites to dolosparite and increased Sr in dolomicrites is due to the function of diagenesis processes on aragonite shrlls.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">منطقه مورد مطالعه در 60 کیلومتری جنوب شرق شهر آباده و در بخش شمال شرقی کوه همبست قرار دارد که رخنمونهای کاملی از پرمین میانی تا پرمین بالایی را شامل می شود و دارای دو مقطع چینه شناسی در دره همبست می باشد. بر پایه شواهد صحرایی، سنگ نگاری و ژئوشیمیایی بر مبنای آنالیز عنصری به روش های (EDS)و (EPMA)، دو گروه اصلی از دولومیت ها شناسایی شد که شامل دولومیت های اولیه و دولومیت های ثانویه می باشند. دولومیت های اولیه شامل دلومیکرایت ها با بافت موزائیکی و اغلب آنهدرال و دولومیت های ثانویه شامل دولومیکرواسپارایت ها بصورت ساب هدرال و دولواسپارایت ها اغلب سابهدرال و یوهدرال می باشند.در دلومیکرایت ها کاهش Mg نسبت به دیگر دلومیت ها به دلیل بالا بودن مقدار Ca می باشد. به طور کلی مقدار Sr در دولومیت های موردمطالعه از دلومیکرایت به سمت دولواسپارایت کاهش را نشان می دهد و افزایش استرانسیم در دلومیکرایت به دلیل عملکرد فرایندهای دیاژنزی روی پوسته های آراگونیتی است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آنالیز عنصری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولومیتی شدن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساز سورمق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازند آباده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همبست</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
