<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Detection of sub-surface spaces, using thermal Infrared Images in Shiramin region, Azarshahr, Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی فضاهای زیرسطحی در منطقه شیرامین آذرشهر با استفاده از تصاویر ماهواره‌ای فروسرخ گرمایی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15346</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28880.1955</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نادر</FirstName>
					<LastName>جلالی</LastName>
<Affiliation>معاون پژوهشی پژوهشکده حفاظت خاک و آبخیزداری</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Subsurface spaces make restrictions for site selection and construction of structures. Although geophysics and drilling help engineers in this issue, but these are cost effective and time consuming. Therefore economic and fast methods should be considered for explorations. In this article an attempt was made to introduce a method for detecting and mapping subsurface spaces using thermal infrared images and other environmental effective factors. Assumption is land surface temperature somehow is being influenced by subsurface temperature. By the time the general conditions of land surface in carbonate rocks to be the same in terms of vegetation cover, antecedent soil moisture, illumination and altitude, any variations and anomalies of temperature on land surface may be attributed to inherent physical and hydrogeological conditions of carbonate rocks. Investigations showed that some parts of carbonate rocks in Shiramin region that are hosting subsurface spaces are relatively appeared cooler than the others on thermal images. Data integration based on applying base rules was taken place by means of ILWIS GIS and data analysis tools. As a result of such data integration, thermal anomalies related to inherent condition of carbonate rocks were identified and consequently spatial distribution map of areas hosting unseen subsurface spaces were prepared.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">فرو افتادگی‌ها، از نگرانی‌های مهندسین در جانمایی سازه‌ها میباشد. بدیهی است که ژئوفیزیک و حفاری‌ها می‌ توانند در این راستا کمک نمایند، لیکن گاهی گستردگی مناطق و هزینه‌های زیاد مانع از بررسی‌ها می‌شود. سعی شده تا قابلیت‌های سنجش از دور گرمایی در شناسایی فضاهای زیرسطحی در منطقه‌ی شیرامین که وجود آن‌ها در این منطقه به اثبات رسیده است، محک زده شود. برای دستیابی به این هدف، از تصاویر فروسرخ گرمایی سنجنده‌های ETM+ و ASTER، مدل ارتفاع رقومی و مشتقات آن و همچنین سایر داده‌های محیطی موثر در کاهش دمای سطح زمین استفاده شده است. نرم افزار پردازش تصاویر ماهواره‌ای، مدیریت داده‌ها، تلفیق اطلاعات مکانی و مدل‌سازی، ILWIS محصول موسسه ITC هلند بوده است.&lt;br /&gt; مدل‌سازی رابطه‌ای بر اساس تلفیق لایه‌های اطلاعاتی مرتبط با موضوع، بر مبنای به کارگیری معیارهای تصمیم گیری، به شناسایی آنومالی‌های گرمایی مرتبط با شرایط ذاتی سنگهای کربناته و در نتیجه تهیه نقشه پراکنش مکانی مناطق دارای فضاهای زیرسطحی در منطقه شیرامین آذرشهر، انجامیده است. &lt;br /&gt; صحت نتایج را مشاهدات میدانی، لاگ چاه‌های اکتشافی و تاریخ زمین‌شناسی منطقه، تایید می‌کنند. nv نتیجه به‌کارگیری توأم تصاویر فروسرخ گرمایی و داده‌های محیطی و تلفیق منطقی آن‌ها می‌تواند در شناسایی مناطقی که در آنها فضاهای زیرسطحی وجود دارند، موثر واقع شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فضاهای زیرسطحی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شیرامین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصاویر فروسرخ گرمایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل‌سازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
