<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" "journalpublishing3.dtd">
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28141.1919</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15068_060baab5dbbdd384072002e7dae0e4d8.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی شکل‌های مختلف گوگرد در خاک اطراف پالایشگاه گاز و ارتباط آن با سایر ویژگی‌های خاک، مثالی از شمال شرق ایران</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>تاج بخشیان</surname>
			            <given-names>مریم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم ، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محمودی قرائی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد حسین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محبوبی</surname>
			            <given-names>اسداله</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>موسوی حرمی</surname>
			            <given-names>سید رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>21</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2020</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>10</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>1</fpage>
			      <lpage>14</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>06</day>
			          <month>01</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>18</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2020, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15068.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15068.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>برای بررسی کیفیت خاک در منطقه پالایشگاه گاز شهید هاشمینژاد از نظر سطح آلودگی به گوگرد تولیدی در این واحد صنعتی، 22 نمونه خاک از مناطق مجاور پالایشگاه و داخل آن برداشت شد. مقدار سولفات خاک در سه شکل قابل‌حل در آب، جذب شده و متصل به کربنات‌ها بهترتیب توسط آب دیونیزه، محلول M 032/0 NaH2PO4 و M 1 HCl استخراج شد. غلظت سولفات مجموع به روش هضم کامل خاک توسط مخلوطی از HF، HCl و HNO3 تعیین شد. مقدار ماده آلی و غلظت آنیون‌های کربنات و بیکربنات موجود در نمونه‌های خاک به روش تیتر کردن تعیین شد. در تمام نمونه‌های خاک برداشت شده، به ترتیب سولفات آلی، متصل به کربنات‌ها، قابل‌حل در آب و در نهایت جذب شده بیشترین غلظت را داشتند، که درمورد نمونه‌های خاک داخل پالایشگاه نه تنها این امر مشخص بود، بلکه از نظر تمامی این اشکال سولفات، غلظت بیشتری را نسبت به سایر نمونه‌ها نیز نشان دادند. شکل سولفات قابل‌حل در آب رابطه معکوسی با pH خاک داشت که نشان داد وجود سولفات توانسته تا حدودی موجب اکسیداسیون گوگرد و ترکیبات آن و غلبه محیط اسیدی در خاک شود.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>پالایشگاه گاز شهید هاشمی نژاد</kwd>
						<kwd>هضم کامل</kwd>
						<kwd>ماده آلی</kwd>
						<kwd>سولفات جذب شده</kwd>
						<kwd>ژیپس و انیدریت</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Afshar Harb, A., 1982. 1:250000 Geological map of Sarakhs, (No.1.4), Ministry of petroleum, Tehran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Afshar Harb, A., 1997. Geology of Koppeh-Dagh, Geological Survey of Iran, Tehran, p.275.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Asghari Jafar Abadi, M., Soltani, A., Mohammadi, M., 2013. Statistics series: correlation and regression. Journal of Diabetes and Lipids of Iran 12, 479-506.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Balik, J., Kulhanek, M., Cerny, J., Szakova, J., Pavlikova, D., Cermak, P., 2009. Differences in soil sulfur fractions due to limitation of atmospheric deposition. Plant and Soil Environment 55, 344-352.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Bertrand, R.A., 1973. Reclaiming of Soils Made Barren by Sulphur from Processing Plants. Dissertation, University of Alberta, Canada.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Blair, G.J., Chinoim, N., Lefroy, R.D.B., Anderson, G.C., Crocker, G.J., 1991. A soil sulfur test for pastures and crops. Australian Journal of Soil Research 29, 619–626.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Bouranis, D.L., Chorianopoulou, S.N., Margetis, S., Saridis, G.L., Sigalas, P.P., 2018. Effect of elemental sulfur as fertilizer ingredient on the mobilization of Iron from the iron pools of a calcareous soil cultivated with Durum Wheat and the crop’s iron and sulfur nutrition. Agriculture 8, 10-17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Brocks, J.J. Summons, R.E., 2003. Sedimentary hydrocarbons, biomarkers for early life. Treatise on Geochemistry 8, 63-115.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Carter, M.R., Gregorich, E.G., 2008. Soil Sampling and Methods of Analysis, 2th edition, CRC Press, Taylor &amp; Francis Group, United States of America, p.1263.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Charman, P.E.V., Roper, M.M., 2007. Soil Organic Matter: Their Properties and Management, 3th edition, Oxford University Press, Melbourne, p.320.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Chavoshi, B., Masoudi Nezhad, M.R., Adib Zadeh, A., 2011. Evaluation the amount of emission and sulfur dioxide emission factor from Tehran Oil Refinery. Iranian Journal of Health Environment 4, 233-244.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, B., Shan, X., Shen, D., Mou, S., 1997. Nature of the HCl-soluble sulfate in the sequential extraction for sulfur speciation in soils. Fresenius Journal of Analytical Chemistry 357, 941-945.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Edwards, P., 1998. Sulfur Cycling, Retention, and Mobility in Soils: A Review (NE-250), United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), United States of America, p.22.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Farooq, M., Bakhtiar, M., Ahmed, S., Ilyas, N., Iltaf Khan., Saboor, A., Solangi, I.A., Ali Yar Khan., Shoaib Khan, Imran Khan., 2018. Influence of sulfur and boron on the growth and yield of Broccoli. International Journal of Environmental &amp; Agriculture Research 4, 9-16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Graveland, D.N., Kacsinko, F., 1974. Subsurface Disposal of Elemental Sulphur, Alberta Environment, Canada, p.56.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Havlin, J.L., Beaton, J.D., Tisdale., S.L., Nelson, W.L., 2004. Soil Fertility and Fertilizers: An Introduction to Nutrient Management, Pearson Education Incorporation, Singapore, p.250.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Huang, P.M., Schnitzer, M., 1986. Interactionsof Soil Minerals with Natural Organics and Microbes, Soil Science Society of America Publication, Medison, p.593.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Ivanov, M.V., Freney, J.R., 1983. The Global Biogeochemical Sulfur Cycle, John Wiley &amp; Sons Incorporation, New York, p.465.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Jaefari Haghighi, M., 2003. Main physical and chemical sampling and analyses emphasizing theory and applied principles, Nedaye Zohaa Publication, Sari, p.115.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Jangjoo, M., Ejtehadi, H., Danesh, S., 2008. Introduction to suitable plant species to farm in around gas refinery of Sarakhs. Research plan. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Jung, K., Ok, Y., Chang, S., 2011. Sulfate adsorption properties of acid-sensitive soils in the Athabasca oil sands region in Alberta, Canada. Chemosphere 84, 457-463.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Karimizarchi, M., Aminuddin, H., 2015. Effect of elemental sulphur on soil micronutrients mobility. Journal of Agricultural Science and Food Technology 1, 34-42.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Kavosh-Pay Advisor Engineering Company., 2010. The successive studies of water resources in Sarakhs region: Environmental report. Regional water incorporation of Khorasan Razavi, Mashhad, p.253.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Landers, D.H., David, M.B., Mitchell, M.J., 1983. Analysis of organic and inorganic sulfur constituents in sediments, soils and water. International Journal of Analytical Chemistry 14, 245–256.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Little, D.N., Syam, N., 2009. Recommended Practice for Stabilization of Sulfate Rich Sub grade Soils, Texas Transportation Institute, Texas A&amp;M University, Texas, p. 56.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Liu, F., He, J., Colombo, C., Violante, A., 1999. Competitive adsorption of sulfate and oxalate on goethite in the absence or presence of phosphate. Soil Science 164, 180–189.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Marsh, K.B., Tillman, R.W., Syers, J.K., 1987. Charge relationships of sulfate sorption by soils. Soil Science Society of America Journal 51, 318–323.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Martinez, C.E., Kleinschmidt, A.W., Tabatabai, M.A., 1998. Sulfate adsorption by variable charge soils: effect of low-molecular weight organic acids. Biology and Fertility of Soils 26, 157– 163.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Maynard, D.G., Germida, J.J., Addison, P.A., 1986. The effect of elemental sulfur on certain chemical and biological properties of surface organic horizons of a forest soil. Canadian Journal for Research 16, 1050-1054.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Momeni, M., Faal Ghayyumi, A., 2009. Comparison of regression analysis types to accounting data. Journal of Accounting researches and Audit 16, 103-112.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Morche, L., 2008. S-Flusse und raumliche Veranderungen anorganischer und organischer Schwefelfraktionen im Boden sowie deren An- und Abreicherung in der Rhizosphare landwirtschaftlicher Kulturpflanzen unter partiellem Einsatz des Radioisotops 35S. Ph.D thesis. Rheinischen Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universitat, Bonn.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Munoz, S.I., 2007. Ecological Research Progress, Nova Science Publishers, New York, p.225.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Neeley, F., Heguy, D., Karr, J., 2010. Sulfur: At the Crossroads of Energy, the Environment, and Agriculture. Fertilizer International 388, 68-72.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Nriagu, J.O., Soon, Y.K., 1985. Distribution and isotopic composition of sulfur in lake sediments of northern Ontario. Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta 49, 823–834.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Oldham, L., 2011. Secondary Plant Nutrients: Calcium, Magnesium, and Sulfur (POD-04-11), Mississippi State University Extension Service, United States of America, p.4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Orem, W., Gilmour, C., Axelrad, D., Krabbenhoft, D., Scheidt, D., Kalla, P., McCormick., Gabriel, M., Aiken, G., 2013. Sulfur in the South Florida Ecosystem: Distribution, Sources, Biogeochemistry, Impacts, and Management for Restoration. Critical Reviews in Environmental Science and Technology 41, 249-288.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Padideh, Y., 2006. Geochemical assessment of gas reservoirs of Koppeh-Dagh basin. Dissertation. Amir Kabir University, Tehran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Pawels, J.M, Van Ranst, E., Verloo, M., Mvondo, Z.A., 1992. Soil and Plant Analysis, Sheffield Academic Press, Bruxelles, p.225.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Pritzel, J., Mayer, B., Legge, A., 2004. Cumulative impact of 40 years of industrial sulfur emissions on a forest soil in west-central Alberta (Canada). Environmental Pollution 132, 129-144.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Rathore, S.S., Shekhawat, K., Kandpal, B.K., Premi, O.P., Singh, S.P., Singh, G.C., Singh, D., 2015. Sulphur management for increased productivity of Indian mustard: a review. Annals of Plant and Soil Research 17, 1-12.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Rezaei, S., Khavazi, K., Nezami, M.T., Saadat, S., 2015. Effects of elemental sulfur and soil compaction on microbial biomass carbon and soil enzyme activities. International Journal of Biosciences 6, 7-14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Riordan, D., Adeeb, F., 2004. Air Quality Monitoring for Sulfur Dioxide in Metropolitan Adelaide, Environment Protection Authority, Adelaide, p.27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Rodrigues, A.L., Rossete, M., Bendassolli, J.A., Trivelin, P.C.O., 2008. Organic Sulfur Oxidation to Sulfate in Soil Samples for Total Sulfur Determination by Turbidimetry. Revista Brasileira de Ciência do Solo 32, 2547-2553.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Rodriguez, N., McLaughlin, M., Pennock, D., 2018. Soil Pollution, A Hidden Reality, Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, Rome, p.160.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Salim Pour, S., 2011. Effect of sulfur on increase yield and improve agricultural products (Nutritional and corrective role in calcareous soils) and its importance to use, Agricultural Promotion Coordination Management Publication, Ahvaz, p.21.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Sankhyan, N.K., Kumari, N., Dutta, J., Sharma, S., Sharma, G.D., 2014. Status and distribution of sulfur in acidic alfisols of District Kangra, Himachal Pradesh. Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis 46, 1659-1667.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Schonhof, I., Blankenburg, D., Muller, S., Krumbein, A., 2007. Sulfur and nitrogen supply influence growth, product appearance, and glucosinolate contents of broccoli. Journal of Plant Nutrition and Soil Science 170, 65-72.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Schwertmann, U., 1985. The effect of pedogenic environments on iron oxide minerals Advances in Soil Science 1, 171–200.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Shahid Hashemi Nezhad Gas Refining Company, 2011. The comprehensive information of Shahid Hashemi Nezhad gas refining incorporation (Khangiran). National Gas Company of Iran, Mashhad, p.85.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Shan, X., Chen, B., Jin, L., Zheng, Y., Hou, X., Mou, S., 1991. Determination of sulfur fractions in soils by sequential extraction, inductively coupled plasma-optical emission spectroscopy and ion chromatography.  Chemical Speciation and Bioavailability 4, 97–103.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Shoji, S., Fujiwara, Y., 1984. Active aluminum and iron in the humus horizons of Andosols from Northeastern Japan: their forms, properties, and significance in clay weathering. Soil Science 137, 216– 226.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Skwierawska, M., Zawartka, L., Skwierawski, A., Nogalska, A., 2014. The effect of different sulfur doses and forms on changes of soil heavy metals. Plant and Soil Environment 58, 135-140.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Spencer, K., Freney, J.R., 1960. A comparison of several procedures for estimating the sulfur status of soils. Australian Journal of Agricultural Research 11, 948 – 959.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Srinivasulu, M., Mohiddin, G., Quimbiulco, K., Rueda Ortiz, D., Tirado, J., Rangaswamy, V., 2015. Effect of Pesticides Alone and in Combinations on Sulphur Oxidation in Soils. International Journal of Current Microbiology and Applied Sciences 4, 412-418.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Tabatabai, M.A., 1982. Methods of Soil Analysis: Chemical and microbiological properties, American Society of agronomy, Soil Science Society of America, Madison, p.560.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation> Thi Lan, B.N., Kobayashi, T., Suetsugu, A., Tian, X., Kameya, T., 2018. Estimating the possibility of surface soil pollution with atmospheric lead deposits using the ADMER model. Sustainability 10, 1-12.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Walkley, A., Black, I.A., 1934. An examination of the Degtjareff method for determining soil organic matter, and a proposed modification of the chromic acid titration method. Soil Science 34, 29-38.  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Wedepohl, K.H., 1978. Handbook of Geochemistry, Springer-Verlag, Berlin, p.563.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Yu, T.R., 1997. Chemistry of Variable Charge Soils, Oxford University Press, New York, p.500.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28197.1922</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15069_427033883fcca86242ee72cf2aecc17c.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>ارزیابی تأثیر چرخه‌های انجماد-ذوب بر روی سرعت امواج فشاری و چگالی سنگ شیست (مطالعه موردی: معدن انگوران)</article-title>
			        <subtitle>ارزیابی تأثیر چرخه‌های انجماد-ذوب بر روی سرعت امواج فشاری و چگالی سنگ شیست (مطالعه موردی: معدن انگوران)</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>سید موسوی</surname>
			            <given-names>سید زانیار</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده فنی‌مهندسی، دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>توکلی</surname>
			            <given-names>حسین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده فنی‌مهندسی، دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>معارف وند</surname>
			            <given-names>پرویز</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده مهندسی معدن و متالوژی، دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رضائی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده مهندسی، دانشگاه کردستان، سنندج، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>21</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2020</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>10</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>15</fpage>
			      <lpage>30</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>01</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>18</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2020, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15069.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15069.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>در این تحقیق تأثیر چرخه‌های مختلف انجماد-ذوب بر سرعت امواج فشاری و چگالی سنگ شیست بررسی شده است. بدین منظور، ابتدا 13 عدد گمانه در معدن انگوران حفاری و تعداد 25 نمونه استوانه‌ای آماده سازی گردید. سپس، نمونه‌ها در آزمایشگاه با استفاده از فرآیند انجماد-ذوب هوازده و پارامترهای سرعت امواج فشاری و چگالی خشک نمونه‌ها در چرخه‌های 0، 7، 15، 40 و 75 اندازه‌گیری گردید. تحلیل نتایج نشان‌دهنده کاهش نمایی سرعت امواج فشاری (50% کاهش) و چگالی خشک (20% کاهش) به‌ازای افزایش تعداد چرخه‌های انجماد-ذوب می‌باشد. همچنین، سرعت امواج فشاری با افزایش چگالی خشک به‌صورت نمایی افزایش می‌یابد. با برازش نتایج حاصله، دو رابطه تجربی مجزا جهت محاسبه سرعت موج فشاری و چگالی خشک در سنگ شیست به‌ازای چرخه‌های مختلف انجماد-ذوب و یک رابطه هم بین سرعت موج فشاری و چگالی خشک ارائه شده است. بعلاوه، بافت نمونه‌ها هم در حالت بکر و هم پس از اعمال 75 چرخه انجماد-ذوب به‌وسیله میکروسکوپ الکترونیکی مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته است. نتایج حاصله نشان دهنده متراکم بودن بافت نمونه‌ها قبل از هوازدگی و افزایش فاصله بین ناپیوستگی‌ها بعد از هوازدگی می باشد. در نهایت، نتایج اعتبارسنجی نشان داد که همخوانی خوبی بین خروجی حاصل از تحقیق حاضر و مطالعات قبلی وجود دارد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>معدن انگوران</kwd>
						<kwd>شیست</kwd>
						<kwd>چرخه انجماد-ذوب</kwd>
						<kwd>سرعت موج فشاری</kwd>
						<kwd>چگالی خشک</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Babuška, V., 1968. Elastic anisotropy of igneous and metamorphic rocks. Studia Geophysica et Geodaetica 12 (3), pp. 291.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Barton, M., Hamilton, D.L., 1978. Water-saturated melting relations to 5 kilobars of three Leucite Hills lavas. Contributions to Mineralogy and Petrology 66 (1), 41-49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Borhani, A., Lashkaripoor, Gh., Ghafouri, M., 2015. Investigation of physical and mechanical properties of the schists in the South of Mashhad, Second National Conference on Geology and Exploration Resources, Shiraz.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Çelik, M.Y., 2017. Water absorption and P-wave velocity changes during freeze–thaw weathering process of crosscut travertine rocks. Environmental Earth Sciences 76, 409, doi: 10.1007/s12665-017-6632-7.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, J., Xu, Z., Yu, Y., Yao, Y., 2014. Experimental characterization of granite damage using nonlinear ultrasonic techniques. NDT &amp; E International 67, 10-16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, T.C., Yeung, M.R., Mori, N., 2004. Effect of water saturation on deterioration of welded tuff due to freeze-thaw action. Cold Regions Science and Technology 38 (2-3), 127-136.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Ding, Q.L., Song, S.B., 2016. Experimental investigation of the relationship between the P-wave velocity and the mechanical properties of damaged sandstone. Advances in Materials Science and Engineering, do: 10.1155/2016/7654234.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Domenico, S.N., 1984. Rock lithology and porosity determination from shear and compressional wave velocity. Geophysics 49 (8), 1188-1195.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Draebing, D., Krautblatter, M., 2012. P-wave velocity changes in freezing hard low-porosity rocks: a laboratory-based time-average model. The Cryosphere 6, (5), 1163-1174.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Dreesen, R., Dusar, M., 2004. Historical building stones in the province of Limburg (NE Belgium): Role of petrography in provenance and durability assessment. Materials Characterization 53 (2-4), 273-287.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>El-Gohary, M. A., 2013. Evaluation of treated and un-treated Nubia Sandstone using ultrasonic as a non-destructive technique. Journal of Archaeological Science 40 (4), 2190-2195.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Fahimifar, A., Soroush, H., 2001. Rock Mechanics Experiments, Theoretical Foundations and Standards Volume I, Technical Lab Joint Stock Company and soil mechanics, Amirkabir University of Technology.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Fahimifar, A., Soroush, H., 2003. Rock Mechanics Experiments - Theoretical Foundations and Standards Volume II Field tests, Amirkabir University of Technology Publishing Center.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Fener, M., Ince, I., 2015. Effects of the freeze–thaw (F–T) cycle on the andesitic rocks (Sille-Konya/Turkey) used in construction building. Journal of African Earth Sciences 109, 96-106.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Freire-Lista, D.M., Fort, R., Varas-Muriel, M.J., 2015. Freeze–thaw fracturing in building granites. Cold Regions Science and Technology 113, 40-51.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Ghobadi, M.H., Babazadeh, R., 2015. Experimental studies on the effects of cyclic freezing–thawing, salt crystallization, and thermal shock on the physical and mechanical characteristics of selected sandstones. Rock Mechanics and Rock Engineering 48(3), 1001-1016.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Grossi, C.M., Brimblecombe, P., Harris, I., 2007. Predicting long term freeze–thaw risks on Europe built heritage and archaeological sites in a changing climate. Science of the Total Environment 377(2-3), 273-281.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Han, D.H., Nur, A., Morgan, D., 1986. Effects of porosity and clay content on wave velocities in sandstones. Geophysics 51 (11), 2093-2107.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Inigo, A.C., Vicente, M.A., Rives, V., 2000. Weathering and decay of granitic rocks: its relation to their pore network. Mechanics of Materials 32 (9), 555-560.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Jamshidi, A., Nikudel, M.R., Khamehchiyan, M., 2016. Evaluation of the durability of Gerdoee travertine after freeze–thaw cycles in fresh water and sodium sulfate solution by decay function models. Engineering Geology 202, 36-43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Khanlari, G., Abdilor, Y., 2015. Influence of wet–dry, freeze–thaw, and heat–cool cycles on the physical and mechanical properties of Upper Red sandstones in central Iran. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment 74(4), 1287-1300.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Khanlori, Gh., Momeni, A., Abdi, Y., 2010. Engineering Geology and Geotechnics, Pablication of university of Bu Ali Sina, Hamedan.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Kurtuluş, C., Sertçelik, F., Sertçelik, I., 2016. Correlating physico-mechanical properties of intact rocks with P-wave velocity. Acta Geodaetica et Geophysica 51 (3), 571-582.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Mahmoud, A.M., Ammar, H.H., Mukdadi, O.M., Ray, I., Imani, F.S., Chen, A., Davalos, J.F., 2010. Non-destructive ultrasonic evaluation of CFRP–concrete specimens subjected to accelerated aging conditions. Ndt &amp; E International 43, (7), 635-641.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Mamillan, M., 1979. Méthodes d’essais au gel des pierres, Problems Raised by Frost Action. In 6th international congress   of the fondation française d’Etudes Nordiques, Le Havre, p. 225-238.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Özbek, A., 2014. Investigation of the effects of wetting–drying and freezing–thawing cycles on some physical and mechanical properties of selected ignimbrites. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment 73(2), 595-609.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Özgan, E., 2007. Determining the stability of asphalt concrete at varying temperature and exposure times using destructive and non-destructive methods. Journal of Applied Sciences 7(24), 3870-3879.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Özgan, E., Serin, S., Ertürk, S., Vural, I., 2015. Effects of freezing and thawing cycles on the engineering properties of soils. Soil Mechanics and Foundation Engineering 52(2), 95-99.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Park, J., Hyun, C.U., Park, H.D., 2015. Changes in microstructure and physical properties of rocks caused by artificial freeze–thaw action. Bulletin of Engineering Geology and the Environment 74(2), 555-565.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Ruedrich, J., Kirchner, D., Siegesmund, S., 2011. Physical weathering of building stones induced by freeze–thaw action: A laboratory long-term study. Environmental Earth Sciences 63(7-8), 1573-1586.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Sousa, L.M., del Río, L.M.S., Calleja, L., de Argandona, V.G.R., Rey, A.R., 2005. Influence of microfractures and porosity on the physico-mechanical properties and weathering of ornamental granites. Engineering Geology 77(1-2), 153-168.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Spetzler, H., Anderson, D.L., 1968. The effect of temperature and partial melting on velocity and attenuation in a simple binary system. Journal of Geophysical Research 73(18), 6051-6060.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Standard, A.S.T.M., 2008. Standard test method for laboratory determination of pulse velocities and ultrasonic elastic constants of rock. ASTM International, West Conshohocken.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Tan, X., Chen, W., Yang, J., Cao, J., 2011. Laboratory investigations on the mechanical properties degradation of granite under freeze–thaw cycles. Cold Regions Science and Technology 68(3), 130-138.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, P., Xu, J. Y., Liu, S., 2015. Ultrasonic method to evaluate the residual properties of thermally damaged sandstone based on time–frequency analysis. Nondestructive Testing and Evaluation 30(1), 74-88.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, P., Xu, J., Fang, X., Wang, P., Zheng, G., Wen, M., 2017. Ultrasonic time-frequency method to evaluate the deterioration properties of rock suffered from freeze-thaw weathering. Cold Regions Science and Technology 143, 13-22.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, P., Xu, J., Liu, S., Liu, S., Wang, H., 2016. A prediction model for the dynamic mechanical degradation of sedimentary rock after a long-term freeze-thaw weathering: Considering the strain-rate effect. Cold Regions Science and Technology 131, 16-23.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Yasar, E., Erdogan, Y., 2004. Correlating sound velocity with the density, compressive strength and Young's modulus of carbonate rocks. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences 41(5), 871-875.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, S., Lai, Y., Zhang, X., Pu, Y., Yu, W., 2004. Study on the damage propagation of surrounding rock from a cold-region tunnel under freeze–thaw cycle condition. Tunnelling and Underground Space Technology 19(3), 295-3.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.29297.1972</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15075_17292665c706e1a9b959a3c8bcb44a78.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>ارزیابی تناسب کاربری زمین در جایگاه دفن پسماند شهر زنجان با بهره‌گیری از دادهای هیدروژئولوژیکی و پیمایش‌های ژئوالکتریکی</article-title>
			        <subtitle>ارزیابی تناسب کاربری زمین در جایگاه دفن پسماند شهر زنجان با بهره‌گیری از دادهای هیدروژئولوژیکی و پیمایش‌های</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>ساعت ساز</surname>
			            <given-names>مسعود</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استایار دانشکده علوم زمین دانشگاه تحصیلات تکمیلی علوم پایه زنجان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>سبزی اتیوند</surname>
			            <given-names>محبوبه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه تحصیلات تکمیلی علوم پایه، زنجان، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>قدس</surname>
			            <given-names>عبدالرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه تحصیلات تکمیلی علوم پایه، زنجان، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>21</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2020</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>10</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>31</fpage>
			      <lpage>46</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>27</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>19</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2020, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15075.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15075.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>در این پژوهش، مطالعات هواشناسی، زمین‌شناسی، آب‌شناسی و ژئوفیزیکی برای ارزیابی زیست‌محیطی جایگاه دفن پسماند واقع در 13 کیلومتری جنوب‌باختر زنجان انجام پذیرفته ‌است. رسیدن به هدف، دربرگیرنده توسعه یک مدل در سامانه اطلاعات جغرافیایی، بررسی‌های مقاومت‌سنجی ژئوالکتریک و اندازه‌گیری نرخ نفوذ با بهره‌گیری نفوذسنج حلقه مضاعف در جایگاه دفن پسماند است. ارزیابی آسیب‌پذیری آبخوان نسبت به آلودگی نشان داد که جایگاه در گستره میانه آسیب‌پذیری جای دارد. آزمون‌های نفوذ‌پذیری حلقه‌ مضاعف تاکید می‌نمایند که جایگاه دفن یک جایگاه قابل‌قبول است که به‌نسبت، نرخ کم نفوذپدیری را نشان می‌دهد . در این پژوهش، با بهره‌گیری از 10 سونداژ الکتریکی قائم با آرایه شلومبرژه نشان داده شد که اندازه مقاومت‌الکتریکی نهشته‌ها در جایگاه از 20 تا 35 اهم‌متر برای انباشت پسماندهای تازه یا مرطوب و از 120 تا200 اهم‌متر برای انباشت‌های خشک و قدیمی نوسان دارد. زیانه آلودگی شیرابه پهنایی کم-وبیش برابر یک کیلومتر داشته و تا عمقی در حدود 55 متری گسترش یافته است. شکل زبانه نشان می‌دهد که مهاجرت شیرابه سمت‌ شمال‌شرق است. با نگرش به عمق سطح ایستابی برآوردشده در بیش‌از 86 متری و سرعت نفوذ محاسبه‌شده برابر 95/1 میلی‌متر در ساعت، چنین می‌توان نتیجه‌گیری کرد که حداقل تا سال 1404 زبانه آلودگی به سطح آب‌زیرزمینی نخواهد رسید.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>آبخوان</kwd>
						<kwd>آزمون نفوذپذیری حلقه مضاعف</kwd>
						<kwd>پیمایش های ژئوفیزیکی</kwd>
						<kwd>آسیب پذیری آب زیرزمینی</kwd>
						<kwd>جایگاه دفن پسماند</kwd>
						<kwd>زنجان</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Aaltonen, J., 1998. The use of current resistivity methods in landfill investigations- A case study on glaciated terrians. TRITA-AMI report. Stockholm, Sweden. p. 37.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Abdi, P., Hasanlo, M. R, 2003. Investigation of geological characteristics of quaternary alluvial alluvium in Zanjan province in order to find a preliminary location for the implementation of aquifer management projects. Retrieved from https://www.civilica.com/Paper-CWM03-CWM03_054.html.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Agamuthu, P., 2001. Solid waste: principles and management: with Malaysian case studies. Ph.D. Thesis. Institute of Biological Sciences, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Alanbari, M. A., Al-Ansari, N., Jasim, H. K., 2014. GIS and Multicriteria Decision Analysis for Landfill Site Selection in Al-Hashimyah Qadaa. Natural Science 6, 282-304.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Alizadeh, A., 2001. Applied Hydrology Principles, Asatan Ghods Razavi Pub, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Aller, L., 1985. DRASTIC: A standardized system for evaluating ground water pollution potential using hydrogeologic settings. In Robert, S., Kerr (ed). Environmental Research Laboratory, Office of Research and Development, US Environmental Protection Agency.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Aller, L., Bennett, T., Lehr, J.H., Petty, R. J., Hackett, G., 1987. DRASTIC: A standardized system for evaluating groundwater pollution potential using hydrogeologic settings. Environmental Protection Agency Report, NWWA/EPA Series EPA-600/2-87-035.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Amayesh Consulting Engineers, 2004. A review on the development plan of Zanjan. First Volume: Statistics, Information and Preliminary Survey. Amayesh Consulting Engineers Reports, Tehran, Iran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>ASTM, D., 2003. Standard Test Method for Infiltration Rate of Soils in Field Using Double-Ring Infiltrometer. American Society for Testing and Materials 10.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Choi, K.I., Lee. D. H., 2006. PCDD/DF in leachates from Korean MSW landfills. Chemosphere 63, 1353-1360.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Civita, M., 1994. Le carte della vulnerabilita` degli acquiferi all’inquinamento. Teoria &amp; practica (Aquifer vulnerability maps to pollution). Pitarora Ed., Bologna, Italy. (In Italian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Civita, M., De-Regibus, C., 1995. Sperimentazione di alcune metodologie per la valutazione della vulnerabilita` degli aquiferi. Quaderni di Geologia Applicata, Pitagora Ed, Bologna, Italy. (In Italian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Dahlin, T., 1993. On theAutomation of 2D Resistivity Surveyingfor Enginnering andEnvironmental Applications. Ph.D Thesis. Department of Engineering Geology, Lund Institute of Technology, Lund University, p. 187.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>De Martonne, E., 1926. A new featureclimate: The index of aridity. La Meteorologie, pp. 449-458.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Doerfliger, N., Jeannin, P. Y., Zwahlen, F., 1999. Water vulnerability assessment in karst environments: A new method of defining protection areas using a multi-attribute approach and GIS tools (EPIK method). Environmental Geology 39, 165-76.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Emberger, L., 1955. Une classification biogéorgaphique des climats. Recueil Trav. Lab. Annales Botanici Societatis Zoologicae Botanicae Fennicae of Université de Montpellier 7, 3-43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>ESRI, 2006. ARCGIS v.9.2. User’s Manual. Environmental Systems Research Institute Inc.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>ESRI, 2012. The 50th Anniversary of GIS. Retrieved From:http://www.esri.com/news/arcnews/fall12articles/the-fiftieth-anniversary-of-gis.html.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Foster, S.D.D., 1987. Fundamental concepts in aquifer vulnerability, pollution risk and protection strategy. In: Duijvenbooden, W., Van Waegeningh, H.G (eds) TNO Committee on Hydrological Research, The Hague. Vulnerability of soil and groundwater to pollutants, Proceedings and Information 38, 69–86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Geological survey of Iran (GSI), 2005. Zanjan Geological map. Scale at 1:100000, series Sheet No. 5663.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Ghorbani, K., 2004. Structural study of Soltanieh pressure fault and its mechanism in Chorzeq-Binder area (southwest of Zanjan). M. ScThesis, Shahid Beheshti University, Iran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Haydari, M.H., Pour Mhammadi, M.R., Jamali, F., Lotfi, F, 2012. Evaluation Human Bioclimatic Zoning of Zanjan and its Role in Housing Design. Scientific Research Quarterly of New Attitudes in Human Geography 4(2), 83-101. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Hiscock, K.M., 2005. Hydrogeology, principal and practice. Blackwell Publishing, UK. p. 405.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Huaser, V.L, 2008. Evapotranspiration Covers for Landfills and Waste Sites. CRC Press, USA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Iran Economy Online, 2013. Reasons for leachate infestation in Gilan nature, especially in Astaneh Ashrafieh. Retrieved from https://www.eghtesadonline.com</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Iran Meteorological Organization, Zanjan Administration 2014. Annual climatological reports. Retrieved from www.zanjanmet.ir.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>IRIS Instruments, 2014. Automatic Resistivity meter for imaging. Retrieved from http://www. iris-instruments.com/Product/Brochure/syscal.html/.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Jabbari, V., 2015. Transformation of waste into compost: maintaining health and the environment. Retrieved from pasmand.qazvin.ir.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Jafari, G.H., 2014. Investigating the Role of Faults in the Morphology of the Northern Plains Zanjanrood. Geography and Environmental Planning, 64(4), 35-48. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Jamrah, A., Al-Futaisi, A., Rajmohan, N., Al-Yaroubi, S., 2007. Assessment of groundwater vulnerability in the coastal region of Oman using DRASTIC index method in GIS environment’. Environental Monitor Assessent 147(1–3), 125–138, doi: 10.1007/s10661-007-0104-6.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Landviser, L.C.C., 2012. 1D Vertical Electrical Sounding (VES) with LandMapper Procedure. Retrieved from http://www.landviser.net/content/1d-vertical-electrical-sounding-ves-landmapper-procedure.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Loke, M. H., Dahlin, T., 2002. A comparison of the Gauss-Newton andquasi-Newton methods in resistivity imaging inversion. Journal of Applied Geophysics 49, 149-162.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Manoiu, V., Fontanine, I., Costache, R., Pravalie, R., Mitof, I., 2013. Using GIS Techniques for Assessing Waste Landfill Placement Suitability. Case Study: Prohova County, Romania. Geographia Technica 08, 47-56.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Moeinaddini, M., Khorasani, N., Danehkar, A., Darvishsefat, A. A., Zienalyan, M., 2010. Siting MSW landﬁll using weighted linear combination and analytical hierarchy process (AHP) methodology in GIS environment (case study: Karaj). Waste Management 30, 912–920.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Municipality of Tehran, 2015. Municipal solid wastegeneration and management in Iran. Municipality of Tehran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Municipality of Zanjan, 2006. Municipal solid waste analysis in Zanjan. Research Office, Internal report. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Municipality of Zanjan, 2014. Zanjan waste management. Administrative Office, Internal report. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Neshat, A., Pradhan, B., Dadras, M., 2014. Groundwater vulnerability assessment using an improved DRASTIC method in GIS. Resources, Conservation and Recycling 86, 74-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Nobes, D.C., 1996. Troubed Water: Environmental Applications of Electrical and Electromagnetic Methods. Groundwater 18, 46-55.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Poehls, D. J., Smith. G. J., 2009. Encyclopedic Dictionary of Hydrogeology. Elsevier’s Science &amp; Technology. CA, USA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Road, Housing &amp; Urban Development Research Center, 2005. The Iranian Code of Practice for Seismic Resistant Design of Buildings (Standard 2800 -Fourth Edition). Ministry of Housing and Urban Development, Islamic Republic of Iran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Saatsaz, M., Sulaiman, W.N.A., Eslamian, S., 2011. GIS DRASTIC model for groundwater vulnerability estimation of Astaneh-Kouchesfahan Plain, Northern Iran. International Journal of Water (IJW), Inderscience Publication Co. International Journal of Water (IJW), 6 (1/2).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Scott, W.J., Sellmann. P.V., Hunter. J.A., 1990. Geophysics in the study of permafrost, in Geotechnical andEnvironmental Geophysics. Society of Exploration Geophysics, Tulsa, pp. 355–384.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Seitz, H.R., Wallace, A.T., Williams, R.E., 1972. Investigation of a landfill in granite-loess terrain. Groundwater 10, 35-41.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Senos Matias, M., Marques da Silva, M., Ferreira, P., Ramalho, E., 1994. A geophysical and hydrogeological study of aquifers contamination by a landfill. Journal of Applied Geophysics. 32 (2–3) pp: 155-162.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Shirazi, S.M., Imran, H.M., Akib, Sh., 2012. GIS-based DRASTIC method for groundwater vulnerability assessment. Journal of Risk Research 15, 8.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Shroff, V.S., 1999. An investigation of leachate production from MSW landfills in semi-arid climates. University of Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Slack, J.R., Gronow, J.R., Voulvoulis, N., 2005. Household hazardous waste in municipal landfills: contaminants inleachate. Science of the Total Environment 337, 119–137.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Sobouti, F., Ghods, A. R., Shabanian, E, 2013. A study on seismicity and seismic hazard for Zanjan state and Tarom region, Academic report to Zanjan Governor. Institute for Advanced Studies in Basic Sciences (IASBS), Iran: Zanjan. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Statistical Center of Iran, 2011. Report of the 2011 census of housing and population of Iran. Tehran: Iran Statistical Center (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>United States Air Force Academy, 2014. The Air Force AcademyBecomes a Reality. Retrieved from http://www.nps.gov/nr/twhp/wwwlps/lessons/114airforce/114facts3.htm.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Wen, X., Wu, J., Si, J., 2008. A GIS-based DRASTIC model for assessing shallow groundwater vulnerability in the Zhangye Basin, northwestern China’, Environmental Geology 57, 1435–1442, doi: 10.1007/s00254-008-1421-y.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Whiteley, R.J., Jewell, C., 1992. Geophysical techniques in contaminated lands assessment? Do they deliver? Exploration Geophysics 23(4), 557 - 565.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Yadav, S.K., 2013. GIS Based Approach for Site Selection in Waste Management. International Journal of Environmental Engineering and Management 4, 507-514.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Yazdan Dad, H., Sadagh, Z., 2000. Investigation of leachate treatment methods in landfills in Mashhad.  First National Congress on Waste Management, Gilan Province, Iran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Zaporozec, A., 2002. Groundwater contamination inventory- a methodological guide. UNESCO, IHP-VI, series on groundwater, No.2, Paris, France.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.32680.2095</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15487_5210e25e486b81434ba8c411b9eaf97e.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی پدیده گرمایش جهانی در استان خوزستان طی دوره 2016-1988 با استفاده از آزمونهای ناپارامتریک</article-title>
			        <subtitle>بررسی پدیده گرمایش جهانی در استان خوزستان طی دوره 2016-1988 با استفاده از آزمونهای ناپارامتریک</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بهادری</surname>
			            <given-names>کورش</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>مدیرکل هواشناسی خوزستان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حجازی زاده</surname>
			            <given-names>زهرابیگم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه خوارزمی تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>سلیقه</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه اقلیم شناسی،دانشکده جغرافی،دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>21</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2020</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>10</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>47</fpage>
			      <lpage>59</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>19</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2020</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>05</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2020</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2020, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15487.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15487.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>افزایش غلظت میزان گازهای گلخانه­ای منجر به تشدید پدیده­ای بنام گرمایش جهانی گردیده است، پدیده­ای که باعث شده تا میانگین دمای سالانه سطح کره زمین طی قرن گذشته 0.74 درجه سانتی­گراد افزایش یابد. گرمایش جهانی پدیده­ای است که اثرات ناخوشایند فراوانی بر زندگی انسان‌ها و جانوران می‌گذارد. رخداد و شدت یافتن پدیده­هایی نظیر خشکسالی­، کاهش بارندگی­، افزایش رخداد روزهای گرد وخاک و سیلاب­ نیز ناشی از پدیده تغییر اقلیم و نهایتاً گرمایش جهانی در دنیا بوده است. در این تحقیق جهت بررسی پدیده گرمایش جهانی در استان خوزستان با استفاده از روش‌های معمول سری‌های زمانی (میانگین‌های متحرک، معادله خط روند-ضریب خط روند) و آزمون ناپارامتریک من کندال، تغییرات درجه حرارت میانگین سالانه هوا طی دوره 2016-1988 در 8 ایستگاه سینوپتیک هواشناسی (آبادان- اهواز- امیدیه- بستان- دزفول رامهرمز- ماهشهر- مسجد سلیمان) مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. نتایج حاصله حاکی از افزایش قابل ملاحظه دمای میانگین هوا در تمام ایستگاه­های استان بوده، به­نحوی که ایستگاه­های منتخب طی دوره مطالعاتی (به جزایستگاه مسجدسلیمان روند افزایشی در سطح 5 درصد) روند افزایشی معنی­­داری در سطح 1 درصد نشان می­دهند. همچنین ایستگاه­های بستان و رامهرمز به ترتیب با 0.107 و 0.097 درجه سانتیگراد در هر سال، بیشترین ضریب افزایش درجه حرارت سالانه را دارا بوده­اند.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>گرمایش جهانی</kwd>
						<kwd>سری‌های زمانی</kwd>
						<kwd>میانگین متحرک</kwd>
						<kwd>معادله خط روند</kwd>
						<kwd>ناپارامتریک</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Alijani, B.V., Ghavidel Rahimi, Y., 2005. Comparison and prediction of annual temperature changes in Tabriz with temperature anomalies of the Earth using linear regression and neural network. Journal of Geography and Development 6, 21-38.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Freiwan, M., Kadioğlu, M., 2008. Climate Variability in Jordan. International Journal of Climatology 28, 69-89.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>IPCC Summary for Policymakers, 2007. In: Solomon, S., Qin, D., Manning, M., Chen, Z., Marquis, M., Averyt, K.B., Tignor, M., Miller, H.L (eds) Climate change 2007: The physical science basis, Contribution of Working Group I to the Fourth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>IPCC Summary for Policymakers, 2013. Detection and Attribution of Climate Change, pp. 14-15.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Jiangping, Z., Zhong, Y., Daojie, W, Xinbao, Z., 2002. Climate change and causes in the Yuanmou Dry-Hot valley of Yunnan, China. Journal of Arid Environments 51, 153-162.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Kumar, P.V., Bindi, M., Crisci, A., Maracchi, G., 2005. Detection of variations in air temperature at different time scales the period 1889-1998 at Firenze, Italy. Climatic Change 72 , 123-50.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Qiang, Z., Jiang, C., Zengxin, Z., 2005. Observed climatic changes in Shanghai during 1873-2002. Journal of Geographical Sciences 15, 217-222.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Shirgholami, H., Ghahraman, B., 2005. The trend of annual temperature change of Iran. Journal of Science and Technology of Agriculture and Natural Resources 9, 10-15.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Sutton, R.T., Dong, B., Gregory, J.M., 2007. Land/sea warming ratio in response to climate change: IPCC AR4 model results and comparison with observations. Geophysical Research Letters 34, 20-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Trenberth, K.E., Jones, P.D., Ambenje, P., Bojariu, R., Easterling, D., Klein, T., Parker, D., 2007. Observations: surface and atmospheric climate change. IPCC, Climate Change, pp. 235-336.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Türkes, M., Sümer, U.M., Kiliç, G., 1998. Observed changes in maximum and minimum temperatures in Turkey. International Journal of Climatology 16, 463-477.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>World Meteorological Organization, 2014. WMO statement on the status of the global climate in 2014.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.30592.2029</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15335_0a945e50801855aa496da34f97506027.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>زمین‌شناسی و زمین‌شیمی کانه زایی مس، در اندیس‌های ده ‌معدن و دره‌یاس، استان چهارمحال و بختیاری، در اندیس‌های ده ‌معدن و دره‌یاس، استان چهارمحال و بختیاری</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>زراسوندی</surname>
			            <given-names>علیرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز ، اهواز، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>پورکاسب</surname>
			            <given-names>هوشنگ</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز ، اهواز، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فاطمی</surname>
			            <given-names>عبدخلیل</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز ، اهواز، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فریدونی</surname>
			            <given-names>زهرا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c5">
			          <name>
			            <surname>قاسمی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمود</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>پژوهشکده علوم زمین، سازمان زمین‌شناسی و اکتشافات معدنی کشور، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>21</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2020</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>10</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>60</fpage>
			      <lpage>77</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>07</day>
			          <month>08</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>18</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2020</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2020, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15335.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15335.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>منطقه مشایخ در استان چهارمحال و بختیاری و از لحاظ ساختاری، در کمربند زاگرس مرتفع واقع شده است. این منطقه از دو کانسار ده‌معدن و دره‌یاس با فاصله‌ی حدوداً 2 کیلومتری، تشکیل شده است. حداکثر کانه‌زایی در ارتباط با واحدهای کربناته‌ی حاوی مواد آلی در کانسار ده‌معدن می‌باشد. حضور گنبد نمکی دو‌آب و گسل‌معکوس آب‌ونک در اطراف منطقه‌ی مورد‌مطالعه باعث تغییر در میزان شوری، Eh، Ph و تحرک سیال کانه‌دار شده است. نتایج زمین‌شیمی، بیانگر وجود ناهنجاری منفی Eu و Ce، غنی‌شدگی عناصر نادر‌خاکی سنگین (HREE‌) نسبت به عناصر نادر‌خاکی سبک (LREE‌) برای کانسار ده‌معدن می‌باشد که بسیار مشابه با کانسارهای مس‌رسوبی کمربند مس آفریقای مرکزی است. کانسار دره‌یاس هم، ناهنجاری منفی Ceو تهی‌شدگی HREE نسبت به LREE را نشان می‌دهد. به طور کلی، نتایج بیانگر این است که سیالی شور با شرایط اکسیدان، فلزات را از واحدهای قدیمی‌تر شسته و به حوضه‌ی رسوبی وارد کرده است. سپس، در اثر برخورد سیالات کانه‌دار با یک واحد کربناته‌ی حاوی مواد آلی، مواد‌معدنی در یک شرایط احیایی ته‌نشین شده اند. در نهایت، ماده معدنی، تحت تاثیر فرآیندهای برون‌زاد و هوازدگی قرار گرفته است.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>مس رسوبی</kwd>
						<kwd>ده‌معدن</kwd>
						<kwd>دره‌یاس</kwd>
						<kwd>منطقه مشایخ</kwd>
						<kwd>چهارمحال و بختیاری</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Ahankoub, M., 2009. Petrological and Geochemical investigation of Naghān Copper Ore Deposit (Ardal), Research Project. Payame Noor University of Shahrekord, p. 113.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Alavi, M.,1994. Tectonics of the Zagros orogenic belt of Iran: newdata and interpretations. Tectonophysics 229, 211–238.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Alavi, M., 2004. Regional stratigraphy of the Zagros fold-thrust belt of Iran and its pro foreland evolution. American Journal of Science 304, 1–20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Alavi, M., 2007. Structure of the Zagros Fold-Thrust Belt in Iran. American Journal of Science 307, 1064–1095.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Bau, M., Dulski, P., 1996. Distribution of yttrium and rare-earth elements in the Penge and Kuruman iron-formations, Transvaal Supergroup, South Africa. Precambrian Research 79, 37–55.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Bhatia, M.R., Crook, K.A.M., 1986. Trace element characteristics of graywackes and tectonic discriminiation of sedimentary basins. Contributions to Mineralogy and Petrology 92, 181-193.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Bornhorst, T.J., Williams, W.C., 2013. The Mesoproterozoic Copperwood sedimentary rock-hosted stratiform copper deposit, Upper Peninsula, Michigan. Economic Geology 108, 1325-1346.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Boynton, W.V., 1984. Geochemistry of the rare earth elements: meteorite studies. In: Henderson. P. Rare Earth Element geochemistry. (Ed.). Elsevier, Amsterdam, pp. 114.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Cailteux, J.L.H., Kampunzu, A.B., Lerouge, C., Kaputo, A.K., Milesi, J.P., 2005. Genesis of sediment-hosted strati-form copper-cobalt deposits, central African Copper belt. Journal of African Earth Sciences 42, 134–158.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Condie, K.C., Wronkiewicz, D.S., 1990. The Ce/Th ratio in Precambrian pelites from the Kaapvaal Craton as an index of cratanic evolution. Earth and Planetary Science Letters 97, 256-267.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Cox, D.P., Bernstein, L.R., 1986. Descriptive model of Kipushi Cu-Pb-Zn, Mineral deposit models: U.S. Geological Survey Bulletin 1693, 227.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Ehsan Bakhshi Kermani, M.H., Rahimzadeh, F., Qomishi, A., Jamshidi, KH., 1996. Map 1: 100000 Ardal, Geological Survey and Mineral Exploration of Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Ghorbani, M., 2007. Economic Geology of Mineral Deposits and Natural Resources of Iran, 1st edition, Arian Zamin Publishers, p. 492.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Hayes, T.S., 1990. A preliminary study of thermometry and metal sources of the Spar Lake stratabound copper-silver deposit, Belt Supergroup, Montana, U.S. Geological Survey 90-484, p. 30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Hitzman, M., Kirkham, R., Broughton, D., Thorson, J., Selley, D., 2005. The sediment hosted stratiform copper ore system. Economic Geology, 609–642.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Hitzman, M.W., Selley, D., Bull, S., 2010. Formation of sedimentary rock-hosted stratiform copper deposits through Earth history. Economic Geology 105, 627–639.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Hongo, Y., Nozaki, Y., 2001. Rare earth element geochemistry of hydrothermal deposits and Calyptogena shell from the Iheya Ridge vent field, Okinawa Trough. Geochemical journal 35, 347–354.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Jones, B., Manning, D.C., 1994. Comparison of geochemical indices used for the interpretation of paleo-redox conditions in Ancient mudstones. Chemical Geology 111, 111-129.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Kirkham, R.V., 1989. Distribution, settings, and genesis of sediment-hosted stratiform copper deposits. In: Boyle, R.W., Brown, A.C., Jefferson, C.W., Jowett, E.C., Kirkham, R.V. (Eds). Sediment-hosted stratiform copper deposits. Geological Association of Canada, Special Paper 36, p. 3–38.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>McLennan, S.M., 1989. Rare earth elements in sedimentary rocks: influence of provenance and sedimentary processes. Geochemistry and mineralogy of rear earth elements. Review in Mineralogy 21, 169-200.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>McLennan, S.M., Taylor, S.R., 1991. Sedimentary rocks and crustal evolution revisited: tectonic setting and secular trends. The Journal of Geology 99, 1-21.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Nesbitt, H.W., Young, G.M., 1982. Early Proterozoic climates and plate motions inferred from major element chemistry of lutites, Nature 299, 715-717.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Nesbitt, H.W., Young, G.M., 1989. Formation and diagenesis of weathering profile, The Journal of Geology 97, 129-174.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Norman, M.D., De Deckker, P., 1990. Trace elements in lacustrine and marine sediments: a case study from gulf of Carpentaria, northern Australia. Chemical geology 82, 299-318.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Nowecki, J.P., 2014. Tracing seawater evaporation and its role in the formation of sediment-hosted stratiform copper deposits (Doctoral dissertation, University of Southampton).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Ohmoto, H., 1986. Stable isotope geochemistry of ore deposits. In: Valley, J.W., Taylor, H.P., O’Neil, J.R. (Eds). Stable isotopes in high temperature geological processes. Reviews in Mineralogy 16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Pirajno, F., Mernagh, T.P., Huston, D., Creaser, R.A. and Seltmann, R., 2016. The Mesoproterozoic Abra polymetallic sedimentary rock-hosted mineral deposit, Edmund Basin, Western Australia. Ore Geology Reviews 76, 442-462.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Richards, J.P., Spell, T., Rameh, E., Razique, A., Fletcher, T., 2012. High Sr/Y Magmas Reflect Arc Maturity, High Magmatic Water Content, and Porphyry Cu ± Mo ± Au Potential: Examples from the Tethyan Arcs of Central and Eastern Iran and Western Pakistan. Economic Geology 107, 295-332.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Rimmer, S.M., 2004. Geochemical paleoredox indicators in the Devonian– Mississippian black shales, central Appalachian Basin (USA). Chemical Geology 206, 373–391.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Roberts, S., Palmer, M.R., Cooper, M.J., Buchaus, P., Sargent, D., 2009. REE and Sr isotope characteristics of carbonate within the Cu–Co mineralized sedimentary sequence of the Nchanga Mine, Zambian Copper belt. Mineralium Deposita 44, 881–891.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Rollinson, H., 1996. Using geochemical data: evaluation, presentation, interpretation. Longman Scientific and Technical, John Wiley and Sons, New York.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Taylor, C.D., Causey, J.D., Denning, P.D., Hammarstrom, J.M., Hayes, T.S., Horton, J.D., Kirschbaum, M.J., Parks, H.L., Wilson, A.B., Wintzer, N.E., Zientek, M.L., 2013. Descriptive models, grade-tonnage relations, and databases for the assessment of sediment-hosted copper deposits-With emphasis on deposits in the Central African Copperbelt, Democratic Republic of the Congo and Zambia, U.S. Geological Survey, Scientific Investigations Report 2010–5090–J, 154.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Toth, J.R., 1980. Deposition of submarine crusts rich in manganese and iron. Geological Society of America Bulletin 91, p. 44– 54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Webb, G.E., Kamber, B.S., 2000. Rare earth elements in Holocene reefal microbialites; a new shallow seawater proxy, Geochimica et Cosmochimica Acta 64, 1557–1565.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Zarasvandi, A., Charchi, A., Carranza, E.J.M., Alizadeh, B., 2008. Karst bauxite occurrence in the Zagros Mountain Belt, Iran. Ore Geology Reviews 34, 521- 553.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Zarasvandi, A., Lentz, D., Rezaei, M., Pourkaseb, H., 2013. Genesis of the Nasirabad manganese occurrence, Fars province, Iran: Geochemical evidences. Geochemistry 73, 495-508.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Zhao, X.F., Zhou, M.F., Li, J.W. and Qi, L., 2013. Late Paleoproterozoic sedimentary rock-hosted stratiform copper deposits in South China: their possible link to the supercontinent cycle. Mineralium Deposita 48, 129-136.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28733.1946</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15072_bba0a26a5f0966543c72edbaa7d414ab.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>مطالعه عوامل مؤثر در تشکیل فرو چاله‌ها در جنوب شهر پل دختر، جنوب غرب ایران</article-title>
			        <subtitle>مطالعه عوامل مؤثر در تشکیل فرو چاله‌ها در جنوب شهر پل دختر، جنوب غرب ایران</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>قبادی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد حسین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>زمین شناسی،دانشکده علوم ،دانشگاه بوعلی سینا،همدان ،ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نوریزدان</surname>
			            <given-names>عبدالرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>21</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2020</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>10</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>78</fpage>
			      <lpage>95</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>27</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>18</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2020, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15072.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15072.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>فرو چاله‌ها در دشت‌های پوشیده از رسوبات کواترنر با سنگ‌بستر انحلال‌پذیر، فراوانی بیش‌تری دارند. بیش‌تر دشت‌ها در منطقه زاگرس چین‌خورده در ایران کارستی هستند. این پژوهش در گستره‌ای به مساحت 155 کیلومترمربع باهدف ارزیابی عوامل مؤثر در فرو چاله زایی در محل قدیمی دریاچه‌های جایدر گوری بلمک در جنوب شهر پل‌دختر، جنوب غرب ایران انجام‌شده است. این دریاچه‌ها در اثر وقوع بهمن سنگی سیمره در جنوب غرب ایران تشکیل‌شده بودند. در این منطقه رسوبات دریاچه‌ای ناشی از ایجاد سدهای زمین‌لغزشی گسترش دارند. بر اساس نتایج حاصل از انجام مطالعات ژئوفیزیکی در منطقه به روش‌های GPR با آنتن 10 مگاهرتز و توموگرافی مقاومت ویژه الکتریکی (ERT)، ضخامت رسوبات دریاچه‌ای قدیمی جایدر در محل دشت جایدر به‌طور متوسط 70 متر و در محل دریاچه قدیمی گوری بلمک کمتر از 10 مترمی باشد. سنگ‌بستر رسوبات هر دو دریاچه سازند تبخیری گچساران است. سازند مذکور ازنظر سنی به سنوزوئیک تعلق دارد. مقاومت فشاری تک‌محوری و کششی بخش ژیپس سنگ بستر به ترتیب 39/16 و 5/1 مگا پاسکال است. حداقل 4 دسته درزه در توده سنگ‌بستر گسترش دارد. منشأ مواد پرکننده درزه‌ها، ناشی از فرسایش واحدهای مارنی سازند گچساران و رسوبات دریاچه‌ای می‌باشند. ..</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>فروچاله</kwd>
						<kwd>سازند گچساران</kwd>
						<kwd>انحلال‌پذیری ژیپس</kwd>
						<kwd>واگرایی مواد پرکننده درزه‌ها</kwd>
						<kwd>بهمن سنگی سیمره</kwd>
						<kwd>پل‌دختر</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Bell, F.G., Maud, R.R., 1994. Dispersive Soils: A Review from a South African Perspective. Quaternary Journal of Engineering Geology 11, 195 -210.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Deer, D.U., Miller, R.P., 1966. Engineering classification and index properties for intact rock. Technical Report No. AFWL-TR-65-116, Air Force Weapons Laboratory, Kirland Air Force Base, New Mexico.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Ezersky, M., Frumkin, A., 2013. Fault-Dissolution fronts relations and the Dead Sea sinkhole problem. Journal of Geomorphology 201, 35-44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Galloway, D., Jones, D.R., Ingebritsen, S.E.,1999. Land subsidence in the United States US geological Survey Circular, pp. 182.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Gutierrez, F., Galve, J.P., Lucha, P., Bonachea, J., Pardo, G., Sanchez, J.A., Gutierrez, M., Gimeno, M. J, Remondo, J., Cendrero, A., 2009. Sinkholes in the salt-bearing evaporate karst of the Ebro River valley upstream of Zaragoza city (NE Spain) Geomorphological mapping and analysis as a basis for risk management. Journal of Geomorphology 108, 145-158.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Gutierrez, F., Guerrero, J., Bonachea, J., Lucha, P., 2008. A sinkhole susceptibility zonation based on paleokarst analysis along a stretch of the Madrid-Barcelona high-speed railway built over gypsum and salt- bearing. Jornal of Engineering Geology 102, 62-73.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Heidari, M., Khanlari, G.R., Taleb Beydokhti, A.R., Momeni, A.A., 2011. The formation of cover collapse sinkholes in North of Hamedan, Iran. Journal of Geomorphology 132, 76-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Jennings, J.E., Knight, K., 1975. A guide to construction on or with materials exhibiting additional settlement due to collapse of grain structure. Proceedings of the sixth Regional Conference for Africa on Soil Mechanics and Foundation Engineering, pp. 99-105.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Sherard, J.L., Dunnigan, L.P., Deker, R.S, 1976. Identification and nature of dispersive soils ASCE. Journal of Geotechnical Division 102, 69-85.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Sourinezhad, A., 2002. The estimation of runoff in the watershed basin of Kashkan River using GIS. Journal of Geoghraphic Researches 43, 57-80. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Taheri, K., Gutierrez, F., Mohseni, H., Raeisi, E., Taheri, M., 2015. Sinkholesusceptibility mapping using the analytical hierarchy process (AHP) and magnitude-frequency relationships: case study in Hamadan province, Iran. Geomorphology 234, 64-79.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Waltham, T., Bell, F., Culshaw, M., 2005. Sinkhols and subsidence, karst and cavernous rock in engineering and construction, Springer, Chichester, pp. 373.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.31475.2047</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15338_bf8b9a8dffddefe9fa82eeb3cc4d1ed7.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تخمین پارامترهای مخزنی با استفاده از داده های چاه پیمایی و بهره گیری از ترکیب شبکه عصبی مصنوعی و الگوریتم بهینه سازی ازدحام ذرات</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>زحمت کش</surname>
			            <given-names>ایمان</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محسنی پور</surname>
			            <given-names>ابوذر</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناس مطالعات پتروفیزیک و مخزن شرکت ملی حفاری ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>امرائی</surname>
			            <given-names>امین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>شرکت پتروپارس</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>21</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2020</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>10</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>96</fpage>
			      <lpage>109</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>21</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>06</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2020</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2020, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15338.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15338.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>پارامترهای ژئومکانیکی و پتروفیزیکی مخزن همانند سرعت موج برشی، تخلخل و تراوایی از جمله پارامترهای مهمی هستند که در شبیه‌سازی مخازن هیدروکربوری و استراتژی‌های اکتشافی نقش موثری ایفا می کنند. اخیراً روش‌های هوش مصنوعی به‌منظور پیش‌بینی این پارامترها با استفاده از داده‌های چاه پیمایی به‌کاربرده شده‌اند. بااین‌حال پیش‌بینی ویژگی‌های مخازن ناهمگن همواره با دشوارهای بسیاری همراه است و به‌سختی پاسخ مناسبی به‌دست‌آمده است. در این مطالعه تلاش شده است تا پارامترهای مخزنی سرعت موج برشی، تخلخل و تراوایی با استفاده از روش نوین ترکیب شبکه عصبی مصنوعی و الگوریتم بهینه سازی ازدحام ذرات (PSO-ANN)، در مخزن هتروژن آسماری میدان منصوری تخمین زده شود. سپس عملکرد این مدل ترکیبی با روش های کلاسیک و مرسوم شبکه عصبی مصنوعی (ANN) و سیستم تطبیقی استنتاج نروفازی (ANFIS) و همچنین روش ترکیب شبکه عصبی مصنوعی و الگوریتم ژنتیک (GA-ANN) مورد مقایسه قرار گرفته است. نتایج نشان دهنده عملکرد بسیار مناسب روش ترکیبی شبکه عصبی مصنوعی و الگوریتم بهینه سازی ازدحام ذرات در تخمین پارامترهای مخزنی است. بنابراین می توان از مدل ترکیبی شبکه عصبی مصنوعی و الگوریتم بهینه سازی ازدحام ذرات به عنوان یک روش قدرتمند در تخمین سایر پارامترهای مخزنی به خصوص در مواقعی که دقت بالای پیش بینی لازم باشد استفاده نمود.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>الگوریتم ازدحام ذرات</kwd>
						<kwd>مدل الگوریتم ازدحام ذرات-شبکه عصبی (PSO-ANN)</kwd>
						<kwd>پارامترهای مخزنی</kwd>
						<kwd>تراوایی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Anselmetti, F.S., Eberli, G.P., 1993. Controls on sonic velocity in carbonates. Pure and Applied Geophysics 141(2–4), 287–323.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Bastos, A.C., Dillon, L.D., Vasquez, G.F., Soares, J.A., 1998. Core-derived acoustic, porosity &amp; permeability correlations for computation pseudo-logs. Geological Society, London, Special Publications, 136(1), 141–146.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Brocher, T.M., 2005. Empirical relations between elastic wavespeeds and density in the Earth’s crust. Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America 95(6), 2081–2092.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Chau, K.W., 2007. Application of a PSO-based neural network in analysis of outcomes of construction claims. Automation in Construction 16(5), 642–646.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Dhanarajan, G., Mandal, M., Sen, R., 2014. A combined artificial neural network modeling–particle swarm optimization strategy for improved production of marine bacterial lipopeptide from food waste. Biochemical Engineering Journal 84, 59–65.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Domenico, S.N., 1984. Rock lithology and porosity determination from shear and compressional wave velocity. Geophysics 49(8), 1188–1195.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Eberhart-Phillips, D., Han, D.H., Zoback, M.D., 1989. Empirical relationships among seismic velocity, effective pressure, porosity, and clay content in sandstone. Geophysics 54(1), 82–89.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Eberhart, R.C., Kennedy, J., 1995. A new optimizer using particle swarm theory. In Proceedings of the sixth international symposium on micro machine and human science. New York, NY, pp. 39–43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Garat, J., Krief, M., Stellingwerf, J., Ventre, J., 1990. A petrophysical interpretation using the velocities of P and S waves (full-waveform sonic). The Log Analyst 31(06).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Gardner, G.H.F., Gardner, L.W., Gregory, A.R., 1974. Formation velocity and density-the diagnostic basics for stratigraphic traps. Geophysics 39(6), 770–780.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Grimaldi, E.M., Grimaccia, F., Mussetta, M., Zich, R.E., 2004. PSO as an effective learning algorithm for neural network applications. In Computational Electromagnetics and Its Applications, 2004. Proceedings. ICCEA 2004. 2004 3rd International Conference on IEEE, pp. 557–560.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Huang, W., Zhou, L., Qian, J., Ma, L., 2005. FIR frequency sampling filters design based on adaptive particle swarm optimization algorithm. In Advances in Natural Computation. Springer, pp. 289–298.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Jamialahmadi, M., Javadpour, F.G., 2000. Relationship of permeability, porosity and depth using an artificial neural network. Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering 26(1), 235–239.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Kadkhodaie-Ilkhchi, A., Rezaee, M.R., Rahimpour-Bonab, H., Chehrazi, A., 2009. Petrophysical data prediction from seismic attributes using committee fuzzy inference system. Computers &amp; Geosciences 35(12), 2314–2330.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Kadkhodaie‐Ilkhchi, A., Amini, A., 2009. A fuzzy logic approach to estimating hydraulic flow units from well log data: A case study from the Ahwaz oilfield, south Iran. Journal of Petroleum Geology 32(1), 67–78.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Karimi, H., Yousefi, F., 2012. Application of artificial neural network–genetic algorithm (ANN–GA) to correlation of density in nanofluids. Fluid Phase Equilibria 336, 79–83.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Kennedy, J., Kennedy, J.F., Eberhart, R.C., Shi, Y., 2001. Swarm intelligence, Morgan Kaufmann.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Labani, M.M., Kadkhodaie-Ilkhchi, A., Salahshoor, K., 2010. Estimation of NMR log parameters from conventional well log data using a committee machine with intelligent systems: A case study from the Iranian part of the South Pars gas field, Persian Gulf Basin. Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering 72(1), 175–185.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Lim, J.S., 2005. Reservoir properties determination using fuzzy logic and neural networks from well data in offshore Korea. Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering 49(3), 182–192.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Lin, X., Sun, J., Palade, V., Fang, W., Wu, X., Xu, W., 2012. Training ANFIS parameters with a quantum-behaved particle swarm optimization algorithm. In Advances in Swarm Intelligence, Springer, pp. 148–155.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Meulenkamp, F., Grima, M.A., 1999. Application of neural networks for the prediction of the unconfined compressive strength (UCS) from Equotip hardness. International Journal of Rock Mechanics and Mining Sciences 36(1), 29–39.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Moradi, M., Tokhmechi, B., Masoudi, P., 2017. Inversion of well logs into rock types, lithofacies and environmental facies, using pattern recognition, a case study of carbonate Sarvak Formation. Carbonates and Evaporites, 1–13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Murphy, W., Reischer, A., Hsu, K., 1993. Modulus decomposition of compressional and shear velocities in sand bodies. Geophysics 58(2), 227–239.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Nawi, N.M., Ransing, M.R., Ransing, R.S., 2006. An Improved Learning Algorithm based on the Conjugate Gradient Method for Back Prooagation Neural Networks. Proc of World Academy of Science, Eng, and Technology, 14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Nikravesh, M., Aminzadeh, F., 2001. Mining and fusion of petroleum data with fuzzy logic and neural network agents. Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering 29(3), 221–238.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Nikravesh, M., Zadeh, L.A., Aminzadeh, F., 2003. Soft computing and intelligent data analysis in oil exploration, Elsevier.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Rini, D. P., Shamsuddin, S. M., Yuhaniz, S.S., 2016. Particle swarm optimization for ANFIS interpretability and accuracy. Soft Computing 20(1), 251–262.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Sfidari, E., Amini, A., Kadkhodaie, A., Ahmadi, B., 2012. Electrofacies clustering and a hybrid intelligent based method for porosity and permeability prediction in the South Pars Gas Field, Persian Gulf. Geopersia 2(2), 11–23.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Tabatabaei, S.M.E., Kadkhodaie-Ilkhchi, A., Hosseini, Z., Moghaddam, A.A., 2015. A hybrid stochastic-gradient optimization to estimating total organic carbon from petrophysical data: A case study from the Ahwaz oilfield, SW Iran. Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering 127, 35–43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Tokhmechi, B., Rasouli, V., Azizi, H., Rabiei, M., 2018. Hybrid clustering-estimation for characterization of thin bed heterogeneous reservoirs. Carbonates and Evaporites, 1–13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Von Altrock, C., 1995. Fuzzy logic and neurofuzzy applications explained. Prentice-Hall, Inc.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Zahmatkesh, I., Soleimani, B., Kadkhodaie, A., Golalzadeh, A., Abdollahi, A.M., 2017. Estimation of DSI log parameters from conventional well log data using a hybrid particle swarm optimization–adaptive neuro-fuzzy inference system. Journal of Petroleum Science and Engineering 157, 842-859.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">JAAG</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2251-7057</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">13</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28325.1934</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15070_6887b3cc25925d54f7e6d16f224b3820.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>آشکارسازی سدهای باطله معدنی با استفاده از تصاویر چندطیفی سنجنده استر، مطالعه موردی: معدن سرب-روی انگوران، جنوب غرب زنجان</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مظهری</surname>
			            <given-names>نازی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه شیراز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>کریمی</surname>
			            <given-names>مرجان</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه شیراز-دانشکده علوم بخش علوم زمین</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بیات</surname>
			            <given-names>پروین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه شیراز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>برومند</surname>
			            <given-names>محمدصالح</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه شیراز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>21</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2020</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>10</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>110</fpage>
			      <lpage>120</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>23</day>
			          <month>01</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>18</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2020, Shahid Chamran University of Ahvaz. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2020</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15070.html">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15070.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>یکی ازاهداف سنجش از دور زمین شناختی، تلاش برای بهبود روش های نقشه برداری انواع سنگ ها و کانی هاست. شناسایی آلودگی‌های زیست محیطی ایجاد شده در اثر فعالیت‌های نامحدود معدنی با استفاده از این داده‌ها از لحاظ اقتصادی و زمانی مقرون به-صرفه بوده ‌است. بارزسازی هر چه سریعتر این آلودگی‌ها در زمینه حل مشکلات زیست محیطی گام مهمی برداشته خواهد شد. بدون شک استفاده از این فناوری در مطالعات اکتشافی ، منابع طبیعی و زیست محیطی نه تنها سرعت انجام مطالعات را بیشتر می‌کند، بلکه از نظر دقت، هزینه و نیروی انسانی نیز بسیار با صرفه‌تر است. هدف از این تحقیق، بارزسازی باطله‌های معدنی سرب-روی انگوران با استفاده از داده‌های استر می‌باشد. بررسی رفتار سنگ‌ها و کانی‌های و استفاده از روش‌های ترکیب رنگی کاذب (R:1,G:6,B:3)، تحلیل مولفه‌های اصلی و نسبت‌گیری باندی به صورت ترکیب رنگی کاذب (R3/2,G5/3,B8/4) موجب نقشه برداری باطله‌های معدن گردید. استفاده از سه PC اول و بررسی مقدار ویژه بردار نشان می‌دهد که مولفه‌های پنجم و نهم با مقادیر ویژه بردار 72/0 و 65/0 دلالت بر رفتار طیفی کانی‌های کربناته و رسی در باندهای 8 و 6 دارد. اعتبارسنجی پردازش‌های انجام شده در نهایت از طریق طیف‌های کتابخانه‌ای، طیف‌های بازنویسی شده و طیف تصویر صورت گرفت.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>معدن سرب-روی انگوران</kwd>
						<kwd>سنجنده استر</kwd>
						<kwd>ترکیب رنگی کاذب</kwd>
						<kwd>تحلیل مؤلفه اصلی</kwd>
						<kwd>نسبت‌گیری باندی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Borg, G., Daliran, F., 2004. Hypogene and supergene formation of sulphides and non-sulphides at the Angouran high-grade zinc deposit, NW-Iran. In: Abstract volume of Geoscience Africa 2004. University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, pp. 69–70.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Bradl, H. B., 2005. Heavy elements in environment, Elsevier Ltd, 283 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Daliran, F., Bor., G., 2005. Characterisation of the nonsulfide zinc ore at Angouran, northwestern Iran, and its genetic aspects, In: Jingwen, M., Bierlein, F.P., (eds) Mineral deposit research: meeting the global change, Springer, Berlin Heidelberg New York, pp. 913–916.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Daliran, F., Hofstra, A., Walther, J., Stüben, D., 2002. Agdarreh and Zarshuran SRHDG deposits, Takab region, NW-Iran. Annual meeting of the Geological Society of America, Denver, pp. 63–68l.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Fu, X. L., Song, T. T., Chen, Y., Wei, Y. M., Wang, Q. J., 2017. Inversion analysis of heavy metal pollution in soil in mining disturbed areas based on remote sensing data: A case study of Lanping Zn-Pb mining area. Journal of Residuals Science and Technology, 14(3).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Fujisada, H., Ono, A., 1994. Observational performance of ASTER instrument on EOS-AM1 spacecraft. Advances in Space Research 14(3), 147-150.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Gasmi, A., Gomez, C., Zouari, H., Masse, A., Ducrot, D., 2016. PCA and SVM as geo-computational methods for geological mapping in the southern of Tunisia, using ASTER remote sensing data set. Arabian Journal of Geosciences 9(20), 753.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Gilg, H.A., 1996. Fluid inclusion and isotope constraints on the genesis of high-temperature carbonate-hosted Pb–Zn–Ag deposits. Society of Economic Geologists Special Publication 4, 501–514.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Gilg, H.A., Allen. C., Balassone. G., Boni. M., Moore. F., 2003. The 3- stage evolution of the   Angouran Zn “oxide”-sulfide deposit, Iran, In: Eliopoulos, D., et al (eds) Mineral exploration and sustainable development. Millpress, Rotterdam, pp. 77–80.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Gupta, R.P., 2017. Remote sensing geology. Springer Publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Gupta, R.P., 1991. Remote sensing geology.Springer Publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Jahromi, H., Kafilzadeh, V., Momeni, H., 2009. The effect of lead acetate on body weight and kidney and tissue structure of all one-day-old children of Balb / C mice. Journal of Environmental Science and Technology 4, 269-277.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Hamdi, B., 1995. Precambrian–Cambrian deposits in Iran. In: Hushmandzadeh, A., (ed) Treatise of the geology of Iran, Geological Survey of Iran, Tehran, pp. 1–535.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Holland, S.M., 2008. Principal components analysis (PCA). Department of Geology, University of Georgia, Athens, GA, 30602-2501.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Kruse, F.A., 1988. Use of airborne imaging spectrometer data to map minerals associated with hydrothermally altered rocks in the northern grapevine mountains, Nevada, and California. Remote Sensing of Environment 24(1), 31-51.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Mezned, N., Abdeljaoued, S., Boussema, M. R., 2007. ASTER multispectral imagery for spectral unmixing based mine tailing cartography in the north of Tunisia. In Remote Sensing and Photogrammetry Society Annual Conference.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Modabberi, S., Ahmadi, A., Tangestani, M. H., 2017. Sub-pixel mapping of alunite and jarosite using ASTER data; a case study from north of Semnan, north central Iran. Ore Geology Reviews 80, 429-436.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Mohy, H., Basta, F.F., Saber, S.G., El Sobky, A.F. A., 2017. Using Landsat 8 and ASTER Data for lithological Discrimination and Mapping in Wadi Hamad area, North Eastern Desert, Egypt. Journal of American Science, 13(7).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Prost, G.L., 2002. Remote sensing for geologists: a guide to image interpretation. CRC Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Richards, J. A., Richards, J. A., 1999. Remote sensing digital image analysis, Springer Publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Sadiya, T. B., Ibrahim, O., Asma, T. F., Mamfe, V., Nsofor, C. J., Oyewmi, A. S., Ozigis, M. S., 2010. Mineral Detection and Mapping Using Band Ratioing and Crosta Technique in Bwari Area Council, Abuja Nigeria.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Sayareh, R., Fonudi, M., Dadsetan, A., 2005. Preliminary report of environmental geological studies in Qorveh and Bijar region, Geological Survey of Iran, pp. 20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Short, A.D., Trembanis, A.C., 2004. Decadal scale patterns in beach oscillation and rotation Narrabeen Beach, Australia—time series, PCA and wavelet analysis. Journal of Coastal Research, 523-532.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Yamaguchi, Y., Kahle, A.B., Tsu, H., Kawakami, T., pinel, M., 1998. Overview of advanced Space borne Thermal Emission and reflection radometr(aster), IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remot Sensing 36, 1062- 1071.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Yang, M., Ren, G., Han, L., Yi, H., Gao, T., 2018. Detection of Pb–Zn mineralization zones in west Kunlun using Landsat 8 and ASTER remote sensing data. Journal of Applied Remote Sensing 12(2), 026018.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>