<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Comparison of ASTER and landsat-8 OLI data for detecting Iron occurrences and alteration in Shahrak area, Kurdistan Province</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مقایسه عملکرد تصاویر ماهواره ای ASTER و لندست-8 OLI در بارزسازی رخداد آهن و دگرسانی ها در منطقه شهرک، استان کردستان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15078</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.29579.1986</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>بنیادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احسان</FirstName>
					<LastName>دریانورد</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم پایه، دانشگاه بین المللی امام خمینی (ره)، قزوین، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The performance of various spectral processing techniques has been studied and evaluated using the ASTER and OLI satellite images of the Shahrak mining district. The district is located 60 kilometers north of Bijar city, Kurdistan province. Different band ratios and false color composites were prepared to determine which of them are more adequate for the detection of iron occurrences, chlorite-epidote and clay alteration. Principal Component Analysis (PCA), Independent Component Analysis (ICA) and Minimum Noise Fraction (MNF) transforms were also applied to the bands of ASTER and OLI images. The extracted images indicate the OLI image in the PCA method is better than the ASTER image, and is able to detect iron mineralization and clay alteration more efficiently. In the ICA technique, the OLI image also reveals more details, so that the color combination IC3, IC2, IC1, in addition to identifying the above phenomena, also has a high potential for lithological mapping. In the MNF transform, the OLI image performs better than the Aster image. From the three transforms applied, ICA and then MNF had better outcomes than the PCA in the OLI image.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مطالعه عملکرد تکنیک های مختلف پردازش طیفی بر روی داده های سنجنده استر و لندست-8 OLI مربوط به محدوده معدنی شهرک واقع در 60 کیلومتری شمال شهرستان بیجار در استان کردستان مورد مقایسه قرار گرفته است. نسبت های باندی و ترکیب های رنگی کاذب متعددی تهیه شدند تا مشخص شود کدام‌یک برای بارزسازی رخداد آهن، مجموعه کلریت-اپیدوت و دگرسانی رسی کارآیی بهتری دارند. تبدیل های طیفی آنالیز مولفه های اصلی (PCA)، آنالیز مولفه های مستقل (ICA) و کسر کمترین نویز (MNF) نیز بر روی باندهای تصاویر استر و OLI اعمال شدند. تصاویر به دست آمده نشان می دهند که تصویر OLI در روش PCA بهتر از تصویر استر قادر به بارزسازی کانه زایی آهن و دگرسانی رسی است. در تکنیک ICA تصویر OLI جزییات بیشتری را آشکار می سازد، به گونه ای که ترکیب رنگی IC3, IC2, IC1 علاوه بر بارزسازی پدیده های فوق، پتانسیل بالایی در تهیه نقشه لیتولوژیکی نیز دارد. در تبدیل MNF نیز تصویر OLI عملکرد بهتری نسبت به تصویر استر دارد. از میان سه تبدیل به کار رفته، ICA و سپس MNF کارایی بهتری نسبت به PCA در تصویر OLI داشتند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لندست 8-OLI</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کانه زایی آهن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دگرسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شهرک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
