<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Determination of empirical relation between Electrical resistivity and moisture content of municipal solid waste at a closed landfil, in Lali, Khuzestan, Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>برآورد رابطه تجربی بین مقاومت الکتریکی و محتوای رطوبت پسماندهای جامد شهری در جایگاه انباشت زباله غیرفعال در شهر لالی، استان خوزستان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15495</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.30422.2019</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>نیامدپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه آزاد مسجدسلیمان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Abstract&lt;br /&gt; In this study, the empirical relation between electrical resistivity and moisture content of municipal solid waste was determined at a closed landfill site. Samples obtained from drilled boreholes were investigated to measure their physical properties. In this study, a specific electrode array, dipole-dipole array, was used in laboratory measurements since it is very useful in 2D and 3D electrical resistivity tomography. After correction of temperature and compression effects on the electrical resistivity data in laboratory, a strong correlation was developed between electrical resistivity and moisture content of samples. The validity of obtained mathematical relation was confirmed by using it in moisture content estimation of a new borehole. The data of this borehole were not used to determine the empirical relation between electrical resistivity and moisture content of the samples. A comparison of the estimated moisture content with the corresponding values measured in the laboratory indicates a very strong correlation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش رابطه تجربی بین مقاومت الکتریکی و محتوای رطوبت زباله‌های جامد شهری در یک جایگاه انباشت زباله‌های غیر فعال برآورد شد. نمونه‌های بدست آمده از گمانه‌های حفر شده، برای اندازه‌گیری خواص فیزیکی آنها مورد بررسی قرار‌گرفتند. پس از انجام تصحیحات اثر دما و فشرده سازی برروی داده-های مقاومت الکتریکی اندازه گیری شده در آزمایشگاه، یک همبستگی بالا بین مقاومت الکتریکی و محتوای رطوبت نمونه‌ها توسعه داده شد. برای ارزیابی اعتبار رابطه ریاضی بدست آمده، از این رابطه برای تخمین مقدار محتوای رطوبت نمونه های مربوط به یک گمانه جدید استفاده شد. داده‌های این گمانه در تعیین رابطه تجربی بدست آمده بین مقاومت الکتریکی و محتوای رطوبت نمونه‌ها استفاده نشده بودند. مقایسه محتوای رطوبت تخمین زده شده با مقادیر متناظر اندازه گیری شده در آزمایشگاه، نشان دهنده یک همبستگی بسیار قوی می‌باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محتوای رطوبت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مقاومت الکتریکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زباله جامد شهری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همبستگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محل دفن زباله</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
