<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study of the formation conditions and gemology potential of cordierite, Kyanite and Andalusites in the metamorphic aureole of Alvand Complex, Hamedan, Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مطالعه شرایط تشکیل و پتانسیل گوهرشناسی کردیریت، کیانیت و آندالوزیت‌های موجود در هاله دگرگونی کمپلکس الوند، همدان، ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>440</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>453</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15071</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28506.1938</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عادل</FirstName>
					<LastName>ساکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مدیر گروه زمین شناسی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>زراسوندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیات علمی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>مزرعه</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The study area is located in the metamorphic aureole of Alvand Complex Hamedan province. Structurally, the study area is placed in the Sanandaj-Sirjan metamorphic zone. The cordierites in the mesosome of the migmatites have coarse crystals and are accompanied by spinel (lal), which has formed due to the increasing of metamorphism temperature and partial melting processes. The molar fraction (Xmg) of cordierite increases with the increasing degree of metamorphism from the zone of K-feldspar-cordierite to spinel- cordierite (0.45 to 0.620).The approximate temperature for the cordierites in the mesosome of the migmatites is estimated to be 750 ° C and the pressure is ~ 4 kb. Kyanite is specifically hosted by quartz veins in the region, but it is also found in the adjacent of metamorphosed rocks and in the vicinity of veins. The existence of kyanite veins indicates that it&#039;s not limited to high pressure facies, but may be formed by hydrothermal pressures. Chiastolite with 20 cm long and 4 cm wide, which is the main outcrop of the Chiastolite schists around Zaman –bad. According to the results of geothermobarometry, the temperature and pressure of Chiastolie schists are 628 ° C, and pressure is about 4 kbar. According to gemology studies, Cordierites are suitable for cabochon and fantasy cut, the high level resistant of this</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">منطقه مورد مطالعه در هاله دگرگونی باتولیت الوند، استان همدان، واقع شده است. کردیریت‌های موجود درمزوسوم میگماتیت‌های منطقه بسیار درشت بلور &lt;br /&gt; می‌باشند و همراه با اسپینل (لعل) هستندکه بالا رفتن دمای دگرگونی و پدیدة ذوب بخشی سبب رشد آنها شده است. مقدار کسر مولی (xmg) کردیریت با افزایش درجه دگرگونی از زون فلدسپار پتاسیم – کردیریت تا اسپینل – کردیریت افزایش می‌یابد ( 45/0 تا 62/0). دما و فشار تشکیل کردیریت‌ها 750 درجه سانتیگراد و فشار آن معادل 4 کیلوبار می‌باشد. کیانیت به طور مشخص خاص رگه‌های کوارتزی در منطقه است، اکیاستولیت‌هایی با طول 20سانتی متر و عرض 4 سانتی متر در منطقه بوجود آمده اند که گسترس اصلی شیست‌های کیاستولیت دار در حوالی زمان آباد است، دما و فشار تشکیل این سنگ‌ها به ترتیب 628 درجه سانتیگراد و فشار حدود 4 کیلوبار می‌باشد. بر اساس مطالعات گوهر شناسی انجام شده، کردیریت‌ها برای تراش‌های دامله و فانتزی مناسب هستند،</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سنندج-سیرجان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همدان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کردیریت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کیانیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گوهرسنگ</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15071_8f710f0927f815f9e0372fc9f0add521.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
