<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study of effective factors in the formation of sinkholes in south of Poldokhtar, Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مطالعه عوامل مؤثر در تشکیل فرو چاله‌ها در جنوب شهر پل دختر، جنوب غرب ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>78</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>95</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15072</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28733.1946</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>قبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>زمین شناسی،دانشکده علوم ،دانشگاه بوعلی سینا،همدان ،ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوریزدان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Sinkholes are more abundant, in the quaternary-covered basins with soluble bedrock. In the folded Zagros in Iran, the Most of plains are karstic. This research was carried out in an area of 155 km2 in location of old the Jaydar and the Gori Balmak lakes, in south of Poldokhtar city, SW Iran. The purpose of this study was to evaluate the factors affecting the formation of sinkhole. In this area are expanding lake sediments of the Seymareh landslide dams. The thickness of lake sediments have been estimated using geophysical studies include GPR with 10 MHz antenna and ERT, respectively an average 70 m and less than 10 m in the Jaydar and Gori Balmak plains. The bedrock of study area is the Gachsaran Formation (Middle Miocene) includes gypsum massive and marl. Uniaxial compressive strength (UCS) and tensile strength of gypsum section of bedrock is respectively 16.39 and 1.5 MPa. At least 4 joint sets are expanded in the bedrock. The source of the filling materials of the joints is eroded marl units of Gachsaran Formation and lake sediments. The dispersion of joints filling material is approved by Crumb, dual hydrometer and chemical tests. The dual consolidation test showed that the covering sediments of bed rock are collapsible. Pezometric data show that the average depth of groundwater in the past 10 years has loss about 3 m and lies at a depth of 20 m at ground level now. Field observations show less than 32 sinkholes in the study area</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">فرو چاله‌ها در دشت‌های پوشیده از رسوبات کواترنر با سنگ‌بستر انحلال‌پذیر، فراوانی بیش‌تری دارند. بیش‌تر دشت‌ها در منطقه زاگرس چین‌خورده در ایران کارستی هستند. این پژوهش در گستره‌ای به مساحت 155 کیلومترمربع باهدف ارزیابی عوامل مؤثر در فرو چاله زایی در محل قدیمی دریاچه‌های جایدر گوری بلمک در جنوب شهر پل‌دختر، جنوب غرب ایران انجام‌شده است. این دریاچه‌ها در اثر وقوع بهمن سنگی سیمره در جنوب غرب ایران تشکیل‌شده بودند. در این منطقه رسوبات دریاچه‌ای ناشی از ایجاد سدهای زمین‌لغزشی گسترش دارند. بر اساس نتایج حاصل از انجام مطالعات ژئوفیزیکی در منطقه به روش‌های GPR با آنتن 10 مگاهرتز و توموگرافی مقاومت ویژه الکتریکی (ERT)، ضخامت رسوبات دریاچه‌ای قدیمی جایدر در محل دشت جایدر به‌طور متوسط 70 متر و در محل دریاچه قدیمی گوری بلمک کمتر از 10 مترمی باشد. سنگ‌بستر رسوبات هر دو دریاچه سازند تبخیری گچساران است. سازند مذکور ازنظر سنی به سنوزوئیک تعلق دارد. مقاومت فشاری تک‌محوری و کششی بخش ژیپس سنگ بستر به ترتیب 39/16 و 5/1 مگا پاسکال است. حداقل 4 دسته درزه در توده سنگ‌بستر گسترش دارد. منشأ مواد پرکننده درزه‌ها، ناشی از فرسایش واحدهای مارنی سازند گچساران و رسوبات دریاچه‌ای می‌باشند. ..</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فروچاله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازند گچساران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انحلال‌پذیری ژیپس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">واگرایی مواد پرکننده درزه‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهمن سنگی سیمره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پل‌دختر</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15072_bba0a26a5f0966543c72edbaa7d414ab.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
