<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluating the effect of freezing-thawing cycles on the compressional wavevelocity and dry density of schist rock (Case study: Angouran mine)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی تأثیر چرخه‌های انجماد-ذوب بر روی سرعت امواج فشاری و چگالی سنگ شیست (مطالعه موردی: معدن انگوران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>15</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>30</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15069</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2019.28197.1922</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید زانیار</FirstName>
					<LastName>سید موسوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده فنی‌مهندسی، دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>توکلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده فنی‌مهندسی، دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پرویز</FirstName>
					<LastName>معارف وند</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مهندسی معدن و متالوژی، دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مهندسی معدن، دانشکده مهندسی، دانشگاه کردستان، سنندج، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0619-2846</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The effects of freezing-thawing cycles on the compressional wave velocities and dry density of schist rock have been investigated in this research. For this purpose, 13 boreholes were drilled in the Angouran mine and 25 cylindrical specimens were prepared. Then, the samples were weathered in the laboratory by freezing-thawing process and the compressional wave velocity and dry density of samples were measured in freeze-thaw cycles of 0, 7, 15, 40 and 75. The results analysis indicates an exponentially decrease in the compressional wave velocities (50% reduction) and dry density (30% reduction) with increasing the number of freeze-thaw cycles. Also, wave velocities exponentially increased with increasing the dry density. By fitting the concluded results, two empirical equations to calculate the compressional wave velocity and dry density in schist rock for different numbers of freeze-thaw cycles and also an equation between compressional wave velocity and dry density have been presented. In addition, the texture of samples was studied in intact situation and after 75 cycles of freezing-thawing by an electronic microscope. The obtained results indicated that the samples texture is condensed before weathering, whereas the discontinuities spacing is increased after weathering. Finally, verification results proved that there is a good conformity between the outputs of current study and other investigations.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این تحقیق تأثیر چرخه‌های مختلف انجماد-ذوب بر سرعت امواج فشاری و چگالی سنگ شیست بررسی شده است. بدین منظور، ابتدا 13 عدد گمانه در معدن انگوران حفاری و تعداد 25 نمونه استوانه‌ای آماده سازی گردید. سپس، نمونه‌ها در آزمایشگاه با استفاده از فرآیند انجماد-ذوب هوازده و پارامترهای سرعت امواج فشاری و چگالی خشک نمونه‌ها در چرخه‌های 0، 7، 15، 40 و 75 اندازه‌گیری گردید. تحلیل نتایج نشان‌دهنده کاهش نمایی سرعت امواج فشاری (50% کاهش) و چگالی خشک (20% کاهش) به‌ازای افزایش تعداد چرخه‌های انجماد-ذوب می‌باشد. همچنین، سرعت امواج فشاری با افزایش چگالی خشک به‌صورت نمایی افزایش می‌یابد. با برازش نتایج حاصله، دو رابطه تجربی مجزا جهت محاسبه سرعت موج فشاری و چگالی خشک در سنگ شیست به‌ازای چرخه‌های مختلف انجماد-ذوب و یک رابطه هم بین سرعت موج فشاری و چگالی خشک ارائه شده است. بعلاوه، بافت نمونه‌ها هم در حالت بکر و هم پس از اعمال 75 چرخه انجماد-ذوب به‌وسیله میکروسکوپ الکترونیکی مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته است. نتایج حاصله نشان دهنده متراکم بودن بافت نمونه‌ها قبل از هوازدگی و افزایش فاصله بین ناپیوستگی‌ها بعد از هوازدگی می باشد. در نهایت، نتایج اعتبارسنجی نشان داد که همخوانی خوبی بین خروجی حاصل از تحقیق حاضر و مطالعات قبلی وجود دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معدن انگوران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شیست</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چرخه انجماد-ذوب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرعت موج فشاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چگالی خشک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://aag.scu.ac.ir/article_15069_427033883fcca86242ee72cf2aecc17c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
