<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زمین شناسی کاربردی پیشرفته</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2251-7057</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Geology, geochemistry and genesis of the Kosaj Fe occurrence, Takab‒Takht-e-Soleiman‒ Anguoran metalogenic zone, SW Zanjan</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>زمین شناسی، زمین‌شیمی و ژنز رخداد معدنی آهن کوسج، پهنه فلززایی تکاب- تخت سلیمان- انگوران، جنوب باختر زنجان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15340</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22055/aag.2020.30531.2026</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>قادری</LastName>
<Affiliation>گزوه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>کوهستانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیات علمی دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3031-9042</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرخنده</FirstName>
					<LastName>توفیقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زمین شناسی، دانشکده علوم، دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Kosaj Fe ore occurrence is located in the Takab‒Takht-e-Soleyman‒Angouran metallogenic zone. At Kosaj, iron mineralization occurs as lens-shaped bodies and layers parallel to the foliation of muscovite schist and actinolite-hornblende schist units (equal to Kahar Formation). Ore minerals are magnetite along with minor pyrite, and quartz and actinolite present as gangue mineral. The ore minerals show disseminated, laminated, banded, massive, lenticular, vein-veinlet and replacement textures. Three stages of mineralization can be distinguished at Kosaj. The first stage is recognized as stratiform and stratabound lenses, laminated and disseminated crystals of magnetite-quartz and magnetite-actinolite bands parallet to the foliation of host rocks. Stage-2 mineralization is recognized by folding of ore bands, σ microfabric, boudinage and elongation of magnetite crystals, quartz pressure shadows and surrounding of foliation around magnetite crystals, and recrystallization of quartz and magnetite crystals. Stage-3 is recognized by brecciated magnetite-quartz vein-veinlets. Actinolitization, silicification and hematitization are main hydrothermal alteration types at Kosaj. Chondrite-nonmineralized REE pattern of host rocks and the mineralized samples indicate that mineralized samples are depleted in REE. Characteristics of Kosaj occurrence are comparable with metamorphosed and deformed volcano-sedimentary type of iron deposits.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">رخداد معدنی آهن کوسج در پهنه فلززایی تکاب- تخت‌سلیمان- انگوران واقع شده است. کانه‌زایی آهن در کوسج به‌صورت عدسی‌شکل و لایه‌ای درون واحدهای مسکوویت شیستی و اکتینولیت هورنبلند شیستی (معادل سازند کهر) رخ داده است. کانی‌های معدنی شامل مگنتیت همراه با میزان اندکی پیریت بوده و کوارتز و اکتینولیت کانی‌های باطله هستند. بافت کانسنگ شامل دانه‌پراکنده، نواری و لامینه‌ای، توده‌ای، عدسی‌شکل، رگه- رگچه‌ای و جانشینی است. سه مرحله کانه‌زایی در رخداد معدنی کوسج قابل تفکیک است. مرحله اول کانه‌زایی به‌صورت مگنتیت‌های دانه‌پراکنده، لایه‌ای- لامینه‌ای و عدسی‌های چینه‌سان و چینه‌کران متشکل از تناوب نوارهای مگنتیت- کوارتز و مگنتیت- اکتینولیت هم‌روند با برگوارگی واحدهای میزبان مشاهده می‌شود. مرحله دوم کانه‌زایی با چین‌خوردگی نوارهای کانه‌دار، تشکیل ریزساختارهای سیگما، بودین‌شدگی و کشیدگی در بلورهای مگنتیت، رشد سایه‌فشاری کوارتز و دور زدن برگ‌وارگی در اطراف بلورهای مگنتیت و تبلور مجدد بلورهای کوارتز و مگنتیت مشخص می‌شود. کانه‌زایی مرحله سوم با رگه و رگچه‌های مگنتیتی- کوارتزی بِرشی مشخص می‌شود. دگرسانی‌ها شامل سیلیسی، اکتینولیتی و هماتیتی است. بررسی الگوی تغییرات عناصر کمیاب خاکی بهنجارشده به کندریت در سنگ‌های میزبان فاقد کانه‌زایی و بخش‌های کانه‌دار بیانگر تهی‌شدگی این عناصر در بخش‌های کانه‌دار است. ویژگی‌های رخداد معدنی کوسج با کانسارهای آهن نوع آتشفشانی-رسوبی دگرگون‌ و دگرشکل‌شده قابل مقایسه است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کانه‌زایی آهن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آتشفشانی- رسوبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کوسج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنجان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تکاب- تخت‌سلیمان- انگوران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
