<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>22</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Study of Syllable Structure in Sarhaddi Balochi Dialect of Granchin</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ساخت هجا در گویش بلوچی سرحدی گرنچین</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>49</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>76</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2059</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباسعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>آهنگر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کارینا</FirstName>
					<LastName>جهانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه اوپسالا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>گلناز</FirstName>
					<LastName>مدرسی قوامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فهیمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>ساغریچی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The study of syllable structure enjoys a specific significance in non-linear phonological studies. The present research, in the form of fieldwork, investigates the syllable structure in Sarhaddi Balochi dialect of Granchin based on the theory of CV phonology as a post-generative theory. It also examines the phonotactic distribution of consonants in initial and final clusters as well as the effect of the nucleus vowel of the syllable on the selection of dissimilar consonant clusters of the coda. The linguistic data has been extracted from the linguistic corpus collected in the Granchin district of Khash in Sistan and Baluchestan province. The data collection and compilation of the linguistic corpus were carried out based on the purposeful recording of speech through interviewing and recording free speech of consultants. The language consultants included 5 females and 5 males living in Granchin, who were illiterate and of different ages, between 60-80 years. The research findings show that the syllable structure of Sarhaddi Balochi Dialect of Granchin consists of one syllabic element, that is, nucleus which is preceded by maximally three consonants and followed by two consonants. In addition, the findings denote that phonotactic restrictions govern the distribution of consonants in initial and final clusters. Likewise, the type of the nucleus vowel of the syllable plays a role in selecting the cluster of the coda. </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">بررسی ساختِ هجا در مطالعاتِ غیرِخطّیِ واج‌شناختی از اهمیتِ خاصّی برخوردار است. پژوهش حاضر، در قالبِ پژوهشی میدانی، به بررسی ساختِ هجا در گویش بلوچی سرحدّی گرنچین، براساسِ نظریۀ واج‌شناسی همخوان- واکه، به‌عنوان نظریه‌ای پسازایشی، می‌پردازد و شیوۀ واج‌آرایی همخوان‌ها در خوشه‌های دوهمخوانی آغازه و پایانۀ هجا و همچنین تأثیرِ واکۀ هستۀ هجا در انتخابِ همخوان‌های خوشۀ ناهمانندِ پایانه را بررسی می‌کند. داده‌های زبانی پژوهش از پیکرۀ زبانی گردآوری‌شده در منطقۀ گرنچین، از توابعِ شهرستانِ خاش در استان سیستان و بلوچستان، استخراج شده است. گردآوری داده‌ها و تدوینِ پیکرۀ زبانی براساسِ روش هدفمند، در قالبِ مصاحبه و گفتارِ آزاد انجام شده است. جامعۀ زبانی این پژوهش را 10 گویشورِ ساکنِ گرنچین، شاملِ 5 زن، و 5 مرد، از رده‌های سنّی متفاوتِ 60 تا 80 سال و بی‌سواد تشکیل می‌دهد. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان می‌دهند که هجا در گویش بلوچی سرحدّی گرنچین دارای یک عنصرِ هجایی، یعنی هسته، است که قبل از آن حدّاکثر سه همخوان و بعد از آن حدّاکثر دو همخوان می‌توانند واقع شوند. به‌علاوه، بر واج‌آرایی خوشه‌های دوهمخوانیِ آغازه و پایانه در این گونۀ زبانی محدودیت‌هایی حاکم است. همچنین، نوعِ واکۀ هستۀ هجا در گزینشِ خوشۀ پایانه نقش دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گویشِ بلوچی سرحدّی گرنچین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">واج‌شناسی همخوان- واکه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هجا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آغازه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هسته</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پایانه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2059_59b22b03341d389de4d9e67074704ccb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
