<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2006</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Morphology and Conjugation of Simple Verbs in Balochi and their Comparison with Persian</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ساخت و صرف فعل سادة بلوچی و مقایسة اجمالی آن با فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>16</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1612</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>موسی</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمودزهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه زبان و زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The morphology and conjugation of simple verb compared in two new Iranian languages_ Balochi and Persian_ in this paper. The comparison indicates that the morphology and conjugation systems of the simple verb in Balochi and Persian are similar in some aspects, while different in some others. Generally the contents of the paper indicate that:

The number of simple verbs in Balochi is more in comparison with that of Persian, and the ability of word-formation through derivation is easier in Balochi than in Persian.
The differences and similarities are mostly based on the rule-governed changes of Iranian languages.
Balochi has more preserved the features of many simple verbs of older Iranian languages than Persian, and Persian has involved more historical changes.
The mutual usage of morphological and conjugational features of Balochi and Persian can be more useful for the enrichment of these two Iranian languages.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله ساخت و صرف فعل ساده در دو زبان ایرانی نو ـ بلوچی و فارسی ـ مقایسه شده است. مقایسه‌ها نشان می‌دهد که مقولات ساخت و صرف فعل ساده در بلوچی و فارسی از بعضی جنبه‌ها شبیه و از سایر نظرها متفاوت است . به طورکلی محتوای مقاله نشان می‌دهد که :
1- تعداد فعلهای ساده در بلوچی امروزی نسبت به فارسی به مراتب بیشتر و توانایی بالقوة ‌آن برای ساخت واژگان جدید از طریق اشتقاق به مراتب راحت‌تر است.
2- تفاوتها و تشابهات تا حد زیادی براساس اصول قانون‌مند زبانهای ایرانی است.
3- بلوچی بسیاری از ویژگیهای فعلهای سادة زبانهای ایرانی قدیم‌تر را نسبت به فارسی بیشترحفظ کرده و فارسی مشمول تحولات تاریخی بیشتری شده است .
4- استفادة متقابل از ویژگیهای ساختی و صرفی فعلهای سادة زبانهای بلوچی و فارسی می‌تواند در توانمندسازی یکدیگر این زبانها به کارآید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساخت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صرف</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فعل‌ساده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بلوچی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1612_80806ca9c6943e4e061807f71e2b4051.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
