<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>23</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Other Mode: Sohrab Sepehri&#039;s cognitive manner</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شیوة شناختیِ سهراب سپهری:آن جورِ دیگر</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>79</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>97</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2254</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرشته</FirstName>
					<LastName>مؤمنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد چالوس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In cognitive linguistics, viewpoint is a part of the process of producing meaning and a factor in different construing of the same subject. Different viewpoints  provide the viewer with particular perspectives to conceptualize the case, which according to cognitive grammar,  is represented in the grammar of the language. The many inconsistent reviews on Sohrab Sepehri&#039;s poetry show that his objective to lead the viewer to perceive the situation of the subject (from the subject’s viewpoint, not the viewer&#039;s) has not been realized. The aim of this paper is to introduce this apparently unknown viewpoint and to give a model of the processes of its formation in the construction of his language. The present paper argues that through foregrounding the case, switching from the perspective of the landmark to the perspective of the trajectory to suggest the situation of the case, he leads the reader to perceive the state of the subject, or &quot;object&#039;s perception&quot; as he expresses.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زبان‌شناسیِ شناختی، زاویة دید را بخشی از فرایند تولید معنا و عاملی در تعبیرهای متفاوت از یک موضوع واحد می‌داند. نگاه از هر زاویة دیدی شناخت و درکی از همان دیدگاه به بیننده می‌دهد و بنابر دستور شناختی، این موضوع در دستور زبان نیز نمودار می‌شود. با توجه به نقدها و داوری‌های متفاوت، متناقض و اغلب مغایر با آمار مربوط به اشعارِ سهراب سپهری، به‌‌نظر می‌رسد زاویة دیدی که او در اشعار خود به‌کار برده است و طی آن، به‌گفتة خود وی، می‌خواسته آدمی را به «ادراک شیء» -و نه به ادراک فرد از شیء- برساند، شناخته نشده است. هدف این مقاله، معرفی زاویة دید موردنظر شاعر و ارائة مدلی از فرایندهای چندمرحله‌ایِ شکل‌گیریِ ساختار زبانیِ شعرِ اوست. طی این مطالعه که به‌روش کتابخانه‌ای انجام یافته و توصیفی-تحلیلی ‌است، مشخص‌می‌شود که سهراب سپهری، با جابه‌جاییِ زاویة دید از چشم‌اندازِ پایگاه به پویه، و با پیش‌نماسازی از آن شیء، خواننده را در جایگاه سوژه/ شی‌، قرار می‌دهد تا با القای وضعیت آن، خواننده (به‌تعبیر خود شاعر) به ادراک شیء دست یابد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شناخت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زاویة دید</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پایگاه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پویه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ادراک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2254_8b2f048233adda2983033782861c2f6d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
