<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>26</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Consonantal Compensatory Lengthening in Persian</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کشش همخوان در زبان فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>19</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>40</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">3200</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فهیمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>خداوردی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>گلناز</FirstName>
					<LastName>مدرسی قوامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This article presents a moraic description of the relation between two prosodic features in Persian: segmental lengthening and syllable weight. The data contains imperative forms in which the initial consonant of verbal stems may undergo compensatory lengthening following the diachronically shortened vowel of the imperative prefixes. The result of analyzing the data in Moraic Theory provides us with  more evidence in support of the idea that vowel or consonant lengthening has no phonemic value and makes no semantic distinction (considering minimal pairs) in modern Persian, however it causes differences in the quantity of syllable weight. In the framework of Moraic Phonology, the distinction among light, heavy and super-heavy syllables is represented by the number of moras assigned to the syllable segments and weight sensitive phonological processes like compensatory lengthening of vowels and consonants apply in order to keep the number of moras unchanged and set the syllable weight fixed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقالۀ حاضر، در چارچوب واج‌شناسی مورایی، به توصیف رابطۀ میان دو ویژگیِ نواییِ کششِ واحدهای زبانی و وزن هجا در زبان فارسی پرداخته‌است. برای این منظور، فرایند کششِ جبرانیِ همخوان پس از کوتاه‌شدن درزمانی واکه مدنظر قرار گرفته‌است. داده‌های مورد بررسی، صورت‌هایی را شامل شده‌اند که در آنها، بنا به نظر صادقی (۱۳۹۲)، همخوان آغازین ستاک‌های فعلی پس از پیشوندهای امریِ مختوم به واکۀ کوتاه، امکان مشدد‌شدن داشته‌اند. نتیجۀ تحلیل داده‌ها در نظریۀ مورایی، شاهد دیگری در تأیید این نکته است که در زبان فارسیِ امروز، کشش واکه‌ها و همخوان‌ها ارزش واجی ندارد و تمایز معنایی به‌وجود نمی‌آورد، اما ارزش کمّی دارد و تمایز وزنی ایجاد می‌‌کند. در نظریۀ مورایی، تمایز وزنی میان هجاهای سبک، سنگین و فوقِ‌سنگین، بر اساس تعداد موراهای اختصاص‌یافته به واحدهای زنجیری بازنمایی می‌شود و فرایندهای واجی حساس به وزن هجا، مانند کشش جبرانیِ واکه‌ها و همخوان‌ها، با هدف حفظ تعداد موراها و ثبات وزنی هجا، به‌وقوع می‌پیوندند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کشش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وزن هجا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همخوان مشدد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">واج‌شناسی مورایی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3200_1ce2e5c2df7e8968ea85214a4f06b517.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
