<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>14</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Status and Application of Persian Language and Tonekaboni Dialect in Tonekabon</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>جایگاه و کاربرد زبان فارسی و گویش تنکابنی در شهر تنکابن</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>41</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>55</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1448</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهمن</FirstName>
					<LastName>زندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بلقیس</FirstName>
					<LastName>روشن</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سارا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نصیری الموتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبان‌شناسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study attempts to reveal the social functions and application of Persian language and Tonekaboni dialect (one of the dialects of West Mazandarani language) on the basis of age, gender, occupation, education and spouse’s mother tongue in six social domains in Tonekabon which are: family, friends, neighborhood, business, educational and official circles. The research sample includes 250 randomly chosen participants from different regions in the town. The participants were grouped on the basis of age, level of education, gender, occupation and spouse’s mother tongue. A questionnaire based on Parasher’s model (1980) was used. It consisted of 36 questions ranging from informal to formal. The data were processed by computer after collection and classification.  Independent samples t-test, paired samples t-test and one-way ANOVA were the statistical procedures applied to the data. In general, the findings  indicate that Persian is the dominant language in all the domains, and that the social variables of age, gender, occupation, education and spouse’s mother tongue impact the use of Tonekaboni and Persian language. The implication is that the use of Tonekaboni is gradually decreasing, which means that Persian may in future replace it in all social domains.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش تلاش می‌شود تا نقش اجتماعیی و گویش تنکابنی (از گویش‌های زبان مازندرانی غربی) براساس متغیرهای سن، جنس، شغل، تحصیلات و زبان مادریِ همسر، در شش حوزۀ اجتماعی خانواده، دوستی، همسایگی، دادوستد، آموزشی و اداری، در جامعۀ زبانی‌این‌منظور 250 آزمودنی براساس گروه سنی، سطح تحصیلات، جنس، شغل و زبان مادری‌صورت تصادفی، برگزیده شدند. سپس داده‌ها (شامل 36 سؤال)، با استفاده از پرسش‌نامۀ الگوی پژوهشی پاراشر (1980)، جمع‌آوری و براساس درجۀ رسمیتِ حوزه، به‌ترتیب از غیررسمی به رسمییوتر پردازش شدند. روش‌های آماری آزمون &lt;span&gt;T&lt;/span&gt; نمونه‌های مستقل، آزمون تیِ نمونه‌های زوجی و تحلیل واریانسِ ی‌طرفه، جهت تجزیه‌وتحلیل یافته‌های پژوهش به‌ند. درمجموع، نتایج حاصل از مقایسۀ کاربرد فارسی و تنکابنی، دررابطه‌با شش حوزۀ اجتماعی، نشان می‌دهد که زبان فارسی، زبانِ غالب در هر شش حوزه است و نیز عوامل اجتماعی سن، جنس، شغل، تحصیلات و زبان مادریِ همسر در کاربرد زبان فارسی و گویی مؤثرند و احتمال می‌رود که کاربرد تنکابنی درمیان گویشوران به‌تدریج کمتر شود و فارسی به‌طور کامل در تمامی حوزه‌های اجتماعی جایگزین این گویش گردد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جامعه‌شناسی زبان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دوزبان‌گونگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل حوزه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گویش تنکابنی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1448_0ff218656c233e4f6dc8c61c0a3b7cee.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
