<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>18</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Syntactic account of Persian Apposition and Nonrestrictive Relative Clause</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ساخت نحوی بدل و بند موصولی توضیحی در زبان فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>129</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>158</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1590</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سولماز</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمودی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترای زبان‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Persian relative clauses are the complex DP containing head and CP. These two make a syntactic constituent and have DP distribution. Following the SOV word order, the base generated position of them is an argument position before verb which can be changed by movement operations. DP embedded CP is introduced by the invariable complementizer (ke) and the embedded verbs are inflected for tense, aspect and mood just as a main verb. Nonrestrictive relative clause is a subordinate clause which does not restrict the meaning of the head it modifies but stands in apposition to it. Nonrestrictive relative clauses are syntactically the same as restrictive relative clauses, i.e. they go through various grammatical operations in the same way. However nonrestrictive relative clauses are similar to the parentheticals (particularly apposition) in the prosodic and semantic aspects. They have distinctive prosodic contour, that is, discontinuity and parentheticals’ semantic contribution to the matrix clause is an additional or supplementive one. one.In this article an attempt is made to show these differences by structural representation:  the apposition as a cooperated construction and nonrestrictive relative clause as  right –adjoined to the head noun.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تفاوت رفتار نحوی‌ای که بندهای موصولی و بدل فارسی براساس خوانش معناییِ خود در هر جمله نشان می‌دهند، توجیه نحوی دارد. به بیانی دیگر، این تفاوت ناشی از محل استقرار فرافکنِ متمم‌نما و گروه حرف تعریف در میان سایر فرافکن‌های نقشی جمله است. در این پژوهش بند موصولی، به صورت افزوده، و بدل‌ها، به صورت افزودگی یا همپایگی، ترسیم می‌شوند. در حالی که با ترسیم افزودگی به‌جای افزوده، نمودارهای بند موصولی و بدل یکی می‌شوند. بنابراین اگر به پیروی از زبان‌شناسانی همچون هگمن، که افزوده را به صورت افزودگی در نظر می‌گیرند، این حد افراط را قبول کنیم، تمایز آن ساخت‌ها مشخص نمی‌شود. بدل‌ها خود نوعی ساخت موازی در نظریۀ عمومی زبان تلقی می‌شوند. ملاک تشخیص این ساخت‌ها، ملاک‌های ساختاری و معناشناختی است. نمودار درختی و ویژگی معنایی آنها حاکی از تمایز این ساخت‌ها با ساخت‌های موصولی و متممی است. در این پژوهش سعی می‌شود پس از ارائۀ توصیفی جامع از ساخت‌های موازی، به‌خصوص بدل در زبان فارسی، کاراییِ رویکرد نحوی در این زمینه بررسی شود و تحلیلی جامع از این ساخت‌ها همراه با توصیف مقولات مورد نظر، برمبنای ویژگی‌های دستوری، به دست داده شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عبارت معترضه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بدل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بند موصولیِ توضیحی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">افزوده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">افزودگی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1590_efac466fe10a5d643f36498750ea164f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
