<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>19</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Comparative Analysis of Inflectional Suffixes and Prefixes of the Verbs in Gurani Kurdish and Standard Persian</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مقایسة پسوندها و پیشوندهای تصریفیِ فعل در کردیِ گورانی و فارسی معیار</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>101</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>120</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1764</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پارسا</FirstName>
					<LastName>بامشادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4573-7810</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>بامشادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد آموزش زبان فارسی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In the present research, after analyzing inflectional structure of more than two hundred verbs in Gurani Kurdish dialect, a comparative analysis of inflectional suffixes and prefixes of  verbs in Gurani Kurdish and standard Persian was carried out. The method of this study was descriptive, analytical and comparative. The results are classified  into  two main groups: verb suffixes and verb prefixes. Verb suffixes in Gurani include 1) agreement suffixes, 2) stem-builder suffixes, 3) aspect-builder suffixes, and 4) subjunctive mood suffix. Stem-builder suffixes include suffixes for the past stem, present stem, passive stem, and causative stem. Aspect-builder suffixes in turn include suffixes for past perfect, past continuous, past perfect continuous, present perfect and present perfect continuous. Finally, verb prefixes are: 1) negative prefixes, 2) imperative prefix, 3) negative imperative prefix, and 4) subjunctive mood prefix.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش با تحلیل ساخت تصریفیِ بیش‌از 200 فعل از کردیِ گورانی، به بررسی پسوندها و پیشوندهای تصریفیِ فعل در این گویش از زبان کردی و مقایسۀ آن با زبان فارسی معیار پرداخته می‌شود. این فعل¬ها در زمرۀ رایج¬ترین و پرکاربردترین فعل¬های ساده در این گویش هستند. روش انجام این پژوهش از گونۀ توصیفی، تحلیلی و تطبیقی است و ما یافته‌های خود را در دو گروه پسوندها و پیشوندهای فعلی، دسته‌بندی کرده‌ایم. پسوندها خود چهار دسته را در بر می‌گیرد: 1. شناسه‌ها، 2. پسوندهای فعلیِ ستاک‌ساز، 3. پسوندهای فعلیِ نمود‌ساز و 4. پسوند التزامی. در دسته‌بندیِ ریزتر، پسوندهای ستاک‌ساز شامل پسوندهای ستاک گذشته، حال ، مجهول و سببی هستند. پسوندهای نمود‌ساز نیز خود به پسوندهای گذشتۀ کامل، گذشتۀ استمراری، گذشتۀ استمراری دور، گذشتۀ استمراری نقلی و حال کامل تقسیم می‌شوند. پیشوندهای فعلی هم چهار دستۀ: 1. نفی، 2. امر ، 3. نهی و 4. التزامی را شامل می‌شوند. یافته‌های این پژوهش همچنین نشان می‌دهد که فعل در گویش گورانی دارای تصریف شمار، شخص، زمان، نمود، وجه و جهت است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گویش کردی گورانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پسوند فعلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیشوند فعلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساخت تصریفی فعل</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1764_531907898a90a078f36ac62eefce7e93.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
