<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2005</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Change of Initial Vowel /a/ to [e] in Words Consisted of two or more Syllables of Hamedani Accent</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تغییر واکه آغازین در واژه های دو هجایی یابیشتر لهجه همدانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>47</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>57</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1576</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عالیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>کرد زعفرانلو کامبوزیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سحر</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهرامی خورشید</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد زبان شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The study of different words in Hamedani accent reveals that one of its salient features is the change of initial /a/ into [e] in words consisted of two syllebles or more having no stress on the first syllable. So, the main goal of this research is the study of this phonological process or in other words the recognition of its phonological enviroment. This article is a field work in which a list of current words was firstly prepared, then their exact pronunciation according to the native speaker’s speech was recorded; also, according to the writer’s intuition as a native speaker, the words were transcribed phonologically and compared with its standard counterparts.
            The main conclusion resulted from this comparison reveals that in Hamedani accent in words made up of two or more syllables the initial  vowel /a/ changes into [e].</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">          بررسی و مطالعه واژگان گوناگون در لهجه همدانی نشان می دهد که یکی از ویژگیهای بارز این لهجه، تغییر واکه آغازین/ ‌a / به [e ] در واژه های دو هجایی یا بیشتر می باشد. لذا هدف از تحقیق حاضر بررسی این فرایند واجی و به عبارت دیگر بررسی و شناسایی محیط واجی این فرایند است که طی آن واکه افتاده / ‌a / به [e ]  ارتقاء می یابد. روش تحقیق در تهیه مقاله حاضر بصورت میدانی بوده است، بدین ترتیب که ابتدا فهرستی از واژگان بنیادی که در گفتار روزمره گویشوران مکرراً شنیده می شود،تهیه شده و سپس با در نظر گرفتن جامعه ای آماری طریقه تلفظ این واژگان توسط اعضای جامعه  ثبت و ضبط گردیده است. بر همین اساس و نیز شم زبانی نگارنده بعنوان یک گویشور بومی، واژگان مورد نظر واج نگاری شده و سپس با همان واژگان در گویش معیار مقایسه شده است. نتیجه حاصله از بررسی و مقایسه این واژگان نشان دهنده این واقعیت است که در واژگان دو هجایی یا بیشتر واکه آغازین/ a/ در محیط بدون تکیه ارتقاء یافته و به [e ]  تبدیل شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هجا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همگونی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ناهمگونی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارتقاء</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1576_537d77e6618242f7edd48b91702d598e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
