<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>22</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Verb “xordan” from the Perspective of Cognitive Linguistics</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>قالب‌های معنایی «خوردن» ازمنظرِ معناشناسیِ قالبی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>26</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2057</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اکبر</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسابی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This paper focuses on a descriptive study of the verb “xordan” from the frame semantics view point. First synonyms of “xordan” were gathered and their differences were explained. Then using different sources such as Hamshahri corpus, some e-books, weblogs, documents and sentences -gathered from daily discussions, different occurrences of “xordan” were collected and studied based on frame semantics. The following questions were addressed in this study: What are the differences between the verbs referring to “taking something into the mouth” and “swallowing it”?; What are the different frames of “xordan”?; And can these frames be used for explaining the semantic aspects of compound verbs in Persian? Results of this study indicate that there are specific differences between synonyms of “xordan”. Occurrences of “xordan” reveal 31 frames for this verb which can be classified and hierarchically grouped. Using these frames, formation of some compound verbs is also explained.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش به‌بررسیِ فعل خوردن ازمنظرِ معناشناسیِ قالبی پرداخته شده است. در این پژوهش که پژوهشی توصیفی است، ابتدا با استفاده از چند منبع، افعال هم‌معنا با خوردن استخراج شد و تفاوت‌های آنها مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. سپس با استفاده از منابع متعددی، مانند پیکرۀ همشهری، کتاب‌های الکترونیکی، وبلاگ‌ها و منابع قابل جستجو با رایانه و جملات ثبت‌شده توسط دانشجویان از محاوره‌های روزانه، رخدادهای مختلفِ خوردن استخراج شد و ازمنظرِ معناشناسیِ قالبی مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. در این پژوهش به‌دنبالِ پاسخ‌گویی به سؤالات زیر بودیم: چه تفاوتی بین فعل‌های مختلفی که به انواع مختلف خوردن اشاره می‌کنند وجود دارد؟ قالب‌های معناییِ مختلفِ فعلِ خوردن چیست؟ آیا این قالب‌ها برای تبیینِ معناییِ باهم‌آیی‌های شامل این فعل قابل استفاده‌اند؟ نتایج نشان داد تفاوت‌های نحوی، معنایی و کاربردشناختی، افعال هم‌معنا با خوردن را از هم متمایز می‌کند. واکاویِ رخدادهای فعل خوردن به یافتن 26 قالب معنایی برای این فعل منجر شد که برخی قابل دسته‌بندی و قرار‌گرفتن زیر چتر قالب‌هایی کلی‌تر مانند قالب‌های هماهنگی و همزمانی، درتماس‌قرارگرفتن و نابودی بودند. با استفاده از قالب‌های معناییِ یافته‌شده و برخی از ویژگی‌های معنایی این قالب‌ها، چگونگیِ شکل‌گیریِ برخی از باهم‌آیی‌های شاملِ خوردن تبیین شد. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معنی‌شناسی واژگانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معناشناسیِ قالبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خوردن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هم‌معنایی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2057_c5892958d210520b76ffd2490be39c50.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
