<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1384</YEAR>
<VOL>1</VOL>
<NO>2</NO>
<MOSALSAL>2</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تغییرات تلفظی واژگان فارسی هنگام استفاده درگفتار رسمی زبان نوشتاری ترک زبانان تبریز</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Pronounciation Changes in Persian Words in Formal Tabriz Variety of Turkish (written language)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زبان عنصر اصلی فرهنگ است و چند زبانگی دقیق ترین بازتاب چند فرهنگی است. کشور ما را به اعتباری می توان چند زبانه دانست،  زیرا که در درون مرزهای سیاسی خود اقوام مختلفی را جای داده که هر کدام از آنها همچنان که دارای فرهنگی کم و بیش خاص خوداند، دارای زبان خاص خود به عنوان یکی از عناصر فرهنگی خود نیز به شمار می روند.اقوام مختلف، در عین حال که هر یک از مراحل تاریخ اجتماعی خود را به شکل خاصی پیموده اند، هیچ وقت به حالت انزوا نزیسته اند بلکه در حال ارتباط با اقوام دیگر به سر برده اند. همین مسئله ارتباط اجتناب ناپذیر جوامع بشری، به تنهایی می تواند دلیل کافی برای تأثیر متقابل زبان‌های‌آنان دریکدیگر باشد. به‌این ترتیب، زبان‌درگذرزمان، تحت‌تأثیر زبان همسایه قرار می‌گیرد و دچار تحول و دگرگونی می شود، به طوری که در سیر عادی و طبیعی خود حتی ناگزیر به قبول کلمات بیگانه می‌گردد، منتها اثراین‌قرض‌گیری‌را معمولاً با مجزا ساختن واژه ی مورد نظر از وابستگی های دستوری زبان اصلی و تعدیل و تغییر آن براساس قوانین آوایی خود از بین می برد. بنابراین، کلمه ای که به این شکل وارد زبان می شود با قواعد خاص تطبیق یافته و خللی در استقلال زبان وارد نمی سازد. بر اساس بررسی انجام یافته، زبان آذری نیز پس از قرض گیری واژه های فارسی به دلایل مختلف )پرکردن خلاء فرهنگی،  اعتبار اجتماعی زبان قرض دهنده و... (تغییراتی را در سطح آوایی به روی واژه وارد کرده است که می توان آن را معلول فرآیندی دانست که طی آن، واژه های قرضی، خود را با ساخت آوایی زبان قرض گیرنده تطبیق می دهند و تلفیق لازم در آنها صورت می گیرد. در این‌مقاله سعی برآن بوده تا قواعد واجی حاکم بر فرآیندهای واجی که با عمل کردن تعدادی از آنها نمودهای روساختی وام واژه‌ها به دست می‌آید کشف و معرفی شوند. این فرآیند ها )هماهنگی واکه ای، همگونی همخوان ها،  فرآیند مربوط به ساخت هجا، فرآیند درج واکه – تقویت و تضعیف) با قاعده های مختلف، با استفاده از توصیف تغییرات حاصله در مشخصه های واجی و گاهی با استفاده از متغییر های α و ß و قواعد گشتاری بیان شده اند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Language is the main factor of the culture and multilingual is the most pricise reflex of multi culture. Our country can be Known as a multilingual country because it has placed different societies in its political boundries that each has its own particular culture as well as its own particular language as one of culture elements. In spite of the fact  that different societies have passed different steps of their social history but never lived in isolatic speakers of every one of these languages are in contact with neighbours who speak different languages. Consequently , every body is in a position to learn some of the words used by their neighbours and very frequently people take a linking to some of their neighboures words and take this words over in to their own language. i.e.new words are constantly coming into use. Every language has its own phonological system (its own collection of available speech sound and its own rules for combining these sounds into pronounceable words) the phonological system of persian and Azari are differnet and hence a loan word can be very difficult for speakers to pronounce.So they usually pronounce the loan word as though it were as native word following the ordinary phonological patterns of their language and as a result changing the original pronouncition of the word perhaps greatly. In this research an attempt is made to discover some phonological rules (vowel harmony , consonant assimilation , weakening and strengthening , change in vowels and syllable structure processes) that by using them phonetic representation of loan word is obtained.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>19</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بتول</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمودی</Family>
						<NameE>Batool</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mahmoodi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد زبان شناسی، مدرس دانشگاه آزاد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد زبان شناسی، مدرس دانشگاه آزاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تغییرات تلفظی واژگان فارسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان نوشتاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ترک زبانان تبریز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>- آرلاتو،  آنتونی (1373 )،  درآمدی بر زبان شناسی تاریخی، ترجمه یحیحی مدرسی،  پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.  ##-  بهزادی،  بهزاد( 1369 )، فرهنگ آذربایجانی – فارسی،  انتشارات دنیا.## -ثمره، یدالله (1378 )،آواشناسی زبان فارسی: آواها و ساخت آوایی هجا،  مرکز نشر دانشگاهی##- حسابگر،  حسن( 1371 )،  نظام آوایی زبان ترکی،  پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد،  دانشگاه علامه##- شهریار,محمد حسین( 1370  )،  کلیات اشعار ترکی: به انضمام حیدر بابایا سلام،  انتشارات نگاه##- عمید،  حسن (1357)،  فرهنگ فارسی عمید،  امیرکبیر.  ##- فرزانه،  محمدعلی ( 1344 )، مبانی دستور زبان آذربایجان: اصوات و کلمات،  انتشارات شمس##- مدرسی،  یحی (1368 )،درآمدی بر جامعه شناسی زبان،  مؤسسه مطالعات و تحقیقات.##- معین،  محمد (1363 )، فرهنگ فارسی،  شش جلد،  امیرکبیر.  ##- هادی،  اسمائیل (1379 )، فرهنگ ترکی نوین: تاملاتی در عرصه ریشه شناسی ترکی فارسی،  انتشارات احراز تبریز.##- هایمن،  لاری (1368 )،  نظام آوایی زبان: نظریه و تحلیل، ترجمه یدالله ثمره،  فرهنگ معاصر.##- هیئت،  جواد ( 1379 )، ویژه نامه وارلیق،  تهران.##- یاری،  سیاوش (1374 )، قرض گیری واژگانی زبان ترکی آذری از زبان فارسی و بررسی علل و زمینه های آن،  پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد،  دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.  ##-kenstowicz, M. and Kisse berth , ch.  (1979) , Generative phonology : Description and theory , Newyork : Academic press.##- Lyons , J. (1968) , Introduction to Theoretical Linguistics ,Cambridge : Cambridge University Press.##- Meillet , A(1926-8) , Linguistique Historique et Linquistique , Generale.  Paris : Champion.##- Salimi , Hosein goli , Generative Phonology of Azerbaijani , Ph.D. dissertation , Florida University , 1976.  ##-Trask , R.L. (1996) , Historical Linguistics , Great Britain by J W Arrow Smith Lth , Bristol.##- Yule , G.  (1988) , The Study of Language , Great Britain at the Bath Press , Avon.##-Wein reich , u. (1963) , Language in Contact , The Hague : Mout.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نکاتی‌ چند درباره‌ مطالعه‌ معنی‌ در شرق‌</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Some Points about the History of Studying Language Meaning in East</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در منابع‌ معتبر زبان‌شناسی‌ جهان‌، آنگاه‌ که‌ سهم‌ شرق‌ در مطالعات‌ زبانی‌ به‌ طور عام‌ ومعنی‌شناسی‌ زبان‌ به‌ صورت‌ خاص‌ مطرح‌ می‌شود، تنها مروری‌ مختصر بر بررسی‌های‌زبان‌شناختی‌ اندیشمندان‌ اسلامی‌ طی‌ قرون‌ دوم‌ تا دهم‌ هجری‌ صورت‌ می‌گیرد. برای‌نگارندة‌ این‌ سطور همواره‌ این‌ سئوال‌ مطرح‌ بوده‌ است‌ که‌ 1- آیا به‌ لحاظ منطقی‌می‌توان‌ پذیرفت‌ که‌ در میان‌ ملل‌ شرقی‌، شوق‌ کنکاش‌ در مورد پدیده‌ پر رمز و راز زبان‌، تنها در مقطعی‌ خاص‌ از طول‌ تاریخ‌ و صرفا در میان‌ اندیشمندان‌ اسلامی‌ برانگیخته‌ شده‌است‌؟ و 2- اگر چنین‌ است‌، چه‌ انگیزه‌ای‌ برای‌ آغاز آن‌ و چه‌ دلیلی‌ برای‌ ادامه‌ نیافتن‌این‌ مطالعات‌ پس‌ از قرن‌ دهم‌ هجری‌ می‌توان‌ یافت‌؟</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Among most of the literature-related to the history of linguistic studies in general and the study of meaningful units of language in particular- when the contribution of eastern countries is under consideration, one can only find a brief review over the Arabic linguistic tradition in the early centuries of the Hijra. Two questions can be proposed in this regard: 1) Is it logically acceptable that this very important subject, has been considered in East, just by Islamic scientists and only during this period of time, but not before or after that? And 2) If it is so, what could be the motivation of paying attention to this subject in early centuries of Hijra, and what is the reason of stopping this kind of investigation in 1500A.C. This paper, attempts to claify the contribution of eastern scientists about language studies, and also find some answers to the above-mentioned questions.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>21</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>37</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پروانه‌</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خسروی‌ زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Parvaneh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khosravizadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دورة دکتری زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دورة دکتری زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زرتشت‌</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پانینی‌</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مکتب‌ میمامسا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اندیشمندان‌ اسلامی‌</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان‌شناسی‌ نوین‌</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1- ارشاد، فرهنگ‌ (1379) مهاجرت‌ تاریخی‌ ایرانیان‌ به‌ هند، پژوهشگاه‌ علوم‌ انسانی‌ و مطالعات‌فرهنگی‌، چاپ‌ دوم‌، تهران‌.##2- اسلامی‌ ندوشن‌، محمدعلی‌ (1374) ” اندیشه‌ گراینده‌ به‌ اشراق‌ و اندیشه‌ گراینده‌ به‌ خرد“، فصلنامه‌هستی‌، چاپخانه‌ بهمن‌، تهران‌.##3- اسمارت‌، نینیان‌ و دیگران‌ (1378) سه‌ سنت‌ فلسفی‌، ترجمه‌ ابوالفضل‌ محمودی‌، مرکز انتشارات‌دفتر تبلیغات‌ اسلامی‌، چاپ‌ اول‌، تهران‌.##4 -افراشی‌، آزیتا (1378) ” نگاهی‌ به‌ پیشنه‌ مطالعات‌ سنتی‌ اندیشمندان‌ اسلامی‌ در باره‌ معنی‌“، چاپ‌نشده‌.##5 – بختیاری‌، آرمان‌ (1380) ” فرهنگ‌ نگاری‌ در ایران‌ باستان‌“، مجله‌ نامه‌ ایران‌ باستان‌، سال‌ اول‌، شماره‌ دوم‌، پاییز و زمستان‌ 1380، تهران‌.##6 - بواس‌. جی‌. بی‌گی‌یام‌ و ج‌. ا. کولوگیلی‌ (1376) سیر زبان‌شناسی‌ درجهان‌ اسلام‌ و دیرینه‌زبان‌شناسی‌ عربی‌، ترجمه‌ سیدعلی‌ میرعمادی‌، انتشارات‌ رهنما، چاپ‌ اول‌، تهران‌.##7- تفضلی‌، احمد (1375) تاریخ‌ ادبیات‌ ایران‌ پیش‌ از اسلام‌، انتشارات‌ سخن‌، چاپ‌ اول‌، تهران‌.##8- جعفری‌، علی‌اکبر (1359) ستوت‌ یسن‌، گات‌های‌ آشوزرتشت‌ و سرودهای‌ وابسته‌ به‌ آن‌، انتشارات‌ فروهر، چاپ‌ اول‌، تهران‌.##9- حقیقت‌، عبدالرفیع‌ (1372)، تاریخ‌ علوم‌ و فلسفه‌ ایرانی‌، انتشارات‌ کومش‌، چاپ‌ اول‌، تهران‌.##10- خسروی‌ زاده‌، پروانه‌ (1378) نگاهی‌ گذرا به‌ تاریخچه‌ معنی‌شناسی‌، پایان‌نامه‌ کارشناسی‌ارشد، دانشگاه‌ آزاد اسلامی‌، رشته‌ زبان‌شناسی‌ همگانی‌، تهران‌.##11- خسروی‌ زاده‌، پروانه‌ (1383) ” خاستگاه‌ نظریه‌های‌ زبانی‌; شرق‌ یا غرب؟‌“، فصلنامه‌ پازند، سال‌اول‌، شماره‌ اول‌، تهران‌.##12- رازی‌، عبدالله‌ (1371) تاریخ‌ کامل‌ ایران‌، انتشارات‌ اقبال‌، چاپ‌ نهم‌، تهران‌.##13- رضایی‌، عبدالعظیم‌ (1368) تاریخ‌ ده‌هزارساله‌ ایران‌، جلد اول‌، از پیدایش‌ آریاها تا انقراض‌مادها، انتشارات‌ اقبال‌، چاپ‌ دوم‌، تهران‌.##14- روبینز، آر. اچ‌ (1373) تاریخ‌ مختصر زبان‌ شناسی‌، ترجمه‌ علی‌محمد حق‌شناس‌، انتشارات‌ مادوابسته‌ به‌ نشر مرکز، چاپ‌ دوم‌، تهران‌.##15- ساسانی‌، فرهاد (1377) ” پژوهش‌ها و نگرش‌های‌ زبانی‌ و زبان‌شناختی‌ ابن‌سینا“، فصلنامه‌ زبان‌و ادب شماره‌ 3، سال‌ دوم‌، انتشارات‌ دانشگاه‌ علامه‌ طباطبایی‌، تهران‌.##16- سجادی‌، سیدجعفر, فرهنگ‌ معارف‌ اسلامی‌، شرکت‌ مؤلفان‌ ومترجمان‌ ایران‌، تهران‌.##17- شمس‌، فرهاد (1384) ” نگاهی‌ به‌ پیشینه‌ مطالعات‌ استعاره‌“، فصلنامه‌ زبان‌، ادبیات‌ و فلسفة ‌هزوارش‌، شماره‌ 1، سال‌ اول‌، نشر خانه‌ فرهنگ‌ دانشجو، تهران‌.##18- صفوی‌، کورش‌ (1373) از زبان‌ شناسی‌ به‌ ادبیات‌، جلد اول‌: نظم‌، نشر چشمه‌، چاپ‌ اول‌، تهران‌.##19- صفوی‌، کورش‌ (1379) درآمدی‌ بر معنی‌شناسی‌، انتشارات‌ پژوهشگاه‌ فرهنگ‌ و هنر اسلامی‌، چاپ‌ اول‌، تهران‌.##20- صفوی‌، کورش‌ (1382) معنی‌ شناسی‌ کاربردی‌، انتشارات‌ همشهری‌، چاپ‌ اول‌، تهران‌.##21- صفوی‌، کورش‌ (زیر چاپ‌) آشنایی‌ با تاریخ‌ زبان‌شناسی‌، تهران‌ : سعاد.##22- طه‌، پیام‌ (1376) سیبویه‌ و زبان‌ شناسی‌ نوین‌، پایان‌نامه‌ کارشناسی‌ ارشد، دانشگاه‌ آزاد اسلامی‌، رشته‌ زبان‌ شناسی‌ همگانی‌، تهران‌.##23- عبدالتواب‌، رمضان‌ (1376) مباحثی‌ در فقه‌اللغه‌ و زبان‌ شناسی‌ عربی‌، ترجمه‌ حمیدرضاشیخی‌، معاونت‌ آستان‌ قدس‌ رضوی‌.##24- فارابی‌، ابونصر. احیاءالعلوم‌، ترجمه‌ حسین‌ خدیوجم‌، انتشارات‌ علمی‌ فرهنگی‌، چاپ‌ دوم‌، تهران‌.##25- کریشنان‌، سروپالی‌ رادا و دیگران‌ (1367) تاریخ‌ فلسفه‌ شرق‌ و غرب‌، جلد اول‌، ترجمه‌ خسروجهانداری‌، سازمان‌ انتشارات‌ و آموزش‌ انقلاب‌ اسلامی‌، چاپ‌ اول‌، تهران‌.##26- کریشنان‌، سروپالی‌ رادا و دیگران‌ (1367) تاریخ‌ فلسفه‌ شرق‌ و غرب‌، جلد دوم‌، ترجمه‌ جوادیوسیفیان‌، سازمان‌ انتشارات‌ و آموزش‌ انقلاب‌ اسلامی‌، چاپ‌ اول‌، تهران‌.##27- مشکور، محمدجواد (1378) نامه‌ باستان‌، به‌ کوشش‌ سعید میرمحمدصادق‌ و نادره‌ جلالی‌، پژوهشگاه‌ علوم‌ انسانی‌ و مطالعات‌ فرهنگی‌، چاپ‌ اول‌، تهران‌.##28- مصاحب‌، غلامحسین‌ (1345) دایره‌المعارف‌ فارسی‌، مؤسسه‌ انتشاراتی‌ فرانکلین‌، تهران‌.##29- معین‌، محمد (1371) لغت‌نامه‌، انتشارات‌ امیرکبیر، چاپ‌ هشتم‌، تهران‌.##30- نیرنوری‌، حمید (1345) سهم‌ ایران‌ در تمدن‌ جهان‌، انتشارات‌ شرکت‌ ملی‌ نفت‌ ایران‌، چاپ‌اول‌، تهران‌.##31. Dinneen, S. J,F. P(1967) An Introduction to General Linguistics, Georgetown University.##32. Mahmooda, Rahat (1993) The Contribution of the House of Qadi Badruddaullah to Persian Literature,Ph. D Thesis, University of Madras.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر روابط بینامتنی در خوانش متن</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Influence of Intertextual Relations on the Interpretation of Texts</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در این جُستار، کوشش خواهد شد تا پس از طرح اجمالیِ مبانی نظری بینامتنیت و معرفی زمینه‌های ایرانی (در ادبیات و تفسیر دینی) و اروپایی (میخائیل باختین، ژولیا کرستوا، ژرار ژنت و اومبرتو اکو)، روابط میان عناصر درون متن با بیرون از متن - خواه بافت و محیط فیزیکی، خواه جهان بیناذهنی جامعة زبانی یا فرهنگ و جهان ذهنی خواننده – و تأثیر آن‌ها در شکل‌گیری معنای کلی متن و در نتیجه، معنایی که فراتر از برآیند معنای تک‌تک عناصر درون متن و ساختار درونی متن است، بررسی شود. در این راستا، نمونه‌هایی از روابط برون‌متنی در متن‌های مختلف ارائه و این روابط دسته‌بندی خواهد شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>A brief study of the theoretical foundations of intertextuality is provided. Its European sources- Mikhail Bakhtin, Julia Kristeva, Gérard Genette, and Umberto Eco- are introduced, and several Iranian sources- both in literature and /Quran exegesis- are suggested. It studies relations between internal and external elements of texts: physical context or environment and the inter-subjective world of each linguistic society or culture, and the subjective world of each text-reader might be regarded as external elements the text. Therefore, their influence over the general process of meaning-formation, which is far beyond the aggregate meaning of individual meanings of internal elements of the text plus their structures, is taken into account as well. To do this, a few external relations within different texts are exemplified and classified.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>39</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>55</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فرهاد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ساسانی</Family>
						<NameE>Farhad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sasani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه الزهرا</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه الزهرا</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>fsasani49@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بینامتن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روابط بینامتنی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انواع روابط بینامتنی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>    آلن، گراهام؛ ترجمه‌ی پیام یزدانجو، بینامتنیت (تهران: نشر مرکز، 1380).##    ابن تیمیه، مقدمه التفسیر، ج8، در مجموعه فتاوی (ریاض، 1382ق).##    ابوزید، نصر حامد؛ ترجمه‌ی مرتضی کریمی‌نیا، معنای متن: پژوهشی در علوم قرآن (تهران: طرح نو، 1380).##    استم، رابرت؛ ترجمه‌ی فرهاد ساسانی، ”از متن تا بینامتن“، در رابرت استم، به کوشش احسان نوروزی،  درآمدی بر نظریه‌ی فیلم (تهران: انتشارات سوره‌ی مهر، حوزه‌ی هنری، درحال انتشار)، صص .##    اشکلوفسکی، ویکتور، ”هنر به مثابه‌ی فن“، ترجمه‌ی فرهاد ساسانی، در فرزان سجودی (گردآورنده)، ساخت‌گرایی، پساساخت‌گرایی و مطالعات ادبی (تهران: پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و هنر اسلامی، حوزه‌ی هنری، 1380)، صص 80-49.##    حسن، تمام، الغع”الـ“ عربیه، معها و نها و مبناها (قاهره، 1973).##    خرمشاهی، بهاء‌الدین، ”قرآن و قرآن‌پژوهی“، در قرآن کریم (تهران: انتشارات نیلوفر، 1374)، صص 94-652.##    داد، سیما، فرهنگ اصطلاحات ادبی (تهران: انتشارات مروارید، چ 2: 1375).##    ربیعیان، محمدرضا، ”سرقات ادبی“، در حسن انوشه‌ (گردآورنده)، فرهنگنامه‌ی ادبی فارسی: دانشنامه‌ی ادب فارسی (2) (تهران: سازمان چاپ و انتشارات، 1376)، صص 811-809.##    ساسانی، فرهاد، عوامل مؤثر در تفسیر فهم متن (تهران: رساله‌ی دکتری دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، 1381).##    ساسانی، فرهاد، ”متن مَجازی چندرسانه‌ای: گفتمان پیوستاری هنرـ ناهنر“، زیباشناخت ش 8 (1382) صص 218-199‌.##    سپهری، سهراب، هشت کتاب (تهران: طهوری، چ 15، 1375).##    صفوی، کورش، ”مناسبات بینامتنی“، در حسن انوشه‌ (گردآورنده)، فرهنگنامه‌ی ادبی فارسی: دانشنامه‌ی ادب فارسی (2) (تهران: سازمان چاپ و انتشارات، 1376)، ص 1276.##    عباسپور، هون، ”تلمیح“، در حسن انوشه‌ (گردآورنده)، فرهنگنامه‌ی ادبی فارسی: دانشنامه‌ی ادب فارسی (2) (تهران: سازمان چاپ و انتشارات، 1376)، صص 404-403.##    عبدالحلیم، م ا س؛ ترجمه‌ی ابوالفضل حرّی، ”بافت و مناسبات بینامتنی“، زیباشناخت (1380) 49-325‌:‌4.##   ##    Allen, Graham, Intertexuality (London &amp; New York: Rpotledge, 2000).##    Bakhtin, M. M.; trans. M.Holquist; ed. C. Emerson and M. Holquist, “Forms of Time and Chronotope in the Novel” [Formy vremeni I khronotopa v romane”, in The Dialogical Imagination:     Four Essays (Austin: University of Texas Press, 181; original text published 1938), pp. 4-83.##    Beaugrande, R.-A. de and W.U. Dressler, Introduction to Text Linguistics (London and New York: Longman, 1981).##    Brown, G. &amp; G. Yule, Discourse Analysis (Cambridge, etc: Cambridge University Press, 1983).##    Chandler, Daniel, Semiotics for Beginners, in http://www.aber.ac.uk/media/Documents/S4B/ (1994, last modified 2003); also Semiotics: Basics (Daniel Taylor &amp; Francis Inc., 2002).##    Eco, Umberto, Ínnovation and Repetition: Between Modern and Post-Modern Aesthetics”, in Umberto Eco, ed. Capozzi Roco, Reading Umberto Eco: An Anthology (Advances in Semiotics) (Indiana University Press, 1997).##    Currie, Mark, Metafiction (Essex: Longman Group, 1995).##    Genette, G.erard, Palimpsestes: la littérature au second gegré (Paris: Seuil, 1982).; English trans, Palimpsets: Literature in the Second Degree (University of Nebraska Press, 1997a).##    Genette, Gerard, Paratexts, Threshold of Interpretation (Cambridge University Press, 1997b; original text  published in 1987).##    Hansen, Tina, “Intertexuality in the Scream Trilogy”, in www.sprog.auc.dk/res/pub/Arb-haefter/Nr29/Kapitel-2.pdf.##    Halliday, M. A. K. and R. Hasan, Cohesion in English (London: Longman, 1976).##    Hegel, G. W. F.; trans. J. B. Ballie, The Phenomenology of Mind (Dover Publications, 2nd ed. 2003); also as  Spirit: The Phenomenology of Spirit, trans. The Trinity College Staff, ed. E. Shannon (Hackett Publishing Company, 2001).##    Malinowski, B., “The Problem of Meaning in Primitive Languages”, Supplement to C.K. Ogden and I.A. Richards, The Meaning of Meaning (London: Kegan Paul, Trench, Trubner, 1923), pp. 451-511.##    Malmkjær, Kirsten, “Text Linguistics”, in Kirsten Malmkjær (ed.), The Linguistic Encyclopedia (London and New York: Routledge, 1991), pp. 461-71.##   Searle, J. R., Speech Acts: An Essay in the Philosophy of Language (Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1969).##    Stam, Robert, Film Theory: An Introduction (Malden, Mass. &amp;  Oxford: Blackwell Publishers, 2000).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نگرش فلسفی- اسلامی به مساله معناداری زبان دین</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Philosophical-Islamic Viewpoint to the Problem of Meaninglessness of Religious Statements</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>با ظهور فلسفه های زبانی با آراء راسل و ویتگنشتاین، مسالة معناداری گزاره ها محور توجه قرار گرفت. با نوع نگاه تجربیِ آنها، معناداری گزاره های دینی، اخلاقی، هنری و مابعدالطبیعی محل تردید شد. پس از ایشان، پزیتیویست های منطقی همچون آیر، گزاره های دینی را با ملاک تحقیق پذیری و سپس ابطال پذیری، بی معنا (نه کاذب) دانستند. در این مقاله به طرح شبهة معناداری گزاره های دینی توسط آنتونی فلو و پاسخ های ریچارد هیر، بازیل میچل، جان هیک و یان کرومبی پرداخته می شود. سپس سعی خواهد شد از منظری دیگر، شبهه و پاسخ ها ارزیابی گردد و در نهایت، پاسخی جدید به شبهه از منظر فلسفیِ اسلامی ارائه گردد. در این پاسخ، به برداشت های غلط از رابطة خدا و عالم و صفات او که منشا این نگاهها شده است و تعمیم نابجای تجربه گرایی پرداخته می شود. در پایان، دیدگاه تصحیح شده ارائه خواهد گردید.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The viewpoints of Russell and Wittgenstein in the beginning of twentieth century made philosophy of language in the center of philosophical attitudes. The meaningfulness of statements was the core of attention. They made the meaningfulness of statements in ethics, religion, aesthetics and metaphysics in doubt. The logical positivists, after them, like A.J.Ayer, accounted religious statements meaningless (not untrue) by their criteria of verifiability and falsification for meaningful statements.
In this paper, the problem of meaninglessness of religious statements which is posed by Anthony Flew and the solutions in the views of Richard Hare, Basil Mitchell, John Hick and Ian Crombie will be examined. Then the problem and solutions will be evaluated. At the end, a new answer to the problem from an Islamic philosophical viewpoint will be introduced with a clarification of some problematical account of religious beliefs.
 </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>57</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>72</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمید رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آیت اللهی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamidreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ayatollahy</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه فلسفه دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه فلسفه دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>معناداری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحقیق پذیری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ابطال پذیری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گزاره دینی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان شناختاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خداوند</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>پوپر، کارل ریموند. (1370) منطق اکتشاف علمی. ترجمه احمد آرام. تهران. انتشارات سروش##چالمرز، آلن اف. (1378) چیستی علم. ترجمه سعید زیبا کلام. تهران. انتشارات سمت## علی زمانی، امیر عباس. (1375) زبان دین. قم. مرکز انتشارات دفتر تبلیغات حوزه علمیه قم##علی زمانی، امیر عباس. (1381) خدا، زبان و معنا. قم. آیت عشق.##لاکوست، ژان. (1375) فلسفه در قرن بیستم. ترجمه دکتر رضا داوری اردکانی. تهران. سمت##هارتناک، یوستوس. (1356) ویتگنشتاین. ترجمه منوچهر بزرگمهر. تهران. انتشارات خوارزمی##هیک، جان. (1372) فلسفه دین. ترجمه بهرام راد. تهران. انتشارات بین المللی الهدی##قائمی نیا، علیرضا. (1380) تجربه دینی و گوهر دین. قم. بوستان کتاب قم##Ayer, Alfred Jules. (1936) Language, Truth and Logic. London, V. Gollancz Ltd.##Ayer, Alfred Jules. (1959) Logical Positivism. Glencoe, Free Press.##Crombie, I.M., (1971). &quot;The Possibility of Theological Statement&quot; in Basil Mitchell (ed.). The Philosophy of Religion. (pp. 23-53) Oxford. Oxford.##Flew, Anthony &amp; MacIntyr, Alasdair (eds.). (1963). New Essays in Philosophical Theology. New York. Macmillan Publishing Company.##Flew, Anthony; Hare, Richard and Mitchell, Basil. (1971) &quot;theology and Falsification&quot; in Basil Mitchell (ed.). The Philosophy of Religion. (pp. 1-13) Oxford. Oxford##Geisler, Norman L. (1974) Philosophy of Religion, Michigan. The Zondervan Corporation Grand Rapids.##Hick, John. (1971). &quot;Theology and Verification&quot; in Basil Mitchell (ed.). The Philosophy of Religion. (pp. 53-72) Oxford. Oxford.##Hick, John. (1990). Classical and Contemporary Readings in the Philosophy of Religion. (3rd edition). New Jersey. Prentice Hall, Englewood Cliffs##Hick, John. (June 1977). &quot;Eschatological Verification Reconsidered&quot;. Religious Studies. Vol. 13, No. 2. 189-202.##Hudson, William Donald. (1968). Ludwig Wittgenstein. John Knox Press.##Mitchell, Basil (ed.). (1957) Faith and Logic. London. George Allen and Unwin.##Sell, Alan P.F. (1988) The Philosophy of Religion 1875-1980. New York. Croom Helm.##Stiver, Dan R. (1996) The Philosophy of Religious Language: Sign, Symbol and Story. Oxford. Blackwell Publishers.##Wisdom, John. (1944). &quot;Gods&quot; in Proceedings of the Aristotelian Society, XLV. (185-206).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی گفتمانی، منظور شناختی، و معنایی قابلیت فراگیری و تجزیة دوگانة پارامتر ضمیرافکنی در دستور جهانی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Discoursal, Pragmatic, and Semantic Analysis of the Learnability and Bifurcation of the Pro-Drop Parameter in UG</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>بنیان دستور جهانی چامسکی به ارائه پاسخ به این پرسش معطوف است که شالودة نظریه پردازی در زبان شناسی چیست (چامسکی، ١٩٨٦). نخستین پرسشی که در این زمینه مطرح می شود، این است که «دانش زبانی از چه تشکیل می شود؟» از دیدگاه چامسکی، دانستن یک زبان به منزلة قرار داشتن در وضعیت ذهنی خاصی است که مشخصة آن، ساختار شناختی خاص متشکل از دستگاه قواعد و اصول است. پرسش دیگری که شالودة نظریه پردازی در زبان شناسی است، این است که «دانش زبانی چگونه فرا گرفته می شود؟» این پرسش به مشکل منطقی فراگیری زبان می انجامد که جنبة خاصی از مشکل افلاطونی است. پاسخ چامسکی به این پرسش در تمامی آثارش، فرضیة ذاتی بودن زبان است که طبق آن، انسان از دانش زبانی ذاتی و غیرآگاهانه برخوردار است که قوة زبان نام دارد. دستور جهانی مربوط به ماهیت این دانش پیشینی برحسب همگانی های زبانی است که نظریة اصول و پارامترها نام دارد. براساس تعامل این اصول با پارامترهای برخوردار از ارزش مقید و غالبا&quot; دوگانه است که همگانی های زبانی و تنوع زبانی در اردوگاه چامسکی تبیین می شود (چامسکی، ١٩٩٣، ١٩٩٥؛ چامسکی و لاسنیک، ١٩٩٣). یکی از جذابیت های اصلی دستور جهانی، ارائه پارامترهایی است که دستورهای قابل اکتساب را محدود می کند و حیطة از پیش تعیین شده ای را مشخص می کند که هر دستور خاص، در چارچوب آن قرار می گیرد. یکی از این پارامترها که چامسکی (١٩٨٢) خصوصا&quot; پس از پلموتر (١٩٧١)، تارالدسن (١٩٧٨)، یگلی (١٩٨٢)، و ریتسی (١٩٨٢) وضع کرد، پارامتر ضمیرافکنی است. این پارامتر معین می کند که آیا می توان فاعل یک جمله یا بند را حذف کرد یا خیر. این پارامتر دارای دو ارزش است: ضمیرافکنی و ضمیرگذاری. براساس دستور جهانی، زبان های ضمیرافکن مانند فارسی و ایتالیایی، دارای جمله های بدون فاعل اند، حال آنکه، زبان های ضمیرگذار مانند انگلیسی و فرانسه، فاقد این جمله هااند. این مقاله به نقد پارامتر ضمیرافکنی از منظر (١) قابلیت فراگیری این پارامتر، (٢) نقش عوامل گفتمانی، منظورشناختی، و معنایی، (٣) تقسیم ساده انگارانة زبان ها به ضمیرافکن و ضمیرگذار می پردازد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The focus of work in Chomsky’s generative grammar is to provide an answer to what he considers to undergird theorizing in linguistics (Chomsky, 1986). The first question to be addressed for this purpose is “what constitutes knowledge of language?” From a Chomskyan point of view, to know a language is to be in a specific mental state characterized by a certain cognitive structure consisting of a system of rules and principles. The second question fundamental to theorizing in linguistics is “How is knowledge of language acquired?” This question constitutes the logical problem of language acquisition, a special case of Plato’s problem. The answer provided by Chomsky throughout his writing is the innateness hypothesis, according to which human beings are endowed with some internal, unconscious knowledge of language known as language faculty. The theory of Universal Grammar (UG) is concerned with the nature of the initial state of this language faculty. UG provides an answer to the nature of a priori linguistic knowledge in terms of universals, a finite array of which are parameterized: hence the principles and parameters theory. It is through the interaction of the principles with the finitely valued parameters that both language universals and language variations are accounted for in Chomsky’s camp (Chomsky, 1993, 1995; Chomsky and Lasnik, 1993). A major attraction of UG is the provision of parameters which constrain the class of attainable grammars and specify the predetermined range that particular grammars fall within. One of the parameters set up by Chomsky (1982), following Pelmutter (1971), Taraldson (1970), Jaeggli (1982), and Rizzi (1982), is the null subject/ pro-drop parameter. This parameter “determines whether the subject of a clause can be suppressed. It has two values: either + pro-drop or pro-drop. According to UG, a pro-drop language, e.g. Persian and Italian, can have null-subject sentences, while non-pro-drop languages, like English and French, cannot. The aim of this paper is to present a critical analysis of the pro-drop parameter in terms of (1) the learnability of the pro-drop parameter, (2) the role of discoursal, pragmatic, and semantic factors in the acquisition of the pro-drop parameter, and (3) the simplistic bifurcation of languages into pro-drop and non-pro-drop.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>73</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>88</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ضیاءالدین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تاج الدین</Family>
						<NameE>Zia</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tajeddin</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دستور جهانی چامسکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دانش زبانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قوة زبان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ضمیرافکنی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Baker, C. L. (1979). Syntactic theory and the projection problem. Linguistic Inquiry 10, 533-581.##Berman, R. H. (1990). On acquiring an (s)vo language: subjectless sentences in children’s Hebrew. Linguistics 28, 1135-1166.##Braine, M. (1971). On two types of models of the internalization of grammar. In D. Slobin (ed.), The Ontogenesis of Grammar. New York: Academic Press.##Brown, R., and Hanlon, C. (1970). Derivation complexity and the order of acquisition in child speech. In J. R. Hayes (ed.), Cognition and the Development of Language. New York: John Wiley.##Chomsky, N. (1965). Aspects of the Theory of syntax. Cambridge, Mass.: MIT Press.##Chomsky, N. (1981). Lectures on Government and Binding. Dordrecht: Foris.##Chomsky, N. (1982). Some Concepts and Consequences of the Theory of Government and Binding. Cambridge, Mass.: MIT Press.##Chomsky, N. (1986). Knowledge of Language: Its Nature, Origin, and Use. New York: Praeger.##Chomsky, N. (1992). On the nature, use, and acquisition of language. In W. G. Lycan (ed.), Mind and Cognition. Oxford: Blackwell.##Chomsky, N. (1993). A minimalist program for linguistic theory. In K. Hale and S. Keyser (eds.), The View from Building 20. Cambridge, Mass.: MIT Press.##Chomsky, N. (1995). The Minimalist Program. Cambridge, Mass.: MIT Press.##Chomsky, N., and Lasnik, H. (1977). Filters and control. Linguistic Inquiry 8, 425-504.##Chomsky, N., and Lasnik, H. (1993). The theory of principles and parameters. In J. Jacobs et al. (eds.), syntax, Vol. 1. Berlin: Walter de Gruyter.##Hawkins, J. A. (1992). Explaining language universals. In J. A. Hawkins (ed.), Explaining Language Universals. Oxford: Blackwell.##Huang, J. C.-T. (1982). Logical relations in Chinese and the theory of grammar. Unpublished Ph. D. dissertation, MIT.##Huang, J. C.-T. (1984). On the distribution and reference of empty pronouns. Linguistic Inquiry 15, 531-574.##Jaeggli, O. A. (1982). Topics in Roman Syntax. Dordrecht: Foris.##Park, H. (2004). A minimalist approach to null subjects and objects in second language acquisition. Second Language Research 20, 1-32.##Pelmutter, D. (1971). Deep and Surface Constraints in Syntax. New York: Holt, Reinhart and Winston.##Rizzi, L. (1982). Issues in Italian Syntax. Dordrecht: Foris##Taraldson, T. (1978). On the NTC, Vacuous Application, and the That-Trace Filter. Bloomington: Indiana University Linguistics Club.##Truscott, J., and Wexler, K. (1989). Some problems in the parametric analysis of learnability. In R. T. Matthews and W. Demopoulos (eds.), Learnability and Linguistic Theory. Dordrecht: Kluwer Academic Publishers.##White, L. (1989). Universal Grammar and Second Language Acquisition. Amsterdam: John Benjamins Publishers.##درویشیان, علی اشرف. ۱٣٥۹. فصل نان (چاپ هفتم). تهران: انتشارات روزبهان.##کلیله و دمنه. تهران: بنگاه مطبوعاتی فرخی.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>برخی از فرایندهای واجی در ترکی بیجار</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Number of Phonological Processes of Bijar Turkish</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مقالۀ حاضر به توصیف و تحلیل برخی از فرایندهای واجی پربسامد در زبان ترکی بیجار، بر اساس گونۀ زبانی روستای &quot;اوچگنبد سلطان&quot; می پردازد. بدین منظور، از چهار گویشور زبان ترکی بیجار و ضبط چهار ساعت مکالمه و طرح پرسشنامۀ از پیش تعیین شده بر مبنای مطالعۀ گویش ها استفاده شده است. همچنین یکی از نگارندگان به عنوان یک گویشور ترک زبان، از صحت اطلاعات کسب شده اطمینان حاصل کرده است. هماهنگی واکه ای در پسوند جمع /l{rـ/ و /lArـ/ و در پسوند مصدرساز /mAxـ/ و /mecـ/، همگونی بین همخوان و واکه، هماهنگی واکه ای به هنگام افزودن پسوند ماضی ساز، تبدیل همخوانهای بی واک به واکدار و درج واکه میان خوشۀ همخوانی پایانی در کلمات قرضی ترکی از مهمترین فرایندهایی است که در این مقاله، با ارائۀ شواهد کافی، مورد تحلیل و بررسی قرار گرفته و قاعدۀ مربوط به هر فرایند، عنوان می شود. 
داده ها و قواعد ارائه شده، به منظور تأیید و اثبات این مطلب به خدمت گرفته می شوند که فرایندهای واجی مذکور، در زبان ترکی بیجار وجود دارد و مشخصه های شرکت کننده در هر فرایند، به تنهایی و مستقل از سایر مشخصه ها، در فرایند های واجی شرکت می کنند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Based on the language variety of the &quot;Ochgonbad Soltan&quot; village, the present paper deals with the description and the analysis of a number of frequent phonological processes of Bijar Turkish language. In order to collect data, four Bijar Turkish speakers, four hours recorded speech and the provided questionnaire according to dialect studies have been used.One of the authors as a native speaker of Bijar Turkish, has been assured of data correctness. Vowel harmony in plural suffix /-l{r/ and /-lAr/, infinitive marker /-mec/ and /-mAx/, assimilation between consonant and vowel, vowel harmony in adding past suffix, changing of voiceless consonants to voiced ones, vowel inserting through final consonant clusters in loan words which are existed in Bijar Turkish language, are of the most frequent phonological processes. Presenting a good number of evidences, the processes would be analyzed and the corresponding rules would be pointed out.
       The data and rules would help to reexamine that the phonological processes mentioned above,exist in Bijar Tukish and involved features in each process take part independently and apart from the other features.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>89</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>103</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عالیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کرد زعفرانلوکامبوزیا</Family>
						<NameE>Aliye</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kord-e- Za’feranloo Kamboozia</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رضویان</Family>
						<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Razavian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد زبان شناسی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد زبان شناسی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هماهنگی واکه ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>همگونی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>درج</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اصل سلسله مراتب رسایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>۱ـ  ثمره، یداله (۱۳۷۸)، آواشناسی زبان فارسی، چ پنجم، تهران، مرکز نشر دانشگاهی.##۲ـ  حق شناس، علی محمد (۱۳۸۰) ، آواشناسی (فنوتیک)، چ هفتم، تهران، انتشارات آگاه.##۳- حسابگر، حسن (1370)، نظام  آوایی زبان ترکی، پایان نامه ی کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه علامۀ طباطبایی.##۴ـ  رضایی باغ بیدی، حسن (۱۳۸۰)، معرفی زبانها و گویشهای ایران، تهران، انتشارات فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی، به مناسبت نخستین همایش گویش شناسی.##5ـ  روحانی علیرضا (۱۳۷۸)، فعل مرکب در زبان ترکی، پایان نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس.##6- کامبوزیا، عالیه، ک.ز. (۱۳82)، &quot;ساخت اسمهای تحبیبی در زبان انگلیسی&quot;، مجلۀ زبان و ادبیات دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان، س1، ش1، ص123-131.##7ـ  محمد نژاد، شمسی (۱۳80)، بررسی اسم مرکب و مشتق در زبان ترکی آذری، پایان نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس.##8ـ  ناصح، محمد امین (۱۳80)، فهرست پایان نامه های کارشناسی ارشد و دکتری در زمینۀ  گویشهای ایران، تهران، انتشارات فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی.##9ـ  نوروزی زیدهی، طاهره (۱۳۷۸)، بررسی فرایندهای واجی گویش گیلکی رشت در چارچوب واج شناسی خود واحد، پایان نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس.##10ـ وزین پور، نادر (۱۳48)، ساختمان فعل در ترکی آذری، تهران، چاپخانۀ  چهر.##11ـ  هیئت، جواد (۱۳66)، سیری در تاریخ زبان و لهجه‌های ترکی، چ دوم، تهران، نشر نو.##12- Clauson, G. (2002) Studies in Turkic and Mongolic linguistics, London, Routledge Curzon.##13-Crystal, D. (1989) The Cambridge encyclopedia of language, New york, Cambridge university press.##14- Katamba, F. (1993) Morphology, London, Macmilian press.##15-Kenstowicz, M. (1994) Phonology in generative grammar, Oxford, Blackwell.##16-Kornfilt, J. (1987) “Turkish and the Turkic languages”, in B. comrie (ed). The world’s major language, London, Roultedge. pp. 619-44.##17-Lass, R. (1998) phonology, Cambridge University press.##18-Laver, J. (1995) Principles of phonetics, Cambridge University press New york.##19-Lyons, J. (1962) “Phonemic and non phonemic phonology”: some typological reflections. International journal of American linguistics, 28:127-33; reprinted in W.E. Jones and J.Laver (eds) phonetics in linguistics: a book of readings, London: Longman.##20-Maryami, M. (1995) A contrastive study of Azarbaijani Turkish and Persian sound system, M.A.thesis, linguistics. TMU.       ##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ممکن‌ها و ناممکن‌های ترجمه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Possibilities and Impossibilities of Translation</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>ترجمه با دو پیام « معادل » در دو « رمز» متفاوت سرو کار دارد . وقتی پیامی از «صورت» اصلی به « صورت » دیگری منتقل می‌شود، اگر کار ترجمه درست باشدکمترین تفاوت مسلّم بین پیام موجود در «صورت» متن اصلی و پیام عرضه شده در «صورت» متن ترجمه، همان «تغییر صورت» یا «تغییر شکل » پیام است. بنابراین، هر ترجمه‌ای  در صورتی که درست و دقیق باشد می‌تواند فقط «معادلی» برای اصل باشد و نه « مساوی» با آن، زیرا در دو «طرز بیان» یا دو «رمز» متفاوت، هرگز نمی‌توان دو پیام کاملاً برابر یا «مساوی» را عرضه کرد. مقالة حاضر، تلاشی است در جهت تبیین ممکن بودن تعادل و ناممکن بودن برابری کامل با اصل  در ترجمه.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Translation occurs when a message is reproduced in a “code” different from that of the original. When a message is transferred from the original “form” into another, the least inevitable difference between the translation and its original will be the change in the “form” of the message. Therefore, every translation, being a true one, can be just an “equivalent”  to the original, not “identical” with it, as there can never be “identity” beween two messages expressed in two different expressions or codes. The present article is an attempt to discouss the possibility of “equivalence” and impossibility of “identity” in translation.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>105</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>118</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سالار</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>منافی اناری</Family>
						<NameE>Salar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Manafi Anari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تعادل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تساوی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>طرز بیان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>معادل بالقوه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>معادل مطلوب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>            Abdul-Raof, H. ,Qur`an Translation: Discourse, Texture and Exegesis, Curzon Press, Great Britain, 2001.##            Baker, M. In Other Words, Routledge, London, 1992.##            Barnstone, W., The Poetics of Translation: History, Theory, Practice,  Yale University Press, New Haven and London, 1993.##            Catford, J. C. , A Linguistic Theory of Translation, OUP, London, 1965.##            Hatim, B. and I. Mason, Discourse and the Translator, Longman, London, 1990.##            Jakobson, R.,``On Linguistic Aspects of Translation``, cited in L. Venuti (ed.) , The Translation Studies Reader, Routledge, London, 2000.##            Larson, M.L., Meanin–Based Translation: A Guide to Cross-Language Equivalence, University Press of America, Lanham, 1984.##            Munday, J., Introducing Translation Studies : Theories and Applications, Routledge, London, 2001.##            Newmark, P., Approaches to Translation, Pergamon Press, Oxford, 1982.##            __________ , A Textbook of Translation, Prentice Hall, Hemel Hempstead, 1988.##            _________ , About Translation, Multilingual Matters Ltd . , Clevedon, 1991.##            Nida, E. A.,  Toward a Science of Translationg , E.J. Brill, Leiden, 1964.##            Nida, E.A. and C. R. Taber, Theory and Practice of Translation, E.J. Brill, Leiden , 1969.##            Reiss, K., Translation Criticism: The Potentials and Limitations, Translated into English by E.F. Rhodes, St. Jerome Publishing, Manchester, 2000.##            Wehr, H. A Dictionary of Modern Written Arabic,  edited by J.M.Cowan, Spoken Language Service, Inc., New York, 1976.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>واژة “ عروس“ در فرهنگ ژرمنی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>“BRAUT” in german Culture</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مقالة حاضر به بررسی واژة عروس (Braut) در زبان ژرمنی و ریشه‌شناختی آن با توجه به چند زبان دیگر خانوادة زبانی هند و اروپایی می‌پردازد. از این کلمه، معانی:  زوجة شرعی، زن در روز ازدواج، نامزد، همسرِ پسر، دوشیزه، باکره و همبستر از متن‌های گوناگون باستان و میانه در دست است. در یک دوره، معنای صفتی هم داشته است که احتمالاً کلمة عروسی (Hochzeit) هم‌ریشه با این معنی است. در تحولات آوایی این واژه, بار فرهنگی آن را نباید فراموش کرد. </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>This Paper studies the word “BRAUT” in german language and the ethymology comparing to a few other Indo-european languages.
There are many meanings related to this word such as: legal partner, woman on her wedding’s day, fiancée, bride, maid, bedfellow, which are coming from different old and middle texts. Probably the term “Hochzeit” (= wedding) comes from an adjective meaning in past.
According to the ethymological view, should be necessary not to forget the cultural aspect of this word.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>119</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>128</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پریسا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>درخشان مقدم</Family>
						<NameE>Parisa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Derakhshan Moghaddam</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ریشه‌شناختی – زبان – زبان‌شناسی – معنی‌شناسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Bechtel, Friedrich (1914): Lexilogus zu Homer. Etymologie und Stammbildung homerischer Wörter. Halle (Nachdruck Darmstadt 1964), (S. 200 f.).##Braune, Wilhelm (1907): Nhd. Braut in den germanischen Sprachen. In: BGDSL 32, S. 30-59. Ausgehend von der Auseinandersetzung mit Behaghel im gleichen Band S. 6-9. Vgl. auch die “Nachträge zu Braut”, im gleichen Band S. 559-562.##Domaszewski, A. von (1893): Das deutsche Wort Braut in lateinischen Inschriften. In: Neue Heidelberger Jahrbücher 3, S. 193-197.##Fischer, Andreas (1986): Engagment, Wedding and Marriage in Old English. Heidelberg.##Gundermann, G. (1901): Das deutsche Wort Braut bei Römern und Griechen. In: ZdW 1, S. 240-246.##van Helten, W. (1909). Zur Etymologie von Braut. In : BGDSL 35, S. 306-310.##Kauffmann, Friedrich (1910): Braut und Gemahl. In: ZdPh 42, S. 129-153.##Kluge, Friedrich (1909): Zur deutschen Etymologie. III (Braut). In: BGDSL 34, S. 561-566.##Köstler, Rudolf (1943): Raub-, Kauf-und Friedelehe bei den Germanen. In: ZRG, gm. Abt. 63, S. 92-136.##W. Krogmann (1932): Frutis. In : Glotta 20, S. 175-180.##ders. (1934): Brautlauf und Braut. In: WuS 16, S. 80-90.##Loewe, Richard (1906): Altgermanische Elemente der Balkansprachen. I Griechisch. A Vermittlung durch das Latein. 5. Mgr. brýtis. In: ZvS 39, S. 276-280.##Markey, T. L. (1985): Possession and “Own” (in Indo-European and Beyond). In: Hansjakob Seiler &amp; Gunter Brettschneider (eds.): Language Invariants and Mental Operations. Tübingen. S. 124-134.##ders. (1987): The Lexical Semantics of Western Indo-European “Girl”. In: Aspects of Language. Studies in Honour of Mario Alinei, ed. N. Arhammar &amp; A. Hagen. Amsterdam. S. 275-288.##Thieme, Paul (1963): “Jungfrauengatte”. In: ZuS 78, S. 161-248.##von Kraus, Carl (1952): Deutsche Liederdichter des 13. Jahrhunderts, Tübingen 38nI.##Wiedemann (1902): Etymologien. 2. Got. brūþs und andre idg. Verwandtschaftsnamen. In: BKIS 27, S. 205-226 (speziell bis 218).##آموزگار، ژاله و احمد تفضلی، 1375. اسطورة زندگی زردشت. تهران: چشمه.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>زبان فارسی به مثابه زبانی هسته آغازین</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Persian is a Head-Initial Language</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>اگر چه بیشتر گروههای نحوی زبان فارسی، همجون گروه اسمی (NP)، گروه صفتی (AP) و گروه قیدی با حرف اضافه (PP) ساختار هسته آغازین تلقی گشته اند و بر این مبنا تحلیل شده اند، با این حال اکثر دستوریان و زبان شناسان بر مبنای توالی عناصر سازندة جمله که ساخت فاعل- مفعول- فعل یا (SOV) را ارائه می دهند، این زبان را اساساً زبانی هسته پایانی تصور نموده اند، در این مقاله، نویسنده با استناد به این واقعیت که اکثر گروههای بیشینه زبان فارسی (XPs) هسته آغازین اند، این طور استدلال می کند که اگر بتوان تحلیلی برای گروههای فعلی ارائه نمود که مزیتی معنی دار برای توالی SOV نسبت به SVO قائل نشود، می توان زبان فارسی را اساساً به مثابه زبانی هسته آغازین تحلیل نمود. نویسنده با استناد به شواهدی همچون تولید جمله های مکمل (CPs) پس از فعل متعدی، جای دهی ضمائر مرخم (Clitics) و جایگاه قید نسبت به هستة گروه فعلی و مکمل آن، در کنار وقوع همزمان توالی (OV) و (VO) به این نتیجه می رسد که در یک تحلیل نحوی نه تنها فرض ساخت زیر بنایی (SOV) برای فارسی توجیه نظری ندارد بلکه فرض SVO برای این زبان، زیر ساخت فارسی را بهتر تحلیل می کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Although the majority of Persian maximal projections (XPs) such as Noun Phrases (NP/DPs), Adjectival Phrases (APs) and Prepositional Phrases (PPs) are head-initial, many grammarians and linguists have considered this language head-final just because of the word order of the sentence which is mostly SOV.  This paper, focusing on the head initial structure of the majority of XPs in Persian argues for the head-initial analysis for this language based on the following three observations: first, post-verbal generation of CP-complements; second, placement of clitics and third, positioning of adverb relative to the V°, head of VP and its complement.  These observations in addition to the dual occurrence of OV and VO structure in Persian sentences conclude that supposing the head-final analysis for Persian does not illustrate the underlying structure of this language and proposes a head-initial analysis for Persian.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>129</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>135</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>معین زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Ahmad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moinzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه انگلیسی، دانشگاه اصفهان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه انگلیسی، دانشگاه اصفهان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هسته آغازین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نحو</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گروههای بیشینه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گروه فعلی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساخت زیر بنایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>مشکوة الدینی، مهدی. (1376). &quot; جایگاه هسته در گروهها و جمله های پیرو فارسی&quot;. مقاله ارائه شده در چهارمین کنفرانس زبانشناسی، تهران: دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی.##Chomsky, N. (1965). Aspects of the Theory of Syntax. Cambridge, Mass: MIT Press.##Greenberg, J.H. (ed.). (1963). Universals of Language. Second Edition. Cambridge,##Mass: MIT Press.##Kayne, R. (1994). The Antisymmetry of Syntax. Cambridge, Mass: MIT Press.##Marashi, M. (1970). &quot;The Persian Verb: A Partial Description for Pedagogical Purposes&quot;.##Ph.D. dissertation. The University of Texas at Austin.##Moinzadeh, A. (2001). &quot;An Antisymmetric, Minimalist Approach to Persian Phrase##Structure&quot;. Ph.D. dissertation. The University of Ottawa.##Moinzadeh, A. (2005). &quot;A New Approach to the Ezafe Phrase in Persian&quot;. In Cahiers Linguistiques d&#039;Ottawa, Vol. 33, pp. 43-64.##Vennemann, T. (1972). &quot;Analogy in Generative Grammar, the Origin of Word Order&quot;. In##L. Heilmann (ed.) Proceedings of the Eleventh International Congress of##Linguistics. 2 Volumes (Bologna:II Mulino)##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ویژگی‌های شاخص گویش سمنانی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Main Characteristics of Semnani Dialect</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>سمنانی یکی از گویش‌های اصیل ایرانی است که بسیاری از ویژگی‌های زبان‌های ایرانی باستان را در خود حفظ کرده است. سه ویژگی مهّم این گویش، کنائی(ergativity)، جنس (gender) و حالت (case) است که هر کدام از آنها را به طور مختصر در اینجا توضیح می دهیم.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>One way to recognize the original Iranian dialects is to search for atleast one of the following three characteristics in them, namely ergativity, gendar, and case. With respect to the fact that semnani dialect possesses all the three mentioned features we can come to the conclusion that semnani dialect is one of the most original dialects of todays Iran.                               </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>137</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>141</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ایران</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کلباسی</Family>
						<NameE>Iran</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>kalbasi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کنایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جنس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حالت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گویش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>پناهی سمنانی، محمداحمد (1366)، فرهنگ سمنانی (شرح حال و نمونه آثار محلی شاعران در گویش سمنانی). تهران، ناشر: مؤلف.##پناهی سمنانی، محمداحمد (1374)، آداب و رسوم مردم سمنان. انتشارات پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##کلباسی، ایران (1367)، ارگتیو در زبان‌ها وگویش‌های ایرانی، مجلةزبان شناسی، مرکز نشردانشگاهی، سال 5، شمارة 2، ص 70- 87.##ویندفور، گرنوت (1383)، حالت در زبان‌های ایرانی، ترجمة اسفندیار طاهری، نامة پارسی، سال 9، شمارة 1، ص 27- 55.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				