<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>23</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An analysis of turn-taking and interruptions as two strategies of communicative skills in IRIB TV talk</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مهارت‌های ارتباطی نوبت‌گیری و قطع کلام در برنامه‌های مجری‌محور سیمای جمهوری اسلامی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>61</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>78</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2253</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>آنی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم سادات</FirstName>
					<LastName>غیاثیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Communication is comprised of verbal and non-verbal skills. Moreover, communication process has some components (e.g. sender, receiver, message, media, channel, noise, feedback, texture, etc.) which have the potentiality to be analyzed from different perspectives. Two principles of turn taking and interruption are among the important communicative competences that have integral connections with other competences. These two principles have close relationships with the principle of social politeness. The correct observation of these principles leads to a more effective and successful rapport between the presenters and audience. This article puts emphasis on interior design (decoration and furniture), and proximities, (territoriality, proximity, and orientation) in the context of the principles turn-taking and interruption . Considering this,  a hundred and twenty minutes of presenter-oriented programs on Iranian national television channels (channels One, Two, Three, and Four) were analyzed , focusing on the first fifteen minutes of eight programs (that is, two programs from each channel). This article employs descriptive-analytic approach to “circumscribe the current communicative competence of presenter-oriented programs in Iranian national television programs in comparison with an ideal condition”.&lt;br /&gt; The findings of this study showed that many factors affect turn-taking,  including failure to observe verbal and non-verbal principles, compliments, concluding phrases, clarification probes, information, adjacency pairs, apologies and their acceptance, subject matters, reflection, imperative demands and doubt</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مهم‌ترین نقش زبان، برقراری ارتباط در روابط اجتماعی و میان‌فردی است. این امر در راستای قواعد کاربردشناختی زبان قرار دارد. توانایی  کاربرد این قواعد و اصول «توانش ارتباطی» نامیده می‌شود و نقش مهمی در کیفیت ارتباطات اجتماعی انسان‌ها از لحاظ تأثیر کنش‌ها و واکنش‌های آنها در اذهان و کنش‌های کلامی و غیرکلامی مخاطبان ایفا می‌کند. مهارت‌های ارتباطی دارای انواع کلامی و غیرکلامی و مؤلفه‌های بسیاری همچون:گیرنده، فرستنده، پیام، رسانه، کانال، سروصدا یا اختلال، بازخورد و بافت است و هریک از آنها، مشمول جنبه‌های گوناگونی است. اصل نوبت‌گیری و قطع گفتار یکی از جنبه‌های مهم مهارت‌های ارتباطی است که به رعایت بسیاری از ظرایف ارتباطی وابسته است. از آنجا که نحوۀ به‌کارگیری مهارت‌های ارتباطی، به‌ویژه اصول نوبت‌گیری و قطع گفتار، با اصل ادب و نزاکت اجتماعی رابطۀ مستقیم دارد، رعایت صحیح این اصول موجب ارتباط مؤثرتر و موفق‌تر مجریان با مخاطبان و درنهایت، اثربخشی مطلوب‌تر پیام خواهد شد. این مقاله، با تأکید بر بخش‌هایی از گفتگو که کلام منتقل یا گسسته می‌شود، صدوبیست دقیقه از گفتگوهای برنامه‌های تلویزیونی شبکه‌های1، 2، 3 و 4، شامل پانزده دقیقۀ آغازین از هشت برنامه (از هر شبکه دو برنامه)، را به‌روش توصیفی- تحلیلی بررسی کرده و مهارت‌های ارتباطی مجریان سیما را با تأکید بر عناصر کلامی در اصل نوبت‌گیری و قطع کلام مورد توجه قرار داده است. یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد عوامل بسیاری در امر نوبت‌گیری مجریان در گفتگوهای تلویزیونی مؤثر است که عبارت‌اند از: نبود هماهنگی در رعایت عناصر کلامی و غیرکلامی، تعارفات، کلمات جداکننده، پرسش‌های سرنخ‌گیر روشن‌کننده، ارائۀ اطلاعات، موضوع بحث، بازگردانی کلام، درخواست آمرانه و تردید در سخن.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مهارت ارتباطی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برنامه مجری‌محور تلویزیون</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوبت‌گیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قطع‌کلام</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عناصر کلامی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2253_eacf82e3bb2acbcd6858e07d289eead5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
