<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>11</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Vowel Harmony and Vowel-to-Vowel Coarticulation in Persian</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>الگوهای هماهنگی واکه‌ای و هم‌تولیدیِ واکه‌به‌واکه در زبان فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>69</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>86</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1548</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>گلناز</FirstName>
					<LastName>مدرسی قوامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Vowel harmony is a phonological process during which vowels acquire the feature(s) of nearby vowel(s). In the first part of the present article, patterns of Persian vowel harmony are discussed. The paper shows that vowel harmony occurs within morphemes and across morpheme boundary in this language and certain consonants are transparent, while others are opaque in different harmony patterns. It is further argued that when vowel harmony occurs within a morpheme, the target is in most cases [e,æ,o] and the trigger is [i,u,A], and when vowel harmony occurs across morpheme boundary, all the six vowels of Persian can be the trigger, whereas only [e] and [æ] are targets. In the second part of the article, patterns of Vowel-to-Vowel coarticulation in Persian are investigated. V-to-V coarticulation is a phonetic process during which vowels in a string of
segments affect one another, but the influences are too subtle for hearers to detect. V-to-V coarticulation can only be detected through instrumental investigation. The acoustic investigation of the laboratory speech of two adult male speakers of  Persian showed that in this language V-to-V coarticulation is sensitive to vowel quality, the voicing characteristics of the intervocalic consonant and its place of articulation. </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در هماهنگی واکه‌ای، واکه(‌ها) مشخصه(های) واکة مجاور را می‌پذیرند و به آن شبیه می‌شوند. در این مقاله، نشان داده‌ایم که این فرایند در فارسی، درون‌تکواژی و بین‌تکواژی است و برخی همخوان‌ها مانع از هماهنگی و برخی دیگر تسهیل‌کنندة آنند. در هماهنگیِ درون‌تکواژی، [i,u,ɑ] آغازگر و [e, o, a] هدفند. در هماهنگیِ بین‌تکواژی، هر شش واکه آغازگرند، ولی تنها  [e] و [a] هدفِ تغییرند. در ادامه، به پدیدة آواییِ هم‌تولیدیِ واکه‌به‌واکه پرداخته‌ایم که طی آن واکه‌ها بر یک‌دیگر تأثیر می‌گذارند، اما این تأثیرات را شنوندگانِ زبان نمی‌شنوند و تنها با بررسی‌های آکوستیکی قابل تشخیص‌اند. هم‌تولیدیِ واکه‌به‌واکه در گفتارِ آزمایشگاهیِ دو مردِ فارسی‌زبان، در توالی‌های بی‌معنای [C&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt;V&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;.C&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt;V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;]، که در آن‌ها C شامل شش همخوانِ انسدادیِ دهانی و V شامل شش واکة سادة فارسی بود، بر اساسِ تأثیرِ هر واکه بر سازة دومِ واکة دیگر در این توالی‌ها، اندازه‌گیری شد. نتایج  نشان داد که در فارسی، [i] کمترین و [e] و [a] بیشترین میزانِ تأثیرپذیری را دارند و واک‌داری/ بی‌واکی و جایگاهِ تولیدِ همخوانِ بین‌واکه‌ای، در میزانِ هم‌تولیدیِ واکه‌به‌واکه مؤثرند. این ملاحظات ارتباط تنگاتنگی را بین الگوهای واجی و آوایی در زبان فارسی نشان می‌دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هماهنگیِ واکه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هم‌تولیدیِ واکه‌به‌واکه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبانِ فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1548_f83ab32e54643be7776e2271b1db75ff.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
