<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The role of families in language maintenance (The case of Azerbaijani in Tabriz)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mirvahedi, Seyed Hadi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[انجمن زبان شناسی ایران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[language change]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[language maintenance. Azerbaijani. Tabriz]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Cultural and linguistic decline has today become one of the most important and unsettling issues in sociolinguistic studies. It is said that of 6000-7000 existent languages half will die out or become moribund by the end of this century. This decline is often due to language shift processes through which linguistic communities begin to learn one or more languages at the cost of losing their own first language. Against this background, this research uses a questionnaire and a focus group interview with mothers of children under ten to examine the role of family and its interaction with the wider ecology in transmitting Azerbaijani to the next generation in Tabriz. The findings suggest that although family members play a significant role in language maintenance, their linguistic attitudes, decisions and behavior are under the influence of the wider ecology outside the home. To ensure the maintenance of a language, it is thus suggested that besides daily use of a language at home, there needs to be a favorable ecology to reinforce and encourage positive linguistic attitudes and behavior towards that language.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2250_2387ec2ea1b9c0584226816b74d6d260.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[زبان و زبان‌شناسی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Text world Analysis of a Short Story: The Case Study of Farewell [Veda'] by Jalal e Al e Ahmad]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Afrashi, Azita]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[انجمن زبان شناسی ایران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[cognitive poetics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Text World Theory]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Discourse]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Text]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[short story]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[ 
This paper presents an analysis of a short story named farewell [veda'] from a cognitive poetic perspective. The analysis uses Text Worlds Theory as developed by Paul Werth (1999). Text Worlds are mental representations which spring from the discourse world . World - building elements denote the basic deictic arrangement of the text world and provide some sense of setting. What the text is actually about is composed of function- advancing propositions. Once the boundaries of the text world are established and the discourse is progressing, further conceptual layers may be created. These layers are known as sub worlds, which are of three types; deictic, attitudinal and epistemic sub worlds. The analysis of "Farewell" showed that although the extension of deictic and attitudinal sub worlds were limited, but the epistemic sub worlds extended considerably in this story, which resulted in remotedness and hypotheticality and deep layers of meaning within the text.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2251_876a91c40fcb8d41a08252a659bda9e0.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[زبان و زبان‌شناسی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The study of Persian exocentric compounding words]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Pourshahian, Bahar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Najafian, Arezoo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rowshan, Belgheis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sabzevari, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[انجمن زبان شناسی ایران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[compound words]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[exocentric]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[endocentric]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[metaphoric compound words]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[conversion compound words]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Compound words, their structures and meanings, are subject of recent linguistic studies. Compound words regarding  their meanings and head existence are divided into endocentric, exocentric, Dvandva  and reciprocal. Each of these groups can be divided into small groups. Endocentric words will become meaningful   in their contrast to exocentric words. On the contrary,  most exocentric compound words have metaphoric meanings, and  can be used as Persian equivalents for foreign scientific words in the process of word formation. This article  presents first a description of compound processes and then a description of exocentric compound process, and at last classifies the exocentric compound Persian words based on Bauer’s (2008) classification. It also attemepts  to show that Persian exocentric compound words have the same domain as Bauer’s classification. Application of this classification can be useful for word formation and also for teaching Persian to non- Persian speakers.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2252_282d12d3ffe5e4dc28b74d367b1f3696.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[زبان و زبان‌شناسی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[An analysis of turn-taking and interruptions as two strategies of communicative skills in IRIB TV talk]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Anizadeh, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghisian, Maryam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[انجمن زبان شناسی ایران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[communicative competence]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[presenter-oriented programs]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[turn taking]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[interruption]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[verbal principles]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Communication is comprised of verbal and non-verbal skills. Moreover, communication process has some components (e.g. sender, receiver, message, media, channel, noise, feedback, texture, etc.) which have the potentiality to be analyzed from different perspectives. Two principles of turn taking and interruption are among the important communicative competences that have integral connections with other competences. These two principles have close relationships with the principle of social politeness. The correct observation of these principles leads to a more effective and successful rapport between the presenters and audience. This article puts emphasis on interior design (decoration and furniture), and proximities, (territoriality, proximity, and orientation) in the context of the principles turn-taking and interruption . Considering this,  a hundred and twenty minutes of presenter-oriented programs on Iranian national television channels (channels One, Two, Three, and Four) were analyzed , focusing on the first fifteen minutes of eight programs (that is, two programs from each channel). This article employs descriptive-analytic approach to “circumscribe the current communicative competence of presenter-oriented programs in Iranian national television programs in comparison with an ideal condition”. The findings of this study showed that many factors affect turn-taking,  including failure to observe verbal and non-verbal principles, compliments, concluding phrases, clarification probes, information, adjacency pairs, apologies and their acceptance, subject matters, reflection, imperative demands and doubt]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2253_eacf82e3bb2acbcd6858e07d289eead5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[زبان و زبان‌شناسی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Other Mode: Sohrab Sepehri's cognitive manner]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Momeni, Fereshteh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[انجمن زبان شناسی ایران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[cognition]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[viewpoint]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[landmark]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[trajectory]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[perception]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In cognitive linguistics, viewpoint is a part of the process of producing meaning and a factor in different construing of the same subject. Different viewpoints  provide the viewer with particular perspectives to conceptualize the case, which according to cognitive grammar,  is represented in the grammar of the language. The many inconsistent reviews on Sohrab Sepehri's poetry show that his objective to lead the viewer to perceive the situation of the subject (from the subject’s viewpoint, not the viewer's) has not been realized. The aim of this paper is to introduce this apparently unknown viewpoint and to give a model of the processes of its formation in the construction of his language. The present paper argues that through foregrounding the case, switching from the perspective of the landmark to the perspective of the trajectory to suggest the situation of the case, he leads the reader to perceive the state of the subject, or "object's perception" as he expresses.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2254_8b2f048233adda2983033782861c2f6d.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[زبان و زبان‌شناسی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Talysh and  language attitudes]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mirzapoor, Fatemeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rezayati, Moharam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mosavi, Seyed Hashem]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[انجمن زبان شناسی ایران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[language attitudes]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[questionnaires]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[sociolinguistic]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[talysh]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[statistical test]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Language attitudes affect the  shift, survival, maintenance, death,  and life of a language. The study of language attitudes therefore deserves examination. The linguistic changes in Talysh community , and the language policies designed and performed for Talysh  have made the language a proper subject of investigation. The present study was designed to examine the attitudes of Talysh speakers.  The data were collected through questionnaires from 240 subjects. The subjects were high school students, 120  girls and 120 boys, from three regions of Talysh: south of Talysh (Masal city), north of Talysh (Keshly and Khotbehsara villages), center of Talysh (Talysh city and Khalehsara village).The results showed that in their attitudes towards Talysh language and culture, 70% of subjects have positive attitudes and 20% have neutral attitudes. In the attitudes towards other Talysh speakers, 42% prefer Talysh speakers, i.e. in watching television and in hospital situations more subjects favored the use of Talysh and 41% of subjects have neutral attitudes .In the attitudes towards literacy in Talysh , 36% of subjects have strongly positive attitudes and 34% have relatively positive attitudes. In the attitudes towards media programs, 63%have positive attitudes and 23%have neutral attitudes. As for media, television is the most favored , while the newspaper is the least favored . Radio ranked in between the two. As for linguistic attitude, there is  statistically significant  difference among Talysh regions and no statistically significant gender difference in the regions.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2255_668eb0cd951778ed9be4334b389989af.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[زبان و زبان‌شناسی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Stylistic Study of a Contemporary Persian Story from Halliday’s Functional Approach]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mostafavi, Pooneh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sanaati, Marzieh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[انجمن زبان شناسی ایران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[functional linguistics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[the Field of Discourse]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[the Tenor of Discourse]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[the Mode of Discourse]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Style]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[There are three metafunctions in systemic functional linguistics named, textual, experiential and interpersonal metafunctions. According to Halliday these metafunctions are considered as three different semantic levels in which clauses can be analyzed. One of this analysis results is stylistics. The purpose of the present article is to analyze a contemporary short story of Zoya Pirzad named “the opposite bench” according to the said metafunctions of systemic functional linguistics, to determine stylistic patterns of the said short story. It is necessary to note that there is not complete overlap between stylistic concept in literature on the one hand and linguistic or functional approach on the other. But they are relatively coincident in some general and basic cases. The short story which is analyzed clause by clause based on the said theory in this paper, consists of 233 clauses but because of paper size limitations, we just mentioned 19 clauses which are the most important ones. We conclude that in most clauses the chief character of the story (hero) is considered as the departure point and the story focuses on him and his affairs. Plenty usage of declarative modality and past tense clauses is the result of the story style which is narrative. Using positive clauses here sustains the validity of clause based on the writer’s opinion. The existence of modal adjuncts in clauses shows the writer’s confidence and approach. Meanwhile the number of material processes indicates the different events in the story.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2256_83acc4a058460043fd9ad1e81e8b43b2.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[زبان و زبان‌شناسی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Identity Construction: The Case of Young Women in Rasht.]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Safi, Hosein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[انجمن زبان شناسی ایران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Padideh Pakpour]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Identity Constructio]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rasht]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Padideh Pakpour (2015). Identity Construction: The Case of Young Women in Rasht. (Studia Iranica Upsaliensia, 1100-326X;  27), 225. Uppsala: Uppsala University Press.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2257_f8d3cea9647566daf04d225ecf54803b.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[زبان و زبان‌شناسی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Research Methods in Linguistics]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghandi, Saeedeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[انجمن زبان شناسی ایران]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lia Litosseliti]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Research Methods]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Lia Litosseliti (ed.) (2010). Research Methods in Linguistics. London: Continuum.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2258_333c3789e19a5fc7e5a236fead6361f3.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[زبان و زبان‌شناسی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>