<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Vol.11, No. 2, Seq. 22, Fall and Winter 2015-2016</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>22</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start></start>
					<end></end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2075_cfae47ee4491cb20cabbbab46843ec37.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Verb “xordan” from the Perspective of Cognitive Linguistics</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Akbar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hesabi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This paper focuses on a descriptive study of the verb “xordan” from the frame semantics view point. First synonyms of “xordan” were gathered and their differences were explained. Then using different sources such as Hamshahri corpus, some e-books, weblogs, documents and sentences -gathered from daily discussions, different occurrences of “xordan” were collected and studied based on frame semantics. The following questions were addressed in this study: What are the differences between the verbs referring to “taking something into the mouth” and “swallowing it”?; What are the different frames of “xordan”?; And can these frames be used for explaining the semantic aspects of compound verbs in Persian? Results of this study indicate that there are specific differences between synonyms of “xordan”. Occurrences of “xordan” reveal 31 frames for this verb which can be classified and hierarchically grouped. Using these frames, formation of some compound verbs is also explained.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>22</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>26</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2057_c5892958d210520b76ffd2490be39c50.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Phonological Processes of the Speech of 4-7 Year-old Hearing Impaired Children Using Hearing Aids in Mashhad</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Behzad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghonsooly</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Samaneh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ramezani-Aliteimour</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد آموزش زبان فارسی به غیر فارسی‌زبانان، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Hearing and speech are two important elements in establishing a natural and practical human communication. In early years of language learning, children take advantage of phonological processes to pronounce words more simply. The purpose of the present research is to review phonological processes used in the speech of hearing impaired children who use hearing aids. This descriptive-analytic research was conducted on 15 hearing impaired Persian speaking children of 4 to 7 years old who had no visual, physical, emotional, mental or psychological impairment. The Persian phonological test (PPT) was conducted on these monolingual Persian speaking children. PPT is a test to assess phonological understanding in which the linguistic data is collected by pronouncing the name of different pictures by examinees. The results of this study show that phonological processes used by these children are: lenition, deletion, insertion, assimilation, dissimilation, metathesis and compensatory lengthening. The processes of deletion and assimilation had high frequencies in the speech of these children.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>22</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>27</start>
					<end>48</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2058_4d10d4fd09d430c36db462082682f315.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Study of Syllable Structure in Sarhaddi Balochi Dialect of Granchin</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abbas Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ahangar</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Carina</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jahani</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه اوپسالا</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Golnaz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Modarresighavami</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fahimeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sagharichi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The study of syllable structure enjoys a specific significance in non-linear phonological studies. The present research, in the form of fieldwork, investigates the syllable structure in Sarhaddi Balochi dialect of Granchin based on the theory of CV phonology as a post-generative theory. It also examines the phonotactic distribution of consonants in initial and final clusters as well as the effect of the nucleus vowel of the syllable on the selection of dissimilar consonant clusters of the coda. The linguistic data has been extracted from the linguistic corpus collected in the Granchin district of Khash in Sistan and Baluchestan province. The data collection and compilation of the linguistic corpus were carried out based on the purposeful recording of speech through interviewing and recording free speech of consultants. The language consultants included 5 females and 5 males living in Granchin, who were illiterate and of different ages, between 60-80 years. The research findings show that the syllable structure of Sarhaddi Balochi Dialect of Granchin consists of one syllabic element, that is, nucleus which is preceded by maximally three consonants and followed by two consonants. In addition, the findings denote that phonotactic restrictions govern the distribution of consonants in initial and final clusters. Likewise, the type of the nucleus vowel of the syllable plays a role in selecting the cluster of the coda. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>22</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>49</start>
					<end>76</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2059_59b22b03341d389de4d9e67074704ccb.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Analyzing the Comprehension of Active and Passive Structures in Persian Autistic Children</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hourieh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ahadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Research In autism has not focused on linguistics, specially grammatical impairment in depth. However representing language profile is essential to recognition and treatment of autisitc children. Due to wide heterogeneity in autism, extensive investigations are required across different language groups. Passive structure is one of the most interesting structures among the developmental researchers. This paper aims to evaluate the comprehension of active and passive structures in Persian autistic children. For this purpose, comprehension of passive and active sentences in 10 autistic children of 6-10 years old was studied and compared to that of children -at similar age- with typical development. First children were presented with four pictures for each of the 13 sentences chosen for this study. Then, active and passive sentences were expressed conversationally and children were asked to choose a picture matching the sentence they heard and their answers were recorded. The Results showed that there was a significant difference between autistic and non-autistic children in comprehension of passive and reversal active sentences (P&lt;0.05), but there was no significant difference in comprehension of non-reversible active sentences (P&gt;0.05). There was no significant difference between the two groups in comprehension of structures active sentences (P&gt;0.05) but there was a significant difference in comprehension of passive sentence (P&lt;0.05). Since autistic children have significant problem in comprehension of passive sentences, the comprehension of passive sentences must be noticed in the recognition and treatment of these children.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>22</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>77</start>
					<end>100</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2060_908b23be0cf24e3160a46a014a1708aa.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Recognition of Some Iranian Dialect Words through Goddess Kali</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Leila</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Asgari</namePart>
				<affiliation>فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Names and words are essentially symbolic entities. They first originated in a time when myth and language were not yet detached. However, as time went by, the connection between names (words) and their referents started to fade away, leaving many words in language completely detached from their mythical origins. Most language symbols have thus largely lost their symbolic characteristics, if not fully. This study takes into account the common origin of myth and language and uses a mythological approach to examine name and word as symbols. The theoretical framework of the study is drawn from Cassirer’s theory on the primitive man’s way of thinking, which he terms the mythical thought. A comparative study between words in Iranian dialects and Indo-European words revealed that a range of objects and natural phenomena with distinct meaning but comparable forms were all associated by the people to Goddess Kālī, and thus were named after her.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>22</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>101</start>
					<end>116</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2061_57fe937c2c31ed01af02826ab97b92fc.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>When Tradition Meets Modernity: Five Life Stories from the Galesh Community in Ziarat, Golestan, Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Amerian</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبان‌شناسی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>22</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>119</start>
					<end>130</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2062_8454f7b73fe9a3fb84f3f87c63c8d321.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>