<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>19</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Comparison of Speech Acts in Young Men’s and Women’s Persian SMSs Based on Searl’s Classification</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مقایسۀ کنش‌های گفتار در پیامک‌های فارسیِ زنان و مردانِ جوان بر اساس طبقه‌بندیِ سرل</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>75</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>88</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1762</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی معصوم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>خاوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبان و ادبیات فارسی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>As one of the most recent and most frequently used communication media, SMS is rapidly penetrating the media culture of different communities. A linguistic/pragmatic analysis of the messages can reveal the hidden aspects of the cultural identity of different sectors of the society. Based on Searl’s classification of speech acts, the present study analyzed the speech acts in 400 Persian messages exchanged among two equal groups of men and women aging 17 to 27. The results indicated that although the order of speech act frequencies were similar in men and women, the usage rate of expressive, representative and commissive acts was higher in men than in women. In return, men used the directive act more than women did. The significance of the findings lies in the fact that a higher usage of expressive and commissive acts in women can illustrate their value-oriented and ethics-centered approach in formal interactions through SMS. Moreover, a high frequency of commissive acts in men’s SMSs can be a sign of pragmatism in their daily engagements. Due to the contextual features of the research data, declarative acts were not observed in the messages.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پیامک، به‌عنوان یکی از جدیدترین و در عین حال پرکاربردترین ابزارهای ارتباطیِ امروز، به‌سرعت در حال نفوذ در فرهنگ رسانه‌ایِ جوامع مختلف است و تحلیلِ متنِ پیامک‌ها، از دیدگاه‌های زبانی و کاربردشناختی، می‌تواند برخی زوایای پنهانِ هویت فرهنگیِ گروه‌های مختلف را برای پژوهشگران آشکار سازد. مقالۀ‌ حاضر به تحلیل کنش‌‌های گفتار، بر اساس دسته‌بندیِ سرل، در 400 پیامک فارسی در دو گروه مساوی از دانشجویانِ زن و مرد بین سنین 17 تا 27 سال می‌پردازد. نتایج نشان داد که هرچند ترتیبِ فراوانیِ انواع کنش‌های گفتار در هر دو گروه تقریباً مشابه است، میزان کاربرد کنش‌های گفتاری عاطفی، اظهاری و تعهدی در زنان بیشتر از مردان بوده است. در مقابل، مردان نیز از کنش ترغیبی بیشتر از زنان استفاده کرده‌اند. اهمیتِ یافته‌ها از این لحاظ است که کاربرد بالاترِ کنش‌های عاطفی و تعهدی در زنان می‌تواند حاکی از نگرش ارزش‌مدار و اخلاق‌محور ایشان در تعاملاتِ رسمیِ اجتماعی، از طریق ابزارهای رسانه‌ای، نظیر پیامک، باشد. همچنین بسامد بالای کنش ترغیبی در پیامک‌های مردان می‌تواند نشانگر نوعی عمل‌گرایی و تبادل خواسته‌ها و توصیه‌ها و اوامر و نواهیِ مبتنی بر نیازهای کاریِ روزمره قلمداد شود. به دلیل ویژگی‌های بافتیِ داده‌های تحقیق، کنش اعلامی در پیامک‌ها مشاهده نشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کنش گفتاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیامک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مردان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشجویان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1762_bd58395dc932a83f9a12ad82856cb325.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
