<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>19</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Fictive Motion in Persian: A cognitive approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>حرکتِ ‌پنداری در زبان فارسی: رویکردِ شناختی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>23</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>36</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1759</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>مسگرخویی</LastName>
<Affiliation>فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Motion is a fundamental human experience and mankind, through motion simulation in mind, extends it to the other areas in which there is no movement. This simulation and extension is also reflected in  language and language users apply the elements of real motion to describe abstract motion. This paper focuses on a specific type of abstract motion, called fictive motion, from the point of view of cognitive semantics. Fictive motion refers to situations in which the state of a static entity, located in a fixed position, is described by a motion verb. In the present paper, fictive motions in Persian are examined, analyzed and explained. To this end,  a corpus of 1750 sentences was established based on the criteria defined for fictive motion components by cognitive researchers. From among them, 42 sentences which are structured in fictive motion were analyzed. The results revealed that the occurrences of the various components of fictive motion construction like Trajector and motion verb follow semantic and stylistic restrictions in Persian. Thus Persian speakers often use Trajectors with a horizontal length and motion verbs that often lexicalize path of motion</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">حرکت یکی از بنیادی‌ترین تجربه‌های بشر است و انسان با شبیه‌سازیِ حرکت در ذهن، آن را به حوزه‌های دیگری، که به‌واقع هیچ‌گونه حرکتی در آنها وجود ندارد، تسری می‌دهد. این شبیه‌سازی و تعمیم در زبان نیز منعکس می‌شود و کاربرانِ زبان، عناصر و اجزای حرکتِ حقیقی را برای توصیف حرکتِ مجازی نیز به‌کار می‌برند. این مقاله بر نوع خاصی از حرکتِ مجازی، با عنوانِ حرکتِ ‌پنداری، متمرکز است. حرکتِ ‌پنداری به موقعیت‌هایی اطلاق می‌شود که در آنها وضعیت یک موجودیتِ ایستا، و به‌ لحاظ مکانی ثابت، با فعل حرکتی توصیف می‌شود. هدف این مقاله، بررسی و تحلیل حرکت‌ِ پنداری بر پایة دادههای زبان فارسی است. برای این منظور پیکره‌ای متشکل از 1750 جمله را بر اساس معیارهایی که برای اجزای حرکتِ ‌پنداری، از سوی پژوهشگرانِ شناختی، تعریف شده است، گردآوری و از بین آنها 42 جمله را، که ساختِ حرکت‌ِ پنداری دارند، بررسی و تحلیل کردیم. نتایج بررسی‌‌ها نشان می‌دهد که در زبان فارسی رخدادِ اجزای مختلفِ ساختِ حرکتِ ‌پنداری، مانند پیکرنما و فعل حرکتی، تابع محدودیت‌های معنایی و سبکی است. به این ترتیب که در فارسی اغلب از پیکرنماهایی که طول افقی دارند استفاده می‌شود. فعل‌های حرکتیِ به‌کاررفته در این ساخت‌ها نیز از نوع فعل‌هایی هستند که مسیر حرکت را واژگانی‌ می‌کنند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شبیه‌سازیِ ذهنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حرکت‌پنداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فعل حرکتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیکرنما</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زمینه‌نما</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1759_129ef6afd04b369ee393aa435f842db7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
