<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>7</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2008</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Truncated Compound Agentive Adjective: Yes or No?</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>صفتِ فاعلیِ مرکبِ مرخم: آری یا خیر؟</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>64</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>80</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1637</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>خرمایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه کردستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>There exists, in the Persian language, a highly productive compounding pattern, in which a verbal element combines with a non-verbal one to produce a noun or adjective. Three distinct views can be identified regarding this pattern. Some scholars, mostly traditional grammarians, call the output &quot;truncated compound agentive adjective&quot;. Some others accept this, but offer a modern linguistic interpretation. Still, others reject the idea of a truncated compound agentive adjective and hold a different view. Based on different pieces of evidence, the present paper, totally rejects the traditional idea and argues that, in this pattern, a verbal element (present root) simply relates to a non-verbal one through compounding. The type of relation, and hence the meaning of the compound are determined by Persian speakers on the basis of pragmatic implicature.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در زبان فارسی و در حیطة ترکیب به عنوان یکی از دو حوزة واژه‌سازی، فرایند بسیار زایایی وجود دارد که طی آن عنصری غیرفعلی (اسم، ضمیر مشترک، صفت، قید) قبل از ستاک حال فعل (مثلاً ‌آموز و بین) قرار می‌گیرد و ماحصل آن اسم یا صفت جدیدی (دانش‌آموز، خودبین) است. در مورد این فرایند سه دیدگاه وجود دارد: برخی که عموماً دستور‌نویسان سنتی هستند، آن را صفتِ فاعلیِ مرکبِ مرخم می‌دانند. پاره‌ای استنباط دستور‌نویسان سنتی را صحیح قلمداد می‌کنند؛ اما تعبیری زبان‌شناسانه و نو بر آن سوار می‌کنند. بعضی نیز به کلی با دیدگاه دستورنویسان سنتی مخالف‌اند و دیدگاه خاص خود را عرضه می‌کنند. در مقالة حاضر نیز، با اتکا بر دلایل مختلف، ایدة سنتیِ صفتِ فاعلیِ مرکبِ مرخم به کلی مردود شمرده می‌شود و استدلال می‌شود که در فرایند مذکور صرفاً میان یک عنصر غیرفعلی و یک عنصر فعلی (ستاک حال) پیوند بر‌قرار می‌شود و نوع پیوند این دو و در نتیجه، معنای ترکیب بر اساس تلویحِ کاربردشناختیِ فارسی‌زبانان مشخص می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترکیب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صفت فاعلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترخیم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ستاک حال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصریح</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تلویحِ کاربردشناختی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1637_3f9aaaaea9324be8505c578e4a1e0977.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
