<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Cooptation in Discourse Grammar: A Reconciliation Process
between Sentence Grammar and Thetical Grammar</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sleiman</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghaderi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Amouzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Discourse Grammar treats two separate but interrelated domains for discourse processing: Sentence Grammar (SG) and Thetical Grammar (TG). The former deals with the structure and meaning of sentences while the latter deals with the organization of discourse at the level beyond the sentence as well as the relationship between linguistic materials and the contextual situation of discourse. Cooptation as a cognitive process mediates between these two domains of language use. It encompasses linguistic elements such as a clause, phrase, word or other chunks of a text located in Sentence Grammar domain are transferred to the domain of TG providing a tool for coding components of the situation of discourse for which SG seems unable to facilitate the discourse function required. The present study investigates the process of cooptation and some unknown issues related to it. Moreover, it divides coopted units according to their structures of instantaneous, constructional and formulaic types. As far as their placement is concerned, coopted units can anchor either in their host utterance or in their context in four ways. In addition, certain motivations including mental processing, economy and iconicity are required in order to cooptation being operationalized. These motivations interact and compete with each other to organize the discourse in an appropriate way.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>13</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>26</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>18</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3199_17693fafbaa833eaebcbd1ef39aad9be.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Consonantal Compensatory Lengthening in Persian</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fahimeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khodaverdi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Golnaz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Modarresighavami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This article presents a moraic description of the relation between two prosodic features in Persian: segmental lengthening and syllable weight. The data contains imperative forms in which the initial consonant of verbal stems may undergo compensatory lengthening following the diachronically shortened vowel of the imperative prefixes. The result of analyzing the data in Moraic Theory provides us with  more evidence in support of the idea that vowel or consonant lengthening has no phonemic value and makes no semantic distinction (considering minimal pairs) in modern Persian, however it causes differences in the quantity of syllable weight. In the framework of Moraic Phonology, the distinction among light, heavy and super-heavy syllables is represented by the number of moras assigned to the syllable segments and weight sensitive phonological processes like compensatory lengthening of vowels and consonants apply in order to keep the number of moras unchanged and set the syllable weight fixed.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>13</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>26</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>19</start>
					<end>40</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3200_1ce2e5c2df7e8968ea85214a4f06b517.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Psychological Evidence for Subject Position in Persian: A Minimalist Syntax</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Dabir-Moghaddam</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shahla</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Raghibdoust</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد دانشگاه و معاون پژوهشی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghasemi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجو دکترای زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In response to this question whether subject stays in its thematic position within VP or moves to Spec, TP, theoretical debates and given language evidence do not provide sufficient information to determine the derived subject position in Persian sentences’ structure. In this regard, although Persian is a free word order language, the findings of this study show that the displacement of sentence elements in this language is distinguished as a change in the original sentence sequence by Persian speakers, and the change affects their processing time. In addition, considering two different perspectives on the subject&#039;s position in Persian and using the psychological evidence, in line with Darzi and Marzban (2014) and Anoshe (2010), we prove that in passive, transitive, and intransitive sentences’ structure in Persian, subject first merges in its thematic position within VP and then moves to Spec, TP.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>13</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>26</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>41</start>
					<end>68</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3201_53b38e282e417c4ef78d11add6df74ab.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Correlation between Conceptual Metaphors and Etymological Patterns of Emotion Concepts with a Cognitive Semantics Approach</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Azita</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Afrashi</namePart>
				<affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This paper suggests the hypothesis that emotion concepts which show similarity in their metaphorical mappings also reveal etymological interrelations across languages. In order to test this hypothesis, the Persian Linguistic Database was searched with keywords of two lexical fields of anger and fear. Thus 899 metaphorical expressions for anger and 600 ones for fear were found. By comparing the names of the mappings of anger and fear metaphors, we found out that these emotion concepts share 17 similar names of the mappings. The etymological data gathered from more than 25 languages for these fields also confirmed etymological and lexical interrelations. Hence, it can be concluded that there are correlations between conceptual metaphors and etymological and lexical patterns of fear and anger. The results of this research may not be limited to these two emotion concepts; it is suggested that such correlations between metaphorical mappings and etymological and lexical patterns can be found between other emotion concepts.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>13</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>26</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>69</start>
					<end>88</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3202_f94fafb1bfd42ed0a2748208875a88a2.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Comparative Study of English Equivalents in Persian: Case Study of Approved Terms by the Third Academy from Viewpoint of Standardization</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">akram</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">dehghanzade</namePart>
				<affiliation>null</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammadreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ahmadkhani</namePart>
				<affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">maryamsadat</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">ghiyasian</namePart>
				<affiliation>null</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Samayi</namePart>
				<affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم و فناوری اطلاعات ( ایرانداک )</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Standardization is one of the main processes in promoting a language&#039;s position. The Academy of Persian Language and Literature as a language planning institution can standardize its new scientific, technical and specialized terms in different fields in order to enable experts of scientific fields use their native language for exchanging information and technical knowledge. This research is theoretical within the framework of Infoterm and it is exploratory with content analysis methodology which is done in two parts. In first part of the research, the approved terms of Academy of Persian Language and Literature, from first to thirteenth pamphlets (1376-1395), are studied from the viewpoint of standardization. The study of the total of approved terms revealed: 1- about 18% of them are referred to each other, 2- about 4% of them are polysemic, and 3- about 2% of them have more than one lexical entry with different equivalents. In the second part of the research, the activities of the Academy of Persian Language and Literature in relation to the standardization of specialized dictionaries in scientific fields are studied. The primary data include more than 100 words from specialized English–Persian dictionaries in 25 scientific fields. The study showed disorders and multiplicity of terms and concepts in the specialized dictionaries; therefore, the standardization of these dictionaries can be considered as a priority for the Academy of Persian Language and Literature.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>13</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>26</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>89</start>
					<end>116</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3203_931950803fe1bf87c4d535d9fb992675.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Redefining the Concepts of Dependent and Independent Clauses According to a Functional Approach</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Azadeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mirzaei</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The subject and object complement clauses, according to review literature on these two concepts, always are considered as dependent clauses and the verbs which are accompanied with these two clauses are introduced as main verbs. In this study, the concepts of dependent and independent complement clauses according to a semantic approach, in particular within the framework of the experiential metafunction in Systemic Functional Grammar, are redefined. With this view and based on the propositional content of the message, the clauses known as the dependent clauses actually contain the original content of the message in the sentence and the clauses known as the independent clauses define only the event structure of the verb of the sentence. The independent clauses which are responsible for representing the concept of mood can also appear in the form of an adverb, prepositional phrase and modal verbs instead of clausal format. Thus, the so-called dependent clauses, based on the propositional content of massage are the main part of the sentences and their verbs are dependent on the so-called independent clauses just because of the grammatical features. Instead, the so-called independent clauses are semantically dependent on the other clause in the sentence. In this research the yes/no question test was used to determine the main clause in compound sentences.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>13</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>26</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>117</start>
					<end>132</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3204_b700e7c510a392037bbc5e71ecf6f66e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Analysis of linguistic features of swindler
Case study of Semnan Province</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Razavian</namePart>
				<affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی گروه زبان‌شناسی - دانشگاه سمنان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jalili</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه سمنان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This study is conducted in a descriptive and analytical way to explain the features of swindlers&#039; spoken language from the view point of forensic linguistics. Fraud is a language crime in which, language plays a main role in forming it. The authors are trying to analyze the speech of two people accused of fraud from the first stages of investigation, to interrogation and court hearing in Semnan province judicial system. The results indicate that background knowledge and language politeness are the main and fixed speech features for this group of offenders. Survey data also indicate that these people also use the principles of friendly performance, giving false hope, appropriate behavior with speech, justification principle, indirect threat, different ways of persuasion, considering religious context, foregrounding and backgrounding principles and other similar techniques appropriate to the context and situation.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>13</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>26</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>133</start>
					<end>163</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3205_653389386067f1b4df76cae93d55da5b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Cognitive English Grammar</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Leila</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sharifi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Radden G. &amp; Dirven R.,(2007).Cognitive English Grammar. V2, Cognitive Linguistics in Practice Series. Amsterdam and Philadelphia: John Benjamins</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>13</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>26</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>167</start>
					<end>172</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3206_ff12a7cea688e954e1834fa4c2aea74d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>No English Title</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammadreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">rashed Mohasel</namePart>
				<affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مزالعات فرهنگی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>No English Abstrat</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>13</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>26</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>157</start>
					<end>160</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3207_5b1f559df88835af0952a4a749b43919.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>