<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>24</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>30</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Sasanian Pahlavi Inscriptions in Kanheri Caves in India</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کتیبه‌های پهلوی ساسانی در غار کانهری در هند</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>107</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>138</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2472</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیروس</FirstName>
					<LastName>نصراله‌زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present article focuses on 6 private and monumental inscriptions in the Sasanian Pahlavi script and language in India. The Buddhist Kanheri Caves have been located at the suburbs of Mumbai. There exist six inscriptions in cursive Pahlavi script that date back to the 11th century A.D. (1009-1021 A.D.). These inscriptions have been written down by a number of Zoroastrian merchants who travelled to India and visited the caves. They are the earliest evidence proving the presence of Zoroastrian merchants in India. The earliest inscription belongs to 378 Yazdgirdi (1009 A.D.) and the second one belongs to the same year but has been written 45 days after the first one. Both inscriptions bear the same names. The third inscription dates back to 390 Yazdgirdi (1021 A.D.) bearing different names and the fourth one also belongs to 390 Yazdgirdi (1021 A.D.) and bears the name of a visitor. The fifth inscription is illegible and the last one bears the proper name “Ābān Āzargušnasb son of Farrox. It has been mentioned in the third inscription that the Zoroastrians (&lt;em&gt;Behdīnān&lt;/em&gt;) have came from Iran. </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقالۀ حاضر دربارۀ کتیبه‌های خصوصی و یادبودی به خط و زبان پهلویِ ساسانی در هند است. در غارهای بوداییِ کانهری در سالسِت نزدیکِ بمبئی( مومبای)، 6 کتیبه به خط متصل پهلوی  وجود دارد که مربوط به قرن 11 میلادی( 1009 تا 1021) است. این کتیبه‌ها را چند گروه از تاجران زردشتی در سفر به هند نوشته‌اند که از این غارها دیدن کرده‌اند و گواه قدیمی‌ترین حضور زردشتیان تاجر در هند است. کتیبۀ نخست تاریخِ سال 378 یزدگردی (1009م.) و کتیبۀ دوم تاریخ 378 یزدگردی، 45 روز پس از کتیبۀ نخست، دارد و نام‌های آمده در هر دو کتیبه مشابه هستند. کتیبۀ سوم با نام‌های متفاوت و به‌تاریخِ 390 یزدگردی (1021م.) و کتیبۀ چهارم به‌سال 390 یزدگردی و نام یک بازدیدکننده از غار است. کتیبۀ پنجم ناخواناست و کتیبۀ ششم نام خاص آبان‌گشنسب پسر فرخ را دارد. در کتیبۀ سوم آمده است که بهدینان از ایران آمده‌اند. بهترین پژوهش بر این کتیبه‌ها را وست (1888) انجام داده است. برخی محققان همچون چرتی و دیگران (2002)؛ چرتی (2007)، ژینیو (1995 برای کتیبه ششم) و از محققان ایرانی مرحوم پورداوود (بر اساس ترجمه وست 1394) به این کتیبه‌ها پرداخته‌است. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کتیبه‌های خصوصی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خط پهلوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زردشتیان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هند</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">غار کانهری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایران اسلامی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2472_714b2e9a8adc56d53c90fbc2774d0c7e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
