<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>22</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Recognition of Some Iranian Dialect Words through Goddess Kali</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بازشناخت پیوند چند واژه از گویش‌های ایرانی با کالی ایزدبانوی بزرگ</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>101</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>116</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2061</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>عسگری</LastName>
<Affiliation>فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Names and words are essentially symbolic entities. They first originated in a time when myth and language were not yet detached. However, as time went by, the connection between names (words) and their referents started to fade away, leaving many words in language completely detached from their mythical origins. Most language symbols have thus largely lost their symbolic characteristics, if not fully. This study takes into account the common origin of myth and language and uses a mythological approach to examine name and word as symbols. The theoretical framework of the study is drawn from Cassirer’s theory on the primitive man’s way of thinking, which he terms the mythical thought. A comparative study between words in Iranian dialects and Indo-European words revealed that a range of objects and natural phenomena with distinct meaning but comparable forms were all associated by the people to Goddess &lt;em&gt;Kālī&lt;/em&gt;, and thus were named after her.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">نام و کلام اصالتاً سرشتی نمادین دارند و زمانی پدید آمده‌اند که پیوند اسطوره و زبان هنوز گسسته نشده بود. با گذشت زمان، پیوند نام و موضوعِ نام‌گذاری سست و بسیاری از نام‌ها از خاستگاه‌های اسطوره‌ایِ آغازین خود رها شده‌اند و این نشانه‌ها، در طی تحول و تکامل، سرشت و خصیصة نمادین خود را، اگرچه نه به‌تمامی، ازدست داده‏اند. در این پژوهش، با توجه به همسان‌بودنِ خاستگاهِ اسطوره و زبان، نام و کلام، به‌مثابۀ نماد، با رویکردِ اسطوره‌شناسی بررسی خواهند شد. چارچوب نظریِ این تحقیق، نظریة کاسیرر دربارة شیوة اندیشة اقوام ابتدایی است که او برای آن اصطلاحِ اندیشة اسطوره‌ای را برگزیده است. مطالعة تطبیقیِ شماری از واژه‌های گویش‌های ایرانی با واژه‌های هندواروپایی، که با توجه به این نظریه بررسی شده بودند، نشان داد که بسیاری از پدیده‌های طبیعی و اشیا با مفاهیمِ متفاوت و صورت‌های آواییِ مشابه، که در ذهن این اقوام برخاسته از باور به ایزدبانوی بزرگ کالی بوده، به‌نام او نام‌گذاری شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گویش‌های ایرانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایزدبانو کالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">واژه‌های هندواروپایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اسطوره</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2061_57fe937c2c31ed01af02826ab97b92fc.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
