<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>14</Volume>
				<Issue>27</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Phonological development in 3-5 year-old Kurdish-speaking Children with Middle Kurmanji- Mukryani Dialect</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رشد واجی درکودکان 3تا 5 سالة‌ کُردزبان با گویش کرمانجی- میانی مکریانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>73</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>86</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">3866</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شهلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>فاطمی سیادر</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد گفتار درمانی، دانشگاه علوم بهزیستی و توانبخشی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طلیعه</FirstName>
					<LastName>ظریفیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علوم بهزیستی و توانبخشی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اکبر</FirstName>
					<LastName>بیگلریان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علوم بهزیستی و توانبخشی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>صدیق زاهدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه فرهنگیان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study reports phonological development in Kurdish speaking children with Middle Kurmanji-Mukryani dialect. Speech samples of 120 children, aged between 3 and 5 years, were randomly collected from nurseries and preschools in Bukan city, western Azerbaijan, and later analyzed. The age of acquisition of 29 Kurdish language consonant in three positions (initial, medial and final) were evaluated by using the speech test. The results revealed that Kurdish-speaking children acquired all consonants in three positions between age 4 and 6, except the consonants / ʒ, z, g, ɣ, ʤ /. The consonants in the initial position were pronounced more correctly than those in the medial and final position. The development concerning Kurdish consonants increased gradually from age 3 to 5. The subjects showed more accuracy in nasals, liquids, laterals, and stops than in fricatives, affricatives, and trill. The findings of this study provide the basis for normal phonology development which can be useful to Kurdish speaking speech-language pathologists in the assessment and treatment of children with disorder.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این پژوهش، رشد واجی کودکان کُردزبان با لهجۀ کرمانجی میانی– مکریانی را گزارش می‌دهد. نمونه‌های گفتاری 120 کودکِ 3 تا 5 سالۀ کُردزبان که به‌طورِ تصادفی از مراکز بهداشت و مهدکودک‌های شهرستان بوکان، آذربایجان غربی، انتخاب شده بودند، جمع‌آوری شد و مورد تحلیل قرار گرفت. سن اکتساب 29 همخوان زبان کُردی در سه موقعیت اول، وسط و آخر با استفاده از آزمون تصویری تولید، ارزیابی شد. نتایج نشان داد که کودکان کُردزبان تا سن چهارونیم‌سالگی همۀ همخوان‌ها را به‌استثنای{ʒ , z, g, ɣ, ʤ}در هر سه موقعیت اول، وسط و آخر کسب می‌کنند. همخوان‌ها در موقعیت آغازین درست‌تر از همخوان‌ها در موقعیت میانی و انتهایی تلفظ می‌شوند. رشد همخوان‌های زبان کُردی از 3 تا 5 سالگی تدریجاً افزایش می‌یابد. کودکان درستی بیشتری در تلفظ همخوان‌های خیشومی، روان و انسدادی نسبت به همخوان‌های سایشی، لرزشی و انسایشی دارند. نتایج این مطالعه پایه‌ای را براساس رشد واج‌شناسی طبیعی برای آسیب شناسان گفتار و زبان کُردی جهت ارزیابی و درمان کودکان دارای اختلال، فراهم می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رشد واجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سن اکتساب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان کُردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کودکان کُردزبان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3866_4b048c34d276b28571a2e475e7a0cc7e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
