<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>13</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A  Phonological Study of Metathesis in Persian</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل فرایند واجی قلب در زبان فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>129</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>146</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1467</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اعظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>استاجی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present paper studies the phonological process of metathesis in Persian. Metathesis is usually considered an irregular, sporadic and marginal process in some languages, but regular and rule governed in some others. It seems that metathesis can be regular when serving a &quot;specific structural purpose&quot;. This structural purpose may be of a phonological nature. The analysis of metathesis in Persian shows that it used to be regular in Middle Persian and resulted in phonologically well-formed words.  But in Modern Persian data, analyzed here, metathesis was found to be not regular. There are of course instances of metathesis that have resulted in phonologically well-formed structures, but there are, at the same time, some other instances of metathesis which have resulted in phonologically ill-formed combinations. It must be mentioned that in the data analyzed here, metathesis leading to phonological well-formed structures showed greater frequency.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقالۀ حاضر به بررسی فرایند قلب در زبان فارسی می‌پردازد. معمولاً قلب فرایندی نظام‌مند تلقی نمی‌شود و درمیان انواع فرایندهای واجی به‌صورت فرایندیی و فرعی درنظر گرفته می‌شود. بااین‌حال، در برخی از زبان‌ها فرایندی منظم و قاعده‌مند است. به‌نظر می‌رسد فرایند قلب اگر &quot;هدف ساختاری خاصی&quot; را تأمیی‌تواند منظم باشد. این هدفِ ساختارییتی عام و واجی داشته باشد. تحلیلِ آن در زبان فارسی نشان می‌دهد که این فرایند در فارسی ‌میانه، پس‌‌های پایانیِ واژه‌ها در غالب موارد به‌طورییر توالی واج‌ها، آن‌ها را تابع اصل توالیِ رسایی یا توزیعِ رسایی می‌که ناظر بر نوعی خوش‌ساختی واجی است&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; اما درمورد داده‌های مورد تحلیل در ایی امروز مربوط می‌شوند، نمی‌توان از نظم آن سخن گفت. زیرا درحالی‌ی، برون‌دادِ فرایند قلب با اصل توالیِ رسایی یا توزیعِ رسایی مطابقت داشته است، در موارد دیگر توالیِ واج‌هایییِ رسایی یا اصل توزیعِ رسایی بوده‌یییشتر از موارد تابع حالت دوم بوده‌اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرایند واجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قلب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اصل توالیِ رسایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اصل توزیعِ رسایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1467_88f4c7e96a128ad15d9d4cff9a460026.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
