<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1393</YEAR>
<VOL>10</VOL>
<NO>20</NO>
<MOSALSAL>20</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>128</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>وزن و قافیه، دو معیار برای تعیین قدمت اشعار شفاهی: مطالعۀ موردی در وزن و قافیۀ کلامات یارسان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Meter and Rhyme as Two Criteria for Archaism of Aral Poetries: A Case Study of Meter and Rhyme in Yarsan Kalams</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>کلامات، نام سروده‌های مذهبی یارسان به زبان گورانی است که در زمرۀ سروده‌های شفاهی ایرانی قرار می‌گیرد. در این مقاله قصد داریم با بررسی تعدادی از کلامات یارسان، تنوع وزن و قافیه را در این متون بررسی کنیم. به این منظور به بررسی چند متن، که اطلاع درستی از تاریخ نگارش آنها در دست نیست، می‌پردازیم و با بررسی شیوۀ تثبیت وزن و قافیه در این اشعار، قدمت آنها را نسبت به هم تعیین می‌کنیم. تنوع وزن و قافیه در کلامات یارسان مبنایی روش‌شناختی در اختیار ما قرار می‌دهد، که براساس آن می‌توان نشان داد که متون قدیم‌تر تنوع وزن و قافیۀ بیشتر، و متون جدیدتر وضعیت تثبیت‌شده‌تری دارند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Kalams are the religious poetries of Yarsan people in Gorani. They are considered as a subset of Iranian oral poetries. In this paper we aim to investigate diversity of meter and rhyme in a number of Kalams of Yarsan. Thus by investigating some texts, for which there is not enough information of their history, we try to investigate diversity of meter and rhyme in these texts and by investigating the fixation of meter and rhyme in these kalams, determine their antiquity. Diversity of meter and rhyme gives us a methodological criterion according to which one can suggest older texts have more diversity in meter and in rhyme but more recent texts have more fixed status.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>16</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مسعود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی‌راد</Family>
						<NameE>Masud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>MohammadiRad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rad.masud@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>اُمید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>طبیب‌زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Omid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tababzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>otabibzadeh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلامات یارسان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گورانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>وزن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قافیه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>حسینی، سید محمد (1382). دیوانَ گَورَه. کرمانشاه: انتشارات باغ نی.##صفی‌زاده،صدیق (1361). دورۀ هفتوانه. تهران: هیرمند.##طاهراحمد، اَمر (1390). &quot;وزن شعر عامیانۀ کردی و جایگاه آن در ادبیات نوشتاری در مقایسه با وزن شعر عامیانۀ فارسی&quot;. وزن شعر فارسی از دیروز تا امروز (مجموعه سخنرانی‌های نخستین هم‌اندیشی وزن شعر فارسی و اشعار ایرانی در انجمن زبان‌شناسی ایران). به کوشش امید طبیب‌زاده. تهران: نشر آثار فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی. 242- 223.##طبیب زاده، امید (1391). &quot;مقایسۀ وزن در اقوال ایزدی‌ها با کلامات یارسان در پرتو برخی سروده‌های ایرانیِ غربی&quot;. ادب پژوهی. ش20، 74- 53.##طبیب زاده، امید (1393). &quot;مقایسۀ قافیه در اقوال ایزدی‌ها با کلامات یارسان (اهل حق)، در پرتو برخی سروده‌های ایرانی غربی&quot;. مجموعه مقالات جشن‌نامۀ دکتر احمد سمیعی. تهران: انتشارات هرمس، 350- 324.##نقشبندی، زانیار (1392). &quot;وزن شعر اشعار عامیانۀ هورامی&quot;. مجموعه‌مقالات دومین هم‌اندیشی وزن شعر. به کوشش امید طبیب‌زاده. تهران: هرمس.##Halm, H. (1982). Ahl-e Haqq. Encyclopædia Iranica. Retrieved from: http://www.iranicaonline.org/articles/ahl-e-haqq-people (accessed January 02, 2016).## Kreyenbroek, P. G. (1995). &quot;Yezidism- Background, Observances and Textual Tradition&quot;. Texts and Studies in Religion, Vol. 62. New York: The Edwin Mellen Press, Lewiston.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی دامنۀ نفوذ، گسترش و دگرگونیِ معناییِ واژه‌های فارسیِ شطرنج در زبان انگلیسی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Study of Range of Penetration and Spread of the Persian Words in Chess and Their Semantic Changes in English</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>نفوذ و گسترش شایان توجه واژه‌های زبان فارسی، در ادوار مختلف، در زبان‌های گوناگون، از جمله موضوعات قابل‌ توجه در حوزۀ ریشه‌شناسی و مطالعات تاریخی است. از جمله زبان‌هایی که در طول تاریخ، به طور غیرمستقیم، وام گیرندۀ واژه‌هایی از زبان فارسی بوده‌اند، می‌توان به زبان‌های اروپایی، و از آن جمله انگلیسی، اشاره کرد. بررسی این دسته از واژه‌ها خود ارائه‌کنندۀ تصویری گویا از فرهنگ، تمدن و رویدادهای اجتماعی و تاریخی ایران‌زمین است. بنابراین، در این مقاله، با بهره­گیری از پیکره حاصل از بررسی جامع ریشه­شناختی واژه­های فارسی در زبان انگلیسی، با شیوه‌ای توصیفی ـ تحلیلی، به طور مشخص به سیر انتقال و گسترش شگرف چهار واژۀ فارسیِ بازی شطرنج در زبان انگلیسی پرداخته می‌شود. نتیجه حاصل نه­تنها تصویری از دامنه نفوذ این واژه­ها را ترسیم می­نماید، بلکه ابعادی ارزشمند از دگرگونی­های معنایی و آوایی را در این دسته از واژه­های قرضی آشکار می­سازد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The significant arrival and spread of Persian words in various languages in different periods of time is an important topic in the fields of etymology and historical linguistics. Persian is among many languages which have lent many words mostly indirectly to European languages including English. The study of these words provides a clear picture of the civilization, culture and social and historical events ofIran. In this paper, with the aid of a corpus derived from a comprehensive etymological study of English words borrowed from Persian, specifically through a descriptive and analytic study, the transfer and spread of four Persian words used in chess which are common in current English are analyzed and their phonetic and semantic changes are considered. </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>17</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>30</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فردوس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آقاگل‌زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Ferdows</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aghagolzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aghagolz@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>داوری</Family>
						<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Davari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه دامغان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه دامغان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>h.davari@du.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ریشه‌شناسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دگرگونی معنایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان فارسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان انگلیسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>واژه‌های قرضی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آقاگل‌زاده، فردوس و حسین داوری (1386). &quot;واژه‌هایی به‌ظاهر دخیل، اما اصیل&quot;، دوفصل‌نامۀ پژوهش زبان و ادبیات فارسی. دورۀ جدید، ش9، 177-159.##انوری، حسن (1382). فرهنگ سخن. چ2. تهران: سخن.##پادشاه، محمد ( 1363). فرهنگ جامع فارسی(آنندراج). زیر نظر محمد دبیر سیاقی. چ2. تهران: انتشارات خیام.##تبریزی، محمدحسین‌بن خلف (1376). برهان قاطع. به اهتمام محمد معین. چ6. تهران: امیرکبیر.##حسینی، عبد‌الرشیدبن عبدالغفور (1337). فرهنگ رشیدی به‌ضمیمۀ معربات رشیدی. به‌کوشش محمد عباسی. تهران: انتشارات بارانی.##داعی‌الاسلام، محمدعلی (1362). فرهنگ نظام. تهران: انتشارات دانش.##دهخدا، علی‌اکبر (1377). لغت‌نامه. چ2. تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##رامپوری، غیاث‌الدین محمد (1363). غیاث‌اللغات. به‌کوشش منصور ثروت. چ1. تهران: امیرکبیر.##سرکاراتی، بهمن (1377). &quot;دربارۀ فرهنگ ریشه‌شناختی زبان فارسی و ضرورت تدوین آن&quot;. نامۀ فرهنگستان. س4، ش1، 72-21.##ظهیری سمرقندی، محمدبن علی (1348). سندبادنامه. به کوشش احمد آتش، استانبول: بی‌نا.##معین، محمد (1360). فرهنگ معین. چ4. تهران: امیرکبیر.##Barnhart, R. (2005). Chambers Dictionary of Etymology. Chambers Harrap Publishers. (CHD)##Brown, L. (1993). The New Shorter Oxford English Dictionary. (2vol). Clavendon Press. (SOD)##Grove, Ph. (1986). Webster&#039;s Third International Dictionary. (3vols). Merriam Company. (WTI)##Kleindler, S. (1997). The American Heritage Dictionary. Dell Publishing. (AHD)##Onions, C. T. (2003).The Oxford Dictionary of English Etymology. Oxford University Press. (OED)##Partridage, E. (1991). Origins: An Etymological Dictionary of Modern English. Routledge. (ORG)##Rooney, K. (2000). Encarta World English Dictionary. St. Martin&#039;s Press. (ENC)##Skeat, W. (1993). Concise Dictionary of English Etymology. Wordsworth Editions Ltd. (CDE)##Stein, M. J. (1998). Random House Webster&#039;s. Random House Group. (RHW)##www.etymonline.com (EON)##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نگاهی به قدرت و جنسیت از منظر ادب و بی‌ادبی در رمان‌های نوجوانانِ فارسی‌زبان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Looking through the Lenses of (Im)Politeness at Power and Gender in Persian-Speaking Youngsters’ Novels</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پژوهش حاضر به بررسیِ تأثیر قدرت و جنسیت در اتخاذ رویکردهای مؤدبانه یا بی‌ادبانه از سوی شخصیت‌های قدرتمند و ضعیف، و نیز مردان و زنان، در ده رُمانِ برگزیدۀ نوجوانان فارسی‌زبان، بر اساس نظریۀ ادبِ براون و لوینسون، و نظریۀ بی‌ادبیِ کالپپر می‌پردازد. رمان‌های نوجوانانِ فارسی‌زبانِ منتشرشده در فاصلۀ سال‌های 1391- 1381، جامعۀ پژوهش را تشکیل می‌دهد و آثار مورد بررسی بر پایۀ معیارهای تألیفی‌بودنِ اثر، گفت‌وگومحوربودنِ داستان، مورد تأییدبودن از سوی صاحب‌نظران، و . . . انتخاب شده است. داده‌های پژوهش با استفاده از آزمون آماریِ خی دو، مورد بررسی قرار گرفته و نتایج حاصل نشان می‌دهد که قدرت و ادب رابطۀ معکوسی باهم دارند، یعنی هرچه قدرت افراد بیشتر باشد، از استراتژی‌های بی‌ادبیِ بیشتر و هرچه جایگاه قدرت ضعیف‌تر باشد، از استراتژی‌های ادبِ بیشتری استفاده می‌کنند. بر همین اساس، مشخص شد که شخصیت‌های زن، در برخورد با شخصیت‌های مرد، رفتار زبانیِ مؤدبانه‌تری دارند و شخصیت‌های مرد، بیشتر از شخصیت‌های زن از استراتژی‌های بی‌ادبی استفاده می‌کنند. </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> 
The present article intends to analyze those conversations in ten Persian-speaking youngsters’ novels that are important in the development of the plots of the stories and to explore the ways power and gender influence the characters’ choices of (im)politeness strategies. Brown and Levinson’s politeness theory and Culpeper’s impoliteness theory are chosen as the theoretical frameworks. To be included in the samples, the novels should be originally written in Persian; the majority of their actions should be in dialogue form; they should have won prize(s) in the field of youth’s literature. According to chi square test the results indicate that power and politeness have a reverse relationship, i.e. the more powerful a character is, the less polite she/he becomes. In addition, female characters make more use of politeness strategies whereas male characters use more of impoliteness strategies.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>31</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>56</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رحمانی</Family>
						<NameE>Hosein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rahmani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه پیام نور</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hosein_rahmani@pnu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ادب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بی‌ادبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رمان نوجوانانِ فارسی‌زبان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قدرت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جنسیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>اکبرپور، احمد (1382). من نوکر بابا نیستم. تهران: افق.##امیریان داوود (1390). گردان قاطرچی‌ها. تهران: کانون پرورش فکری کودکان و نوجوانان.##بابامرندی، مژگان (1391). من یک مرد عنکبوتی شبیه رستم خواهم شد. تهران: کانون پرورش فکری کودکان و نوجوانان.##بایرامی محمدرضا (1383). پل معلق. تهران: افق.##بایرامی محمدرضا (1387). گرگ‌ها از برف نمی‌ترسند. تهران، قدیانی.##ثابت، فرزانه (1388). راهکارهای ادب در درخواست. پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد زبان‌شناسی همگانی. دانشگاه تربیت معلم سبزوار.##حاجی محمدی، ساناز (1389). بررسی زبان غیرمؤدبانه بین زنان و مردان فارسی‌زبان تهرانی. پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد زبان‌شناسی همگانی. دانشگاه علامۀ طباطبایی.##خانیان، جمشید (1387). طبقۀ هفتم غربی. تهران: افق.##خانیان، جمشید (1389). شب گربه‌های چشم­سفید. تهران: کانون پرورش فکری کودکان و نوجوانان.##شاه آبادی، حمیدرضا (1386). لالایی برای دختر مرده. تهران: افق.##شکاری، الهه (1390). مطالعۀ زبان و قدرت در گفتمانِ محل کار فارسی‌زبانان با توجه به صورت‌های خطاب و استراتژی‌های ادب. پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد هنرهای نمایشی. دانشگاه تبریز.##رفیعی سخایی، سودابه (1390). تحلیل گفتمان ادب در شخصیت‌پردازی و پیشبرد کنشِ نمایش‌نامه: مطالعۀ موردیِ گزیده‌ای از نمایش‌نامه‌های ایرانی. پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد زبان‌شناسی همگانی. دانشگاه هنر.##گلشیری، سیامک (1389). اولین روز تابستان. تهران: کانون پرورش فکری کودکان و نوجوانان.##لطفی، خدیجه (1390). عدم رعایت ادب و قدرت: رویکرد منظورشناختیِ بین‌زبانی به استفاده از الگوهای غیرمؤدبانه با توجه به قدرت. پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد زبان‌شناسی همگانی. دانشگاه علامۀ طباطبایی.##نعمتی، آزاده (1382). &quot;تحلیلی بر تفاوت‌های زبانیِ زنان و مردان: تحقیقی در جامعه‌شناسی زبان&quot;. مجلۀ دانشکدۀ علوم انسانی دانشگاه سمنان، ش5، 92ـ73.##هدایت، ندا (1384). &quot;تأثیر جنسیت بر نحوۀ تقاضا (پژوهشی در حوزۀ جامعه‌شناسی زبان)&quot;. دوفصلنامۀ پژوهش زبان و ادبیات فارسی، دورۀ جدید، ش4، بهار و تابستان 1384، 40 ـ17.##یگانه، علی (1375). رابطۀ جنس و سن با ادب: مطالعۀ بین‌فرهنگی. پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد آموزش زبان انگلیسی. دانشگاه اصفهان.##یوسفی، محمدرضا (1382). گواتی. تهران: شعلۀ اندیشه.##Andersson, L. M. and M. P. Christine (1999). &quot;Tit for Tat? The Spiraling Effect of Incivility in the Workplace&quot;. Academy of Management Review, 24 (3), 452-471.##Aydinoglu, N. (2013). &quot;Politeness and Impoliteness Strategies: An Analysis of Gender Differences in Geralyn L. Horton’s Plays&quot;. Procedia, 83, 473-482.##Bacha, N. N. and R. Bahous and R. L. Diab (2012). &quot;Gender and Politeness in a Foreign Language Academic Context&quot;. International Journal of English Linguistics, Vol. 2, No. 1, 79-96.##Baxter, L. A. (1984). &quot;An Investigation of Compliance-Gaining as Politeness&quot;. Human Communication Research, Vol. 10, No. 3, 427– 456.##Beebe, L. M. (1995). “The Social Rules of Speaking: Basics-Not Frosting on the Cake”. The Language Teacher, 19 (3), 4-11.##Behnam, B. and M. Niroomand (2011). “An Investigation of Iranian EFL learners’ Use of Politeness Strategies and Power Relations in Disagreement across Different Proficiency Levels”. English Language Teaching, Vol. 4, No. 4, 204-220.##Berger, Charles. (1994). &quot;Power, dominance, and social interaction&quot;. In Mark L. Knapp and Gerald R. Miller (eds.): Handbook of Interpersonal Communication. Thousand Oaks: Sage, 450-507.##BlumـKulka, S. (1990). “You Don’t Touch Lettuce with Your Finger: Parental Politeness in Family Discourse”. Journal of Pragmatics, 14,259-288.##Bousfield, D. (2008). Impoliteness in Interaction. Amsterdam/Philadelphia: John Benjamin Publishing Company.##Brown, P. and S. C. Levinson (1987). Politeness: Some Universals in Language Usage. London: Cambridge University Press.##Brown, R. and A. Gilman (1989). “Politeness Theory and Shakespeare’s Four Major Tragedies”. Language in Society, 18 (2), 159-213.##Brown, R. and A. Gilman (1960). The pronouns of power and solidarity. In Giglioli, Pier Paolo (ed.): Languageand Social Context. Penguin: Harmondsworth, 252-282.##Craig, R. and K. Tracy and F. Spisak (1986). “The Discourse of Requests: Assessment of a PolitenessApproach”. Human Communication Research, 12, 437ـ468.##Culpeper, J. (1996). “Towards an Anatomy of Impoliteness”. Journal of Pragmatics, 25, 349–367.##Culpeper, J.  (1998). “(Im)politeness in Drama”. In J. Culpeper and M. Short and P. Verdonk (eds.): Exploring the Language of Drama: From text to context, 83-95. London: Routledge.##Culpeper, J. and Derek Bousfield and Anne Wichman (2003). &quot;Impoliteness revisited: With special reference to dynamic and prosodic aspects&quot;. Journal of Pragmatics, 35 (10-11), 1545-1579.##De Klerk, V. (1992). “How Taboo Are Taboo Words for Girls?” Language in Society, Vol. 21, No. 2, 277-289.##Eelen, G. (2001). A Critique of Politeness Theories. Manchester: St. Jerome Publishing.##Ermida, I. (2006). “Linguistic mechanisms of power in Nineteen EightyـFour: Applying politeness theory to Orwell’s World”. Journal of Pragmatics, 38, 842-862.##Foyster, E. (2002). “Creating a Veil of Silence? Politeness and Marital Violence in the English Household”. Transactions of the Royal Historical Society, Sixth Series, Vol. 12, 395-415.##Goffman, Erving (1967). &quot;On Face-work: An Analysis of Ritual Elements of Social Interaction&quot;. Psychiatr: Journal for the Study of Interpersonal Processes 18 (3): 213–231.##Goodwin, C. and M. H. Goodwin (1990). “Interstitial Argument”. In D. Grimshaw, Allen (ed.): Conflict Talk: Sociolinguistic Investigations of Arguments in Conversations, 85-117. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Grice, H. (1975). &quot;Logic and conversation&quot; in Cole, P. and J. Morgan (eds.): Syntax and Semantics 3. Speech Acts. New York: Academic Press, 41- 58.##Holmes, J. (1995). Women, Men and Politeness. London: Longman.##Holtgraves, T. (1986). “Language Structure in Social Interaction: Perceptions of Direct and IndirectSpeech Acts and Interactants Who Use Them”. Journal of Personality and SocialPsychology, 51 (2), 305-314.##Holtgraves, T. and Y. Joong-Nam (1990). “Politeness as Universal: Cross-Cultural Perceptions of Request Strategies and Inferences Based on Their Use”. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 59 (4), 719-729.##Hutchby, I. (1996). “Confrontation Talk: Aspects of Interruption in Argument Sequences onTalk Radio”. Text: Interdisciplinary Journal for the Study of Discourse, 12 (3), 343-371.##Kamisli, S. and S. Dogancay (1996). “Effects of Social Power on Language Use Acros Speech Communities”. International Journal of Applied Linguistics, Vol. 6, No. 2, 199-222.##Kantara, A. (2010). “Impoliteness Strategies in House M. D.”. Lodz Papers in Pragmatics, 6. 2, 305-339.##Kienpointner, M. (1997). “Varieties of Rudeness: Types and Functions of Impolite Utterances”. Functionsof Language, 4 (2), 251-287.##Labov, W. and D. Fanshel (1977). Therapeutic Discourse: Psychotherapy as Conversation. New York: Academic Press.##Lachenicht, L. G. (1980). “Aggravating Language: A Study of Abusive and Insulting Language”. InternationalJournal of Human Communication, 13 (4), 607-688.##Ladegaard, H. J. (2004). “Politeness in Young Children’s Speech: Context, Peer Group Influence and Pragmatic Competence”. Journal of Pragmatics, 36, 2003-2022.##Lakoff, R. T. (1989). “The Way We Were; or, the Real Actual Truth about Generative Semantics: A memoir”. Journal of Pragmatics, 13, 939-988.##Leech, Geoffrey N. (1983). Principles of Pragmatics. NewYork: Longman.##Leichty, G. and J. L. Applegate (1991). “SocialـCognitive and Situational Influences on the Use of Face-Saving PersuasiveStrategies”. Human Communication Research, 17 (3), 451-484.##Lim, T. and J. W. Bowers (1991). “Facework, Solidarity, Approbation and Tact”. Human Communication Research, 17 (3), 415-450.##Locher, M. A. (2004). Power and Politeness in Action: Disagreements in Oral Communication. Berlin: Mouton de Gruyter.##Mey, J. L. (2009). Pragmatics. Oxford: Elsevier.##Mills, S. (2003). Gender and Politeness. Cambridge: CambridgeUniversity Press.##Morand, D. A. (1996). ”Dominance, Deference, and Egalitarianism in Organizational Interaction: A Sociolinguistic Analysis of Power and Politeness”. Organization Science, Vol. 7, No. 5, 544-556.##Morand, D. A. (2000). &quot;Language and Power: an Empirical Analysis of LinguisticStrategies Used in Superiorـ Subordinate Communication&quot;. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 21, 235-248.##Murni, S. M. and M. Solin (2012). “Linguistic Impoliteness: A Small Corpus Analysis on the Use of Impolite Language by Children”. Aceh International Journal of Social Sciences, 1 (1), 11-15.##Niroomand, M. (2012). “An Exploration of Upper-intermediate Iranian EFL learners’ Perception of Politeness Strategies and Power Relations in Disagreement”. English Language Teaching, Vol. 5, No. 10,180-191.##Penman, R. (1990). “Facework and Politeness: Multiple Goals in Courtroom Discourse”. Journal of Languageand Social Psychology, 9, 15-38.##Sadeghi, S. (2012). &quot;Application of Critical Classroom Discourse Analysis in Analyzing Classroom Interaction&quot;. English Language Teaching, 5, No. 1, 166-173.##Sifianou, M. (1992). Politeness Phenomena in England and Greece: A Cross-Cultural Approach. Oxford: Oxford University Press.##Smith-Hefner, N. J. (1988). “Women and Politeness: The Javanese Example”. Language in Society, Vol. 17, No. 4, 535-554.##Smith, J. S. (1992). “Women in Charge: Politeness and Directives in the Speech of Japanese Women”. Language in Society, Vol. 21, No. 1, 59-82.##Tannen, D. (1990). “Silence as Conflict Management in Fiction and Drama: Pinter’s Betrayaland a Short Story Great Wits”. In A. D. Grimshaw (ed.): Conflict Talk: Sociolinguistic Investigations ofArgumentsand Conversations, 260-279. Cambridge: Cambridge UniversityPress.##Thomas J. (1995). Meaning in Interaction. An Introduction to Pragmatics. London: Longman.##Tracy, K. And S. J. Tracy (1998). “Rudeness at 911: Reconceptualizing Face and Face Attack”. Human CommunicationResearch, 25 (2), 225-251.##Watts, Richard J. and Sachiko Ide and Konrad Ehlich. (1992). &quot;Introduction&quot;. In Richard J. Watts and Sachiko Ide and Konrad Ehlich (eds.): Politeness in Language: Studies in its History, Theory and Practice. Berlin: Mouton de Gruyter, 1-17.##Watts, R. J. (2003). Politeness. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press. ##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>دگرگونی‌های دستوریِ فارسی معاصر در آینۀ مطبوعات ورزشی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Grammatical Innovations in the Persian Sport Media</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زبان به‌عنوان نهادی اجتماعی که مهم‌ترین نقش آن ایجاد ارتباط است،به منظور برآوردنِ نیازهای ارتباطیِ سخن‌گویانِ خود متحول می‌شود. با توجه به ویژگی‌های خاصِ مطبوعات ورزشی، نوآوری‌های زبانیِ بیشتری در این نوع مطبوعات رخ می‌دهد. در این تحقیق سعی شده است،ضمن جمع‌آوری و دسته‌بندیِ نوآوری‌های دستوری در متون مطبوعات ورزشی فارسی معاصر (فارسی نوشتاریِ گونۀ مطبوعاتی)، این نوآوری‌ها،در چارچوب اصول مربوط به دگرگونی دستوری،مورد بررسی و تحلیل قرارگیرند. این مطالعه، تحقیقی داده‌بنیاد است که در آن متون مورد نظر بررسی و جمله‌هایی که حاوی نوعی دگرگونی دستوری بوده‌اند، استخراج شده‌اند. ساخت‌هایی به‌عنوان نمونۀ تغییر گردآوری شده‌اند، که در جامعۀ آماری به صورت متعدد ظاهر شده‌اند، و ساخت‌هایی، که بسامد معدودی داشته‌اند، نادیده گرفته شده‌اند. یافته‌های این تحقیق نشان می‌دهدکه مطبوعات ورزشی، به علت اینکه کمتر در قید زبان معیارند،دگرگونی‌های دستوری را آسان‌تر درخود بازتاب می‌دهند و این گونه تغییر زبان به طور وسیعی در این نوع مطبوعات روی می‌دهد.مهم‌ترین نتیجۀ این پژوهش این است که دگرگونی‌های موجود در مطبوعات ورزشیِ فارسی معاصر را نمی‌توان صرفاً محصول عدم پایبندیِ نویسندگان به قواعد دستوریِ زبان و عدول از هنجارهای زبان دانست، بلکه این نوآوری‌ها نشان از تغییراتی دارد که در دستور زبان در حال رخ دادن است، اما با توجه به ویژگی‌های خاصِ زبان مطبوعات،در این گونه متون مجال ظهور بیشتری پیدا می‌کنند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Communication is the main function of the human language as a social institution. It is constantly changed in order to meet the communication needs of the speakers. Due to the specific characteristics of sport media, innovations occur mainly in this type of text. In this study, we tried to investigate the innovations in contemporary Persian sports media. These innovations are studied and analyzed in the framework of the Functional Grammar. The findings of this research show that in the contemporary sports media many sorts of grammatical changes have taken place. Valency reduction, changes in word order, aspectual innovations, analogical constructions, creating new derivations and slang word formations are the most common innovations in this genre. These innovations should not be regarded as mere mistakes, but they show the process of grammatical changes that are in progress in the language.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>79</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>80</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>والی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رضایی</Family>
						<NameE>Vali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rezai</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه اصفهان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه اصفهان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>vali.rezai@fgn.ui.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فهیمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جمالی</Family>
						<NameE>Fahimeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jamali</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد زبانشناسی همگانی، دانشگاه اصفهان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد زبانشناسی همگانی، دانشگاه اصفهان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>fahimeh.jamali@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دگرگونی دستوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فارسی معیار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مطبوعات ورزشی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قیاس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آرلاتو، آنتونی (1373). درآمدی بر زبان‌شناسی تاریخی. ترجمۀ یحیی مدرسی. تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##آقاگل‌زاده، فردوس و همکاران (1390). &quot;سبک‌شناسیِ داستان بر اساس فعل: رویکرد نقش‌گرا&quot;. فصل‌نامۀتخصصی سبک‌شناسی ِنظم و نثر فارسی (بهارادب)،ش1، 254- 243.##ابوالقاسمی، محسن (1373). تاریخ زبان فارسی. تهران: سمت.##اسلامی، افروز (1375). بررسی تغییرات نحوی و واژگانی فارسی معاصر(انقلاب مشروطیت تا ابتدای انقلاب اسلامی). پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد. تهران: دانشگاه تربیت مدرس.##افتخاری، سید اسماعیل (1384). &quot;نقش کم‌کوشیِ زبانی در پیدایش فارسی محاوره&quot;. فصل‌نامۀ پژوهش‌های ادبی، ش7، 60- 25.##بهار، محمدتقی ملک‌الشعرا (1331). سبک شناسی. تهران: امیرکبیر.##حق‌شناس، علی‌محمد (1379). &quot;واژه‌سازی درون متن، یک علاج قطعی&quot;. نشر دانش، س17، ش1، 31- 27.##خاتمی، احمد (1384).&quot;ویژگی‌های نثر مطبوعاتی&quot;. نشر فرهنگ، ش55، 64- 45.##خانلری، پرویز ناتل (1347). زبان‌شناسی و زبان فارسی. تهران: انتشارات بنیاد فرهنگ ایران.##ذوالفقاری، حسن و همکاران (1385).الگوهای غیر‌معیار در زبان مطبوعات. تهران: دانشگاه تربیت مدرس.##راسخ‌مهند، محمد (1386).&quot;ساخت ناگذرا در فارسی&quot;. مجلۀزبان و زبان‌شناسی، ش5، 20- 1.##راسخ‌مهند، محمد (1391). &quot;گروه حرف اضافه‌ای پس‌از فعل، دلایل نقشی و رده‌شناختی&quot;. مجموعه‌مقالات هشتمین همایش زبان‌شناسی، 178- 156. تهران: دانشگاه علامۀ طباطبایی.##رضایی، والی(1389).&quot;نگاهی تازه به ساخت مجهول در زبان فارسی&quot;. پژوهش‌های زبان‌شناسی، ش2، 34- 17.##رضایی، والی (1391).&quot;نمود استمراری در فارسی معاصر&quot;. مجلۀ فنون ادبی دانشگاه اصفهان، ش1، 92- 79.##رضایی، والی (1393). &quot;گواه‌نمایی در زبان فارسی امروز&quot;. پژوهش‌های زبانی، ش9، 39- 21.##رضی،احمد و حسام ضیایی (1385). &quot;ویژگی‌ها و مسائل زبانیِ وب ‌نوشت‌های فارسی&quot;. نامۀفرهنگستان،ش43، 53- 44.##شریعت، محمدجواد (1364). دستور زبان فارسی. تهران: اساطیر.##شقاقی، ویدا (1386). مبانی صرف. تهران: سمت.##شریعت، محمدجواد (1364). دستورزبان فارسی. انتشارات اساطیر.##صادقی، علی اشرف (1370).&quot;شیوه‌ها و امکانات واژه‌سازی در زبان فارسی معاصر(4)&quot;.  نشر دانش، ش69، 25- 21.##صادقی، علی اشرف (1372). &quot;شیوه‌ها و امکانات واژه‌سازی در زبان فارسی معاصر (12)&quot;. نشر دانش، ش 79و80، 15- 12##صحرایی، رضا و رقیه کاظمی‌نهاد (1385). &quot;تأملی در ساخت مجهول فارسی امروز&quot;. نشریۀ دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم انسانی دانشگاهشهید باهنر کرمان، ش20، 97- 77.##علوی‌مقدم، سیدبهنام (1386). &quot;انواع جمله از نظر تعداد اجزا&quot;. رشد آموزش زبان و ادب فارسی، ش4، 45- 41.##علیزاده، علی (1382). &quot;پدیدۀ قرض‌گیری در زبان&quot;.مجلۀادبیات و علوم انسانیدانشگاه بیرجند،ش3، 148- 137.##کشانی، خسرو (1371). اشتقاق پسوندی در زبان فارسی امروز. تهران: مرکز نشر دانشگاهی.##مارتینه، آندره (1378). اصول زبان‌شناسی عمومی. ترجمۀ سید علاءالدین گوشه‌گیر. اهواز: انتشارات دانشگاه شهید چمران.##مدرسی، یحیی (1368). درآمدی بر جامعه‌شناسی زبان. تهران: مؤسسه مطالعات و تحقیقات فرهنگی.##نجفی، ابوالحسن (1366). &quot;گلدان توسط بچه شکسته شد&quot;.نشر دانش، ش41، 13- 11.##Aarts, B. &amp; M. Lopez&amp; B. Mendez Naya (2012). &quot;Late modern English syntax&quot;. In Historical Linguistics of English: An International Handbook. Vol I, eds. Alexander Bergs &amp; Laurel J. Brinton. Berlin: Mouton de Gruyter.##Ahsan, A. )1976(. Modern trends in the Persian language. Islamabad: Iran Pakistan Institute of Persian Studies.##Benveniste, E. (1968). &quot;Mutations of Linguistic Categories&quot;. In Lehman,W, &amp; Malkiel,Y, (eds.): Directions for Historical Linguistics, 83-94.Austin: University of Texas Press.##Campbell, L. (1999). Historical Linguistics: An Introduction. Cambridge: MIT Press.##Haspelmath, M. (1993). &quot;More on the typology of Inchoative/Causative Verb Alternations&quot;. In. B. Comrie &amp; M. Polinsky (Eds.), Causatives and Transitivity,87-120. Amesterdam: John Benjamins.##Katamba, F. &amp;J. Stonham (2006). Morphology. Palgrave macmillan.##Leech, G. (2004). &quot;Recent grammatical changes in English: data, description, theory&quot;. in K. Aijmer &amp; B. Altenberg (eds.), Advances in Corpus Linguistics,61-81, Amsterdam: Rodopi.##Leech, G. et al. (2009).Change in contemporary English: A grammatical study.Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Tallerman, M. (2015).Understanding Syntax.4th Ed. London:Routledge.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اتصال پی‌بست‌های ضمیری به اسامیِ مختوم به واکه در زبان فارسی: چگونگی اتصال و بازنگری نظام پی‌بست‌های ضمیری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Attaching  Pronominal Enclitics to Vowel-ending Nominals: Revision of Pronominal Enclitics System</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>این مقاله به بررسی چگونگی اتصال پی‌بست‌های ضمیریِ زبان فارسی به اسامیِ مختوم به واکه می‌پردازد. هدف از انجام این پژوهش بازنماییِ صورت زیرساختیِ این نوع ضمایر در زبان فارسی و چگونگیِ اتصال آنها به گروه‌های اسمیِ مختوم به واکه، و همچنین مطالعۀ انواع فرایندهای درجِ موجود بین ستاک و پی‌بست است. بررسی داده‌ها نشان می‌دهد که نظام پی‌بست‌های ضمیری در زبان فارسی، نظامی سه‌عضوی است که هریک بیانگر اول شخص، دوم شخص و سوم شخص مفرد است. این ضمایر تنها از یک همخوانِ منفرد تشکیل شده‌اند، که صورت جمع متناظر آنها با افزودن پسوند جمع‌ساز ‘-An’حاصل می‌گردد. همچنین، نشان داده می‌شود که واکۀ درج‌شده میان ستاکِ مختوم به واکه و ضمیر در ‌قیاس با ستاک‌های مختوم به همخوان درج می‌گردد. این نوع فرایندِ درج، خود زمینه‌سازِ درجِ غلت یا نیم‌واکه میان ضمیر و واکۀ درجی می‌شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The present paper studies how the pronominal enclitics in Persian attach to the NPs ended in vowels. The main goal of this paper is revealing the underlying representation of such pronouns: how they attach to nouns ending in vowels, studying the insertion process occurred between the stem and the enclitic. After analyzing data, two hypotheses were proposed, of which one was finally confirmed. The results show that the pronominal enclitics system in Persian is a three-membered system (-m, -t, -S) revealing three singular persons. These pronouns consist of one single consonant and their plural counterparts are made by adding the regular plural suffix “- n”. Also, it is shown that the insertion of vowel between the stem and pronouns is the result of analogy with the stems ending in consonants. This process feeds the insertion of a semi-vowel.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>81</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>102</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سحر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بهرامی خورشید</Family>
						<NameE>Sahar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bahrami Khorshid</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sahbahrami@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عالیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کرد زعفرانلو کامبوزیا</Family>
						<NameE>Alieh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kord Zafaranlu Kambuzia</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>akord@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پی‌بست‌های ضمیری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>درج</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>واکه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گروه اسمی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظام وندی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>قرآن کریم (1386). ترجمۀ مهدی الهی قمشه‌ای. قم: انتشارات دانش.##ابوالقاسمی، محسن (1375). دستور تاریخی زبان فارسی. تهران: (سمت).##احمدی گیوی، حسن و حسن انوری (1372). دستور زبان فارسی. تهران: موسسۀ انتشارات ناظمی.##پی‌سیکوف، لازار سامویلویچ (1380). لهجۀ تهرانی. ترجمه محسن شجاعی. تهران: نشر آثار.##شقاقی، ویدا (1374). &quot;واژه‌بست چیست؟ آیا در زبان فارسی چنین مفهومی کاربرد دارد؟&quot;مجموعه‌مقاله‌های سومین کنفرانس زبان‌شناسی. تهران: 157- 141.##صادقی، علی‌اشرف (1365). &quot;التقای مصوت‌ها و مسئلۀ صامت‌های میانجی در زبان فارسی&quot;. مجلۀ زبان‌شناسی، س3، ش2: پاییز و زمستان، 22- 3.##عمادافشار، حسین (1372). دستور و ساختمان زبان فارسی. تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه علامۀ طباطبایی.##فردوسی، ابوالقاسم (1350). شاهنامه. تصحیح محمدجعفر محجوب. ج 6. تهران: انتشارات امیرکبیر.##قریب، عبدالعظیم و همکاران (1370). دستور زبان فارسی. چ9. تهران: سازمان انتشارات اشرافی.##کرد زعفرانلو کامبوزیا، عالیه (1385). نقد و تصحیح مقالۀ محمدرضا مجیدی و المار ترنز. مجلۀ زبان و زبان‌شناسی. س2، ش1: بهار و تابستان. 118- 109.##مشکوه‌الدینی، مهدی (1384). دستور زبان فارسی: واژگان و پیوندهای ساختی. تهران: (سمت).##مکنزی، دیوید نیل (1379). فرهنگ کوچک زبان پهلوی. ترجمۀ مهشید میرفخرایی. تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##Jensen, John. T. (2004). Principles of Generative Phonology: An Introduction. Amsterdam: John Benjamins Publishing Company.##Katamba, Francis. (1993). Morphology. London: Macmillan Press Ltd.##Klavans, Judith. L. (1982). Some Problems in a Theory of Clitics. Bloomington: Indian University. Linguistics Club.##Whaley, L. J. (1997). Introduction to Typology: The Unity and Diversity of Language. New York: Sage Publications.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی پدیدۀ رمزگردانی با نگاهی به گفتار دوزبانه‌های ارمنی- فارسی تهرانی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A study of code-switching according to Armenian conversations of Armenian-Persian bilinguals</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در جوامعی که بیش‌از یک زبان در آنها وجود دارد، شاهد تماس یا برخورد زبان‌ها به شکل‌های مختلف هستیم. از جمله پیامدهای برخورد زبانی، رمزگردانی است که به استفادۀ متناوب از دو یا چند زبان، در یک پاره‌گفتار، گفته می‌شود. افراد دوزبانه غالباً در حین گفت‌وگو از زبانی به زبان دیگر روی می‌آورند. یکی از جوامع دوزبانه در ایران را دوزبانه‌های ارمنی- فارسی تشکیل می­دهند. مقاله حاضر به بررسی پدیده رمزگردانی در دوزبانه های ارمنی- فارسی تهرانی می­پردازد. این بررسی بر اساس داده‌هایی است که از ده ساعت مکالمات روزمرۀ ارامنۀ تهرانی گردآوری شده است. در بررسیِ رمزگردانیِ برون‌جمله‌ای، از دیدگاه بلوم و گامپرز (1972)، و در بررسیِ رمزگردانیِ درون‌جمله‌ای از مدل میرز- اسکاتن (1993، 2002) استفاده شده است. نتایج به دست آمده از تحلیل داده‌ها نشان می­دهد که در مکالمات دوزبانه‌های ارمنی- فارسیِ تهرانی به زبان ارمنی، رمزگردانی از هر دو نوع اتفاق می‌افتد و رمزگردانیِ درون‌جمله‌ای از بسامد بسیار بالایی برخوردار است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Language contact occurs in various ways in multi-language societies. One of the most significant results of language contact is code switching, which refers to the use of phrases and words of more than one language within the same utterance or the same conversation. Code switching can be divided into two types: intra-sentential and inter-sentential. Armenian-Persian bilinguals frequently switch from Armenian to Persian in their Armenian conversations. This study examines two types of code switching based on 10 hours of recorded informal Armenian conversations in Tehran. In order to investigate intra-sentential code switching in this research, the model proposed by Myers-Scatton is utilized. For inter-sentential code switching the approach presented by Blom and Gumperz is employed. The results show that in Armenian conversations of Armenian- Persian bilinguals both kinds of code switching take place and intra-sentential is used more frequently.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>103</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>120</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مریم‌سادات</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>غیاثیان</Family>
						<NameE>Maryam Sadat</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghiasian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه پیام نور</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m_ghiasian@pnu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حکیمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رضایی</Family>
						<NameE>Hakimeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rezayi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد زبانشناسی همگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد زبانشناسی همگانی، دانشگاه پیام</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hakimeh.rezayi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان ارمنی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان فارسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>برخورد زبانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دوزبانگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رمزگردانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>غیاثیان، مریم و حکیمه رضایی (1393). &quot;بررسی نقش‌نماهای کلامی فارسی در مکالمات دوزبانه‌های ارمنی- فارسی&quot;. زبان‌شناخت. 5 (1)، 147- 125.##مدرسی، یحیی (1387). جامعه‌شناسی زبان. تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی.##Blom, J. P. &amp; Gumperz, J. J. (1972). “social meaning in linguistics structure: code-switching in Norway”. In J.J. Gumperz and D. Hymes (eds.): Directions in sociolinguistics: the ethnography of communication. New York. New York: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 407- 434.##Dam-tragut, J. (2009). Armenian. Amsterdam/ Philadelphia: John Benjamins Publishing Company.##Grosjean, F. (1984). Life with two languages: an introduction to bilingualism. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Gumperz, J. J. (1982). Discourse strategies. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##Hamers, J. F. and Blanc, H. A. (2000). Bilinguality and bilingualism. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##McCormick, K. (1995). &quot;Code-switching, code-mixing and convergence in Cape Town&quot;. In R. Mesthrie (ed.), Language and social history .Cape Town: David Philip Publishers, 193-208.##Muysken, P. (1995). “Code switching and grammatical theory”. In L. Mylroy and P. Muysken (eds.): One speaker two languages. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 177-197.##Myers-Scotton, Carol (1993). Dueling languages: grammatical structure in code switching. Oxford: Clarendon Press.##Myers-Scotton, Carol and J. L. Jake (2000). &quot;Testing a model of morpheme classification with language contact data&quot;. International journal of bilingualism. 4(1), 1-8##Myers-Scotton, Carol (2002).&quot;Explaining aspect of codeswitching and their implications&quot; In J. Nicole (ed.): One mind, two languages; Bilingual Language Processing. Oxford: Blackwell, 84-116.##Myers-Scotton, Carol (2002). Contact linguistics: bilingual encounters and grammatical outcomes. Oxford: Oxford university press.##Nilep, Chad (2006). “Code Switching in Sociocultural Linguistics”. Colorado research in linguistics. vol. 19. Boulder: University of Colorado.##Spolsky, B. (1998). Sociolinguistics. Oxford: Oxford University Press.##Van Dulm, O. (2007). The grammar of English-Afrikaans code switching: A feature checking account. Utrecht: LOT.##Weinreich, U. (1953). Language in contact. Paris: Mouton.##Wray, A. (2002). Formulaic language and the lexicon. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نقد و بررسی: فرهنگ اصطلاحات و عبارات رایج فارسی (فارسی – انگلیسی)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>No English Title</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>فرهنگ اصطلاحات و عبارات رایج فارسی (فارسی – انگلیسی)، تألیف استاد دکتر محمدرضا باطنی با دستیاری زهرا احمدی‌نیا در سال 1392 توسط انتشارات فرهنگ معاصر در 1089 صفحه به چاپ رسیده است. در زبان انگلیسی فرهنگ‌های متعددی وجود دارند که مدخل‌های آنها به شرح اصطلاحات و ترکیبات زبان اختصاص دارد. فرهنگ اصطلاحات کالینز کوبیلد[1]، فرهنگ اصطلاحات کمبریج[2] و فرهنگ اصطلاحات امریکن هریتیج[3]نمونه‌هایی از این‌گونه فرهنگ‌ها هستند. با توجه به اینکه تعداد این‌ فرهنگ‌ها در ایران بسیار کمتر از فرهنگ‌های انگلیسی به فارسی است، انتشار چنین فرهنگی پدیده‌ای است درخور توجه.


1. Collins Cobuild Idioms Dictionary


2. Cambridge International Idioms Dictionary


3. The American Heritage Dictionary of Idioms</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>-</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>123</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>128</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ساغر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شریفی</Family>
						<NameE>saghar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sharifi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد کرج</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد کرج</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>saghar.sharifi@kiau.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرهنگ اصطلاحات و عبارات رایج فارسی (فارسی – انگلیسی)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>محمدرضا باطنی با دستیاری زهرا احمدی‌نیا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تهران: انتشارات فرهنگ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				