<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>the representation of internal and external information structure in Persian complex sentences</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بازنمایی ساخت اطلاعی درونی و بیرونی در جملات مرکب زبان فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">4495</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فریده</FirstName>
					<LastName>حق بین</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه الزهرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پریسا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نجفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد/ دانشگاه الزهرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;span&gt;The information structure and how to represent it in a variety of constructions is one of the topics that has attracted much attention in the functional approaches to language review. In this essay, we will look at how to distribute information from the perspective of common ground management in complex sentences. In the role and reference grammar, subordination constructions are divided into two types; daughter subordination and ad subordination. Hence, it is possible to construct external information, including information structure in an entirely subordinate clause, and constructing internal information including the embedded clause. In this research, based on the above parameters [daughter subordinate constructions vs ad subordinate and external information structure vs internal information structure] we considered the distribution of information in complex sentences of Persian language and obtained the results which are summarized as follows: restrictive relative clauses normally cannot host the focus of the sentence and Similarly, and they are not a good domain for contrastive topics, Because if there are any such categories of information then it cannot successfully fulfil its primary function, to help identify the referent of the head noun. The adverbial clauses that are kind of ad subordinate clauses cannot have internal information structure or, in other words, they cannot be questioned by any of their inner constituents. The only way to question these elements is through echo or in situ questions, which is highly dependent on texture. The complement clauses in the Persian language have a full internal information structure and the complement clauses with manner and factive verbs, in the Persian language, especially in the language of speech, can have internal information structure; if there is a contrastive presupposition, the complement clauses will have internal information structure.&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ساخت اطلاعی و چگونگی بازنمایی آن در انواع ساخت‌ها از جمله مباحثی است که توجه زیادی را در حوزۀ رویکردهای نقش‌گرا نسبت به بررسی زبان به خود جلب کرده است. در این جستار برآنیم که به بررسی چگونگی توزیع اطلاع ازمنظرِ مدیریت زمینۀ مشترک در جملات مرکب بپردازیم. در دستور نقش و ارجاع بندهای ناهم‌پایه به دو نوعِ ناهم‌پایۀ دختر و ناهم‌پایۀ افزودنی تقسیم می‌شود. از این رو می‌توان ساخت اطلاعیِ بیرونی را شامل ساخت اطلاعی در کل بندِ ناهم‌پایه و ساخت اطلاعیِ درونی را مشتمل بر ساخت اطلاعیِ بند درونه محسوب کرد. در این پژوهش براساسِ پارامترهای مذکور [ساخت‌های ناهم‌پایۀ دختر دربرابر ناهم‌پایۀ افزودنی و ساخت اطلاعیِ بیرونی در برابر ساخت اطلاعیِ درونی] به بررسیِ چگونگیِ توزیعِ اطلاع در جملات مرکب زبان فارسی پرداختیم و به نتایجی دست یافتیم که به‌طور خلاصه به این شرح است: بندهای موصولیِ تحدیدی عموماً نمی‌توانند میزبان کانون جمله و همچنین محدودة مناسبی برای ظهور مبتداهای تقابلی باشند، چراکه درصورت وجود مقوله‌های اطلاعیِ مذکور، این بند نمی‌تواند وظیفۀ اصلی خود را که کمک به شناسایی مرجع (اسم هسته‌ای مورد توصیف) است انجام دهد. بندهای قیدی که نوعی از بندهای افزودنی هستند نمی‌توانند دارای ساخت اطلاعیِ درونی باشند یا به‌عبارتی نمی‌توان هیچ‌یک از سازه‌های درونیِ آنها را مورد سؤال قرار داد. تنها راه سؤالی‌سازیِ این عناصر به‌طریقِ انعکاسی یا درجاست که این موضوع به‌شدت وابسته به بافت است. بندهای متممی در زبان فارسی دارای ساخت اطلاعیِ درونیِ کامل هستند و بندهای متممیِ دارای افعال شیوۀ بیان و واقعیت‌نما، در زبان فارسی به‌خصوص در زبان گفتار می‌توانند ساخت اطلاعیِ درونی داشته باشند، درصورتِ وجودِ پیش‌انگارۀ تقابلی نیز بندهای متممی دارای ساختِ اطلاعیِ درونی خواهند بود. لازم به ذکر است که تجزیه و تحلیل پژوهش حاضر بر پایه داده‌های ماشینیِ خواندنی از داستان‌هایی با نثرِ نزدیک به زبان گفتار از شبکه جهانی وب صورت گرفته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساخت اطلاعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت زمینۀ مشترک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ناهم‌پایۀ دختر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ناهم‌پایۀ افزودنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساخت اطلاعیِ درونی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساخت اطلاعیِ بیرونی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_4495_abe975af08f432a2e62f2570e1db6310.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
