<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>20</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Attaching  Pronominal Enclitics to Vowel-ending Nominals: Revision of Pronominal Enclitics System</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اتصال پی‌بست‌های ضمیری به اسامیِ مختوم به واکه در زبان فارسی: چگونگی اتصال و بازنگری نظام پی‌بست‌های ضمیری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>81</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>102</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1879</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سحر</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهرامی خورشید</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عالیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>کرد زعفرانلو کامبوزیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present paper studies how the pronominal enclitics in Persian attach to the NPs ended in vowels. The main goal of this paper is revealing the underlying representation of such pronouns: how they attach to nouns ending in vowels, studying the insertion process occurred between the stem and the enclitic. After analyzing data, two hypotheses were proposed, of which one was finally confirmed. The results show that the pronominal enclitics system in Persian is a three-membered system (-m, -t, -S) revealing three singular persons. These pronouns consist of one single consonant and their plural counterparts are made by adding the regular plural suffix “- n”. Also, it is shown that the insertion of vowel between the stem and pronouns is the result of analogy with the stems ending in consonants. This process feeds the insertion of a semi-vowel.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این مقاله به بررسی چگونگی اتصال پی‌بست‌های ضمیریِ زبان فارسی به اسامیِ مختوم به واکه می‌پردازد. هدف از انجام این پژوهش بازنماییِ صورت زیرساختیِ این نوع ضمایر در زبان فارسی و چگونگیِ اتصال آنها به گروه‌های اسمیِ مختوم به واکه، و همچنین مطالعۀ انواع فرایندهای درجِ موجود بین ستاک و پی‌بست است. بررسی داده‌ها نشان می‌دهد که نظام پی‌بست‌های ضمیری در زبان فارسی، نظامی سه‌عضوی است که هریک بیانگر اول شخص، دوم شخص و سوم شخص مفرد است. این ضمایر تنها از یک همخوانِ منفرد تشکیل شده‌اند، که صورت جمع متناظر آنها با افزودن پسوند جمع‌ساز ‘-An’حاصل می‌گردد. همچنین، نشان داده می‌شود که واکۀ درج‌شده میان ستاکِ مختوم به واکه و ضمیر در ‌قیاس با ستاک‌های مختوم به همخوان درج می‌گردد. این نوع فرایندِ درج، خود زمینه‌سازِ درجِ غلت یا نیم‌واکه میان ضمیر و واکۀ درجی می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پی‌بست‌های ضمیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">واکه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گروه اسمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام وندی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1879_40a6b105c424ce148923c00cdb9be880.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
