<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>24</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>30</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Analysis of the Development of Grammatical Cohesion in persian-Speaking Students’ Written Discourse</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>گفتمان روایتیِ کودکان تک‌زبانۀ فارسی‌زبانِ مبتلا به آسیب ویژه و غیرویژۀ زبانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>74</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>106</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2469</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهه</FirstName>
					<LastName>کمری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This research aims at analyzing and comparing the development of grammatical cohesive devices (reference, conjunction, ellipsis and substitution) in Persian-speaking students’ written discourse at primary level (9 to 12 years old) according to logical meta-function introduced in Halliday and Matthiessen’s systemic functional grammar (2004),  by using a descriptive analytical method. 45 students (boys) studying at primary school (4th, 5th and 6th grades) in 2014-15 were selected through random-sampling. Two written tests in the form of picture stories were administered for gathering data from their writings. Frequency, percentage and pattern of development of using grammatical cohesive devices were compared in seeking the answer to the question of how age affects the frequency and the variety of grammatical cohesive devices. The frequency of grammatical cohesive devices among the 4th, 5th and 6th grade students was 1285, 1866, 2198 respectively. So the use of grammatical cohesive devices proved to increase in higher grades. Based on the Kruskal–Wallis test, the differences were significant (p≤ 0/05). The distribution of different cohesive devices showed some changes as the grades moved higher. In addition, more sophisticated devices were noticed . Personal references were the most and comparative references were the least frequent devices in the category of reference. In conjunction, additive, adversative, spatio- temporal and causal- conditional conjunction were the most and the least frequent ones. In ellipsis and substitution, nominal phrase deletion was the most, and verb phrase deletion was the least frequent one. The percentage of different devices were as follows: reference (62%), conjunction (22%), ellipsis and substitution (16%).</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تحقیقات نشان داده است که کودکان مبتلا به آسیب ویژۀ زبانی ازنظر توانایی‌های شناختی غیرکلامی با کودکان مبتلا به آسیب غیرویژۀ زبانی تفاوت دارند. با این حال، در رابطه با تفاوت‌های این دو گروه برحسب ویژگی‌های زبانی هنوز توافقی حاصل نشده است. هدف از انجام پژوهش توصیفی-تحلیلی و مقطعیِ حاضر بررسی ویژگی‌های روایت داستان در کودکان مبتلا به اختلال ویژه و غیرویژۀ زبانی با توجه به مقیاس‌های ساختار، محتوا و انسجام گفتمان روایتی است. به این منظور، دو گروه از کودکان مبتلا به اختلال ویژه و غیرویژۀ زبانی (هر گروه 15 پسر) با دو گروه از کودکان طبیعی، به‌عنوان گروه کنترل (همتای زبانی و همتای سنی (هر گروه 15 پسر))، مورد مقایسه قرار گرفتند. کودکان با استفاده از دو مجموعه از محرک‌های تصویریِ مسئله‌بنیاد به روایت داستان ترغیب شدند. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان داد که بین دو گروه مبتلا به آسیب زبانی، تفاوت آماریِ معناداری، ازلحاظِ مقیاس‌های ساختارِ داستان، اطلاعات ارائه‌شده و انسجام وجود ندارد (001/0p&gt; ). تفاوت بین دو گروه مبتلا به آسیب زبانیِ ویژه و گروه همتای زبانی، ازلحاظِ طول داستان‌های روایت‌شده و میزان اطلاعات ارائه‌شده، ازنظر آماری معنادار بود (001/0p&lt; ). با این حال، گروه مبتلا به آسیب غیرویژۀ زبانی با گروه همتای زبانی در مقیاس‌های کمتری تفاوت داشتند. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که تأثیر مهارت‌های زبانیِ یکسانِ دو گروه به‌مراتب بیشتر از تأثیر توانایی‌های شناختیِ غیرکلامیِ متفاوتِ آنها بر مقیاسِ روایتِ شفاهیِ داستان است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آسیب ویژۀ زبانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آسیب غیرویژۀ زبانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گفتمان روایتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2469_a159ee0e141732638d24afccf4a69ea9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
