<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>9</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Redundancies in conversation: a study on the process of producing and understanding</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی فرایند تولید و درک حشوهای گفتمانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>33</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>48</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1568</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پروانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>خسروی‌زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This article considers the function of redundancies at the discourse level of language. It examines the reason(s) why people use informationally redundant utterances.
Semantic redundancies identify unnecessary or predictable information in some stretch of language usage. From the theoretical point of view, the application of them is plausible by virtue of the principle of least effort (Martinet, 1962), and maxim of quantity (Grice, 1975). However, at the discourse level of communication, speakers use a considerable amount of redundant utterances in their daily conversation. This article is an attempt to explain the paradox.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">نظریه‌های مطرح در علم زبان‌شناسی، در سطح تولید، تراز زبان را حاصل برایند دو نیروی کمترین تلاش و بیشترین بهرة اطلاعی می‌دانند و به رعایت اختصار کلام تأکید دارند. از سوی دیگر، درک کلامِ بدون حشو، نیازمند دقت و توجه بسیار است. عدم حضور حشوهای زبانی، سرعت درک پیام را در استنباط ‌های پیچیده کاهش می‌دهد و شاهدی برای تقویت باورها، رفع ابهام‌ها و در نهایت، تقلیل جهان‌های ممکن، در اختیار مخاطب قرار نمی‌دهد. در صورتی‌که بپذیریم وقوع حشو در زبان بر خلاف اصل کم‌کوشی و شرط کمیت از اصول گرایس است، باید برای حضور حشوهای زبان تبیینی ارائه دهیم. هدف از نگارش این مقاله، بررسی دلایل وقوع حشو در امر ارتباط بااستفاده از داده های زبان فارسی است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حشو</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اصل همکاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اقتصاد زبان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حشو تولیدی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حشو ادراکی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1568_58f2d6efb940c46ef901ab962512529f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
