<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2005</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Philosophical-Islamic Viewpoint to the Problem of Meaninglessness of Religious Statements</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نگرش فلسفی- اسلامی به مساله معناداری زبان دین</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>57</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>72</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1594</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>آیت اللهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه فلسفه دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The viewpoints of Russell and Wittgenstein in the beginning of twentieth century made philosophy of language in the center of philosophical attitudes. The meaningfulness of statements was the core of attention. They made the meaningfulness of statements in ethics, religion, aesthetics and metaphysics in doubt. The logical positivists, after them, like A.J.Ayer, accounted religious statements meaningless (not untrue) by their criteria of verifiability and falsification for meaningful statements.
In this paper, the problem of meaninglessness of religious statements which is posed by Anthony Flew and the solutions in the views of Richard Hare, Basil Mitchell, John Hick and Ian Crombie will be examined. Then the problem and solutions will be evaluated. At the end, a new answer to the problem from an Islamic philosophical viewpoint will be introduced with a clarification of some problematical account of religious beliefs.
 </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با ظهور فلسفه های زبانی با آراء راسل و ویتگنشتاین، مسالة معناداری گزاره ها محور توجه قرار گرفت. با نوع نگاه تجربیِ آنها، معناداری گزاره های دینی، اخلاقی، هنری و مابعدالطبیعی محل تردید شد. پس از ایشان، پزیتیویست های منطقی همچون آیر، گزاره های دینی را با ملاک تحقیق پذیری و سپس ابطال پذیری، بی معنا (نه کاذب) دانستند. در این مقاله به طرح شبهة معناداری گزاره های دینی توسط آنتونی فلو و پاسخ های ریچارد هیر، بازیل میچل، جان هیک و یان کرومبی پرداخته می شود. سپس سعی خواهد شد از منظری دیگر، شبهه و پاسخ ها ارزیابی گردد و در نهایت، پاسخی جدید به شبهه از منظر فلسفیِ اسلامی ارائه گردد. در این پاسخ، به برداشت های غلط از رابطة خدا و عالم و صفات او که منشا این نگاهها شده است و تعمیم نابجای تجربه گرایی پرداخته می شود. در پایان، دیدگاه تصحیح شده ارائه خواهد گردید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معناداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحقیق پذیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ابطال پذیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گزاره دینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان شناختاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خداوند</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1594_78ddebcc0161f1ad2c660f46a2b481fe.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
