<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>13</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Formal and semantic aspects of modal elements
in Persian  sentences</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>جنبه‌ها‌ی صوری و معنایی عناصر وجهی در جمله‌های فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>33</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>50</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1462</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جلال</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحیمیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The way speakers react towards modal structures basically differs from the way they treat independent constructions. The most common means of expressing modality are modal components such as modal verbs, sentence adverbs and certain lexical verbs. The present paper focuses on modal constructions and aims at analyzing modality, its functions, types and degrees in modern Persian. It also makes a distinction between formal and semantic dimensions of modality in this language.
This paper demonstrates, for the first time, that xâstan ,  in addition to its role as a future tense auxiliary , can be considered a modal auxiliary which entails a proposition. This means that the modal auxiliary  xâstan  is a proper means of expressing a strong degree of modality in Persian, a fact  unnoticed in previous studies. Accordingly, one can claim that Persian benefits from all the three degrees of modality, i.e.  weak, moderate and strong. As for types of modality, the paper provides examples of all the three types, i.e. epistemic, dynamic and deontic in sentences extracted from Iranian daily newspapers.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یان زبان در برابر جملات وجهی‌العمل آنها در مقابل جمله‌های غیروجهی متفاوت است. از مهمترین و معمولترین راههای بیان جمله های وجهی استفاده از عناصر وجهی از قبیل افعال وجهی، قیود جمله، و دسته مشخصی از افعال واژگانی است. از اهداف این تحقیق، تحلیل و تبیین نقشها، انواع و درجات مفهوم وجهیت در فارسی امروز است. این پژوهش همچنین تمایز مطلوبی را میان جنبه های صوری و معنائی مقوله وجهیت در فارسی ایجاد می
پژوهش حاضر برای نخستین مرتبه، نشان میخواستن علاوه بر نقشی‌های زمان آینده ایفا می‌یله مناسبی برای بیان درجه قوی وجهیت است، به گونه‌ایی متضمن وقوع رخداد می‌شود، و این مهم از دید تمامی پژوهش‌های پیشین پنهان مانده است. بنابراین براحتی می‌ی ازهر سه درجه ضعیف، متوسط و قوی وجهیت بهره مند است. در باب انواع وجهیت نیز بایی‌های فارسی زبان، هر سه نوع وجهییت معرفتی، پویا و الزامی، در فارسی امروز بطور عادی مورد استفاده قرار می‌گیرند. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">افعال وجهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عنصر وجهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جمله‌های وجهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوع وجهیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درجۀ وجهیت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1462_b4593d40720f89e90af1398b70d5f614.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
