<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2005</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Influence of Intertextual Relations on the Interpretation of Texts</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر روابط بینامتنی در خوانش متن</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>39</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>55</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1593</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرهاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>ساسانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه الزهرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>A brief study of the theoretical foundations of intertextuality is provided. Its European sources- Mikhail Bakhtin, Julia Kristeva, Gérard Genette, and Umberto Eco- are introduced, and several Iranian sources- both in literature and /Quran exegesis- are suggested. It studies relations between internal and external elements of texts: physical context or environment and the inter-subjective world of each linguistic society or culture, and the subjective world of each text-reader might be regarded as external elements the text. Therefore, their influence over the general process of meaning-formation, which is far beyond the aggregate meaning of individual meanings of internal elements of the text plus their structures, is taken into account as well. To do this, a few external relations within different texts are exemplified and classified.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;em&gt;در این جُستار، کوشش خواهد شد تا پس از طرح اجمالیِ مبانی نظری بینامتنیت و معرفی زمینه‌های ایرانی (در ادبیات و تفسیر دینی) و اروپایی (میخائیل باختین، ژولیا کرستوا، ژرار ژنت و اومبرتو اکو)، روابط میان عناصر درون متن با بیرون از متن - خواه بافت و محیط فیزیکی&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;،&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; خواه جهان بیناذهنی جامع&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;ة&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; زبانی یا فرهنگ و جهان ذهنی خواننده &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;–&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; و تأثیر آن‌ها در شکل‌گیری معنای کلی متن و در نتیجه&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;،&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; معنایی که فراتر از برآیند معنای تک‌تک عناصر درون متن و ساختار درونی متن است، بررسی شود. در این راستا، نمونه‌هایی از روابط برون‌متنی در متن‌های مختلف ارائه و این روابط دسته‌بندی خواهد شد.&lt;/em&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بینامتن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روابط بینامتنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انواع روابط بینامتنی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1593_b4380227e8f61bf07910d0287e1110f9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
