<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2005</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Significance of Dialect Studies in Historical Linguistics</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اهمیت یافته های لهجه شناسی در مطالعات تاریخی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>115</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>127</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1581</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهرداد</FirstName>
					<LastName>نغزگوی کهن</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه بوعلی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This article examines the relation of dialectology as a discipline in its own right with historical linguistics. There are however some brief remarks on the relation of the former with other branches of linguistic studies, like those of socio-linguistics, and typology. In order to trace the connection and interrelation of historical linguistics and dialectology and their probable influences on each other, efforts are made to provide the reader with some information on the origin of dialectology and its emergence as a separate discipline. In this context a comparison is made as to the aims and methods used in both disciplines. In almost all discussions, examples are cited from Persian and other Iranian languages. Some evidences are also given to illustrate the earliest interests of Iranians in different dialects. This takes us back to as early as 12&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century. In the remaining part of the article two instances of the practical uses of dialectology in diachronic studies of Persian language are exemplified.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این مقاله ابتدا به تعریف و توصیف لهجه شناسی به عنوان رشته ای مستقل با اهداف و روش های خاص خود میپردازیم. سپس به طور اجمالی زبانشناسی تاریخی ، اهداف کلی و روشهای رایج در آن را توضیح می دهیم. این توضیحات  به ما در شناخت خاستگاه لهجه شناسی کمک خواهد کرد. آنگاه تاریخچه توجه ایرانیان به گوناگونی های لهجه ای را مرور می کنیم و سرانجام به دو نمونه عینی از کاربرد لهجه شناسی در زبانشناسی تاریخی اشاره می نماییم. در این گزارش بیشتر از منظر مطالعات تاریخی به کاربرد های لهجه شناسی توجه می کنیم و سعی ما در این است که با  به دستدادن شواهد و مثال های عینی از فارسی و لهجه های ایرانی اهمیت لهجه شناسی را در مطالعات تاریخی باز نماییم.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لهجه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لهجه شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبانشناسی تاریخی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1581_7ccb6919e0707aa6a8281aea2e1c30b5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
