<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2005</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Linguistic Approach to Translation</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رویکردی زبانشناختی به ترجمه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>75</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>90</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1579</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سالار</FirstName>
					<LastName>منافی اناری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Linguistics, commonly defined as the science of language, has close connections with many other fields of study and human sciences due to the uniqueness of language to the human species. The field of translation studies, with regard to the nature of its issues, can be considered as the closest field to linguistics, the scientific study of language. The common issues of language and translation are so many and their interconnection is so firm that in many cases they cannot be regarded as independent of one another. &lt;br /&gt;            The relation between language and translation is an undeniable fact. What is discussed in this article is the nature of this relation. Some scholars believe that any translation is based implicitly on a theory of language, and as such, translation is, in fact, an exercise in applied linguistics. Some others maintain that any theory of language is based on a theory of translation. A third view is also suggested saying that language is essentially a translation of man’s mental concepts. Based on this view man practices language and translation simutaneously in his daily life.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زبانشناسی که معمولاً به عنوان علم زبان تعریف می‌شود ، به خاطر مختص بودن زبان به نوع انسان ، با بسیاری از حوزه‌های دیگر مطالعات و علوم انسانی ارتباط نزدیکی دارد. مطالعات ترجمه را با توجه به ماهیت مسایل مورد بحث در آن می‌توان نزدیکترین حوزه به زبانشناسی یا مطالعة علمی زبان دانست . مشترکات زبان و ترجمه آن قدر زیاد و پیوندشان چنان محکم است که در موارد زیادی نمی‌توان آنها را  بی‌نیاز از هم دانست . &lt;br /&gt;            ارتباط بین زبان و ترجمه حقیقی انکار ناپذیر است . آنچه در این مقاله مورد بحث و بررسی قرار گرفته نحوة این ارتباط است . برخی از صاحبنظران بر این عقیده‌اند که هر ترجمه‌ای بطور ضمنی مبتنی بر نظریه‌ای از زبان است و لذا ترجمه در واقع تمرینی در زبانشناسی کاربردی است . اما برخی دیگر عقیده دارند هر نظریه‌ای از زبان مبنی بر نظریه‌ای از ترجمه است . نظریة سومی هم مطرح است و آن اینکه خود زبان در اصل ترجمه‌ای از تصورات و مفاهیم ذهنی انسان است و بنابراین انسان در زندگی روزمرة خود بطور همزمان با هر دو مقولة زبان و ترجمه سروکار دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازنویسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قلب ماهیّت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام لفظی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام غیرلفظی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترجمة زبانشناختی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1579_50c5a4ed468de037ce0e2e6d21605d22.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
