<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>20</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A study of code-switching according to Armenian conversations of Armenian-Persian bilinguals</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی پدیدۀ رمزگردانی با نگاهی به گفتار دوزبانه‌های ارمنی- فارسی تهرانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>103</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>120</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1880</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم‌سادات</FirstName>
					<LastName>غیاثیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حکیمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبانشناسی همگانی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Language contact occurs in various ways in multi-language societies. One of the most significant results of language contact is code switching, which refers to the use of phrases and words of more than one language within the same utterance or the same conversation. Code switching can be divided into two types: intra-sentential and inter-sentential. Armenian-Persian bilinguals frequently switch from Armenian to Persian in their Armenian conversations. This study examines two types of code switching based on 10 hours of recorded informal Armenian conversations in Tehran. In order to investigate intra-sentential code switching in this research, the model proposed by Myers-Scatton is utilized. For inter-sentential code switching the approach presented by Blom and Gumperz is employed. The results show that in Armenian conversations of Armenian- Persian bilinguals both kinds of code switching take place and intra-sentential is used more frequently.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot;&gt;در جوامعی که بیش‌از یک زبان در آنها وجود دارد، شاهد تماس یا برخورد زبان‌ها به شکل‌های مختلف هستیم. از جمله پیامدهای برخورد زبانی، رمزگردانی است که به استفادۀ متناوب از دو یا چند زبان، در یک پاره‌گفتار، گفته می‌شود. افراد دوزبانه غالباً در حین گفت‌وگو از زبانی به زبان دیگر روی می‌آورند. یکی از جوامع دوزبانه در ایران را دوزبانه‌های ارمنی- فارسی تشکیل می­دهند. مقاله حاضر به بررسی پدیده رمزگردانی در دوزبانه های ارمنی- فارسی تهرانی می­پردازد. این بررسی بر اساس داده‌هایی است که از ده ساعت مکالمات روزمرۀ ارامنۀ تهرانی گردآوری شده است. در بررسیِ رمزگردانیِ برون‌جمله‌ای، از دیدگاه بلوم و گامپرز (1972)، و در بررسیِ رمزگردانیِ درون‌جمله‌ای از مدل میرز- اسکاتن (1993، 2002) استفاده شده است. نتایج به دست آمده از تحلیل داده‌ها نشان می­دهد که در مکالمات دوزبانه‌های ارمنی- فارسیِ تهرانی به زبان ارمنی، رمزگردانی از هر دو نوع اتفاق می‌افتد و رمزگردانیِ درون‌جمله‌ای از بسامد بسیار بالایی برخوردار است.&lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان ارمنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برخورد زبانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دوزبانگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رمزگردانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1880_b824b18b26d0050a3ee8c34758b5038d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
