<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Vol. 10, No. 1, Seq. 19, Spring and Summer 2014</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>19</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start></start>
					<end></end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2076_0653e0476080a4488c2cdb5ccad6cfea.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Preferred Argument Structure in Persian</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rasekh Mahand</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghaderi</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبان شناسی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This research used the framework of Du Bois (1980, 1987, 2003 and 2006) to investigate the phenomenon of ergativity and its relation to patterns of surface grammar and information flow in discourse. The corpus for this study comprised a set of narratives about a short film, as told by speakers of Persian. First the key grammatical, morphological and information states of all the full NPs in argument positions were statistically examined. After recognizing the Preferred Argument Structure in Persian discourse, which appeared as the speakers&#039; tendencies in distribution of full NPs with new information, it was concluded that the tendency resulted in a preferred pattern corresponding to the grammatical pattern of ergativity in case system. In other words, Persian speakers preferentially put the lexical arguments and new mentions in &quot;S&quot; and &quot;O&quot; positions and not in &quot;A&quot; position. Next the two other discourse tendencies i.e. Topic Continuity and Topic Animacy were examined to show that the dominant case pattern of Persian is a consequence of competition among different discourse factors. Therefor it was noted that, although the Preferred Argument Structure lead Persian in having a discourse ergative pattern, these two tendencies display a nominative/accusative,{A,S}{O}, alignment in successive clauses. Therefore it can be concluded that in discourse there is a motivation for the grammatical phenomenon of ergativity.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>19</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>22</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1757_81eb9d40b42af391b950030f09faeea6.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Fictive Motion in Persian: A cognitive approach</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mesgarkhoyi</namePart>
				<affiliation>فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Motion is a fundamental human experience and mankind, through motion simulation in mind, extends it to the other areas in which there is no movement. This simulation and extension is also reflected in  language and language users apply the elements of real motion to describe abstract motion. This paper focuses on a specific type of abstract motion, called fictive motion, from the point of view of cognitive semantics. Fictive motion refers to situations in which the state of a static entity, located in a fixed position, is described by a motion verb. In the present paper, fictive motions in Persian are examined, analyzed and explained. To this end,  a corpus of 1750 sentences was established based on the criteria defined for fictive motion components by cognitive researchers. From among them, 42 sentences which are structured in fictive motion were analyzed. The results revealed that the occurrences of the various components of fictive motion construction like Trajector and motion verb follow semantic and stylistic restrictions in Persian. Thus Persian speakers often use Trajectors with a horizontal length and motion verbs that often lexicalize path of motion</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>19</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>23</start>
					<end>36</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1759_129ef6afd04b369ee393aa435f842db7.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Impact of Outmigration and Intermarriage on the Endangerment of Azerbaijani Turkish</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Naser</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nouri</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی اهر</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Endangerment of language resources and treasures is accepted worldwide as an undeniable fact. About 90 percent of the approximately 7000 languages and dialects are predicted to lose all of their speakers up to the end of the century. Indigenous languages of ethnic minorities in an unequal battle with the dominant languages are in danger and threat. Iran is a multiethnic country and Azerbaijani Turkish with a large number of speakers is one of the most important languages in the country. However, comprehensive sociological studies which scrutinize the situation and status of this language are scarce . The researches about other languages and dialects of Iran, including Baluchi, Mazandarani, Bakhtiari, and Gilaki show that most of them are at risk of decline. Despite having a large speaker population, Azerbaijani Turkish is as well expected to face a  similar situation, and Persian as  the dominant and most prestigious language of the country,  is expected to negatively affect the current position of the ethnic languages even more than before. To test such a hypothesis, 180 questionnaires were distributed among 180 male and female respondents  who were randomly selected from different regions of the three cities of Tabriz, Ahar and Marand to answer 44 questions to evaluate the influence of factors of out-migration (migration to Persian speaking areas) and intermarriage on the endangerment of Azerbaijani Turkish. Statistical analysis of the questionnaire data suggests that these factors have had very negative impact on this language and have largely interrupted intergenerational transmission of language in immigrant families, which is the most important factor for survival and endurance of a language.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>19</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>37</start>
					<end>54</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1760_1c2d5c5254d1de1d2c4557baaede3c8c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Discourse Function of Lexical Antonymy in Persian Language</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">RezaGholi Famian</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Discourse function of lexical antonymy was initially introduced in Jones (2002). In that theoretical model, main classes of discourse functions were labeled as ancillary, coordinated, distinguished, transitive, negated, comparative and idiom. The present study attempted to examine the discourse function of antonymy across a natural corpus of Persian language. The corpus included 16 Persian texts from which 1000 sentences are extracted. Each sentence represents one antonymous pair. The findings show that from among four lexical categories, i.e. adjective, noun, verb and adverb, the adjective category outnumbers other categories in making antonymous pairs. Two Persian word-pairs ‘chap-rAst’ (left-right) and ‘bAlA-pA’in’ (up-down) proved to be the most frequent antonymous word pairs. The results showed that unlike English, Swedish and Japanese where the ancillary discourse function tops the function classes, in Persian the most frequent function is coordination. The high frequency of idiomatic function confirms the claim that a function of antnymy in Persian makes idioms and proverbs.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>19</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>55</start>
					<end>74</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1761_4ce4b23a2e955c0e82a989591aa72ab1.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Comparison of Speech Acts in Young Men’s and Women’s Persian SMSs Based on Searl’s Classification</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hosseini-Maasoum</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kahvari</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبان و ادبیات فارسی، دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>As one of the most recent and most frequently used communication media, SMS is rapidly penetrating the media culture of different communities. A linguistic/pragmatic analysis of the messages can reveal the hidden aspects of the cultural identity of different sectors of the society. Based on Searl’s classification of speech acts, the present study analyzed the speech acts in 400 Persian messages exchanged among two equal groups of men and women aging 17 to 27. The results indicated that although the order of speech act frequencies were similar in men and women, the usage rate of expressive, representative and commissive acts was higher in men than in women. In return, men used the directive act more than women did. The significance of the findings lies in the fact that a higher usage of expressive and commissive acts in women can illustrate their value-oriented and ethics-centered approach in formal interactions through SMS. Moreover, a high frequency of commissive acts in men’s SMSs can be a sign of pragmatism in their daily engagements. Due to the contextual features of the research data, declarative acts were not observed in the messages.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>19</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>75</start>
					<end>88</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1762_bd58395dc932a83f9a12ad82856cb325.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Latin Roots in Medical Terminology and Their Persian Equivalents</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jamali</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه اصفهان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Adel</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rafiei</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This study focuses on the most important Latin stems used in medical terminology and their Persian equivalents. The study was based on the importance of choosing appropriate equivalents for medical terminology, and the constants efforts made by the academy of Persian language and literature in this field. The results indicated that contrary to what some physicians believe, constructing Persian equivalents for medical terms is possible, and that due to the morphological system of Persian language, this can be done in a systematic and scientific way. Adopting a scientific approach in this area will undoubtedly lead to a more creative morphological system in Persian language</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>19</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>89</start>
					<end>100</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1763_30126646b7998ea1b52d432fa60888d5.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Comparative Analysis of Inflectional Suffixes and Prefixes of the Verbs in Gurani Kurdish and Standard Persian</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parsa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bamshadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bamshadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد آموزش زبان فارسی، دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In the present research, after analyzing inflectional structure of more than two hundred verbs in Gurani Kurdish dialect, a comparative analysis of inflectional suffixes and prefixes of  verbs in Gurani Kurdish and standard Persian was carried out. The method of this study was descriptive, analytical and comparative. The results are classified  into  two main groups: verb suffixes and verb prefixes. Verb suffixes in Gurani include 1) agreement suffixes, 2) stem-builder suffixes, 3) aspect-builder suffixes, and 4) subjunctive mood suffix. Stem-builder suffixes include suffixes for the past stem, present stem, passive stem, and causative stem. Aspect-builder suffixes in turn include suffixes for past perfect, past continuous, past perfect continuous, present perfect and present perfect continuous. Finally, verb prefixes are: 1) negative prefixes, 2) imperative prefix, 3) negative imperative prefix, and 4) subjunctive mood prefix.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>19</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>101</start>
					<end>120</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1764_531907898a90a078f36ac62eefce7e93.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>No English Title</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Talieh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zarifian</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه علوم بهزیستی و توانبخشی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn"></identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>10</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>19</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>123</start>
					<end>128</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1765_406b75d1fefda5a7d6af6ab6f0e37641.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>