<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>15</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Classifying Persian Derivational Affixes</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طبقه‌بندی وندهای اشتقاقیِ زبان فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>125</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>138</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1403</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>گیتی</FirstName>
					<LastName>تاکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>There are different ways to classify derivational affixes. This article investigates Persian derivational affixes according to the classification presented by Beard (2001). His classification is different from others in considering the affixes’ features, semantic functions, and grammatical changes. The problems and the limitations of this classification in Persian are also discussed here. Moreover, based on Beard’s theory on derivational head (which suggests that if affixes are lexical items selected for phrase structures, they should be served as heads), the derivational head in Persian is discussed together with the inadequacy of this theory. To overcome some of these shortcomings, the present study suggests at least three additional classes of derivation: Archi derivation (including several classes), semantic derivation (changing just the function) and referent derivation (changing just the reference)</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">وندهای اشتقاقی می‌توانند به راه‌های مختلفی طبقه‌بندی شوند. برد (2001( با درنظرگرفتنِ تمایزاتِ ذاتی، معنایی، دستوری و نقش‌های معنایی، طبقه‌بندی متفاوتی را نسبت‌به دیگران ارائه می‌دهد. در این مقاله سعی شده است براساس طبقه‌بندیِ برد، وندهای اشتقاقیِ فارسی به چهار گروه اشتقاق مشخصه‌ای، اشتقاق نقشی، اشتقاق انتقالی و اشتقاق بیانی طبقه‌بندی شوند و مشکلات و محدودیت‌های این‌نوع طبقه‌بندی در زبان فارسی به‌طور اجمال بررسی گردد. نتایی از ایین طبقه‌بندی برای وندهای اشتقاقیِ فارسی جامع و مانع نیست. تعدادی از وندها در هیچ‌یین چهار گروه جای نمی‌گیرند و تعدادی از آن‌ها در چندین گروه جای می‌گیرند. برخی وندها نقش&lt;span&gt;‌&lt;/span&gt;های متعدد دارند و برخی به چندین طبقۀ دستوری متعلق‌اند. بنابراین پیشنهادِ افزودنِ حداقل سه طبقۀ دیگر، به طبقه‌بندی برد، معقول به‌نظر می‌رسد: اشتقاق شامل (برای وندهای قابل طبقه‌بندی در چند طبقه)، اشتقاق معنایی (برای وندهاییییر نقش ایجاد می‌ی (برای آن‌هاییۀ ارجاعی را تغییر می‌دهند).</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وند اشتقاقی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتقاق مشخصه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتقاق نقشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتقاق انتقالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتقاق بیانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1403_8baa961551c78e168e7ec8d6ca0c89ab.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
