<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>17</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Comparison of word definition skills between children with specific language impairment and normal children in Persian - Azeri bilinguals</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مقایسۀ مهارتِ تعریفِ واژه بین کودکانِ دوزبانۀ دارای آسیبِ ویژۀ زبانی و کودکان طبیعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>27</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>47</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1380</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حوریه</FirstName>
					<LastName>احدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The goal of this study is to compare word definition skills in Persian-Azeri bilinguals with specific language impairment and normal children. Six (7-8 year-old) children with specific language impairmentand 12 normal children were evaluated for their word definition skills. Impaired children were diagnosed as exhibiting a significant delay &lt;em&gt;(more than one year)&lt;/em&gt; in language skills that could not be explained by intelligence deficits, hearing loss or visual impairment. We used narrative speech and specific language impairment test for diagnosis and Man Whitney and Wilcox tests for analyzing data. Bilingual children with SLI showed meaningful difference from the normal groups in structural aspect of word definition. In comparison between Persian and Azeri, the impaired children showed significant difference in structural aspect and normal children in content aspect.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از این پژوهش بررسی مهارتِ تعریفِ واژه در ۀ دارای آسیب ویژۀ زبانی و مقایسۀۀ طبیعی است. در ای7 تا 8 سالۀ دوزبانۀ (آذری – فارسی) با آسیب ویژۀ زبانی و 12ی سنی و زبانی از لحاظ مهارتِ تعریفِ واژه بررسی شدند. داشتن تأخیر زبانییی، بینایی و هوشی از معیارهای ورود به پژوهش بودند. برای تشخیص آسیب از آزمون رشد زبانی، آزمون آسیب ویژۀ زبانی و نمونۀ گفتار پیوسته و برای مقایسۀ مهارتِ تعریفِ واژه، بین گروه‌ها، از آزمون من‌ویتنی و ویمبتلا در جنبۀ ساختاری، نسبت به همتایان سنی و زبانی تأخیر معناداری داشتند و در مقایسۀ بین زبان فارسی و آذریۀ ساختاری و گروه‌های شاهد در جنبۀ محتوایی تفاوت معنادار داشتند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آسیبِ ویژۀ زبانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دوزبانگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مهارتِ تعریفِ واژه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1380_ab8c6c913f4279f8ad5ceaaf6e794041.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
