<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>24</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>30</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Analysis of the Development of Grammatical Cohesion in persian-Speaking Students’ Written Discourse</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رشد ابزارهای انسجام دستوری در گفتمان نوشتاری دانش‌آموزان فارسی‌زبان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>45</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>72</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2468</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آتوسا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رستم بیک</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امین</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاجی رضایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>عاصی</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهسا</FirstName>
					<LastName>پهلوان زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;span&gt;This research aims at analyzing and comparing the development of grammatical cohesive devices (reference, conjunction, ellipsis and substitution) in Persian-speaking students’ written discourse at primary level (9 to 12 years old) according to logical meta-function introduced in Halliday and Matthiessen’s systemic functional grammar (2004),  by using a descriptive analytical method. 45 students (boys) studying at primary school (4th, 5th and 6th grades) in 2014-15 were selected through random-sampling. Two written tests in the form of picture stories were administered for gathering data from their writings. Frequency, percentage and pattern of development of using grammatical cohesive devices were compared in seeking the answer to the question of how age affects the frequency and the variety of grammatical cohesive devices. The frequency of grammatical cohesive devices among the 4th, 5th and 6th grade students was 1285, 1866, 2198 respectively. So the use of grammatical cohesive devices proved to increase in higher grades. Based on the Kruskal–Wallis test, the differences were significant (p≤ 0/05). The distribution of different cohesive devices showed some changes as the grades moved higher. In addition, more sophisticated devices were noticed . Personal references were the most and comparative references were the least frequent devices in the category of reference. In conjunction, additive, adversative, spatio- temporal and causal- conditional conjunction were the most and the least frequent ones. In ellipsis and substitution, nominal phrase deletion was the most, and verb phrase deletion was the least frequent one. The percentage of different devices were as follows: reference (62%), conjunction (22%), ellipsis and substitution (16%).&lt;/span&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی رشد گفتمانی در کودکان، به بررسی کاربرد ابزارهای انسجام دستوری (ارجاع، حرف ربط، حذف و جانشینی) در&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;AR-SA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;روایت‌های نوشتاری دانش‌آموزان فارسی‌زبانِ پایه‌های چهارم، پنجم و ششم ابتدایی (12-9ساله) در چارچوب دستور نقش‌گرای نظام‌مندِ هلیدی و متیسن (2004) می‌پردازد. گردآوری داده به‌شیوۀ میدانی و تحلیل مبتنی بر روشِ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;توصیفی- تحلیلی است. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;AR-SA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;نمونۀ آماری&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;45 دانش‌آموز پسر یک مدرسۀ دولتی در تهران در سال تحصیلی 94-93&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;AR-SA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;است.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;با استفاده از دو داستان مصوّر، در مجموع 90 روایت نوشتاری گردآوری و ازمنظرِ فراوانی، درصد و الگوی رشد تحلیل شد تا به این پرسش پاسخ داده شود که &lt;/span&gt; &lt;br /&gt;بالارفتن سن چه تأثیری بر فراوانی و تنوع رخداد انواع ابزارهای انسجام دستوری دارد. فراوانی ابزارهای انسجام دستوری در پایه‌های چهارم، پنجم و ششم، به‌ترتیب، 1285، 1866 و 2198 گزارش می‌شود. بنابراین با بالارفتن سن، کاربرد انواع ابزارهای انسجام افزایش می‌یابد و مطابق آمار تحلیلیِ کروسکال والیس این اختلاف در سطح p≤0/05 معنادار است. همچنین نسبت رخداد انواع ابزارهای انسجام با بالارفتن سن تغییر می‌کند و رخداد ابزارهای انسجامیِ پیچیده‌تر افزایش می‌یابد. در مقولۀ ارجاع، ارجاع شخصی بیشترین و ارجاع مقایسه‌ای کمترین بسامد را دارند. در مقولۀ انسجامِ پیوندی، حروف ربطِ افزایشی، تقابلی، زمانی- مکانی، علّی شرطی و در نهایت شرح‌دهنده، به‌ترتیب، بیشترین تا کمترین بسامد رخداد را دارند. در حذف و جانشینی، بیشترین بسامد به حذفِ گروهِ اسمی و کمترین به حذفِ گروهِ فعلی تعلق دارد. در پیکرۀ مورد بررسی، 62 درصد از ابزارهای انسجامیِ مشاهده شده از نوع مقولۀ ارجاع، 22 درصد از نوع حرف ربط و 16 درصد از نوعِ مقولۀ حذف و جانشینی بوده‌اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارجاع</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حذف و جانشینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حروف ربط</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رشد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گفتمان نوشتاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2468_32242296e0b7a9e8e1fe8877af47aea3.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
