<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2006</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Analysis of Passive Construction in Persian: A Cognitive Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نگاهی به ساخت مجهول در زبان فارسی با تکیه بر دیدگاه شناختی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>57</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>76</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1625</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ارسلان</FirstName>
					<LastName>گلفام</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رویا</FirstName>
					<LastName>صدیق‌ضیابری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آزیتا</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This paper is an attempt to analyze the passive construction, based on Cognitive approach. In this respect, after introducing the theoretical concepts of this approach, authors try to compare it with Generative view. Within Generative framework, a formal and abstract relation is considered between passive and active constructions through the operation of transformational rules, yet from a Cognitive perspective such a direct relation between two mentioned constructions is refused, so considering basic concepts such as: figure, ground, construal, perspective and profile, a certain event can be reported in different ways with regards to conceptualization and the manner of cognitive process in the speaker’s mind.
It is concluded that, the Cognitive approach is effective in analyzing the passive construction in Persian. So, the speaker would select the subject as the topic in active sentence, or the object in passive ones.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در زبان‌شناسی امروز سه دیدگاهِ بارز وجود دارد که هر یک از زاویه‌ای خاص به مقولة زبان و پدیده‌های مرتبط با آن می‌نگرند. این سه نگرش عبارتند از: &lt;em&gt;زبان&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;‌&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;شناسی صورت&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;‌&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;گرا&lt;/em&gt;،  &lt;em&gt;زبان&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;‌&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;شناسی نقش&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;‌&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;گرا&lt;/em&gt; و &lt;em&gt;زبان‌شناسی شناختی&lt;/em&gt;. زبان‌شناسی صورت‌گرا، زبان را همچون نظامی ساختْ بنیان و ریاضی‌گونه می‌پندارد؛ زبان‌شناسی نقش‌گرا زبان را نظامی برای ارتباط و زبان‌شناسی شناختی آن را نظامی شناختی می‌داند. بنیان‌گذاران این سه نگرش به ترتیب عبارتند از چامسکی (1957) و گیون (1979) و لانگاکر (1976).
در مقالة حاضر، نگارندگان در صدد هستند تا با معرفیِ مبانی نظری رویکرد شناختی و معرفی مفاهیم اساسی این رویکرد در تحلیل ساخت مجهول و مقایسة آن با مبانی نظری رویکرد زایشی (صورتگرا) در این مورد، تصویر واقعی‌تری از دیدگاه شناختی عرضه کنند و از این طریق به بررسی ساخت مجهول در زبان فارسی با تکیه بر دیدگاه شناختی بپردازند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساخت مجهول</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌شناسی‌شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انطباق ذهنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چشم‌انداز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طرح صحنه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضبط‌صحنه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1625_7b136343f7cfe2a97c578c1181805b23.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
