<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>25</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The homonymy of a preposition and a pronoun in Kermani spoken variant</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>هم‌نامیِ یک حرف اضافه و یک ضمیر در گونۀ گفتاری کرمان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>89</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>106</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2968</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسحاقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آزاده</FirstName>
					<LastName>شریفی مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Prepositions and pronouns are two completely different lexical categories in languages. The present study investigates the word &quot;Xod&quot; in kermani variant of Persian. This word on the one hand functions as reflexive and emphatic pronouns, in the same way as Standard Persian, and on the other hand works as Preposition, in exactly the same way as &quot;ba&quot; in standard Persian. The data related to this study have been extracted from some of the most common books related to the kerman proverbs and idioms. Since there are two words with different grammatical categories and completely unrelated meanings in this variant of Persian, they are considered as homonyms. The proverbs containing &quot;xod&quot; were divided into two groups: one in which &quot;xod&quot; works as pronoun and one in which it works as preposition. The results reveal that the origin of this homonymy is grammaticalization, a hypothesis which is in line with Hopper&#039;s first principle , i.e. layering.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">حروف اضافه و ضمایر دو مقولۀ واژگانیِ کاملاً متفاوت و مجزا در زبان‌ها محسوب می‌شوند. پژوهش حاضر به بررسی واژۀ «خود» در گونۀ گفتاری کرمان می‌پردازد که از یک سو، مانند فارسی معیار، کارکرد ضمیر انعکاسی و تأکیدی را دارد و از سوی دیگر معادل حرف اضافۀ «با» در فارسی معیار است. درواقع، با دو واژۀ «خود» در این گونۀ گفتاری مواجه هستیم. داده‌های مورد بررسی در این پژوهش برگرفته از تعدادی از منابعی است که به ضرب‌المثل‌ها و اصطلاحات رایج در گونۀ گفتاری کرمان پرداخته‌اند. از میان این ضرب المثل‌ها، مواردی که در آنها واژۀ «خود» به‌کار رفته، استخراج شده است. در تعدادی از این ضرب‌المثل‌ها واژۀ «خود» کارکرد حرف اضافه دارد و در تعدادی کارکرد ضمیر انعکاسی و تأکیدی. این واژه در کارکرد حرف اضافه در گونۀ گفتاری کرمان توزیع نحویِ کاملاً مشابهِ حرف اضافۀ «با» در فارسی معیار را داراست و در کارکرد به‌عنوان ضمیر انعکاسی و تأکیدی نیز کاملاً مشابه فارسی معیار عمل می‌کند. نتایج پژوهش حاکی از این است که رابطۀ معناییِ هم‌نامی میان دو واژۀ «خود» در این گونۀ گفتاری برقرار است و دلیل این هم‌نامی پدیدۀ زبانیِ دستوری‌شدگی در زبان‌هاست.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هم‌نامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضمیر انعکاسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضمیر تأکیدی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حرف اضافه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2968_a891a0a10e2dc93212fcf65c3a80d8af.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
