<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>20</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Meter and Rhyme as Two Criteria for Archaism of Aral Poetries: A Case Study of Meter and Rhyme in Yarsan Kalams</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>وزن و قافیه، دو معیار برای تعیین قدمت اشعار شفاهی: مطالعۀ موردی در وزن و قافیۀ کلامات یارسان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>16</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1875</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسعود</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی‌راد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اُمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>طبیب‌زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Kalams are the religious poetries of Yarsan people in Gorani. They are considered as a subset of Iranian oral poetries. In this paper we aim to investigate diversity of meter and rhyme in a number of Kalams of Yarsan. Thus by investigating some texts, for which there is not enough information of their history, we try to investigate diversity of meter and rhyme in these texts and by investigating the fixation of meter and rhyme in these kalams, determine their antiquity. Diversity of meter and rhyme gives us a methodological criterion according to which one can suggest older texts have more diversity in meter and in rhyme but more recent texts have more fixed status.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کلامات، نام سروده‌های مذهبی یارسان به زبان گورانی است که در زمرۀ سروده‌های شفاهی ایرانی قرار می‌گیرد. در این مقاله قصد داریم با بررسی تعدادی از کلامات یارسان، تنوع وزن و قافیه را در این متون بررسی کنیم. به این منظور به بررسی چند متن، که اطلاع درستی از تاریخ نگارش آنها در دست نیست، می‌پردازیم و با بررسی شیوۀ تثبیت وزن و قافیه در این اشعار، قدمت آنها را نسبت به هم تعیین می‌کنیم. تنوع وزن و قافیه در کلامات یارسان مبنایی روش‌شناختی در اختیار ما قرار می‌دهد، که براساس آن می‌توان نشان داد که متون قدیم‌تر تنوع وزن و قافیۀ بیشتر، و متون جدیدتر وضعیت تثبیت‌شده‌تری دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کلامات یارسان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گورانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وزن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قافیه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1875_943c50b04fcbcd31004762f5320593e7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
