<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>25</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Domestication in Translated Literature:  A Strategy of Resistance to Foreign Cultural Patterns</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بومی‌سازی در ادبیات امریکایی ترجمه‌شده: راهبردی برای مقاومت در برابر الگوسازیِ فرهنگیِ خارجی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>51</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>66</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2966</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مزدک</FirstName>
					<LastName>بلوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، گروه مترجمی زبان انگلیسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Domestication, as noted by Venuti, is the dominant translation strategy in powerful cultures such as the Anglo-American culture. This strategy has political, cultural and economic motivations in such dominant cultures and when applied, the cultural products of smaller countries are framed according to the cultural standards of the target culture; consequently, texts are manipulated in such a way that they seem ‘transparent’ and ‘familiar’. The present paper intends to introduce other motivations for the phenomenon called ‘domestication’. The purpose is to find other reasons behind domestication in the translated literature published under a ‘Fundamentalist’ administration in power in contemporary Iran. To achieve this purpose, the manipulations imposed by the administration on the published translations are used to study and cast light on a kind of state-imposed domestication and its motivations. Thus, the source and target texts of four American novels translated under this administration were compared and the mismatches in the translated texts were analyzed. The results showed that the world pictured in the Persian versions had been rendered closer to the social and cultural conditions in Iran, hence a kind of domestication. Therefore, it can be claimed that: 1) domestication is not confined to powerful cultures such as the Anglo-American culture; the Iranian culture, too, resorts to this translation strategy, but in a different manner, i.e. in order to maintain its sociopolitical stability and prevent the infiltration of foreign cultures. 2) domestication can become the dominant translation strategy under the influence of institutions of power and as a result of the policies adopted by those institutions. </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10.0pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: &#039;B Nazanin&#039;;&quot; lang=&quot;AR-SA&quot;&gt;بومی‌سازی، چنان‌که ونوتی می‌گوید، شیوۀ غالب ترجمه در فرهنگ‌های قدرتمندی همچون فرهنگ انگلیسی-امریکایی است. این راهبرد ترجمه‌ای در فرهنگ‌های پرنفوذ دلایل سیاسی، فرهنگی و اقتصادی دارد و در نتیجۀ اعمال آن آثار فرهنگی کشورهای کوچک‌تر در قالب فرهنگیِ بومی ریخته می‌شود و متن‌ها به‌شکلی تغییر می‌یابند که «شفاف» و «آشنا» به‌نظر برسند. این مقاله در پی آن است که به معرفی دلایل دیگری برای پدیدۀ بومی‌سازی بپردازد. هدف یافتن انگیزه‌های بومی‌سازی در زمان تصدی دولتی «اصولگرا» در ایران دوران معاصر است. برای این منظور، دستکاری‌های اعمال‌شده از طرف دولت در ترجمه‌های منتشرشده در این دوران را ابزار کار خود قرار می‌دهد تا تصویر روشن‌تری از نوعی بومی‌سازی دولتی و دلایل و انگیزه‌هایش به‌دست آورد. ازاین‌رو، متن اصلی و متن ترجمه‌شدۀ چهار رمان امریکایی که تحت نظارت این دولت به زبان فارسی ترجمه شده بودند با هم مقایسه شد و موارد تغییر در ترجمه‌ها بررسی شد. یافته‌های این پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که جهان به‌تصویرکشیده‌شده در این رمان‌ها در اثر نظارت دولت و تحمیل برخی دستکاری‌ها به شرایط اجتماعی و فرهنگی ایران نزدیک‌تر شده و نوعی بومی‌سازی در آنها صورت گرفته است. ازاین‌رو، اولاً بومی‌سازی پدیده‌ای منحصر به فرهنگ‌های پرنفوذتر، همچون فرهنگ انگلیسی-امریکایی، نیست و فرهنگ ایرانی نیز برای حفظ ثبات سیاسی و اجتماعی خود و جلوگیری از نفوذ فرهنگ بیگانه از آن بهره می‌گیرد. ثانیاً بومی‌سازی ممکن است تحت تاثیر نهادهای قدرت و در اثر اعمال برخی سیاست‌ها به راهبردی غالب در ترجمه تبدیل شود.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 14.0pt; line-height: 115%; font-family: &#039;B Nazanin&#039;;&quot; lang=&quot;AR-SA&quot;&gt;بومی‌سازی در ادبیات امریکایی ترجمه‌شده: راهبردی برای مقاومت در برابر الگوسازیِ فرهنگیِ خارجی&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
 </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بومی‌سازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دستکاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حمایت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دولت «اصولگرا»</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایدئولوژی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2966_a014d4f0661112833c06fe976b06a6e3.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
