<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1385</YEAR>
<VOL>2</VOL>
<NO>3</NO>
<MOSALSAL>3</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ساخت و صرف فعل سادة بلوچی و مقایسة اجمالی آن با فارسی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Morphology and Conjugation of Simple Verbs in Balochi and their Comparison with Persian</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در این مقاله ساخت و صرف فعل ساده در دو زبان ایرانی نو ـ بلوچی و فارسی ـ مقایسه شده است. مقایسه‌ها نشان می‌دهد که مقولات ساخت و صرف فعل ساده در بلوچی و فارسی از بعضی جنبه‌ها شبیه و از سایر نظرها متفاوت است . به طورکلی محتوای مقاله نشان می‌دهد که :
1- تعداد فعلهای ساده در بلوچی امروزی نسبت به فارسی به مراتب بیشتر و توانایی بالقوة ‌آن برای ساخت واژگان جدید از طریق اشتقاق به مراتب راحت‌تر است.
2- تفاوتها و تشابهات تا حد زیادی براساس اصول قانون‌مند زبانهای ایرانی است.
3- بلوچی بسیاری از ویژگیهای فعلهای سادة زبانهای ایرانی قدیم‌تر را نسبت به فارسی بیشترحفظ کرده و فارسی مشمول تحولات تاریخی بیشتری شده است .
4- استفادة متقابل از ویژگیهای ساختی و صرفی فعلهای سادة زبانهای بلوچی و فارسی می‌تواند در توانمندسازی یکدیگر این زبانها به کارآید.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The morphology and conjugation of simple verb compared in two new Iranian languages_ Balochi and Persian_ in this paper. The comparison indicates that the morphology and conjugation systems of the simple verb in Balochi and Persian are similar in some aspects, while different in some others. Generally the contents of the paper indicate that:

The number of simple verbs in Balochi is more in comparison with that of Persian, and the ability of word-formation through derivation is easier in Balochi than in Persian.
The differences and similarities are mostly based on the rule-governed changes of Iranian languages.
Balochi has more preserved the features of many simple verbs of older Iranian languages than Persian, and Persian has involved more historical changes.
The mutual usage of morphological and conjugational features of Balochi and Persian can be more useful for the enrichment of these two Iranian languages.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>16</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>موسی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمودزهی</Family>
						<NameE>Mousa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mahmoud Zehi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه زبان و زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه زبان و زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه سیستان و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساخت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>صرف</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فعل‌ساده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بلوچی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فارسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-   آموزگار، ژاله و تفضلی، احمد؛ زبان پهلوی: ادبیات ودستورآن؛ تهران: چاپخانه‌ی مهارت، 1373.##-   احمدی گیوی، حسن؛  ادب ونگارش؛ تهران: نشرقطره، 1378.##-   ارانسکی، ی. م؛ زبانهای ایرانی؛ ترجمه:علی اشرف صادقی، تهران: انتشارات سخن، 1378.##-   باطنی، محمدرضا؛ پیرامون زبان وزبان‌شناسی؛ تهران: فرهنگ معاصر، 1371.##-   زرشناس، زهره؛  نخستین هم اندیشی گویش شناسی ایران؛ تهران: انتشارات فرهنگستان زبان وادب فارسی، 1380.  ##-   شریعت زاده، ناهید؛ واژه نامه‌ی زبا‌‌‌‌ن‌شناسی؛ [بی‌جا]: نشرسهیل، 1374.##-   طباطبایی، علاءالدین؛ فعل بسیط فارسی و واژه سازی؛ تهران: مرکزدانشگاهی، 1376.##-   فرشیدورد، خسرو؛ &quot;ساختمان دستوری وتحلیل معنایی اصطلاحات علمی وفنی&quot;، مجموعه مقالات سمینار زبان فارسی و زبان علم؛ تهران: مرکزنشردانشگاهی، 1372.##-   کلباسی، ایران؛ ساخت اشتقاقی واژه درفارسی امروز؛ تهران: مؤسسه مطالعات وتحقیقات فرهنگی، 1371.##-   محمودزهی، موسی؛ &quot;گردآوری نمونه‌های گویشی زبان بلوچی دربلوچستان ایران&quot; طرح تحقیقاتی عرضه شده به ادارة کل میراث فرهنگی استان سیستان وبلوچستان، 1381.##-   مشکوةالدینی، مهدی؛ دستورزبان فارسی(برپایة  نظریة  گشتاری)؛ مشهد: انتشارات دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، 1374.##-   &quot;نشانه‌ی استمرار درلهجه‌ها و گویشهای ایرانی&quot;، مجلة  گویش‌شناسی، تهران: ج 1، ش 1، 1382.##-   وحیدیان کامیار، تقی باهمکاری عمرانی، غلامرضا؛ دستورزبان فارسی (1 )؛ تهران: انتشارات سمت، 1383.##-   هاشمی، سیدظهورشاه؛ سیدگنج؛ کراچی: انتشارات سیدهاشمی اکیدمی، 2000 میلادی.##-   Ahmadzai , Agha Amir Nasir Khan, THE GRAMMAR OF BALOCHI LANGUEGE , Quetta, 1984.                                                                                    ##-   Elfenbein, J., AN ANTHOLOGY OF CLASSICAL AND MODERN BALOCHI LITERATURE,  Wiesbaden, 1990.                                                                         ##-   Farrell , Tim , &quot; A STUDY OF ERGATIVITY IN BALOCHI &quot; , M.A. Dssertation, 1989.                                                                                                   ##-   __________ ,&quot; BASIC BALOCHI &quot; , an introductory course , Napl, 1990.          -##-   Jahani, Carina, &quot;BALOCHI&quot;, facts about the worlds languages, an encyclopedia of the worlds major languages ,Dublin, 2002.##-   ____________, and Korn, Agnes, THE  BALOCH AND THEIR NEIGHBHBOURES, Wiesbaden , Reichert Verlag, 2003.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>قرآن و گذر از نظم خطی: یک بررسی زبان‌شناختی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Quran Trespassing the Linear Order: A Linguistic Approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>عالمان غربی معمولاً ترتیب غیر خطی آیات را نشانی ازعدم انسجام و گسستگی متن قرآن دانسته‌اند؛ با این‌حال، به‌نظر می‌رسد طرح پرسش ِ انسجام و دیگر مفاهیم مرتبط با آن همواره یکی از ویژگیهای مهم متن قرآنی، یعنی«غیر خطی بودن» را از نظر پنهان ‌داشته است. نگارنده بر این اعتقاد است که برای آشکار ساختن این ویژگی، آیات باید در رابطه با خداوندی در نظر آورده شوند که خود را در زبان همچون گوینده‌ای که کلامش آغاز و پایانی دارد، آشکار نمی‌سازد. خالق چون بشر سخن نمی‌گوید. قرآن در این مطالعه به منزلة متنی غیر خطی و بی‌زمان در نظر گرفته می‌شود که ماهیت الهی خود را از طریق در هم شکستن مداوم بافت زمانی ـ مکانی و گذر از زبانِ خطی آشکار می‌سازد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The non-linear order of revelations is often considered by western scholars to signify lack of coherence, disunity, and fragmentariness. It seems that &#039;coherence&#039; and the related terms have veiled a significant linguistic feature, namely, the non-linear nature of revelations which could be used to make a distinction between ordinary and Quranic discourse. I will argue that to unveil the non-linearity, we should consider revelations in relation to a divinity that reveals itself in language not as an ordinary speaker whose speech is limited to a certain context, with a beginning and an end. We should not expect God to speak like a man. The Quran, thus is seen here as a non-temporal, non-linear text that reflects its divine origin, by systematically destructing the temporal context, the linear order of language and the speaking subject.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>17</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>31</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عامر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قیطوری</Family>
						<NameE>Amer</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gheitury</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه رازی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه رازی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خطی بودن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انسجام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بافت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قرآن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تکرار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>- ابوزید، نصرحامد؛ معنای متن: پژوهشی در علوم قرآن؛ ترجمه مرتضی کریمی‌نیا؛ تهران: طرح نو، 1380##ـ ارکون، محمد؛ قرآن را چگونه بخوانیم؟؛ ترجمه دکتر حامد فولادوند؛ تهران: مؤسسه مطبوعاتی عطایی، 1362##ـ بازرگان، عبدالعلی؛ نظم قرآن؛ تهران: قلم، 1372##ـ خرم شاهی، بهاءالدین؛ قرآن کریم (ترجمه فارسی)؛ تهران: نیلوفر و جامی؛ 1376##ـ سوسور، فردینان‌دو؛ دوره زبان‌شناسی عمومی؛ ترجمة کوروش صفوی؛ تهران: هرمس، 1378## ـ سیوطی، جلال‌الدین عبدالرحمن؛ الاتقان فی علوم القرآن؛ جلد دوم؛ ترجمة سید مهدی حائری قزوینی؛ تهران: امیر کبیر، 1963##ـ زرکشی، بدرالدین؛ البرهان فی علوم القرآن؛ بیروت: دارالمعرفه؛ چ3، 1977##- Adams, Charles J. &quot;Qur’an: The Text and Its History&quot;  in The Encyclopedia Of Religion Vol. 12, 1987, pp. 157-176.##- Arberry, A. J., The Koran Interpreted. New York, Macmillan Publising Company, 1955##- Barthes, R. “The Death of the Author”, in Modern Criticism and Theory, ed. David Lodge,London and New York, Longman, 1988##- Brown G. and Yule G. Discourse Analysis, Cambridge University Press, 1983##- Derrida, J. Of Grammatology trans. Gayatri C. Spivak, Baltimore and London, John Hopkins University Press,1974##- Derrida, J. Writing and Difference , trans. Alan Bass, London, Routledge and Kegan,1978##- Gadamer, Hans-George  Truth and Method , trans. Gartrett Barden and John Cumming, New York, Shead and Ward,1980##- Halliday, M. A. K. and Hasan, R. Cohesion in English, London, Edward Arnold, 1978.##- Harland, R. Superstructuralism: The philosophy of structuralism and post-structuralismLondon, Routledge, 1987.##- Hasan, R., Linguistics, Language and Verbal Art, Oxford, Oxford University Press, 1985.##- Levinson, Stephen C. Pragmatics, Cambridge University Press, 1983.##- Mir, M. &quot;The Qur&#039;ânic Story OF Joseph: Plot, Themes, and Characters&quot;. The Muslim World, Vol. LXXVI, No. 1, 1987, pp. 1-15.  ##- Salehi, M. The Quran: Literary Patterns - (Un) Translatabilities, Tehran, Imam Hossein University Press,1995.##- Saussure, Ferdinand de. &quot;Nature of the Linguistic Sign&quot;, Modern Criticism and Theory ed. David Lodge, Longman, 1988.##- Watt, W. Montgomery, Bell’s Introduction To The Quran, Edinburgh: Edinburgh University Press, 1970.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی حروف اضافة مکانی در چارچوبِ شناختی: مطالعة موردی حرف اضافة «در/ توی»</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Analysis of Spatial Prepositions within the Cognitive Framework</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مفاهیمی که حروف اضافة مکانی بیان می‌کنند، از مفاهیم شناختی اولیة ما هستند؛ بنابراین حروف اضافة‌مکانی منبعی غنی برای مطالعه در حوزة معنی‌شناسیِ شناختی محسوب می‌شوند.
در این مقاله پس از مروری بر اصول رویکرد معناشناسیِ شناختی، برخی تعاریف حروف اضافه در رویکردهای سنتی آورده شده و سپس رویکرد معنی‌شناسیِ شناختی به حروف اضافه معرفی شده است . در نهایت، حرف اضافة &quot;در/ توی&quot; در چارچوب شناختی مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. در این مقاله نشان داده می‌شود رویکرد شناختی با مدد‌جستن از مفاهیمی چون طرحواره، شکل و زمینه، انطباق و ... تبیین گویاتری از حروف اضافة مکانی عرضه می‌کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The concepts expressed by spatial prepositions are among our basic cognitive concepts and hence spatial preposition are considered a rich resource of study in cognitive semantics.
In this paper, after a review of the principles of cognitive semantics, some of the definitions of the category of “preposition” in traditional frameworks have been presented and then the cognitive semantic approach towards prepositions has been introduced. Finally the Persian preposition “dar/tooye” has been studied within the cognitive semantic frame.
It is shown that the cognitive approach presents a more illustrative explanation of spatial prepositions, due to its notions of schemata, figure, ground, construal, etc.
 
 </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>33</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>46</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ارسلان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گلفام</Family>
						<NameE>Arsalan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Golfam</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی گروه زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی گروه زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه تربیت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>golfamarsalan@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فاطمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یوسفی‌راد</Family>
						<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Yussefi Rad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری زبان‌شناسی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>معنی‌شناسیِ شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حروف اضافه مکانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>معنی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-   خطیب رهبر، خلیل؛ دستور زبان فارسی: کتاب حروف اضافه و ربط؛ تهران: سعدی، 1367##-   صفوی، کورش؛ درآمدی بر معنی‌شناسی؛ تهران: حوزه هنری، 1379##-   ناتل خانلری، پرویز؛ دستورزبان فارسی؛ تهران: توس، 1377##-   همایونفرخ، عبدالرحیم؛ دستور جامع زبان فارسی؛ تهران: علمی، 1364##-   Achord, Michel, Cognitive Grammar, International Encyclopedia of Linguistics, Edital by Frawley, William, Oxford University press, 2003##-   Bussmann, Hadumod, Routledge dictionary of Language and Linguistics, Routledse, 1996##-   Caron, Jean, Cognitive Linguistics, Handbook of pragmatics, edited by: Verschueren, Ostman and Blommaert, John Benjamins Pub. Co. Amsterdam, 1995##-   Chierchia, Gennaro and Mc Connel- Ginet, Sally, Meaning and Grammar, An Introduction to Semantics, MIT Press, 2000##-   Cruse, william and Croft, D.A. Cognitive Linguistics, Cambridge University Press, 2003##-   Gardenfors, Peter, “Some Tenets of Cognitive Semantics.” In Cognitive Semantics, Meaning and Cognition, Ed. Allwood and Gardenfors, John Benjamins pub.Co. 1999##-   Geeraerts, Dirk, Cognitive Linguistics, Handbook of pragmatics, John Benjamin, pub. Co, Amsterdam, 1995##-   Halpelmath, Martin, “Adpositions”, International Encyclopadia of Linguistics, Ed. Frawley, William, Oxford University Press, 2003##-   Jaworska, E. “Preposition and Prepositional Phrases”, Asher Encyclopedia of Language and Linguistics, Edited by R.E. Asher, Pergamon Press, Vol.  6, P. 3303##-   Lakoff, George and Johnson, Mark. Metaphors we live by, university of Chicago prss, Chicago, 1980##-   Langacker, Ronald. Concept, Image and Symbol, The Cognitive Basis of Grammar, Second Edition, 2002##-   Lee, David. Cognitive Linguistics, An Introduction, Oxford University press, Oxford, 2001##-   Nassaji, Hossein, “Schema Theory and knowledge-based processes in second language reading comprehension”, language learning, Vol 52, Blackwell pub, June, 2002##-   Saeed, John.I, Semantics, Blackwell publishers, 1997##-   Talmy, Leonard, Toward a Cognitive Semantics, MIT press, vol 1, 2000##-   Taylor, R. John. Cognitive Grammer, Oxford University press, 2004##-   Taylor, R. john, Linguistic Categorization, Oxford University Press, 1995##- Ungerer, F. and Schmid, H.J. An Introduction to Cognitive Linguistics, Longman Pub, 1995##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بسامدنگاری و دستاوردهای آن در آموزش</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Concordancing and its Pedagogical Implications</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف مقالة حاضر معرفی بسامدنگاری به مثابه یک فناوری بدیع آموزشی است که متخصصان زبان از طریق آن به بعضی از اهداف خود در مطالعات زبانی و آموزش زبان نائل خواهند شد. تیم جانز (1991) در تعریف ساده‌ی بسامدنگاری آن را ‍جستجوی هم‌نشینی‌های لغات می‌داند. این جستجو برای یافتن یک کلمة خاص و یا یک ساختار نحوی در متن یا گنجینه‌ای از متون انجام می‌پذیرد . هدف از این جستجو تحقیق در معانی متفاوت، بافتهای متنی نحوی یک کلمة خاص است و بررسی‹ باهم‌آیی›‌های لغت را نیز شامل می‌شود.
نرم افزار بسامدنگاری که در ابتدا به مثابه ابزاری برای کمک در جستجوی گنجینه‌های زبانی تهیه گردید، وسیله‌ای است که امکان تهیة مواد آموزشی تحقیق - محور را به‌وجود می‌آورد. از این ابزار می‌توان برای بسامدنگاری متون بی‌شماری که در رایانه ذخیره شده استفاده کرد.کارکرد عمدة این ابزار استخراج فهرستهایی است که لغت یا لغات مورد نظر در آنها به کاررفته است. کاربرد این فهرستها اساس یادگیری داده- محور به تعریف تیم جانز (1991) است. مقالة حاضر به همین موضوع می‌پردازد.
یکی از دست آوردهای بسامدنگاری فراهم کردن مجموعه‌ای از متون مستخرج از زبان گفتاری و نوشتاری برای استفادة تهیه کنندگان فرهنگ‌های لغت است. این مجموعه متون را می‌توان در زمرة مطمئن‌ترین منابعی دانست که فرهنگ‌نویسان از آن در جمع آوری لغات برای تهیة فرهنگ لغت استفاده می‌کنند.در این مقاله به بعضی از موارد استفادة این دست آورد پرداخته شده است.
تا جایی که به آموزش و یادگیری زبان مربوط می‌شود، بسامدنگاری روشی است جدید در یادگیری زبان به کمک رایانه که بسیاری از مشکلات موجود را بر طرف می‌کند. به خصوص مشکلاتی را که در زمینة کاوش در زبان معیار وجوددارد. در این مقاله چند مثال از تمرینهایی که از طریق آن زبان آموزان اطلاعات فراوانی در مورد یک لغت خاص در زبان مورد فراگیری به دست می‌آورند داده شده است. برخی اطلاعات حاصل از این کاوش عبارت است از: معانی لغات، الگوهای نحوی‌ای که لغت در آنها ظاهر می‌شود وهمچنین با هم‌آیی‌های لغت.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The purpose of this article is to introduce concordancing as an innovative educational technology with which language practitioners may reach some of their goals in their language studies and language teaching. Concordancing ,as defined by Tim Johns (1991),  is “researching the company that words keep ”.The aim of such kind of research is to investigate different aspects of a particular word like different meanings, grammatical contexts  in which it is used, and other words with which  it collocates.
Concordancing software is a tool that allows for the creation of discovery-based and exploratory learning materials. Its basic function is to extract lists with sample contexts of any word or structure being searched for. Such lists can then be used as a basis for what Tim Johns (1991) refers to as Data-Driven Learning (DDL).This article tries to elaborate on the issue.
One of the implications of concordancing is to provide dictionary compilers with large collections of texts drawn from both written and spoken language. These collections of texts can be the most reliable sources from which lexicographers can obtain their data for compiling a dictionary
As far as language teaching and language learning are concerned, Concordancing as a new method of Computer Assisted Language Learning(CALL) may solve a large number of practical problems particularly in the area of exploiting authentic resources. The present article gives some practical exercise examples through which language learners may learn a lot about any given word in the language. Word meanings, grammatical patterns in which a given word may appear, and word collocations are some pieces of information obtained from these kinds of exercises.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>47</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>60</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهرداد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سپهری</Family>
						<NameE>Mehrdad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sepehri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شهرکرد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شهرکرد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بسامدنگاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گنجینه‌های زبانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اصالت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>باهم‌آیی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>یادگیری داده ـ محور</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-   Aston, Guy, &#039;Corpora in language pedagogy: matching theory and practice&#039; in G. Cook and B. Seidlhofer (Eds.) Principle and practice in Applied Linguistics: Studies in honour of H.G. Widdowson (Oxford University Press, 1955, pp. 257-270).##-   Brown,H.Douglas, Teaching by Principles:An Interactive Approach to Language Pedagogy,Second Edittion.Addison Wesley Longman,Inc, 2001##-   Buttler,J. Cloze procedures and concordances:The advantages of discourse level authenticity in testing expectancy grammar, 1990, System 19,1/2:29-38.##-   Dudley-Evans,T. English for specific purposes.In Ronald Carter &amp;David Nunan (Eds.) The Cambridge Guide to Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages.Cambridge University Press, 2001.##-   Francis.G and Sinclair,J. I Bet He Drinks Carling Black Label: A Reposte to Owen on Corpus Grammar.Applied Linguistics.Volume 15,Issue 2, 1994.##-   Gledhill,C. The discourse function of collocation in research article introductions.English for Specific Purposes 19, 2000, 115-136.##-   Harmer,J. How to Teach English.Pearson Education Ltd.London, 1998.##-   Harmer,J. The Practice of English Language Teaching,3rd edition,Pearson Education Ltd in (AELL) Journal,vol 6#2, 2001, pp.2 - 10.##-   Higgins,J. &amp; Johns,T. Computers in language learning.Reading,MA:Addison Wesley, 1984.##-   Hunt,A &amp; Beglar,D. Current Research and Practice in Teaching Vocabulary. In Jack C. Richards &amp; Willy A.Renandya (eds.)Methodology in Language Teaching:An Anthology of Current Practice.Cambridge University Press, 1991.##-   Ilse,W-R Concordancing in Vocational Training.In Johns,Tim &amp;Philip King (Eds.) Classroom Concordancing,ELR Journal 4,University of Birmengham, 1991, pp.1-16.##-   Jackson,H.  Lexicography:An Introduction.Routledge, 2002.##-   Johns,T. Whence and Wither Classroom Concordancing? In Bongaerts,Theo et al. (Eds.) Computer Applications in Language Learning.Foris, 1988.##-   Larsen-Freeman,D. Grammar.In Ronald Carter and David Nunan (Eds.) The Cambridge Guide to Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages.Cambridge University Press, 2001.##-   Lewis,M. Implementing the Lexical Approach.Hove.Language Teaching Publications, 1997.##-   Maftoon,Parviz, Let’s Take a Break.In Roshd ELT Journal.No.67,Vol.17, 2003.##-   McDonough, Steven H. Psychology in Foreign Language Teaching,second edition.London.Unwin Hyman, 1986.##-   Mills,D.&amp;Salzmann,A. Grammar Safari (on line) Intensive English Institute DEIL Lingua Center,University of Illinois, 1998.##-   Mpartusa,Cynthia,Alison Love,and Andrew Morrison Bringing Concord to the ESP Classroom.In Johns,T.&amp;Philip King (Eds.) Classroom Concordancing,ELR Journal 4.University of Birmengham, 1991, pp.115-134.##-   Nunan,David, Second Language Teaching and Learning.Boston,MA:Heinle and Heinle, 1999.##-   Oller,J.W. Evidence for a General Language Proficiency Factor:An Expectancy Grammar.Die Neuerren Sprachen, 1976, pp. 165-174.##-   Owen,C. Corpus-Based Grammar and the Heineken Effect:Lexico-grammatical Description for Language Learners.Applied Linguistics,Volume 14,Issue 2:June 1993.##-   Richards,Jack,C. Postscripts: The ideology of TESOL. In Carter,R. and Nunan,D.##-   (Eds.) Teaching English to Speakers of Other Languages.Cambridge University Press, 2001, pp. 213-217.##-   Ruschoff,Bernd,(1999) Data-Driven Learning: The idea. Internet document on www.ecml.at/projects/voll/rationale_and_help/booklets/resources/menu_booklet_ddl.htm##-   Sinclair,J. (Eds.) Collins COBUILD English Grammar.London.Collins, 1990.##-   Skeehan,P. ESP teachers,Computers and Resarch.In ELT documents112-The ESP teacher Role.development and prospects.London:The British Council, 1981.##-   Stevens,V.  Concordance-based vocabulary exercises: A viable alternative to gap fillers. In Johns,T. and King,P. (Eds.) Classroom Concordancing: ELR Journal 4 pp. 47-63. University of Birmengham:  Centre of English Language Studies, 1991a.##-   Stevens, V. Classroom Concordancing: Vocabulary materials derived from relevant, authentic text. English for Specific Purposes Journal 10: 34-46, 1991b.##-   Stevens,V. Concordancing with Language Learners:Why?When?What?##-   Published in CAELL Journal,Vol 6#2, 1995, pp.2-10.##-   Widdowson,H.G. Explorations in Applied Linguistics. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1979.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>رویکرد حوزه‌ای به ذهن و زبان از منظر عصب‌شناسی و زبان‌شناسی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Modularity Approach to Language and Mind from Neurological and Linguistic Point of View</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در این مقاله رویکرد حوزه‌ای به زبان، هم‌آن‌گونه که در زبان‌شناسی نظری به آن نگریسته شده و هم به طریقی که در بررسیهای عصب‌شناختی به آن توجه شده، مورد بررسی قرارگرفته است و با استفاده از داده‌های به‌دست آمده از بررسی بیماران مبتلا به آفازی و همچنین روشهای تازه‌ای که در سالهای  اخیر برای مشخص کردن چگونگی عملکرد مغز به هنگام فعالیتهای زبانی متداول شده، به نقد این رویکرد پرداخته شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In this paper the modularity approach to language and mind has been studied from two points of view; neurology and linguistics.
It has been shown that there are some criticisms on this approach by using the data gained from the study of aphasics and the new neuroimaging techniques used in the recent 17 years to determine the places which are activated in the brain and the ways these places act through the language tasks. The results show that we need to be very careful to accept the modularity approach, at least in the way that it has been presented in the classic model.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>61</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>73</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شهلا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شریفی</Family>
						<NameE>Shahla</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sharifi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رویکرد حوزه‌ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پردازش زبان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تصویربرداری عصبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آفازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-   دبیرمقدم، محمد؛ زبان‌شناسی نظری: پیدایش و تکوین دستور زایشی؛ تهران: سخن، 1378.##-   نجل رحیم، عبدالرحمن؛ &quot;ریشه‌های نوروبیولوژیکی معناشناسی در زبان&quot;، مجموعه مقالات سومین کنفرانس زبان‌شناسی؛  1374؛  صص 266 ـ 261.##-   نعمت زاده، شهین؛ &quot;ساختار پیمانه‌ای ذهن&quot;، تازه‌های علوم شناختی، س 1، ش 1، 1378. ##-   Grensbacher,M.A and D.Hargreave.&#039;The Privilege of Primacy: Experimental Data and Cognitive Explanations&#039;. In D.L.Payne(ed.). Pragmatics of Word Order Flexibility. John Benjamins Publishing Company, 19992, pp.120-135.##-   Obler, Loraine K. and Kris, Gjerlow. Language and the Brain, Cambridge University Press, 1999.##-   Smith, Michael Sharwood.&#039; Language modules and bilingual processing&#039;, In Ellen Bialystok(ed.), Language  Processing in Bilingual Children, Cambridge University  press, 1991.               ##-   Stowe, Laurie A. and Marco, Haverkort and Frans, Zwarts. &#039;Rethinking the neurological basis of language&#039;, Lingua, Vol. 115, Issue 7, 2005, PP.997-1042.    ##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مقدمه‌ای بر روش کیفی نظریه‌سازی داده‌بنیاد</TitleF>
				<TitleE>An Introduction to Grounded Theory</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>معرفی و بررسی روشهای تحقیق، از جملة مهمترین موضوعاتی است که در مجلات علمی ـ پژوهشی قابل طرح است. با توجه به رویکرد علوم انسانی ـ اجتماعی به روشهای کیفی پژوهش و نیز جایگاه ویژة روش کیفی نظریه‌سازی داده بنیاد، این مقاله به بررسی این روش می‌پردازد. در این مقاله سعی شده است نه فقط تکنیکهای مورد استفاده در این روش معرفی گردند، بلکه جایگاه معرفت‌شناسی آن نیز مورد بررسی قرار گیرد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>This paper is an attempt to introduce Grounded Theory (Glaser and Strauss 1967; Glaser 1992), which is among the most important qualitative research traditions. It will not only refer to techniques used in this method, but it will also analyse its underlying epistemological orientations (Schwandt 2000; Schweizer 1998). It will mainly focus on two different version of Grounded Theory, namely the positivist and the social constructivist (Charmaz 2000). Finally, it will situate grounded theory within the social turn movement (Gee 2000) in the social sciences / humanities and will argue for its application in a number of sociolinguistic areas of research.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>75</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>86</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مصطفی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسرتی</Family>
						<NameE>Mostafa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hasrati</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روش تحقیق</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظریه‌سازی داده‌بنیاد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قوم‌نگاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>معرفت‌شناسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پوزیتیویزم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جمعی‌ساخت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-   Agar, M. The professional stranger: An informal introduction to ethnography. San Diego and London: Academic Press, 1996.##-   Charmaz, K. The grounded theory method: An explication and interpretation. In Glaser, B. (Ed.) More grounded theory methodology. Mill Valley; CA: Sociology Press, 1994:  95-115.##-   Charmaz, K. Grounded theory: Objectivist and constructivist methods. In Denzin, N.K., and Lincoln, Y.S. (Eds.) Handbook of qualitative research. London: Sage, 2000.##-   Charmaz, K.The grounded theory method: An explication and  interpretation. In Glaser, B. (Ed.) More grounded theory methodology.Mill Valley; CA: Sociology Press, 1994:  95-115.##-   Charmaz, K. Grounded theory: Objectivist and constructivist methods. In Denzin, N.K., and Lincoln, Y.S. (Eds.) Handbook of  qualitative research. London: Sage, 2000.##-   Einstein, A. Essays in science. New York: The Philosophical  Library, 1934.##-   Gee, J. P. The new literacy studies. In Barton, D., Hamilton, M., and Ivanic, R. (Eds.) London and New York: Routledge, 2000.##-   Glaser, B. G. Basics of grounded theory analysis. Mill Valley, CA, Sociology Press, 1992.##-   Glaser, B.G., and Strauss, A.L. (1967). The discovery of grounded theory: Strategies for qualitative research. Chicago: Aldine, 1967.  ##-   Griffiths, M. Educationa research for social justice. Buckinghan, Philadelphia: Open university press, 1998.##-   Haddan, S.C., and Lester, M. Grounded theory methodology as a  resource for doing ethnomethodology. In Glaser, B. (Ed.) More  grounded theory methodology. Valley, CA: Sociology Press, 1994: 159 - 180.##-   Hammersley, M. What&#039;s wrong with ethnography? London and New York: Routledge, 1992.##-   Hasrati, M. Legitimate peripheral participation and supervising Ph.D. students. Studies in Higher Education Vol 30, No. 5.2005. pp. 557 - 570.##-   Lave, J., and Wenger, E. Situated learning: Legitimate peripheral  participation. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1991.##-   Latour, B., and Woolgar, S. Laboratory life: The social construction of scientific acts. Beverly Hills, London: Sage publication, 1979.##-   Schweizer, T. Epistemology: The nature and validation of epistemological knowledge. In Bernard, H. Russell (ed.). Handbook of Methods in Cultural Anthropology. Walnut Creek, CA: Altamira Press, 1998.##-   Stern, P. N. Grounded theory methodology: Its uses and processes In Glaser, B. (Ed.) More grounded theory methodology. Mill Valley: CA: Sociology Press, 1994: 116-126.##-   Wiliam, D. A framework for thinking about research in education. Paper Presented in Research Training Workshop for PhD Students at  King’s College London. October 1999.##-   Wolcott, H. Transforming qualitative data: Description, analysis and Interpretation. London: Sage, 1994.##-   Wenger, E. Communities of practice. Cambridge: Cambridge  University Press, 1998.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>پیشینة درمانگری در سنّت هند و اروپایی، ژرمنی و ایرانی بر اساس شواهد زبان شناختی و اساطیری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>An Indo-European, German and Iranian Healing Tradition on the basis of Linguistic and Mythological Evidences</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>این مقاله به بررسی تاریخچة درمانگری در طب هند و اروپایی، ژرمنی و ایرانی بر اساس شواهد زبان‌شناختی و اساطیری می‌پردازد. آدالبرت کوهن دانشمند آلمانی دربارة طب سنتی ژرمنی و بر اساس کتاب مرزه‌برگ ژرمنی و مقایسة آن با هندی ودایی (آتهاروودا) دربارة به‌کارگیری طلسم برای مداوای بسیاری از بیماریها مقالة مفصلی عرضه کرد. او بیشتر بیماریهای مداوا شده با طلسم و جادو را  بیماریهای حیوانات می‌دانست. ضمناً پی برد که آنها تعداد بیماریها را به صورت ارقامی با یکان و دهگان یکسان می‌شماردند؛ مثلاً 55، 77، 99 و ... همچنین علت بیماریها را حلول روح شر در بدن شخص بیمار می‌پنداشتند. سه دانشمند دربارة طب هند و اروپایی مقاله نوشته‌اند: بنونیست، یان پوول و دومزیل.
طبق نظریة بنونیست بر اساس شواهد زبان‌شناختی در دورانی بسیار قدیم هند و اروپاییان دارای مهارتهایی برای درمان بیماریها بودند و این سنت درمانگری برای شخصِ درمانگر، توانایی به همراه می‌آورد. پوول اعتقاد دارد طب هند و اروپایی بیشتر یک پدیدة اجتماعی، دینی و اسطوره‌ای بوده تا یک واقعة علمی و برای بازسازی آن دوران از اساطیر ودایی بهره می‌جوید. رسالة دومزیل بر اساس خویشکاریهای سه‌گانة سنت هند و اروپایی است. دربارة طب در ایران باستان در ادبیات پهلوی و سنت فلسفی -  اخلاقی ایرانی به طور مشروح صحبت شده است. در ایران باستان، سلامت در نتیجة اعتدال امزاج چهارگانه در بدن و بیماری بر  اثر به هم خوردن این اعتدال به وجود می‌آید. در اوستا سه نوع راه درمان عرضه شده است: 1- با کارد ، 2- با گیاهان دارویی و 3- با کلام جادویی (مانتره).
در زادسپرم و بندهشن نیز به طور مفصل دربارة سلامت مزدیسنان و چگونگی تأیید پزشک برای درمانگری بحث شده است. همچنین آناتومی بدن در این آثار تشریح می‌شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>This paper studies the history of healing tradition in Indo- European, German and Iranian Medicine on the basis of Mythology and Linguistics. Three different scientists have written article due to this point of view.
According to Benvéniste Indo-Europeans were able to heal the diseases and the healer had a great power. Puhvel claims that indo – European medicine was more a social, religious and mythological Phenomenon and was not considered as a science.
Dumézil&#039;s observation that Indo-European medicine functions in the third estate and paradigmatically consists of three parts provides a theoretical framework for deeper analysis of individual systems of healing in Indo-European cultures.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>87</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>98</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پریسا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>درخشان مقدم</Family>
						<NameE>Parisa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Derakhshan Moghaddam</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان‌شناسی تاریخی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هند و اروپایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ژرمنی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ایرانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هندی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ودایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان‌شناسی تطبیقی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-   ایونس، ورونیکا؛ شناخت اساطیر هند؛ ترجمه باجلان فرخی؛ تهران: اساطیر، 1373.##-   شایگان، داریوش؛ ادیان و مکتبهای فلسفی هند؛ تهران: امیرکبیر، 1375.##-   Benvéniste, Emile; “La doctrine médicale des Indo-Européen”, Revue de l’histoire des religions, 130 (1945) 5-12.##-   Dumezil Georges, “La médecine et les trois fonctions”, Magazine littéraire, 229 (1986), 36-39.##-   Forrest, E. Clements, Primitive Concepts of Disease (Berkeley, University of California Press, 1932), and Henry E. Sigerist, A History of Medicine, Vol. 1 : Primitive and Archaic Medicine; New York : Oxford University Press, 1951.##-   Gignoux, Philippe, “Health &amp; Medicine in Ancient Iran”, in: SOAS.##-   Kuhn, Adalbert “Indische und germanische Segensspruche”, Zeistschrift fur Vergleichende Sprachforschung, vol. 13 (1864), 49-74, 113-157). Hereafter: IGS.##-   Zysk, K.G. Religious healing in the Veda. With translations and annotations of medical hymns from the Rgveda and the Atharvaveda and renderings from the corresponding ritual texts; Philadelphia: The American Philosophical Society, 1985. [Transactions of the American Philosophical Society, 75.7], 72-73. Hereafter: RHV.##-   Zysk, K.G, Reflections on an Indo-European Healing Tradition, In Perspectives on Indo-European Language, Culture and Religion (1992) 321-337.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>رابطة زبان و ژنتیک و یافته‌های جدید علمی در مورد ژن زبان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Language and Genetics and the New Findings of Scholars about Language Gene</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در پانزده سال اخیر این مسئله که آیا زبان پایة ژنتیکی دارد یا خیر به شدت مورد توجه زبان‌شناسان قرار گرفته است. علت این توجه هم پیدا شدن خانواده‌ای بود که نیمی از اعضای آن در سه نسل دارای مشکلات زبانی بودند. طبیعتاً مسئلة تکرار یک بیماری در نسلهای متفاوت در یک خانواده این ایده را به ذهن متبادر می‌کند که مسئله باید مربوط به ژنها باشد. مقالة حاضر به بررسی مطالعاتی می‌پردازد که بالأخص دربارة اعضای این خانواده برای اثبات یا رد نظریة ژنتیکی بودن زبان انجام گرفته است و نتایج این تحقیقات را پیش روی خوانندگان قرار می‌دهد. با توجه به یافته‌های کنونی، با وجود شواهدی که در تأیید دخالت احتمالی ژنها در زبان آموزی وجود دارد، به نظر نمی‌رسد بتوان ادعا کرد که ژنی مختص زبان پیدا شده است؛ فقط می‌توان گفت ژنی یافت شده است که با زبان ارتباط دارد. بدین صورت که اختلال در کار آن سبب بروز برخی اختلالات زبانی می‌شود؛ اما حتی اینکه آیا این اختلالات عارضة اولیة حاصل از اختلال در این ژن هستند یا عارضة ثانویه کاملاً معلوم نیست.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In the recent 15 years the question of genetic basis of language has attracted a lot of attention, especially among the linguists who are working on biolinguistics. The reason why was that a family was found whose in the half of the members some language disorders were observed. Naturally when it’s the matter of occurrence of a case in different generations, it comes to the mind that something related to the genes should be involved in. In this paper the findings of different scholars in this case and the results we can get from these findings have been presented. Although there are some evidences which protect the idea of involving the genes in language acquisition in human beings, we can’t claim that the complicated and vital phenomenon like language can be emerged by the activity of a single gene in the human body. It can be just said that a gene has been found which has a kind of relationship with language in the way that if something goes wrong with that, some language disorders will appear but it’s not quite clear whether these disorders are the primary or secondary complication of the gene impairment.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>99</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>108</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شهلا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شریفی</Family>
						<NameE>Shahla</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sharifi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ژن زبان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نسخه برداری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جهش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انتخاب طبیعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-   دبیرمقدم، محمد؛ زبان‌شناسی نظری: پیدایش و تکوین دستور زایشی؛ تهران: سخن؛ 1378.##-   Bates, E, J. Elman, M. Johnson, A. Karmiloff-Smith, D. Parisi&amp; K. Plunkett. &quot;Innateness and emergentism&quot;, In W., Bechtel &amp; George Graham(eds.). A companion to Cognitive Science, Oxford: Basil Blackwell, 1998.##-   Chomsky, N.  Rules and Representations, New York: Colombia University Press, 1980c.##-   ــــــــــــ  . ‘Things no amount of learning can teach’. In C. P. Otero (ed.), 1983, Noam Chomsky: Language and Politics, Monteral Balck Rose, PP. 407-419. ##-   Enard, W, M. Prezeworskim, SE. Fisher, CS. Lai, V. Wrebe, T. Kitano, AP. Monaco, S. Paabo. &quot; Molecular evolution of foxp2, a gene involved in speech and language&quot;, Nature,Vol. 418, 2002, pp. 869-872.##-   Gong,X., M. Jia, Y Ruan, M. Shang, J. Liu, S. Wu, Y. Guo, J. Yang, Y. Ling, X. Yang and D. Zhang.&quot; Association between the FOXP2 gene and autistic disorder in Chinese population&quot;, Am J. Med.Genetics, 15; 127(1), 2004, pp. 113-116.##-   Hewes,G.&quot;Primate communication and the gestural origin of language&quot;, Current Anthropology, Vol.14, 1973, PP. 2-24.##-   Jenkins, L. Biolinguistics: Exploring the biology of language, Cambridge University Press, 2000.##-   Krauss,R.M. &quot;Why do we gesture when we speak&quot;? Current Directions in psychological Science, Vol.8, Issue 2, 1998, pp.54-60.##-   Lai, CS, A. Monaco. &quot;A fork head-domain gene is mutated in a sever speech and language disorder&quot;, Nature, Vol. 413, 2001, pp. 519-523.##-   Lauria, S.E. What can biologists solve? In A. Montagu(ed.), Race and IQ, PP. 42-51.NewYork:Oxford University Press, 1975b.##-   MacAndrew, A. (2003). &quot;Foxp2 and the evolution of language&quot;, available online at: www.evolutionpages.com/foxp2-language.htm.##-   Meaburn, E, PS. Dale, IW. Craig, R. Plomin.&quot; Language-impaired children: No sign of the foxp2 mutation&quot;, Neuroreport, vol. 13, 2002, pp. 1075-1077. ##-   Newburry, DE, E. Bonora, JA. Lamb, SE. Fisher, CS. Lai and et al. &quot;FOXP2 is not a major susceptibility for autism or specific language impairments&quot;, Am. J. Hum. Genetics, 70(5), 2000, pp. 1318-1327.##-   Pinker,S. The language instinct: How the mind creates  language. New York: William Morrow, 1994.##-   Vargha-Khadem, F., K. Watkins, K. Alcock, P. Fletcher and R. F. Passingham. &quot;Praxic and nonverbal cognitive deficits in a large family with a genetically transmitted speech and language disorder&quot;,  Proceedings of the National Academy of Science USA, 92, 1995, 930-933. ##-    ____________, K. Watkins, C. J. Prince, J. Ashburner, K. Alcock, A. Connelly, R. S. Frckowiak, K. J. Friston, M. E. Pembrely, M. Mishkin, D. G. Gadian, R. F. Passingham.&quot; Neural basis of an inherited speech and language disorder&quot;, Proc Natal Acad Sci USA,Vol. 95, 1998, pp. 12695-12700.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نقد و تصحیح مقالۀ محمدرضا مجیدی و المار ترنز</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Criticism and Correction of Mohammad Reza Majidi and Elmar Terners’ Paper</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف از نگارش این تحقیق بررسی نکته‌های مثبت و منفی در مقالۀ محمدرضا مجیدی و المار ترنز دربارۀ &quot;واحدهای واجی زبان فارسی&quot; در کتاب راهنمای انجمن بین‌المللی آوایی: راهنمایِ استفاده از  IPA (1999: 124-125) است. تعدادی از واج شناسان ایرانی، طی سه نشست به بحث پیرامون مسائل موجود در این مقاله پرداختند. سپس کمبودها و اشتباهات و اطلاعات غلطی که در آن وجود داشت مطرح شد و در پایان به تصحیح آن اقدام کردند. این نقد، حاصلِ مباحثِ مطرح شدۀ این سه نشست است. همچنین منابعی در نگارش این نقد مورد استفاده قرار گرفتند که در کتابنامه ذکر شده اند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The article at hand is an investigation on the positive as well as the negative points and aspects of Mohammad Reza Majidi and Elmar Ternes’ paper. The subject of the paper is about &quot;the segments of Persian (Farsi)&quot; in the Handbook of the International Phonetic Association: A Guide to the Use of the IPA, 1999: 124-125. A number of Iranian phonologists held three meetings to discuss the problems which were existed in the paper. They then, stated the shortcomings and incorrect information and at the end, they made it correct. This article indicates the results of the meetings discussions.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>109</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>118</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عالیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کردزعفرانلو کامبوزیا</Family>
						<NameE>Aliyeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kord-e Zafaranlu Kambuziya</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الفبای بین‌المللی آوایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فارسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آوانویسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>واحد واجی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-   ثمره، یداله؛ آواشناسی زبان فارسی، چاپ ششم، ویرایش دوم، تهران: مرکز نشردانشگاهی، 1380.##-   حق‌شناس، علی‌محمد؛ آواشناسی عمومی(فنوتیک)، تهران: انتشارات آگاه، 1356.##-   صادقی، علی‌اشرف؛ &quot;التقای مصوتها و ﻣﺴﺌﻠﮥ صامتهای میانجی در زبان فارسی&quot;، ﻣﺠﻠﮥ ﺯبان شناسی، سال سوم، ش دوم، 1365، صص 22 ـ 3.##-   _____________؛ &quot;عوض شدنِ جایِ تکیه در بعضی از کلمات فارسی&quot;، ﻣﺠﻠﮥ ﺯبان شناسی، سال ششم، ش اول، 1368، صص 28 ـ 23.##-   _____________؛ مساﺋﻞِ تاریخی ﺯبان فارسی، تهران: انتشارات سخن، 1380.##-   کردزعفرانلوکامبوزیا، عالیه؛ &quot;درج یا ﺣﺬف انسداد ﭼﺎکنایی&quot;، مجلۀ ﺯبان شناسی، سال هجدهم، ش اول، 1382، صص 40- 25.##-   __________________؛ &quot;فرﺁیند تضعیف در زبان فارسی&quot;، ﭘﮋوهشهای زبان شناسی ایرانی(2): جشن‌ناﻣﮥ دکتریداله ثمره، به اهتمام امید ﻃبیب‌زاده و محمد راسخ‌مهند، همدان: انتشارات داﻧﺸﮕﺎه بوعلی سینا، 1383، صص 198 - 189.##-   Catford, J.C. A Practical Introduction to phonetics, Oxford University Press, 2001, Second Edition.##-   Kenstowicz, M. Phonology in generative grammar,Basil Blackwell Ltd, 1994.##-   Ternes, E. Majidi, M.R. &quot;Persian (Farsi)&quot;, A Handbook of the International Phonetic Association: A Guide to the use of the International Phonetic Alphabet, Cambridge University Press, 1999, pp.124-125.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مفهومی نو از زبان‌شناسی کاربردی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Towards a Reconceptualization of Applied Linguistics</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>دانش زبان‌شناسی کاربردی در طول تاریخِ طولانی حیاتش زیر و بم‌های زیادی متحمل شده  است. ‌آنچه در اینجا ترجیحاً از آن به‌ نام حرکت تکاملی زبان‌شناسی کاربردی یاد می‌گردد، در سال 1940 و با دیدگاه مثبت گرایانه (پوزی تیویست) از زبان‌شناسی کاربردی آغاز شد؛ اما در سال 1960، دانش زبان‌شناسی کاربردی به سمت مثبت گرایی فراگیر گرایش یافت و دورة موسوم به الگوی قالبی توسعه یافته از میان این تلاشها سر برآورد. سومین دورة مطالعات و تلاشهای زبان‌شناسی کاربردی به دهة 70 تعلق دارد و اغلب به‌ نام رویکرد واسطه‌ای یا الگوی چند زمینه‌ای شناخته می‌شود. تحقیق فراگیری زبان دوم مرحلة بعدی تلاشها در زمینه زبان‌شناسی کاربردی را تشکیل می‌دهد. این مرحله در طول دهة 80 رواج داشت. پنجمین مرحلة مطالعات زبان‌شناسی کاربردی با عنوان ساختارگرایی در دهة 90 پدیدار گشت. بالأخره دورة پایانی مطالعات زبان‌شناسی کاربردی از فعالیتهای پساساختاریِ اخیر نشأت گرفته و هنوز هم به‌عنوان جنبه‌ای غالب که از طریق آن مطالعات انتقادی متعددی شکل یافته‌اند، مطرح است. نکته‌ای که نباید از ذهن دور داشت این است که زبان‌شناسی کاربردی یک زمینة علمی مسئله محور و مبتنی بر جهان واقع است. آخرین نکته اینکه مفهوم مطالعات انتقادی به‌ویژه زبان‌شناسی کاربردی انتقادی، مسئله‌ای است که مستلزم بررسی عمیق‌تر و تفکر بیشتر است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The field of applied linguistics has witnessed several ups and downs during its long history of existence. What is preferably referred to here as the evolutionary movement of applied linguistics, commenced in the 1940s and with the positivist view of applied linguistics. In the 1960s, however, the field was inclined towards extensive positivism and the phase of extended paradigm model arose out of these attempts. The third phase of applied linguistics studies and endeavors belongs to 1970s and is mostly referred to as the mediatory approach or multi-disciplinary model. Second language acquisition research constitutes the next stage of applied linguistics attempts. This phase was dominant during the 1980s. The fifth step of applied linguistics studies is that of constructivism coming to the scene in 1990s. Finally, the last era of applied linguistics studies emerged out of the recent post-structuralist attempts and it is still the dominant aspect through which several critical studies have been configured. A point to be borne in mind is that applied linguistics is a problem-based and real-life oriented discipline. Last but not the least, the concept of critical studies, especially critical applied linguistics is a matter requiring to be probed with more depth and contemplation.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>119</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>127</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پرویز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>علوی‌نیا</Family>
						<NameE>Parviz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Alavinia</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان‌شناسی کاربردی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زبان‌شناسی کاربردی انتقادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پوزیتیویست</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مثبت‌گرایی ِفراگیر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رویکرد واسطه‌ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحقیق فراگیری زبان دوم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساختارگرایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پساساختارگرایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-   Corder, S. P. Introducing Applied Linguistics. Harmondsworth. Penguin Books,1973.##-   Davies, A. An Introduction to Applied Linguistics: From Practice to Theory. Edinburgh: The Edinburgh University Press, 1999a.##-   Davies, A. Ethics in Educational Linguistics. In B. Spolsky (ed.) Concise Encyclopedia of Educational Linguistics. Amsterdam, 1999b: Elsevier, 21-25.##-   Fairclough, N. Critical Discourse Analysis. London: Longman, 1995.##-   Farhady, H. Unpublished Presentation on the Scope of Applied Linguistics. ICOLLT Seminar. Tarbiat Modarress University, Tehran, Iran, 2003.##-   Halliday, M.A.K., A. McIntosh, and P. Strevens. The Linguistics Sciences and Language Teaching. London: Longman, 1964.##-   Kaplan, R. The Oxford Handbook of Applied Linguistics. Oxford University Press, 2002.##-   Kaplan, R.B. (ed.). On the Scope of Applied Linguistics. Rowley, MA: Newbury House, 1980.##-   Kaplan, R.B., and H.G. Widdoson. Applied Linguistics: An Overview. In W. Bright, (ed.) International Encyclopedia of Linguistics. 4 vols. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1992, 1: 176-80.##-   Kaplan, R.B., et al. (eds.). Annual Review of Applied Linguistics. Rowley, MA: Newbury House, 1981.##-   Kress, G. (1990). Critical Discourse Analysis. In W. Grabe (Ed.), Annual Review of Applied Linguistics, 1990, 11: 84-99.##-   McNamara, T.F. Policy and Social Considerations in Language Assessment. In W. Grabe et al. (eds.) Annual Review of Applied Linguistics 18: Foundations of Second Language Teaching. New York: Cambridge University Press, 1998. 304-319.##-   Pennycook, A. Critical Applied Linguistics and Education. In R. Wodak and D. Corson (eds.) Encyclopedia of Language and Education. Vol.1: Language Policy and Political Issues in Education. Dordrecht, Netherlands: Kluwer Academic, 1997b. 23-31.##-   Rampton, B. Retuning in Applied Linguistics. International Journal of Applied Linguistics, 1997b. 7: 3-25.##-   Rivers, W. The Psycholinguist and the Foreign Language Teacher. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1968.##-   Strevens, P. Applied Linguistics: An Overview. In W. Grabe and R.B. Kaplan (eds.) Introduction to Applied Linguistics. Reading, MA: Addison Wesley, 1992. 13-31.##-   Van Dijk, T.A. Principles of Critical Discourse Analysis. Discourse and Society, 1993. 4(2): 249-283.##-   Van Lier, L. Apply within, Apply without? International Journal of Applied Linguistics, 1997. 7: 95-105.##-   Weideman, A. Five Generations of Applied Linguistics: Some Framework Issues. Department of Didactics, University of the Western Cape, 1996.##-   Widdowson, H.G. Coming to Terms with Reality: Applied Linguistics in Perspective. In D. Graddol, (ed.). Applied Linguistics for the 21st Century, AILA Review, 2001. 14: 2-17.##-   Widdowson, H.G. Explorations in Applied Linguistics. 2 vols. Oxford: Oxford University Press,1979 / 1984.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				