<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>12</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Electronic Name Address as Individual Identity</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نشانی الکترونیکی به‌مثابه هویت فردی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>87</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>114</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1391</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری زبان شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمی دوستان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present article reports a study which examined the essence and implication of real name, the relationship between electronic name address and individual identity, and the individual and social value of the nomination phenomenon. The assumption was that the unconscious choice of a theme of nomination partially reveals a user’s view of his/her self and his/her individual identity. To this end, the researcher developed a questionnaire consisting of 10 multiple-choice questions. Based on the results obtained from 222 respondents, 13 themes of virtual nomination were identified and analyzed with the use of descriptive statistics. The results of the study showed that the user’s choice of  name in the virtual world can, as a signifying system, provide clues to his/her psychological profile, contrary to the discourse system of the real name which is referential. On the other hand, the user’s personality can, to some extent, influence his/her choice of the virtual name. So, there are some differences in the use and choice of real and virtual names, in that virtual names entail individual and social identity of the internet users, whereas virtual names throw light on their personality.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این مقاله به بررسی چیستی و دلالت‌های “نام واقعی” و سپس نام مجازی می‌پردازد. هدف این است که با مقایسۀ این‌دو، به تفاوت‌های میان ساختِ نام مجازی و واقعی و نیز رابطۀ میان نام مجازی (الکترونیکی) با هویت فردی بپردازیم. و همچنین ارزش فردی، اجتماعی و فرهنگیِ پدیدۀ نام‌گذاریِ مجازی را مورد بررسی قرار‌‌‌ دهیم. مبنای داده‌های این پژوهش، پرسش‌نامه‌ای است شاملِ 10 سؤالِ 4 گزینه‌ای، که 222 آزمودنی به آن پاسخ داده‌اند. ازاین‌طریق، 13 الگوی نام‌گذاریِ مجازی استخراج شد. روش پژوهش، توصیفی- تحلیلی است مبنی‌بر این‌که انتخابِ هر نام‌، به‌صورتِ ناخودآگاه از سوی فرد، اشاره به نوعِ نگاهِ او به مقولۀ خود، و نیز دلالت بر بخشی از هویتِ فردیِ او دارد. درنتیجه، کارکردهای نام در دنیای واقعی و مجازی تفاوت‌هایی دارند. چنان‌که در نام‌های واقعی، نام به‌دلیلِ ملازمتِ درزمانی با فرد، بر هویتِ او تأثیر می‌گذارد، ولی در نام‌های مجازی، فرد خواسته‌های خود را به‌واسطۀ نام، مطرح می‌کند و بر نامِ خود تأثیر می‌گذارد. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نام الکترونیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نام مجازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نام واقعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هویت فردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام ارجاعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام دلالتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نام‌گذاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1391_5519445fa8a18000709692d2ccb2100c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
