<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>14</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Fundamental Frequency in Persian-Mazandarani Bilinguals</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بسامد پایۀ صوت در دوزبانه‌های مازندرانی- فارسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>79</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>95</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1450</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آتوسا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رستم‌بیک تفرشی</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>رمضانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>سازمان پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی آموزشی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract> 
The present research aimed at studying the fundamental frequency of voiced phonemes in Persian-Mazandarani bilinguals in 2007. The hypothesis was that the differences between the average of FO of voiced phonemes in bilinguals in Mazanadarani and Persian are significant. The descriptive-analytic approach was applied and no intervention was administered. The informants were 3 men and 2 women aged between 25 and 35. A test was developed by the researchers. Its content Validity was accredited by professionals in the field. The informants were asked to pronounce 57 words in Mazandarani and 57 words in Persian three times. So the voiced phonemes were studied in the beginning, final and middle positions of different words. The average of FO for each phoneme was measured using Dr. Speech software. After estimating the average of FOs for each voiced phoneme, and each informant, T-test was used to assess the significance of the differences of FOs. The difference between FOs of voiced phonemes in Persian and Mazandarani was not significant (p&gt;0/05). However,the differences between the average of FOs between men and women were found to be significant (p&lt;span&gt;&lt;&lt;/span&gt;0/05 in Mazandarani and p&lt;span&gt;&lt;&lt;/span&gt;0/01 in Persian). The null hypothesis (Ho) of the study was proved. In other words, in Persian-Mazandarani bilinguals the differences between averages of FOs in voiced phonemes are not significant, but in male and female informants the differences proved to be significant in both languages.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی بسامد پایۀ &lt;span&gt;(F0)&lt;/span&gt; واکهها و همخوان‌دار در دوزبانههای مازندرانی- فارسی و پاسخ به این پرسشکه چه تفاوتی میان بسامد پایة صوت در این زبانها وجود دارد، به انجام رسیده است. به‌ این‌ترتیب، روشِ این پژوهش به‌طور مقطعی، توصیفی، تحلیلی و غیرمداخله‌ای است. تعداد آزمودنی‌ها 5 نفر داوطلب (3 مرد و 2 زن)، و سن آزمودنی‌ها 25 تا 35 سال است. ابزار این پژوهش که در سال 1386 به انجام رسیده، آزمونی محقق‌ی و 57 واژه در زبان فارسییی آن به تأیید متخصصانِ این حیطه رسیده است. آواها در سه جایگاه آغازی، میانی و پایانی واژهها بررسی شدهاند. از آزمودنی‌ها خواسته شد تا هر واژه را سه‌بار تلفظ کنند و درنهایت میانگین بسامد پایه، با استفاده از نرم‌افزار تحلیل‌یچ،&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt; برای هر آوا و هر آزمودنی محاسبه گردید. سپس برای هر 5 فرد به‌طور جداگانه، با استفاده از آزمون تی، معناداریِ تغییراتِ به‌دست‌آمده مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. با توجه به این‌&lt;span&gt;p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  است، تفاوت معناداری میان بسامد پایه در زبان فارسی و مازندرانی مشاهده نشد. درعین‌حال، تفاوتِ میانگینِ بسامد پایۀ آوا‌ها در آزمودنی‌های مرد و زن در زبان فارسیی پس‌از بررسی نتایج، فرضیة صفر پژوهش مورد تأیید قرار گرفت. به‌عبارت‌دیگر، تغییرات بسامد پایه و انحرافِ معیار در زبان فارسی و مازندرانی در افراد دو زبانه معنادار نیست. اما تفاوت بسامد پایه در آزمودنی‌های مرد و زن معنادار است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بسامد پایه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">واکه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همخوان واک‌دار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دوزبانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مازندرانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1450_0e944e4b6430934dcf5baf52ae1f4fef.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
