<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>20</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Looking through the Lenses of (Im)Politeness at Power and Gender in Persian-Speaking Youngsters’ Novels</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نگاهی به قدرت و جنسیت از منظر ادب و بی‌ادبی در رمان‌های نوجوانانِ فارسی‌زبان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>31</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>56</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1877</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2570-6256</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract> 
The present article intends to analyze those conversations in ten Persian-speaking youngsters’ novels that are important in the development of the plots of the stories and to explore the ways power and gender influence the characters’ choices of (im)politeness strategies. Brown and Levinson’s politeness theory and Culpeper’s impoliteness theory are chosen as the theoretical frameworks. To be included in the samples, the novels should be originally written in Persian; the majority of their actions should be in dialogue form; they should have won prize(s) in the field of youth’s literature. According to chi square test the results indicate that power and politeness have a reverse relationship, i.e. the more powerful a character is, the less polite she/he becomes. In addition, female characters make more use of politeness strategies whereas male characters use more of impoliteness strategies.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر به بررسیِ تأثیر قدرت و جنسیت در اتخاذ رویکردهای مؤدبانه یا بی‌ادبانه از سوی شخصیت‌های قدرتمند و ضعیف، و نیز مردان و زنان، در ده رُمانِ برگزیدۀ نوجوانان فارسی‌زبان، بر اساس نظریۀ ادبِ براون و لوینسون، و نظریۀ بی‌ادبیِ کالپپر می‌پردازد. رمان‌های نوجوانانِ فارسی‌زبانِ منتشرشده در فاصلۀ سال‌های 1391- 1381، جامعۀ پژوهش را تشکیل می‌دهد و آثار مورد بررسی بر پایۀ معیارهای تألیفی‌بودنِ اثر، گفت‌وگومحوربودنِ داستان، مورد تأییدبودن از سوی صاحب‌نظران، و . . . انتخاب شده است. داده‌های پژوهش با استفاده از آزمون آماریِ خی دو، مورد بررسی قرار گرفته و نتایج حاصل نشان می‌دهد که قدرت و ادب رابطۀ معکوسی باهم دارند، یعنی هرچه قدرت افراد بیشتر باشد، از استراتژی‌های بی‌ادبیِ بیشتر و هرچه جایگاه قدرت ضعیف‌تر باشد، از استراتژی‌های ادبِ بیشتری استفاده می‌کنند. بر همین اساس، مشخص شد که شخصیت‌های زن، در برخورد با شخصیت‌های مرد، رفتار زبانیِ مؤدبانه‌تری دارند و شخصیت‌های مرد، بیشتر از شخصیت‌های زن از استراتژی‌های بی‌ادبی استفاده می‌کنند. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ادب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بی‌ادبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رمان نوجوانانِ فارسی‌زبان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قدرت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1877_34dc677a70f388855cfbac75c5bfe9b7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
