<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2006</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Language and Genetics and the New Findings of Scholars about Language Gene</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطة زبان و ژنتیک و یافته‌های جدید علمی در مورد ژن زبان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>99</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>108</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1619</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شهلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>شریفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه زبان‌شناسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In the recent 15 years the question of genetic basis of language has attracted a lot of attention, especially among the linguists who are working on biolinguistics. The reason why was that a family was found whose in the half of the members some language disorders were observed. Naturally when it’s the matter of occurrence of a case in different generations, it comes to the mind that something related to the genes should be involved in. In this paper the findings of different scholars in this case and the results we can get from these findings have been presented. Although there are some evidences which protect the idea of involving the genes in language acquisition in human beings, we can’t claim that the complicated and vital phenomenon like language can be emerged by the activity of a single gene in the human body. It can be just said that a gene has been found which has a kind of relationship with language in the way that if something goes wrong with that, some language disorders will appear but it’s not quite clear whether these disorders are the primary or secondary complication of the gene impairment.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در پانزده سال اخیر این مسئله که آیا زبان پایة ژنتیکی دارد یا خیر به شدت مورد توجه زبان‌شناسان قرار گرفته است. علت این توجه هم پیدا شدن خانواده‌ای بود که نیمی از اعضای آن در سه نسل دارای مشکلات زبانی بودند. طبیعتاً مسئلة تکرار یک بیماری در نسلهای متفاوت در یک خانواده این ایده را به ذهن متبادر می‌کند که مسئله باید مربوط به ژنها باشد. مقالة حاضر به بررسی مطالعاتی می‌پردازد که بالأخص دربارة اعضای این خانواده برای اثبات یا رد نظریة ژنتیکی بودن زبان انجام گرفته است و نتایج این تحقیقات را پیش روی خوانندگان قرار می‌دهد. با توجه به یافته‌های کنونی، با وجود شواهدی که در تأیید دخالت احتمالی ژنها در زبان آموزی وجود دارد، به نظر نمی‌رسد بتوان ادعا کرد که ژنی مختص زبان پیدا شده است؛ فقط می‌توان گفت ژنی یافت شده است که با زبان ارتباط دارد. بدین صورت که اختلال در کار آن سبب بروز برخی اختلالات زبانی می‌شود؛ اما حتی اینکه آیا این اختلالات عارضة اولیة حاصل از اختلال در این ژن هستند یا عارضة ثانویه کاملاً معلوم نیست.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ژن زبان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نسخه برداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جهش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انتخاب طبیعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1619_17bc1b77a55b14822756ce2c83495c94.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
