<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>14</Volume>
				<Issue>27</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Semantic-Pragmatic Study of /Ɂæra/ in Kurdish : a Cognitive Perspective</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی کاربردی-معنایی Ɂæra// در کردی از دیدگاه شناختی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>147</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>165</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">3869</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسعود</FirstName>
					<LastName>دهقان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه کردستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهناز</FirstName>
					<LastName>افشاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری زبانشناسی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد کرمانشاه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of this study was to investigate the place of /Ɂæra/ and its polysemy in Kalhori Kurdish based on the principled-polysemy approach ( Tylor &amp; Evanz 2001,2003; Evanz &amp; Tylor 2004a, 2004b; Evanz 2005,2004,2006), which presents basic and applied criteria for identifying different and primary meanings of prepositions. The study is analytic-descriptive and data-based. The data was collected from interviews with Kalhori speakers, and their originality was verified by native speakers. This study focused only on some samples for each distinct meaning due to the limitation of time and space. The research findings show that /Ɂæra/ questions the causality, as a wh-word in the initial position of a sentence or wh-in-situ and before a verb. The findings as well show that it has eight meanings and two semantic clusters, and that in the initial position, its meaning is “for”, and that when placed before a noun or noun phrase, it functions as a preposition.  A semantic network presented shows the distinct meanings of /Ɂæra/ as a preposition.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از پژوهش حاضر بررسی جایگاه Ɂæra&lt;strong&gt;/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/ &lt;/strong&gt;و چندمعنایی آن در کردی (گویش کلهری)، براساس انگارۀ چندمعناییِ اصول‌مند (الگوی چما) (تایلر و ایوانز،­2001 و 2003؛ ایوانز و تایلرa، 2004؛­b،­2004؛­ایوانز،­2004، 2006) است که معیارهای اساسی و کاربردی‌ برای شناخت معانی مجزا و معنای سرنمون حروف اضافه ارائه می‌دهد. با بهره‌گیری از این انگاره، ماهیت روش انجام این پژوهشِ کیفی، توصیفی-تحلیلی و نوع روش داده-بنیاد است. داده‌های انتخاب‌شده از مصاحبه با گویشوران کردیِ کلهری به‌دست آمده و صحت آنها نیز کاملاً مورد تأیید گویشوران بومی است که در این بررسی، به‌دلیل محدودیت حجم مقاله، به ذکر نمونه‌هایی از هر مفهوم بسنده کرده‌ایم. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که /Ɂæra/ به‌عنوان پرسش‌واژه در جایگاه ابتدای جمله یا در جای اصلی آن قبل از مقولۀ فعل، «چرایی و علت» را مورد پرسش قرار می‌دهد و همچنین در جایگاه قبل از اسم یا گروه اسمی، به‌عنوان حرف اضافه شامل هشت معنای مجزا و دو خوشۀ معنایی است که معنای سرنمون آن «برای» است. نگارنده برای واکاویِ معانیِ متمایزِ این حرف اضافه، آنها را جداگانه در یک شبکۀ معنایی ترسیم کرده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معناشناسی شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگویِ چما</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شبکۀ معنایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کردی کلهری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_3869_c76e0917f4e1ca9c5268bf5aba4f29e8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
