<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>9</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Focus Role of Cleft Constituent in It-Cleft Sentence</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نقش کانونی سازة گسسته در جملات گسسته</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>17</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>32</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1567</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>خرمایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>افسانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>شهباز</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ارشد زبان‌شناسی همگانی، دانشگاه کردستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>‍An it-cleft sentence is a construction expressing a single proposition in two clauses instead of one: a main clause containing a cleft constituent and a relative clause. Numerous works have been written on the subject within the framework of information structure. One issue under discussion relates to the information status of the cleft constituent. It has repeatedly been discussed if the cleft constituent is always the focus and hence containing new information or it can also involve old information. This paper, based on four reasons which are also supported by Persian data, tries to prove that the cleft constituent is always the focus, whether it has previously been evoked in the discourse model or not.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">جملة گسسته ساختی است که گزاره‌ای واحد را به­جای یک بند، در دو بند بیان می‌کند: یکی بند اصلی، که حاوی سازة گسسته است و دیگری بند موصولی. در چارچوب ساختار اطلاعی، آثار متعددی در باب این جملات نوشته شده است. یکی از مباحث مطرح این بوده است که آیا سازة گسسته همواره کانون جمله و در نتیجه، حاوی اطلاع نو است یا این سازه می‌تواند بنا به مدل کلامی، حاوی اطلاع کهنه نیز باشد. در مقالة حاضر، با ارائه چهار دلیل، که متکی بر داده‌های زبان فارسی نیز هست، استدلال می‌شود که سازة ‌گسسته همیشه کانون و حاوی اطلاعات نو است. چه از پیش در مدلِ کلامی آمده باشد، چه نیامده باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گسسته</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساخت دو بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازة ‌گسسته</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قضیة باز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کانون</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1567_32fdaae415100130142d09292e5eb6dc.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
