<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>17</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Acoustic analysis of Liquid sounds in Standard Persian</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی صوت‌شناختی همخوان کناری در زبان فارسی معیار</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>75</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>91</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1382</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>شکری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبان‌شناسی همگانی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ماندانا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوربخش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه الزهرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present paper studies the acoustic-phonetic characteristics of liquids ([r] and [l]) in Standard Persian. The study used 19 male and female speakers, who articulated 204 samples of each consonant in various phonetic contexts in initial, medial and final positions. In different languages, the nature of the liquids and rhotics in particular, has a great amount of variability in different phonetic contexts and may easily be affected and changed by the surrounding sounds or due to various non-phonetic reasons. Persian phoneticians have always known [r] in this language to be an apical trill that has some allophones like the tap and voiceless [r] which occurs in some specific contexts. However, the results of this study showed that Persian [r] is not a trill, but on the contrary, this manner of articulation is limited to one specific context with a very low frequency. In fact the manner of articulation of this consonant in Persian language is approximant. The other liquid ([l]) was also studied in different phonetic contexts. Formants frequencies of these two liquid sounds were analyzed and measured in initial position only.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در این پژوهش ویژگیهای صوت‌شناختی و آواشناختی یی از همخوان‌هایِ روانِ زبان فارسیِ معیار -[l]- بر اساس تلفظ 19 سخنگوی زن و مرد مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته است. به این منظور ایهای آواییِ آغازین، میانی و پایانی قرار گرفت و گوی81 نمونۀ آواییِ حاویِ این واج را تولی‌اند. ماهیت همخوانهای روان در زبان‌های مختلف به گونه‌ای‌های آواییِ متفاوت بسیار تغییرپذیرند و زیر تأثیر عوامل متعددیییر شوند. در خصوص همخوان روان [λ] تغییرات میۀ دوم بسیار حائز اهمیین تغییرات منجر به ایجاد دو شیوۀ تولیدِ متفاوت از این همخوان میشود، آنچه در سنت آواشناسی [λ] روشن و ]ɫ[ تیره نامیده میشود. در این پژوهش، علاوه بر بررسی جایگاه این همخوان در پیوستارِ روشنی و تیرگی، شیوۀ تولید آن در بافت‌های آواییِ متفاوت و همچنین ِ سازه‌هایِ اول، دوم و سومِ این همخوانِ روان نیز در جایگاههای آغازین و بیای اندازه‌گیری شده‌است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آواشناسی صوت‌شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فارسی معیار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همخوان روان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کناری‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1382_82868cad516781b66d19ab13a4e1c8b2.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
