<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>24</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>30</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Word and Phrase Stress in Persian Language: Optimality Theory</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تکیة واژه و گروه در زبان فارسی بر مبنای نظریۀ بهینگی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>20</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2466</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>راضیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>شجاعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محرم</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسلامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6811-1511</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمود</FirstName>
					<LastName>بی‎جن‎خان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present paper studies the stress pattern of Persian language at the word and syntactic phrase level and shows that in the framework of prosodic phonology lexical stress in Persian follows a consistent pattern. The lexical stress in Persian follows the phonological word stress rule (that is right-most), but in accounting for phrasal stress, reference to syntactic information and internal constituent structure of the syntactic constituent is inevitable. Head avoidance principle (Eslami 1379, 1384) clearly explains this issue. The present research therefore uses this principle for analyzing the data. This paper also examines the Optimality Theoretic (OT) grammar of phonological word, clitic group and phonological group’s prosodic pattern. In this regard, the research data are analyzed within the framework of Optimality Theory, and a grammar is presented benefitting from Optimality violable constraints.  </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقالة حاضر به بررسی الگوی تکیۀ زبان فارسی در سطوح کلمه و گروه نحوی می‏پردازد و نشان می‏دهد که در چارچوب نظریة واج‏شناسیِ نوایی، تکیة واژگانی در زبان فارسی از الگویی ثابت پیروی می‏کند. تکیۀ واژگانی در زبان فارسی تابع قاعدۀ تکیة کلمة واجی یعنی راست‌رو است، اما در بررسی تکیة گروه، رجوع به اطلاعات نحوی و ساخت سازه‎ایِ درونیِ سازة نحوی امری اجتناب‏ناپذیر است. اصل هسته‏گریزی (اسلامی، 1379 و 1384) به‌خوبی از پس تبیین این مسئله برمی‏آید. از این روی، پژوهش حاضر در تحلیل داده‎ها از اصل یادشده بهره می‏جوید. هدف دیگر این مقاله، ارائة دستور الگوی آهنگِ کلمۀ واجی، گروه واژه‏بست و گروه واجیِ زبان فارسی در چارچوب نظریة بهینگی (OT) است. به این منظور، داده‎های پژوهش که برگرفته‎اند از اثر اسلامی (1384) در چارچوب نظریة بهینگی تحلیل می‏شوند و دستوری با استفاده از محدودیت‎های نقض‏پذیر بهینگی ارائه می‏شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تکیة واژگانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تکیة گروه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اصل هسته‏گریزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">واج‏شناسیِ نوایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریة بهینگی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2466_eeccd06a4969fb1619859dba908eaa8e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
