<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>16</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Harmonic Serialism in Azbayjani</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>توالی هماهنگ در زبان ترکی آذربایجانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>15</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>33</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1280</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضی‌نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Harmonic serialism (HS) was first mentioned by Prince and Smolensky (1993), but it was not pursued and was rejected in favor of the standard OT. HS was reopened by McCarthy (2000). In standard OT, GEN can make many changes at once when it produces a candidate. In HS, GEN is limited to making just one change at a time. HS’s candidate sets are less diverse than standard OT’s. In HS the path to optimality is longer and more gradual. The optimal candidate chosen by EVAL is the input to another pass through GEN, which generates a set of candidates that go to EVAL, and so on. By applying HS theory to Azarbayjan Turkish, we can see why making the specified change in each step is better than doing nothing at all and also we can follow steps of derivations from input to optimal output easily.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">توالیِ هماهنگ مدلی از نظریۀ بهینگی است، که اولین بار توسط پرینس و اسمولنسکیدر سال 1993 مطرح شد اما با توجه به اینکه در آن زمان رویکرد بهینگیِ استاندارد بسیار مورد توجه قرار گرفته بود، کنار گذاشته شد. این نظریه مجدداً توسط مکارتیدر سال‌های 2002- 2000 مطرح شد(مکارتی،2010: 8). تفاوت اصلی این رویکرد با رویکرد بهینگیِ استاندارد در نحوۀ فعالیت بخش مولّد است. در چارچوب رویکرد توالیِ هماهنگ، بخش مولد، در هر مرحله از فعالیت، یک و فقط یک تغییر در درون‌داد ایجاد می‌کند و بالطبع گزینه‌های حاصل در هر مرحله از فعالیت مولد، تغییرات اندکی را نسبت به شکل درون‌دادنشان می‌دهند و با هم شباهت زیادی دارند&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;در این مقاله سعی بر آن داری تحلیلِداده‌حل اشتقاقِبرون‌داد از درون‌داد، وهمچنین رتبه‌بندیِ محدودیت‌ها، دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان ترکیِ آذربایجانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویکرد بهینگیِ استاندارد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویکرد توالیِ هماهنگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تابلوی پیشرفت هماهنگ</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1280_1b1c62236a9f4e222f2bf8f64725767c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
