<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>23</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Stylistic Study of a Contemporary Persian Story from Halliday’s Functional Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی سبکی یک داستانِ کوتاهِ معاصر ازمنظر نقش‌گراییِ هلیدی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>131</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>156</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2256</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پونه</FirstName>
					<LastName>مصطفوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگاه میراث فرهنگی و گردشگری</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرضیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>صناعتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگاه میراث فرهنگی و گردشگری</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>There are three metafunctions in systemic functional linguistics named, textual, experiential and interpersonal metafunctions. According to Halliday these metafunctions are considered as three different semantic levels in which clauses can be analyzed. One of this analysis results is stylistics. The purpose of the present article is to analyze a contemporary short story of Zoya Pirzad named “the opposite bench” according to the said metafunctions of systemic functional linguistics, to determine stylistic patterns of the said short story. It is necessary to note that there is not complete overlap between stylistic concept in literature on the one hand and linguistic or functional approach on the other. But they are relatively coincident in some general and basic cases. The short story which is analyzed clause by clause based on the said theory in this paper, consists of 233 clauses but because of paper size limitations, we just mentioned 19 clauses which are the most important ones. We conclude that in most clauses the chief character of the story (hero) is considered as the departure point and the story focuses on him and his affairs. Plenty usage of declarative modality and past tense clauses is the result of the story style which is narrative. Using positive clauses here sustains the validity of clause based on the writer’s opinion. The existence of modal adjuncts in clauses shows the writer’s confidence and approach. Meanwhile the number of material processes indicates the different events in the story.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در زبان‌شناسیِ نقش‌گراییِ نظام‌مندِ هلیدی، سه فرانقش متنی، تجربی و بینافردی، سه لایة معنایی متفاوت هستند که با کمک آنها بندهای متن تحلیل می‌شوند و از این تحلیل، سبک‌شناسی متون حاصل می‌شود. هدف از این مقاله، تحلیل داستان کوتاه «نیمکت روبه‌رو»ی زویا پیرزاد ازمنظر نقش‌گرایی نظام‌مند و براساسِ سه فرانقش مذکور و تحلیلِ سبک‌شناسیِ آن است. نگاه زبان‌شناختی و نقش‌گرایی به سبک، با تعاریف سبک در ادبیات همپوشی ندارد اما در مواردی کلی، این مفهوم قابل انطباق است. داستان مورد بررسی 233 بند دارد که یک‌به‌یک، براساسِ این مدل، تحلیل شده‌اند اما به‌دلیل محدودیتِ حجم مقاله، تنها به ذکر 18 بند از شاخص‌ترین نمونه‌ها بسنده شده است. انتخاب این مثال­ها به گونه­ای صورت گرفته است که بندها، تمام اجزای موجود در فرانقش­ها را دارا باشند. برخی از نتایجِ حاصل از تحلیل مذکور عبارت‌اند از: در اکثرِ بندهای داستان، شخصیت اول نقطة عزیمت نویسنده است و داستان بر او و مسائلش تمرکز دارد. با توجه به روایی‌بودنِ سبک داستان، کاربرد وجه خبری و زمان گذشته فراوان است. وجود تعداد زیاد افعال به‌صورت فرایند مادی در این داستان حاکی از این است که نویسنده قصدِ بیانِ رویدادها و وقایع را دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‌شناسیِ نقش‌گرا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حوزۀ گفتمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عامل گفتمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شیوۀ گفتمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرانقش‌های هلیدی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سبک‌شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2256_83acc4a058460043fd9ad1e81e8b43b2.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
