<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>10</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Study of Sociolinguistic variables of Persian in Nehbandani Dialect: Consonants</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی متغیرهای اجتماعی- زبانیِ فارسی در گویشِ نهبندانی: همخوان‌ها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>71</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>114</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1558</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباسعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>آهنگر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محبوبه</FirstName>
					<LastName>شاهسوار</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد زبانشناسی همگانی دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This article aims at exploring the relation between social variables, including gender, age and education, with Persian linguistic (consonant) variables occurring in the speech of Nehbandani dialect speakers. The relevant linguistic variables were extracted from the speech of 24 qualified (adolescent, young and adult) informants. The findings of this study show that education, in the case of some linguistic variables, does not cause a decline in the use of non-standard forms and it just plays a significant role in differentiating the speech of literate and no-literate adults. It is also observed that, in employing some of linguistic variables, the men’s speech is more standard than women’s. Furthermore, in cases where the speech of women being more standard than that of men, their speech differences are trifling and the role of age is not distinctive. The increase in the age of the adolescents having literate parents and literate adults correlates with the increase in the use of standard linguistic forms. In adolescent groups, in half of the linguistic variables studied, the gender does not make a distinction between the speech of boys and that of girls.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این مقاله به بررسیِ رابطۀ متغیرهای اجتماعی همچون جنسیت، سن و تحصیلات با متغیرهای زبانیِ(همخوانی) زبان فارسی در گفتار گویشورانِ نهبندانی می‌پردازد. متغیرهای زبانیِ مربوط از گفتارِ 24 گویشورِ نوجوان، جوان و مسنِ واجدِ شرایط استخراج گردید. نتایجِ این پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که تحصیلات در برخی‌از متغیرها باعثِ کاهشِ استفاده از صورت‌های غیرمعیار نشده است و نقشِ تحصیلات به‌عنوانِ یک متغیر اجتماعی تنها در تمایزِ گفتارِ گویشورانِ مسنِ باسواد و بی‌سواد مشهود است. همچنین، در این گویش، در برخی متغیرها مشاهده شده است که گفتارِ گویشورانِ مرد به گونۀ معیار نزدیک‌تر است. به‌علاوه، در بیشترِ موارد نیز درصورتِ نزدیک تر بودنِ گفتارِ زنان به گونه معیار، اختلافِ گفتارِ آن‌ها با مردان ناچیز بوده است و عاملِ جنسیت نقشِ تمایزدهنده‌ای نداشته است. افزایش سن در گروه نوجوانانِ دارای والدینِ باسواد و گویشورانِ مسنِ باسواد با افزایشِ استفاده از صورت‌های معیار همراه است. در گروهِ نوجوانان در نیمی از متغیرهای زبانیِ موردِ مطالعه، جنسیت نقشی در تمایزِ گفتار  نداشته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">متغیر اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">متغیر زبانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحصیلات</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1558_6bbc9f08f8487d2fd7a223e550c2baae.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
