<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>13</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Contrastive Role of Laryngeal Features for Plosives of the Standard Persian</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نقش تقابلی مشخصه‌های حنجره در انفجاری‌های زبان فارسی معیار</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>32</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1461</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمود</FirstName>
					<LastName>بی‌جن‌خان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to investigate the impact of laryngeal features on the   contrastive system of the plosives in Standard Persian. First, the underlying structure of the features was examined based on the derivational approach. Then, descriptive generalization observed in the data was formalized by inviolable constraints of the filter theory and violable constraints of the optimality theory. Based on conspiracy among phonological rules, the contrastive role of the features was explained according to four violable constraints. The results showed that neutralization of the features can be explained by dominance of context-sensitive markedness constraints over faithfulness constraints of voicing and aspiration, while explaining the contrastive role of the features requires a reverse order of dominance relation mentioned above.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این مقاله تجزیه و تحلیل مشخصه‌های حنجره در نظام تقابلی انفجاری‌های زبان فارسی معیار است. برای این منظور، در چارچوب رویکرد اشتقاقی، بازنمایی زیرساختی مشخصه‌های حنجره در انفجاری‌ها، و قواعد واجی برای اشتقاق بازنماییِ روساختیِ آن‌ها به‌دست داده شده است. تعمیم توصیفی که از داده‌های آوایی به‌دست می‌آید، نشان‌گر هم‌نواییِ قواعد واجی به‌سوی محدودیت‌هایی است که نظام تقابلی مشخصه‌های حنجره را در انفجاری‌ها تبیین می‌کند.مسألۀ اصلی، ناشی از عدم تواناییِ رویکرد اشتقاقی و صافی‌ها در تبیینِ هم‌نواییِ قواعد واجی است. برای حل این مسأله با طرح چهار محدودیتِ نقض‌پذیر، دستور بهینگی برای نظام تقابلی مشخصه‌های حنجره در زبان فارسی معیار اثبات شده است. براین‌اساس، خنثی‌شدگیِ مشخصه‌های حنجره، ازطریق تسلطِ محدودیت‌های نشان‌داریِ حساس‌به‌بافت، بر محدودیتِ پایاییِ مشخصه‌های واک‌داری و دمیدگی، و تقابل مشخصه‌های حنجره، ازطریق تسلطِ محدودیتِ پایاییِ واک‌داری و دمیدگی، بر یک محدودیتِ نشان‌داریِ آزاد از بافت، صورت‌بندی و تبیین شده‌است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشخصه‌های حنجره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هم‌نوایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محدودیت‌های نقض‌پذیر</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1461_35ca113f5ad852820a46f4ecf03b87cd.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
