<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>6</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2007</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Phonological Legacy of Avicenna Compared With Relevant Topics in Modern Structural Linguistics</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>میراث صوت‌شناسی ابن‌سینا و مقایسة آن با مفاهیم و حوزه‌‌های مشابه در زبان‌شناسی ساختاری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>31</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>54</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1646</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سپیده</FirstName>
					<LastName>چیت‌ساز</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی – واحد مرودشت</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Language as an innate phenomenon has been studied in different cultures. The value and importance of these kinds of studies is obvious. As western linguists do not value the studies and researches of ancient Muslim scholars, so in the writer&#039;s opinion by studying their works, it should be possible to rewrite the history of linguistics. In this paper by studying one of Avicenna&#039;s works, &lt;em&gt;Makhaarej-Al-Horoof&lt;/em&gt;, and comparing it with some aspects of modern structural linguistics, it is tried to take a step forward in the investigation of old Persian linguistics. Historically, therefore, it is for us to protect and develop such invaluable legacies. &lt;br /&gt;The works of Muslim scholars in the field of language studies seen to have been ignored in the west, whereas examining them may load to a rewriting of the history of linguistics. This paper examines &lt;em&gt;Makhaarej – Al Horoof&lt;/em&gt;, one of Avicenna’s major works, and compares it with some aspects of modern structural linguistics in the hope of providing great, insight into old Persian linguistic studies.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ارزش و اهمیت مطالعه و تحقیق دربارة مطالعات دانشمندان گذشته که به بررسی زبان پرداخته‌اند بر کسی پوشیده نیست. از آنجا که زبان‌شناسان غربی ارزش چندانی برای تحقیقات و مطالعات دانشمندان قدیم ایرانی در این زمینه قائل نیستند، به عقیدة نگارنده با بررسی و مطالعة آثار محققان گذشته در کشورهای اسلامی از جمله ایران شاید بتوان تاریخ علم زبان‌شناسی را مورد بازنگری قرار داد. در این مقاله با بررسی رسالة &lt;em&gt;مخارج‌الحروف&lt;/em&gt; ابن‌سینا و مقایسة مطالب آن با دستاوردهای جدید زبان‌شناسی ساختاری، سعی بر این است تا گامی نو در جهت شناخت زبان‌شناسی قدیم ایران برداشته شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مخارج‌الحروف</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ابن سینا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آواشناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تاریخ علم زبان‌شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1646_83628e5fc550c60f7af89688ef99b525.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
