<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>6</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2007</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Specific Use of Language in Iraj Mirza’s Poetry</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کارکرد‍ِ زبان در شعر ایرج میرزا</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>83</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>105</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1649</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سهیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>صارمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Iraj Mirza’s poetry occupies a special place in Persian literature as compared to the works of other poets of his time, due to his almost unrivalled use of language and rhetorics. Deviating from syntactic, semantic and pragmatic norms, he creates a new atmosphere with the simple language he uses, which draws his poetry close to the language of nature. The present paper examines Iraj Mirza’s poetry in terms of language function and his expert play with language. He deviates from the accepted linguistic norms of syntax, semantics and pragmatics, with an artistic courage, creating a new atmosphere in literary language: It is worth mentioning that he does so with such a simple language that one can claim, without unnecessary exaggeration that his poems are closer to the language of the nature than those of his contemporary poets.
This article studies some of the language functions of Iraj&#039;s poems, revealing a small part of his skill in playing with the language.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در میان شاعران عصر مشروطه، شعر ایرج میرزا، ازلحاظ کاربرد ویژة زبان و شگردهای کلامی - که آگاهانه بدان پرداخته است - جایگاهی ویژه دارد. وی با جسارتی هنرمندانه هنجارهای زبان رایج را در سطح‌های صرفی، نحوی و واژگانی، واجی و معنایی در هم می‌شکند و فضایی تازه در حیطة زبان ادبی ایجاد می‌کند و این کار را با زبانی ساده و روان انجام می‌دهد؛ به گونه‌ای که بی‌اغراق، می‌توان گفت در بین شاعران این عصر، شعر وی بیش از دیگران به زبان طبیعی نزدیک است.
این مقاله به بررسی پاره‌ای عملکردهای زبانی ایرج پرداخته و نشان داده است که وی چگونه به کمک این زبانِ ساده و روان، شعر خود را وسیلة بیان مفاهیم انقلابی، اجتماعی ـ سیاسی، طنزآلود، شکوائیه و ... قرار داده و با بهره‌گیری از ترکیب‌های نوساخته و لطیفه‌پردازی‌های کم سابقه، خود را صاحبِ سبکی ویژه ساخته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شعر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام زبانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هنجارشکنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارکردزبانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روانی و سادگی بیان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1649_c162eebb78bd14be5453f4b60c0a7327.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
