<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>24</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>30</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Attitudes of Tabrizi Citizens towards Dialectal Variation across East Azerbaijan Province with Focus on Linguistic Difference, correctness and Pleasantness</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نگرش شهروندان تبریز به تنوعات گویشی در استان آذربایجان‌شرقی با تأکید بر سه شاخص تفاوت زبانی، صحیح‌بودن و خوشایندی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>21</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>44</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">2467</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>قلی فامیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Linguistic attitude, i.e. any type of feeling or sensation of an individual towards his or her own language and that of others, involves concepts such as culture, identity, and mechanisms such as language planning. In this study, considering the three parameters of linguistic difference, correctness, and pleasantness, the attitudes of Tabrizi citizens towards dialectal variation across East Azerbaijan province were evaluated. A researcher-made questionnaire with three maps of the province was presented to 384 citizens of Tabriz who speak Azeri Turkish as their first language. The participants marked their opinion towards linguistic differences with Tabrizi accent in a scale from 1 to 4. The correctness and pleasantness parameters were evaluated in a scale from 1 to 7. The statistical data shows that the proximity principle is a valid parameter, as the least differences with Tabrizi dialect were recorded in six adjacent cities. Secondly, most participants considered Tabrizi dialect as the most correct and most pleasant variety across the province. With the two exceptions of Meraghe and Bonab, other counties showed a positive correlation between correctness and pleasantness parameters. The group of females ranked Tabrizi higher in terms of correctness and pleasantness. The age group 26-45 recognized more difference between Tabrizi accent and those of other counties. The non-educated group showed more significant attention towards the pleasantness parameter. In addition to theoretical achievements in sociolinguistics and dialectology, the findings of the present study could support language planning projects and decision making in institutions such as local IRIB as well as centers for teaching Azeri Turkish.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">نگرش زبانی که ناظر بر هرگونه احساس و تلقی یک فرد از زبان خود یا دیگری است، با مفاهیمی مانند فرهنگ، هویت و سازوکارهایی همچون برنامه‌ریزی زبان سروکار دارد. در این پژوهش براساسِ سه شاخص «تفاوت گویشی»، «صحیح‌بودن» (اعتبار اجتماعی) و «خوشایندی»، نگرش شهروندان تبریز در خصوص تنوعات گویشی زبان ترکی آذری در سطح استان آذربایجان‌شرقی ارزیابی شده است. به این منظور پرسشنامه‌ای شامل سه نقشۀ استان در اختیار 384 شهروند آذری‌زبان ساکن تبریز قرار گرفت. آزمودنی‌ها نظر خود را دربارۀ میزان تفاوت گویش‌های شهرستان‌های استان نسبت به تبریز با مقیاس عددی 1 تا 4، و میزان صحیح‌بودن و خوشایندی گونه‌های زبانی رایج در شهرستان‌ها را با مقیاس عددی 1 تا 7 اعلام کردند. نتایج آماری نشان داد که اصل همجواری در نگرش شهروندان تبریز نسبت به تفاوت گویشی صدق می‌کند، زیرا از نظر آنان، گویش‌های رایج در شش شهرستان همجوار با تبریز، کمترین تفاوت را با گونۀ زبانی تبریز دارند. از سوی دیگر، اغلب آزمودنی‌ها، گونۀ رایج در شهر تبریز را صحیح‌تر و خوشایندتر از گونه‌های زبانی سایر شهرستان‌ها دانستند. به‌جز دو استثنا - مراغه و بناب- در سایر شهرستان‌های استان، میان دو شاخص صحیح‌بودن و خوشایندی، همبستگی مثبت مشاهده شد. گروه زنان نسبت به مردان، گونۀ زبانی تبریز را صحیح‌تر خوشایندتر معرفی کردند. گروه سنی 45-26 ساله به وجود تفاوت‌ بیشتر بین گویش تبریز با گونه‌های سایر شهرستان‌ها قائل شدند. گروه غیرتحصیل‌کرده حساسیت بیشتری به مفهوم خوشایندی گونه‌های زبانی استان نشان دادند. نتایج این مطالعه، ضمن ارائۀ دستاوردهای نظری در چارچوب جامعه‌شناسی زبان و گویش‌شناسی، می‌تواند به برنامه‌ریزی زبانی و تصمیم‌گیری در نهادهایی مانند صداوسیمای استان و مراکز آموزش زبان ترکی آذری کمک کند.و </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نگرش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تفاوت زبانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صحیح‌‌بودن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خوشایندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تبریز</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_2467_0b796066a7b364f18250c8c635b18877.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
