<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>انجمن زبان شناسی ایران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زبان و زبان‌شناسی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn></Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>21</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Cognitive Representation of the Persian Category ‘Flower’ based on the Prototype Theory</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بازنمایی شناختیِ مقولۀ گل در زبان فارسی برپایۀ نظریۀ پیش‌نمونه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>89</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>115</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">1973</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدحسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>ترابی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای زبان‌شناسی همگانی، پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شهلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رقیب دوست</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The current work investigated the prototypes of the concrete category of ‘flower’ for Persian-speaking male and female students of primary school (10-13 years old), middle school (13-15 years old) and high school (16-18 years old) and also college students of agriculture, psychology and medical sciences. It also investigated the effect of age, gender and educational background on these prototypes based on Rosch (1975) and Liu et al.’s (2009) methodologies. To collect data, different groups of participants were provided with two types of questionnaires in two steps. In the first questionnaire, participants were asked to write whatever examples they recalled from the category of ‘flower’. In the second questionnaire, which was based on the first one, participants were asked to score each member of the category from 1 to 5. Rose, Damascus rose and lilac were found to be strong prototypes for the category of ‘flower’ in Persian language in all the twelve groups of Persian-speaking students. The results also showed that environmental factors have a great effect on prototype formation of the category ‘flower’ in Persian language.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر برپایۀ شیوۀ پژوهش روش (1975) و میتینگ ‌لیو و همکاران به بررسی پیش‌نمونه‌های مقولۀ عینی گل برای دانش‌آموزان دختر و پسر ابتدایی (13-10 سال)، راهنمایی (15-13 سال) و دبیرستان (18-16 سال) و دانشجویان دختر و پسر رشته‌های کشاورزی، روان‌شناسی و علوم پزشکی فارسی‌زبان پرداخته و تأثیر متغیرهای سن، جنسیت و پیشینۀ تحصیلی را بر شکل‌گیریِ این پیش‌نمونه‌ها مورد مطالعه قرار داده است. برای گردآوری داده‌های پژوهش، در دو مرحله، دو پرسش‌نامۀ مجزا در اختیار آزمودنی‌ها قرار گرفت. در پرسش‌نامۀ اول از آنان خواسته شد تا هر نمونه‌ای از اعضای مقوله‌های مورد نظر را که در ذهن دارند، بنویسند. در پرسش‌نامۀ دوم، که برپایۀ داده‌های پرسش‌نامۀ اول تهیه شد، نیز از آنان خواسته شد تا به اعضای مقوله‌های مختلف از 1 تا 5 امتیاز بدهند. نتایج این پژوهش نشان داد که گل‌های رز، محمدی و یاس به ‌ترتیب پیش‌نمونه‌هایی قوی برای مقولۀ گل در زبان فارسی بودند و همۀ پیش‌نمونه‌های دوازده گروه آزمودنی پژوهش حاضر را تشکیل می‌دادند. برپایۀ یافته‌های این پژوهش، به‌نظر می‌رسد عوامل محیطی تأثیر زیادی بر شکل‌گیری پیش‌نمونۀ مقولۀ گل در زبان فارسی دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مقوله‌بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیش‌نمونه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">میزان تحصیلات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://lsi-linguistics.ihcs.ac.ir/article_1973_38b480c659ff1292d83450c0580eec85.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
