<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Assessing Effect Social Capital to Intellectual Capital Components
(Case: Office of Qom Tax Affairs)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر سرمایه اجتماعی بر مؤلفه‌های سرمایه فکری (مورد مطالعه: اداره کل امور مالیاتی استان قم)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>265</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>287</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53465</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2014.53465</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالله</FirstName>
					<LastName>توکلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار پژوهشگاه حوزه و دانشگاه، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالصمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>عزیزپور لیندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهام</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اشرف</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرزایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>By the more advances in science and knowledge, the role of staff and human relations (HR) becomes more evident in the progress of the organization and the community. Social capital and intellectual capital are the two subjects that in the recent two decades have been considered and their formative roles in organizational development and performance have been confirmed. This study examines the role of social capital and intellectual capital components in the Office of Qom tax affairs in the research, the population consisted of 142 employees of this organization and 104 individuals were randomly selected and they were examined by standard questionnaires. We evaluate and analysis the research hypotheses using structural equation and Smart-PLS (partial least squares) application, the results showed a significant effect of social capital on the intellectual capital, structural capital, and human relationships. Finally, suggestions are presented to improve the organization&#039;s social capital and intellectual capital components.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با پیشرفت روزافزون علم نقش کارکنان و ارتباطات انسانی (سرمایه­های انسانی) در پیشرفت سازمان و جامعه بیش از پیش آشکار شده است. در دو دهه اخیر به سرمایه اجتماعی و سرمایه فکری توجه شده است و نقش سازنده آن‌ها در پیشرفت و عملکرد برتر سازمانی تأیید شده است. تحقیق حاضر نقش سرمایه اجتماعی بر مؤلفه­های سرمایه فکری در اداره کل امور مالیاتی استان قم بررسی کرده است. این تحقیق از نظر هدف، کاربردی، و از نظر روش توصیفی و همبستگی است. جامعه آماری این تحقی 142 نفر کارکنان این سازمان بوده است، که تعداد 104 نفر به‌طور تصادفی انتخاب شدند. ابزار پژوهش پرسشنامه استاندارد است. ارزیابی و تجزیه­و­تحلیل داده‌ها با مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری و نرم­افزار Smart-PLS انجام گرفته است. نتایج حاکی از معنی­داری اثر سرمایه اجتماعی بر مؤلفه‌های سرمایه فکری شامل سرمایه ساختاری، انسانی و رابطه­ای است. در پایان، جهت بهبود سرمایه اجتماعی و مؤلفه‌های سرمایه فکری در سازمان پیشنهادهایی مطرح گردید. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه رابطه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه ساختاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_53465_7f0df7cba9a0c1a12444d8cbb1ea66a4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
