<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Studying Effect of Social Capital on Organizational Innovation with Mediating Role of Dual Knowledge Management Strategies</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر نوآوری سازمانی با تأکید بر نقش میانجی استراتژی‏ های دوگانۀ مدیریت دانش</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>75</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>94</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63071</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2017.236724.1408</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>حمیدی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>کوچک زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی‌‌ارشد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاج کریمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی‌‌ارشد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In today&#039;s competitive world, the survival of companies requires special attention to innovation. Social capital is a fundamental concept in understanding innovation, creativity and dynamism of the organization. Accordingly, this research examines the effect of social capital on organizational innovation with the role of mediator of dual knowledge management strategies. The present research is applied and in terms of descriptive-correlational method, in which the questionnaire has been used to collect data. The population consists of 112 employees of Qom Power Distribution Company According to the Morgan table and random sampling method, 87 people are selected as samples. Data collected by structural equation software WarpPLS has been analyzed. The results of path analysis showed that social capital has a positive and significant effect on organizational innovation and dual knowledge management strategies and dual knowledge management strategies on organizational innovation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;در دنیای رقابتی و دانشی کنونی، بقای شرکت‌ها مستلزم توجه ویژه به نوآوری است. سرمایة اجتماعی مفهومی زیربنایی در درک نوآوری، خلاقیت و پویایی‏های سازمان به شمار می‌آید. بر این اساس، این تحقیق تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعی بر نوآوری سازمانی با نقش میانجی استراتژی‏های دوگانة مدیریت دانش را بررسی می‌کند. پژوهش حاضر از لحاظ هدف کاربردی و از نظر نحوة اجرا، توصیفی- همبستگی است که در آن ابزار پرسشنامه برای جمع‏آوری داده‏ها به‌کار گرفته شد. جامعة آماری، شامل 112 نفر از کارکنان شرکت توزیع برق قم است که براساس جدول مورگان و به روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی، 87 نفر انتخاب شدند. داده‌های گردآوری‌شده توسط نرم‌افزار warpPLS تجزیه‌وتحلیل شد. نتایج نشان داد سرمایة اجتماعی بر نوآوری سازمانی و استراتژی‏های دوگانة مدیریت دانش و استراتژی‏های دوگانة مدیریت دانش بر نوآوری سازمانی تأثیر مثبت و معنادار می‌گذارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استراتژی‏ مدیریت دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63071_b58a0b3ca2e84768cf8b7fd679f5a385.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
