<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Survey of Relationship between Organizational Justice and Employee’s Social Capital in Electric Power Distribution Company of Kurdistan</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطه عدالت سازمانی و سرمایه‌های اجتماعی کارکنان در شرکت توزیع برق استان کردستان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>247</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>264</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53464</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2014.53464</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رسول</FirstName>
					<LastName>چاوشینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ارشد مدیریت استراتژیک، مدیر آموزش شرکت توزیع برق استان کردستان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ماریا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نقش بندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت اجرایی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد سنندج، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The most fundamental insight in heavenly religions is to recognize the god as a justice commanding and a justice rising which is the base of human’s relation with god. Justice philosophical concept is the basis of resurrection. Justice and its performance is one of the human’s basic and natural needs, that its existence is ready a good basis for humans society development .The accomplished researches show that one of the most important results of organizational justice is the promotion of the social capitals in organization. This research the relation between organizational justice and the amount of employee’s social capitals in organization recognizes. Organizational justice is including “distributive justice, procedural justice and interactional justice”. Social capital is including “confidence capability, partnership and civil leadership, forgiveness and voluntary moral, ability of informal social relations establishment, variety in associations and friendships and political and social communion”. According to the research results and with regard to the average of 3.88 percent of organizational justice and the average of 3.55 percent of employee’s social capital that both of them are higher than the medium limitation of 3, a meaningful correlation between the organizational justice and the employees social capital was proved.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;sub&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;اساسی‌ترین معرفت در ادیان آسمانی، شناخت خداوند به عنوان «امرکننده به عدل» و «به پادارنده عدل» است که اساس رابطه انسان با خدا نیز هست. عدل در مفهوم اجتماعی، هدف نبوت و به مفهوم فلسفی، مبنای معاد است. عدالت و اجرای آن یکی از نیازهای اساسی و فطری انسان است که همواره در طول تاریخ، بستری مناسب جهت توسعه جوامع انسانی، فراهم کرده است. پژوهش‌های انجام‌گرفته نشان می‌دهند عدالت سازمانی پیش‌بینی‌کننده بسیاری از متغیرهای دیگر سازمانی است که یکی از مهم‌ترین پیامدهای عدالت سازمانی، ارتقای سرمایه‌های اجتماعی و به تبع آن افزایش بهره‌وری کارکنان سازمان است. این مقاله رابطه عدالت سازمانی و سرمایه اجتماعی را به عنوان یکی از عوامل تأثیرگذار بر ارتقای بهره‌وری کارکنان شناسایی و تحلیل می‌کند. عدالت سازمانی به عنوان متغیر مستقل شامل بعدهای عدالت توزیعی، عدالت رویه‌ای و عدالت مراوده‌ای و ابعاد و مراتب سرمایه اجتماعی به عنوان متغیر وابسته شامل: قابلیت اعتماد، مشارکت مدنی و روحیه کار تیمی، بخشش و روحیه داوطلبی، توانایی برقراری روابط اجتماعی غیررسمی، تنوع در معاشرت‌ها و دوستی‌ها، و مشارکت‌های سیاسی و اجتماعی است. براساس نتایج پژوهش و با توجه به میانگین 88&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;3 درصدی عدالت سازمانی و 55&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;3 درصدی سرمایه اجتماعی کارکنان که هر دو بالاتر از حد مفروض 3 بودند، همبستگی معناداری بین عدالت سازمانی و سرمایه اجتماعی به عنوان عامل مؤثر بر بهره‌وری کارکنان ثابت شد. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهره‌وری کارکنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عدالت سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_53464_dd337349ee2282bd2a7dd2d81262fbd8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
