<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying the Outcomes of Employees’ Vigor as an Affecting Factor on Social Capital</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی پیامدهای نشاط کارکنان به عنوان یکی از عوامل مؤثر بر سرمایۀ اجتماعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>23</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>41</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">58324</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2016.58324</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زلفا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حقگویان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت رفتار سازمانی، مدرس دانشگاه حضرت معصومه (س)، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارعی متین</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>جندقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحمتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of this qualitative research is to identify the outcomes of vigor. Since 2000, in UN’s view, such variables as vigor, life expectancy, gratification and satisfaction are computed as key variables in determining nations’ development level which shows the importance of studying vigor. The methodology is an Exploratory Study in terms of purpose and it is a Qualitative survey in terms of data collection method. Identified outcomes include personal outcomes, family outcomes, organizational outcomes and social outcomes. Personal outcomes include such concepts as personal success improvement, life working quality improvement, receiving more social supports and health enhancement. Family outcomes include calmness increase in family, vigor increase in family environment, family members’ health improvement, family satisfaction enhancement and family success improvement. Identified organizational outcomes include such concepts as social capital development, citizenship behavior improvement, productivity enhancement and customer satisfaction improvement. Ultimately, social outcomes include a happy society and a happy generation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">از سال 2000 در نگاه سازمان ملل برای تعیین سطح توسعه‌یافتگی کشور‌ها نشاط، امید به آینده، خشنودی و رضایتمندی افراد جامعه به عنوان متغیرهای اصلی وارد محاسبات شده است که نشان‌دهندة اهمیت مطالعه و بررسی نشاط است. بنابراین، این پژوهش کیفی با هدف شناسایی پیامدهای نشاط کارکنان انجام گرفته است. پژوهش حاضر از نظر هدف، مطالعه‌ای اکتشافی و از نظر شیوة جمع‌آوری اطلاعات پژوهش آمیخته است. پیامدهای شناسایی‌شده در این پژوهش عبارت‌اند از پیامدهای شخصی، پیامدهای خانوادگی، پیامدهای سازمانی و پیامدهای اجتماعی. پیامدهای شخصی خود شامل مفاهیمی مانند افزایش موفقیت شخصی، بهبود کیفیت زندگی کاری، دریافت حمایت اجتماعی بیشتر و بهبود سلامتی است. پیامدهای خانوادگی شامل افزایش آرامش در خانواده، افزایش نشاط در محیط خانوادگی، بهبود سلامتی اعضای خانواده، افزایش رضایت خانواده و افزایش موفقیت خانوادگی، و پیامدهای سازمانی شناسایی‌شده در این پژوهش شامل مفاهیمی مانند توسعة سرمایة اجتماعی، افزایش رفتار شهروندی، افزایش بهره‌وری و افزایش رضایت مشتریان است. در نهایت، پیامدهای اجتماعی نشاط شامل داشتن جامعة بانشاط‌تر و ایجاد نسلی بانشاط است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انرژی عاطفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانایی جسمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درگیرکارشدن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرزندگی شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نشاط</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_58324_5fe0cde51dc1d671f6753dfbf239255f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
