<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[First Pages]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63387_23e47d56056e8e4254582e879e387abb.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Role of Employer Branding in Creating Social Capital]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Farajzadeh, Solmaz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Alvani, Seyed Mahdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ataee, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shahgholiyan, Keyvan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Corporate social responsibility]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Employer Branding]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[trust]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This study examines how corporate social responsibility by becoming the employer brand can be converted to social capital. To achieve this goal, participants study were Ph.D. Students were studying at the years 1391 to 1395 at the Faculty of Management and Accounting of Islamic Azad University of Qazvin, which were selected 161 students by simple random sampling method. Current research in terms of dimension of the goal is applied research and the method of data collection, is descriptive-correlational. In order to test the hypothesis, the information collected by a questionnaire. Content, convergent and divergent validity was used. Index reliability, were measured by two criteria: Cronbach's alpha and composite reliability that all of them were approved. In this research were used to test the research hypotheses, structural equation modeling with Partial Least Squares approach and analysis by SmartPLS software. The findings showed: direct effect of corporate social responsibility on social capital was rejected, but the direct impacts of employer branding, internal audience satisfaction, external audience’s image were confirmed. Also indirect effect of corporate social responsibility by employer branding and internal audience satisfaction and external audiences image, indirect effect of employer branding by internal audience satisfaction and external audiences image, indirect effect of internal audience satisfaction by external audiences image on social capital were confirmed.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63128_78317c173cb6849451484e441d171aa4.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2017.234538.1378]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Ethical Capital Generating Social Capital]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Zareie Zarei‌matin, Hassan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shamsi, Fatemeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Adibzadeh, Marzieyh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ethical Capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ethical Virtue]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ethics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The present ideology of neo-classical economic paradigm to follow their own interests and are destroying the ethical basis and its consequences, ethical virtuous society is low. Lean thinking judgment based on knowledge of human capital to "do the right thing" is not merely to "do it right". Doing the right things with just the ethical value management by humans as creatures is possible. Therefore, attention to the concept of ethical capital to create value beyond the existing mission and values will be doubled. In the present article aims to identify ethical capital, and reviewed different views on this issue.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63037_2e0a3e7b31ba3de2ac92262aacb93822.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2017.228653.1315]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Drawing up the Native Model of Social Capital for Achieving the Resistance Economy Goals: Using Grounded Theory Qualitative]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nammamian, Farshid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mir, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Behavioral-collaborative dimension]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cognitive - mental dimension]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[resistive economy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This research aims to design a model for achieving the resistance economy goals in two areas of employment and production and the role of social capital on the realization of these goals using the qualitative method of grounded theory. The main tools of the research were semi-structured interviews with knowledgeable and specialized subjects in the subject area and the sampling was done theoretically. After conducting interviews and collecting data, the codes obtained were analyzed in different sections and ended up in the open, axial and selective coding stages. This model included of the subjects required, causal conditions, Confounding conditions, and the consequences, which may be due to the current situation and role taking resistance economy aspects of mental and behavioral social capital, while respecting the requirements, causal conditions, Confounding conditions and strategies can help to increase domestic production, increase in occupation and Domestic production capacity. At the end, with emphasis on the role play of resistance economy from trust building, awareness, civic participation and networking as dimensions of social capital, it was suggested to be used from social capital in different dimensions for developing the small, family, rural and conversion businesses to attraction the participation of the people and become the culture in this context.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63153_96ea7abb5265f3ab0b0c9723d538738f.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2017.234760.1379]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Studying Effect of Social Capital on Organizational Innovation with Mediating Role of Dual Knowledge Management Strategies]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hamidizadeh, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Kouchakzadeh, Zahra]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hajkarimi, Fatemeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Knowledge management Strategies]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In today's competitive world, the survival of companies requires special attention to innovation. Social capital is a fundamental concept in understanding innovation, creativity and dynamism of the organization. Accordingly, this research examines the effect of social capital on organizational innovation with the role of mediator of dual knowledge management strategies. The present research is applied and in terms of descriptive-correlational method, in which the questionnaire has been used to collect data. The population consists of 112 employees of Qom Power Distribution Company According to the Morgan table and random sampling method, 87 people are selected as samples. Data collected by structural equation software WarpPLS has been analyzed. The results of path analysis showed that social capital has a positive and significant effect on organizational innovation and dual knowledge management strategies and dual knowledge management strategies on organizational innovation.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63071_b58a0b3ca2e84768cf8b7fd679f5a385.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2017.236724.1408]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Effective Factors on Women's Social Capital in the Multi- Cultivate and Farmhouse Systems]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mirzaee, Khalil]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sepah Sepahpanah, Marjan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Movahedi, Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agricultural development]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Farmhouse system]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Multi-cultivate system]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Women's agricultural technologies]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The purpose of this study was to examine Effective factors on Social capital women in the the Multi- Cultivate and Farmhouse systems. The population for the study was 740 women of in the west of Iran (Hamadan Province). A sampling randomization resulted (Bartlett’s table) in a sample of 254 participants from the population. A survey questionnaire was constructed and used to collect data from randomly selected students and were analyzed by SPSS and Excel software’s. The results show that there are Significant differences between Social capital components in both systems. According to Leven test (<0.05) and Equality of variances, the family system is intercropping component of a sense of security and trust, valuing the life and capacity of differences among women, But in farmhouse system, more than components of friendship and family relationships, neighborhood associations, participation in local community and activism among women. In addition, the results of path analysis indicated that 0.61% of the social capital changes explain variables such as work experience, education, income and ownership of the land mass media. That is most effective education and mass media in increasing social capital among women.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_62095_790cf3eb1d269999e2a6df2ff470f452.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2017.62095]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Mediating Role of Social Capital in the Impact of Spiritual Leadership on Organizational Learning]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghashghaeizadeh, Nasrolah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ahmadi Nick, Fazel]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[organizational learning]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spiritual leadership]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The aim of this study was to investigate the mediating role of social capital variable in the impact of spiritual leadership on organizational learning. This study in term of purpose applied, and in terms of method quantitative and descriptive-correlation. The population included employee (N=2950) of the Khozestan Islamic Azad universities. 343 people were selected through stratified random. Data gathering instruments were 3 standard questionnaires includes spiritual leadership questionnaire, social capital questionnaire and organizational learning questionnaire. Data analysis is performed using equation modeling by LISREL software. The findings suggest that spiritual leadership has a significant positive impact on social capital. Social capital has a significant positive impact on organizational learning. At the same time, spiritual leadership through the mediation of social capital directly and indirectly affected the organizational learning.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63028_02c3834ff12b2b1b121ac3fd8635dc75.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2017.229120.1321]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Study Relationship between Efficacies of Spiritual Education with Emphasis on Islam with Social Capital (Case: Public Organizations in Sanandaj City)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ahmadi, Freyedon]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tavreh, Naser]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cognitive Capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Communication capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spirituality]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Structural Capital]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This research tries to identify the efficacy of spiritual education with an emphasis on Islam on social capital in public organizations in Sanandaj city. From the point of Islam, Spirituality is found meaning based on grate creature, it is rooted in the subconscious, it is effective in the evolution and guidance of the individual's life and Achieving spirituality is possible through religious guidance. The purpose of this study is to determine the extent to which there is a significant relationship between participation or non-participation of employees in spiritual education courses and their social capital?  Current study based on the objective is applied research and based on gathering data is quasi-experimental research and pretest-posttest design with a control group. For doing this study 60 volunteers from 5 public organizations according assigned to two experimental and control groups (each group 30 person), have been selected as sample. Then the experimental group received 10 sessions education spirituality. Using analysis of covariance differences the average social capital in two pre and post-test for both test and a control group was calculated. The results show that difference in averages pre and post-test of social capital and its dimension for experimental group is bigger than the control group. This means that the spiritual training based on Islamic teachings has been effective on the strengthening of employee's social capital.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63328_9522cfd4b22ea7b9dc5c8e3f4af21680.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2017.235845.1394]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[English Abstracts]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63981_a07e93a8f3d7c412b83286d3b5e85ddd.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2017.63981]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>