<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Physical Activity on Depression in the Elderly with an Emphasis on the Mediating Role of Social Capital</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر فعالیت بدنی بر افسردگی سالمندان با تأکید بر نقش میانجی سرمایۀ اجتماعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>23</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">73746</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2019.276844.1810</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>صابری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>صمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>گودرزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سلیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>عباسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to measure the effect of physical activity on depression in the elderly considering the mediating role of social capital. This study is an applied research in terms of purpose and a descriptive-correlational one based on structural equation modeling in terms of data collection methods. The statistical population of the study was all the elderly over 55 years old in Qom who had continuous physical activity and exercise. The sample consisted of 203 people who were selected through purposive sampling. In order to measure the variables, Karimiyan’s (1396) physical activity participation rate, Nahapiet and Ghoshal’s (1998) social capital, and Beck’s (1972) depression questionnaires were used. The validity of the questionnaires was confirmed based on a survey of 12 sports management professors, while their reliability coefficients were found through Cronbach&#039;s alpha to be 0.83, 0.87, and 0.79, respectively, using a pilot test. The findings of the study obtained through structural equation modeling showed that physical activity has a negative and significant effect on the elderly depression rate through the mediating role of social capital. As a result, social capital might effectively reduce the elderly depression rate by increasing social relationships, social support, and social trust obtained through participation in sports activities.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از پژوهش حاضر سنجش تأثیر فعالیت بدنی بر میزان افسردگی سالمندان با نقش میانجی سرمایة اجتماعی بود. این پژوهش از نظر هدف از پژوهش‌های کاربردی محسوب می‌شود و از حیث شیوة گردآوری داده‌ها پژوهشی توصیفی‌ـ همبستگی مبتنی بر معادلات ساختاری است. جامعة آماری پژوهش همة سالمندان بالای 55 سال شهر قم بودند که در فعالیت بدنی و ورزش مشارکت مستمر داشتند. نمونة آماری پژوهش شامل 203 نفر بود که به صورت هدفمند انتخاب شدند. برای سنجش متغیرها از پرسشنامة میزان مشارکت در فعالیت بدنی کریمیان (1396)، سرمایة اجتماعی ناهاپیت و گوشال (1998)، و افسردگی بک (1972) استفاده شد. روایی پرسشنامه‌ها با نظرخواهی از 12 استاد مدیریت ورزشی تأیید شد و پایایی آن در یک مطالعة مقدماتی از طریق آلفای کرونباخ به ترتیب 83/0 و 87/0 و 79/0 به دست آمد. یافته‏های تحقیق از طریق روش معادلات ساختاری نشان دادند فعالیت بدنی با میانجی‏گری سرمایة اجتماعی بر افسردگی سالمندان تأثیر منفی و معنادار می‌گذارد. در نتیجه سرمایة اجتماعی با افزایش روابط اجتماعی، حمایت اجتماعی، و اعتماد که از طریق شرکت در فعالیت‏های ورزشی به دست می‏آید بر کاهش میزان افسردگی سالمندان اثرگذار است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">افسردگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سالمندان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فعالیت بدنی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Corporate Social Responsibility and Firm Value: The Mediating Role of Earnings Management</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مسئولیت‏ پذیری اجتماعی و ارزش شرکت: نقش تعدیلگر مدیریت سود</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>25</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>58</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">71593</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2019.276161.1792</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امید</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرجی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار حسابداری، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>جنتی دریاکناری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ارشد حسابداری، دانشکدة مهندسی صنایع، مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه شهاب دانش، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کفسان</FirstName>
					<LastName>منصوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ارشد حسابداری، دانشکدة علوم اقتصادی و اجتماعی، دانشگاه بوعلی‏سینا، همدان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>یونسی مطیع</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ارشد حسابداری، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه قم، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>According to the agency theory, the company manager may use his discretion to maximize his personal welfare. Thus, on the one hand, he manages earnings and on the other hand – based on the entrenchment strategy – uses his discretion to conceal the negative effect of earnings management on the firm value by performing and disclosing real social responsibility activities or by formally disclosing such activities (where both will have a positive effect on the company reputation and stakeholders’ support). The main purpose of this paper is to examine the effect of earnings management on the relationship between social responsibility and the firm value. To this end, a sample of 150 companies listed in the Tehran Stock Exchange during the period 2011-2016 has been used to test the research hypotheses. The research findings obtained through regression analysis showed that carrying out social responsibility activities increases the value of the company in the stock market, but earnings management cannot affect the relationship between social responsibility and stock market value of the company. It seems that on the one hand, due to the novelty of the social responsibility discussion in Iran, both in its performing and disclosing, managers are not aware of the enveloping effect of the disclosure of social activities on the abuse of their discretion. On the other hand, because of the deficiencies in Iran&#039;s capital market, investors do not get aware of the lowered quality of social responsibility.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">طبق تئوری نمایندگی، مدیریت شرکت ممکن است از اختیارات خود جهت حداکثر کردن رفاه شخصی بهره ببرد. بدین‏ ترتیب، از یک سو به مدیریت سود پرداخته و از سوی دیگر، بر اساس استراتژی تحکیم‏بخشی، با استفاده از اختیار خود، می‏تواند آثار منفی مدیریت سود بر ارزش شرکت را با پرداختن به فعالیت‏های مسئولیت‏پذیری اجتماعی و افشای آن یا صرفاً افشای صوری این‏گونه فعالیت‏ها، که بر شهرت شرکت و حمایت ذی‏نفعان تأثیر مثبت می‌گذارد، مخفی کند. هدف از این پژوهش بررسی تأثیر مدیریت سود بر رابطة بین مسئولیت‌پذیری اجتماعی و ارزش شرکت بود. بدین منظور نمونه‌ای شامل 150 شرکت پذیرفته‏شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در سال‏های 1390 تا 1395 برای آزمون فرضیه‌های پژوهش مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. یافته‏های پژوهش بر اساس تحلیل رگرسیونی نشان داد فعالیت‏های مسئولیت‏پذیری اجتماعی ارزش بازار سهام شرکت را افزایش می‏دهد. اما مدیریت سود نمی‏تواند رابطۀ مسئولیت‏پذیری اجتماعی و ارزش بازار سهام شرکت را تحت تأثیر قرار دهد. به نظر می‏رسد با توجه به نو بودن موضوع مسئولیت‏پذیری اجتماعی در ایران، هم در بعد انجام فعالیت هم در بعد افشا، از یک طرف مدیران به اثر پوششی افشای فعالیت‏های اجتماعی بر سوءاستفاده از اختیاراتشان واقف نیستند و از طرف دیگر، به دلیل نقص در کارآیی بازار سرمایه در ایران، سرمایه‏گذاران به کیفیت مخدوش‏شدة مسئولیت‏پذیری اجتماعی پی نخواهند برد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اختیار مدیریتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استراتژی تحکیم ‏بخشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مسئولیت‏ پذیری اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Investigation of the Effect of External Social Capital on Dynamic Organizational Capabilities Considering the Mediating Role of Exchange Climate</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر سرمایۀ اجتماعی بیرونی بر قابلیت‏ های پویای سازمانی با تأکید بر نقش میانجی فضای مبادله</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>59</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>86</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">74839</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2020.292055.1934</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هانیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>قادری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترا، دانشکدة علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضایی دولت آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آذرنوش</FirstName>
					<LastName>انصاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Competing in international export markets poses considerable challenges to companies and calls for dynamic capabilities. This study aimed at identifying the dynamic capabilities necessary to be successful in export markets and investigating the effect of external social capital on identified dynamic capabilities considering the mediating role of exchange climate. The study was a mix-method research project, and included qualitative and quantitative phases. Semi-structured interviews and thematic analysis were used to collect and analyze qualitative data. Thematic analysis resulted in the extraction of five sub-themes and two broad themes for dynamic capabilities. The sub-themes of “export market exploitation” and “manufacturing flexibility capabilities” were categorized into the broad theme of “exploitation dynamic capabilities.” In addition, the sub-themes of “export market exploration”, “research and development”, and “export entrepreneurial orientation capabilities” were classified into the broad theme of “exploration dynamic capabilities.” In the quantitative phase, research population included export companies of Isfahan province selected as top export companies in 2016 and 2017. The statistical population was limited, so all of the population members were studied. The data was collected via a questionnaire and analyzed through structural equation modeling conducted by Smart PLS3. The obtained results indicated that external social capital positively influences dynamic capabilities and exchange climate. Moreover, the mediating role of exchange climate in the relationship between external social capital and dynamic capabilities was confirmed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">رقابت در بازارهای صادراتی با چالش‏های بسیار همراه است که در اختیار داشتن قابلیت‏های پویا را ضروری می‌سازد. پژوهش حاضر با هدف شناسایی قابلیت‏های پویایی که برای موفقیت در بازارهای صادراتی لازم است و بررسی تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعی بیرونی بر قابلیت‏های پویای شناسایی‌شده با نقش میانجی فضای مبادله انجام گرفت. پژوهش از نوع آمیخته و شامل دو بخش کیفی و کمّی است. برای جمع‏آوری و تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‏ها در بخش کیفی از مصاحبة نیمه‌ساختاریافته و تحلیل تم استفاده شد. پنج تم فرعی و دو تم اصلی برای قابلیت‏های پویا شناسایی شد. تم‏های فرعی قابلیت‏های بهره‏برداری بازار صادراتی و انعطاف‏پذیری تولید در قالب تم اصلی قابلیت‏های پویای بهره‏برداری قرار گرفت. تم‏های فرعی قابلیت‏های اکتشاف بازار صادراتی، پژوهش و توسعه، و کارآفرینی‏گرایی صادراتی در قالب تم اصلی قابلیت‏های پویای اکتشافی قرار داده شد. جامعة آماری در بخش کمّی شرکت‏های صادراتی استان اصفهان بود که در سال‏‏های 1395 و 1396 به عنوان صادرکنندة نمونه انتخاب شده بودند. به دلیل محدود بودن اندازة جامعه، نمونه‏گیری انجام نشد و جامعة آماری به صورت سرشماری بررسی شد. داده‏های پژوهش با استفاده از پرسشنامه جمع‏آوری و به شیوة مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری در نرم‏افزار  Smart PLS3تحلیل شد. نتایج پژوهش نشان داد سرمایة اجتماعی بر قابلیت‏های پویا و فضای مبادله تأثیر مثبت می‌گذارد. همچنین، نقش میانجی فضای مبادله در رابطة بین سرمایة اجتماعی و قابلیت‏های پویا تأیید شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فضای مبادله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قابلیت‏ پویا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Impact of Social Capital on Strategic Innovation with an Emphasis on the Mediating Role of Innovative Organizational Climate</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر نوآوری راهبردی با توجه به نقش تعدیلگر جوّ سازمانی نوآورانه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>87</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>109</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">75036</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2020.289889.1913</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالله</FirstName>
					<LastName>توکلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت، پژوهشگاه حوزه و دانشگاه، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>معتمدی گلوگاهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت دولتی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today’s fast-changing and uncertain business world has changed the competitive business environment, and organizations must pay attention to innovation to achieve success, growth, and competitive advantages. Accordingly, the main objective of this study was to examine the effect of social capital on strategic innovation in insurance companies of Tehran. Furthermore, the study intended to examine the role of innovative climate in strengthening or weakening the foregoing relationship. The study was comparative in terms of approach and a correlational survey in terms of data collection. To this end, after reviewing the literature and designing the conceptual model, a questionnaire consisting of 21 questions was distributed among 43 companies. At least three managers from every company answered the questions, and the average scores of their responses were analyzed. Face and content validity of the questionnaire was verified based on expert opinion and the use of a standard questionnaire, while its construct validity was ensured through confirmatory factor analysis. In addition, the reliability of the questionnaire was approved by the application of Cronbach&#039;s alpha test and composite reliability. Then, the collected data was analyzed using Smart PLS software through the correlation matrix, the structural equation modeling, and the model fitness analysis. Finally, it was found that social capital is effective on strategic innovation. In addition, the innovative organizational climate has a mediating role in the relationship between social capital and strategic innovation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه سرعت تغییرات و عدم اطمینان محیطی موجب تحول در محیط رقابتی کسب‌وکارها شده و سازمان‌ها باید برای موفقیت و رشد و کسب مزیت رقابتی به نوآوری توجه کنند. هدف اصلی پژوهش حاضر تحلیل تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعی بر نوآوری راهبردی در شرکت‏های بیمه واقع در شهر تهران بود. همچنین در این پژوهش به بررسی جو‌ّ سازمانی نوآورانه و نقش آن در تقویت یا تضعیف این رابطه پرداخته شد. رویکرد پژوهش قیاسی و استراتژی آن پیمایش از نوع همبستگی است. بر این اساس و پس از مرور پیشینه و طراحی مدل مفهومی‌ْ پرسشنامه‌ای مشتمل بر 21 پرسش با نمونة آماری متشکل از 43 شرکت ارائه شد. از هر شرکت دست‌کم سه نفر از مدیران ارشد به پرسش‌ها پاسخ دادند و میانگین نظر آن‌ها تحلیل شد. روایی صوری و محتوایی پرسشنامه بر اساس نظر متخصصان و استفاده از پرسشنامة استاندارد و روایی سازه نیز بر اساس تحلیل عاملی تأییدی تأیید شد. پایایی پرسشنامه نیز از طریق آزمون‌های آلفای کرونباخ، پایایی مرکب تأیید شد. سپس، داده‌های گردآوری‌شده به کمک نرم‌افزار اسمارت پی‌ال‌اس و از طریق ماتریس همبستگی، آزمون معادلات ساختاری، و آزمون برازش مدل تحلیل شدند. در نهایت، مشخص شد سرمایة اجتماعی بر نوآوری راهبردی تأثیرگذار است. همچنین، جو‌ّ نوآورانة سازمانی نیز در رابطة بین سرمایة اجتماعی و نوآوری راهبردی نقش تعدیلگر ایفا می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جو‌ّ سازمانی نوآورانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری راهبردی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Investigation of the Effect of Markazi Province NGOs’ Social Capital on Democracy</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر سرمایۀ اجتماعیِ تشکل‌های مردم‌نهاد استان مرکزی بر مردم‌سالاری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>111</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>134</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">75687</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2020.290257.1919</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میترا</FirstName>
					<LastName>بیات</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترا، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، نراق، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>خیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، نراق، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>پوریانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، نراق، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the key factors that influences democracy is social capital. The current study seeks to investigate the effect of social capital of Non-Governmental Organizations of Markazi province in Iran on democracy. The intended indicators of social capital are social trust, participation, and cohesion. To this end, the theories of Putnam, Coleman, and Fukuyama have been used. In addition, data collection was done through survey (using a questionnaire) and document analysis (using books and articles). Then, using Amos software and structural equation modeling, confirmatory factor analysis was performed, while the descriptive statistics were obtained using SPSS software. The Cronbach&#039;s alpha for 22 items was found to be 0.929, which is an acceptable rate of reliability. The statistical population included the members of Markazi province NGOs (1304 individuals), out of which a sample of 384 participants was selected using stratified random sampling based on the Cochran formula. The findings of the study revealed that the social capital of Markazi province NGOs has a positive and significant effect on democracy. It plays an important role in realizing the socio-cultural forefront of the Revolution, creating democratic institutions and developing a civil society, and synergizing all capacities to organize the political objectives of Iran, fight enemies, and face challenges ahead. NGOs should attract and use talented and young individuals to reach their goals. They should also have mutual relationships with various networks, organizations, governmental organizations, and different layers of people.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">از عوامل تأثیرگذار بر مردم‌سالاری عامل بسیار مهم سرمایة اجتماعی است. پژوهش حاضر به منظور بررسی تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعیِ تشکل‌های مردم‌نهاد استان مرکزی بر مردم‌سالاری انجام شد. شاخص‌های مورد نظر سرمایة اجتماعی اعتماد، مشارکت، و انسجام اجتماعی بودند. برای دستیابی به این هدف، از دیدگاه پاتنام و کلمن و فوکویاما و از روش پیمایشی (با ابزار پرسشنامه) و اسنادی (با استفاده از کتاب‌ها و مقالات) بهره گرفته شد و با استفاده از نرم‌افزار آموس و مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری تحلیل عاملی تأییدی انجام گرفت و به کمک نرم‌افزار SPSS شاخص‌های توصیفی به دست آمد. ضریب آلفای کرونباخ برای 22 گویه 929/0 و دارای پایایی قابل قبول بود. جامعة آماری اعضای تشکل‌های مردم‌نهاد استان مرکزی (1304 نفر) بودند و از نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌بندی‌شده استفاده شد. حجم نمونه بر اساس فرمول کوکران به طور سخت‌گیرانه 384 نفر بود. یافتة پژوهش این بود که سرمایة اجتماعی تشکل‌های مردم‌نهاد استان مرکزی بر مردم‌سالاری تأثیر مثبت و معنادار می‌گذارد و برای تحقق جبهة فرهنگی‌ـ اجتماعی انقلاب و هم‌افزایی استعدادها و ظرفیت‌ها به منظور سامان دادن به اهداف سیاسی نظام و مبارزه با دشمنان و شفاف‌سازی چالش‌های پیش رو و ایجاد نهادهای دموکراتیک و توسعة جامعة مدنی نقشی مهم ایفا می‌کند. در این زمینه باید از نیروهای مستعد و جوان استفاده کرد. آن‌ها باید از سرمایة خود برای پیشبرد اهدافشان نهایت بهره را ببرند و با شبکه‌ها و تشکل‌های متفاوت و سازمان‌های دولتی و آحاد مردم روابط متقابل برقرار کنند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتماد اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تشکل‌های مردم‌نهاد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مردم‌سالاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشارکت اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Validation of the Persian Version of the Social Capital Questionnaire in Recreational-Sports Clubs</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اعتبارسنجی نسخۀ فارسی پرسشنامۀ سرمایۀ اجتماعی در باشگاه‌های تفریحی‌ـ ورزشی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>135</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>154</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">75688</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2020.294942.1959</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رسول</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوروزی سید حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه تربیت‌بدنی، دانشکدة علوم انسانی، دانشگاه تربیت‌مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0575-6811</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عرفان</FirstName>
					<LastName>مرادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترا، مدیریت ورزشی، دانشکدة علوم انسانی، دانشگاه تربیت‌مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6400-8058</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Considering the importance of the social capital subject and its unique role in the context of a multifaceted phenomenon such as sports that can underpin various interdisciplinary studies and be of interest to researchers, the necessity of having a valid and reliable instrument matching the context of sports is increasingly felt. Therefore, this study aimed at determining the validity and reliability of the Persian version of the Social Capital Questionnaire in recreational-sports clubs by Forsell, Tower, and Polman (2018). The methodology of this study is descriptive-survey, and in terms of purpose, it is an applied study. The power-based sample size estimation was performed using SPSS Sample Power software. Indices such as confirmatory factor analysis based on structural equation modeling were used to evaluate the validity and reliability of the tool. In addition, maximum and average shared variance (for discriminant validity), average variance extracted (for convergent validity), and Cronbach&#039;s alpha and combined reliability (to estimate internal consistency and component reliability) were used. The results of all indices showed the desirable evaluation of the instrument in the sport context. In other words, empirical data supported the theoretical model of research. Therefore, it is recommended that the Persian version of the Social Capital questionnaire in the sports context can be used as a suitable tool for studying and evaluating the social capital in sports.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با توجه به اهمیت موضوع سرمایة اجتماعی و نقش بی‌بدیل آن در بستر پدیده‌ای چندوجهی همچون ورزش، که می‌تواند زمینه‌ساز پژوهش‌های مختلف بین‌‌رشته‌ای باشد و پژوهشگران بدان توجه کنند، ضرورت داشتن ابزاری معتبر و پایا منطبق بر بستر ورزش بیش از پیش احساس می‌شود. بنابراین، هدف از پژوهش حاضر اعتبارسنجی نسخة فارسی پرسشنامة سرمایة اجتماعی در باشگاه‌های تفریحی‌ـ ورزشی فورسل، تاور، و پلمن (2018) بود. روش‌شناسی پژوهش حاضر توصیفی‌ـ پیمایشی و بر اساس هدف از نوع مطالعات کاربردی است. برآورد حجم نمونه مبتنی بر توان با استفاده از نرم‌افزار SPSS Sample power انجام پذیرفت. به جهت ارزیابی روایی و پایایی ابزار مورد نظر از شاخص‌هایی همچون تحلیل عاملی تأییدی مبتنی بر مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری، حداکثر و متوسط واریانس اشتراک‌گذاشته‌شده (جهت تشخیص اعتبار ممیز)؛ متوسط واریانس استخراج‌شده (جهت تشخیص اعتبار همگرا)؛ آلفای کرونباخ و پایایی ترکیبی (جهت برآورد همسانی درونی و پایایی سازه) استفاده شد و نتایج همة شاخص‌ها از ارزیابی مطلوب ابزار مورد نظر در بستر ورزش حکایت داشت. به بیانی دیگر داده‌های تجربی از مدل نظری پژوهش حمایت کرد. بنابراین، پیشنهاد می‌شود از نسخة فارسی پرسشنامة سرمایة اجتماعی در بستر ورزش به منزلة ابزاری مناسب برای مطالعه و ارزیابی سرمایة اجتماعی در ورزش استفاده کرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتبارسنجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اوقات فراغت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ورزش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
