<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1394</YEAR>
<VOL>2</VOL>
<NO>1</NO>
<MOSALSAL>1</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>154</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی رابطۀ هوش عاطفی و سرمایۀ اجتماعی در تشکل‌های مردم نهاد(NGOs)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The relationship between emotional intelligence and social Capital in Non- Governmental Organization (NGOs)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>سرمایۀ اجتماعی به‌دلیل فوایدی که دارد، جایگاهی عالی در نظریات اجتماعی، اقتصادی و سیاسی به‌دست آورده است. با توجه‌ به کارکردهای مثبت سرمایۀ اجتماعی، شناخت منابع و راهکارهای تقویت آن، پیامدهای مفیدی برای جامعه در بر دارد. در این ‌میان، توجه به بسترهای روان‌شناختی که «هوش عاطفی» یکی از مهم‌ترین آنهاست، اهمیت ویژه‌ای دارد. ازاین‌رو، هدف تحقیق حاضر، بررسی رابطۀ هوش عاطفی و سرمایۀ اجتماعی در تشکل‌های مردم‌نهاد استان قم است. با توجه ‌به نقش تسهیلگری NGOها در شکل‌گیری گروه و ایجاد سرمایۀ اجتماعی، در این پژوهش اعضای مؤثرNGO های استان قم، به تعداد 859 نفر، به‌عنوان جامعۀ آماری انتخاب شدند. از این جامعه، نمونه‌ای به حجم 265 نفر با شیوۀ نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌ای انتخاب شد. این تحقیق ازنظر هدف تحقیق، کاربردی و ازنظر نحوۀ گردآوری داده‌ها، توصیفی و از نوع هم‌بستگی است. برای سنجش متغیرها، از پرسش‌نامۀ هوش عاطفی سیبریا شرینگ (آلفای کرونباخ 845/0) و پرسش‌نامۀ سرمایۀ اجتماعی ناهاپیت و قشال (آلفای کرونباخ 865/0) استفاده شد. نتایج آزمون اسپیرمن نشان داد بین هوش عاطفی و سرمایۀ اجتماعی رابطۀ مستقیمی وجود دارد. ضریب هم‌بستگی به‌دست‌آمده نیز مثبت و برابر 469/0 بود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The benefits of social capital make a higher position in the views of the social, economic and political. Due to the positive functions of social capital, resources cognition and solutions of reinforce can have positive outcomes for society. In the meantime, attention to psychological grounds that &quot;emotional intelligence&quot; is one of the most important has a particular importance. The purpose of this study is to investigate the relationship between emotional intelligence and social capital of Qom province NGOs organizations. Given the role of NGOs facilitation in the formation of group and social capital, In this study, 859 persons was selected as effective members of statistical population of NGO Qom province, this community sample of 265 people were selected by random Stratified sampling method. The purpose of this study aimed to applied research, and the data collection methods, are descriptive and the correlation type. To measure the variables, have been used emotional intelligence questionnaire Sybrya Schering (Cronbach&#039;s alpha 0.845) and social capital Nahapyt and Qshal questionnaire (Cronbach&#039;s alpha 0.865). Spearman test results showed there is a direct relationship between emotional intelligence and social capital and achieved correlation coefficient is positive and equal to 0.469.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>22</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زارعی متین</Family>
						<NameE>Hasan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zaree Matin</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>matin@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی اکبر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قنبری</Family>
						<NameE>Ali Akbar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghanbari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، دانشگاه علوم تحقیقات، واحد ساوه، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aliakbarghambari@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مرضیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قانع</Family>
						<NameE>Marziah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Qane</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، دانشگاه علوم تحقیقات، واحد ساوه، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mqe51@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تشکل‌های مردم‌نهاد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایۀ اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هوش عاطفی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF> آقایار، سیروس؛ شریفی، پرویز (1386)، هوش هیجانی سازمانی، تهران، انتشارات سپاهان.## بردبار، غلام‌رضا؛ کنجکاو منفرد، امیررضا (1390)، &quot;بررسی نقش هوش عاطفی در راهبردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی&quot;، دو ماهنامه توسعه انسانی پلیس، سال 8، شماره 34، صفحات 119 – 139.##برومند، زهرا؛ جلیلی، سودابه (1388)، &quot;بررسی تأثیر هوش عاطفی، سرمایۀ اجتماعی و توسعه منابع انسانی بر بهره وری شرکت همشهری&quot;، ‌پژوهش­نامه مدیریت و سرمایۀ اجتماعی ، شماره 40 صفحات 107 – 134.##تسلیمی، محمد سعید؛ منوریان، عباس؛ آشنا، مصطفی (1385)، &quot; بررسی رابطه بین سرمایه اجتماعی و کارآفرینی درون سازمانی&quot;،  فرهنگ مدیریت، شماره14، صفحات27-56.## داودآبادی، مریم؛ زارعی، ریحانه (1390)، &quot;مفاهیم، مدل­ها و کارکردهای هوش عاطفی در سازمان و چگونگی اندازه‌گیری آن&quot;، نشریه راهبرد، دانشگاه تهران، شماره 6، صفحات 113 – 138.## زارعی متین، حسن (1392)، مدیریت رفتار سازمانی پیشرفته، تهران، نشر آگه.## زارعی متین، حسن؛ مقیمی، محمد؛ غفوریان یاورپناه، هادی (1392)، &quot;تحلیل رابطه فرهنگ‌سازمانی کارآفرینانه و هوش عاطفی&quot; فصل­نامه مدیریت فرهنگ‌سازمانی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، زمستان 1392، دوره 11 شماره 4، صفحات 5 - 31.##8.       سکاران، اوما (1384)، روش‌های تحقیق در مدیریت، ترجمه صائبی، شیرازی، تهران، انتشارات موسسه عالی آموزش و پژوهش مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی.## عباس زاده ، حمید (1390)، مدیریت در سازمان­های مردم نهاد، تهران، انتشارات گنج دانش.## علینی، محمد (1391)، سرمایه اجتماعی در آموزه‌های اسلامی، دانشگاه باقرالعلوم(ع)، قم، موسسه بوستان کتاب چاپ اول، مرکز چاپ و نشر دفتر تبلیغات اسلامی حوزه علمیه قم.## غریبی، ‌حسن؛ زلیخا، ‌قلی­زاده (1390)، ‌&quot;نقش مؤلفه‌های هوش هیجانی در پیش‌بینی سرمایۀ اجتماعی در دانشجویان دانشگاه آزاد منطقه 11&quot;،‌ فصل­نامه اندیشه‌های تازه در علوم تربیتی ،‌سال هفتم،‌ شماره اول، ‌زمستان 1390، صفحات 30 – 54.## فوکویاما، فرانسیس (1379)، پایان نظم، سرمایه اجتماعی و حفظ آن، ترجمه غلام عباس توسلی، تهران، جامعه ایران.## فیضی، طاهره؛ عابدینی، سعید (1389)، &quot;بررسی رابطه هوش عاطفی و سرمایه اجتماعی&quot; ( مطالعه موردی مرکز تحقیقات صدا و سیما)، پژوهش­نامه اقتصاد و کسب ‌و کار، سال اول، شماره یک، تابستان 1389، صفحات 43 – 58.## قلیچ لی، بهروز (1385)، &quot;تبیین نقش سرمایه اجتماعی و سرمایه فکری در مزیت رقابتی&quot;، رساله دکترا، تهران، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس.##آینده بان، رسانه تخصصی آینده پژوهی، گزارش آینده­پژوهی ایران (1393)، برگرفته از:##http://www.ayandeban.ir## گلمن، دانیل (1995)، هوش هیجانی، ترجمه نسرین پارسا، (1383)، تهران، چاپ سوم.## مقیمی، سید محمد (1383)، کارآفرینی در نهادهای جامعه مدنی – پژوهشی در سازمان‌های غیردولتی(NGOS) ایران، تهران، انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.## نمازی، باقر؛ اختری، شهلا (1381)، بررسی وضعیت تشکل‌های مردمی داوطلب در جمهوری اسلامی ایران، تهران، انتشارات سازمان شهرداری‌های کشور.## Bardzil, P.; Slaski, M. (2003), Emotional intelligence: Fundamental competencies for enhanced service provision. Managing Service Quality: An International Journal, 13(2), 97-104.## Bolino, M. C.; Turnley, W. H.; Bloodgood, J. M. (2002), Citizenship behavior and the creation of social capital in organizations. Academy of management review, 27(4), 505-522.## Carmeli, A. (2003), The relationship between emotional intelligence and work attitudes, behavior and outcomes: An examination among senior managers. Journal of managerial Psychology, 18(8), 788-813.## Lee, M.; Lee, S. (2008), The influence of emotional intelligence and organizational climate for nurse job satisfaction. Journal of Business Administration, 4(1), 1-10.## Chrusciel, D. (2006), Considerations of emotional intelligence (EI) in dealing with change decision management. Management decision, 44(5), 644-657.## Cohen, D.; Prusak, L. (2001), In good company: How social capital makes organizations work. Harvard Business Press.## Goleman, D. (1998), Working with emotional intelligence. Bantam.## Leana, C. R.; Van Buren, H. J. (1999), Organizational social capital and employment practices. Academy of management review, 24(3), 538-555.##Lewis, D. (2006), The Management of Non-Governmental Development Organizations 2e. Routledge.## Lin, S. C.; Huang, Y. M. (2005), The role of social capital in the relationship between human capital and career mobility: Moderator or mediator?. Journal of Intellectual Capital, 6(2), 191-205.## Nahapiet, J.; Ghoshal, S. (1998), Social capital, intellectual capital, and the organizational advantage. Academy of management review, 23(2), 242-266.## Ratten, V.; Suseno, Y. (2006), Knowledge development, social capital and alliance learning. International Journal of Educational Management, 20(1), 60-72.## USAID (1995), new partnership initiative, NGO empowerment, NPI core report, Washington D.C.## Vilanova, P. T.; Josa, R. T. (2003), Social capital as a managerial phenomenon. Department of Industrial Engineering &amp; Management, Tampere university of Technology.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی نقش مهار سرمایۀ روان شناختی رهبر در ایجاد سرمایۀ روان شناختی کارکنان: نقش میانجی درک کارکنان از تحول‌آفرینی رهبر (مورد مطالعه: سازمان‌های نوپا و یا در حال تحول)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the role of harnessing the psychological capital of leader in developing the psychological capital of employees: The moderating role of employees’ perception of transformational leadership</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>چگونگی ایجاد سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی، وجه فراموش‌شدۀ مطالعات سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی است. در این مقاله، مدل مفهومی ایجاد سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی کارکنان، با به‌کارگیری مهار سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی رهبر ارائه شده است. گفتنی است تحول‌آفرینی رهبر، نقشی بسیار مهم در ایجاد سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی دارد و حتی مانند متغیر میانجی عمل می‌کند. در این پژوهش، 33 شرکت نوپا یا در حال تحول در استان‌های تهران، البرز، اصفهان و آذربایجان غربی بررسی شدند. پرسش‌نامه‌ها میان 142 مدیر و 573 کارمند این سازمان‌ها توزیع شد. نتایج مدل معادلات ساختاری، این موضوع را تأیید کرد که مهار سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی رهبر، سبب ایجاد رابطه میان سبک رهبری تحول‌آفرین و افزایش درک کارکنان می‌شود. همچنین این نتایج، رابطۀ میان درک کارکنان از تحول‌آفرینی رهبر و ایجاد سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی مثبت را تأیید کرد. با توجه‌ به نتایج این پژوهش، به مدیرانی که می‌خواهند در سازمان‌های خود، سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی ایجاد کنند، دلالت‌ها و توصیه‌هایی کاربردی ارائه شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>How psychological capital (PsyCap) can be developed in organizations, is the left side of PsyCap studies. A conceptual model of developing PsyCap of employees by harnessing the PsyCap of leader has been developed in this article that Employees’ Perception of Transformational Leadership (EPTL) plays a moderator role in this model. Because of key role of EPTL in this model, 33 start-ups or changing organizations in Tehran, Alborz, Isfahan, and Azerbayjan Gharbi were studied, and questionnaires have distributed among 142 managers and 573 employees. The results of structural equations modeling (SEM) verified the relation of EPTL and developing the PsyCap of themselves. Considering to the results of this study, some implications and practical guides to the managers who want to develop PsyCap in their organizations will be offered.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>23</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>48</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عباس علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رستگار</Family>
						<NameE>Abbas-Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rastgar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار دانشکدۀ اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اداری، دانشگاه سمنان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار دانشکدۀ اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اداری،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a_rastgar_2005@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بابک</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>وطن‌دوست</Family>
						<NameE>Babak</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Vatandoost</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، پردیس فارابی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>vatandoost@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قنبرزاده میان دهی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghanbarzadeh Miandehi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه شهیدبهشتی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه شهیدبهشتی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>r.ghanbarzadeh@mail.sbu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ایجاد سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>درک کارکنان از تحول‌آفرینی رهبر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدل معادلات ساختاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Avey, J. B. (2014). The left side of psychological capital: new evidence on the antecedents of psycap. Journal of Leadership &amp; Organizational Studies, 21(2), 141-149.##Avey, J. B., Reichard, R., Luthans, F., &amp; Mhatre, K. (2011). Meta-analysis of the impact of positive psychological capital on employee attitudes, behaviors and performance. Human Resource Development Quarterly, 22, 127-152.##Avolio, B. J. (1999). Full leadership development: Building the vital forces in organizations. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.##Bandura, A. (2000). Cultivate self-efficacy for personal and organizational effectiveness. In E. A. Locke (Ed.), The Blackwell handbook of principles of organizational behavior (pp. 120- 136). Oxford, UK: Blackwell.##Bass, B. M. (1985). Leadership and performance beyond expectations. New York: Free Press.##Bass, B. M. (1990). Handbook of leadership (3rd ed.). New York: Free Press.##Bass, B. M. (1998). Transformational leadership: Industry, military, and education impact. Mahwah, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum.##Bass, B. M.,Avolio, B. J., Jung, D. I., &amp; Berson,Y. (2003). Predicting unit performance by assessing transformational and transactional leadership. Journal of Applied Psychology, 88: 207-218.##Brissette, I., Scheier, M. F., &amp; Carver, C. S. (2002). The role of optimism in social network development, coping, and psychological adjustment during a life transition. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 82: 102-111.##Carver, C., &amp; Scheier, M. (2002). Optimism. In C. R. Snyder &amp; S. Lopez (Eds.), Handbook of positive psychology: 231-243. Oxford, UK: Oxford University Press.##Conger, J. A., &amp; Kanungo, R. (1987). Toward a behavioral theory of charismatic leadership in organizational settings. Academy of Management Review, 12: 637-647.##Eisenbach, R., Watson, K., &amp; Pillai, R. (1999). Transformational Leadership in the context of organizational change. Journal of Organizational Change, 12(2), 80-88.##Feldman, B. L., &amp; Gross, J. (2001). Emotional intelligence: A process model of emotion representation and regulation. In T. J. Mayne &amp; G. A. Bonnano (Eds.), Emotions: Current issues and future directions: 286-310. New York: Guilford.##Fitzgerald, T. E., Tennen, H., Affleck, G., &amp; Pransky, G. S. (1993). The relative importance of dispositional optimism and control appraisals in quality of life after coronary artery bypass surgery. Journal of Behavioral Medicine, 16: 25-43.##Gooty, J., Galvin, M., Johnson, P., Frazier, M., &amp; Snow, D. (2009). In the eyes of the beholder: transformational leadership, positive psychological capital, and performance. Journal of Leadership &amp; Organizational Studies, 15, 353-367.##Helland, M., &amp; Winston, B. (2005). Towards a deeper understanding of hope and leadership. Journal of Leadership &amp; Organizational Studies, 12(2), 42-54.##Law, K. S., Wong, C., &amp; Mobley, W. H. (1998). Toward a taxonomy of multidimensional constructs. Academy of Management Review, 23, 741-755.##Luthans, F. (2002). Positive organizational behavior: Developing and managing psychological strengths. Academy of Management Executive, 16, 57-72.##Luthans, F., Avolio, B., Avey, J. B., &amp; Norman, S. M. (2007). Psychological capital: Measurement and relationship with performance and job satisfaction. Personnel Psychology, 60, 541–572.##Luthans, F., Vogelgesang, G., &amp; Lester, P. (2006). Developing the psychological capital of resiliency. Human Resource Development Review, 5(1), 25-44.##Luthans, F., &amp; Youssef, C. M. (2004). Human, social and now positive psychological capital management: Investing in people for competitive advantage. Organizational Dynamics33(2), 143–160.##Luthans, F., &amp; Youssef, C. M. (2007). Emerging positive organizational behavior. Journal of Management, 33: 321-349.##Luthans, F., Youssef, C. M., &amp; Avolio, B. J. (2007). Psychologicalcapital. New York, NY: Oxford University Press.##Masten, A. S. (2001). Ordinary magic: Resilience processes in development. American Psychologist, 56: 227-239.##Mayer, R. C., Davis, J. H., &amp; Schoorman, D. F. (1995). An integrative view of organizational trust. Academy of Management Review, 20: 709-734.##Norman, S., Luthans, B., &amp; Luthans, K. (2005). The proposed contagion effect of hopeful leaders on the resiliency of employees and organizations. Journal of Leadership and Organization Studies, 12(2), 55-64.##Peterson, S., Walumbwa, F., Byron, K., &amp; Myrowitz, J. (2009). CEO positive traits, transformational leadership, and firm performance in high-technology start-up and established firms. Journal of Management, 35 (2), 348-368.##Peterson, S. J., &amp; Byron, K. (2007). Exploring the role of hope in job performance: Results from four studies. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 28, 785–803.##Scheier, M. F., &amp; Carver, C. S. (1985). Optimism, coping, and health: Assessment and implications of generalized outcome expectancies. Health Psychology, 4: 219-247.##Segerstrom, S. C., Taylor, S. E., Kemeny, M. E., &amp; Fahey, J. L. (1998). Optimism is associated with mood, coping, and immune change in response to stress. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 74: 1646-1655.##Seligman, M. E. P. (1998). Learned optimism. New York, NY: Pocket Books.##Snyder, C. R. (2000). Handbook of hope: Theory, measures and applications. San Diego, CA: Academic Press.##Snyder, C. R., Harris, C., Anderson, J. R., Holleran, S. A., Irving. L. M., Sigmon, S. T., Yoshinobu, L., Gibb, J., Langelle, C., &amp; Harney, P. (1991). The will and the ways: Development and validation of an individual differences measure of hope. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 60, 570-585.##Snyder, C. R., &amp; Shorey, H. (2003). Hope and leadership. In K. Christensen (Ed.), Encyclopedia of leadership. Harrison, NY: Berkshire.##Stajkovic, A., &amp; Luthans, F. (1998). Self-efficacy and workrelated performance: A meta-analysis. Psychological Bulletin, 124, 240-261.##Waldman, D. A., Ramirez, G. G., House, R. J., &amp; Puranam, P. (2001). Does leadership matter? CEO leadership attributes and profitability under conditions of perceived environmental uncertainty. Academy of Management Journal, 44: 134-143.##Wenglert, L., &amp; Rosen, A. (1995). Optimism, self-esteem, mood and subjective health. Personality and Individual Differences, 18: 653-661.##Werner, E., &amp; Smith, R. S. (1992). Overcoming the odds: High risk children from birth to adulthood. Ithaca, NY: Cornell University.##Youssef-Morgan, C. (2014). Advancing OB research: an illustration using psychological capital. Journal of Leadership and Organization Studies, 21(2), 130-140.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>سنجش میزان تأثیر سرمایه اجتماعی برخلاقیت کارکنان (مورد مطالعه : شرکت های تولیدی لوازم خانگی الکتریکی و الکترونیکی درایران)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluating the impact of social capital on employees’ creativity (Case study: electrical and electronic household appliances manufacturing companies in Iran)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>سازمان‌ها برای اینکه بتوانند در جهان پیچیده و متغیر امروز به حیات خود ادامه دهند، باید خلاقیت و نوآوری را به‌عنوان استراتژی ضروری در عصر کنونی درنظر بگیرند. با توجه‌ به اهمیت خلاقیت و نوآوری، در این پژوهش سعی بر آن است که با بررسی نقش سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر خلاقیت کارکنان، گامی مثبت در راستای ارتقای عملکرد سازمان‌ها برداشته شود. هدف کلی این تحقیق، بررسی تأثیر سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر خلاقیت کارکنان است. تحقیق حاضر، توصیفی‌پیمایشی و از نوع هم‌بستگی و ازنظر هدف کاربردی است. جامعۀ آماری در این پژوهش شامل همۀ کارشناسان و مدیران متعلق به چهار شرکت تولیدی لوازم خانگی الکتریکی و الکترونیکی در ایران است که 146 نفر از آنها به روش نمونه‌گیری سهمیه‌ای انتخاب شدند. برای جمع‌آوری داده‌های تحقیق از پرسش‌نامه استفاده شد. برای بررسی آزمون فرضیه‌ها از روش حداقل مربعات جزئی و نرم‌افزار  Pls -Smart استفاده شد. نتایج این تحقیق نشان می‌دهد سرمایۀ اجتماعی با ابعاد اعتماد اجتماعی، شبکه و هنجار مشترک، تعاون و همکاری متقابل، انسجام و هم‌بستگی جمعی، همدلی و مشارکت و هویت جمعی، تأثیر مثبت و معنی‌داری بر خلاقیت کارکنان دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Organizations should consider innovation and creativity as an essential strategy in order to keep their existence in today complex and change able world. According to the importance of creativity and innovation, the aim of this paper is to improve organizations&#039; performance by study the role of social capital on employees&#039; creativity. The total target of this research is survey on the effect of social capital on employees&#039; innovation. The type of present research is descriptive in the form of correlation and according to its aim is practical. The population of this project consists of all of the managers and experts who work in 4 electric and electronics household manufacturing companies in Iran. According to quato sampling method, 146 persons have been selected among this population. The questionnaire has been used for the collection of research data. In this research for studying of the hypothesis tests, the Partial least squares and (smart-pls) is used. the results of the research shows that the dimensions of social capital (social trust, network and common norm, mutual cooperative and cooperation, collective cohesion, empathy and participation, and collective identity has positive and significant effect on creativity of employees.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>49</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>74</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>میر هادی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>موذن جمشیدی</Family>
						<NameE>Mir Hadi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moazen Jamshidi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه پیام‌نور، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه پیام‌نور،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>jamshidi.hadi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نرجس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حق پرست کنارسری</Family>
						<NameE>Narjes</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Haghparast Kenarsari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام‌نور، رشت، گیلان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام‌نور،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>haghparast.matin@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خلاقیت کارکنان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایۀ اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شرکت‌های تولیدی لوازم خانگی الکتریکی و الکترونیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ابراهیم زاده انتظام، نفیسه (1387)، لوازم خانگی صنعتی در باد. روزنامه ایران، سال چهاردهم، شماره 410، صفحه 9.  ## 2 . ابیلی، خدایار، فرجی ده سرخی، حاتم، شاطری، کریم، یوزباشی، علیرضا ( 1389)، بررسی       رابطه سرمایه اجتماعی و تمایل به نوآوری در کارکنان دانشگاه تهران.دوماهنامه                                علمی، پژوهشی،دانشگاه شاهد، سال هفدهم دوره جدید، شماره45، صفحات 79-90         .    3 . اشرف نظری، علی  (1386)،همبستگی و وحدت یابی جمعی: تأملی بر ابعاد فردی و                 جمعی هویت. مجله علمی تخصصی تاریخ پژوهان.انجمن تاریخ‌پژوهان ایران.  سال                سوم.شماره   12                                         .  ##4. امیدوار، اسیه ( 1392)، خانواده و مشاوره ، مهارت­های زندگی،راه و رسم همدلی.روزنامه              خراسان صبح امروزایران، شماره 18520، صفحه6                                            .##5. امین بیدختی، علی اکبر، نظری، ماشاالله  (1388)، ارایه یک مدل نظری با استفاده از مولفه           های سرمایه اجتماعی برای ایجاد سازمان دانش محور: راهکاری جهت بهبود عملکرد             اقتصادی، دانشگاه سمنان، همایش ملی سرمایه اجتماعی و توسعه اقتصادی سمنان.           6. پیران، محمد، شوقی، بهزاد، آقاجانی، طهمورث، رضا زاده، آرش، دهقان نجم آبادی، عامر        (1391 )، بررسی تأثیر سرمایه اجتماعی بر خلاقیت کارکنان در صنایع ریخته گری . فصلنامه    ابتکار و خلاقیت در علوم انسانی. سال 2, شماره1، صفحات 163-182.##7. حسن پور، اکبر، نیاکان، نازیلا  (1386)،  سرمایه اجتماعی و جنسیت در محیط کار. ماهنامه تدبیر، سال هجدهم، شماره 183.##8. حمیدی زاده، علی؛ شهیدزاده، فریبا؛ موحدی فر، عرفانه (1393)، بررسی تاثیر مولفه های سرمایه اجتماعی بر نوآوری سازمانی(مورد مطالعه: اداره کل مخابرات شهرستان قم)، نشریه مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی،دوره 1، شماره 2، صفحات 203-223.##9. حیدر ابادی، ابوالقاسم  (1389)،  اعتماد اجتماعی و عوامل اجتماعی- فرهنگی موثر بر آن      مطالعه موردی جوانان 20 تا 29 ساله استان مازندران)، مجله مطالعات جامعه شناختی         جوانان، سال اول، پیش شماره1، صفحات 39-66.                                                 10. رابینز، استیفن پی(1390)، مبانی رفتار سازمانی، ترجمه علی پارسیان، سید محمد اعرابی،      تهران: دفتر پژوهش­های فرهنگی.                                ##11. رجایی پور، سعید، چوپانی، حیدر، زار ع خلیلی، مجتبی، غلا م زاده، حجت، کاظم پور،            مریم (1392)، نقش سرمایه اجتماعی در گرایش به نوآوری کارکنان در شرکت سهامی          بیمه معلم. فصلنامه مدیریت و توسعه. دوره 26, شماره 1، صفحات 161-189.            ##12. رضازاده، حسین، اقازاده، هاشم (1383)، کارافرینی سازمانی، تدبیر، شماره153##13. سید نقوی، میرعلی، عباس­پور،حسین( 1389)،تحلیل رابطه توانمندی و خلاقیت نیروی        انسانی­بافرهنگ سازمانی .فصلنامه­مدیریت­ومنابع انسانی­درصنعت­ نفت،شماره11، صفحات       77 -100.                 ##14. شهبازی، مظفرالدین، قربانی، فاطمه (1389)، عوامل موثر بر گرایش دانشجویان دانشگاه          تبریز به عضویت در تعاونی­های اشتغالزا. تعاون، سال بیست و یکم،شماره 4،صفحات1- 28. 15 . شیری، نعمت الله، میرک زاده، علی اصغر، ادریس اله ویسی، محمد، کرمی دارابخانی، رویا      (1391)، نقش سرمایه اجتماعی دریادگیری سازمان کارکنان سازمان جهاد کشاورزی­استان      کردستان، مجله اقتصاد و توسعه کشاورزی، مقاله 12،دوره43،شماره3،صفحات447- 459.##16. صالحی امیری، سیدرضا، باباخانی، لیلا (1387)، بررسی خلاقیت به عنوان پیش درآمدی        بر کارآفرینی« کانون پرورش فکری کودکان و نوجوانان » با رویکردی به در پرورش               خلاقیت،پژوهشنامه فرهنگ و کارافرینی، شماره32،صفحات1-60.                               17.  طغرایی، محمد تقی، رضوانی، مهران (1390)، نقش آفرینی سرمایه اجتماعی سازمانی در          گرایش به نوآوری سازمانی درشرکت های دانش بنیان،مورد مطالعه: شرکت­های مستقر در       پارک علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران.پژوهش نامه مدیریت تحول، سال سوم، شمارة 6 ،              صفحات 28-53.                                                  ##18. فصیحی، امان الله (1386)، دین و سرمایه اجتماعی، مجله معرفت، شماره123،                                  صفحات79-100.                                         ## 19. کاظمی نربین، مریم (1391)، بررسی رابطه سرمایه اجتماعی با افزایش خلاقیت در             کارکنان سازمان­های دولتی و خصوصی استان آذربایجان شرقی،پایان نامه کارشناسی               ارشد، دانشگاه پیام نور تهران،دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری.                                    20. گل دهان، طیبه، شاه طالبی، بدری ، خدری، علی (1392)،تبیین رابطه بین ابعاد                 سرمایه  اجتماعی و خلاقیت سازمانی در بین کارکنان ستادی اداره کل آموزش و                پرورش استان  اصفهان، کنفرانس بین المللی مدیریت چالش ها و راهکارها.                       ##21. مقیمی، سید محمد ( 1388)، سازمان و مدیریت:رویکردی پژوهشی،چاپ دوم، تهران،                                   انتشارات ترمه.                                                                  ##22. نظری، غلامرضا، نیکچه فراهانی، حمید  (1388)، نقش سرمایه اجتماعی در بهره وری                   نیروی کار. تدبیر، سال  نوزدهم، شماره202 ، صفحات43-49.                               ##23.    Aparna, M. &amp; Smita, P.) 2014(, “Fostering student creativity using brain-based     learning”,Scholarly Research Journal&#039;s, I/IV, pp. 549-560##24.   Ahrweiler, M. and T. Keane. (2013), “Innovation networks”, Mind &amp; Society,      Vol.12, No.1, pp. 73-90.##  25.    Agrifoglio, R., Metallo, C. (2011), “Virtual Environment and Collaborative         Work: The Role of Relationship Quality in Facilitating Individual Creativity”,      In   Information Technology and Innovation Trends in Organizations,                     Heidelberg, Germany, Physica- Verlag HD, pp. 389-397.                          ##26.   Akbari, P., Baharestan, O. (2013), “The Analysis of the Impact of Information Technology and Social Capital on Entrepreneurial Orientation in Iran Pharmaceutical Industry (Case Study: Alborz Drug Company)”, International Journal of Management and Business, 3, pp.215-232.##27. Cadima, R. Ojeda, J. &amp; Monguet, J.M. (2012), “Social Networks and Performance in Distributed Learning Communities”, Educational Technology &amp; Society, Vol.15, No.4, pp.296-304.##28.  Camps, S., Marques, P. (2011), “Social capital and innovation: exploring intraorganizational differences”, UAM-Accenture Working Papers, pp.1- 39.##  29.  Coleman, J. S. (1998), “Social capital in the creation of human capital”, American journal of sociology, pp.95-120.##30.   Darabeigi, M. &amp; Ajili, Z.G.H. (2013), “Relationship between Social Capital and Teachers’ Creativity Considering the Mediator Role of knowledge Management Case Study: High School Teachers of Saveh County”, Journal of Basic and Applied Scientific Research, Vol.3, No.8, pp.665-674.##31.   DiPietro, W.R. (2012), “Favorable and Unfavorable Conditions for Innovation: Some Cross Country Evidence”, Asian Economic and Financial Review, Vol.2, No.1, pp.14-19.##32. Farsi, J.Y., Rezazadeh, A. &amp; Najmabadi, A.D. (2013), “Social capital and organizational innovation: The mediating effect of entrepreneurial orientation”, Journal of Community Positive Practices, Vol. 13, No.2, pp.22-40.##33.  Fine, B. (2002), Social capital versus social theory: Political economy and                 social science at the turn ofthe millennium, Londan, England, Routledge.           34. Franken, R.E.( 2007),Human motivation, USA, Thomson Wadsworth.##35. Fornell, C., Larcker, D. F. (1981), “Structural equation models with                            unobservable variables and measurement error: Algebra and statistics”,                      Journal of    marketing research, Vol.18, No. 3, pp. 382-388.                          ##36. Guilford, G.P. (1977), Way beyond the IQ, USA, Creative education foundation.     ##37. Haslam, S. A., Adarves-Yorno, I., Postmes, T &amp; Jans, L. (2013). “The Collective Origins of Valued Originality A Social Identity Approach to Creativity”, Personality and Social Psychology Review, Vol.17, No.4, pp. 384-401.##38. Heidari, H. &amp; Rostami, F. (2012), “Survey of Relationship between Social Capital and   Organization Entrepreneurship Case Study: Agricultural Organization of Sonqhur County”, Annals of Biological Research, Vol. 3, No.7, pp.3192-3199.##39. Jaoui, H. (1991), Creatifs au quotidian, France: Hommes Et Perspectives.##40. Jia, L., J.Shaw, A. Tsui and T.Y. Park. (2014), “A social- structural perspective on employee-organization relationship and team creativity”, Academy of Management Journal, Vol.57, No. 3, pp.869–891.##41. Khosravi, R., C.W. Hodshire and S. Lotfi. (2014), “Social Capital and Suicide: Social Workers&#039; Obligation toward Contemporary Suicide Prevention”, International Journal of Humanities and Social Science, Vol.4, No.4, pp. 83-91.##42. Latif, W.B., M.A. Islam and I.B.M. Noor (2014), “A Conceptual Framework to Build Brand Loyalty in the Modern Marketing Environment”, Journal of Asian Scientific Research, Vol. 4, No.10, pp.547-557.##43.  Moqbel, M. (2012), “The Effect of the use of social networking sites in the          workplace on job performance”, Doctoral dissertation, Texas A&amp;M International University.##44. Ogada, R. (2013). The influence of social capital on career success for staff of the county, government  of   Mombasa, Doctoral dissertation, Nairobi , Kenya, University of Nairobi.##45. Portes, A. (1998), “&quot;Social capital: Its origins and applications in modern       sociology,&quot; Annual Review of    Sociology, vol.24, pp.1-24.##46.  Ramezanpour, S., Amiriyan S. &amp; Shirazy, A.N.M. (2014), “Investigation of the Relationship between Entrepreneurial Opportunity Recognition and Entrepreneurial Capitals”, International Journal of Asian Social Science, Vol.4, No.5, pp.598-613.##  47. Sahlberg, P. (2009), &quot;Creativity and innovation through lifelong learning,&quot;                 Journal of Lifelong Learningin   Europe, vol.14, pp. 53-60.                     ##48. Salajegheh, S., Pirmoradi, N. (2013), “Social Capital of the Organization”,         published at International Journal of Engineering Research and                               Development, Vol.7, (Issue 12), pp. 40-52.## 49. Sarlak, M. A., Salamzadeh, Y. (2014), “Analyzing the Impacts of Informal Organizations on Formal Routines in a Networked Organization”, Journal of Asian Scientific Research, Vol.4, No.12, pp.768-783.##50. Savari, M., Eslami, M. &amp; Monavarifard, F. (2013), “The Impact of Social      Capital on Agricultural Employees&#039; Job Satisfaction, City of Divandarreh”, International Research Journal of Applied and Basic Sciences, 4(2), 291-295##51. Siegler, V. (2014).Measuring social capital, London, England, Office for                                    National Statistics.##52. Shoghi,B.,Asgarani, M. &amp; Ashnagohar,N.r.(2013),“Mediating Effect of Organizational structure on the Relationship between Managers&#039; Leadership Style and Employees&#039; Creativity Case study: Metal Industries of Kaveh Industrial City)”,International Journal of Learning and Development,Vol. 3,No,3,pp.63-80.##53. Veismoradi, A., Akbari, P. &amp; Rostami, R. (2014), “A study on the effect of social capital on learning organization: A case study of Jihad Agriculture Organization of Kermanshah”, Iran, Management Science Letters, 2, pp.2909-2916.##55. Vlaisavljevic, V., Medina, C.C. &amp; Pérez-Luño, A. (2014). Does the diversity of partners in alliances guarantees innovation performance?, working papers, Seville, Spain, University Pablo de Olavide de Sevilla.##56. Westlund, H., Andersson, M. &amp; Karlsson, C. (2013), Creativity as an integral element of   social capital and its role for economic performance, Stockholm, Sweden,Royal Institute   of   Technology. ##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی نقش انسجام گروهی در سرمایۀ اجتماعی (مورد مطالعه: بازیکنان حرفه ای فوتبال استان فارس)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Analysis of role of team cohesion in social capital (Professional Soccer Players in Fars Province)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف کلی این تحقیق، بررسی نقش انسجام گروهی در سرمایۀ اجتماعی بین ورزشکاران حرفه‌ای فوتبال بود. روش تحقیق، توصیفی و از نوع هم‌بستگی بود. جامعۀ آماری، ورزشکاران حرفه‌ای فوتبال در استان فارس بودند که قرارداد داشتند. با توجه به اینکه جامعۀ آماری (78=N) این تحقیق به فوتبالیست‌های حرفه‌ای شیراز محدود بود، حجم نمونه برابر با جامعه در نظر گرفته شده و از روش نمونه‌گیری سرشماری استفاده شد. ابزار اندازه‌گیری، پرسش‌نامه‌های انسجام گروهی (کارون) و سرمایۀ اجتماعی (ناهاپیت و گوشال) بود. برای پایایی پرسش‌نامه‌ها، در مطالعه‌ای مقدماتی از روش آلفای کرونباخ استفاده شد. ضریب پایایی به‌دست‌آمده برای سرمایۀ اجتماعی 89/0 و برای انسجام گروهی 86/0 بود. برای تأیید روایی پرسش‌نامه نیز از نظر متخصصان مدیریت ورزشی استفاده شد. به‌منظور تجزیه‌وتحلیل اطلاعات در دو سطح آمار توصیفی (میانگین و انحراف استاندارد) و استنباطی (ضریب هم‌بستگی، رگرسیون و آنالیز واریانس) استفاده شد. نتایج با نرم‌افزار spss تجزیه‌وتحلیل شد و نشان داد بین سرمایۀ اجتماعی و انسجام گروهی و ابعاد آن، رابطۀ معناداری وجود دارد و انسجام گروهی، پیش‌بینی‌کنندۀ خوبی برای سرمایۀ اجتماعی است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>General purpose of the present study was Analysis of Role of Team Cohesion in Social Capital between Professional Soccer Players. Statistical population was professional athletes having soccer contract in Fars. Regarding this issue that statistical population of the present study was restricted to professional soccer players from Shiraz, sample size was considered equal to population and census was used for sampling. Measuring instruments were team cohesion questionnaire (Karon) and social capital (Nahapit and Goushal). In a primary study Alpha Cronbach was used for stability so that stability coefficient for social capita was (89%) and team cohesion was 86%. sports management specialist&#039;s points of view was used to approve validity of questionnaire. For data analysis in descriptive statistical level (mean and standard deviation) and in conceptual level (correlation coefficient, regression, and variance analysis) were used. Gained data was analyzed through SPSS software and the result showed that there is a significant relationship between social capital and team cohesion and its dimensions, in addition it showed that team Cohesion is a good predictor for social capital.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>75</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>94</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صابری</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Saberi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس فارابی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ali_saberi1364@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>قدرت الله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>باقری</Family>
						<NameE>Ghodratollah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bagheri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ghbagheri@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بی غرض</Family>
						<NameE>Mohamad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bigharaz</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.bigharaz@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انسجام گروهی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایۀ اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ورزشکاران حرفه‌ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>احمدی، سید علی اکبر؛ فیض آبادی، حوریه (1390). بررسی ارتقاء سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر بهبود عملکرد سازمان.(نمونه ی موردی: سازمان‌های ستادی شهرداری تهران). مجله مدیریت دولتی، 3(6)، صص: 53-54.##احمدی، علی اکبر؛ فراهانی، ابوالفضل؛بهمنی چوبستی، اکبر؛ شهبازی؛ مهدی(1391). نقش سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر بهبود مدیریت استعداد‌ها در سازمان تربیت بدنی. مجله مطالعات مدیریت ورزشی (13): 237-260.##امیر خانی، طیبه؛ عارف نژاد محسن(1391). تحلیل تاثیر رفتار شهروندی سازمانی و سرمایه روانشناختی بر سرمایۀ اجتماعی. فصلنامه علوم مدیریت ایران؛7(26): 89-112##الوانی، مهدی؛ شیروانی، علیرضا (1385). .سرمایۀ اجتماعی، مفاهیم، نظزیه‌ها و کاربرد‌ها، اصفهان، انتشارات مانی ص 1.##بختی، میلاد؛ ترابی، محسن؛ قلی پور، آرین(1390). رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی به عنوان متغیر میانجی میان حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده و سرمایۀ اجتماعی. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مطالعات بهبود مدیریت و تحول  21(66). صص: 25-46.##جاریوس، مت(1390). روانشناسی ورزش. ترجمه نور علی وند خواجوی. انتشارات دستان##حسین پور، داوود؛ آذر، مهدی (1390).  بررسی رابطه سرمایه فکری و اجتماعی با عملکرد سازمانی ازنظر مدیران و کارکنان. فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه و تحول. صص: 19-29##خطیبی، امین؛ غرباوی، ایوب؛ بختیاری، محمد. 1390. بررسی ارتباط بین عدالت ادراک شده  با انسجام گروهی و موفقیت گروهی در گروه‌های لیگ برتری والیبال کشور. مجله پژوهش در علوم ورزشی (11): 57-72##طالبی ناهید ، عبداللهی فاطمه(1391).  ارتباط بین رفتار رهبری مربی، انسجام گروهی و عملکرد گروه‌های والیبال لیگ برتر زنان ایران. مطالعات مدیریت ورزشی. (16) :78-63.##فقیهی، ابوالحسن؛ فیضی، طاهره (1385). سرمایۀ اجتماعی: رویکردی نو در سازمان، فصلنامه دانش مدیریت سال، 19، شماره 72:  23-46##-فوکویاما، فرانسیس(1379). پایان نظم، سرمایه اجتماعی و حفظ آن، ترجمة غلامعباس توسلی، چاپ اول، تهران: انتشارات جامعه ایرانیان، .##فیلد، جان(1377). سرمایۀ اجتماعی، ترجمه غلامرضا غفاری، حسین رمضانی، چاب اول.تهران، انتشارات کویر، ص : 55.##مرادی، محمدرضا؛ جعفری، اکرم؛ مرادی چالشتری، جواد(1390). رابطه سبک رهبری مربیان با انسجام گروهی و عملکرد گروهی در گروه‌های لیگ برتر بسکتبال کشور، همایش ملی علم و بسکتبال، دانشگاه گیلان، رشت.##Andrew, R (2010). Organizational social capital structure and performance. Human relations. 63(5) 583–608##Carron AV, Brawley LR, Widmeyer WN (1998).  The measurement of cohesiveness in sport groups. In: Duda JL (Ed.) Advances in sport and exercise psychology measurement, Fitness Information Technology: Morgantown, WV: 213-26.##Carron, A.V (1982). &quot;Cohesiveness in sport groups: interpretations and considerations&quot;. J SPORT EXERCISE PSY.Vol. 4: 123-138.##Carron, A.V., Colman M.M., Wheelar, J. &amp; Stevens. D (2002).  “Cohesion and performance in sport J SPORT EXERCISE PSY, 24 :68-188.##Collins.j and Durand-Bush. N (2010).  Enhancing the Cohesion and Performance of an Elite Curling Team through a Self-Regulation Intervention. International Journal of Sports Science &amp; Coaching, Volume 5 · Number 3: 343-362-##Francisco M. Leo, Pedro A. Sánchez-Migue2, David Sánchez-Oliva, Diana Amad1, Tomás García-Calvo (2013).  Analysis of Cohesion and Collective Efficacy Profiles for the Performance of Soccer Players. j of Hum Kinet. Volume 39: 221-229.##Gil de Zuniga, H.,Jung, N., Valenzuela, S (2012). Social Medial use for News and individuals social capital, civic engagement and Political participation. Journal of computer-mediated communication. vol 17: 319- 336##Harvey, j., Lévesque, m., Donnelly, p (2007).  Sport Volunteerism and Social Capital. SOCIOL SPORT J, vol, 24 : 206-223.##.Huvila, l., Holmberg, k, e, s, and widen- wolff, G (2010).  Social capital in second life. online information review, vol, 34 (2): 295- 316.##Kaplan, R, S., and David. P. Norton  (2007). Strategy maps: converting intangible assets into tangible outcomesBoston: Harvard Business Press.##Krause D.R, &amp; R.B. Hand field, &amp; B.B, Tyler (2007).  &quot;The relationships between supplier development, commitment, and social capital accumulation and performance improvement&quot;, J OPER MANAG, Vol. 25: 528_545.##Nahapiet, J., &amp; Ghoshal, S (1998).  &quot;Social Capital, Intellectual Capital &amp; theorganizational advantage&quot;, ACAD MANAGE REV, Vol. 23, NO. 2: 242_260.##Putnam, R (1995). &quot;Bowling Alone: America&#039;s Declining Social Capital.&quot; Jouranl of Demicracy. 6:65-78.##Tajfel, H., Turner, J. C(1986). The social identity of intergroup behavior. In S- Worchel &amp; W. G. Austin (Eds.). Psychology of Intergroup Relations, Chicago: Nelson Hall.: 7-24.##Tobias, R (2013). The Role of Social Capital in the Explanation of Educational Success and Educational Inequalities. Irish Educational Studie. 32 (3) p335-354.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی رابطۀ مهارت‌های ارتباطی مدیران و سرمایۀ اجتماعی سازمان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Survey the relationship between communicational skill of managers and social capital of organization</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف این تحقیق آن است که ضمن شناسایی مؤلفه‌های سرمایۀ اجتماعی سازمان، وضعیت رابطۀ این مؤلفه‌ها و مهارت ارتباطی مدیران را بررسی کند. این پژوهش ازنظر هدف، کاربردی و ازنظر روش، توصیفی و از نوع هم‌بستگی است. جامعۀ آماری این پژوهش، کارکنان سازمان‌های غیرانتفاعی شهرستان نور (243=N) بودند. 85 نفر از جامعه، به روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌ای و به‌عنوان نمونۀ آماری انتخاب شدند. همچنین برای گردآوری اطلاعات درزمینۀ مبانی نظری و شناسایی مؤلفه‌های سرمایۀ اجتماعی، از روش مطالعۀ کتابخانه‌ای و مصاحبه با استادان، خبرگان، صاحب‌نظران و مدیران جامعۀ موردمطالعه استفاده شد. سپس برای جمع‌آوری اطلاعات برای آزمون فرضیه‌ها، از پرسش‌نامه استفاده شد. پنج مؤلفه برای سرمایۀ اجتماعی سازمان شناسایی شدند که عبارت‌اند از: اعتماد متقابل، شبکه‌ها و هنجارهای مشترک، تعاون و همکاری متقابل، انسجام و هم‌بستگی جمعی، همیاری و مشارکت داوطلبانه. نتایج تحقیق نشان‌دهندۀ آن بود که رابطۀ بین مهارت ارتباطی مدیران و سرمایۀ اجتماعی سازمان، مثبت و معنادار است. به‌علاوه، قوی‌ترین رابطه، بین مؤلفۀ اعتماد متقابل با مهارت ارتباطی و ضعیف‌ترین رابطه درخصوص مؤلفۀ شبکه‌ها و هنجارهای مشترک مشاهده شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>s
The purpose of this study was to identify indicators of social capital and pursue their correlation to communicational skill of mangers. This descriptive-correlation study has an applied objective. The population is composed of all employees (243 individuals) of nonprofit organizations in Noor city. The total number of 85 individuals was selected in random sampling as the sample. In this study, to collect data in the field of theoretical and identify the components of social capital, the study of literature and interviews with professors, experts and scholars, as well as managers of the population studied was used. Then, the questionnaire was used to collect data to test hypotheses. Five indicators identified for social capital that includes: mutual trust, shared networks and norms, mutual cooperation, collective cohesion, voluntary participation. The results of research indicate that the relationship between communicational skill of managers and social capital is positive and significant. In addition, the strongest relationship between mutual trust and communicational skill were and weakest relationship between shared networks and norms and communicational skill were seen.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>95</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>116</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یوسف زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Saeid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Yousefzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مربی گروه حسابداری، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد نوشهر، نوشهر، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مربی گروه حسابداری، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>saeid_yousefzadeh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>داود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کیاکجوری</Family>
						<NameE>Davood</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kia Kojoori</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد چالوس، چالوس، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>davoodkia@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اعتماد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انسجام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تعاون</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مشارکت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هنجار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>. آغاز، عسل و امیرخانی، طیبه و عبدالله پور، مونا (1390). بررسی ارتباط میان رهبری تحول آفرین و سرمایۀ اجتماعی، دوماهنامه علمی-پژوهشی دانشور رفتار، سال هجدهم-دوره جدید، شماره 47-1، صفحات 147-162##2. ازگلی، محمد (1383). رهبری استراتژیک چشم انداز. تهران: موسسه چاپ و انتشارات دانشگاه امام حسین(ع).##3. باستانی، سوسن و کمالی، افسانه و صالحی هیکویی، مریم (1387). سرمایۀ اجتماعی و اعتماد متقابل بین شخصی، مجله دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی دانشگاه الزهراء، سال 16، شماره 61، 41-81##4. پاشاشریفی، حسن و نجفی‌زند، جعفر (1376). روشهای آماری در علوم رفتاری، تهران:انتشارات سخن##5. حق گویان، زلفا و سیدجوادین، سیدرضا و مشایخی، مریم و منتظری، عباس (1393). بررسی وضعیت سرمایۀ اجتماعی در سازمان امور مالیاتی استان قم، مدیریت سرمایۀ اجتماعی، دوره 1، شماره 1، صفحات 21-42##6. رضایی منش، بهروز و عادلی، راحیل و بهرامی، داود و زندی، فیروز (1391). رابطه رهبری تحول آفرین و سرمایۀ اجتماعی در  کسب و کارهای کوچک، فصلنامه علمی پژوهشی مطالعات مدیریت(بهبود و تحول)، سال بیست و دوم، شماره 69، صفحات 151-170##7. زارعی متین، حسن و ملایی، مصطفی (1393). بررسی وضعیت مؤلفه های سرمایۀ اجتماعی در سازمانهای اجرایی استان قم، مدیریت سرمایۀ اجتماعی، دوره 1، شماره 1، صفحات 119-137##8. زارعی متین، حسن و یوسف زاده، سعید (1390). تبیین شاخصهای مهارت ارتباطی مدیران و نقش آن در رضایت شغلی کارکنان، دوماهنامه علمی-پژوهشی دانشور رفتار، سال هجدهم-دوره جدید، شماره 47-2، صفحات 441-466##9. زره ساز، محمد (1391). تبیین پرسشها و چالشهای مرتبط با تولید سرمایۀ اجتماعی در کتابخانه های عمومی ایران، نشریه الکترونیکی شمسه(نشریه الکترونیکی سازمان کتابخانه ها موزه ها و مرکز اسناد آستان قدس رضوی)، شماره 14و15، صفحات 1-14##10. فرحبد، فرزین و امیرعلوی، سیروس و نجف زاده، صدیقه (1390). جایگاه مدیریت تعارض و گشودگی ارتباط در ارتقای اعتماد کارکنان پرستاری، مجله دانشگاه علوم پزشکی گیلان، دوره بیستم، شماره 79، صفحات 24-30##11. فرهنگی، علی اکبر (1382). ارتباطات انسانی، تهران: خدمات فرهنگی رسا.##12. قاسمی، وحید و فائقی، سحر و امیر، آرمین (1392). سنجش سرمایۀ اجتماعی و سطح بندی آن در طبقات مختلف مناطق 14 گانه شهر اصفهان در سال 1390-91، مجله مطالعات توسعه اجتماعی ایران، سال پنجم، شماره سوم، صفحات 7-32##13. نوابخش، مهرداد و فیروزآبادی، آمنه (1391). انسجام اجتماعی شهری و عوامل مرتبط بر آن در شهر کرمانشاه، فصلنامه مطالعات جامعه شناختی شهری، سال دوم، شماره پنجم، صفحات 33-58##14. Anssi Smedlund (2008) The knowledge system of a firm: social capital for explicit, tacit and potential knowledge. Journal of Knowledge Management. Vol. 12, No. 1, 63-77##15. Burrt R. S (1992) Strutural holes: The Social Structur of Competition. Cambriddge, MA: Harvard University Press##16. Catherine A. Johnson (2012) How do public libraries create social capital?. Library &amp; Information Science Research. Vol. 34, 52-62##17. Dong Liu and B. Bradford Brown (2014) Self-disclosure on Social Networking Sites, Positive Feedback, and Social Capital Among Chinese College Students. Computers in Human Behavior. Vol. 38, 213-219##18. Fattah Nazem and Susan Gheytasi (2014) Prediction of Social Capital Based on The Emotional Intelligence In Education Ministry. Indian Journal of Fundamental and Applied Life Sciences. Vol. 4 (s4), 3309-3313##19. Flora, C.B. and J. L. Flora. (1996) The Past and Future: Social Contract, Social Policy and Social Capital. pp. 53-64 in Farm Foundation: Increasing Understanding of Public Problems and Policies##20. Fred, Stutzman. Jessica, Vitak. Nicole, B. Ellison. Rebecca, Gray and Cliff, Lampe (2012) Privacy in Interaction: Exploring Disclosure and Social Capital in Facebook. Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence##21. Glalbraith, C.S. Rodriguez, C.L. Stiles, C.H (2007) Social capital as a club good. Journal of enterprising communities. Vol. 1, No. 1, 38-53.##22. Goleman D. (1999) Working With Emotional Intelligence. London: Bloomsbury Publishing PLC. 26-27##23. Jane, E. Dutton. Laura, Morgan Romerts and Jeffrey, Bednar (2010) Pathways for Positive Identitiy Construction at Work. Academy of management review. Vol. 35, No.2, 265-293##24. Janine Nahapiet and Sumantra Ghoshal (1998) Social Capital, intellectual Capital, and the organizational advantage. Academy of management review. Vol. 23, No.2, 242-266##25. Jan Royal (2012) Evaluating Human, Social and Cultural Capital in Nurse Education. Nurse Education Today. Vol. 32, 19-22##26. Javier Boyas and Leslie H. Wind (2010) Employment-based social capital, job stress, and employee burnout. Children &amp; Youth Services Review 32.  380–388##27. Jayant, Venkatanathan. Evangelos, Karapanos. Vassilis, Kostakos and Jorge, Gonçalves (2008) A Network Science Approach to Modelling and Predicting Empathy. Portuguese Foundation for Science and Technology (FCT)##28. Jayant, Venkatanathan. Evangelos, Karapanos. Vassilis, Kostakos and Jorge, Gonçalves (2012) Network, Personality and Social Capital. Evanston IL, USA##29. KennethNewton (2001) Trust, Social Capital, civil society, and democracy. International Political Science Review. Vol. 22, No. 2, 201-214##30. Kit Brooks and Fredrick Muyia Nafukho (2006) Human Resource Development,  Social Capital, Emotional Intelligence Any link to Productivity?. Journal of European Industrial Training. Vol. 30,  No. 2, 117-128##31. Lawrence Jacob Van De Valk (2008) Leadership Development and Social Capital: Is There a Relationship?. Journal of Leadership Education. Vol 7, 47-64##32. Michael Woolcock and Deepa Narayan (2000) Social Capital: Implications for Development Theory, Research, and Policy, World Bank Research Abserver. Vol. 15(2)##33. Nan Lin (2005) A Network Theory of Social Capital. Duke university. Electronic copy available at: pro-classic.com/ethnicgv/SN/SC/paper-final-041605.pdf##34. Paul s. Adler and Seok-Woo kwon (2002). Social capital: prospects for a new concept. Academy of Management Review. Vol. 27, No. 1, 17-40##35. Seyed Yahya, Seyed Danesh. Esmaeil, Malekakhlagh. Tayebeh, Taghavi and Mir Mohammad, Seyed Danesh (2012) The Relationship between Transformational Leadership and Social Capitals in Education Organization of Guilan Province. Journal of Basic and Applied Scientific Research. Vol. 2(4), 4153-4158##36. Vittorio Pelligra (2011)Empathy, Guilt-Aversion, and Patterns of Reciprocity. Journal of Neuroscience, Psychology, and Economics. Vol. 4, No. 3, 161–173##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر رفتار شهروندی سازمانی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The effect of social capital on organizational citizenship behavior</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف اصلی این تحقیق، بررسی تأثیر سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر رفتار شهروندی سازمانی است. این تحقیق از نظر هدف کاربردی و از نظر نحوۀ گردآوری داده‌ها، توصیفی - هم‌بستگی است و با ابزار پرسش‌نامه انجام گرفته است. فرضیه‌ها با نمونۀ 102نفری در شهرداری همدان آزموده شدند. برای توصیف جمعیت‌شناختی پاسخ‌گویان و آزمون فرضیه‌ها از نرم‌افزار Spss 19 استفاده شد. برای آزمون فرضیه‌ها روش تحلیل هم‌بستگی و رگرسیون گام‌به‌گام به کار گرفته شد. بر اساس یافته‌های تحقیق، سرمایۀ اجتماعی، اثر مثبت و معنادار بر رفتار شهروندی سازمانی دارد. همچنین هر سه بعد سرمایۀ اجتماعی؛ یعنی ساختاری، ارتباطی و شناختی، اثر مثبت و معناداری بر رفتار شهروندی سازمانی دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Considering the importance and necessity of efficient and capable manpower in achieving organizational goals, the aim of this study was to investigate the relationship between social capital and organizational citizenship behavior. This research uses descriptive– correlational questionnaire. These hypotheses are tested by a sample of 102 people in the municipality of Hamedan. Describing the demographic characteristics of respondents and regression testing was conducted by SPSS19. Multiple regression and correlation was used. Finding showed that social capital variable has the significant positive impact on organizational citizenship behavior. Also, the results showed that all three dimensions of social capital, structural, relational and cognitive and significant positive effect on organizational citizenship behavior.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>117</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>136</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زهرا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شمسی</Family>
						<NameE>Zahra</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shamsi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناسی ارشد، دانشکدۀ مدیریت دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناسی ارشد، دانشکدۀ مدیریت دانشگاه تربیت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zahra.shams22@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>منیره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محبعلی پور</Family>
						<NameE>Monire</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moehbalipour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناسی ارشد، دانشکدۀ مدیریت دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناسی ارشد، دانشکدۀ مدیریت دانشگاه تربیت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.malipour@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>الوداری</Family>
						<NameE>Hassan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Allodari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>alvedari@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رفتار شهروندی سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایۀ اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شهرداری استان همدان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>سبحانی نژاد . مهدی. شاطری، کریم. فرجی ده سرخی، حاتم. اکبری، معصومه. (1389). &quot;تبیین رابطه رفتار شهروندی سازمانی و سرمایه اجتماعی بین کارشناسان دانشگاه تهران&quot;. دانشور رفتار. تربیت و اجتماع. دانشگاه شاهد. سال هفدهم. اسفند 89. شماره 45##خرازی، کمال. واعظی، مظفر الدین، سینکی، عبدالله. (1391). “رابطه سرمایه اجتماعی با گرایش به رفتار شهروندی سازمانی در دفتر مرکزی یک شرکت بیمه”. پژوهشنامه بیمه. سال بیست و هفتم. شماره 106. صفحات 159-171##دانایی فرد، حسن،الوانی، سید مهدی، آذر، عادل. (1389). “روش شناسی: پژوهش کمی در مدیریت رویکردی جامع”. تهران: انتشارات اشراقی##فتاحی،مهدی(1386). “بررسی معنویت کاری بر رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی و ارتباط آن با وفاداری مشتری و کیفیت خدمات در سازمان تامین اجتماعی” . پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران##فوکویاما، فرانسیس؛ (1385)“پایان نظم: سرمایه اجتماعی و حفظ آن”.   مترجم ،غلامعباس توسلی. تهران. حکایت قلم نوین.  ص12-11.##Ahmadi P, Forouzandeh S, Safari M. &quot;The relationship between OCB and social exchange constructs Europeans&quot;. Journal of Economics, Finance and Administrative Sciences. 2010;19: 107-120##Archibong,  Chi,  Anyansi.  (2004) &quot; Technology,  Infrastructure  and Entrepreneurship:  Role  of  the  Government  in  Building  a  sustainable Economy&quot;.  School of Business and Economics North Carolian A &amp; T State University.##Bolino , Mark C., William H. Turnley &amp; James M. Blood Good (2002). &quot; Citizenship behavio and the creation of social capital in organizations&quot; .Academy of Mmanagement Review, 27(4):505-522##Castro,C.B., E.M. Armario and D.M. Ruiz (2004). &quot;The influence of employee organizational citizenship behavior on customer loyalty&quot;. International Journal of Service Industry Management, 15(1):27##Feldman. T.W.H. Ng, D.C (2011).&quot; Affective organizational commitment and citizenship behavior: Linear and non-linear moderating effects of organizational tenure&quot;. Journal of Vocational Behavior 79 528–537##Francis, P. (2002). &quot;Social capital at World Bank :strategic and operational implications of the concept, Social Development Strategy ,World Bank.##Fukuyama,F.(1995)&quot;. Trust:the social virtues and the creation prosperity&quot;  .New York:Free Press chapter 9.##Gloede TD, Hammer A, Ommen O, Ernstmann N, Pfaff H.(2012).  &quot;Is social capital as perceived by the medical director associated with coordination among hospital staff? A nationwide survey in German hospitals&quot;. Journal Interprofessional Care. 2012; 27: 124-39.##Goyal.A,;  Akhilesh.K.B  (2007),  ”Interplay  among  innovativeness  ,cognitive intelligence,  emotional  intelligence  and  social  capital  of  work  team”,  Team Performance Management, 3(1/8), 206-226.##Hsu CP, Chang CW, Huang HC, Chiang CY. . (2011). “The relationships among social capital, organisational commitment and customer-oriented prosocial behaviour of hospital nurses”. Journal of Clinical Nursing.; 20(9-10):1383-92.##Jiang,j.yun sun,li.law.s(2011).” Job Satisfaction and Organization Structure as moderators of the effects of empowerment on the organizational citizen ship behaviour :A self-consistence and social exchange perspective”.international journal of management vol.28 No.3 part 1 sept##Kokobyo, A.K.,) 2009(. Operant  competence, organizational  social capital, organizational  commitment  and  organizational  citizenship behavior, Uganda Scholarly Digital Library##Nahapiet,J; Ghoshal , S.(1998). &quot;Social capital , intellectual capital and the  organizational  advantage&quot;  ,  Academy  of  Management  Review  , vol23 No(2),. Pp242-266.##Nobel, Ann, Deborah. (2006 ). “The Relationship of formal   Education And Gender To organizational citizen ship behaviour”. .DISERTATION.  Argosy University/Sarasota, Florida##Philip M. Podsakoff, Scott B. MacKenzie, Julie Beth Paine, and Daniel G. Bachrach Indiana University .(2000).” Organizational Citizenship Behaviors: A Critical Review of the Theoretical and Empirical Literature and Suggestions for Future Research”. JOURNAL OF MANAGEMENT, VOL. 26, NO. 3, 2000##Winter, I. (2000).” Family life and social capital: toward a theorized understanding”.  Working Paper, No.21##Zareimatin H, Ahmadi F.(2007) “The role of university in the development of organizational citizenship behavior”. The Islamic University Journal. 13(41): 23-31.[Persian].##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر جو سازمانی بر عملکرد سازمانی کارکنان از طریق سرمایۀ اجتماعی (مورد مطالعه: کارکنان شهرداری مناطق پنج گانه شهر رشت)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The effect of climate organizational on performance through social capital (Case Study: Municipal employees from five districts in Rasht)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>سرمایۀ اجتماعی را می‌توان چارچوب زیرساختی برای بهبود عملکرد سازمانی دانست. پژوهش حاضر، ضمن بررسی تأثیرگذاری سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر عملکرد سازمانی، به ارزیابی رابطۀ غیرمستقیم جو سازمانی بر عملکرد سازمانی پرداخته است. این مطالعه، با نمونه‌ای 132نفری از کارکنان شهرداری مناطق پنج‌گانۀ شهر رشت صورت گرفته است. روش پژوهش، توصیفی از نوع پیمایشی - هم‌بستگی است. برای جمع‌آوری داده‌‌‌‌ها از پرسش‌‌‌‌نامه استفاده شده است. تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌‌‌‌ها به کمک روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری در نرم‌‌‌‌افزار لیزرل انجام گرفته است. یافته‌‌‌‌های پژوهش نشان می‌‌‌‌دهد که جو سازمانی به‌صورت مستقیم بر سرمایۀ اجتماعی و به‌صورت غیرمستقیم بر عملکرد سازمانی اثر مثبت و معنادار می‌گذارد و سرمایۀ اجتماعی تأثیر مثبت و مستقیم بر عملکرد سازمانی گذاشته است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Social capital can be considered within the framework of organizational performance improvement in infrastructural need. The study also examines the influence of social capital on the performance of the enterprise, to evaluate the relationship between the organizational climates organizational performance indirectly is paid. The study on a sample of 132 people from the five regions of the municipality&#039;s employees in Rasht is done. The research method is descriptive of the type of work and solidarity-to collect the data from the questionnaire has been used. Data analysis methods of structural equations modeling in software lissrel have been doing the study shows findings that organizational climate directly on social capital and organizational performance indirectly affect a significant positive effect. Social capital and direct positive impact on organizational performance is laid.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>137</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>154</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نوروزی</Family>
						<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Norouzi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>norouzi.h@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کاملی</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>kameli</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت، دانشکدۀ مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ar.kameli@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رویا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بیگی</Family>
						<NameE>Roya</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Beigi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت، دانشکدۀ مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rbeigi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مهذبی</Family>
						<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohazabi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت، دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت، دانشکدۀ مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mmg.mohazabi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جو سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایۀ اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ابزری، مهدی، رنجبریان، بهرام، فتحی، سعید، قربانی، حسن. ( 1388). تأثیر بازاریابی داخلی                    بر بازارگرایی و عملکرد سازمانی در صنعت هتلداری. چشم انداز مدیریت، ش31- 57 :42.##الوانی، مهدی، شیروانی، علیرضا. (1385). سرمایۀ اجتماعی،مفاهیم،نظریه‌‌‌‌های و کاربردها، اصفهان: نشر مانی.##ترابی، پردیس، حیدری، علیقلی، قلی نیا، جواد محمد (1389). بررسی میزان تأثیر مولفه های سرمایۀ اجتماعی در عملکرد شرکت های تعاونی(مطالعه موردی: تعاونی های، دام و طیور در شهرستان مشهد،) تعاون ، سال بیست و یکم ، دور جدید، شمارۀ 2 صفحات اول و آخر.##حیدری، زهرا، عسکریان، مصطفی، دوایی، مهدی (1389). بررسی رابطه بین جو سازمانی و مدیریت تعارض از دیدگاه دبیران، فصلنامه تازه های روانشناسی صنعتی/سازمانی، سال اول، شمارۀ سوم##سویزی، محسن.، محمدی، فریبرز. (1390). نقش سرمایۀ اجتماعی در تامین امنیت سرمایه گذاری.فصلنامه ره نامه سیاستگذاری ،2(3)، 146-119.##صفرزاده، حسین، احمدی شریف، محمود، ذاکری، علیرضا (1389). تأثیر آموزش مولفه‌‌‌‌های سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر فعالیت های شغلی اعضای هیات علمی‌، نشر یه علمی‌ پژوهشی فن آوری آموزش، سال پنجم، جلد 5، شمارۀ 2، ص 1.##فیضی،کامران، و رونقی،محمدحسین.(1390).ارزیابی سرمایه های فکری و اجتماعی شرکت‌‌‌‌های رتبه بندی شده  توسط شورای عالی انفورماتیک ایران.فصلنامه علمی‌پژوهشی پژوهشگاه علوم و فن آوری اطلاعات،ایران، دورۀ 1( 2)،189.##کلمن، جیمز  (1384).  &quot;بنیادهای نظریه اجتماعی&quot;، مترجم: منوچهر صبوری، تهران : نشر نی.##گودرزوندچگینی، مهرداد، رضایی دیزگاه، مراد، اسدی، محمد. (1390). تأثیر عدالت سازمانی بر سرمایۀ اجتماعی در صنعت بیمه ایران،2: 12-1##عباس‌‌‌‌زادگان، سیدمحمد (1384)؛ مدیریت بهداشت روانی، مجلۀ مدیریت، شمارۀ 103 و 104(28-31)##مقیمی، سیدمحمد، امامی، فرزانه، کاظمی، معصومه. (1390). ارزیابی و اولویت بندی شاخصه های سرمایۀ اجتماعی و تأثیر آن بر عملکرد سازمانی در نظام دانشگاهی،نشریه علمی‌پژوهشی مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی، 9(2)،29-60##منظور، داود، یادی‌‌‌‌پور، مهدی. (1387). سرمایۀ اجتماعی عامل ایجاد توسعه اجتماعی و اقتصادی، مجلۀ راهبرد یاس،15: 162-140.##یزدانی، حمیدرضا، حمیدی زاده، علی، کاملی، علیرضا. (1394).  بررسی تأثیر سبک رهبری و جو سازمانی بر مدیریت دانش با توجه به نقش میانجی ساختار سازمانی و تعامل اجتماعی(پیمایشی پیرامون بخش ستادی بانک ملت)، نشریه مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دورۀ هفتم،شمارۀ یکم،:199-216 .## Amabile, T. M., Conti, R., Coon, H., Lazenby, J., &amp; Herron, M. (1996). Assessing the work environment for creativity. Academy of Management Journal, 39(5), 1154-1184.##Busi, M (2006) &quot;Collaborative performance mangament: present gaps and future research&quot;, International Journal of Procuctivity and Performance Management, Vol 55. No. 10.##Chen, C. J. &amp; Huang, J. W. (2007). How organizational climate and structure affect knowledge management- social interaction perspective. International journal of information management, 27 (2): 104-118.##Dackert, I., Loov, L.A., &amp; Martensson, M. (2004). Leadership and climate for innovation in teams. Economic and Industrial Democracy, 25(2), 301-318.##18. Ekvall, G. (1996). Organizational climate for creativity and innovation. European Journal of Work and Organizational Psychology, 5(1), 105-123.##Ellis JR, Hartley CL. (2000). Managing and coordinating nursing care. 3rd ed. Philadelphia: Lippincott.##Huselid, M.A. (1995). The impact of human resource practices on turnover, productivity, and corporate financial performance. Academy of Management journal. 38(3): 635-672.##Johnson, J.J. (2004), “Differences in supervisor and non-supervisor perceptions of quality culture and organizational climate”, Public Personnel Management, (29) 1, 119-28.##Kit Brooks, Fredrick Muyia Nafukho, (2006) &quot;Human resource development, social capital, emotional intelligence: Any link to productivity?&quot;, Journal of European Industrial Training, Vol. 30 Iss: 2, pp.117 – 128.##Levin, D. Z., Whitener, E. M., &amp; Cross, R. (2006). Perceived trustworthiness of knowledge sources: The moderating impact of relationship length. Journal of Applied Psychology, 91(5), 1163-1171.##Millar, P; Stevens, J. (2012), Managemtn training and national sport organization managers: Examining the impact of training on individual and organizational performances&quot;, sport management, vol. 15, No.3, p288-303.##Smedlund,(2008)The knowledge system of a firm: social capital for explicit, tacit and potential knowledge;journal of knowledge management,vol 12,no 1,pp. 63-77.##Soonhee, K. (2009). Managerial leadership, the Climate for Creativity and innovation, and a culture of innovation and Performance-Driven in local Government. Paper Prepared for the PMRA conference.##Tangen, S. (2004), Professional practice performance Measurement: from philosophy to practice&quot;, International Journal of Productivity and performance Management, Vol.53, No.8, pp726-37.## Yauch, Ch. (2010), &quot;Measuring agility as a performance autcome&quot;, Journal of Manufacturing Technology Management, vol. 22, NO.3, pp.384-404.## Yang Koh ,T., Rowlinson, S.( 2011). Relational approach in managing construction project safety: Journal of A social capital perspective, Accident Analysis and Prevention.## West, M. A., &amp; Farr, J. L. (1989). Innovation at work: psychological perspectives. Social behaviour, 4 (11), 15-30.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				