<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Model of Spin off Companies to Develop Social Capital in Universities</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل شرکت‌های زایشی پژوهشی با هدف توسعۀ سرمایۀ اجتماعی در دانشگاه‌ها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>21</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">58171</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2016.58171</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>عالی پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد ساری، ساری، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ترانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>عنایتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد ساری، ساری، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the element universities in research that not much attention is the development of social capital in research centers) incubators and spin-off companies (can lead to knowledge sharing and new creation of knowledge. in the study of social capital development at universities and research spin-off companies is to provide a model. The study involved the administration of faculty universities and incubators and science and technology parks is the province, in this paper, the key indicators of social development of spin-off companies examined. To achieve this purpose, we used the expert&#039;s idea professional educational organizations. With using fuzzy TOPSIS in the ranking indices and the most important factors affecting indices development of social capital in order of priority specified. First priority: academic working teams with the purpose of social partnership; the second priority: research and development with the goal of academic excellence, the third priority: supporting institutions to promote cultural diversity at the university. Then, using qualitative research through interviews narrative and deep interview fifteen academic experts that at least ten years in the field of entrepreneurship, incubators and Science and Technology have executive experience final model through content analysis was presented.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از مؤلفه­هایی که در تحقیقات دانشگاه­ها به آن توجه زیادی نشده است، توسعة سرمایة اجتماعی در مراکز تحقیقاتی (مراکز رشد و شرکت­های زایشی پژوهشی) است که باعث مشارکت در دانش و خلق دانش جدید می­شود. محقق در این پژوهش با هدف توسعة سرمایة اجتماعی در دانشگاه­ها و شرکت­های زایشی پژوهشی، مدلی طراحی کرده است. محدودة اجرایی این پژوهش اعضای هیئت علمی دانشگاه­ها و مراکز رشد و پارک علم و فناوری استان مازندران است. در این مقاله سعی شده است شاخص­های اصلی توسعة سرمایة اجتماعی در شرکت­های زایشی پژوهشی بررسی شود. برای نیل به این منظور، با به‌کارگیری نظرهای کارشناسان، صاحب­نظران، و متخصصان سازمان­های آموزشی، این شاخص­ها شناسایی شد و با فن تاپسیس در محیط فازی، این شاخص­ها رتبه­بندی شده، تا مهم‌ترین عوامل و شاخص­های مؤثر در توسعة سرمایة اجتماعی به ترتیب اولویت مشخص شوند. اولویت اول، تیم­های کاری دانشگاهی با هدف مشارکت اجتماعی؛ اولویت دوم، تحقیق و توسعه با هدف تعالی دانشگاه؛ اولویت سوم، نهادهای حمایتی برای توسعة تکثر فرهنگی در دانشگاه بود. پس از آن، با به‌کارگیری روش تحقیق کیفی از طریق مصاحبه­های نیمه­ساختاریافتة عمیق با پانزده نفر از پژوهشگران دانشگاهی، الگوی نهایی از طریق تحلیل محتوای مصاحبه­ها طراحی شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحقیق و توسعه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشگاه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرکت‌های زایشی پژوهشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_58171_af570ff5bf08e6a8bf978b32df264762.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
