<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Influence of Human Resource Maturity and Social Capital on Sustainable Human Resource Management (A Study of the Petrochemical Industry)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر سرمایۀ اجتماعی و بلوغ منابع انسانی بر مدیریت منابع انسانی پایدار (مورد مطالعه: شرکت‌های فعال در صنعت پتروشیمی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>113</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>138</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">58850</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2016.58850</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مانی</FirstName>
					<LastName>آرمان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه خلیج فارس، بوشهر، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید یعقوب</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه خلیج فارس، بوشهر، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهام</FirstName>
					<LastName>تنگستانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه خلیج فارس، بوشهر، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Importance of human resources and its unique role as a strategic resource, designer and systems executive and organizational systems has found higher position than in the past As far as the advanced enterprise thinking Considers human being as the most important resource and asset for an organization. Today, new approaches to human resource management emphasizes that should human resource with sustainable approach to be managed. Therefore, sustainable human resource management is defined as a suitable strategy for human resource management and ways to achieve company’s financial, social and environmental goals. The aim of this study is to evaluate the impact of social capital and maturity of human resources on sustainable human resource management. This study in terms of aims is applied research and in terms of data gathering is correlation- descriptive research. The study population consisted of all companies operating in Iran’s Petrochemical Industry. In order to test the hypothesis and model is also used Smart PLS software. Research findings show that social capital and human resources maturity have a significant and positive impact on sustainable human resource management, also in sub-hypothesis, Relational capital, Organizational Image, personal health has management a significant and positive impact on sustainable human resource, but structural and cognitive capital, Alignment Personal and Organizational Goals and productivity of human resources and have not Significant and positive impact on human resource management.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">منابع انسانی و نقش منحصربه‌فرد آن به‌منزلة منبعی استراتژیک، باعث شده است در تفکر سازمانی پیشرفته انسان مهم‌ترین منبع و دارایی در نظر گرفته شود. امروزه رویکردهای نوین به مدیریت منابع انسانی تأکید می‌کنند که باید منابع انسانی با رویکردی پایدار، مدیریت شود. مدیریت منابع انسانی پایدار استراتژی مناسبی را برای مدیریت منابع انسانی و شیوه­های دستیابی به اهداف اجتماعی و زیست‌محیطی برای شرکت فراهم می­کند. هدف اصلی پژوهش حاضر بررسی تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعی و بلوغ منابع انسانی بر مدیریت منابع انسانی پایدار است. پژوهش حاضر از نظر هدف، کاربردی و از نظر روش جمع­آوری داده‌ها، توصیفی است. جامعة آماری این پژوهش را شرکت­های فعال در صنعت پتروشیمی ایران تشکیل داده‌اند. برای آزمون فرضیه‌ها و مدل پژوهش نرم‌افزار Smart PLS به‌کار گرفته شد. یافته­های پژوهش نشان داد سرمایة اجتماعی و بلوغ منابع انسانی بر پایداری تأثیر مثبت و معناداری می‌گذارد، در فرضیه­های فرعی، در تأثیر ابعاد سرمایة اجتماعی بر مدیریت منابع انسانی پایدار، فقط تأثیر بعد سرمایة رابطه­ای معنادار، و دو بعد دیگر یعنی سرمایة ساختاری و شناختی بی‌تأثیر شناخته شدند. همچنین، در بررسی تأثیر ابعاد بلوغ منابع انسانی نیز، تصویر سازمانی و سلامت فردی بر مدیریت منابع انسانی پایدار تأثیر مثبت می‌گذارند، اما ابعاد همسوسازی اهداف سازمان و افراد و بهره­وری بر مدیریت منابع انسانی پایدار تأثیر نمی‌گذارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بلوغ منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت منابع انسانی پایدار</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_58850_fd40695d82b7aff072f8827bbfeec3b1.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
