<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Explaining the Concept of Reason and Rationalism from the Perspective of Narrations as a Basis for Organizational Capital;(Human, Social, Psychological, Spiritual)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تبیین مفهوم عقل و عقل‌ورزی از منظر روایات به عنوان مبنایی برای سرمایه‌های سازمان (انسانی، اجتماعی، روان‌شناختی، معنوی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>579</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>603</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">69764</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2019.236635.1407</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احسان</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحیمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارعی متین</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>پرکان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت سیاستگذاری فرهنگی، دانشگاه باقرالعلوم (ع)، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In this research, intellect and rationalism have been introduced from the perspective of the traditions of the infallibles as the basis for the types of organizational capital. The strategy of this research is the analysis of the subject in which the literature on organizational capital and then the narratives related to the characteristics of reason are analyzed first using two patterns of Rhine and Bernard, King and Horwax. Then the conceptual framework derived from these themes is analyzed together. The result of the analysis shows that all the features of reason and rationalism in narratives include not only the characteristics of organizational capital, such as social, psychological, spiritual, and human, but beyond them, so that spiritual capital is a manifestation of rationalization in the domain of thought; The psychological capital of a manifestation of rationalism in the field of social traits and social capital is a manifestation of rationalization in the domain of human actions. Therefore, focusing on the concept of reason and rationality in the traditions of the innocent and looking at its dimensions and components can be a new bobby for the development of native-Islamic knowledge in the field of managing capital of the organization.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر عقل و عقل‌ورزی از منظر روایات معصومان &lt;sup&gt;(ع) &lt;/sup&gt;به‌عنوان مبنایی برای انواع سرمایه‌های سازمانی معرفی شده است. راهبرد پژوهش تحلیل مضمون است که طی آن ابتدا متون نظری موجود دربارة سرمایه‌های سازمانی، سپس، روایات مطرح‌شده در زمینة ویژگی‌های عقل و مشتقات آن با بهره‌گیری دو الگویراین و برنارد، و کینگ و هوروکس تحلیل شد. سپس، چارچوب مفهومی حاصل‌شده از مضامین یادشده با یکدیگر به صورت توأمان تحلیل شده‌اند. نتیجة تحلیل نشان داد همة ویژگی‌های عقل و عقل‌ورزی در روایات مطرح نه‌تنها متضمن ویژگی‌های سرمایه‌های یادشده بوده، بلکه فراتر از آن‌هاست، به‌طوری که می‌توان گفت سرمایة معنوی جلوه‌ای از عقل‌ورزی در ساحت اندیشه؛ سرمایة روان‌شناختی جلوه‌ای از عقل‌ورزی در ساحت گرایش‌ها و صفات، و سرمایة اجتماعی جلوه‌ای از عقل‌ورزی در ساحت اعمال و رفتارهای انسان است. بنابراین، تمرکز بر مفهوم عقل و عقل‌ورزی مطرح‌شده در روایات معصومان (ع) و واکاوی ابعاد و مؤلفه‌های آن می‌تواند بابی جدید برای توسعة دانشی بومی-اسلامی در حوزة مربوط به مدیریت سرمایه‌های سازمان باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة روان‌شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة معنوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عقل‌ورزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عقل</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_69764_3aa840c536f0167ab86d8b3419a477ea.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
