<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analyzing of Urban Social Capital Pattern base on Arbaeen Phenomenon</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیلی بر تدوین الگوی سرمایۀ اجتماعی شهری بر مبنای جریان اربعین</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>475</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>499</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">64992</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.239509.1438</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امین</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرجی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>ذوالفقارزاده کرمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>باقری کاهکش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی‌‌ارشد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Urban managers are seeking ways to solve urban issues and improve its indicators toward an ideal utopia, so that studding Arbaeen phenomena with focusing on urban issues shows that most of these issues are solved during Arbaeen’s pilgrimage and moreover Arbaeen moves its citizens toward premier goals with progress and group spirituality. In this regard this research is seeking different and specific aspects of Arbaeen’s phenomenon and codification of social capitals’ pattern specially recently because this movement has changed from an individual pilgrimage activity to a knowingly massive group movements. The research is theoretical and based on qualitative research method; dimensions of the research are texts, books, researches and speeches around Arbaeen and elements of social capital. Data gathering is by the aid of library and filed studies and from expert of relevant fields and Arbaeen’s participants. The samples were selected by snowball sampling and sample size required amount is based on theoretical saturation criterion. Interview transcripts and gathered texts were analyzed by thematic method and mains themes were respectively identified related to questions. As a result different aspects of Arbeen and also codification of social capitals detected and also some suggestion to use them in current urban managements submitted.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مدیران شهری همواره به دنبال حل مشکلات شهر به‌منظور ایجاد یک آرمان‌شهر ایده‌آل هستند، در این زمینه بررسی حرکت اربعین با درنظرگرفتن مسائل و مشکلاتی که مدیران شهری با آن مواجهند، نشان می‌دهد نه‌تنها بسیاری از این مشکلات در فضای اربعین حل ‌می‌شود، بلکه فراتر از آن، اربعین ساکنان خود را به‌سوی اهدافی والاتر و حرکت همراه با رشد دعوت می‌کند. این پژوهش با هدف بررسی جریان اربعین به‌ویژه در سال‌های اخیر به دنبال شناسایی ابعاد مختلف و متمایز، و تدوین الگوی سرمایة اجتماعی آن است. نوع تحقیق نظری و کاربردی و روش تحقیق کیفی است. قلمرو تحقیق، متن‌های مکتوب و شفاهی بوده و سعی بر توصیف کیفی محتوای مفاهیم متون شده است. روش گردآوری اطلاعات، میدانی و کتابخانه‌ای است و جامعه آماری شامل خبرگان حوزة معرفتی، شهری، مدیران و مجریان حاضر در اربعین و مجموعة کتب مرتبط با موضوع است. نمونه‌های پژوهش با روش نمونه‌گیری گلوله برفی انتخاب و حجم نمونة مورد نیاز براساس معیار اشباع نظری تعیین ‌شد. روش تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده، تحلیل مضمون بود. در نتیجة این پژوهش، ابعاد مختلفی از جریان اربعین و مؤلفه‌های سرمایة اجتماعی شناسایی‌ و پیشنهادهایی نیز برای به‌کارگیری الگوی به‌دست‌آمده برای مدیریت شهری مطرح شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جریان اربعین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت شهری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_64992_05cec01143bfee1bb9b3abaf6e6f5e00.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Relationship between Social Capital and Organizational Forgetting (The Case of Employees of the University of Isfahan)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطۀ بین سرمایۀ اجتماعی و فراموشی سازمانی (مورد مطالعه: کارکنان دانشگاه اصفهان)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>501</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>526</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">65031</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.240259.1443</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>مقتدایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشکدة علوم تربیتی و روان‌شناسی، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, organizations acknowledged the importance of social capital and its role to develop organizational and human resources. On the other hand, organizational forgetting is a new concept drawing the researchers &#039;attention. The present descriptive- survey study aims to explain the relationship between social capital and organizational forgetting. 200 staff of university of Isfahan were selected as sample by using Sample Power software. Two questionnaires of social capital and organizational forgetting were used as research tools. Pearson correlation coefficient and multivariate regression were used in this research. The results suggested that, there is a positive and significant relationship between social capital and intentional organizational forgetting, while a negative and significant relationship exists between social capital and accidental organizational forgetting. Data analysis showed a positive and significant relationship between social capital and organizational forgetting, that is, by using social capital, individuals can participate in decision making, so that they accept and implement the forgetting plan with awareness and confidence to its goals. This acceptance leads to decrease in resistance toward changes, decrease in knowledge waste, enhancement of absorption coefficient in organizations, development of stored knowledge, and finally improvement of organization.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه سازمان‌ها به اهمیت سرمایة اجتماعی و نقش آن در توسعة منابع انسانی و سازمانی اذعان دارند. از سویی، فراموشی سازمانی مفهومی جدید است که مورد توجه محققان قرار گرفته است. هدف این مقاله بررسی رابطة بین سرمایة اجتماعی و فراموشی سازمانی است. روش پژوهش حاضر توصیفی و از نوع همبستگی است. حجم نمونه با به‌کارگیری نرم‌افزار سمپل‌پاور، 200 نفر از کارکنان دانشگاه اصفهان برآورد شد. ابزار پژوهش دو پرسشنامة سرمایة اجتماعی و فراموشی سازمانی بود. نتایج بررسی ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و رگرسیون چندمتغیره حاکی از رابطة معنادار و مثبت سرمایة اجتماعی و فراموشی سازمانی هدفمند و رابطة معنا‌دار و منفی بین سرمایة اجتماعی و فراموشی سازمانی تصادفی بود. نتایج تحلیل داده‌ها نشان داد بین سرمایة اجتماعی و فراموشی سازمانی رابطة معنادار و مثبت وجود دارد. بدان معنا که با به‌کارگیری سرمایة اجتماعی می‌توان افراد را در تصمیم‌گیری‌هایی مشارکت داد که با آگاهی و اعتماد نسبت به اهداف برنامة فراموشی‌، به پذیرش و اجرای آن اقدام کنند. این پذیرش سبب کاهش مقاومت در برابر تغییر، کاهش زوال و اتلاف دانش‌، ارتقای ضریب جذب در سازمان و توسعة دانش ذخیره‌شده خواهد شد و سرانجام به بهسازی سازمان منجر می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراموشی تصادفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراموشی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراموشی هدفمند</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_65031_391e24be3df94c84934e43e89a2a434d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effect of Ambidextrous Leadership on Work Attitudes; Moderating Role of Social Capital and Self-efficacy</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر رهبری دوسوتوان بر نگرش‌های کاری با درنظرگرفتن نقش تعدیل‌گر سرمایۀ اجتماعی و خودکارآمدی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>527</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>545</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">64993</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.242067.1454</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>یزدان شناس</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aims to examine the effect of ambidextrous leadership on work attitudes in which the moderating role of social capital and self-efficacy were considered as well. Research method is of descriptive- correctional surveys. Statistical population consisted 1520 employees of Telecommunications Infrastructure Company which a random sample of them was selected which consisted 307 employees. Data were collected via questionnaires that have been used in previous researches. Collected data were analyzed according to structural equation modeling using AMOS software. Results show that ambidextrous leadership has a positive effect on job satisfaction and emotional commitment as the main work attitudes. Meanwhile, findings show that social capital and self-efficacy play the moderating roles in this relationship. Therefore, ambidextrous leadership behaviors would have greater positive effect on employees` work attitudes if they enjoy social capital and self-efficacy.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف تحقیق حاضر بررسی تأثیر رهبری دوسوتوان بر نگرش‌های کاری است که در این رابطه، به نقش تعدیل‌کنندة سرمایة اجتماعی و خودکارآمدی نیز توجه شده است. روش تحقیق از نوع توصیفی - همبستگی است. کارکنان شرکت ارتباطات زیرساخت به تعداد 1520 نفر جامعة آماری تحقیق را تشکیل دادند که از بین آن‌ها نمونه­ای تصادفی به تعداد 307 نفر انتخاب شد. داده­های تحقیق با ابزار پرسشنامة استاندارد جمع‌آوری شد. داده­های جمع­آوری‌شده با روش مدل­سازی معادلات ساختاری و با نرم­افزار AMOS تحلیل شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد رهبری دوسوتوان تأثیر مثبتی بر رضایت شغلی و تعهد عاطفی به عنوان نگرش‌های مهم کاری دارد. ضمن اینکه یافته­ها نشان داد سرمایة اجتماعی و خودکارآمدی نقش تعدیل‌کنندة مثبت در رابطة یادشده ایفا می­کنند. بنابراین، رفتارهای رهبری دوسوتوان در صورت برخورداری کارکنان از سرمایة اجتماعی و احساس خودکارآمدی، تأثیر مثبت بیشتری بر نگرش­های کاری کارکنان خواهد داشت.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خودکارآمدی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری دوسوتوان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نگرش‌های کاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_64993_75c8cba1be4a2e60b09237971d51ca0f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Social Capital, Entrepreneurship Marketing and Mediated Role of Shared Knowledge</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سرمایۀ اجتماعی، بازاریابی کارآفرینانه و نقش میانجی تسهیم دانش</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>547</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>569</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">64994</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.248962.1518</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>امینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه شیراز، شیراز، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4739-6148</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پیمان</FirstName>
					<LastName>دولتشاه</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد کارآفرینی، دانشکدة علوم انسانی، دانشگاه کاشان،کاشان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>فتاحی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد کارآفرینی، دانشکدة علوم انسانی، دانشگاه کاشان،کاشان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Home-based businesses have a hidden and key role in the development of indigenous economies. The importance of maintaining these companies in competitive environments has made marketing a vital part of them. Therefore, the social capital of the manager / staff in these businesses can be an incentive for the proper use of entrepreneurial marketing for the development and improvement of these firms, and since the use of entrepreneurial marketing requires rich and multifaceted knowledge, knowledge sharing can be a tool for improvement. This research studies the home-based businesses in Isfahan province. For data analysis, structural equation modeling and Smart PLS 2 software have been used. The results indicate that the existence of social capital is predictive of the use of entrepreneurial marketing dimensions in these businesses. It was also found that higher levels of social capital could increase the likelihood of knowledge sharing. And finally, the promotion of knowledge sharing culture can be a stimulus to employ entrepreneurial marketing.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کسب وکارهای خانگی نقشی پنهان، و در عین حال کلیدی، در توسعه اقتصاد بومی دارند. اهمیت حفظ ایظن کظرکت هظا در میظی هظای&lt;br /&gt;رقابتی باعث کده است که بازاریابی برای آن ها امری حیاتی میسوب کود. بنابراین، سرمایة اجتماعی مدیر/کارکنظان ایظن کسظب وکارهظا&lt;br /&gt;میتواند میرکی برای استفاده درست و مناسب از بازاریابی کارآفرینانه برای بهبود و توسعه این بنگاهها باکد، و از آنجا کظه بظه کظار یری&lt;br /&gt;بازاریابی کارآفرینانه به دانشی غنی و چندوجهی نیاز دارد، تسهیم دانش میتواند ابزاری برای بهبود این ویژ ی باکد. پژوهش حاضظر بظه&lt;br /&gt;مطالعة کسب وکارهای خانگی مستقر در استان اصفهان پرداخته است. برای تیلیل داده ها از مدل سازی معظادت سظاختاری و نظر افظزار&lt;br /&gt;Smart PLS2 به کار رفته کده است. نتایج نشان داد سرمایة اجتماعی پیشبینی کنندة بظه کظار یری ابعظا د بازاریظابی کارآفرینانظه در ایظن&lt;br /&gt;کسبوکارها است. همچنین، مشخص کد سطوح باتتر سرمایة اجتماعی میتواند احتمال تسهیم دانش را افزایش دهد. در نهایت، تظرویج&lt;br /&gt;فرهنگ تسهیم دانش میتواند میرکی برای به کار یری بازاریابی کارآفرینانه باکد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازاریابی کارآفرینانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تسهیم دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کسب‌وکارهای خانگی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_64994_f13931dc9360fa272a0ba4f17269ee26.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Promoting Citizens’ Public Trust: Studying the Role of Good Governance and E-Government Services</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارتقای اعتماد عمومی شهروندان: بررسی نقش حکمرانی خوب و خدمات دولت الکترونیکی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>571</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>594</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">65023</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.249639.1524</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زینب</FirstName>
					<LastName>مولوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>معصومه</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی ابوعلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی‌ارشد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدمحمدباقر</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>By more complexity of societies, types of trust are manifested including public trust, trust in state and trust in political entities.IT has made confronted communication more limiter, and build trust among citizens is more difficult. The aim of present research is to study the role of e-government services and good governance in creating citizens’ public trust. This is an applied research with correlation – descriptive method based on SEM. Research population consists of all 18-65 year-old citizens who have used government’ e-services at least one time. Finally, 89were selected as sample by Morgan table and simple sampling method. Data collection tool is a questionnaire that its reliability was confirmed by mix reliability and Cronbach’s alpha methods while its validity was confirmed by convergent and divergent methods upon confirmation by elites. Data analysis was conducted by SEM and using Amos22 software package. The findings indicate that the quality of e-services and good governance impacts on public trust positively and significantly while good governance plays a moderating role in the relationship between e-government and public trust. By expanding the quality of government’ e-services, communications, coordination and standardization of information and services provided on the side of accountability and transparency mechanisms to increase citizens&#039; trust and consequently it is.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اعتماد یکی از ابعاد سرمایة اجتماعی است که با پیچیده‌ترشدن جوامع، ناگزیر انواعی از آن، از جمله اعتماد عمومی، در بطن نیازهای جامعه خودنمایی می‌کند. بنابراین، پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی نقش خدمات دولت الکترونیکی و حکمرانی خوب در ارتقای اعتماد عمومی شهروندان انجام گرفت. این پژوهش از نوع کاربردی و به روش توصیفی- همبستگی اجرا شده است. جامعة آماری پژوهش حاضر، همة شهروندان 18 تا 65 ساله بودند که حداقل یکبار از خدمات دولت الکترونیکی استفاده کرده باشند. در نهایت، براساس جدول مورگان، 384 نفر برای پاسخ به پرسشنامه در نظر گرفته شدند. در مجموع، 386 نفر به روش دردسترس به‌عنوان نمونه انتخاب شدند. ابزار پژوهش پرسشنامه بود که پایایی آن به روش‌های پایایی مرکب و آزمون آلفای کرونباخ، و روایی آن پس از تأیید خبرگان به روش‌های روایی واگرا و همگرا تأیید شد. داده‌ها به روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری و با نرم‌افزار Amos22 تحلیل شد. نتایج نشان داد اعتماد شهروندان به سازمان‌ها و نهادهای عمومی از طریق بهبود کیفیت خدمات دولت الکترونیکی و حکمرانی خوب ارتقا می‌یابد و حکمرانی خوب در رابطة خدمات دولت الکترونیکی و اعتماد عمومی نقش میانجی دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتماد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتماد عمومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خدمات دولت الکترونیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حکمرانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حکمرانی خوب</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_65023_501c67d758c44e56a9e7abbdf6d41bfc.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analyzing and Evaluating the Social Resilience against Natural Disasters in Deteriorate Texture of Tehran&#039;s District 12</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل و ارزیابی تاب‌آوری اجتماعی بافت فرسودۀ منطقۀ 12 شهر تهران در مواجهه با سوانح طبیعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>595</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>612</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">65122</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.251670.1540</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدتقی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضویان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، دانشکدة علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جمیله</FirstName>
					<LastName>توکلی‌نیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة علوم زمین، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرزاد بهتاش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری شهرسازی، دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خزایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی شهری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today, vulnerability of cities, especially old and deteriorate texture, has become a global problem for various experts. Problem of the research: according to the effects that situation of deteriorate texture of Tehran&#039;s District 12 has in the economic and cultural development of Tehran metropolis, and lack of attention and proper consideration, social dimension of resilience in the district is a situation of trouble. Purpose of the research is measurement social resilience in order to favorable against natural disasters. Research method: The present research is an applied and descriptive-analytic study. The sample amount was estimated using the Cochran formula which equivalent to 400 people by random selection. In order to data analysis, we used statistical methods of SPSS that is one-sample T-test and Structural equations with PLS software. Result of the research shows that the condition of social resilience in deteriorate texture of Tehran&#039;s District 12 is an unfavorable situation, it should be noted that this affair have done by survey and evaluation three factors: citizenship education, social participation and belong sense of place which factor of belong sense of place in this district is more fragile situation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه، آسیب‌پذیری شهرها و به‌ویژه بافت‌های قدیمی و فرسوده در برابر سوانح طبیعی، به‌عنوان مسئله‌ای جهانی پیشِ روی متخصصان رشته‌های گوناگون قرار گرفته است. با توجه به شرایط و موقعیتی که بافت فرسودة منطقة­ 12 شهرداری تهران در توسعة اقتصادی و فرهنگی کلان‌شهر تهران دارد، و عدم توجه و رسیدگی مناسب، شرایط در بعد اجتماعی تاب‌آوری در منطقة مورد نظر در وضعیت نابسامانی است،سنجش میزان تاب­آوری اجتماعی به‌منظور مواجهة مطلوب با پیامدهای سوانح طبیعی ضروری است. تحقیق حاضر از نظر هدف، کاربردی و از نظر روشِ بررسی، توصیفی - تحلیلی است. حجم نمونه نیز براساس فرمول کوکران، 400 نفر برآورد شد که به روش تصادفی انتخاب شدند. به‌منظور تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌ها از آزمون‌های آماری تی تک‌نمونه­ای و مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری بهره گرفته شد&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;. نتایج نشان داد&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; وضعیت تاب‌آوری اجتماعی در منطقة 12 در شرایط نامطلوبی قرار دارد، شایان ذکر است این امر با تحلیل و ارزیابی سه مؤلفة آموزش شهروندی، مشارکت اجتماعی و حس تعلق مکانی انجام گرفت که مؤلفة حس تعلق مکانی در این منطقه در وضعیت نابسامان­تری است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بافت فرسوده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تاب‌آوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تاب‌آوری اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سوانح طبیعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_65122_9d224edaddfdd652b38790d985740f36.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Winners and Losers of Brain Drain in the Middle East Countries; With Emphasize on Human Capital</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>برندگان و بازندگان فرار مغزها در کشورهای منطقۀ خاورمیانه با تأکید بر سرمایۀ انسانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>613</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>642</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">65151</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.245052.1481</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حشمت الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>عسگری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایلام، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>بادپا</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی‌ارشد، دانشکدة ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه ایلام، ایلام، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>For some years now, the phenomenon of brain drain in developing countries, and especially in the countries of the Middle East, has attracted the attention of economists. According to economic theories about the economic consequences of brain drain, there are two traditional views. The traditional view of brain drain is considered as a direct reduction of human capital, but in the new perspective, in addition to those considered in traditional perspectives, the positive effects of brain drain are also considered. The main reason for the discussion here is the positive role of brain drain in increasing the motivation to acquire education in the community, the transfer of knowledge and technology through the return of short-term immigration, the formation of the effects of immigration networks and returning income to countries of origin versus The negative impact of brain drain is the reduction of human capital in the country of origin. Therefore, in this research, the clarity of the importance and importance of the effects of brain drain on human capital accumulation, as well as judgments about the traditional and modern perspectives on the brain drain literature in Middle Eastern countries during the period 1991-2010, has been addressed. The results of the study show that the brain drain has a positive effect on the accumulation of human capital in the studied countries and at existing rates of brain drain, 9 countries benefited from brain drain and 5 affected countries. In addition, considering that Iran is suffering from brain drain, it is suggested that by creating favorable conditions for the elites, it is suggested that their survival coefficient in the country be provided.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">چند سالی است پدیدة فرار مغزها در کشورهای در حال توسعه و به‌ویژه کشورهای منطقة خاورمیانه توجه اقتصاددانان را به خود جلب کرده است. براساس نظریه‌­های اقتصادی در زمینة تبعات اقتصادی فرار مغزها، دو دیدگاه سنتی و نوین وجود دارد. دیدگاه سنتی فرار مغزها را به‌عنوان کاهش مستقیم سرمایة انسانی در نظر می­گیرد، اما در دیدگاه نوین علاوه بر مواردی که در دیدگاه­های سنتی مد نظر بوده، آثار مثبت ناشی از فرار مغزها نیز در نظر گرفته شده است. شالودة اصلی بحث در اینجا بر نقش مثبت فرار مغزها در افزایش انگیزة کسب تحصیل در جامعه، انتقال دانش و تکنولوژی از طریق برگشت مهاجرت­های کوتاه­مدت، شکل­گیری آثار شبکه­ای مهاجرت و درآمد برگشتی به کشورهای مبدأ در مقابل اثر منفی فرار مغزها یعنی کاهش سرمایة انسانی کشور مبدأ متمرکز است. بنابراین، در این تحقیق به شفاف‌کردن علامت و اهمیت آثار فرار مغزها بر انباشت سرمایة انسانی و نیز قضاوت دربارة دیدگاه­های سنتی و نوین در متون نظری فرار مغزها در کشورهای منطقة خاورمیانه طی سال­های 1991 تا 2010 پرداخته شده است. نتیجة تحقیق نشان داد جریان فرار مغزها اثر مثبت بر انباشت سرمایة انسانی کشورهای مورد بررسی داشته است و در نرخ­های موجود فرار مغزها، 9 کشور از فرار مغزها منتفع و 5 کشور متضرر شده­اند. ضمن اینکه با توجه به متضررشدن ایران از فرار مغزها، پیشنهاد می­شود با ایجاد شرایط مطلوب برای نخبگان، ضریب ماندگاری آنان در کشور افزایش یابد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انباشت سرمایة انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دیدگاه‌های سنتی و نوین فرار مغزها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرار مغزها</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_65151_92f2ddfd29230a2598f1d7ae300bc96e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
