<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Organizational Justice on Social Capital with Studying the Moderating Role of Meritocracy in Organization</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر عدالت سازمانی بر ارتقای سرمایۀ اجتماعی با میانجی‌گری شایسته‌سالاری در سازمان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>291</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>314</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">67429</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.246381.1498</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خیراندیش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه علوم و فنون هوایی شهید ستاری، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری‌نیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The importance of social capital is to the extent that it is considered as the facilitator of all social activities. Hence, in many researches, it has been studied the factors causing it. Then, the present paper will investigate the effect of organizational justice on social capital with the mediating role of meritocracy in organization. This paper, from objective point of view and type of use is applied and descriptive, respectively. The Statistical Population of this paper includes 500 people working in Exploration Management at National Iranian Oil Company. The sample of 218 clerks based upon Morgan Sampling Table and Stratified Random Sampling method were selected. In this paper, we have used two standard questionnaires namely Social Capital Questionnaire, Organizational justice questionnaire and meritocracy researcher made Questionnaire. The Questionnaires have been validated by the experts and elites of this field. Furthermore, Cronbach&#039;s alpha was employed to confirm the reliability of the study instruments. The results obtained by Structural Equation Modeling have revealed that organizational justice affects both social capital and meritocracy. Also, meritocracy has positive effects on social capital. Additionally, organizational justice directly (.39) and indirectly has a moderating role of job meritocracy (.50) impacts social capital.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اهمیت سرمایة اجتماعی به‌ اندازه‌ای است که از آن به‌عنوان عامل تسهیل‌کنندة همة فعالیت‌های اجتماعی یاد می‌شود. از این رو، در پژوهش‌های زیادی به شناخت عوامل ایجادکنندة آن پرداخته شده است. بر این اساس، پژوهش حاضر به بررسی تأثیر عدالت سازمانی بر ارتقای سرمایة اجتماعی با نقش میانجی شایسته‌سالاری در سازمان می‌پردازد. تحقیق حاضر از نظر هدف، کاربردی و از نظر نحوة اجرا، تحقیقی توصیفی- همبستگی است. جامعه‏ی آماری تحقیق شامل 500 نفر از کارکنان مدیریت اکتشاف شرکت ملی نفت ایران است که براساس جدول مورگان و با روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌ای، 218 نفر به‌عنوان نمونه انتخاب شدند. ابزار پژوهش سه پرسشنامة استاندارد سرمایة اجتماعی ناپاهیت و گوشال (1998)، عدالت سازمانی مورمن و نیهوف (1993) و پرسشنامة محقق‌ساختة شایسته‌سالاری بود. روایی محتوای پرسشنامه‌ها براساس نظرات تخصصی استادان و خبرگان و پایایی آن‌ها نیز با محاسبة ضریب آلفای کرونباخ تأیید شد. نتایج تحلیل داده‌ها با روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری نشان داد عدالت سازمانی از طریق سرمایة اجتماعی بر شایسته‌سالاری تأثیر می‌گذارد. همچنین، تأثیر مستقیم عدالت سازمانی بر ارتقای سرمایة اجتماعی برابر با 39&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 و تأثیر غیرمستقیم آن به‌واسطة متغیر میانجی شایسته‌سالاری برابر با 5&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شایسته‌سالاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عدالت سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_67429_2943bd3d6987f3ffa193d235bcc3c5eb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
