<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Qualitative Assessment of the Condition of Social Capital by Using Grounded Theory (Case: Abarik District, The City Sonqur and Kolyaee)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی کیفی وضعیت سرمایة اجتماعی با به‌کارگیری نظریة بنیانی (مورد مطالعه: دهستان آبباریک، شهرستان‌ سنقر و کلیائی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>209</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>231</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">59963</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2016.59963</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>افسانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>ملک حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدة کشاورزی، دانشگاه رازی، کرمانشاه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>همزه ای</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة کشاورزی، دانشگاه رازی، کرمانشاه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>حیدری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدة کشاورزی، دانشگاه رازی، کرمانشاه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اکرم</FirstName>
					<LastName>بیناییان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدة کشاورزی، دانشگاه رازی، کرمانشاه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Rural social capital is important factors in rural development and social welfare, improve the productivity of factors of production and the result of modifying the pattern of production and consumption in the rural community. The aim of qualitative research was done using grounded theory methods to assess the social capital of Abarik district of the city Sonqur and Kolyaee. The study populations were 20 inhabitants of the Abarik district that were select by using purposive sampling method. In this study, according to the study, the data collection techniques were used in-depth interviews and direct observation in the form of tow open and selective coding analyzed. Findings showed that feeling of confidence and security, capacity of differences adoption, social participation, social activism, cooperation, value of life, civic participation, accepted norms, labor relations and social protection, as elements of social capital are in a different situation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سرمایة اجتماعی روستاییان از عوامل مهم در توسعه و رفاه اجتماعی روستایی، ارتقای بهره‌وری عوامل تولید و در نتیجه اصلاح الگوی تولید و مصرف در جامعة روستایی است. هدف تحقیق کیفی حاضر که با بهره‌گیری از روش نظریة بنیانی انجام گرفته است، ارزیابی سرمایة‌ اجتماعی دهستان آبباریک از توابع شهرستان‌ سنقر و کلیائی بود. جامعة مورد مطالعه 20 نفر از ساکنان دهستان آبباریک بودند که به روش نمونه‌گیری گلوله برفی انتخاب شدند. در این مطالعه با توجه به مسئلة تحقیق، داده‌ها با ابزارهای مصاحبة عمیق و مشاهدة مستقیم جمع‌آوری، و در قالب سه مرحله کدگذاری باز، محوری و انتخابی تحلیل شد. یافته‌های تحقیق نشان داد احساس اعتماد و امنیت، ظرفیت پذیرش تفاوت‌ها، مشارکت اجتماعی، عملگرایی اجتماعی، همکاری، ارزش زندگی، مشارکت مدنی، هنجارپذیری، پیوندهای کاری و حمایت اجتماعی، به‌عنوان عناصر سرمایة اجتماعی در وضعیت‌های متفاوتی قرار دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزیابی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دهستان آبباریک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریة بنیانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_59963_0c20a7b66c0ea10fe27455b640e556be.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
