<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Meta-Analysis of the Antecedents and Consequences of Social Capital in Organizations</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>فراتحلیل پیشایندها و پیامدهای سرمایة اجتماعی در سازمان‏ها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>351</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>373</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">72615</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2019.285598.1878</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بلال</FirstName>
					<LastName>پناهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشکدة مدیریت، اقتصاد و حسابداری، دانشگاه پیام نور، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In recent decades, social capital has been one of the issues that have found great attention from researchers. It arises due to numerous factors, and affects important organizational elements in organizations. Using the meta-analysis method, this study aims at the quantitative compilation of the results of previous studies on the factors effective on social capital management and its consequences in Iran. The Comprehensive Meta-Analysis software has been used to analyze the obtained data. In this research project, 20 independent variables and 35 dependent variables were identified in 83 related studies. The results of the meta-analysis on social capital in organizations showed that the variables of human capital, organizational citizenship behavior, ethical intelligence, organizational strategies, organizational justice, social networks, organizational intelligence, vertical communications, transformational leadership, and social responsibility had the greatest effects on the formation and enhancement of social capital in the organizations. Also, the results of this study showed that social capital affects important organizational variables such as organizational health, participation, organizational success, organizational excellence, quality of life, job satisfaction, team effectiveness, knowledge management, talent management, accountability, performance improvement, Customer-orientation, organizational learning, intellectual capital, value creation, vitality and happiness, and organizational commitment.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سرمایة اجتماعی یکی از موضوعاتی است که در دهه‏های اخیر در پژوهش‏ها جایگاهی مهم یافته است. سرمایة اجتماعی در اثر عوامل متعدد در سازمان‏ها به وجود می‌آید و عناصر مهم سازمانی را تحت تأثیر قرار می‏دهد. این پژوهش با به‌کارگیری روش فراتحلیل و با هدف ترکیب کمّی نتایج پژوهش‏های قبلی در حوزة عوامل مؤثر بر مدیریت سرمایة اجتماعی در سازمان‏ها و پیامدهای آن در کشور ایران انجام گرفت و برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‏های آن از نرم‏افزار جامع فراتحلیل استفاده شد. در این بررسی، از 83 مطالعة منتخب، تعداد 20 متغیر مستقل و 35 متغیر وابستة مختلف شناسایی شد. نتیجة بررسی فراتحلیل سرمایة اجتماعی در حوزة سازمان‏ها نشان ‏داد متغیرهای سرمایة انسانی، رفتار شهروندی سازمانی، هوش اخلاقی، استراتژی‏های سازمان، عدالت سازمانی، شبکه‏های اجتماعی، هوش سازمانی، ارتباطات عمودی، رهبری تحول‏آفرین، و مسئولیت‏پذیری اجتماعی بیشترین تأثیر را در شکل‏گیری و تشدید سرمایة اجتماعی در سازمان‏های ایرانی داشته‏اند. همچنین، نتایج این تحقیق نشان داد سرمایة اجتماعی متغیرهای مهم سازمانی ـ مثل سلامت سازمانی، مشارکت، موفقیت سازمانی، کیفیت زندگی، رضایت شغلی، اثربخشی تیمی، مدیریت دانش، مدیریت استعدادها، پاسخگویی، بهبود عملکرد، مشتری‏گرایی، یادگیری سازمانی، سرمایة فکری، ارزش‏آفرینی، شادابی و شادکامی، تعهد سازمانی ـ را تحت تأثیر قرار می‏دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیامدهای سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیشایندهای سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراتحلیل</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_72615_99e5664b6bbd0a89e27548638ba17fa6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
