<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analyzing and assessing the relation between social capital and delinquency 
Case study: Isfahan city students</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل و بررسی ارتباط بین سرمایه اجتماعی وکاهش بزهکاری؛ مورد مطالعه: دانش‌آموزان مناطق شهر اصفهان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">75743</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2020.279243.1827</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمود</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرخلیلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پردیس فارابی تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسعود</FirstName>
					<LastName>حیدری</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه آزاد اصفهان(خوراسگان)</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Social capital due to its context and connections with the humanitarian social aspects constitute a vulnerable social jurisdiction. With respect to these social interactions, attempt is made here to assess the social capital relation and delinquency. The method adopted here is of survey, run among 384 boy students within 19-25 years of age range in the 6th and 7th districts of Isfahan city. The findings indicate that the social capital with all its dimensions like: trust, support, social coherence and interactions among others and delinquents is of 95% coefficient of confidence, indicating a negative statistical significance. The age, education level and socio-economic stance as the conceptual variables with 95% coefficient of confidence indicate a positive statistical significance. It is found that in the new social structure, the more the social capital, as the cumulative valuable resources like social, emotional, and financial support, sense of belonging, dependency and participation in different aspects of social life for the individuals, the healthier the population in better settings.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سرمایه اجتماعی به دلیل محتوایی که دارد، با موضوعات مطرح در حوزه انسانی ، از جمله حوزه آسیب‌های اجتماعی ،ارتباط پیدا می‌کند. با توجه به این تأثیرات متقابل، هدف تحقیق حاضر بررسی رابطه بین سرمایه اجتماعی و بزهکاری است.روش این مطالعه به روش پیمایشی در بین ۳۸۴ نفر از دانش آموزان پسر 25 تا 19 سال مناطق 6 و 7 شهر اصفهان انجام شده است. یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد بین سرمایه اجتماعی و تمام ابعاد آن اعم از مشارکت، اعتماد، حمایت و انسجام اجتماعی و همچنین روابط متقابل با دیگران با بزهکاری ، با ضریب اطمینان ۹۵ درصد از نظر آماری رابطه منفی وجود دارد. همچنین، سن و پایه تحصیلی و پایگاه اقتصادی و اجتماعی به عنوان متغیرهای زمینه‌ای با ضریب اطمینان ۹۵ درصد، از نظر آماری رابطه معنی داری نشان داده‌اند. نتایج این تحقیق نشان می‌دهد هر اندازه افراد در ساختار جدید اجتماعی، سرمایه اجتماعی بیشتری داشته باشند، یعنی این متغیر به عنوان مجموع ذخایر ارزشمندی مانند حمایت‌های اجتماعی، روانی و مالی، حس تعلق، وابستگی و مشارکت در جنبه‌های مختلف زندگی اجتماعی برای افراد وجود داشته باشد، سلامت اجتماعی آنها در وضعیت بهتری قرار خواهد گرفت.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انسجام اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بزهکاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانش آموزان اصفهان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
