<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Dimensions of Social Capital and Its Relation to Moral Marketing (Case: Sepah Bank Branches of Qom Province)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی ابعاد سرمایۀ اجتماعی و رابطۀ آن با بازاریابی اخلاقی (مورد مطالعه: شعب بانک سپه استان قم)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>309</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>332</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">64694</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.136506.1133</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>جندقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدمهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>قریشی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، ساوه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدمجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>احدی شعار</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، ساوه، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Social capital refers to links and connections among members of a network as a source of value, which serves the purposes of the members by creating the norms and mutual trust. Also ethical marketing is seeking for honest and true presentation of a product, in the field of customer&#039;s desired cultural and social values. This research aims to investigate the dimensions of social capital and their impact on ethical marketing among employees of Sepah Bank Branches in Qom. The present study is of applicable type, a descriptive-correlative method. The statistical population of this study was composed of all 227 employees of Sepah Bank Branchs in Qom Province. The random simple sampling method was used and the sample size was estimated to be 143 by Cochran formula. The research instrument was a questionnaire whose validity was confirmed by experts and its reliability was confirmed by Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient. The data were analyzed by correlation test. The results showed that there is a positive and significant relationship between social capital (and its dimensions) and ethical marketing.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA"> سرمایة اجتماعی به پیوندها و ارتباطات میان اعضای یک شبکه به‌عنوان منبع باارزشی اشاره می‌کند که با خلق هنجارها و اعتماد متقابل موجب تحقق اهداف اعضا می‌شود. بازاریابی اخلاقی نیز به دنبال عرضة صادقانه و حقیقی یک محصول، در حوزة ارزش‌های فرهنگی و اجتماعی مورد نظر مصرف‌کننده است. این پژوهش به دنبال بررسی ابعاد سرمایة اجتماعی و تأثیر آن‌ها بر بازاریابی اخلاقی در میان کارکنان شعب بانک سپه استان قم بوده است. پژوهش حاضر از نوع کاربردی است و به روش توصیفی – همبستگی اجرا شد. جامعة آماری این پژوهش را همة کارمندان شعب بانک سپه استان قم به تعداد 227 نفر تشکیل دادند. روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی ساده بود و حجم نمونه براساس فرمول کوکران 143 نفر برآورد شد. ابزار پژوهش پرسشنامه بود که روایی آن از طریق نظر خبرگان، و پایایی آن با ضریب آلفای کرونباخ تأیید شد. داده‌ها با آزمون همبستگی تحلیل شد. نتایج نشان داد بین سرمایة اجتماعی (و ابعاد آن) و بازاریابی اخلاقی رابطة مثبت و معناداری وجود دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اخلاق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازاریابی اخلاقی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازاریابی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_64694_6f5d62135ee6df7ce60310abcbad5dd8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
