<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Social Capital Impact on the Employees&#039; Organizational Entrepreneurship Development Process in the Post Offices of the Mazandaran Province</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر سرمایه اجتماعی بر توسعة فرآیند کارآفرینی سازمانی کارکنان ادارات پست استان مازندران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>391</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>413</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60665</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2016.60665</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>صمدی میارکلائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ارشد مدیریت دولتی، باشگاه پژوهشگران جوان و نخبگان، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، قائم‌شهر، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمزه</FirstName>
					<LastName>صمدی میارکلائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم‌وتحقیقات، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسعود</FirstName>
					<LastName>بسطامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد سنندج، سنندج، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رمضان</FirstName>
					<LastName>غلامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Organization entrepreneurship is method to deal with environmental changes within the organization, which in the case of entrepreneurship non-fulfillment, organizational viability and survival will be exposed to the problem in long-term. Social capital also as the ability of employees to work with others so as to achieve the common goals in groups and organizations has a significant impact on the development of organizational entrepreneurship. In fact, the purpose of the present study was to examine and explain the impacts of social capital and its component on the organizational entrepreneurship. The method used in this study in terms of data collection is descriptive- survey method and in terms of research purposes, it is an applied research. Statistical population in this research includes 346 persons of Post office in Mazandaran province (central department) that by considering the particular limitations of data collection, 150 persons were selected as a sample. For data collection, questionnaire is used, and data analysis also was done by SPSS and LISREL software. The results of structural equation modeling showed that there were significant relationships between social capital (β=0.95) and its components (structural capital (β=0.49), communicative capital (β=0.32), and cognitive capital (β=0.52)) with organizational entrepreneurship.
 
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
 </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کارآفرینی سازمانی روشی برای رویارویی با تغییرهای محیطی و داخلی سازمان است، که در صورت محقق‌نشدن کارآفرینی، حیات و بقای سازمان در بلندمدت با مشکل مواجه خواهد شد. سرمایة ­اجتماعی به­عنوان توانایی افراد برای کارکردن با دیگران، به­منظور دستیابی به اهداف مشترک در گروه­ها و سازمان­ها، تأثیر زیادی در توسعۀ کارآفرینی سازمانی دارد. در واقع، هدف از پژوهش حاضر تبیین و بررسی آثار سرمایة اجتماعی و مؤلفه­های آن بر توسعة کارآفرینی سازمانی است. روش تحقیق از لحاظ نحوة گردآوری داده‌ها، توصیفی- همبستگی و از نظر هدف کاربردی است. جامعة آماری این تحقیق، 346 نفر از کارکنان ادارات پست استان مازندران (بخش مرکزی) می­باشند، که با توجه به محدودیت­های خاص جمع­آوری داده­ها 150 نفر به روش تصادفی ساده به‌عنوان نمونه انتخاب شدند. ابزار جمع­آوری داده­ها پرسشنامه است، و تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده­ها نیز به‌وسیلة نرم­افزارهای SPSS و Lisrel انجام گرفت. یافته­های مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری نشان داد ارتباط معنا­دار میان سرمایة ­اجتماعی (95/0=b) و مؤلفه­های آن (سرمایة ساختاری: 49/0=b، سرمایة رابطه­ای: 32/0=b و سرمایة شناختی: 52/0=b) با کارآفرینی سازمانی وجود دارد.
&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;
 </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ادارات پست</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_60665_8343d5313d31432629fbdc055c5456cb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
