<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Investigation of the Effect of Markazi Province NGOs’ Social Capital on Democracy</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر سرمایۀ اجتماعیِ تشکل‌های مردم‌نهاد استان مرکزی بر مردم‌سالاری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>111</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>134</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">75687</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2020.290257.1919</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میترا</FirstName>
					<LastName>بیات</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترا، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، نراق، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>خیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، نراق، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>پوریانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، نراق، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the key factors that influences democracy is social capital. The current study seeks to investigate the effect of social capital of Non-Governmental Organizations of Markazi province in Iran on democracy. The intended indicators of social capital are social trust, participation, and cohesion. To this end, the theories of Putnam, Coleman, and Fukuyama have been used. In addition, data collection was done through survey (using a questionnaire) and document analysis (using books and articles). Then, using Amos software and structural equation modeling, confirmatory factor analysis was performed, while the descriptive statistics were obtained using SPSS software. The Cronbach&#039;s alpha for 22 items was found to be 0.929, which is an acceptable rate of reliability. The statistical population included the members of Markazi province NGOs (1304 individuals), out of which a sample of 384 participants was selected using stratified random sampling based on the Cochran formula. The findings of the study revealed that the social capital of Markazi province NGOs has a positive and significant effect on democracy. It plays an important role in realizing the socio-cultural forefront of the Revolution, creating democratic institutions and developing a civil society, and synergizing all capacities to organize the political objectives of Iran, fight enemies, and face challenges ahead. NGOs should attract and use talented and young individuals to reach their goals. They should also have mutual relationships with various networks, organizations, governmental organizations, and different layers of people.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">از عوامل تأثیرگذار بر مردم‌سالاری عامل بسیار مهم سرمایة اجتماعی است. پژوهش حاضر به منظور بررسی تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعیِ تشکل‌های مردم‌نهاد استان مرکزی بر مردم‌سالاری انجام شد. شاخص‌های مورد نظر سرمایة اجتماعی اعتماد، مشارکت، و انسجام اجتماعی بودند. برای دستیابی به این هدف، از دیدگاه پاتنام و کلمن و فوکویاما و از روش پیمایشی (با ابزار پرسشنامه) و اسنادی (با استفاده از کتاب‌ها و مقالات) بهره گرفته شد و با استفاده از نرم‌افزار آموس و مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری تحلیل عاملی تأییدی انجام گرفت و به کمک نرم‌افزار SPSS شاخص‌های توصیفی به دست آمد. ضریب آلفای کرونباخ برای 22 گویه 929/0 و دارای پایایی قابل قبول بود. جامعة آماری اعضای تشکل‌های مردم‌نهاد استان مرکزی (1304 نفر) بودند و از نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌بندی‌شده استفاده شد. حجم نمونه بر اساس فرمول کوکران به طور سخت‌گیرانه 384 نفر بود. یافتة پژوهش این بود که سرمایة اجتماعی تشکل‌های مردم‌نهاد استان مرکزی بر مردم‌سالاری تأثیر مثبت و معنادار می‌گذارد و برای تحقق جبهة فرهنگی‌ـ اجتماعی انقلاب و هم‌افزایی استعدادها و ظرفیت‌ها به منظور سامان دادن به اهداف سیاسی نظام و مبارزه با دشمنان و شفاف‌سازی چالش‌های پیش رو و ایجاد نهادهای دموکراتیک و توسعة جامعة مدنی نقشی مهم ایفا می‌کند. در این زمینه باید از نیروهای مستعد و جوان استفاده کرد. آن‌ها باید از سرمایة خود برای پیشبرد اهدافشان نهایت بهره را ببرند و با شبکه‌ها و تشکل‌های متفاوت و سازمان‌های دولتی و آحاد مردم روابط متقابل برقرار کنند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتماد اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تشکل‌های مردم‌نهاد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مردم‌سالاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشارکت اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_75687_53e09a585fcf3d57cad5a82737eaeb55.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
