<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effective Factors on Women&#039;s Social Capital in the Multi- Cultivate and Farmhouse Systems</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>عوامل مؤثربر سرمایۀ اجتماعی زنان، در نظام‌های چندکشتی و رعیتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>95</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>114</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">62095</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2017.62095</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خلیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرزائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرجان</FirstName>
					<LastName>سپه‌پناه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>موحدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار ،گروه ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا، همدان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to examine Effective factors on Social capital women in the the Multi- Cultivate and Farmhouse systems. The population for the study was 740 women of in the west of Iran (Hamadan Province). A sampling randomization resulted (Bartlett’s table) in a sample of 254 participants from the population. A survey questionnaire was constructed and used to collect data from randomly selected students and were analyzed by SPSS and Excel software’s. The results show that there are Significant differences between Social capital components in both systems. According to Leven test (&lt;0.05) and Equality of variances, the family system is intercropping component of a sense of security and trust, valuing the life and capacity of differences among women, But in farmhouse system, more than components of friendship and family relationships, neighborhood associations, participation in local community and activism among women. In addition, the results of path analysis indicated that 0.61% of the social capital changes explain variables such as work experience, education, income and ownership of the land mass media. That is most effective education and mass media in increasing social capital among women.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این تحقیق، بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر سرمایة اجتماعی زنان در نظام­های چندکشتی و رعیتی است. جامعة آماری پژوهش شامل740 نفر از زنان بخش فیروزان نهاوند (استان همدان) بودند که براساس شاخص کفایت نمونة بارتلت 254 نفر از آن‏ها به روش نمونه‏گیری ساده تصادفی برای مطالعه انتخاب شدند. ابزار اصلی تحقیق، پرسشنامه بود. نتایج پژوهش نشان داد تفاوت معناداری بین مؤلفه­های سرمایة اجتماعی در هر دو نظام وجود دارد. با توجه به تست لون (کمتر از 05&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0) و برابری واریانس­ها، میزان مؤلفه­های احساس امنیت و اعتماد، بهادادن به زندگی و ظرفیت پذیرش تفاوت‏ها بین زنان در نظام­های خانوادگی چندکشتی بیشتر است. در مقابل، مؤلفه­های دوستی و روابط خانوادگی، پیوندهای همسایگی، مشارکت در اجتماعات محلی و عمل­گرایی در بافت اجتماعی بین زنان در نظام کشت رعیتی بیشتر است. علاوه بر این، نتایج تحلیل مسیر گویای آن است که 61&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 درصد از تغییرات سرمایة اجتماعی را متغیرهایی مانند سابقة کار، تحصیلات، درآمد، رسانه­های انبوهی و مالکیت زمین می­تواند تبیین کند که میزان تحصیلات و رسانه‌های انبوهی بیشترین اثر را بر افزایش سرمایة اجتماعی بین زنان دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توسعة کشاورزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام چندکشتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام رعیتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فناوری‏های کشاورزی زنان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_62095_790cf3eb1d269999e2a6df2ff470f452.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
