<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Relationship between Human Capital Development and Crisis Management (Case Study: State Tax Administration)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطۀ بین توسعۀ سرمایۀ انسانی و مدیریت بحران (مورد مطالعه: سازمان امور مالیاتی کشور)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>127</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>148</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">71056</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2019.261769.1650</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>عزیزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری دانشکدة مدیریت، پژوهشگاه شاخص‌پژوه، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدمهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رشیدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مؤسسة مطالعات بین‌المللی انرژی، وزات نفت، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اکبر</FirstName>
					<LastName>نیلی پور طباطبایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکدة مهندسی صنایع ـ فناوری صنعتی مالک‌اشتر، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Organizations face different challenges in achieving goals, and they may end up in crisis. Organization management to overcome the crisis requires the specific tools of that organization, but in all organizations, human capital is a common factor that helps in facing the management crisis of the organization. The purpose of this research is to investigate the relationship between crisis management and human capital. The research method is correlational. Sample size using the Cochran formula were estimated 379. Our population was employees of the Tax Affairs Organization. Simple sampling method was used for sampling. The research tool was a researcher-made questionnaire: human capital development and crisis management. The results of Pearson correlation coefficient show a significant and positive relationship between the crisis management and human capital development of 0.686. There is also a positive and significant relationship between the dimensions of human capital development and crisis management. The hypotheses test using the PLS method indicated that human capital development has an impact on crisis management, and human capital explains 67.6% of crisis management changes.  </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سازمان‌ها در رسیدن به اهداف با چالش‌های متفاوت مواجه می‌شوند و در پی آن ممکن است دچار بحران شوند. مدیریت سازمان برای غلبه بر بحران نیازمند ابزار خاص آن سازمان است. لیکن، در همة سازمان‌ها سرمایة انسانی عاملی مشترک است که سازمان را در مواجهه با بحران مدیریت یاری می‌کند. هدف این تحقیق بررسی رابطة بین مدیریت بحران و توسعة سرمایة انسانی است. روش پژوهش از نوع همبستگی است. حجم نمونه، با استفاده از فرمول کوکران، 379 نفر از کارکنان سازمان امور مالیاتی کشور برآورد شد. برای نمونه‌برداری از روش تصادفی ساده استفاده شد. ابزار پژوهش دو پرسش‌نامة محقق‌ساختة توسعة سرمایة انسانی و مدیریت بحران بود. نتایج بررسی ضریبِ همبستگیِ پیرسون رابطة معنادار و مثبت به میزان 668&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 بین مدیریت بحران و توسعة سرمایة انسانی را نشان داد. همچنین، میان مؤلفه‌های توسعة سرمایة انسانی و مدیریت بحران رابطة مثبت و معنادار وجود دارد. آزمون فرضیات با روش PLS نشان داد توسعة سرمایة انسانی بر مدیریت بحران تأثیر دارد و توسعة سرمایة انسانی 6&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;67 درصد از تغییرات مدیریت بحران را تبیین می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بحران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت بحران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نیروی انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_71056_235812e51d189374204abfaaf7a0b85a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
