<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Role of Spiritual Capital on Organizational Resilience: Emphasizing the Mediation of Ethical Climate</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی نقش سرمایۀ معنوی بر تاب آوری سازمانی، با تأکید بر میانجی‌گری جو اخلاقی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>22</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">71050</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2019.269691.1732</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباسعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رستگار</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه سمنان، سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>درویش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دولتی و جهانگردی، سازمان مرکزی دانشگاه پیام نور استان تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مینا</FirstName>
					<LastName>خلیلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت رفتار سازمانی، دانشگاه سمنان، سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0876-741X</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوده فراهانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد قزوین، قزوین، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today, organizations are facing a lot of challenges, and in this regard, the resilience is the organization&#039;s ability to deal with change through a renewed business operation to prevent the dissolution of the organization. For this purpose, the present study attempted to investigate the role of gender variables, ethical climate, and spiritual capital in organizational resilience. This research is applied in terms of purpose, and the method is descriptive-survey and correlation. The statistical population of the study consisted of employees of Tehran Fire Department, and the sample includes 102 employees. The data collection tool is a standard questionnaire consisting of 66 questions. Also, to analyze the research data, structural equation modeling based on Smart-PLS software was used. Research findings indicate that spiritual capital has a positive and significant effect on organizational resilience, and this effect is moderated through the gender variable. In addition, spiritual capital has a direct and meaningful effect on the ethical climate, and as the ethical climate of the organization increases, organizational resilience will increase. In this way, the ethical climate can play an intermediary role in improving organizational viability through spiritual capital.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه سازمان‏ها با چالش‏های زیادی روبه‌رو هستند و توانایی تاب‌آوری سازمان برای مقابله با تغییر، از طریق تجدید پیوستة عملیات کسب‌وکار، از انحلال سازمان جلوگیری می‌کند. در پژوهش حاضر تلاش شد نقش متغیرهای جنسیت، جو‌ّ اخلاقی، و سرمایة معنوی در تا‏ب‏آوری سازمانی مطالعه شود. این پژوهش به لحاظ هدف کاربردی و به لحاظ روش توصیفی‌ـ پیمایشی از نوع همبستگی است. جامعة آماری پژوهش شامل کارکنان معاونت‏های سازمان آتش‌نشانی و خدمات ایمنی تهران و نمونة آماری شامل 102 نفر از کارکنان بود. ابزار گردآوری اطلاعات پرسش‌نامة استاندارد، حاوی 66 سؤال، بود. همچنین، برای تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‏های تحقیق از مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری بر اساس نرم‏افزار ‏Smart‏-PLS استفاده شد. یافته‏های تحقیق حاکی از آن است که سرمایة معنوی بر تاب‏آوری سازمانی تأثیر مثبت و معنادار دارد و این تأثیر از طریق متغیر جنسیت تعدیل می‏شود. افزون بر این، سرمایة معنوی بر جو‌ّ اخلاقی تأثیر مستقیم و معنا‏دار دارد و با بهبود جو‌ّ اخلاقی حاکم بر سازمان تا‏ب‏آوری سازمانی افزایش می‏یابد. از این طریق می‏توان دریافت جو‌ّ اخلاقی کاری در بهبود تاب‏آوری سازمانی از طریق سرمایة معنوی نقشی میانجی دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تاب‏آوری سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جو‌ّ اخلاقی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة معنوی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_71050_a0d9e5a19d2b53a490e0964aaf7b6319.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
