<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Sustainable Corporate Development Model Designing: Explaining the Role of Corporate Social Responsibility, Corporate Governance, and Creating Shared Value</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل توسعۀ پایدار شرکتی: تبیین نقش مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکتی، حاکمیت شرکتی، و خلق ارزش مشترک</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>305</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>325</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">72254</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2019.279369.1828</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>شراعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی‌ارشد، دانشکدة مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیرمحمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>کلابی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدحمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>خدادادحسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، دانشکدة مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In recent years, special attention has been paid to corporate sustainability, both in the business model and in the case of companies that have been eliminated from the competition, their lack of attention to such areas as corporate social responsibility, the creation of shared values with the stakeholders, and appropriate governance corporation. The present study intends to design an integrated, sustainable corporate developmental model based on the corporate social responsibility, the corporate governance, and the creation of shared value in general. This study is a descriptive-correlational research project and is a descriptive-correlational one in terms of purpose. The statistical population consists of 13 companies that have received the national award. The data was collected from available sample cases through questionnaires and was analyzed by AMOS software. The results indicate that corporate social responsibility with a strength rate of 69%, and the creation of shared value with a 63% intensity rate can affect the company&#039;s development sustainability. On the other hand, corporate governance improves the corporate social responsibility and generates shared value for stakeholders. It has also an indirect impact on the sustainability of companies with a strength rate of 27%.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در سال‌های اخیر به توسعة پایداری شرکت‌ها توجه ویژه‌ای شده است؛ هم در زمینة مدل‌های کسب‌وکار هم در زمینة شرکت‌هایی که بی‌توجهی آن‌ها به موضوعاتی چون مسئولیت‌پذیری شرکتی، خلق ارزش مشترک با ذی‌نفعان، و حاکمیت شرکتی مناسب از گردونة رقابت حذف شده‌اند. بنابراین، پژوهش حاضر با هدف طراحی مدل توسعة پایدار شرکتی به صورت یکپارچه و منسجم، با توجه به ابعاد مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکتی و حاکمیت شرکتی و خلق ارزش مشترک، انجام گرفت. نوع پژوهش توصیفی ـ همبستگی و از نظر هدف کاربردی است. جامعة آماری پژوهش 13 شرکت بودند که همگی موفق به دریافت جایزة ملی شده‌اند. پس از جمع‌آوری داده‌ها از بین 281 نمونة در دسترس، از طریق نرم‌افزار Amos به مدل‌سازی و تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌ها پرداخته شد. نتایج حاکی از آن بود که مسئولیت‌پذیری اجتماعی شرکتی با شدت 69 درصد و خلق ارزش مشترک با شدت 63 درصد بر توسعة پایداری شرکت‌ها تأثیرگذار است و حاکمیت شرکتی نیز باعث بهبود رابطة مسئولیت‌پذیری شرکتی و خلق ارزش مشترک برای ذی‌نفعان می‌شود. همچنین، با شدت 27 درصد به صورت غیرمستقیم بر توسعة پایداری شرکت‌ها تأثیرگذار است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توسعة پایداری شرکت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حاکمیت شرکتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خلق ارزش مشترک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_72254_1a61eb9f72aadd0f308f2cfd0bded456.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
