<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Estimation of the Relative Contribution of the Social Capital from Spiritual Leadership</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>برآورد سهم نسبی میزان سرمایۀ اجتماعی از رهبری معنوی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>167</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>185</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">67388</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.130990.1064</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>صابری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>قدرت‌‌الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>باقری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of this study was to estimate the relative contribution of the social capital from spiritual leadership. The research method was descriptive-correlational and the statistical population of this study was all football players in the Fars Football Premier League, Vision Asia that in this study was used a census sampling method or a total number (N=165). The research tools was a questionnaire that In this research was used sport management experts view point for questionnaires validity and its reliability was confirmed by the Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient. Cronbach&#039;s alpha was 0.89. Also Cronbach&#039;s alpha for spiritual leadership obtained 0.89 and for social capital 0.90. Data analyzed in two levels descriptive statistics (average, correlation coefficient, variance) and inferential statistics (Regression Pearson correlation coefficient). The results showed that there is a significant relationship between spiritual leadership and social capital and its dimensions. In todays&#039; turbulent environments of sport teams through a series of relatively small and highly focused interventions that coaches want instant feedback on their teams performance results, the nature of social capital development could be helpful.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف پژوهش حاضر برآورد سهم نسبی سرمایة اجتماعی از رهبری معنوی بود. روش پژوهش توصیفی- همبستگی بوده و جامعة آماری، همۀ فوتبالیست‌های حاضر در لیگ برتر فوتبال استان فارس، ویژن آسیا بودند. در پژوهش حاضر روش سرشماری به‌کار گرفته شده است (165N=). ابزار پژوهش پرسشنامه بود که روایی آن با به‌کارگیری نظر متخصصان مدیریت ورزشی، و پایایی آن با محاسبۀ ضریب آلفای کرونباخ بررسی و تأیید شد. آلفای پرسشنامه برابر با 89&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 به‌دست آمد. همچنین،  آلفای کرونباخ برای رهبری معنوی 89&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0، و سرمایة اجتماعی 90&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 به دست آمد. تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌ها در دو روش ‌آمار توصیفی (میانگین، انحراف معیار، واریانس) و آمار استنباطی (ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و رگرسیون) انجام گرفت. نتایج نشان داد بین رهبری معنوی با سرمایة اجتماعی و ابعاد آن رابطة معناداری وجود دارد (547&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0r=). در محیط پرتلاطم تیم‌های ورزشی امروزی، از طریق یک­سری مداخلات به‌نسبت جزئی و بسیار متمرکز که مربیان خواستار بازخورد سریع نتایج عملکرد تیم خود هستند، ماهیت توسعة سرمایة اجتماعی می‌تواند کارگشا باشد و این نیز از طریق رهبری معنوی به‌خوبی امکان‌پذیر است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری معنوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لیگ آسیا ویژن</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_67388_b5320ac9a4fcac44cd408a01b8c150f7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Explanation of the Social Capital Elements based on Islamic Narrations Pertaining to the Mutual Relations</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تبیین مؤلفه‌های سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر مبنای روایات ناظر به روابط متقابل در کتاب مفاتیح‌الحیات</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>187</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>212</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">67386</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.250428.1531</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه معارف، دانشگاه بین‌‌المللی امام خمینی(ره)، قزوین، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>موسوی مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Social capital as a major concept has been focused by social scientists. It can be studied also in the field of religious teachings. Islamic narrations pertaining to mutual relations among people provide a ground for studying social capital elements, which have been dealt with in this article. The aforementioned narrations, having a qualitative approach and using content analysis method, have been categorized in order to explain relational, cognitive, and structural elements. Relational elements provide the ground for mental link, i.e., inclination toward social cooperation. The continuation of its production line depends on the actualization of the element of confidence. It can promote individual link from mental, abstract level to concrete level, which has been discussed in cognitive elements as a trust making principle. The concrete level of relations manifests itself in “brotherhood” organization, which has been considered as the ground for the production of social capital. Accordingly, the conceptual structure of social capital is formed the exercise of which can strengthen social system and promote its growth.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سرمایة اجتماعی یکی از اصلی­ترین مفاهیمی است که مورد توجه دانشمندان علوم اجتماعی قرار گرفته است. این مفهوم در حوزة معارف دینی قابل بررسی است. در این مقاله روایات مربوط به ارتباط متقابل بین افراد از جمله بسترهای بررسی مؤلفه­های سرمایة اجتماعی بررسی شده است. روایات یادشده با رویکرد کیفی و با به‌کارگیری روش تحلیل محتوا در راستای تبیین مؤلفه­های ارتباطی، شناختی و ساختاری بررسی شد. مؤلفه­های ارتباطی زمینه را برای پیوند ذهنی در معنای تمایل به مشارکت اجتماعی فراهم می­کند که نقطة شروع فرایند تولید سرمایة اجتماعی است. تداوم خط تولید آن منوط به تحقق عنصر اعتماد است. این عنصر می­تواند پیوند افراد را از سطح ذهنی به عینی ارتقا دهد که در ذیل مؤلفه­های شناختی به عنوان اصول اعتمادزا از آن بحث شده است. جایگاه بروز سطح عینی ارتباطات، سازمان «اخوت» است که بستر تولید سرمایة اجتماعی تلقی شده است. بر این اساس، ساختار مفهومی سرمایة اجتماعی شکل می­گیرد که کاربست آن می­تواند نظام اجتماعی را تقویت بخشیده و بر بالندگی آن بیفزاید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتماد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روایت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مفاتیح‌الحیات</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_67386_4163312bc29e2fbc8b871dea9ff1905b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Factors of Preservation and Development of Social Capital of the Family for the Purpose of Prevention of Children and Juvenile Delinquency</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>عوامل حفظ و توسعۀ سرمایۀ اجتماعی خانواده در پیشگیری ازبزهکاری اطفال و نوجوانان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>213</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>231</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">67387</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.254518.1572</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید محمود</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرخلیلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکدة حقوق، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>عسگری مروت</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی‌ارشد، حقوق جزا و جرم‌شناسی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسلم</FirstName>
					<LastName>واحدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی‌ارشد، حقوق جزا و جرم‌شناسی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The family as a source of social capital with features which govern it plays a fundamental role in the socialization and education of children. The main purpose of this article is to Study of economic factors, parent supervision, consolidation of the family, quality of life environment and the ability of parents to train as factors of maintaining and developing social capital of the family In order to prevent social deviance and committing crimes by children and juveniles. Moreover, by studying of criminology theories, we discuss this subject how far the family is effective in children and juvenile offenders. In other words, if the social capital of the family is weakened, under the theory of “differential association”, children and juveniles will move away from the family environment and take refuge in offender groups. This makes it possible to provide an opportunity for committing crime and consequently by entrancing to criminal environment they learn how to commit a crime.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;خانواده به‌عنوان یک منبع سرمایة اجتماعی با قابلیت‌هایی که در آن حاکم است، در اجتماعی‌سازی و تربیت فرزندان نقش اساسی و بنیادی ایفا می­کند. هدف اصلی مقالة حاضر بررسی عوامل اقتصادی، نظارت والدین، تثبیت و تحکیم خانواده، کیفیت محیط زندگی و توانایی تربیتی والدین به‌عنوان عوامل حفظ و توسعة سرمایة اجتماعی خانواده به‌منظور پیشگیری از انحرافات اجتماعی و ارتکاب جرایم اطفال و نوجوانان است. بنابراین، با بررسی نظریه­های جرم­شناسی به این موضوع پرداخته شده است که خانواده تا چه حدی در پیشگیری از جرایم اطفال و نوجوانان مؤثر است. به عبارت دیگر، اگر سرمایة اجتماعی خانواده تضعیف شود، طبق نظریة جرم‌شناختی «معاشرت‌های ترجیحی» اطفال و نوجوانان از محیط خانواده فاصله گرفته و به گروه‌های بزهکارانه پناه می‌برند و این امر سبب می‌شود بسترهای ارتکاب جرم برای این دسته از اشخاص فراهم شود و در نتیجه طبق نظریة «یادگیری اجتماعی» افراد یادشده با قرارگرفتن در محیط بزهکارانه، نحوة ارتکاب جرم را فراگیرند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اطفال و نوجوانان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بزهکاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیشگیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خانواده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_67387_7913fa91942a7995aea98f4c2b873789.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Social Capital Indicators Affecting Resident&#039;s Satisfaction in Informal Settlements (Case: Farahzad-Tehran, North Farahzad)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شاخص‌های سرمایۀ اجتماعی مؤثر بر رضایتمندی ساکنان سکونتگاه‌های غیررسمی (مطالعۀ موردی: محلۀ فرحزاد شمالی، تهران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>233</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>261</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">67384</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.255954.1585</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>صبا</FirstName>
					<LastName>خراسانی مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدة معماری و شهرسازی، دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرهنگ</FirstName>
					<LastName>مظفر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة معماری و شهرسازی، دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید باقر</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة معماری و شهرسازی، دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Given the importance of sustainable urban development, the problem of informal settlements is entering a new phase of research and social capital, as an important aspect of the quality of life, is being widely explored. The present study seeks to compile social capital factors affecting the quality of life. It seems that, improving the social capital indicators could be a way to achieve the sustainable development goals. This article investigates the relationship between the life quality and social capital indicators. The methodology is descriptive-analytical and the indicators are determined by means of logical argumentation. According to the findings, outstanding indicators of the social capital turn out to be trust, norm-orientation, as well as network connections in direct evaluation. A case study in a poor neighborhood of Farahzad, Tehran is used to illustrate the arguments. For this purpose, we develop a Questionnaire to investigate which factor has the most impact on life quality? We then, carry out a survey of households living nearby and explore how they are affected by quality of life factors. According to the results, the social factor has the most relation with resident’s satisfaction and it could be consider as a main factor in redevelopment programs.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با مطرح‌شدن توسعة پایدار شهری، لزوم دستیابی به کیفیت زندگی مناسب و تأمین رضایتمندی ساکنان، پدیدة اسکان غیررسمی با دیدی جامع­تر توسط محققان مطالعه می‌شود. سرمایة اجتماعی به عنوان یکی از معیارهای اصلی توسعة پایدار، بر کیفیت زندگی و رضایتمندی از کیفیت زندگی تأثیر شایان توجهی دارد. هدف پژوهش حاضر تعیین ابعاد مختلف سرمایة اجتماعی مؤثر بر رضایتمندی ساکنان سکونتگاه­های غیررسمی و تبیین ارتباط این دو مفهوم در چارچوب اهداف توسعة پایدار است. مطالعة حاضر در سطح سکونتگاه غیررسمی محلة فرحزاد تهران با روش توصیفی- همبستگی انجام گرفته است. ابزار جمع‌آوری داده­ها پرسشنامه است. حجم نمونه معادل 110 نفر بوده و تحلیل داده­ها با نرم‌افزار SPSS انجام گرفته است. طبق نتایج، رضایتمندی از کیفیت زندگی در حد متوسط 5&gt;72&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;2&gt;1، با میانة نظری 3 ارزیابی شد. همچنین، در سطح اطمینان 95 درصد ابعاد اعتماد غیررسمی، اعتماد تعمیم­یافته، اعتماد رسمی، احساس امنیت، حمایت اجتماعی، همیاری، وساطت اجتماعی، مشارکت اجتماعی، همکاری و انسجام اجتماعی، بر رضایتمندی تأثیر مثبت و معنادار دارند. براساس نتایج رگرسیون چندگانه، متغیر وابسته به‌طور مستقیم از متغیرهای اعتماد غیررسمی، حمایت اجتماعی، همیاری، مشارکت اجتماعی و اعتماد رسمی، تأثیر می­پذیرد و این متغیرها حدود 52 درصد تغییرات متغیر وابسته را تبیین می­کنند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اسکان غیررسمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رضایتمندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کیفیت زندگی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_67384_3d1718a9df7b1471b4dcc7ae67463e31.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Typology of Work Groups in the Organization: The Combination of Social Capital and Group Effectiveness</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نوع‌شناسی گروه‌های کاری در سازمان: ترکیب سرمایۀ اجتماعی و اثربخشی گروهی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>263</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>290</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">67385</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.241509.1452</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحیمیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة روان‌شناسی و علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسن‌زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدة روان‌شناسی و علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Types of work groups have been investigated according to various features and variables, but today it has been noted that features such as social capital of the groups have been neglected, which can form different combinations of groups. Therefore, the present study aimed to provide a typology of groups based on their two characteristics of social capital and effectiveness. It also tried to describe, through follow-up studies, the best conditions that led to these two characteristics’ influence on the groups. To examine the groups, a quantitative-qualitative (mixed) research method was applied. The sample consisted of 30 groups and the data were collected by questionnaires (208 questionnaires) and interviews (12 in-depth interviews). The results of the quantitative phase showed that the groups were classified into four clusters based on their social capital and effectiveness. In the qualitative phase, after deepening the findings of the quantitative phase, the first cluster was named as self-managing teams, the second cluster was called disrupted groups, the third cluster was named as the evolving groups and the fourth cluster called mechanical groups. The findings of the qualitative phase also revealed that the effectiveness of social capital on the groups was dependent on the leadership style.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">انواع گروه‌های کاری با توجه به ویژگی‌ها و متغیرهای مختلف تاکنون بررسی شده‌اند، اما امروزه مشخص شده است در این بین، ویژگی‌هایی مانند سرمایة اجتماعی گروه‌ها مورد غفلت واقع شده است که می‌تواند ترکیب متفاوتی از گروه‌ها را شکل دهد. از این رو، این مطالعه به دنبال ارائة یک نوع‌شناسی از گروه‌ها بر مبنای دو ویژگی سرمایة اجتماعی و اثربخشی آن‌ها است. همچنین، سعی کرده است با مطالعات تعقیبی، بهترین شرایط برای تأثیرگذاری این دو ویژگی بر گروه‌ها را تشریح کند. مطالعة حاضر با به‌کارگیری طرح ترکیبی (کمی-کیفی) گروه‌ها را بررسی کرده است. نمونة مورد بررسی متشکل از 30 گروه بود و داده‌ها با ابزار پرسشنامه (بین همة اعضای گروه‌ها/ 208 پرسشنامه) و مصاحبه (12 مصاحبة عمیق) جمع‌آوری شد. نتایج فاز کمی نشان داد گروه‌ها بر مبنای سرمایة اجتماعی و اثربخشی به چهار خوشه گروه‌بندی می‌شوند. در فاز کیفی پس از تعمیق‌بخشیدن یافته‌های فاز کمی، خوشة اول با عنوان تیم‌های خودگردان، خوشة دوم با عنوان گروه‌های از هم پاشیده، خوشة سوم با عنوان گروه‌های در حال تحول و خوشة چهارم با عنوان گروه‌های مکانیکی نام‌گذاری شدند. همچنین، نتایج فاز کیفی آشکار کرد که تأثیرگذاری سرمایة اجتماعی بر اثربخشی گروه‌ها تحت تأثیر سبک رهبری قرار دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اثربخشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گروه‌های کاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوع‌‌شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_67385_27a6eca1de93782bd9a2d1cea026b857.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Organizational Justice on Social Capital with Studying the Moderating Role of Meritocracy in Organization</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر عدالت سازمانی بر ارتقای سرمایۀ اجتماعی با میانجی‌گری شایسته‌سالاری در سازمان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>291</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>314</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">67429</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.246381.1498</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خیراندیش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه علوم و فنون هوایی شهید ستاری، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری‌نیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The importance of social capital is to the extent that it is considered as the facilitator of all social activities. Hence, in many researches, it has been studied the factors causing it. Then, the present paper will investigate the effect of organizational justice on social capital with the mediating role of meritocracy in organization. This paper, from objective point of view and type of use is applied and descriptive, respectively. The Statistical Population of this paper includes 500 people working in Exploration Management at National Iranian Oil Company. The sample of 218 clerks based upon Morgan Sampling Table and Stratified Random Sampling method were selected. In this paper, we have used two standard questionnaires namely Social Capital Questionnaire, Organizational justice questionnaire and meritocracy researcher made Questionnaire. The Questionnaires have been validated by the experts and elites of this field. Furthermore, Cronbach&#039;s alpha was employed to confirm the reliability of the study instruments. The results obtained by Structural Equation Modeling have revealed that organizational justice affects both social capital and meritocracy. Also, meritocracy has positive effects on social capital. Additionally, organizational justice directly (.39) and indirectly has a moderating role of job meritocracy (.50) impacts social capital.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اهمیت سرمایة اجتماعی به‌ اندازه‌ای است که از آن به‌عنوان عامل تسهیل‌کنندة همة فعالیت‌های اجتماعی یاد می‌شود. از این رو، در پژوهش‌های زیادی به شناخت عوامل ایجادکنندة آن پرداخته شده است. بر این اساس، پژوهش حاضر به بررسی تأثیر عدالت سازمانی بر ارتقای سرمایة اجتماعی با نقش میانجی شایسته‌سالاری در سازمان می‌پردازد. تحقیق حاضر از نظر هدف، کاربردی و از نظر نحوة اجرا، تحقیقی توصیفی- همبستگی است. جامعه‏ی آماری تحقیق شامل 500 نفر از کارکنان مدیریت اکتشاف شرکت ملی نفت ایران است که براساس جدول مورگان و با روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌ای، 218 نفر به‌عنوان نمونه انتخاب شدند. ابزار پژوهش سه پرسشنامة استاندارد سرمایة اجتماعی ناپاهیت و گوشال (1998)، عدالت سازمانی مورمن و نیهوف (1993) و پرسشنامة محقق‌ساختة شایسته‌سالاری بود. روایی محتوای پرسشنامه‌ها براساس نظرات تخصصی استادان و خبرگان و پایایی آن‌ها نیز با محاسبة ضریب آلفای کرونباخ تأیید شد. نتایج تحلیل داده‌ها با روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری نشان داد عدالت سازمانی از طریق سرمایة اجتماعی بر شایسته‌سالاری تأثیر می‌گذارد. همچنین، تأثیر مستقیم عدالت سازمانی بر ارتقای سرمایة اجتماعی برابر با 39&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 و تأثیر غیرمستقیم آن به‌واسطة متغیر میانجی شایسته‌سالاری برابر با 5&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شایسته‌سالاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عدالت سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_67429_2943bd3d6987f3ffa193d235bcc3c5eb.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Drawing the Pattern of Social Capital Promotion in Iranian Public Organizations: Qualitative Research based on Grounded Theory</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ترسیم الگوی ارتقای سرمایۀ اجتماعی در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران: پژوهشی کیفی مبتنی بر نظریۀ داده‌بنیاد</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>315</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>336</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">67499</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.247628.1505</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منصور</FirstName>
					<LastName>خیرگو</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه افسری امام علی (ع)، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>سهیلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدة مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today, one of the important issues facing public organizations is social capital and its promotion in organizations. Accordingly, the purpose of this qualitative research is to design a pattern through which social capital of Iranian Public organizations could be promoted. In accordance with the purpose of the research, the qualitative research approach and the method of grounded theory were used; the statistical population of the research is Iran&#039;s public managers and executives who were interviewed with 27 public managers of Tehran province with theoretical saturation logic and snowball method. The data collection tool was interviewed. Thus, through interviewing and analyzing the documents, and by studying the theoretical literature, existing theories on social capital; dimensions, components and indicators were collected, Then, by using the grounded theory strategy, Social Capital Promotion Pattern includes internal factors such as individual factors, structural factors, managerial factors, safety and trust factors, educational factors, cohesion factors, and external factors such as institutional and public factors, Informational factors, technological factors, cultural and ideological factors, social and family factors, and collaborative factors were identified.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه یکی از موضوعات مهمی که سازمان‌های دولتی با آن مواجهند، سرمایة اجتماعی و ارتقای آن در سازمان‌هاست. بر همین اساس، هدف این پژوهش کیفی طراحی الگویی است که بتوان از طریق آن سرمایة اجتماعی سازمان‌های دولتی ایران را ارتقا بخشید. متناسب با هدف پژوهش، رویکرد پژوهش کیفی و روش تحلیل نظریة داده‌بنیاد به‌کار گرفته شد، جامعة آماری پژوهش مدیران و مجریان بخش دولتی ایران است که با 27 تن از مدیران دولتی استان تهران با منطق اشباع نظری و روش گلوله‌برفی مصاحبه شد. ابزار گردآوری داده‌ها مصاحبه بود. بدین صورت که از طریق مصاحبه و تحلیل اسناد، و با مطالعة متون نظری تحقیق و نظریه‌های موجود در زمینة سرمایة اجتماعی؛  ابعاد، مؤلفه‌ها و شاخص‌های آن جمع‌آوری شد، سپس، با به‌کارگیری روش تحلیل داده‌بنیاد الگوی ارتقای سرمایة اجتماعی شامل عوامل درون‌سازمانی نظیر عوامل فردی، عوامل ساختاری، عوامل مدیریتی، عوامل ایمنی و اعتماد، عوامل آموزشی، عوامل انسجام و همبستگی، و عوامل برون‌سازمانی نظیر عوامل نهادی و دولتی، عوامل اطلاعاتی، عوامل فناوری، عوامل فرهنگی و ایدئولوژیکی، عوامل اجتماعی و خانوادگی، عوامل مشارکتی شناسایی شدند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شبکه‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریه داده بنیاد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_67499_ee1cc0df6294e9a90d576447ecc8aeab.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
