<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effect of Ambidextrous Leadership on Work Attitudes; Moderating Role of Social Capital and Self-efficacy</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر رهبری دوسوتوان بر نگرش‌های کاری با درنظرگرفتن نقش تعدیل‌گر سرمایۀ اجتماعی و خودکارآمدی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>527</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>545</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">64993</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2018.242067.1454</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>یزدان شناس</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aims to examine the effect of ambidextrous leadership on work attitudes in which the moderating role of social capital and self-efficacy were considered as well. Research method is of descriptive- correctional surveys. Statistical population consisted 1520 employees of Telecommunications Infrastructure Company which a random sample of them was selected which consisted 307 employees. Data were collected via questionnaires that have been used in previous researches. Collected data were analyzed according to structural equation modeling using AMOS software. Results show that ambidextrous leadership has a positive effect on job satisfaction and emotional commitment as the main work attitudes. Meanwhile, findings show that social capital and self-efficacy play the moderating roles in this relationship. Therefore, ambidextrous leadership behaviors would have greater positive effect on employees` work attitudes if they enjoy social capital and self-efficacy.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف تحقیق حاضر بررسی تأثیر رهبری دوسوتوان بر نگرش‌های کاری است که در این رابطه، به نقش تعدیل‌کنندة سرمایة اجتماعی و خودکارآمدی نیز توجه شده است. روش تحقیق از نوع توصیفی - همبستگی است. کارکنان شرکت ارتباطات زیرساخت به تعداد 1520 نفر جامعة آماری تحقیق را تشکیل دادند که از بین آن‌ها نمونه­ای تصادفی به تعداد 307 نفر انتخاب شد. داده­های تحقیق با ابزار پرسشنامة استاندارد جمع‌آوری شد. داده­های جمع­آوری‌شده با روش مدل­سازی معادلات ساختاری و با نرم­افزار AMOS تحلیل شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد رهبری دوسوتوان تأثیر مثبتی بر رضایت شغلی و تعهد عاطفی به عنوان نگرش‌های مهم کاری دارد. ضمن اینکه یافته­ها نشان داد سرمایة اجتماعی و خودکارآمدی نقش تعدیل‌کنندة مثبت در رابطة یادشده ایفا می­کنند. بنابراین، رفتارهای رهبری دوسوتوان در صورت برخورداری کارکنان از سرمایة اجتماعی و احساس خودکارآمدی، تأثیر مثبت بیشتری بر نگرش­های کاری کارکنان خواهد داشت.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خودکارآمدی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری دوسوتوان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نگرش‌های کاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_64993_75c8cba1be4a2e60b09237971d51ca0f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
