<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Social Capital on Organizational Entrepreneurship with Studying the Moderating Role of job Motivation</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی با میانجی‌گری انگیزش شغلی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>43</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>68</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">58172</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2016.58172</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خیراندیش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة مدیریت، دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمزه</FirstName>
					<LastName>جمشیدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی،مشاور سازمان مدیریت صنعتی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Identifying the factors affecting entrepreneurship has always been one of the concerns of scientists. The emphasis has been changed from external and hard factors to internal and hard drives. Accordingly, the present paper will investigate the effect of social capital on organizational entrepreneurship with the moderating role of job motivation. This paper, from objective point of view and type of use is applied and correlation- descriptive. The Statistical Population of this paper includes 460 people working in different branches of Parsian Bank in 13 districts of Tehran in which the questionnaire instrument was used for collecting data. The sample of 210 clerks based upon Morgan Table and Stratified Random Sampling method were selected. The Questionnaires have been validated by the experts of this field. Furthermore, Cronbach&#039;s alpha was employed to confirm the reliability of the study instruments. The results obtained by Structural Equation Modeling have revealed that social capital affects both organizational entrepreneurship and job motivation. Also, job motivation has positive effects on organizational entrepreneurship. Additionally, social capital directly (.56) and indirectly (as a result of moderating role of job motivation) (.28) impacts entrepreneurship. Hence, Statistical Population managers can upgrade organizational entrepreneurship by providing trust-based relationships and employees&#039; motivation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">شناخت عوامل مؤثر بر کارآفرینی سازمانی همواره یکی از دغدغه‌های اندیشمندان بوده است. این تأکید از عوامل بیرونی و سخت به‌سوی محرک‌های درونی و نرم تغییر یافته است. بر این اساس، این تحقیق به بررسی تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی با نقش میانجی انگیزش شغلی می‌پردازد. تحقیق حاضر از نظر هدف، کاربردی و از نظر نحوة اجرا، توصیفی- همبستگی است که در آن ابزار پرسشنامه برای جمع‌آوری داده‌ها به‌کار گرفته شد. جامعة آماری تحقیق شامل 460 نفر از کارکنان شعب بانک پارسیان منطقة ١٣ شهر تهران است که بر اساس جدول مورگان و روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌ای، 210 نفر به‌عنوان نمونه انتخاب شدند. روایی محتوایی پرسشنامه‌ها بر اساس نظر خبرگان، و پایایی آن‌ها نیز با محاسبة ضریب آلفای کرونباخ تأیید شد. نتایج تحلیل داده‌ها با روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری نشان داد سرمایة اجتماعی بر انگیزش شغلی و کارآفرینی سازمانی و انگیزش شغلی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی تأثیر دارد. همچنین نتایج نشان داد تأثیر مستقیم سرمایة اجتماعی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی برابر با 56&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 و تأثیر غیرمستقیم آن به‌واسطۀ متغیر میانجی انگیزش برابر با 28&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 است. با توجه به این نتایج، مدیران جامعة آماری می‌توانند با تقویت روابط مبتنی بر اعتماد و انگیزش کارکنان کارآفرینی سازمانی را ارتقا دهند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انگیزش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_58172_8039adc34072e5c81e9dd0777efc25fe.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
