<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study of Islamic Social Capital Indicators in the Quran and Traditions Through the Relationship of Science and Religion</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی مؤلفه‌های سرمایۀ اجتماعی اسلامی در نص و احادیث در رهگذر رابطۀ علم و دین</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>317</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>346</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56527</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2015.56527</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یوسف</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>خنیفر</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Social capital as a resource that may be used by individuals, groups and communities to achieve the desired results is considered. Social capital is the concept that in many cases by social analysts used to describe a wide range of social processes and helps to understand why some people groups and social classes to the political, economic and social achieve more positive than others, are to be realized. In the formation and development of social capital, is required to study religion and religious culture more than any other. Divine religion as a system can be used as one of the most important factors in the formation of social capital in a world where, once again, the role of religion in this field confessed, is effective. This article by using texts and traditions and the philosophical relationship of religion and science tries scientifically, to explain elements of Islamic social capital.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سرمایة اجتماعی منبعی است که ممکن است افراد، گروه‌ها و جوامع برای نیل به نتایج مطلوب آن را به‌کار گیرند، و مفهومی است که در بسیاری موارد توسط تحلیلگران اجتماعی برای توصیف طیف وسیعی از فرایندهای اجتماعی به‌کار گرفته می‌شود و به درک اینکه چرا برخی افراد، گروه‌ها و طبقات اجتماعی به نتایج سیاسی، اقتصادی، یا اجتماعی مثبت‌تری نسبت به دیگران نایل می‌شوند، کمک می‌کند. در زمینة شکل‌گیری و تکوین سرمایة اجتماعی، بررسی دین و فرهنگ دینی بیش از هر مورد دیگری لازم است. دین به عنوان نظامی ماورایی می‌تواند به عنوان یکی از اساسی‌ترین عوامل در شکل‌گیری سرمایة اجتماعی در جهانی که بار دیگر به نقش‌آفرینی دین در این عرصه اقرار کرده است، تأثیرگذار است. این مقاله در توجه به رابطة فسلفی دین و علم، به دنبال تبیین علمی و رهیافت عقلی - نقلی مؤلفه‌های سرمایة اجتماعی اسلامی در نص و احادیث است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معرفت‌شناسی دینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریه‌پردازی دینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نص و احادیث</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_56527_507ddb8adf3aa3404bc80e867828e7f6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
