<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1394</YEAR>
<VOL>2</VOL>
<NO>3</NO>
<MOSALSAL>3</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>158</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی مؤلفه‌های سرمایۀ اجتماعی اسلامی در نص و احادیث در رهگذر رابطۀ علم و دین</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Study of Islamic Social Capital Indicators in the Quran and Traditions Through the Relationship of Science and Religion</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>سرمایة اجتماعی منبعی است که ممکن است افراد، گروه‌ها و جوامع برای نیل به نتایج مطلوب آن را به‌کار گیرند، و مفهومی است که در بسیاری موارد توسط تحلیلگران اجتماعی برای توصیف طیف وسیعی از فرایندهای اجتماعی به‌کار گرفته می‌شود و به درک اینکه چرا برخی افراد، گروه‌ها و طبقات اجتماعی به نتایج سیاسی، اقتصادی، یا اجتماعی مثبت‌تری نسبت به دیگران نایل می‌شوند، کمک می‌کند. در زمینة شکل‌گیری و تکوین سرمایة اجتماعی، بررسی دین و فرهنگ دینی بیش از هر مورد دیگری لازم است. دین به عنوان نظامی ماورایی می‌تواند به عنوان یکی از اساسی‌ترین عوامل در شکل‌گیری سرمایة اجتماعی در جهانی که بار دیگر به نقش‌آفرینی دین در این عرصه اقرار کرده است، تأثیرگذار است. این مقاله در توجه به رابطة فسلفی دین و علم، به دنبال تبیین علمی و رهیافت عقلی - نقلی مؤلفه‌های سرمایة اجتماعی اسلامی در نص و احادیث است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Social capital as a resource that may be used by individuals, groups and communities to achieve the desired results is considered. Social capital is the concept that in many cases by social analysts used to describe a wide range of social processes and helps to understand why some people groups and social classes to the political, economic and social achieve more positive than others, are to be realized. In the formation and development of social capital, is required to study religion and religious culture more than any other. Divine religion as a system can be used as one of the most important factors in the formation of social capital in a world where, once again, the role of religion in this field confessed, is effective. This article by using texts and traditions and the philosophical relationship of religion and science tries scientifically, to explain elements of Islamic social capital.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>317</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>346</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>یوسف</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صادقی</Family>
						<NameE>Yousef</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sadeghi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>youseff.sadeghii@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خنیفر</Family>
						<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khanifar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khanifar@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایة اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>معرفت‌شناسی دینی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظریه‌پردازی دینی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نص و احادیث</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>1.       افشانی، سیدعلیرضا (1381). بررسی چگگونگی تساهل سیاسی در شکلهای دانشجویی. پایان نامة کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.##ایوانز، تی دیوید (1380). «بررسی مجدد رابطة دین و جرم». روش شناسی علوم انسانی، شمارة 23، صفحات 178-142.##الوانی، سیدمهدی؛ پورعزت، علی‌اصغر (1382). «عدالت اجتماعی شالودة توسعة پایدار». کمال مدیریت، شماره‌های دوم و سوم، صفحات 28 – 17.##باستانی، سوسن؛ صالحی هیکویی، مریم (1386). «سرمایة اجتماعی شبکه و جنسیت؛ بررسی ویژگی‌های ساختی و تعاملی و کارکردهای شبکة اجتماعی زنان و مردان در تهران». نامة علوم اجتماعی، شمارة 30، صفحات 95-63.##باستانی، سوسن؛ کماتلی، افسانه؛ صالحی هیکویی، مریم (1387). «سرمایة اجتماعی شبکه و روابط متقابل شخصی». مجلة دانشکدة ادبیات و علوم انسانی، سال 16، شمارة 61، صفحات 80-41.##بهروان، حسین؛ بهروان، ندا (1392). «تحلیل محتوای مفهوم سرمایة اجتماعی در احادیث امام رضا (ع) ». فصل‌نامة تحقیقات فرهنگی ایران، دورة ششم، شمارة سوم، صفحات 149 – 115.##پاک‌سرشت، سلیمان (1393). «ملاحظات و راهبردهای ارتقای سرمایة اجتماعی». راهبرد فرهنگ،  دورة دوم، شمارة 25، صفحات 104-71.##حسن‌زاده ثمرین، تورج؛ سیدمحمد، مقیمی (1389). «اثر سرمایة اجتماعی بر تعالی سازمانی». فصل‌نامة مطالعات مدیریت راهبردی، سال اول، شمارة سوم، صفحات 143-123.##حکمت، ناهید (1392). «درآمدی بر رویکرد روش‌شناختی پیر بوردیو به مفهوم سرمایة فرهنگی». فصل‌نامة جامعه‌پژوهی فرهنگی، دورة چهارم، شمارة اول،صفحات 178-155.##رستگار خالد، امیر؛ کاوه، مهدی؛ محمدی، مهدی (1393).«سرمایة اجتماعی و بیگانگی از کار (مطالعة موردی معلمان آموزش‌وپرورش مقطع ابتدایی شهر تهران)».. دورة ششم، شمارة 19، صفحات 251-203.  ##زمردیان، غلامرضا؛ رستمی، علی (1389). «استقرار نظام مدیریت دانش مبتنی بر سرمایة اجتماعی (مطالعة موردی: واحدهای دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی منطقة 8)». حسابداریمدیریت، سال سوم، شمارة پنجم، صفحات 63-45.##سرلک، محمدعلی؛ اسلامی، طاهره (1390). «تسهیم دانش در دانشگاه صنعتی شریف: رویکرد سرمایة اجتماعی». فصل‌نامةمدیریتدولتی، سال سوم، شمارة هشتم، صفحات 18-1.##شجاعی زند، علی (1384). «مدلی برای سنجش دینداری». مجلة جامعه‌شناسی ایران، دورة ششم، شمارة 34، صفحات 66-34.##ضیایی، محمدصادق؛ منوریان، عباس؛ کاظمی کفرانی، ابراهیم (1390). «بررسی رابطة سرمایة اجتماعی و میزان آمادگی سازمانی برای استقرار مدیریت دانش (مطالعة شرکت فولادساز ایرانی(».فصل‌نامةمدیریتدولتی، سال سوم، شمارة هشتم، صفحات 198-179.##طباطبایی، سیدمحمدحسین (1386). تفسیر المیزان. ترجمة سیدمحمدباقر موسوی همدانی، قم، دفتر انتشارات جامعة مدرسین حوزة علمیة قم.##عبدللهی، محمد؛ موسوی، میرطاهر (1386). «سرمایة اجتماعی در ایران، وضعیت موجود و دورنمای آینده و امکان‌شناسی گذار». فصل‌نامة علمی پژوهشی رفاه اجتماعی، سال ششم، شمارة 25، صفحات 234-195.##عابدی، منیره؛ نوروزی، رضاعلی؛ بختیاری نصرآبادی، حسنعلی (1390). «تربیت اجتماعی از دیدگاه فردگرایان و نقد آن بر اساس دیدگاه علامه طباطبایی». پژوهش در مسائل تعلیم و تربیت اسلامی، سال 19، دورةجدید، صفحات 63– 39.##عباس‌زاده، محمد؛ نورآذر، مهرناز؛ محمدپور، نیر (1390). «بررسی جامعه‌شناختی مفهوم سرمایة اجتماعی در سورة بقره». مطالعات قدرت نرم، سال اول، شمارة چهارم، صفحات 24-7.##فاضلی، محمد؛ اشتیاقی، معصومه (1391). وضعیت سرمایة اجتماعی در ایران. تهران، مرکز مطالعات استراتژیک مجمع تشخیص مصلحت نظام.##فوکویاما، فرانسیس (1379). پایان نظم سرمایة اجتماعی و حفظ آن. ترجمة غلامعباس توسلی، چاپ اول، تهران، انتشارات جامعة ایرانیان.##فیلد، جان (1388). سرمایة اجتماعی. ترجمة غلامرضا غفاری و حسین رمضانی، تهران، انتشارات کویر.##کامران، فریدون؛ ارشادی، خدیجه (1387).«بررسی رابطة سرمایة اجتماعی شبکه و سلامت روان». فصل‌نامة پژوهش رفاه اجتماعی، سال دوم، شمارة سوم، صفحات 56-29.##گیدنز، آنتونی (1384). جامعه‌شناسی. ترجمة حسن صبوری، تهران، نشر نی.##محسنی تبریزی، علیرضا؛ آقامحسنی، مریم (1389).«بررسی نقش سرمایة اجتماعی در توسعة شهری، موردپژوهی: شهر محلات ». مدیریت شهری، دورة هشتم، شمارة 25، صفحات 162-147.##محمدپور زرندی، حسین؛ طباطبایی مزدآبادی، سیدمحسن؛ کریمی، سمانه (1392). مدیریتمنابعانسانیدرشهرداری‌ها، تهران، انتشارات کوهسار.##نوغانی، محسن؛ اضغرپور ماسوله، احمدرضا؛ صفا، شیما؛ کرمانی، مهدی (1387). «کیفیت زندگی شهروندان و رابطة آن با سرمایة اجتماعی در شهر مشهد». مجلة علوم اجتماعی دانشکدة ادبیات و علوم انسانی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، دورة پنجم، شمارة اول، صفحات140-111.##وولکاک، مایکل؛ نارایان، دیپا(1389). «سرمایة اجتماعی و تبعات آن برای نظریة توسعة پژوهش و سیاست». مجموعه مقالات سرمایة اجتماعی، اعتماد، دموکراسی و توسعه، گردآورنده  کیان تاجبخش، ترجمة افشین خاکباز و حسن پویان، تهران، نشر شیرازه.##ویلم، ژان پل (1377). جامعه‌شناسیادیان. ترجمة عبدالرحیم گواهی، تهران، مؤسسة فرهنگی انتشاراتی تبیان.##هرندی، عطاالله (1393). «تبیین نقش سرمایة اجتماعی و انتقال دانش در یادگیری سازمانی شرکت‌های دانش بنیان». فصل‌نامة مدیریت توسعة فناوری، سال اول، شمارة چهارم، صفحات 182-161.##Akçomak, S. (2011). “Social Capital of Social Capital Researchers“. Review of Economics and Institutions, 2(2), 1-27##Alguezaui, Salma; Filieri, Raffaele (2010). “Investigating the role of social capital ininnovation: sparse versus dense network”. Journal of Knowledge Management, 14(6), 891-909.##Anderiani, L. (2013). Social Capital: A Road Map of Theoretical Frameworks and EmpiricalLimitaions, Department of Management – Birkbeck College University of London.##Candland, Christophen (2000). Religion and Community in Southern Asia, Kluwer Academic Publishers, 33, 355-374.##Chen, Jiun-Shiu; Lovvorn, Al. S. (2011). “The speed of knowledge transfer withinmultinational enterprises: the role of social capital”. International Journal of Commerceand Management, 21(1), 46-62.##Illingworth, Patricia (2012). Ethics and social capital for global well-being, Springer, published online, 12 May 2012, DOI 10.1007/s12232-012-0160-2.##Jansen, Rob J. G.; Curseu, Petru L.; Vermeulen, Patrick A. M.; Geurts, Jac L. A.; Gibcus, Petra (2013). “Information processing and strategic decision-making in smalland medium-sized enterprises: The role of human and social capital in attaining decision effectiveness”. International Small Business Journal, 31(2), 192-216.##Jonker, Jan; Eskildsen, Jacob (2009). Management Models for the Future. Springer. Verlag Berlin Heidelberg##Marques, A. I.; Rosa, M. J.; Soares, P.; Santos, R.; Mota, J.; Carvalho, J. (2011). “Evaluation of physical activity programmes for elderly people - a descriptivestudy using the EFQM’criteria”. BMC Public Health, 11(123), 1-16.##Putnam, R. (2000). Bowlling ALONE: The collapse and Revival of American community. New York, Simon Schuster.##Trevorhides, M. (2006). “Implementation Organizational Excellence Models Self-assessment in the UK Higher Education Sector-lessons Learned from Other Sectors”. TQM magazine, 16(3), 194-201.##Turkina, Ekaterina; Thi, Mai; Thai, Thanh (2013). “Social capital, networks, trustand immigrant entrepreneurship: a cross-country analysis”. Journal of EnterprisingCommunities, 7(2), 108-124.##Wald, K. D. (2003). Religion and Politics in the United State. Landan, MD, Rowman &amp; Littlefield.##Wickramasinghe, Vathsala; Weliwitigoda, Purnima (2011). “Benefits gained from dimensions of social capital: a study of software developers in Sri Lanka”. InformationTechnology &amp; People, 24(4), 393-413.##Yeung, Anne Birgitta (2004). “An Intricate TriangleReligiosity, Volunteering, and Social Capital: The European Perspective, the Case of Finland“. Nonprofit and Voluntary Sector Quarterly, 33(3), 401-422.##     ##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعی در تمایل به تسهیم دانش (مورد مطالعه: کارکنان شرکت‌های صنایع دارویی استان گیلان)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Study of the Impact of Social Capital on Intention to Knowledge Sharing Evidence from: Pharmaceutical Industries Employee of Guilan Province</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در اقتصاد مبتنی بر دانش، سازمان‌ها دانش کارکنان را به عنوان منبعی در جهت خلق و افزایش ارزش سازمانی به‌کار می‌گیرند و موفقیتشان به توانایی‌شان در مدیریت این منبع کمیاب بستگی دارد. یکی از قابلیت‌های مهم سازمانی که می‌تواند به سازمان‌ها در خلق و تسهیم دانش کمک کند و برای آن‌ها در مقایسه با سازمان‌های دیگر مزیت سازمانی پایدار ایجاد کند، وجود سرمایة اجتماعی است. هدف این مقاله بررسی تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعی در بهبود تسهیم دانش در صنایع دارویی استان گیلان است. روش تحقیق، توصیفی از نوع همبستگی و جامعة آماری این تحقیق کارشناسان صنایع داروسازی استان گیلان می‌باشند که تعداد آن‌ها 103 نفر است و از کل جامعه بررسی شد. در این تحقیق دو پرسشنامة استاندارد سرمایة اجتماعی و تسهیم دانش به‌کار گرفته شده است. یافته‌های پژوهش که از طریق آزمون رگرسیون به دست آمد، نشان داد سرمایة اجتماعی در افزایش تسهیم دانش نقش دارد. از سه بعد درنظرگرفته‌شده برای سرمایة اجتماعی، بعد شناختی بیشترین نقش را در بهبود تسهیم دانش دارد و بعد از آن بعد رابطه‌ای در بهبود تسهیم دانش نقش دارد، اما بعد ساختاری نسبت به دو بعد دیگر نقش بسزایی در بهبود تسهیم دانش ندارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In an economy based on knowledge, organizations use their employees’ knowledge as a resource for creating and increasing organizational value and their success depends on their ability to manage their rare and volatile resources. One of the important organizational capabilities is social capital which can greatly help organizations to create and share knowledge as well as to create “permanent organizational advantage. “The purpose of this paper is to study the role of social capital in knowledge sharing in Medical Industries of Guilan province. This research is a correlational research and data has been collected based on survey methods. The population consists of experts and managers working in pharmaceutical companies of Guilan province. Data was collected from 103 experts. In this regard, were used two standard questionnaires of social capital and knowledge sharing .The findings, which were obtained through regression analysis shows that social capital impact on increasing knowledge sharing. However, among the three dimensions of social capital, cognitive social capital plays the most important role in improving knowledge sharing and then relational social capital have the significant role in improving knowledge sharing. But in the present study, in multiple regression analysis, the structural dimension of social capital did not play a significant role in knowledge sharing.         </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>347</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>365</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدصادق</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسن زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Sadegh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hassanzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه پیام نور،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sa_hassanzadeh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سارا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صادقی</Family>
						<NameE>Sara</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sadeghi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس‌‌ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس‌‌ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sadeghi.sara14@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بعد رابطه‌ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بعد ساختاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بعد شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تسهیم دانش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایة اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>الوانی، سیدمهدی؛ ناطق، تهمینه؛ فراحی، محمدمهدی (1386). «نقش سرمایة اجتماعی در توسعة مدیریت دانش سامانی». فصل‌نامة علوم مدیریت ایران، سال دوم، شمارة پنجم، صفحات 70- 35.##حسن‌زاده، محمد؛ علیپور ایرانق، سکینه؛ زندیان، فاطمه (1393). «بررسی رابطة بین سرمایة اجتماعی و تسهیم دانش در مراکز ملی اطلاعات». تعامل انسان و اطلاعات، دورة اول، شمارة اول، صفحات 43-27.##دموری، داریوش؛ و منصوری، حسین؛ طاهری دمنه، محسن (1388). «بررسی ارتباط مدیریت دانش با سرمایة اجتماعی در دانشگاه اسلامی (از دیدگاه اعضای هیئت علمی دانشگاه یزد)». مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی 41، سال سیزدهم، شمارة اول، صفحات 64-44.##دوستار، محمد؛ ابراهیم‌پور ازبری، مصطفی؛هاشمی، سیدحامد (1391). «تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعی بر توسعة مدیریت دانش در دانشگاه‌های وابسته به وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری استان گیلان». بهبود مدیریت، سال ششم، شمارة سوم، پیاپی 17، صفحات 31- 5.##سرلک، محمدعلی؛ اسلامی، طاهره (1390). «تسهیم دانش در دانشگاه صنعتی شریف: رویکرد سرمایة اجتماعی». نشریة مدیریت دولتی، دورة سوم، شمارة هشتم، صفحات 18- 1.##علامه، سیدمحسن؛ سلطانی، فرزانه؛ نریمانی، مهدی (1393). «بررسی نقش تعدیلگر متغیر سرمایة اجتماعی بر رابطة بین مدیریت استعداد و تسهیم دانش در سازمان». پژوهش‌های مدیریت در ایران، دورة 18، شمارة دوم، صفحات 148-127.##فقیهی، ابوالحسن؛ فیضی، طاهره (1384). «سرمایة اجتماعی در سازمان». پیک نور، سال سوم، شمارة سوم، صفحات 21-11.##قلیچ‌لی، بهروز؛ شقاقی، زهرا (1389). «بررسی تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعی بر تسهیم دانش میان اعضای شرکت پارس و شل». دومین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت سرمایة فکری، زنجان، دانشگاه تحصیلات تکمیلی علوم پایة زنجان.##قلیچ‌لی، بهروز؛ مشبکی، اصغر (1385). «نقش سرمایة اجتماعی در ایجاد سرمایة فکری سازمان (مطالعة دو شرکت خودروساز ایرانی)». فصل‌نامة دانش مدیریت، سال 19، شمارة 75، صفحات 147- 125.##10. معمارزاده، غلامرضا؛ عطایی، محمد؛ اکبری، احمد (1388). «بررسی نقش سرمایة اجتماعی بر بهبود عملکرد کارکنان». مجلة مدیریت توسعه و تحول، پیش‌شمارة سوم، صفحات 15-9.##مقیمی، سیدمحمد؛ رمضان، مجید (1390). پژوهش‌نامة مدیریت،جلد 11، تهران، انتشارات راه‌دان.##12. مهدیان‌راد، امیراحمد؛ فضلی، صفر (1390).«بررسی تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعی در توسعة مدیریت دانش (مطالعة موردی: سازمان امور مالیاتی کشور)». پژوهش‌نامة مالیات، شمارة دوازدهم، پیاپی 60، صفحات 321-291.##Aizpurua, Leonardo Lebra; Zegarra Saldana, Pablo E.; Zegarra Saldana, Alejandro (2011). “Learning for sharing: an empirical analysis of organizational learning and knowledge sharing“. International Entrepreneurship and Management Journal, 7(4), 509-518##Bolino, M. C.; Turnley, W. H.; Bloodgood, J. M. (2002). “Citizenship behavior and the creation of social capital in organizations“. Academy of management Review, 27(4), 505-522 .##Chang, Hsin Hsin; Chuang, Shuang-Shii (2011). “Social capital and individual motivations on knowledge sharing: Participant involvement as a moderator“. Information &amp; Management, 48, 9-18.##Chen, J.; Zhu, Z.; Xie Yuan, H. (2004). “Measuring intellectual capital a new model and empirical study”. Journal of intellectual capital, 5(1), 195-212.##Chow, Wing S.; Chan, Lai Sheung (2008). “Social network, Social trust and shared goals in organizational knowledge sharing“. Information &amp; Management, 45, 458-465.##Hooff, Bart Van den; Huysman, Marleen (2009). “Managing knowledge sharing: Emergent and engineering approaches”. Information &amp; Management, 46, 1-8.##Hsu, Meng-Hsiang; Teresa, L. Ju; Yen, Chia-Hui; Chang, Chun-Ming (2007). “Knowledge sharing behavior in virtual communities: The relationship between trust, self-efficacy, and outcome expectations“. Human-Computer studies, 65, 153-169.##Kau, Feng-Yang; Young, Mei-Lien (2008). “Predicting knowledge sharing practices through intention: A test of competing models“. Computers in Human Behavior, 24, 2697-2722.##Li, Yina; Ye, Fei; Sheu, Chwen (2014). “Social capital, information sharing and performance Evidence from China“. International Journal of Operations  &amp;Production Management, (11), 1440-1462.##Li, Z.; Luo, F. (2011). “Research on the relationship among social capital, organizational learning and knowledge transfer performance”. Journal of software, 6(9), 1763-1770.##Mat Isa, Rosmah; Abdullah, Nor Liza; Che Senik, Zizah (2010). “Social capital Dimensions for tacit knowledge sharing: Exploring The Indicators“. Journal pengurusan, 30, 75-91.##Michailova, Senjina; Minbaeva, Dana B. (2012). “Organizational values and knowledge sharing in multinational corporations: The Danisco case“. International Business Review, 21, 59-70.##Nahapiet, Janine; Ghoshal, Sumantra (1998). “Social capital, intellectual capital, and the organizational Advantage“. The Academy of Management Review, 23(2), 242-266.##Nizam, Akhbar, Anis Rosniza; Musa, Mohd Fauzee (2012). “Enhancing Human Interaction of knowledge sharing in Higher Learning Workplace Environment“. Procedia-social and Behavioral Sciences, 35, 137-145.##Sheng, Margaret; Hartono, Rendi (2015). “An exploratory study of knowledge creation and sharing in online community: a social capital perspective“. Total Quality Management, 26(1), 93–107.##Wang, Jing; Gwebu, Kholekile; Shanker, Murali; Trouth, Marvin D.; (2009). “An application of agent-based simulation to knowledge sharing”. Dicision Support Systems, 46(2), 532-541.##Widen-Wulff, Ginman Mariam (2004). “Explaining knowledge sharing in the dimensions of social capital“. Journal of information science, 30(5), 448-458.  Yang, Shu_Chen; Forn, Cheng_Kiang (2009). “Social capital, behavioural control, and tacit knowledge sharing—A multi-informant design”. International Journal of Information management, 29, 210_218.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعی بر کارآفرینی و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی (بررسی نقش تعدیل‌گری هوش هیجانی کارکنان)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Impact of Social Capital On Entrepreneurship and Organizational Citizenship Behavior (Examine the Moderator Role of Emotional Intelligence)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>سرمایة اجتماعی مفهومی است که در حوزه­های گوناگون مطرح شده­ است. اهمیت سرمایة اجتماعی این است که سبب اجتماع افراد می‌شود و انجام‌دادن موفقیت‌آمیز فعالیت­ها را ممکن می­کند. هوش هیجانی نیز نقشی اساسی در محیط کار دارد. با توجه به وابسته‌بودن سرمایة اجتماعی به روابط بین افراد و تأثیر هوش هیجانی بر روابط بین‌فردی، هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی تأثیر سرمایة اجتماعی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی با توجه به نقش تعدیلگر هوش هیجانی است. برای نیل به این هدف، فضای نمونه 184 نفری از کارمندان دانشگاه یزد است که با  فرمول کوکران و روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌ای انتخاب شد. ابزار گردآوری داده­ها پرسشنامه است که روایی آن با نظر استادان تأیید شد. پس از تکمیل نمونة اولیه، پایایی پرسشنامه با محاسبة آلفای کرونباخ تأیید شد. داده­های جمع­آوری‌شده با نرم­افزارهای  SPSSو SmartPLS2 تحلیل شد. نتایج نشان داد سرمایة اجتماعی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی و رفتار شهروندی اثر مثبت و معنادار دارد. همچنین، متغیر هوش هیجانی علاوه بر نقش تعدیل­گر، اثر مستقیم و معنادار بر کارآفرینی و رفتار شهروندی دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Social capital is a concept that has been proposed in various fields. The importance of social capital is that people and successful community provide activities. Emotional intelligence has a major role in the workplace. Due to, that social capital depends on the relationships between people and the Undeniable effects of emotional intelligence on the formation of interpersonal relationships, the aim of study is examines the effects of social capital on organizational entrepreneurship and organizational citizenship behavior with moderator role of emotional intelligence. To achieve this goal, the sample size is 184 members of Yazd University staff were selected by means of Cochran formula and random sampling method. The data collected with questionnaire that, its validity was confirmed with view point of professors and after completion of the prototype, reliability with Cronbach&#039;s alpha showed the reliability of the tool. The collected data analyzed with SPSS and Smart PLS2 software the results showed that social capital has significant and positive effect on entrepreneurship and organizational citizenship behavior .Also, Emotional Intelligence as addition of the role of moderator, has a direct and significant effect on Entrepreneurship and citizenship behavior.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>367</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>392</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نگارالسادات</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مصباحی جهرمی</Family>
						<NameE>Negar Alsadat</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mesbahi Jahromi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس‌ارشد، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس‌ارشد، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>negar.mesbahe@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مرضیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ادیب زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Marzieyh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Adibzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشنا‌س‌ارشد، دانشکدة اقتصاد، مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه یزد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشنا‌س‌ارشد، دانشکدة اقتصاد، مدیریت و حسابداری،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.adibzadeh1369@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سکینه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نخعی</Family>
						<NameE>Sakineh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nakhaei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشنا‌س‌ارشد، دانشکدة اقتصاد، مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه یزد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشنا‌س‌ارشد، دانشکدة اقتصاد، مدیریت و حسابداری،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sakineh.nakhei@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید محمود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسینی</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Mahmoud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hosseini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.hosseini33@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رفتار شهروندی سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایة اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارآفرینی سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هوش هیجانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>احمدی کافشانی، عبداله؛ ناظمی، علی (1393). «بررسی ارتباط هوش هیجانی با قصد کارآفرینانه، مورد مطالعه: دانشجویان کارشناسی تربیت بدنی دانشگاه تهران». نشریة مدیریت ورزشی، دورة ششم، شمارة سوم، صفحات 441-421.##چاوشی، فرزانه (1387). مدیریتوسرمایةاجتماعی،سرمایة اجتماعی درمقایسهباسایرسرمایه­ها. مجمع تشخیص مصلحت نظام، پژوهشکدة تحقیقات استراتژیک، گروه پژوهش­های فرهنگی و اجتماعی.##دهقانی، محمد؛ مصطفای،داوود؛ حیوی حقیقی، محمدحسین؛ استبصاری، فاطمه؛ رفعتی، شیده؛ خرمی، فرید (1394). «بررسی رابطة سرمایة اجتماعی و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی در بین کارکنان بیمارستان­های آموزشی درمانی دانشگاه علوم پزشکی هرمزگان». مجلة اطلاع‌رسانی پزشکی نوین، سال اول،شمارة اول، صفحات 32-24.##زارع، حمید (1383). «نقش رفتار شهروندی سازمانی در عملکرد سازمان».فرهنگمدیریت، سال دوم، شمارة اول، صفحات 169- 151.##عباس‌پور اسفدن، قنبر؛ چراغعلی، محمدحسن؛ رحمانی، محمد (1389). «شناخت و مطالعة رابطة هوش هیجانی و کارآفرینی مدیران صنایع لاستیک و پلاستیک شهر تهران». پژوهش‌نامة اقتصاد و کسب‌وکار، سال اول، شمارة دوم، صفحات 34-27.##عبدالهی، بیژن؛ فرحی ده‌سرخی، حاتم؛ حیات، علی‌اصغر؛ کهولت، نعیمه (1391). «بررسی رابطة هوش هیجانی با سرمایة اجتماعی سازمانی، مطالعة موردی: دانشگاه شیراز». تحقیقات مدیریت آموزشی، سال چهارم، شمارة دوم، پیاپی 14، صفحات 89-77.##فرازی، کمال؛ واعظی، مظفرالدین؛ جبلی سینکی، عبدالله (1391). «رابطة سرمایة اجتماعی با گرایش به رفتار شهروندی سازمانی در دفتر مرکزی یک شرکت بیمه در شهر تهران». پژوهش‌نامة بیمه (صنعت بیمة سابق)، سال 27، شمارة دوم، پیاپی اول و ششم، صفحات 171-1591.##فیضی، طاهره؛ عابدینی، سعید (1389). «بررسی رابطة هوش هیجانی و سرمایة اجتماعی (مطالعة موردی)» پژوهش‌نامة اقتصاد و کسب‌وکار، شمارة اول، صفحات 58- 43.##کمالیان، امین؛ رضاغ فاضل، امیر (1390). «بررسی رابطة هوش هیجانی و میزان کارآفرینی دانشجویان (مطالعة موردی: دانشگاه سیستان‌وبلوچستان)». فصل‌نامة توسعة کارآفرینی، سال سوم، شمارة یازدهم، صفحات 146-127.##مشبکی، اصغر؛ تباربائی، محمدعلی؛ شایگان‌فر، زهرا (1391). «بررسی رابطة مؤلفه‌های هوش هیجانی و کارآفرینی در بین دانشجویان». فصل‌نامة اندیشه‌های تازه در علوم تربیتی، سال هفتم، شمارة دوم، پیاپی 26، صفحات 17-7.##هادیزاده مقدم، اکرم؛ رامین‌مهر، حمید؛ حسینی، سجاد (1388). «هوش هیجانی با گرایش کارآفرینانه، مطالعة موردی :سازمان­های وابسته به شرکت نفت». توسعة کارآفرینی، شمارة چهارم، صفحات 162-139.##یداللهی فارسی، جهانگیر؛ عزیزی زیارت، امید؛ خواستار، حمزه (1388). «بررسی رابطة بین ساختار و کارآفرینی سازمانی (مطالعة موردی: بانک‌های خصوصی سطح شهر تهران)». توسعةکارآفرینی، سال دوم، شمارة پنجم، صفحات 80- 55.##Aktan, B.; Bulut, C. (2008). &quot;Financial performance impacts of corporate entrepreneurship in emerging markets: A case of Turkey&quot;. European Journal of Economics, Finance and Administrative Sciences, 12, 69-79.##Alegre, J.; Chiva, R. (2009). Entrepreneurial orientation, organizational learning capability and performance in the ceramic tiles industry. (No. 2009-08). Instituto Valenciano de Investigaciones Económicas, SA (Ivie).##Appelbaum, S.; Bartolomucci, N.; Beaumier, E.; Boulanger, J.; Corrigan, R.; Dore, I.; Girard, C.; Serroni, C. (2004). &quot;Organizational citizenship behavior: a case study of culture&quot;. leadership and trust management decision, 42(1), 13-40.##Ariani, D. W. (2012). &quot;The relationship between social capital, organizational citizenship behaviors, and individual performance: An empirical study from banking industry in Indonesia&quot;. Journal of Management Research, 4(2), 226-241.##Bolino, Mark C.; Turnley, William H.; Blood good, James M. (2002). ”Citizenship behavior and the creation of social capital in organizations&quot;. Academy of management review, 27(4), 505-522.##Brooks, K.; Muyia Nafukho, F. (2006). &quot;Human resource development, social capital, emotional intelligence: Any link to productivity?&quot;. Journal of European Industrial Training, 30(2), 117-128.##Brundin, E.; Patzelt, H.; Shepherd, D. A. (2008). &quot;Managers&#039; emotional displays and employees&#039; willingness to act entrepreneurially&quot;. Journal of Business Venturing, 23(2), 221-243.## Carlo, K. L. E. I. N. (2011). Social capital or social cohesion: what matters for subjective well-being (SWB)? (No. 2011-36). CEPS/INSTEAD.##Casson, D. P. Nisar, T. M. (2007). &quot;Entrepreneurship And Organizational desighn: investor specialization&quot;. Management decision, 45(5), 883-896.##Cheah, Yeh. Ying; Shirley, Ken. Tzu Ting. (2013). &quot;The effects of emotional Intelligence on counterproductive work behaviors and organizational citizenship behaviors&quot;. International Journal of Accounting and Management (IJABM), 1(1), 185-196.##Chehrazi, S.; Hoseinishakib, M.; Askariazad, M. H. (2014). &quot;A study on the relationship between emotional intelligence, organizational commitment and organizational citizenship behavior&quot;. Management science letters, 4, 1103-1106.##Chen, S. X.; Carey, T. P. (2009). &quot;Assessing citizenship behavior in education contexts the role of personality, motivation, and culture&quot;. Journal of Psycho educational Assessment, 27(2), 125-137.##Chen, Y.; Tang, G.; Jin, J.; Xie, Q.; Li, J. (2014). &quot;CEOs’ Transformational Leadership and Product Innovation Performance: The Roles of Corporate Entrepreneurship and Technology Orientation&quot;. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 31(S1), 2-17.##Cohen, D.; Prusak, L. (2001). In good company: How social capital makes organizations work. Harvard Business Press.##27.                Engelen, A.; Kaulfersch A.; Schmidt. S. (2015). &quot;The contigent role of top management&#039;s social capital on the relationship between entrepreneurial orientation and performance&quot;. Journal of small business management, Available at http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com.##28.                Goyal, A.; Akhilesh, K. B. (2007). &quot;Interplay among innovativeness, cognitive intelligence,emotional intelligence, and social capital of work teams&quot;. Team Performance Management, 13(7/8), 206-226.##Grave, A.; Salaff. J. W. (2005). &quot;Social net works and entrepreneurship&quot;. Entrepreneurship theory and practice, 28(1), 1-22.##Hermann, F.; Manfred, L.; Christian, K. (2007). &quot;The Significance of Personality in Business Start-up Intentions, Start-up Realization and Business Success&quot;. Entrepreneurship and Regional Development, 19(3), 227–251##Hough, J.; Scheepers, R. (2008). Creating corporate entrepreneurship through strategic leadership.##Hulland, J. (1999). &quot;Use of partial least squares (PLS) in strategic management research: a review of four recent studies&quot;. Strategic management journal, 20(2), 195-204.##Hyo, Sun Jung; Hye, Hyun Yoon (2012). &quot;The effects of emotional intelligence on counterproductive work behaviors and organizational citizen behaviors among food and beverage employees in a deluxe hotel&quot;. International Journal of Hospitality Management, 31, 369-378.##Jack, S. L.; Hyman, J.; Osborne, F. (2006). &quot;Small entrepreneurial venture culture, change and the impact on HRM: A critical review&quot;. Human resource management review, 16(4), 456-466.##Jung, H. S. ; Yoon, H. H. (2012). &quot;The effects of emotional intelligence on counterproductive work behaviors and organizational citizen behaviors among food and beverage employees in a deluxe hotel&quot;. International Journal of Hospitality Management, 31(2), pp.369-378.##Kaasa, A.; Kaldaru, H.; Parts, E. (2007). Social capital and institutional quality as factors of innovation: evidence from Europe. University of Tartu Faculty of Economics and Business Administration Working Paper.##Kale, P.; Singh, H.; Perlmutter, H. (2000). “Learning and protection of proprietary assets in strategic alliances: Building relational capital”. Strategic Management Journal, 21(3), 217-237.##Kamalian A. R.; Fazel A. (2011). &quot;The Relationship between Emotional Intelligence and Students’ Entrepreneurship: A case study of University of Sistan and Baluchestan&quot;. Entrepreneurship Development, 3(11), 127-46.##Khasawneh, S. (2011). &quot;Shared leadership and organizational citizenship behaviour in Jordanian public universities: Developing a global workforce for the 21st century&quot;. Educational ManagementAdministration and Leadership, 39(5), 621-634.##Kim, S. (2006). &quot;Public service motivation and organizational citizenship behavior in Korea&quot;.International journal of manpower, 27(8), 722-740.##Kokobyo, A. K. (2009). &quot;Operant competence, organizational social capital, organizational commitment and organizational citizenship behavior&quot;. Uganda Scholarly Digital Library.##Order No. 292. pp. 44-56.##Korte, R.; Lin, S. (2013). “Getting on board: Organizational socialization and the contribution of social capital”. Human relations, 66(3), 407-428.##Lawson, B.; Tyler, B. B.; Cousins, P. D. (2008). &quot;Antecedents and consequences of social capital on buyer performance improvement&quot;. Journal of Operations Management, 26(3), 446-460.##45.                Leana, Carrie R.; Van Buren, Harry J. (1999). &quot;Organizational social capital and employment practices&quot;. The Academy of Management Review, 24(3), 538-555.##Lewis, L. F.; SIU, W. S. (2015). &quot;Corporate Entrepreneurship and Ethical Decision-Making of Marketing Managers&quot;. In Proceedings of the 1997 World Marketing Congress, 646-655.##Mair, J. (2005). &quot;Entrepreneurial Behaviour in a Large Traditional Firm: Exploring key Drivers&quot;. In Corporate Entrepreneurship and Ven-Turing, Springer, 49–72.##McLaughlin, E. B. (2012). An emotional business: The role of emotional intelligence in entrepreneurial success. University of North Texas.##Modassir, A.; Singh, T. (2008). &quot;Relationship of emotional intelligence with transformational leadership and organizational citizenship behavior&quot;. International journal of leadership studies, 4(1), 3-21.##Mortan, R. A.; Ripoll, P.; Carvalho, C.; Bernal, M. C. (2014). &quot;Effects of emotional intelligence on entrepreneurial intention and self-efficacy&quot;. Revista de Psicología del Trabajo y de las Organizaciones, 30(3), 97-104.##51.                Nahapiet, J.; Ghoshal, S. (1998). &quot;Social Capital, Intellectual capital &amp; the organizational advantage&quot;. Academy of management Review ,23(2), 242-260.##Oz, H., Demirezen, M.; Pourfeiz, J. (2015). &quot;Emotional Intelligence and Attitudes Towards Foreign Language Learning: Pursuit of Relevance and Implications&quot;. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 186, pp.416-423.##Paine, J. B.; Organ, D. W. (2004). &quot;The cultural matrix of organizational citizenship behavior: Some preliminary conceptual and empirical observations&quot;. Human resource management review, 10(1), 45-59.##Podsakoff, P. M.; Mackenzie, S. B.; Paine, J. B.; Bachrach, D. G. (2000). &quot;Organizational citizenship behaviors: A critical review of the theoretical and empirical literature and suggestions for future research&quot;. Journal of Management, 6(3), 513-563.##Polat, S. (2009). &quot;Organizational citizenship behavior display levels of the teachers at secondary schools according to the perceptions of the school&quot;. Journal of procedia social and behavioral sciences, 1,1591-1596.##Richard, H. (2010). &quot;Organisational citizenship behaviour, emotional intelligence and spirituality: What’s the relationship?&quot;. Australian Catholic University, St Patrick’s Campus,Victoria  Fitzroy Victoria 3065 Australia.##Salarzehi, H.; Yaghoubi, N. M.; Naroei, M.; Sin, L. G. (2011). &quot;A Survey Of Relationship Between Emotional Intelligence And Organizational Citizenship Behavior In Iran&quot;. International Business And Management, 3(1), 130-135.##Salovey, P.; Mayer, J. D. (1990). &quot;Emotional intelligence&quot;. Imagination, Cognition and Personality, 9(3), 185-211.##Scheepers, M. J.; Hough, J.; Bloom, J. Z. (2008). &quot;Nurturing the corporate entrepreneurship capability&quot;. Southern African Business Review, 12(3), pp.50-75.##Stone W. (2001). &quot;Measuring social capital: Towards a theoretically informed measurement framework for researching social capital in family and community life&quot;. Australian Institute of Family Studies Melbourne. Szeman, I.; Kaposy, T. (2010). Cultural theory: an anthology. John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Unni, A. S. V. (2014). &quot;A study of relationship between social capital andorganizational citizenship behavior&quot;. International journal of managerial studies and research, 2(4), 76-81.##Utami, A. F.; Bangun, Y. R.; Lantu, D. C. (2014). &quot;Understanding the Role of Emotional Intelligence and Trust to the Relationship between Organizational Politics and Organizational Commitment&quot;. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 115, 378-386.##Wagstaff, C.; Fletcher, D.; Hanton, S. (2012). &quot;Exploring Emotion Abilities and Regulation Strategies in Sport Organizations&quot;. Sport, Exercise, and Performance Psychology. (4), 268-282.##Wang, Y.; Zhang, X. (2008). &quot;Operationalization of corporate entrepreneurship and its performance implications in China: an empirical study&quot;. Journal of Chinese Entrepreneurship, 1(1), 8-20.##Wiedmer, R.; Boyer, K. (2015). &quot;A Dyadic Investigation of Collaborative Competence, Social Capital, and Performance in Buyer–Supplier Relationships&quot;. Journal of Supply Chain Management, 51(2), 3-21.##66.                Xin, H. (2009). &quot;The study of relationship between OCB and social capital based on different culture”. The British Psychology Society.##Yaghoubi, E.; Ahmadzadeh, S.; Abdullah, H. (2011). &quot;An Analysis of Correlation between Organizational Citizenship Behavior (OCB) and Emotional Intelligence (EI) &quot;. Modern Applied Science, (5), 25-37.##68.                Yazdanpanah, R.; Pordal, A. (2014). &quot;The Relationship between Social Capital and Organizational Citizenship Behaviour (Case Study: Yasouj Education and Training)&quot;. Indian Journal of Fundamental and Applied Life, 4(S4),2092-2099.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر عدالت سازمانی بر سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی از طریق سرمایۀ اجتماعی (پیمایشی در ادارۀ‌ کل ورزش و جوانان استان اصفهان)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigation of Effect Organizational Justice on the Psychological Capital by Social Capital (Survey of Department of Youth and Sport of Esfahan Province)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> هدف از این پژوهش بررسی تأثیر عدالت سازمانی بر سرمایة روان‌شناختی از طریق سرمایة اجتماعی در کارکنان ادارات ورزش و جوانان استان اصفهان بود. روش پژوهش توصیفی و از نوع همبستگی بود. جامعة آماری پژوهش عبارت است از همة کارکنان ادارات ورزش و جوانان استان اصفهان که تعداد آن‌ها برابر با 405 نفر بود که با توجه به مشخص‌بودن جامعة آماری، با به‌کارگیری جدول کرجسی و مورگان، 210 نفر به عنوان نمونة آماری با روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌ای متناسب انتخاب شدند. داده‌های پژوهش با به‌کارگیری پرسشنامه‌های استاندارد عدالت سازمانی نیهوف و مورمن، سرمایة اجتماعی ناهابیت و گوشال و سرمایة روان‌شناختی لوتانز گردآوری شد. داده‌ها با دو روش آمار توصیفی (میانگین و انحراف معیار) و آمار استنباطی (آزمون کولموگروف اسمیرنوف، ضریب همبستگی پیرسون، تحلیل مسیر، آزمون سوبل) با نرم‌افزارهای اس. پی. اس. اس و لیزرل تجزیه‌وتحلیل شد. نتایج نشان داد عدالت سازمانی با سرمایة روان‌شناختی رابطة معنادار دارد. همچنین، عدالت از طریق متغیر میانجی سرمایة اجتماعی بر سرمایة روان‌شناختی تأثیر می‌گذارد. در نهایت، آزمون برازندگی مدل نشان‌دهندة مناسب‌بودن آن برای سازمان‌های ورزشی بود. در حقیقت، عدالت سازمانی نقش محوری در سازمان‌ها دارد و با برقراری آن می‌توان روابط قوی بین کارکنان و بازده بالاتری را مشاهده کرد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The aim of this study was Investigation of effect organizational justice on the psychological capital by social capital (survey of department of youth and sport of Esfahan province). This research was descriptive correlation. The study population includes all the employees&#039; offices youth and sports of Isfahan province that thire number was equal to 405 people. According to specified target population, by using krejcie and Morgan table, 210 subjects stratified random sample proportional to size sampling were selected. Data of research collected by using standard questionnaires organizational justice of Niehoff and Moorman, social capital and Nahabyt and Ghoshal and psychological capital Luthans were collected. Data on two levels Descriptive statistics (mean, standard deviation and percentage) and inferential statistics (K-S test, Pearson correlation, Path analysis, Sobel test) using SPSS software and LISREL were analyzed. The results showed that there was significant relationship between organizational justice and psychological capital and also organization justice through the social capital on psychological capital affect, and finally the model was suitable for sports organizations. In fact, organizational justice plays a central role in the organization and establishing strong relationships between staff and can be observed greater efficiency.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>393</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>413</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صابری</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Saberi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، مدیریت ورزشی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، مدیریت ورزشی، دانشگاه تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ali_saberi1364@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سلطان حسینی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Soltan Hosseini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت ورزشی دانشکدة تربیت‌بدنی، دانشگاه اصفهان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه مدیریت ورزشی دانشکدة تربیت‌بدنی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.soltanhoseini@spr.ui.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهزاد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ایزدی</Family>
						<NameE>Behzad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Izadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه مدیریت ورزشی، دانشگاه کردستان، سنندج، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه مدیریت ورزشی، دانشگاه کردستان،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>b.izadi@uok.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهنوش</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>وزیریان</Family>
						<NameE>Behnoosh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Vazirian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس‌‌ارشد، مدیریت ورزشی، دانشگاه آزاد، واحد مبارکه، اصفهان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس‌‌ارشد، مدیریت ورزشی، دانشگاه آزاد،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>behnooshvazirian@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عدالت سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایة اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایة روان‌شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>احمدی، سیدعلی‌اکبر؛ فیض‌آبادی، حوریه (1390). «بررسی ارتقای سرمایة اجتماعی بر بهبود عملکرد سازمان». مدیریت دولتی، دورة سوم، شمارة ششم، صفحات 45-35.##اسماعیلی، محمدرضا، جوادی‌پور، محمد؛ طالپ‌پور، مهدی (1393). «مدل معادلات ساختاری عدالت سازمانی، رفتار شهروندی سازمانی و سرمایة اجتماعی کارکنان ادارات ورزش و جوانان خراسان رضوی». نشریة پژوهش‌های معاصر در مدیریت ورزشی، دورة چهارم، شمارة هشتم، صفحات 13-1.##الوانی، مهدی؛ شیروانی، علیرضا (1383). «سرمایة اجتماعی، اصل محور توسعه». مجلة تدبیر، شمارة 147، صفحات 22-16.##امیرخانی، طیبه؛ عارف‌نژاد، محسن (1391). «تحلیل تأثیر رفتار شهروندی سازمانی و سرمایة روان‌شناختی بر سرمایۀ اجتماعی». فصل‌نامة علوم مدیریت ایران. دورة هفتم، شمارة 26، صفحات 112-89.##رامین‌مهر، حمید؛ هادیزاده، اکرم؛ احمدی، ایمان (1388). «بررسی رابطة بین ادراک از عدالت سازمانی و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی (مطالعة موردی: شرکت پخش فراورده‌های نفتی ستاد تهران)». فصل‌نامة مدیریت تحول، دورة اول، شمارة دوم، صفحات 89-65.##سلطان‌حسینی، محمد؛ نادریان، مسعود؛ صابری، علی (1392). «برآورد سهم نسبی رفتار شهروندی سازمانی از عدالت سازمانی در ورزشکاران مرد نخبة کشور». مجلة مدیریت ورزشی، دورة چهارم، شمارة پنجم، صفحات 160-145.##شاکر، زینب؛ محرم‌زاده، مهرداد (1390). «ارتباط عدالت سازمانی و سرمایة اجتماعی در کارکنان ادارات تربیت بدنی استان آذربایجان غربی». ششمین همایش ملی دانشجویان تربیت بدنی و علوم ورزشی، تهران، پژوهشکدة تربیت بدنی و علوم ورزشی.##فیضی، کامران؛ و رونقی، محمدحسین (1390). ارزیابی سرمایه‌های فکری و اجتماعی شرکت‌های رتبه‌بندی‌شده توسط شورای عالی انفورماتیک ایران». فصل‌نامة پژوهشگاه علوم و فناوری اطلاعات ایران، دورة اول، شمارة دوم، صفحات 206-189.##گنجی، محمد؛ هلالس ستوده، مینا (1389). «رابطة گونه‌های دینداری و سرمایة اجتماعی». جامعه‌شناسی کاربردی، سال 22، شمارة 42، صفحات 120-95.##Bies, R. J. (1987). &quot;The predicament of injustice: The management of moral outrage&quot;.In L.L. Cummings &amp; B. M. Staw (Eds), Research in organizational behavior, 9, 289-319.##Choudhary, N.; Kumar, D. R.; Philip, P. J. (2012). “Organizational Justice as Predictor of Satisfaction with Personal and Organizational Outcomes”. Proceedings of National Conference on Emerging Challenges for Sustainable Business. 971–981.##Choudhary, N.; Philip, P. J.; Kumar, R. (2011). “Impact of Organizational Justice on Organizational Effectiveness”. Industrial Engineering Letters, 1(3), 18–25.##Colquitt, J.; Conlon, D. E.; Porter, C. (2001). &quot;Justice at the millennium: A metaanalytical organizational&quot;. Journal of Applied Psychology, (3), 200- 215.##Emhan, A.; Bakiev, E.; Taşdöven, H.; Kula, S. (2014). “Analysis of Relationship among Social Capital, Organizational Justice and Performance with Structural Equation Model: The Case of Banking Sector”. International Review of Social Sciences, 2(7), 425- 445.##Fatih, C. (2011). &quot;The effects of the organizational psychological capital on the attitudes of commitment and satisfaction: A public sample in Turkey&quot;. European Journal of Social Sciences, 21(3), 373-380.Greenberg, J. (2004). &quot;Stress Fairness to fare No stress:Managing workplace stress by promoting Organizational Justice&quot;. Organizational Dynamics. 33, 322-335.##Lambert, Eric (2003). &quot;The impact of organizational justice on correctional staff&quot;. Journal of criminal justice,31, 371-383.##Luthans, F.; Avolio, B. J. Avey (2007). &quot;Positive psychological capital: Measurement and relationship with performance and satisfaction&quot;. Personnel Psychology, 541-572.##Mahajan. A.; Benson, P. H. (2013). “Organizational justice climate, social capital and firm performance”. Journal of Management Development, 32(7), 721 – 736.##Messer, B. A. E.; White, F. A. (2006). &quot;Employees’ mode perceptions of fairness and organizational citizenship behavior&quot;. Journal of business and psychology, 4, 97-105.##Moorman, R. H. (1991).&quot;Relationship between organizational citizenship behaviors: do fairnessreceptions influence employee citizenship?”.Journal of applied psychology, 76, 845-855.##Nahapiet, J.; Ghoshal, S. (1998). &quot;Social Capital, Intellectual Capital &amp; theorganizational advantage&quot;. ACAD MANAGE REV, 23(2), 242_260.##Niehoff, B. P.; Moorman, R. H. (1993). “Justice as a mediator of the relationship between methods of monitoring and organizational citizenship behavior”. Academy of Management Journal, 36, 527–556.##Niehoff, B. P.; Moorman, R. H. (1993). &quot;Justice as a mediator of the relationship between methods of monitoring and organizational citizenship behavior”. Academy of Management Journal, 36, 527-556.##Philip, P. J.; Kumar, R.; Choudhary, N. (2012). Relationship between Organizational Citizenship Behavior and Organizational Justice at Work Place“. Proceeding Ninth AIMS International Conference on Management, January 1-4, 1215–1221.##Ryan R. M.; Deci E. L. (2005). &quot;On happiness and human potentials: A review of research on hedonic and eudemonic well-being&quot;. Annual Review Psychology, 52, 141-166.   5.        حضوری، محمدجواد؛ صالحی، علی؛ دانایی‌فر، حسن؛ نجاری، رضا (1392). «طراحی مدل ارتقای سرمایة روان‌شناختی در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران: تبیین نقش کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی». پژوهش‌های مدیریت در ایران، دورة 17، شمارة سوم، صفحات 47-23.##Snyder, C. R.; Lopez S. J. (2007). Positive psychology: The scientific and practical explorations of human strengths. US, Sage Publications.##Yuong, Koh T.; Rowlinson, S. (2011). “Relational approach in managing construction project safety“. Journal of A social capital perspective, 48, 134-144.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تاثیر سرمایه اجتماعی بر کارآفرینی زنان در شهر ایلام با توجه به نقش میانجی نوآوری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the Effect of Social Capital on Women&#039;s Entrepreneurship in the City of Ilam with Regard to the Role of Mediator Innovation</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>امروزه علاوه بر سرمایة فیزیکی، سرمایة اجتماعی، عامل تعیین­کننده­ در کارآفرینی است. بدین منظور، پژوهش حاضر، ضمن بررسی تأثیرگذاری سرمایة اجتماعی بر کارآفرینی، نقش میانجی نوآوری در تأثیرگذاری سرمایة اجتماعی بر کارآفرینی را ارزیابی می‌کند. این مطالعه در نمونه­ای 130 نفری از کارآفرینان زن شهر ایلام با روش نمونه­گیری تصادفی ساده انجام گرفته است. روش پژوهش، توصیفی، از نوع همبستگی است و برای جمع­آوری داده­ها پرسشنامة محقق‌ساخته به‌کار گرفته شده است. همچنین، برای بررسی روایی، روایی صوری بررسی شد و برای بررسی پایایی، آلفای کرونباخ محاسبه شد. نتایج نشان داد ابزار تحقیق پایایی و روایی مناسبی دارد. تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده­ها با روش مدل­سازی معادلات ساختاری با نرم­افزار LISREL8.8 انجام گرفته است. یافته­های پژوهش نشان می­دهد، سرمایة اجتماعی و نوآوری تأثیر مثبت و معنادار بر کارآفرینی دارد، اما سرمایة اجتماعی بر نوآوری تأثیر ندارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Today, in addition to physical capital, social capital, entrepreneurship is the determining factor. Therefore, this study was designed to investigate the influence of social capital on entrepreneurship; to evaluate the impact of social capital on entrepreneurial innovation is the role of mediator. The study had a sample of 130 female entrepreneurs Ilam through simple random sampling has been done. Research methodology is descriptive and correlation survey questionnaire researcher-building was used to collect data. Also, researcher for validity, the content validity and for reliability, using of Cronbach&#039;s alpha, which result indicated the suitability of variable. Data analysis software LISREL structural equation model-building has been done. Research findings show that social capital is a positive and significant impact on entrepreneurship and innovation, but innovation could not affect social capital.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>415</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>434</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نادر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سیدامیری</Family>
						<NameE>Nader</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Seyedamiri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، دانشکدة کارآفرینی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، دانشکدة کارآفرینی، دانشگاه تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nadersa@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کاملی</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kameli</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>arkameli91@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سمیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مرادی</Family>
						<NameE>Somaye</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moradi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس‌‌ارشد، دانشکدة کارآفرینی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس‌‌ارشد، دانشکدة کارآفرینی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>somayemoradi5@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>هادی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>واشقانی فراهانی</Family>
						<NameE>Hadi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Vasheqani Farahani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس‌‌ارشد، دانشکدة کارآفرینی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس‌‌ارشد، دانشکدة کارآفرینی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>h_v_f_i@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایة اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارآفرینی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>الوانی، سیدمهدی؛ ناطق، تهمینه؛ فراحی، محمدمهدی (1386). «نقش سرمایة اجتماعی در توسعة مدیریت دانش سازمانی». فصل‌نامة علوم مدیریت ایران، سال دوم، شمارة پنجم، صفحات 70-35.##برومند، زهرا؛ جلیلی، سودابه (1387). «بررسی تأثیر هوش عاطفی، سرمایة اجتماعی و توسعة منابع انسانی بر بهره‌وری شرکت همشهری». پژوهشنامة مدیریت و سرمایة اجتماعی، شمارة چهارم، صفحات 28-15.##الوانی، سیدمهدی؛ شیروانی، علیرضا (1385) .سرمایةاجتماعی (مفاهیم،نظریه­هاوکاربردها). چاپ اول، تهران، انتشارات مانی.##Acs, Z. J.; Anselin, L.;, Varga, A. (2002). “Patents and innovations counts as measures of regional production of new knowledge”. Res Policy, 31, 1069–1085##Ahuja, G.; Lampert, C. M. (2001). “Entrepreneurship in the large corporation: a longitudinal study of how established firms create breakthrough inventions”. Strategic Management Journal, 22(6–7), 521-543.##Adler, P. S.; Kwon, S. W. (2002). “Social Capital: Prospects for a New Concept“. The Academy of Management Review, 27(1), 17-40##Baum, J.; Locke, E. A.; Smith, K. G. (2001). “A multidimensional model of venture growth“. Academy of Management Journal, 44(2), 292–303.##Bosma, Niels; Praag, Mirjam van; Thurik, Roy; Wit, Gerrit de (2004). “The value of human and social investments for the business performance of startups”. Small Business Economics, 23, 227-236.##Bolino, M. C.; Turneley, W. H.; Bloo , J. M. (2002). “Citizenship behaviour and creation of social capital in organization”. Acadmic Management Review. 27, 505-522##Bennett, R. J.; Robson, P. J. A. (1999). “The use of external business advice by SMEs in Britain”. Entrepreneurship and Regional Development, 34, 53-63..##Bala Ramasamy, K. W.; Matthew, G.; Yeung, C. H. (2006). “IS guanxi (relationship) a bridge to knowledge transfer”. Journal of Business Research, 59(1),130-139.##Djankov, S.; Miguel, E.; Qian, Y.; Roland, G.; Zhuravskaya, E. (2005). “Who are the entrepreneurs in Russia?”. Journal of the European Economic Association, 3, 1–11.##Dong,Y.; Jin, J.; Yang, R. (2008). ”The Empirical Relationship Analysis between Social Capital and Innovation of Industry Cluster”. Journal of the Elearnica, 1-4##Djankov, S.; Qian, Y.; Roland, G.; Zhuravskaya, E. (2006). “Who are China&#039;s entrepreneurs?”. American Economic Review, 96, 348–352##De Clerq, D.; Dakhli, M. (2004). “Human capital, social capital and innovation: A multicountry study”. Entrepreneurship and Regional Development, 16, 107-128.##Drucker, P. (1999). “Knowledge Worker Productivity: The BiggestChallenge California”. Management Review. 3, 79-94##Egbert, H. (2009). “Business success through social networks? A comment on social networks and business success”. American Journal of Economics and Sociology, 68, 665-677.##Greve, A.; Salaff, J. (2003). “Social networks and entrepreneurship. Entrepreneurship”. International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Innovation Management, 28, 1–22.##Hanson, S. (2009). “Changing places through women’s entrepreneurship. Economic Geography”. International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Innovation Management, 85, 245-267.##Hitt, M. A.; Ireland, R. D. (2000). “The intersection of entrepreneurship and strategic management research”. In D.L. Sexton &amp; H. Landstrom (Eds.), Handbook of entrepreneurship, Oxford: Blackwell Publishers 45–63..##Bessie, House (2000). “Does economic culture and social capital matter?: An analysis of African-American entrepreneurs in Cleveland, Ohio”. Western Journal of Black Studies, 24(3) 183–192.##Hesselbein, F. (2002). Marshall Goldsmith, and Iain Somerville, edLeading for Innovation: And Organizing for Results. Jossey-Bass. ISBN##Ingram, P.; Roberts, P. W. (2000). “Friendships among Competitors in the Sydney Hotel Industry”. American Journal of Sociology, 387-423.##Kelley, J. D.; Brush, G. C.; Greene, G. P.; Litovsky, Y. (2013). “Global Entrepreneurship Monitor Women’s Report”, GERA/GEM, available at: www.gemconsortium.org##Kraus, S.; Harms, R.; Fink, M. (2010). “Entrepreneurial marketing: moving beyond marketing in new ventures”. International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Innovation Management, 11(1), 19-34##Kai, K.; Jie, Z. (2009). “An empirical study of the effects of social capital on inter-firm knowledge transfer and innovation performance “. International Conference on Information Management, Innovation Management and Industrial Engineering.##Kafouros, M. I.; Buckley, P. J.; Sharp, J. A.; Wang, C. (2008). “The role of internationalization in explaining innovation performance”. Technovation, 28 (1–2), 63–74.##Landry, R.; Amara, N.; Lamari, M. (2002). “Does social capital determine innovation?To what extent?”. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 69(7), 681-701.##Larraza, M.; Contı´n, I.; Bayona, C. (2007). “Actividad emprendedora, innovacio´n y desarrollo econo´mico”. Econ Ind, 363,119–128##Lyons, T. S. (2002). “Building social capital for rural enterprise development: three case studies in the United States”. Journal of Developmental Entrepreneurship, 7(2), 193–216.##Maskel, P. (2001). “Social Capital, innovation and competitiveness”. In S. Baron, J. Field, and T. Schuller (Eds.), Social Capital: Critical Perspectives, Oxford, U.K.: Oxford University press, 111-123.##Minniti, M.; Nardone, C. (2007). “Being in someone else’s shoes: the role of gender in nascent entrepreneurship”. Small Business Economics, 28, 223–238.##Minniti, M.; Arenius, P.; Langowitz, N. (2005). GEM 2004 Report on Women and Entrepreneurship. Babson Park. MA: Global Entrepreneurship Monitor Program and Center for Women’s Leadership at Babson College, Babson College##Marlino, D.; Wilson, F. (2003). Teen Girls on Business: Are They Empowered?. Simmons School of Management and The Committee of 200, Chicago, IL##Nan, C. Chen (2007). “The relationship among social entrepreneurial orientation”. organizational resources and entrepreneurial, 12(3), 24-39##Nahapiet, J.; Ghoshal S. (1998). “Social capital, intellectual cap-ital, and the organizational advantage”. Academy of Management Review, 23(2), 242-266.##Phene, K.; Fladmoe-Lindouits, Marsh, L. (2006). “Breakthrough innovations in the U.S. biotechnology industry: The effects of technological space and geographic origin”. Strategic Management Journal,. 27, 369–388.##Poon, J. (2012). ”Social capital and female entrepreneurship in rural regions: Evidence from Vietnam”. Journal of the Marketing Management, 308, 1-8.##Putnam, R, D. (2000). Bowling Alone: The Collapse and Revival of American Community”. New Tork, NY, Simon&amp; Schuster.##Rogers, E. M. (2008). Diffusion of Innovations. 5 ed. New York, Free Press.## Runco, M. A. (2005). “Predicting entrepreneurship from ideation and divergent thinking”. Creativity and Innovation Management, 14, 311-315##Schumpeter, J .A. (1961). “The theory of economic development :an inquiry into profits, capital, credit, interest and the business cycle##Shane, S. A. (2004). A General Theory of Entrepreneurship: The Individual opportunity Nexus. Cheltenham, UK, Edward Elgar.##Shane, S.; Venkataraman, S. (2000). “The promise of entrepreneurship as a field of research”. Academy of Management Review, 25, 217–226.##schuster, B, S.; Falck, O.; Heblich, S. (2010). “Social capital access and entrepreneurship”. Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, 76, 821-833.##Verheul I.; Uhlaner L. M.; Thurik A. R. (2005). “Business accomplishments, gender and entrepreneurial self-image”. Journal of Bus Venturing, 20(4) 483–518.##Wahba, J.; Zenou, Y. (2012). ”Out of sight, out of mind: Migration, entrepreneurship and social capital”. Management Review, 890, 1-14.##Walter, J.; Lechner, C.; Kellermanns, F. W. (2007). “Knowledge transfer between and within alliance partners: Private versus collective benefits of social capital”. Journal of Business Research, 698–710##Wen Lin, B.; Chien Li, P. (2006). ”Social capital, capabilities, and entrepreneurial strategies: a study of Taiwanese high-tech new ventures”., Journal of Business Research, 1-14.##Yadav, M. S.; Prabhu, J. C.; Chandy, R. K. (2007). “Managing the future: CEO attention and innovation outcomes”. Journal of Marketing, 71, 84–101.##Zhang, F. (2003). “An Empirical Study on Relationship between firm’s Social Capital and its Learning Efficiency in China”. Journal of Business management, 137, 1-5##Zhan, H.; Hailin, L. (2011). “Does Knowledge Energy Mediate the Relationship between Internal Social Capital and Management Innovation”. International Conference on Information Management, Innovation Management and Industrial Engineering, 1-4##Zhang, H. (2008). ”The Research of Relationship between Social Capital and Corporate Knowledge’s Transfer and Innovation”. Management Review,1-4.##Zahra, Z.; George, G. (2002). “Absorptive capacity: A review, reconceptualization and extension”. Academy of Management Review, 27(2): 185-203.##Zhan Zhan,H.; Hailin,L.,(2011). “Does Knowledge Energy Mediate the Relationship between Internal Social Capital and Management Innovation”. Academy of Management Review, 25(3), 35-48.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>دینداری و تأثیر آن در سرمایة اجتماعی خانواده (مورد مطالعه: خانواده‌های ساکن شهر قم)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Religiousness and its Effects on the Social Capital of Family (A Case Study of Qom)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پژوهش حاضر در پی بررسی تأثیر دینداری در سرمایة اجتماعی خانواده‌های ساکن شهر قم است. تحقیق از نوع کاربردی است که به روش اسنادی و پیمایشی انجام گرفته است. جامعة آماری، خانواده‌های ساکن قم به تعداد 160565 خانوار بوده است. حجم نمونة انتخابی بر اساس فرمول کوکران 376 خانوار به دست آمد. در نهایت، 400 خانوار با روش خوشه‌ای از چهار منطقة شهر قم انتخاب شدند. اطلاعات مورد نیاز این پژوهش با به‌‎کارگیری پرسشنامة محقق‌ساخته جمع‌آوری شد. میزان آلفای کل سؤال‌های پرسشنامه 72/0 به دست آمد که نشان‌دهندة ثبات و قابلیت اعتماد ابزار تحقیق است. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد سرمایة اجتماعی 5/65 درصد از خانواده‌ها بالا، 33 درصد متوسط و 5/0 درصد پایین بوده است. متغیرهای مستقل، دین‌داری، و پایگاه اجتماعی - اقتصادی در سرمایة اجتماعی خانواده تأثیر زیادی داشتند. فراز­ و فرود سرمایة اجتماعی در خانواده بیشتر متأثر از عوامل برون­خانوادگی و اجتماعی است، زیرا تغییرات اجتماعی و محیطی بر ساخت‌های کوچکتر، از جمله خانواده مؤثر بوده­اند. برای جلوگیری از کاهش سرمایة اجتماعی خانواده، نقش مراکز و نهادهای دینی و هیئت­های مذهبی، دوستان و الگوهای انتخابی و مذهبی اهمیت دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The present research seeks to investigate the effects of religiousness on the social capital of families residing in Qom. It is an applied kind of research conducted through using documentary and survey methods. The statistical population has been 160565 households living in Qom. Based on Cochran&#039;s formula, the sample size was determined to be 376 households which finally it was decided to be 400 people, who were chosen from four districts of Qom using cluster sampling. Data were collected through questionnaires and interviews. The Alpha of all questions of the questionnaire was 0.72 (which shows its consistency and reliability). The results showed that the social capital of 65.50 percent of families was high, of 33 percent of them it was average, and it was low for 0.5 percent of them. Independent variables, i.e. religiousness and socioeconomic status, had increasing effect on the social capital of families. The rise and fall of social capital in families was influenced by external and social factors; since social and environmental changes influenced smaller structures like families. The role of religious institutions and organizations, friends, and selected and religious exemplars are highly important in preventing the reduction of the social capital of families.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>435</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>452</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سلیمانی</Family>
						<NameE>Majid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Soleimani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مربی پژوهشگاه علوم اسلامی امام صادق (ع)، قم، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مربی پژوهشگاه علوم اسلامی امام صادق (ع)،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sociosol@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>باقی نصرآبادی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Baghi Nasrabadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، پژوهشگاه علوم اسلامی امام صادق (ع)، قم، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، پژوهشگاه علوم اسلامی امام صادق</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>baqi1341@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فاضل</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Fazel</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تهران مرکز، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rfazel49@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اعتماد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دینداری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خانواده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایة اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مشارکت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>. الوانی، مهدی؛ سیدنقوی، میرعلی (1381). «سرمایة اجتماعی؛ مفاهیم و نظریه‌ها». فصل‌نامة مطالعات مدیریت، شماره‌های 33 و 34.##2. بوردیو، پیر (1380). نظریة کنش. ترجمة مرتضی مردیها، تهران، انتشارات نقش و نگار.##3. تحقیقی، امیرحسین (1382). «سرمایة اجتماعی، دولت و نهادها در ایران». اندیشة صادق، شماره‌های 11و12.##4. تاجبخش، کیان ( 1384). سرمایة اجتماعی، اعتماد، دموکراسی و توسعه. ترجمة افشین خاکباز و حسن پویان، تهران، نشر شیرازه.##5. پارسونز، تالکوت؛ وبر، ماکس؛ لوویت، کارل و دیگران (1379). عقلانیت و آزادی، مقالاتی از ماکس وبر دربارة ماکس وبر. ترجمة یدالله موقن و احمد تدین، تهران، هرمس.##6. حسن‌تبار، منیرالسادات (1384). بررسی رابطة سرمایة اجتماعی خانواده‌ها و موفقیت تحصیلی فرزندان. پایان‌نامة کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه الزهرا.##7. ذکائی، محمدسعید (1384). «رابطة سرمایة اجتماعی و کیفیت زندگی در محلات شهری». فصل‌نامة علوم اجتماعی، شمارة 32.##8. رحمانی، جعفر؛ میرزاحسینی، حسن (1380). طرح بررسی قابلیت‌ها و موانع فرهنگی در توسعة استان قم. استانداری قم.##9. ساروخانی، باقر (1379). مقدمه­ای بر جامعه­شناسی خانواده. تهران، سروش.##10. شجاعی‌زند، علیرضا (1381). عرفی‌شدن در تجربة مسیحی و اسلامی. تهران، نشر باز.##11. شارع‌پور، محمود (1383). ابعاد و کارکردهای سرمایة اجتماعی و پیامدهای حاصل از فرسایش آن. مجموعه مقالات مسائل اجتماعی ایران، تهران، نشرآگه.##12. شریفیان ثانی، مریم (1380). «سرمایة اجتماعی: مفاهیم اصلی و چهارچوب نظری». فصل‌نامة رفاه اجتماعی، سال اول، شمارة دوم.##13. صفری شالی، رضا (1382). طرح بررسی اعتماد اجتماعی و عوامل مؤثر بر آن در بین مردم شهر قم. سازمان مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی استان قم.##14. طباطبایی، سیدمحمدحسین (1370). مجموعةرسائل.ترجمةسیدهادیخسروشاهی، تهران، دفتر نشر فرهنگ اسلامی.##15. علی‌پور، مسیح ( 1379). «بررسی وضعیت فرهنگ عمومی استان قم». فصل‌نامة پژوهشی نامة قم، سال چهارم، شمارة 14.##16. عبدی، کافیه (1382). طرح بررسی وضعیت اشتغال زنان و موانع توسعة آن در استان قم. استانداری قم.##17. فوکویاما، فرانسیس (1385). پایان نظم، سرمایة اجتماعی و حفظ آن. ترجمة غلامعباس توسلی، تهران، حکایت قلم نوین.##18. کلمن، جیمز ( 1377). بنیادهای نظریة اجتماعی. ترجمة منوچهرصبوری، تهران، نشر نی.##19. مطهری، مرتضی (1377). مجموعه ‏آثار استاد شهید مطهرى. جلد دوم، تهران، صدرا.##20.Grootaert, C.; Narayan, D.; Jones, V.; Woolcock, M. )2004). “Measuring Social Capital: an integraterd questionnaire, , P 3.##21.Stone, W.; Hughes, J. )2002.( Social Capital :Empirical Meaning and Measurement Validity Research. Australian Institute of Family Studies.##22.Winter, I. (2000). “Family Life and Social Capital :toward a theorized understanding,Working Paper No.21,Australian Institute of Family Studies ,Melbourn. no.18,ISBN 0-8213-566-5 .##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نقش سرمایه اجتماعی در شکل گیری محافل کاری (تأملی بر ابعاد و مؤلفه های مفهوم محافل کاری)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Role of Social Capital in Formation of Communities of Practice (The Contemplation on the Components and Dimensions of the Concept of Communities of Practice)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در سال­های اخیر همزمان با پیشرفت پژوهش­ها در حوزة مدیریت دانش و تأکید بر یکپارچه­سازی فرایندهای خلق و تسهیم دانش، الگوهای کاری شرکت­های بزرگ جهانی تغییر یافته و ساختارهای نوینی در آن­ها ظهور کرده است. از جملۀ این ساختارها، محافل کاری است که به‌طور بنیادی با اشکال قبلی (گروه­های کاری و تیم­های کاری) متفاوت است. بر خلاف ساختارهای رسمی، محافل کاری نوعی ساختار غیررسمی است که به‌طور داوطلبانه توسط گروهی از افراد با دغدغه­ها و علائق مشترک و مشابه شکل گرفته است و به‌طور خاص متمرکز بر فعالیت­های خلق و تسهیم دانش است. یکی از مهم‌ترین مؤلفه­ها در شکل­گیری محافل کاری سرمایة اجتماعی است که بدون وجود اعتماد میان اعضا و بدون ایجاد هویت مشترک محافل کاری پایدار نخواهند بود. مقالة حاضر دو هدف اصلی دارد. هدف اول، معرفی مفهوم، ابعاد و مؤلفه­های محافل کاری است؛ و هدف دوم، شناخت ارتباط متقابل محافل کاری با سرمایة اجتماعی و نقش مهم سرمایة اجتماعی در شکل­گیری این ساختارهای غیررسمی است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In Recent Years, Coinciding with the Progress of Research in the Field of Knowledge Management and Emphasis on the Integrating Processes of Knowledge Creation and Sharing, Global Corporations Working Patterns Change and New Structures in Them Emerged.One of Such Structures, Communities of Practice that to Form the Fundamental with Previous Forms (Working Groups and Working Teams) is Different.Contrary to Formal Structures, Communities of Practice is an Informal Structure on a Voluntary Basis by a Group of People with Common Interests and Similar Concerns was Formed and Specifically Focused on the Activities of the Creation and Sharing of Knowledge.Concept of the Social Capital is one of the Most Important Components in the Formation of Communities of Practice.Without Trust between Members and Common Identity, the Communities of Practice will not be Sustainable.This Paper has two Main Aims. First, The Introduction of the Concept, Dimensions and Components of the Communities of Practice; andthe Second Objective is Determine the Relationship between Communities of Practice with Social Capital and Social Capital Important Role in the Formation of Informal Structures.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>453</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>474</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>طهماسبی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tahmasebi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rtahmasebi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خاندل</Family>
						<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khandel</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس‌ارشد، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس‌ارشد، دانشکدة مدیریت و حسابداری،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mohsenkhandel69@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خودانتخابی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خودجاودانگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>محافل کاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایة اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>یادگیری وضعیتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Adler, K.; Woo Kwon, S. (2002). “Social Capital: Prospects for A New Concept”. Academy of Management Review, 27, 17- 40.##Bolino, M. C.; Turnley, W. H.; Blood Good, J. M. (2002). “Citizenship Behavior and the Creation of Social Capital in Organizations”. Academy of Management Review, 27 (4), 505-522.##Bourdieu, P. (1985). The Forms of Capital. G. Richardson (Ed), Handbook of Theory and Research for the Sociology of Education, New York, Greenwood, 241-258.##4.       Brown, J.; Duguid, P. (1991). “Organizational Learning and Communities-of-Practice; Toward A Unified View of Working, Learning and Innovation”. Organization Science, 2(1), 40-57.##Brown, J. S.; Duguid, P. (2001). “Knowledge and Organization: A Social-Practice Perspective”. Organization Science, 12(2), 198-213.##Coleman, J. S. (1990). Foundations of Social Theory. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press.##Cook, S.;Brown, J. (1999). “Bridging Epistemologies: The Generative Dance between Organizational Knowledge and Organizational Learning”. Organization Science, 10(4), 381-400.##Crossan, M.; Lane, H.; White, R. E. (1999). “An Organizational Learning Framework: From Intuition to Institution”. Academy of Management Review, 24(3), 522-537.##Drucker, P. (1993). Post-Capitalist Society. New York, Harper Collins.##Elkjaer, B. (1999). In Search of a Social Learning Theory. In M. Easter By-Smith, L. Araujo, &amp; J. Burgoyne (Eds.), Organizational Learning and the Learning Organization (130-156). London, SAGE.##Gilley, A.; Steven, J.; Kerno, J. (2010). “Groups, Teams, and Communities of Practice: A Comparison”. Advances in Developing Human Resources, 12(1), 46–60.##Harrison, D. A.; Mohammed, S.; Mcgrath, J. E.; Florey, A. T.; Vanderstoep, S. W. (2003). “Time Matters in Team Performance: Effects of Member Familiarity, Entrainments, and Task Discontinuity on Speed and Quality”. Personnel Psychology, 56, 633-669.##13.    Hasmath, R.; Hsu, J. (2015). “Communities of Practice and The NGO Sector in China”. Paper Presented at Association for Research on Nonprofit Organizations and Voluntary Action Annual Conference (Chicago, USA), November (19-21), 1-16.##Hersh, A.; Aladwan, K. (2014). &quot;The Role of Marketing Knowledge Management in Achieving Competitive Advantage: A Field Study on Amman’s Hotels&quot;. International Journal of Marketing Studies; 6(3), 163-179.##Kerno, S. J.; Mace, S. L. (2010). “Communities of Practice: Beyond Teams”. Advances in Developing Human Resources, 12(1), 78-92.## Kline, J.; Alex-Brown, K. (2013). “The Social Body of Knowledge: Nurturing Organizational Social Capital Via Social Media Based Communities of Practice”. Technical Communication, 60(4), PP. 279-292.##Lesser, E.; Storck, J. (2001). “Communities of Practice and Organizational Performance”. IBM Systems Journal, 40(4), 831-840.##Lesser, E.;Prusak, L. (1999). “Communities of Practice, Social Capital and Organizational Knowledge”. Information Systems Review, 1(1), 3-9.##Mayer, R. C.; Davis, J. H.; Schoorman, F. D. (1995). “An Integrative Model of Organizational Trust”. Academy of Management Review, 20(3), 709-734.##Nahapiet, J.; Ghoshal, S. (1998). “Social Capital, Intellectual Capital and the Organizational Advantage”. Academy of Management Review, 23, 242-266.##Nonaka, I. (1994). “A Dynamic Theory of Organizational Knowledge Creation”. Organization Science, 5(1), 14-37.##Pastoors, K. (2007). “Consultants: Love-Hate Relationships with Communities of Practice”. The Learning Organization, 14, 21-33.##Schiavone, F. (2014). Communities of Practice and Vintage Innovation: A Strategic Reaction to Technological Change. Springer Briefs in Business, New York.##Sherif, k.; Hoffman, J.; Thomas, B. (2006). ”Can Technology Build Organizational Social Capital? The Case of a Global IT Consulting Firm”. Information &amp; Management, 43(7), 795–804.##Sinha, M. (2004). “Presence of Community of Practice: Its Effect on Social Capital and Competitive Advantage of The Firm”. A Thesis in the John Molson School of Business, Concordia University Montreal Canada, 1-105.##26.    Sierhuis, M.; Clancey, W. (1997). “Knowledge. Practice. Activities and People”, Http://Cogprints.Org/444/1/146.Htm.##Snyder, W. M. (1997). “Communities of Practice: Combining Organizational Learning and Strategy Insights to Create a Bridge to the 21st Century”, Academy of Management Conference, 3-20.##Sommerfeldt, E. J.; Taylor, M. (2011). “A Social Capital Approach to Improving Public Relations’ Efficacy: Diagnosing Internal Constraints on External Communication. Public Relations Review, 37(3), 197–206.##Spender, J. C. (1996). “Making Knowledge the Basis of a Dynamic Theory of the Firm”. Strategic Management Journal, 17, 45-62.##Tsoukas, H.; Vladimirou, E. (2001). “What is Organizational Knowledge”. Journal of Management Studies, 38(7), 973-993.##Wageman, R. (1997). “Critical Success Factors for Creating Superb Self-Managing Teams”. OrganizationalDynamics, 26, 49-61.##Wartburg, I. V.; Rost, K.; Teichert, T. (2006). “The Creation of Social and Intellectual Capital in Virtual Communities of Practice: Shaping Social Structure in Virtual Communities of Practice“. International Journal of Learning and Change, 1(3), 299-316.##Wenger, E.; Lave, J. (1991). Situated Learning, Legitimate Peripheral Participation. Cambridge, Cambridge University Press.##Wenger, E. (1998). Communities of Practice: Learning, Meaning and Identity. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge.##Wenger, E. (2000). Communities of Practice: The Structure of Knowledge Stewarding. Knowledge Horizons: The Present and the Promise of Knowledge Management. D. Shauvel. Boston, Butterworth-Heinemann, 203-224.##Wenger, E. C.; Snyder, W. M. (2000). “Communities of Practice: The Organizational Frontier”. Harvard Business Review, 78(1), 139-145.##Wenger, E. (2000). “Communities of Practice and Social Learning Systems”. Organization Articles, 7 (2), 225-246.##Wenger, E.; Mcdermott, R. A. Snyder, W. (2002). Cultivating Communities of Practice. Cambridge, MA, Harvard Business School Press.##39.    Wenger, E. (2006). “Communities of Practice: A Brief Introduction”. Retrieved From Http://Www.Ewenger.Com/Theory/ Communities of Practice _Intro.Htm.##40.    Yeo, R. K. (2008). “How Does Learning (Not) Take Place in Problem-Based Learning Activities in Workplace Contexts?”. Human Resource Development International, 11, 317-330.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				