<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>13</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Efficiency of Police Role and its Relationship Model with the Prosecution Service on Increasing Judiciary Social Capital</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر کارآمدی نقش پلیس و مدل روابط آن با دادسرا بر افزایش سرمایه اجتماعی نهاد قضائی کشور</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">77039</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2020.293920.1963</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>شیداییان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار ، دانشکده حقوق، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زینب</FirstName>
					<LastName>شیدائیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترا، دانشکده حقوق و معارف اسلامی، دانشگاه امام صادق (ع)، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The lack of social capital of the judiciary means the citizens&#039; distrust of the justice of that institution and, consequently, the lack of public engagement with its officials and officials. The increase in the number of crimes and their repetition and the violations of the laws indicate a decrease in the social capital of the judiciary within society. The present article seeks to examine the dimensions of the efficient model of police-prosecution service relations from the perspective of increasing social capital by logically analyzing related documents and based on preliminary research. This article concludes in its analysis that the restoration of the judicial police helps increase social capital. This article proposes to improve the law enforcement organization&#039;s relationship with the Office of the Judiciary in the context of network communication in the process of judicial reform. It is also recommended that the Department of Justice and its affiliation with the Judicial Police be more flexible in the hierarchical model by employing the capacities of the network communication model.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">فقدان یا کمبودِ سرمایه اجتماعی نسبت به نهاد قضائی به معنای بی‌اعتمادی شهروندان نسبت به عدالت گستری آن دستگاه و در نتیجه عدم مشارکت عمومی با مسئولین و مأمورین این نهاد است. افزایش جرائم و تکرار آن‌ها و نقض قوانین نشانگر کاهش سرمایه اجتماعی نهاد قضائی در میان جامعه است. مقاله حاضر درصدد است با تحلیل منطقی اسناد و مدارک مرتبط و بر مبنای پژوهش پیشینی به بررسی ابعاد مدل کارآمد روابط پلیس و دادسرا از منظر افزایش سرمایه اجتماعی بپردازد. این مقاله در تحلیل‌های خود به این نتیجه می‌رسد که احیاء پلیس قضایی به افزایش سرمایه اجتماعی کمک می‌نماید. این نوشتار پیشنهاد می‌کند در فرآیند احیاء پلیس قضائی به بهبود روابط سازمانی نیروی انتظامی با سازمان دادسرا در قالب ارتباط شبکه‌ای توجه شود. هم‌چنین توصیه می‌شود در سازمان دادسرا و ارتباطی که با پلیس قضائی زیرمجموعه خود دارد، سازمان دادسرا با به کارگیری ظرفیت‌های مدل ارتباط شبکه‌ای به انعطاف بخشی بیش‌تر در مدل سلسله مراتبی بپردازد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پلیس قضائی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دادسرا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل ارتباط</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قوه قضائیه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
