<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[First Pages]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_54639_38390ad741948f32ea219be7cab25df2.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The relationship between emotional intelligence and social Capital in Non- Governmental Organization (NGOs)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Zaree Matin, Hasan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghanbari, Ali Akbar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Qane, Marziah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Emotional intelligence]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Governmental organizations]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The benefits of social capital make a higher position in the views of the social, economic and political. Due to the positive functions of social capital, resources cognition and solutions of reinforce can have positive outcomes for society. In the meantime, attention to psychological grounds that "emotional intelligence" is one of the most important has a particular importance. The purpose of this study is to investigate the relationship between emotional intelligence and social capital of Qom province NGOs organizations. Given the role of NGOs facilitation in the formation of group and social capital, In this study, 859 persons was selected as effective members of statistical population of NGO Qom province, this community sample of 265 people were selected by random Stratified sampling method. The purpose of this study aimed to applied research, and the data collection methods, are descriptive and the correlation type. To measure the variables, have been used emotional intelligence questionnaire Sybrya Schering (Cronbach's alpha 0.845) and social capital Nahapyt and Qshal questionnaire (Cronbach's alpha 0.865). Spearman test results showed there is a direct relationship between emotional intelligence and social capital and achieved correlation coefficient is positive and equal to 0.469.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_54087_38a26de1fa3d3b3d2b174af5037c9d62.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2015.54087]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the role of harnessing the psychological capital of leader in developing the psychological capital of employees: The moderating role of employees’ perception of transformational leadership]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rastgar, Abbas-Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Vatandoost, Babak]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghanbarzadeh Miandehi, Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[EPTL]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Developing PsyCap]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[PsyCap]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[SEM]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[How psychological capital (PsyCap) can be developed in organizations, is the left side of PsyCap studies. A conceptual model of developing PsyCap of employees by harnessing the PsyCap of leader has been developed in this article that Employees’ Perception of Transformational Leadership (EPTL) plays a moderator role in this model. Because of key role of EPTL in this model, 33 start-ups or changing organizations in Tehran, Alborz, Isfahan, and Azerbayjan Gharbi were studied, and questionnaires have distributed among 142 managers and 573 employees. The results of structural equations modeling (SEM) verified the relation of EPTL and developing the PsyCap of themselves. Considering to the results of this study, some implications and practical guides to the managers who want to develop PsyCap in their organizations will be offered.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_54088_c3eff9939ea180b52bace31d1f34f1a0.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2015.54088]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Evaluating the impact of social capital on employees’ creativity (Case study: electrical and electronic household appliances manufacturing companies in Iran)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Moazen Jamshidi, Mir Hadi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Haghparast Kenarsari, Narjes]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[creativity of employees]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Electronica and Electronic Household appliances Manufacturing Companies]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Organizations should consider innovation and creativity as an essential strategy in order to keep their existence in today complex and change able world. According to the importance of creativity and innovation, the aim of this paper is to improve organizations' performance by study the role of social capital on employees' creativity. The total target of this research is survey on the effect of social capital on employees' innovation. The type of present research is descriptive in the form of correlation and according to its aim is practical. The population of this project consists of all of the managers and experts who work in 4 electric and electronics household manufacturing companies in Iran. According to quato sampling method, 146 persons have been selected among this population. The questionnaire has been used for the collection of research data. In this research for studying of the hypothesis tests, the Partial least squares and (smart-pls) is used. the results of the research shows that the dimensions of social capital (social trust, network and common norm, mutual cooperative and cooperation, collective cohesion, empathy and participation, and collective identity has positive and significant effect on creativity of employees.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_54089_52bd3070235cf2707859a8aa4ee4aa20.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2015.54089]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Analysis of role of team cohesion in social capital (Professional Soccer Players in Fars Province)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Saberi, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bagheri, Ghodratollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bigharaz, Mohamad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Professional Athletes]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[team cohesion]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[General purpose of the present study was Analysis of Role of Team Cohesion in Social Capital between Professional Soccer Players. Statistical population was professional athletes having soccer contract in Fars. Regarding this issue that statistical population of the present study was restricted to professional soccer players from Shiraz, sample size was considered equal to population and census was used for sampling. Measuring instruments were team cohesion questionnaire (Karon) and social capital (Nahapit and Goushal). In a primary study Alpha Cronbach was used for stability so that stability coefficient for social capita was (89%) and team cohesion was 86%. sports management specialist's points of view was used to approve validity of questionnaire. For data analysis in descriptive statistical level (mean and standard deviation) and in conceptual level (correlation coefficient, regression, and variance analysis) were used. Gained data was analyzed through SPSS software and the result showed that there is a significant relationship between social capital and team cohesion and its dimensions, in addition it showed that team Cohesion is a good predictor for social capital.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_54093_48f139eb6cbaf9388e157411c04c43b4.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2015.54093]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Survey the relationship between communicational skill of managers and social capital of organization]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Yousefzadeh, Saeid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Kia Kojoori, Davood]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[cohesion]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cooperation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Norms]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[participation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[trust]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[s
The purpose of this study was to identify indicators of social capital and pursue their correlation to communicational skill of mangers. This descriptive-correlation study has an applied objective. The population is composed of all employees (243 individuals) of nonprofit organizations in Noor city. The total number of 85 individuals was selected in random sampling as the sample. In this study, to collect data in the field of theoretical and identify the components of social capital, the study of literature and interviews with professors, experts and scholars, as well as managers of the population studied was used. Then, the questionnaire was used to collect data to test hypotheses. Five indicators identified for social capital that includes: mutual trust, shared networks and norms, mutual cooperation, collective cohesion, voluntary participation. The results of research indicate that the relationship between communicational skill of managers and social capital is positive and significant. In addition, the strongest relationship between mutual trust and communicational skill were and weakest relationship between shared networks and norms and communicational skill were seen.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_54090_15475078bd2ff50cd85862a7ddf780b0.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2015.54090]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The effect of social capital on organizational citizenship behavior]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shamsi, Zahra]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Moehbalipour, Monire]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Allodari, Hassan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Municipality of Hamedan]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational Citizenship Behavior]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Considering the importance and necessity of efficient and capable manpower in achieving organizational goals, the aim of this study was to investigate the relationship between social capital and organizational citizenship behavior. This research uses descriptive– correlational questionnaire. These hypotheses are tested by a sample of 102 people in the municipality of Hamedan. Describing the demographic characteristics of respondents and regression testing was conducted by SPSS19. Multiple regression and correlation was used. Finding showed that social capital variable has the significant positive impact on organizational citizenship behavior. Also, the results showed that all three dimensions of social capital, structural, relational and cognitive and significant positive effect on organizational citizenship behavior.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_54091_83105b2dec2b129b964013380c68ba31.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2015.54091]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The effect of climate organizational on performance through social capital (Case Study: Municipal employees from five districts in Rasht)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Norouzi, Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[kameli, Alireza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Beigi, Roya]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohazabi, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational climate]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[organizational performance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Social capital can be considered within the framework of organizational performance improvement in infrastructural need. The study also examines the influence of social capital on the performance of the enterprise, to evaluate the relationship between the organizational climates organizational performance indirectly is paid. The study on a sample of 132 people from the five regions of the municipality's employees in Rasht is done. The research method is descriptive of the type of work and solidarity-to collect the data from the questionnaire has been used. Data analysis methods of structural equations modeling in software lissrel have been doing the study shows findings that organizational climate directly on social capital and organizational performance indirectly affect a significant positive effect. Social capital and direct positive impact on organizational performance is laid.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_54092_6e95588823d8467d9a6e8367387553b8.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2015.54092]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[English Abstracts]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_54638_bfcf46321f0d260c5751e2e0eb90004a.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>