<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>First Pages</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Social Capital Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>College of Farabi, University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2423-6071</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>4</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_70514_eb092b53c7dcc179a30c5b5daef57c79.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jscm.2018.70514</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Effect of Organizational Transparency on Organizational Trauma Management by Mediating Social Capital</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Deyhimpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Student, Faculty of Management, Payam-e Noor of University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Kamal</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Miandari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Faculty of Management, Payam-e Noor of University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Najjari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Faculty of Management, Payam-e Noor of University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abedi Jafari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Nowadays, organizations are vulnerable to various injuries as organizational trauma, and the need to manage these blows is a priority. Therefore, the present study aims to manage organizational trauma with emphasis on organizational transparency and social capital variables that are applied in terms of purpose and in terms of method, descriptive-survey is. The statistical population of the study consisted of 385 employees of governmental organizations of Chalus and Noshahr cities. They were selected using simple random sampling method and based on Morgan table, 191 individuals were selected. The data collection tool was a questionnaire whose reliability and validity were confirmed by Cronbach&#039;s alpha and combined reliability, and confirmed by professors and experts familiar with the subject. Data analysis was done by SPSS and LISREL software. The findings of structural equation modeling showed that all the paths from organizational transparency and social capital to management of psychological blows, as well as the path of organizational transparency through the intermediary variable of social capital on the management of mental stroke are significant and the relationship between them is confirmed and it can be concluded investment on social capital Along with organizational transparency, it can help manage organizational mental shocks.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Social Capital Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>College of Farabi, University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2423-6071</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>337</start>
					<end>363</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_68718_a6216b5b1d4192a8a6e14b7fc1e00c7d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jscm.2018.250257.1528</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Drawing a Supportive Framework for Creation of Social Startups in Accelerators</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Aidin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Salamzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. of Entrepreneurship, Faculty of Entrepreneurship, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Zahra</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Arasti</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Faculty of Entrepreneurship, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ghanbar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi Elyasi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Faculty of Entrepreneurship, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>By the advent of support mechanisms and due to their significant role in augmenting the failure rate of startups, today we are witnessing the exponential growth of startup accelerators around the Globe. But, unfortunately, the main approach of these accelerators is focused on economical and not social ideas. While a great number of social startups are able to solve fundamental problems and have high social impacts. In the one hand, there is not an integrated support framework for a typical social accelerator, and generally these entities render selective services. Thus, this research is conducted in order to draw a support framework for social accelerators according to different stages, and therefore seven social accelerators from different locations around the world are selected and studied. This research, which is a multiple case study, is an applied qualitative research- narrative research. The results revealed that visiting social businesses, and introducing social entrepreneurs at the “entry stage”, introduction to social problems, initial market building, legitimacy, and confidence building at the “pre acceleration and acceleration stages”, and legitimizing, absorbing the stakeholders, as well as obtaining the necessary permissions at the “exit stage” are of paramount importance, and are rarely emphasized in the extant literature.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Social Capital Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>College of Farabi, University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2423-6071</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>365</start>
					<end>384</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_68719_f260047e25a3a9a37ab69bcddc06aedd.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jscm.2018.252206.1550</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Study of the Relationship between Social Capital and Future Hope with the Apathy of the Youth; A Study of the City of Kermanshah</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Moradi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Sociology, Islamic Azad University, Eslam Abad-e-gharb. Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohsen</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Safarian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Instructor, Department of Sociology, Payam-e-Noor University, Kermanshah, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The present research seeks to identify and investigate the relationship between social capital and future hopes with the indifference of youth in Kermanshah. According to the theoretical paradigm dominating the research, a survey method and a questionnaire tool were used for the study. The statistical population of the 20-30 year old youths in Kermanshah, at the time of the research (1397), was 42017 people. 400 people were studied as a sample. Pearson correlation test, t-test and ANOVA were used to test the hypotheses and to measure the research model; multiple regression and path analysis were used. The results of this study show that among the independent variables such as social capital, hope for the future, income and residential type have a significant effect on the dependent variable (social indifference). The results of multivariate regression show that social capital variables and hope for the future managed to explain and predict 23% of the variation of the dependent variable in total. It can be inferred that with the increase of social capital and hope for the future, the level of social indifference of youth will be reduced In other words, social harm will decrease, and naturally the solidarity of individuals will increase and indifference will decrease. Therefore, the two variables can have a deterrent effect on social indifference.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Social Capital Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>College of Farabi, University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2423-6071</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>385</start>
					<end>410</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_68720_764bd7f1c7fad93106eda4559cc6bf8a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jscm.2018.265081.1677</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Drawing Structural Model for Explaining the Impact of Social Capital on Creativity of Employees with Emphasis on Knowledge Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abutaleb</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Motallebi Varkani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Faculty of Management, University of Imam Khomaini, Nowshahr, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sanaz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mazaheri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. of Educational Administration, Young Researchers and Elit Club, Roudehen Branch, Islamic Azad University, Roudehen, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aalipour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Faculty of Management, University of Imam Khomaini, Nowshahr, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The purpose of this study was to drawing structural model for explaining the impact of social capital on employee creativity in terms of the role of mediator of knowledge management. The method was applied for the purpose of the research and the method of data collection was descriptive-survey. The statistical population of the study consisted of 233 employees of Alzahra University, which was considered as the sample size of 146 people. The data were collected from three standard questionnaire social capital of Cheng and Chang (2011), Darche Knowledge Management (2003) and Torrance Creativity (1959). Data analysis was performed using AMOS20 software. The findings show that social capital has a positive impact on the creativity and knowledge management, and knowledge management has a positive impact on creativity. Also, in the impact of social capital on the creativity, knowledge management has a mediator role. According to the findings of the research, said that by increasing the trust and interpersonal relations as well as knowledge sharing, we can add to the creativity of the staff. Finally, a structural model derived from the relationship between social capital and creativity of employees with the role of mediator of knowledge management has been presented.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Social Capital Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>College of Farabi, University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2423-6071</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>411</start>
					<end>432</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_68721_c69a36e8a8ba3ee7b6ae68c653c5e554.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jscm.2018.259332.1623</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating and Analyzing the Capabilities of the Doctrine of Mahdism in Creating Social Capital</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Rouholla</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shakeri Zevardehi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, College of Farabi, University of Tehran, Qom, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Akram</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghorbani Qomi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Student, College of Farabi, University of Tehran, Qom, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Social capital is one of the most important assets of a society that helps individuals to achieve common goals and preserve society and solidarity. Mahdi Barouri, with its capacities and wide range of opportunities, can create, strengthen and strengthen the social capital of the expectations of society in the field of norms, values ​​and the structure of networks of relations among people of the society. One can mention the influence of this thought in the Shiite society, positive thinking and hope creation, activism, oppression, social solidarity, etc. According to the features of the Age of Advent, such as the lack of economic, social and ethnic discrimination, Security and. . . The modeling of these characteristics in the society of Mehdi Babe can influence the creation and strengthening of social capital in the absence of time.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Social Capital Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>College of Farabi, University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2423-6071</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>433</start>
					<end>455</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_68722_90e1efee0d2da223a896ec763fb48fcd.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jscm.2018.260235.1630</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Inefficient Governance of Water Resources and Strategic Insecurity</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sohrab</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Asgari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Geography, Faculty of Social Sciences, Payam-e- Noor University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahereh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kohnavard</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc. Student in Political Sciences, Faculty of Law and Political Sciences, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Masomeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hadavand</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc. Student in Geography, Department of Geography, Kharazmi University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>While Acquaintance of water resources and supply limitations are important bases for sustainable water management strategies, it’s believed that current issues in the country are outcome of miss governance in the water resources but not because of resources deficiencies. It is clear that water crisis can convert to a political dilemma and even demolish civilization, as water crisis in recent decades has led to huge migration to the cities, unplanned extension of urban areas, abnormal behaviors and generally has jeopardized national interests. The main aim of this research, which has been conducted in library method indicating documentary study, is to identify inefficient rules in the water resources managing. Results of this article indicate because of non-scientific approaches in using and maintenance of water resources in the country, water shortage is converting to water crisis meanwhile has affected political, economic and social bases of the country and continuation of this unpleasant trend will cause insecurity in the national scale.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Social Capital Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>College of Farabi, University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2423-6071</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>457</start>
					<end>477</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_68723_6d6de9903e1989f119b35170e8cf467f.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jscm.2018.266619.1694</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>English Abstracts</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Social Capital Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>College of Farabi, University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2423-6071</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>6</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_70513_16f0d27e45ecbada70ddc5332b711257.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jscm.2018.70513</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>