<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Functions, Methods and Obstacles Patterning of Social Ethics of the Prophet</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کارکردها، روش‌ها و موانع الگوگیری از اخلاق اجتماعی نبوی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>159</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>180</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63605</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2017.231505.1359</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسلم</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمودی خورندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌ارشد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The most effective natural forces of mankind that can help him in the ascension to human perfection is the desire for &quot;modeling&quot;, which in the present study, argued this principle of human influence according to the social life of the prophet of Islam (PBUH).Since the three sides of modeling are: the functions, methods, and barriers, the research in the present case, without diminishing one another, has drawn these three fundamental principles into research and analysis. Therefore, the first functions of the pattern of the Prophet (PBUH), that is, from the introduction of the ultimate goal to individuals, the sacrament of morality, the guarantee of the implementation of ethical principles, the mental persuasion of followers, followed by modeling methods such as: modeling based on values, (PBUH) and modeling and ... Finally, the obstacles and damages are transcendental description, obscure ambiguous processing, historical look and devotion have been analyzed and analyzed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">از مؤثرترین نیروهای فطری آدمی که می‌تواند او را در صعود به کمال انسانی کمک کند، میل به «الگوپذیری» است. تحقیق حاضر، این اصل تأثیرگذار بشری را بنا بر زندگی اجتماعی شخص پیامبر اسلام (ص) تبیین و استدلال کرده است. از آنجا که اضلاع سه‌گانة الگوسازی عبارت‌اند از کارکردها، روش‌ها و موانع، تحقیق پیش‌رو به صورت موردپژوهانه و بدون فروکاستن یکی به دیگری، این سه اصل مهم و بنیادین را تحقیق و تحلیل کرده است. از این رو، ابتدا کارکردهای الگوبودن پیامبر (ص) که عبارت‌اند از معرفی هدف غایی به افراد، قداست‌بخشی به اخلاق، ضمانت اجرایی اصول اخلاقی، اقناع ذهنی پیروان، در ادامه روش‌های الگوسازی مانند الگوسازی بر پایة ارزش‌ها، شناخت سیرة پیامبر (ص) و مدل‌سازی و جز آن، و در نهایت، موانع و آسیب‌های فرارو: توصیف فرابشری، پردازش مبهمم نامفهوم، نگاه تاریخی و تقدس‌زدایی بررسی و تحلیل شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اخلاق اجتماعی نبوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارکردها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">موانع</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63605_367adb3c54921aa9c9c936420f8e4780.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
