<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Relationship between Social Capital and Law-aversion; Sociological Explanation</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطۀ سرمایۀ اجتماعی با قانون‌گریزی؛ تبیینی جامعه‌شناختی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>265</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>282</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63607</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2017.235786.1393</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیاوش</FirstName>
					<LastName>خدایاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدة تحصیلات تکمیلی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد دهاقان، دهاقان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اسماعیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>جهانبخش</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار جامعه‌شناسی، دانشکدة تحصیلات تکمیلی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد دهاقان، دهاقان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منصور</FirstName>
					<LastName>حقیقتیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، دانشکدة تحصیلات تکمیلی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد دهاقان، دهاقان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This research aims to investigate the relationship between social capital (Bonding and Bridging) with the law-aversion (subjective and objective) was conducted. And its boundary is the entire province of Ilam. Method: This research is a descriptive study and a tool for collecting information from this questionnaire. The statistical population of the study consisted of all citizens over 18 years old in 1395. The sampling method was a multi-stage cluster, and a sample size of 384 was determined based on Morgan&#039;s table. Data were analyzed using SPSS and Amos software and correlation test. Results: The results of the research indicate that there is a positive relationship and meaningful between Bonding social capital with subjective and objective law-aversion and Bridging social capital of weak with subjective and objective law-aversion there. The results of the structural equation model test show that the Bonding social capital variable explains 68% of the variance of the dependent variable in the society, and the Bridging social capital predicts the variance of 92% variance of the dependent variable of the law-aversion in society. According to the findings of this research, the factors affecting the law-aversion in Ilam province are the erosion of Bridging capital and the overcoming of social capital bonding.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این تحقیق با هدف بررسی رابطة سرمایة اجتماعی (درون و برون‌گروهی) با قانون‌گریزی (ذهنی و عینی) انجام گرفته و محدودۀ آن، کل استان ایلام است.تحقیق حاضر از نوع کاربردی و به روش توصیفی - همبستگی انجام گرفته است. ابزار گردآوری اطلاعات پرسشنامه بود. جامعة آماری تحقیق شامل همة شهروندان بالای 18 سال در سال 1395 بود. براساس جدول مورگان، 384 نفر به روش خوشه‌ای چندمرحله‌ای انتخاب شدند. داده‌ها با نرم‌افزارهای SPSS و Amos تحلیل شد. نتایج پژوهش نشان داد بین سرمایة اجتماعی درون‌گروهی قوی با قانون‌گریزی ذهنی و عینی، و سرمایة اجتماعی برون‌گروهی ضعیف با قانون‌گریزی ذهنی و عینی رابطة مثبت و معنادار وجود دارد. نتایج مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری نشان داد متغیر سرمایة اجتماعی درون‌گروهی و سرمایة اجتماعی برون‌گروهی در مجموع، 89 درصد از واریانس قانون‌گریزی ذهنی و 45 درصد از واریانس قانون‌گریزی عینی را تبیین می‌کنند. با توجه به یافته‌های تحقیق، از عوامل مؤثر بر قانون‌گریزی در استان ایلام فرسایش سرمایة اجتماعی برون‌گروهی و غلبة سرمایة اجتماعی درون‌گروهی است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی برون‌گروهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی درون‌گروهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قانون‌گریزی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63607_98b14896178b7ef46c390673f38b2c47.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
