<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[First Pages]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_65084_cc1533caf2f9569e82e2cf9a7b26ba96.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2017.65084]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the Dimensions of Social Capital and Its Relation to Moral Marketing (Case: Sepah Bank Branches of Qom Province)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Jandaghi, Gholamreza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghoreishi, Seyed Mahdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ahadi Shoar, Seyed Majid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ethics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Marketing ethics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Marketing]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Social capital refers to links and connections among members of a network as a source of value, which serves the purposes of the members by creating the norms and mutual trust. Also ethical marketing is seeking for honest and true presentation of a product, in the field of customer's desired cultural and social values. This research aims to investigate the dimensions of social capital and their impact on ethical marketing among employees of Sepah Bank Branches in Qom. The present study is of applicable type, a descriptive-correlative method. The statistical population of this study was composed of all 227 employees of Sepah Bank Branchs in Qom Province. The random simple sampling method was used and the sample size was estimated to be 143 by Cochran formula. The research instrument was a questionnaire whose validity was confirmed by experts and its reliability was confirmed by Cronbach's alpha coefficient. The data were analyzed by correlation test. The results showed that there is a positive and significant relationship between social capital (and its dimensions) and ethical marketing.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_64694_6f5d62135ee6df7ce60310abcbad5dd8.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2018.136506.1133]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[An Analysis of the Position and Level of Social Responsibility in Tourism Industry (Case: Yazd Cultural Heritage Organization)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shafiee, Meysam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Asadi, Mir Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohammad Mirzaei, Negar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Corporate social responsibility]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cultural Heritage Organization]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[tourism industry]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The importance of social responsibility is rising and has found a great role in tourism industry. One of the reasons for growing development of the tourism industry in different societies is the importance of this industry in the global economy. Therefore, allocation of resources in this field is not considered as cost, but investment to gain competitive advantage. The purpose of this article is to investigate the level and importance of social responsibility of Tourism Organization and Yazd Cultural Heritage as governmental institutions in tourism sector. Collecting data is based on questionnaire. 300 questionnaires were distributed among tourism activists and experts in Yazd in this research. Content validity of the questionnaire was verified by using the convergent and divergent validity of PLS ​​and by Cronbach's alpha, the validity of the questionnaire was confirmed. The current research is descriptive and has a survey method. Data were analyzed by structural equation modeling approach based on partial least squares method using Smart PLS and SPSS software. The results show that the concept of social responsibility in the tourism industry can accelerate the growth of this industry. However, social responsibility in the organization has not been introduced and discussed as a strategy.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63207_45ba2aebb3817b7fc679416749edbe5c.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2017.227378.1303]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Measuring the Monetary Value of Social Capital in Tehran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ebrahimi Salari, Taghi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Salehnia, Nafiseh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Connectedness]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Monetary Value]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[trust]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Welfare function]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Calculating the monetary value of social capital give decision makers the opportunity to expand and strengthen dimensions that are more valuable to the people. The purpose of this study was to estimate the monetary value of social capital in Tehran. In order to this, social capital questionnaire was distributed between 345 people then by having capita income annual per households an estimated Probity model was estimated using STATA13. To estimate the parameters, use eight regression models, and after estimating the welfare function, the monetary value of social capital using the shadow price model was estimated in two steps.The results show that on average a one standard deviation increase in interpersonal-trust is worth an extra 7000000, in people’s-fairness 2000000, institutional-trust 16000000, and in Trustworthiness is 3000000 Rail per year in terms of foregone income. In the field of informal participation and Meeting-people has been worth an extra 1500000 and 4000000 Rail respectively. The findings indicate that social capital has significant monetary value to individuals. This should be considered when designing government policies aiming at e.g., labor market mobility that are accompanied by a decreasing social capital stock that, in turn, may negatively affect economic and political development.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_64610_7668d80145dac4aacdae27faee3d729f.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2018.244984.1480]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Role of social capital in promoting sense of place (Case: rural areas in Zaboul County)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sharifzadeh, Mohammad Sharif]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Abdollahzadeh, Gholam Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Azhdarpour, Ali Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sharifi, Mehnoosh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Emotional Ecosystem]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rural Households]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sense of Place]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sustainable Habitation]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This research aimed to investigate role of social capital in promoting sense of place and identify influencing factors on sense of place among rural people. This research was done by using questionnaire survey. The target population includes 26010 of rural people in Zabol County in which 310 people (heads of rural households) selected as samples of this research. The multi-stage cluster sampling technique with appropriate allocation among eight villages was used to select samples. The face and content validity of questionnaire as research tool was verified using comments of faculty members and local experts and its reliability was confirmed according to Cronbach's alpha coefficient which calculated for several scales of the questionnaire, including: sense of place (0.91), social capital (0.81) and life satisfaction (0.93). Results showed that the sense of place of 27 %of respondents was measured at high level, 49% at mediate level and 24% at low level. According to correlation coefficient, there is a significant relationship between social capital and sense of place of respondents. The results of path analysis showed that “social capital” (with path coefficient 0.268) have most impact on final dependent variable, sense of place. Some variables such “occupation situation (0.249)” “education (-0.216)”, “receiving social services (0.207)”, “experience of membership in local institutions (0.197)”, “years of residence in village (0.308)”, “immigration of family members (-0.188)”, and “life satisfaction (0.156)” are in next rank. Overall, according to the research findings, using participatory approach to promote social capital and to enhance integrated community development could be led to increase sense of place and sustainable settlement in the rural areas of Zabol County.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_59966_218d9fab38554edb0b5436c74309ee43.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2016.59966]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Study of the effect of Organizational Culture on Social Capital with the Mediating Role of Professional Ethics in Department of Transportation in Sari]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Emamgholizadeh, Saeed]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Fallahpour, Farhad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ranjbar, Kooshan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational Culture]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Professional Ethics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[trust]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Recently, the concept of organizational culture and social capital is important in society, and observing these concepts is a competitive advantage. Therefore, the purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of organizational culture on social capital with the mediating role of professional ethics in Department of Transportation in Sari. The research type is applied using descriptive-correlational method and correlation. The statistical population is all employees of the transportation department of Sari city which number is 110. 82 people were selected as sample size by Krejcie and Morgan table and simple random sampling method. The tool for gathering information is the Standard Questionnaire of "Cadozir's" Professional Ethics, the standard questionnaire of "Denison's" Organizational Culture, and the standard questionnaire of "Nahapiet and Ghosal's" Social Capital. Data analysis was carried out by using Structural Equation Model (SEM) with the help of PLS ​​software. The results of the research show that Professional Ethics plays a positive and significant mediator role on the effect of Organizational Culture on Social Capital]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_64609_f70a53d8bbadc17d288cc168e57d325e.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2018.241515.1453]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Comparative Analysis of Formal and Informal Researcher's Network (Case: Tourism Research Institute)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Majdi, Aliakbar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Massoudi, Hamid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sadeghinejad, Mahsa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Corporate communications]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Formal organizational relationships]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Informal organizational relationships]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[social networks]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The aim of this study is a comparative analysis of formal and informal researcher's network in Tourism Research Institute. A questionnaire was designed and sample size in this study has been 19 researchers. The formal part dimensions are production and publication of scientific papers, workshops, research project and informal dimensions are travel and solving the problems. Research method is Network analysis and data has been analyze using UCINET 6. The results showed the density of formal relationships network is 20%, and the density of informal relationships network is 55%. Two networks have significant differences in the popularity of social, social cohesion, social relations, social distance and social influence.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_64781_b3dcae1cd3623e095e77d6d33f8064b5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2018.240512.1444]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the Relationship between Social Capital and Environmental Behaviors of Students in University of Birjand]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bakhshi, Mohammad Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Pirdadeh Bayranvand, Kobra]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Falaki, Malihe]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Environmental Behavior]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[environment]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social Action]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[A significant part of the environmental problems and risks is due to individual and collective irresponsible behaviors of the community. The main objective of this study was to investigate the influence of social capital and its dimensions on the environmental responsible behaviors of Student at the Faculties of Agriculture, Natural Resources and Environment. The current study is applied in purpose and analytical in nature, used descriptive –correlational method along with a survey approach. The statistical population consisted of students of three educational level includes undergraduate, graduate and doctoral in colleges of Agriculture, Natural Resources and Environment at the University of Birjand that 125 as sample were selected using Cochran formula and multi-stage random sampling method. The data collection instrument was a researcher made questionnaire that it’s validity by professors and experts and its reliability through the pre-test and Cronbach's alpha was confirmed. The results showed: Firstly, the social capital of students is moderate. Secondly, the level of environmental responsible behaviors of students is undesirable and slightly higher than average. In addition, results showed a positive and direct relationship between social capital and environmental behaviors of students. Two dimensions of social capital, social cohesion and social participation have a stronger correlation with environmental behaviors of students.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_64820_738a01d302954880f47e1d54efc2a185.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2018.239044.1432]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[English Abstracts]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[College of Farabi, University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_65083_a2777e7e38ff7799c80e4ef91b474c14.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jscm.2017.65083]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Social Capital Management]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>