<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Religiousness and its Effects on the Social Capital of Family (A Case Study of Qom)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>دینداری و تأثیر آن در سرمایة اجتماعی خانواده (مورد مطالعه: خانواده‌های ساکن شهر قم)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>435</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>452</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56532</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2015.56532</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>سلیمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی پژوهشگاه علوم اسلامی امام صادق (ع)، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>باقی نصرآبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، پژوهشگاه علوم اسلامی امام صادق (ع)، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>فاضل</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تهران مرکز، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present research seeks to investigate the effects of religiousness on the social capital of families residing in Qom. It is an applied kind of research conducted through using documentary and survey methods. The statistical population has been 160565 households living in Qom. Based on Cochran&#039;s formula, the sample size was determined to be 376 households which finally it was decided to be 400 people, who were chosen from four districts of Qom using cluster sampling. Data were collected through questionnaires and interviews. The Alpha of all questions of the questionnaire was 0.72 (which shows its consistency and reliability). The results showed that the social capital of 65.50 percent of families was high, of 33 percent of them it was average, and it was low for 0.5 percent of them. Independent variables, i.e. religiousness and socioeconomic status, had increasing effect on the social capital of families. The rise and fall of social capital in families was influenced by external and social factors; since social and environmental changes influenced smaller structures like families. The role of religious institutions and organizations, friends, and selected and religious exemplars are highly important in preventing the reduction of the social capital of families.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر در پی بررسی تأثیر دینداری در سرمایة اجتماعی خانواده‌های ساکن شهر قم است. تحقیق از نوع کاربردی است که به روش اسنادی و پیمایشی انجام گرفته است. جامعة آماری، خانواده‌های ساکن قم به تعداد 160565 خانوار بوده است. حجم نمونة انتخابی بر اساس فرمول کوکران 376 خانوار به دست آمد. در نهایت، 400 خانوار با روش خوشه‌ای از چهار منطقة شهر قم انتخاب شدند. اطلاعات مورد نیاز این پژوهش با به‌‎کارگیری پرسشنامة محقق‌ساخته جمع‌آوری شد. میزان آلفای کل سؤال‌های پرسشنامه 72&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 به دست آمد که نشان‌دهندة ثبات و قابلیت اعتماد ابزار تحقیق است. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد سرمایة اجتماعی 5&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;65 درصد از خانواده‌ها بالا، 33 درصد متوسط و 5&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 درصد پایین بوده است. متغیرهای مستقل، دین‌داری، و پایگاه اجتماعی - اقتصادی در سرمایة اجتماعی خانواده تأثیر زیادی داشتند. فراز­ و فرود سرمایة اجتماعی در خانواده بیشتر متأثر از عوامل برون­خانوادگی و اجتماعی است، زیرا تغییرات اجتماعی و محیطی بر ساخت‌های کوچکتر، از جمله خانواده مؤثر بوده­اند. برای جلوگیری از کاهش سرمایة اجتماعی خانواده، نقش مراکز و نهادهای دینی و هیئت­های مذهبی، دوستان و الگوهای انتخابی و مذهبی اهمیت دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتماد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دینداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خانواده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایة اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشارکت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_56532_ba2921779b4bc02c278c6f0e64a981b6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
