<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analysis of role of team cohesion in social capital (Professional Soccer Players in Fars Province)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی نقش انسجام گروهی در سرمایۀ اجتماعی (مورد مطالعه: بازیکنان حرفه ای فوتبال استان فارس)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>75</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>94</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54093</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2015.54093</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>صابری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>قدرت الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>باقری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکدۀ مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>بی غرض</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>General purpose of the present study was Analysis of Role of Team Cohesion in Social Capital between Professional Soccer Players. Statistical population was professional athletes having soccer contract in Fars. Regarding this issue that statistical population of the present study was restricted to professional soccer players from Shiraz, sample size was considered equal to population and census was used for sampling. Measuring instruments were team cohesion questionnaire (Karon) and social capital (Nahapit and Goushal). In a primary study Alpha Cronbach was used for stability so that stability coefficient for social capita was (89%) and team cohesion was 86%. sports management specialist&#039;s points of view was used to approve validity of questionnaire. For data analysis in descriptive statistical level (mean and standard deviation) and in conceptual level (correlation coefficient, regression, and variance analysis) were used. Gained data was analyzed through SPSS software and the result showed that there is a significant relationship between social capital and team cohesion and its dimensions, in addition it showed that team Cohesion is a good predictor for social capital.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف کلی این تحقیق، بررسی نقش انسجام گروهی در سرمایۀ اجتماعی بین ورزشکاران حرفه‌ای فوتبال بود. روش تحقیق، توصیفی و از نوع هم‌بستگی بود. جامعۀ آماری، ورزشکاران حرفه‌ای فوتبال در استان فارس بودند که قرارداد داشتند. با توجه به اینکه جامعۀ آماری (78=N) این تحقیق به فوتبالیست‌های حرفه‌ای شیراز محدود بود، حجم نمونه برابر با جامعه در نظر گرفته شده و از روش نمونه‌گیری سرشماری استفاده شد. ابزار اندازه‌گیری، پرسش‌نامه‌های انسجام گروهی (کارون) و سرمایۀ اجتماعی (ناهاپیت و گوشال) بود. برای پایایی پرسش‌نامه‌ها، در مطالعه‌ای مقدماتی از روش آلفای کرونباخ استفاده شد. ضریب پایایی به‌دست‌آمده برای سرمایۀ اجتماعی 89/0 و برای انسجام گروهی 86/0 بود. برای تأیید روایی پرسش‌نامه نیز از نظر متخصصان مدیریت ورزشی استفاده شد. به‌منظور تجزیه‌وتحلیل اطلاعات در دو سطح آمار توصیفی (میانگین و انحراف استاندارد) و استنباطی (ضریب هم‌بستگی، رگرسیون و آنالیز واریانس) استفاده شد. نتایج با نرم‌افزار spss تجزیه‌وتحلیل شد و نشان داد بین سرمایۀ اجتماعی و انسجام گروهی و ابعاد آن، رابطۀ معناداری وجود دارد و انسجام گروهی، پیش‌بینی‌کنندۀ خوبی برای سرمایۀ اجتماعی است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انسجام گروهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایۀ اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ورزشکاران حرفه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_54093_48f139eb6cbaf9388e157411c04c43b4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
