<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>13</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Alturism and Social Capital: A Quranic approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سرمایه‌ی اجتماعی و ایثار: رویکردی قرآنی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">77040</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2020.287920.2018</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>ردادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیأت علمی پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و اندیشه اسلامی</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6797-6871</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Social capital is one of the concepts used in the social sciences to describe solidarity and trust in society. The existence of social capital facilitates many social connections. In this article, an attempt is made to discuss the relationship between social capital and altruism. The main question of the article is &quot;How can social capital help strengthen altruism in society?&quot; This article first divides altruism into &quot;cognitive&quot; and &quot;behavioral&quot; levels. Then, an attempt is made to present an Islamic model of social capital that is cognitively related to altruism. The religious model of social capital that increases altruism in society is: &quot;The pervasiveness of social trust based on faith in God, by the norm of passing over what you love and need, in the Brotherhood network.&quot; This social capital can spread altruism in society and pave the way for altruism behaviors in society. The research method in this paper is conceptual analysis.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سرمایه‌ی اجتماعی از جمله مفاهیمی است که در علوم اجتماعی برای توصیف همبستگی و اعتماد در جامعه به کار گرفته شده است. وجود سرمایه‌ی اجتماعی بسیاری از ارتباطهای اجتماعی را تسهیل می‌کند.  در این نوشتار تلاش می‌شود ارتباط سرمایه‌ی اجتماعی در ایجاد ایثار مورد بحث و بررسی قرار گیرد. سوال اصلی مقاله این است که «سرمایه‌ی اجتماعی چگونه می‌تواند به تقویت ایثار در جامعه کمک کند؟» با بهره‌گیری از آیات شریفه‌ی قرآن کریم، الگویی از سرمایه‌ی اجتماعی ارائه می‌گردد که باعث افزایش ایثار در جامعه گردد. مدل دینی سرمایه‌ی اجتماعی که باعث افزایش ایثار در جامعه می شود عبارت است از: «فراگیر شدن اعتماد اجتماعی متکی به ایمان به خدا، به وسیله‌ی هنجارِ گذشتن از آنچه دوست دارید و به آن نیاز دارید، در شبکه اخوت». این سرمایه‌ی اجتماعی می‌تواند ایثار را در جامعه گسترش دهد و زمینه‌ساز رفتارهای ایثارگرانه در جامعه باشد. روش تحقیق در این مقاله، تحلیل مفهومی است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایثار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مطالعات قرآنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاستگذاری اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
