<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study of the Effect of Social Capital on Innovation
Emphasize on Mediation Role of Knowledge Management</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی و تبیین تأثیر سرمایه اجتماعی بر نوآوری با تأکید بر نقش میانجی مدیریت دانش</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>20</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53270</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2014.53270</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>روح الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>استاک</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری جامعه‌شناسی فرهنگی، دانشگاه آزاد، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جمال</FirstName>
					<LastName>عبدالملکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری برنامه‌ریزی درسی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The objective of the paper is to design, arrange, and evaluate the causal model of creativity and innovation emphasizing the mediating role of knowledge management: analyzing the relations of organizational culture and social capital with knowledge management and the relations of knowledge management with creativity and innovation in educational offices staff in Kurdistan Province. All staff of the educational offices is the population of the sampling in the study from which we selected a sample of 275 practitioners using class-random method. In order to measure the variables, we used some questionnaires including organizational culture, social capital, knowledge management, creativity, and innovation, the results of the study indicate that organizational culture variable, at a level of 0.01, have a significant positive impact on social capital and knowledge management variables. Variables organizational culture and social capital have the significant positive impact on knowledge management, at 0.01. Knowledge management variable have the significant positive impact, at 0.01, on creativity and innovation variables. Creativity variable have the same impact at the same level on innovation variable. Creativity and innovation model emphasizing the mediating role of Knowledge management variable, have a proper fitting.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از مقاله حاضر طراحی، تدوین و ارزیابی مدل علّی خلاقیت و نوآوری با تأکید بر نقش واسطه‌‌ای مدیریت دانش و تحلیل روابط فرهنگ سازمانی و سرمایه اجتماعی با مدیریت دانش و رابطه مدیریت دانش با خلاقیت و نوآوری است. جامعه پژوهش همه کارکنان ادارات آموزش و پرورش استان کردستان می‌باشد که از این جامعه نمونه‌‌ای به حجم 278 کارمند با شیوه تصادفی – طبقه‌‌ای انتخاب شدند. این تحقیق از نظر هدف کاربردی، و از نظر نحوه گردآوری داده‌ها، توصیفی و از نوع همبستگی و به روش مدل‌یابی معادلات ساختاری است. جهت سنجش متغیرها پرسشنامه‌های فرهنگ سازمانی دنیسون، سرمایه اجتماعی، مدیریت دانش، خلاقیت و نوآوری به‌کار گرفته شده است. نتایج نشان می‌دهد فرهنگ سازمانی اثر مثبت و معنادار بر سرمایه اجتماعی و مدیریت دانش دارد. همچنین، فرهنگ سازمانی و سرمایه اجتماعی اثر مثبت و معنادار بر مدیریت دانش دارند و مدیریت دانش اثر مثبت و معنادار بر خلاقیت و نوآوری دارد. از سوی دیگر، نتایج نشان داد خلاقیت بر نوآوری اثر مثبت و معنادار دارد. بنابراین، مدل علّی خلاقیت و نوآوری با تأکید بر نقش واسطه‌‌ای متغیر مدیریت دانش تأیید می‌شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خلاقیت و نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دانش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_53270_705c6773029ddf0e0cda98ab4f4dab10.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
