<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>National Security in the Noble Quran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>امنیت ملی در قرآن کریم</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>375</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>394</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">72018</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2019.266434.1692</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدهادی</FirstName>
					<LastName>کاویانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری حقوق عمومی و مدرس پردیس فارابی، دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>National security is a multidimensional issue, and the responsibility of governments to provide these services to citizens, as well as their abuse of this issue, has added to its complexity in consolidating its political position. In the simplest definition of national security, it is the security of people who are governed by a legal system in a particular geography. Naturally, the security of this social environment is needed and the dangers that threaten the existence of this issue must be eliminated. According to the national security theory, this threat elimination includes security, political, social, economic and environmental threats. According to this theory, the threats whose elimination is suggested in the Quran for the purpose of achieving national security in those days are only social and economic threats. The military threat that could destroy the intended community of the Quran, i.e. Mecca, was removed through the divine miracle of the Flights of Birds, and the political threat posed by the primitive nature of that society and the lack of a consolidated government was not a threat, even with the criteria of the states of that era. The environmental threat was essentially non-existent.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امنیت ملی موضوعی است که چندبُعدی بودن آن و مسئولیت دولت‌ها در فراهم آوردن آن برای شهروندان، نیز، سوء‌استفادة آن‌ها از این موضوع برای تحکیم موقعیت سیاسی خود بر پیچیدگی مفهومی و مصداقی آن می‌افزاید. در ساده‌ترین تعریف، امنیت ملی امنیت مردمی است که در جغرافیایی خاص تحت حاکمیت نظمی سیاسی ـ حقوقی می‌زیند. طبعاً امنیت این زیست اجتماعی اقتضا می‌کند تهدیدهایی که موجودیت این موضوع را به خطر می‌اندازند دفع شود. بر اساس نظریة امنیت ملی، برای تحقق این امنیت باید تهدیدهای پنجگانة نظامی، سیاسی، اجتماعی، اقتصادی، و زیست‌محیطی منتفی شود. بر مبنای این نظریه، تهدیدهایی که نفی آن‌ها در قرآن برای برای تحقق امنیت ملی در جامعة آن روزگار مورد توجه قرار گرفته فقط تهدیدهای اجتماعی و اقتصادی است. تهدید نظامی، که موجودیت جامعة مورد نظر قرآن، یعنی مکه، را به خطر می‌انداخت با معجزة الهی ابابیل منتفی شد و تهدید سیاسی به دلیل بدوی بودن آن جامعه و عدم‌حضور دولتی منسجم، حتی با کارویژه‌های دولت‌های موجود در آن روزگار، ممکن نیست تهدید زیست‌محیطی نیز موضوعاً منتفی است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">امنیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">امنیت ملی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تهدید</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قرآن</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_72018_98b543311f0a88905a5ec777b4a6b03a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
