<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Ethical Leadership and its Impact on Social Capital in Service Public Organizations (Case: Tehran Central Instruments and Landed Property Registration Department)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رهبری اخلاقی و تأثیر آن بر سرمایۀ اجتماعی در سازمان‌های خدماتی دولتی (مورد مطالعه: سازمان ثبت اسناد و املاک تهران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>245</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>264</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63702</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2017.236070.1399</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>عبدالشاه</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مهندسی صنایع، واحد سمنان، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>مقیمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس‌‌ارشد MBA، دانشکدۀ مهندسی مواد و صنایع، دانشگاه سمنان، سمنان، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7894-4704</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید امیرمحمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>خطیبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، دانشکدۀ علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Ethics is an issue that recently a lot of attention is surrounding social capital. The goal of this study is investigate the role of ethical leadership in the production of social capital in service public organizations on Instruments and Landed Property Registration Department. The sample size of this study is 202 persons of Tehran Central’s staff. Instruments are included two specialized questionnaires (social capital and ethical leadership). To analyze the data is used SPSS.22 and PLS. Using structural equation modeling technique, the results showed significant impact of ethical leadership on all three dimensions of social capital (structural dimension, relational dimension, cognitive dimension). This means that using ethical leadership can image a common future for organizational members that create unification between them. Finally, this unification leads members to constructive engagement which is also a win-win relationship among.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;یکی از موضوعات مهمی که اخیراً پیرامون سرمایة اجتماعی به آن توجه زیادی می‌شود، اخلاق است. به همین منظور، هدف این پژوهش مطالعة تجربی تأثیر رهبری اخلاقی بر تولید سرمایة اجتماعی در سازمان‌های دولتی با مطالعة سازمان ثبت اسناد و املاک است. پژوهش حاضر از نوع کاربردی و به روش توصیفی- همبستگی اجرا شد. نمونة این تحقیق 202 نفر از کارمندان ثبت اسناد شهر تهران بود. ابزار پژوهش دو پرسشنامة تخصصی (سرمایة اجتماعی و رهبری اخلاقی) بود. با به‌کارگیری تکنیک مدلسازی معادلات ساختاری، نتایج حاکی از تأثیر رهبری اخلاقی بر هر سه بعد سرمایة اجتماعی (بعد ساختاری، بعد ارتباطی و بعد شناختی) است. نتایج تحلیل داده‌ها نشان داد نقش رهبری اخلاقی بر تولید سرمایه‌های اجتماعی در سازمان‌های دولتی معنادار است، بدان معنا که با به‌کارگیری رهبری اخلاقی می‌توان برای اعضای سازمان آیندة مشترکی متصور شد که سبب ایجاد وحدت میان اعضای سازمان خواهد شد. این وحدت سرانجام به تعامل سازنده و آن هم به رابطه‌ای برد - برد میان اعضا می‌انجامد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بعد رابطه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بعد ساختاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بعد شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری اخلاقی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63702_41bd1cd00c5b148e6abcdcd65ed28260.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
