<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مجله علمی "مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی"</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2423-6071</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Modeling the Influencing Factors on Social Responsibility of National Iranian Oil Company</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدل عوامل مؤثر بر مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکت ملی نفت ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>181</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>197</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63670</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jscm.2017.244498.1472</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فیاضی آزاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت دولتی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحمتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>خنیفر</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، قم، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>According to the goal of this research,designing a model of influencing factors on social responsibility of National Iranian Oil Company, first of all, the dimensions and the influencing factors on social responsibility of NIOC is determined by studying the documents and literature study, survey by questionnaire and interview of 29 people in elite group. Meanwhile, Delphi method is used in two stages to obtain the most important dimensions and influencing factors. Based on the conceptual model and for collecting the data, the questionnaire which is prepared by the researcher was sent for 385 of managers and senior experts of NIOC with high reliability and validity. In this stage the Snowballing sampling was used. The data analysis process is done by theme method and structural equation modeling (Amos software). According to the results of the analyzing the questionnaires’ data, it has been specified that the beliefs and awareness of managers, training employees, environmental protection, competition, employees’ knowledge, community relations and control are the factors which are influence on the social responsibility which is consist of transparency, accountability, Observe ethical-social codes, considering the stakeholders benefits, rules and laws in this regard).</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف مقالة حاضر طراحی مدل عوامل مؤثر بر مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکت ملی نفت ایران است. به‌منظور تحقق این هدف، ابتدا ابعاد مفهوم مسئولیت اجتماعی و عوامل مؤثر بر آن در شرکت ملی نفت ایران از طریق مصاحبه، مطالعات کتابخانه‌ای و فیش‌برداری و تحلیل تم، استخراج شد. سپس، با به‌کارگیری روش دلفی و بهره‌گیری از نظرهای 29 نفر از خبرگان آشنا به موضوع تحقیق، مهم‌ترین ابعاد مسئولیت اجتماعی و عوامل مؤثر بر آن در شرکت نفت شناسایی شد. در مرحلة بعد، پس از تعیین حجم نمونه براساس جدول مورگان و روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی ساده، 385 نفر از کارشناسان ارشد و مدیران شرکت نفت ایران انتخاب شدند و ابعاد و عوامل شناسایی‌شده در قالب پرسشنامه‌ای در اختیار آن‌ها قرار گرفت. داده‌ها با روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری تجزیه‌وتحلیل شد. در نهایت، مدل عوامل مؤثر بر مسئولیت اجتماعی شرکت نفت شامل 12 متغیر، در دو بخش ابعاد مسئولیت اجتماعی (شامل پاسخگویی، رعایت اصول اخلاقی- اجتماعی، قوانین تدوین‌شده، شفافیت، حفظ منافع ذی‎نفعان) و نیز عوامل مؤثر بر آن (شامل آگاهی و باور مدیران ارشد، آموزش، دانش، توجه به رقابت، حفظ محیط زیست، کنترل و ارتباطات) طراحی شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پاسخگویی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حفظ منافع ذی‎نفعان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رعایت اصول اخلاقی- اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شفافیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قوانین</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_63670_b3237cb8935714fa902b8d25de97e84c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
