<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Investigation of Faculty Employment Measures of Iran's Ministry of Science, Research and Technology Public Universities, Worldwide Public Universities, and Former Educational System of Qom Shia Seminary</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">hadi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mosadegh</namePart>
				<affiliation>دکترای مدیریت آموزشی و کارشناس سابق مرکز جذب وزارت علوم ؛ پژوهشگر پژوهشکده سیاست پژوهی و مطالعات راهبردی حکمت</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">hasan reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zinabadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه خوارزمی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohammad reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Behrangi</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه خوارزمی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">bijan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abdollahi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه خوارزمی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Investigation of faculty employment measures of Iran&#039;s ministry of science, research and technology public universities, worldwide public universities, and former educational system of Qom Shia seminary. Hence, three research questions deal with to: 1. investigating of the current domestic measures of ministry 2.investigating due measures of other universities all around the world, and 3.cognitification of employment measures in former educational system of Qom Shia seminary.Method: Paper methodologically relies on library studies and the approach phenomenography via quasi structural interviews. The face validity and content validity of the interview questions have assessed by specialists and for reliability has used test-retest reliability (94%) and inter coder reliability (%79). The population of interview was all experts of Qom Shia seminary. These individuals were purposefully selected and interviewed. The interviews were recorded, typed, coded, and analysed. Results: Our document studies produced 73 appropriate measures, and qualitative studies have identified 38 appropriate measures from the expert point. Conclusions: We have compared the measures of process of various countries, Qom Shia seminary with process of ministry of science, and proposed some appropriate suggestive measures in order to process betterment.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>3</start>
					<end>20</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_339_bd900d5d5ef60c7053b40e189740f549.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Structural Model to Clarify the Empathy in Universities (The Effect of Spirituality, Social Capital and Good Governance)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">ZareiMatin</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">behzad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadian</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت رفتاری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Gharachorloo</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sholeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Empathy is having a common sense with others. The context in which have been emphasized in religious texts. This study aims to provide a model to explain the factors affecting empathy. Method: Data analyzed with SPSS and Smart-PLS. Community of study was Qom universities students. And a sample of 400 of them participated in this study. A questionnaire with five point Likert scale was designed and its validity was confirmed by the professors opinion and then distributed and completed by self-report. Reliability tested by Cronbach&#039;s alpha and different parts of the tools were validated in Research model and  tested by using structural equation modeling with partial least squares approach. Results and Conclusion: The results of the survey indicates a good fit for the model and also showed that the hypothesis of the study were approved and spirituality with social capital have important role in the development of empathy between the people and the government. In this regard, practical recommendations were presented to the government and people to the development of empathy.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>21</start>
					<end>36</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_340_c71206c816692dc38e50bcba38a2441c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Developing Academic Managers’ Competency Model Based on Islamic Models: Comparative Study</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">parisa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghorbannejad</namePart>
				<affiliation>دکترای تخصصی تاریخ فرهنگ و تمدن ملل اسلامی؛ استادیار دانشکده علوم انسانی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد ارومیه</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Isakhani</namePart>
				<affiliation>دکترای تخصصی مدیریت رفتاری استادیار دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This research aims to develop academic managers; competency model based on Islamic models with emphasize on Nahjolbalaghe (by Imam Ali). Method: In the first phase of study by reviewing research literature, previous studies have been reviewed and all speeches, letters and statements of Imam Ali have been studied precisely. All themes are codified based on open coding method in grounded theory. In the next phase of study all codes were classified in main and sub categories of competencies. In order to make sure of validity of identified competencies, the developed model is verified by 24 academic experts and Final competencies have been identified after statistical analysis. Results: The results of the article shows piety, behavioral- ethical, trusteeship, fairness and justice and decision making have been identified as managers’ competencies. Conclusion: Comparative study between common approaches in competency models with Islamic models has been done and based on Islamic model some suggestions have been provided for using in academic and higher education organizations.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>37</start>
					<end>48</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_341_03a35466e83542cd135e22d5c8851c4a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Cultural Model of Holly Struggle Based on Religious and Islamic Revolution Principles in Islamic University  (Case Study: Tehran AllamehTabatabaee University)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Madani</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی (خط مشی گذاری عمومی) ، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">davod</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hoseinpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>دکتری مدیریت دولتی (خط مشی گذاری عمومی)، استادیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">masoumeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Yari</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد تاریخ ایران اسلامی، دانشگاه خوارزمی، تهران، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The present study aims at planning a Cultural model of Holly struggle based on religious and Islamic revolution principles in Islamic university.Method: The method of the present study is a combination of qualitative and quantitative approach. Analysis – descriptive (library and documents) and questionnaire and survey method. Results: The results of the survey indicate three Cultural model of Holly struggle in Islamic university and 23 criteria. Conclusion:The authors of the research conclude that compliance based culture is in the first level and knowledge based culture is in the third level. Pure Obedience to jurisdiction ( velayat madari) is the most important factor among the researched factors</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>49</start>
					<end>70</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_342_d840a0fb18d3f8b6cd2f08873d7a16ff.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Tolerance Level of Ambiguity among Students: (Comparative Study between Accounting and Management Students)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">zakieh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Marandi</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد، گروه حسابداری، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، مشهد، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Moradi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار گروه حسابداری دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد ، ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The aim of this study was to compare the level of ambiguity tolerance among  accounting and management students. Method: This study is a descriptive survey.  McDonald (1970) ambiguity tolerance Inventory was used to collect data. The statistical community of the research included accounting and management students in graduate and PhD level. The sample measure was 398 and research hypotheses were tested by MANOVAtest. Results: The results of the study indicated no significant difference between accounting and management students in the tolerance of ambiguity,. The results also showed gender, age, work experience and education level had no effect on students&#039; tolerance of ambiguity.  Conclusion: The results suggest that students during their school years should aim to increase the strength of confronting the problems and to know how Pairing with ambiguous situations should receive appropriate training. In this regard universities have the most important role</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>71</start>
					<end>82</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_343_441c5b2fac723fc7276f3504b2c19400.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Impact of Spiritual Leadership on Employees' Spiritual Well-Being and LMX Quality in Treatment and Health System</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">sedigheh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khorshid</namePart>
				<affiliation>دکترای مدیریت سیستم، دانشیار دانشگاه سمنان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">nasim</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Qolizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی رشته مدیریت کسب و کار، دانشگاه سمنان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This research intends to study the impact of the style of spiritual leadership on LMX quality through employees&#039; spiritual well-being and in Health and treatment system. Method: Research method is descriptive-correlation. The statistical population consists of physicians and paramedics of the Health and Treatment Centers affiliated with medical universities in Esferayen and Mashhad cities from which a sample of 101 was selected through available Non-probability sampling. The data was collected by a questionnaire, and was analyzed by the descriptive and inferential statistical tests. Results: This research showed that: A) Leader altruistic love has a positive and direct effect on his/her vision and hope/faith, and followers membership. B) Leader vision has a positive and direct effect on his/her followers calling. C) Followers calling and membership have positive and direct effects on LMX. D) Spiritual leadership has a positive and direct effect on employee’s spiritual well-being, and employee’s spiritual well-being has a positive and direct effect on LMX. Conclusion: The author of the survey concluded As attitude and behavior of subordinates, as well as leader-follower / manager-subordinate relationship are formed by values supported in organizational culture, spiritual leadership can create an altruistic / philanthropic loving values, consistency, unity, solidarity, peace, trust and honesty, and institutionalizing them into organizational culture, as well as foster a spirit of self-confidence, improve subordinates&#039; self-efficacy, and instilling hope / believe in them towards to the future, as well as empowering them to analyze and draw the larger picture of the organization, and, as a result, develop collaboratively prospects through the process of open strategy, and the creation of a collective commitment to realize the developed vision through giving meaning to work, to determine purpose for work life, and to praise and appreciate subordinates&#039; extra-job behaviors, create a work climate, that they feel to be valuable and their work can be creative  and can be sources of changing  their lives and other people inside and outside the organization, and feel a self devotion  to self-work units</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>83</start>
					<end>106</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_344_3eda420f77ce412e55c629531b8202ff.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Effect of Organizational Supervision Dimensions Through Islamic Approach on Administrative Corruption in State Organizations of Iran from the Employee’s Perspective</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">amin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nikpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>دکترای مدیریت دولتی؛ استادیار گروه مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد کرمان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Aim of recent research is to determine the effect of organizational supervision dimensions through Islamic approach on administrative corruption in state agencies of Iran from the employee’s perspective.Method:This study is a descriptive- correlation research that has been conducted through the survey method. Statistical society of research included all employees in state organizations of Iran and sampling has been conducted through multistage cluster and number of 3021 persons had been selected as volume of sample. The data gathering tool was questionnaires of organizational supervision through Islamic approach and administrative corruption. To analyze the data have been used descriptive and inferential statistics. Results: Findings of research indicated that organizational supervision dimensions through Islamic approach have negative effect on administrative corruption in state organizations of Iran. Another finding of research showed that variable of belief in divine supervision has had the highest rank among the variables of organizational supervision through Islamic approach, and managerial supervision, self-supervision and public supervision have located in the next ranks.Conclusion: All dimensions of organizational supervision through Islamic approach have reducer effect on administrative corruption in state agencies of Iran, and of among the dimensions, managerial supervision variable has had the most negative reducer on administrative corruption.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>5</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>11</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>107</start>
					<end>126</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_345_736696b42d31b9272d9e98c0719a11db.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>