<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1397</YEAR>
<VOL>7</VOL>
<NO>16</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارائه چارچوب سطح بندی شده عوامل موثر بر توسعه دیپلماسی علم و فناوری دانشگاه های ج.ا.ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Classified Framework of Effective Factors on Science and Technology Diplomacy Development in Iran Universities</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>حوزۀ دیپلماسی علم و فنّاوری(دعف) دارای قلمرو مفهومی نوپایی دارد و با وجود قوّت قلمرو کاربردی، فاقد ادبیات نظری درخور در متون علمی و دانشگاهی است. دانشگاههای علوم انسانی به دلیل تعامل بیشتر با مسائل سیاسی، همواره مدّ نظر دستگاههای سیاست خارجۀ کشورها بوده‌اند و قبل از ورود دانشگاههای فنی و مهندسی و علوم پزشکی، زمینه‌ساز تعاملات بین‌المللی تلقی شده‌اند. هدف: هدف از انجام پژوهش پیشِ رو، علاوه بر شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر دعف، ارائۀ چارچوب توسعۀ آن از طریق ظرفیتهای دانشگاههای علوم انسانی ج.ا.ایران بود. روش: در این مقاله، نخست به شناسایی درخت دانش عوامل مؤثر بر تأثیرگذاری دانشگاههای علوم انسانی کشور بر توسعۀ دعف پرداخته شده، سپس با استفاده از رویکرد مدلسازی تفسیری- ساختاری به سطح‌بندی عوامل و در نهایت، با استفاده از نرم‌افزار دیمتل به اندازه‌گیری شدت روابط بین عوامل در سطوح مختلف اقدام شده است. یافته‌ها: پنج سطح کلی زمینه‌ها، موانع، علل و لوازم، راهبردها و پیامدها و شدت روابط بین آنها و متغیّرهای درونی آنها ارائه شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives: Science and Technology Diplomacy (STD) is a nascent concept lacking worthy of academic literature and scientific texts, despite the strength of the applied field. Universities of Human Sciences have always been highly concered by the foreign policy administrations due to greater engagement with political issues and have paved the path for international interactions ahead of Engineering and Medical Science Universities.Aim: Hence, the current paper aims to establish development (STD) framework by Islamic Republic of Iran Universities of Human Sciences, in addition to identifying the affecting factors. Method: Therefore, first we identified the Knowledge Tree of Universities of Human Sciences impact on development of STD and then classified factors using Interpretive Structural Modeling approach. Finally, we measured the intensity of the relationships between factors at different levels using DEMATEL software.  Results: At the end, we provided five overall levels of grounds, obstacles, causes and tools, strategies and outcomes and intensity of relations among them as well as internal variables.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>215</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>234</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>تسلیمی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمد سعید</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت؛ استاد گروه آموزشی مدیریت دولتی دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت؛ استاد گروه آموزشی مدیریت دولتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>خلیل</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نوروزی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری سیاستگذاری علم و فنّاوری دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری سیاستگذاری علم و فنّاوری دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>vtarvirdizadeh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>وحید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تارویردی زاده</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد معارف اسلامی و مدیریت بازرگانی دانشگاه امام صادق(ع).</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد معارف اسلامی و مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>tarvirdizadeh@isu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدعلی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صادقی کیا</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد معارف اسلامی و مدیریت دولتی و سیاستگذاری عمومی دانشگاه امام صادق(ع).</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد معارف اسلامی و مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sadeghikia89@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دیپلماسی علم و فنّاوری(دعف)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دانشگاه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چارچوب توسعۀ دیپلماسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دیمتل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آی.اس.ام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-       آشنا، ح. و ن. جعفری هفتخوانی(1386). «دیپلماسی عمومی و سیاست خارجی؛ پیوندها و اهداف». دانش سیاسی، ش ؟: 206-179. ##-       اصغرپور، م.(1382). تصمیم‌گیری گروهی و نظریه‌بازی‌ها با نگرش «تحقیق در عملیات»، تصمیمات گروهی و چندشاخصه، قضاوت خبرگان به منظور کسب اطلاعات. تهران: دانشگاه تهران. ##-       ایتان(1390). بررسی مفهومی دیپلماسی علم و فنّاوری و ترسیم وضع موجود آن در جمهوری اسلامی ایران. تهران: معاونت علمی و فنّاوری ریاست جمهوری. ##-       تیزرو، ع.(1389). طراحی مدل زنجیرۀ تأمین چابک؛ رویکرد مدل‌سازی ساختاری تفسیری. رسالۀ دکتری به راهنمایی عادل آذر. تهران: دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس. ##-       طاهری، م.؛ ر. عباسپور و س. علوی‌پناه(1393). «استفاده از تصمیم‌گیری چندمعیاره مبتنی بر تلفیق روشهای DEMATEL و ANP در انتخاب مکان بهینۀ آرامستان‌ها(مطالعۀ موردی: اصفهان)». محیط شناسی، ش 2: 480-463. ##-       قوام، ع.(1384). «از دیپلماسی مدرن به دیپلماسی رسانه‌ای». پژوهش حقوق و سیاست، ش 17: 18-7. ##-       محسنی سهی، هـ. و ف. محسنی سهی(1394). «تأثیر دیپلماسی علم و فنّاوری بر افزایش قدرت نرم جمهوری اسلامی ایران». مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی، ش 9: 116-97. ##-       میرعمادی، ط.(1394). «مدل تحلیل دیپلماسی علم و فنّاوری در یک کشور». رهیافت، ش 59: 16-1. ##-       نوروزی، خ؛ م. باقری کنی، ج. آزادی احمدآبادی و م. نوروزی(1391). «ارتقای قابلیتهای پویا در دانشکده‌های مدیریت جمهوری اسلامی ایران؛ مورد مطالعه: دانشکده معارف اسلامی و مدیریت دانشگاه امام صادق(ع)». مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی، ش 3: 446-423. ##-       Aranzales, B., &amp; Kelly, J. (2017). The role of epistemic communities in Science diplomacy: An analysis of US and German foreign policy towards Colombia. ##-       Asgharpur, M. (1382). Group decisions and game theory with the view of &quot;research in operations&quot;, group decisions and multipliers, judgment of experts for information. Tehran: Publishing and Printing Institute of Tehran University. ##-       Ashna, H., &amp; Jafari Sevenfamily, N. (1386). Public Diplomacy and Foreign Policy, Links and Objectives. Political Knowledge, 179-206. ##-       Barston, R. (2014). Modern diplomacy (Fourth Edition ed.). New York: Routledge. ##-       Berg, L.-P. (2010). Science Diplomacy Networks. Cell , 136(1), 9-11. ##-       Berkman, P. A., Kullerud, L., Pope, A., Vylegzhanin, A. N., &amp; Young, O. R. (2017). The Arctic Science Agreement propels science diplomacy. Science, 358(6363), 596-598. ##-       copeland, d. (2010). A Role for Science Diplomacy, Soft Power and Global Challenges – Part I. Retrieved from http://www.guerrilladiplomacy.com/2010/11/a-role-for-science-diplomacy-soft-power-and-global-challenges-part-i/ ##-       Council for Science and Technology Policy. (2008). Toward the Reinforcement of Science and Technology Diplomacy. Tokyo: Japans Council for Science and Technology Policy. ##-       Davis, L. S., &amp; Patman, R. G. (2015). Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? World Scientific. ##-       EDWARDS, A. (2010). Conscience sans Science: Staging Science Diplomacy for the 21 st Century. oxford journals, social sciences, science and public policy, 37(9), 665-677. ##-       Fähnrich, B. (2017). Science diplomacy: Investigating the perspective of scholars on politics–science collaboration in international affairs. Public Understanding of Science, 26(6), 688-703. ##-       Itan (1390). Conceptual study of science and technology diplomacy and its current status in the Islamic Republic of Iran. Vice Presidency for Science and Technology. ##-       Leshner, a. (2008). written testimony before the committee on science and technology, subcommittee on research and science education. science &amp; diplomacy. ##-       mazur, E. (2012). science and technology diplomacy and international collaboration. 8th Sci. Technol. Soc. Forum. ##-       Miramadi, T. (1394). A model for analyzing the diplomacy of science and technology in a country. Approach, 1-16. ##-       Mohseni Sahi, H., &amp; Mohseni Sahi, F. (1394). Effect of Diplomacy of Science and Technology on Increasing Soft Power of the Islamic Republic of Iran. Management at Islamic University, 97-116. ##-       mphadzula, p. (2014). opportunities and challenges of science and technology diplomacy. In b. zahuranec, v. ittekkot, &amp; e. montgomery (Eds.), Science and Technology Diplomacy in Developing Countries (pp. 119-126). New Delhi: Centre for Science &amp; Technology of the Non-Aligned and Other Developing Countries. ##-       Norouzi, Kh., Bagheri Kani, M., Azadi Ahmadabadi, J., &amp; Norouzi M. (1391). Promotion of Dynamic Capabilities in the Schools of Management of the Islamic Republic of Iran - Case Study: Islamic School of Management and Imam Sadiq University. Management at Islamic University, 423-446. ##-       Nye, J. S. (2004). Soft Power: The Means To Success In World Politics. PublicAffairs. ##-       Patman, R. G., &amp; Davis, L. S. (2017). Science Diplomacy in the Indo‐Pacific Region: A Mixed but Promising Experience. Politics &amp; Policy, 45(5), 862-878. ##-       Patman, R. G., &amp; Davis, L. S. (Eds.). (2017). The Advent of Science Diplomacy. In WORLD SCIENTIFIC REFERENCE ON NATURAL RESOURCES AND ENVIRONMENTAL POLICY IN THE ERA OF GLOBAL CHANGE: Volume 2: The Social Ecology of the Anthropocene: Continuity and Change in Global Environmental Politics (pp. 81-98). ##-       Qavam, AS. (1384). from modern diplomacy to media diplomacy. Law and Politics Research, 7-18. ##-       Royal Society. (2010). New frontiers in science diplomacy. London: Royal Society. ##-       Taheri, M., Abbaspour, R., &amp; Alavi Panah, S. (1393). Using Multi-Criteria Decision Based on Combination of DEMATEL and ANP Methods in Choosing Optimum Location of Arhangash (Case Study: Isfahan). Ecology, 480-463. ##-       Tizro, A (1389). Agile Supply Chain Model Design-Structural Interpretative Modeling Approach, Doctoral Dissertation to Adel Azar. Tehran: Faculty of Management, Tarbiat Modares University. ##-       Wang, T. C. (2013). The Evoluton and Future of Science Diplomacy: A U.S. Perspective. University of Tokyo: Amirican Assosiation for the Advancement of Science (AAAS).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>وضعیت اشتغال دانش‌آموختگان رشتۀ مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Alumni Employment in the Field of Educational Administration at Allameh Tabataba&#039;i University (ATU)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: بررسی وضعیت اشتغال دانش‌آموختگان رشتۀ مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی. روش: پژوهش حاضر به روش توصیفی- پیمایشی انجام شد. جامعۀ آماری پژوهش، کلیۀ دانش‌آموختگان رشتۀ مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی طی سالهای 94-1390 به تعداد 338 نفر(191 کارشناس و 147 کارشناس ارشد) بودند. نمونه‌ در دسترس طبقه‌ای، به ترتیب 123 و 108 نفر و ابزار جمع‌آوری داده‌ها، پرسشنامۀ محقق‌ساخته بود. یافته‌ها: 4/53 درصد از دانش‌آموختگان بیکارند. اشتغال اکثر شاغلان از طریق شرکت در آزمون استخدامی و در سازمانهای خصوصی از نوع خدماتی بوده است. میزان رضایت شغلی و ارتباط شغل با رشتۀ‌ تحصیلی اکثر شاغلان، متوسط بوده است. تأثیر برند دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی بر اشتغال در حد متوسط متمایل به زیاد بوده است. از 53 عنوان درس تخصصی و اصلی مدیریت آموزشی در مقاطع کارشناسی و ارشد، تنها 7 درس برای شاغلان کاربرد داشته و از طرفی ، بیشتر نیازهای آموزشی آنان برای انجام بهینۀ شغل، شامل مهارت‌آموزی، کارهای رایانه‌ای و نرم‌افزاری، دوره‌های آموزشی شغلی، زبان، مهارتهای نیازسنجی آموزشی و آشنایی با کارهای اداری است. نتیجه‌گیری: در ایران، بین نیاز جامعه به نیروی کار دانا و ماهر با کیفیتِ خروجی‌های دانشگاهی فاصلۀ قابل توجهی وجود دارد. بنا به یافته‌های پژوهش، ضرورت تحول و دگرگون‌سازی محتوای آموزشی و برنامۀ درسی در رشتۀ مدیریت آموزشی کاملاً احساس می‌شود. همچنین لازم است دو درس کار عملی در سازمانهای آموزشی با جدّیت و بهره‌وری بیشتر اجرا شود تا مهارت لازم برای دانشجو تا حدودی حاصل شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives: It is to determine the status of alumni in the field of educational administration in Allameh Tabataba&#039;i University (ATU). Method: It is a descriptive-survey study. The population includes all 338 alumni of educational administration including 191 undergrads and 147 graduates within 1390-94. Stratified sample includes 123 and 108 persons totaling to 231. A researcher-developed questionnaire was employed. Results: Near half of the participants (53.4%) are unemployed mainly due to lack of job opportunities. Most of the individuals are hired through employment exams, mostly in private and service sector. Job satisfaction as well as relevance between job and specialization is at the medium level. The role of ATU brand in their employment is medium to high. Only 7 out of 53 undergrad and grad courses have been of some use for their jobs. Nevertheless, their training needs to be covered include: skills training, computer and software, job-related training, English language, Training need assessment skills, and administrative work. Conclusion: In general, there is a considerable gap between the market need for knowledgeable and skillful individuals and university outputs. Thus according to findings of the study, a transformation is needed in the content and curriculum of the field of educational administration more than ever. In addition, the two courses, practicum in educational organizations and practicum in educational institutions, must be taken more seriously and more productively in order to provide some skills for the students.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>235</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>252</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رحیمیان</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت آموزشی. دانشیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت آموزشی. دانشیار گروه مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hamrahimian@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فاطمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جهانی جوانمردی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه علامه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>f.jahani.14@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نوروزی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد فلسفۀ تعلیم و تربیت دانشگاه شاهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد فلسفۀ تعلیم و تربیت دانشگاه شاهد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mnma67@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اشتغال دانش‌آموختگان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت آموزشی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-       احمدی، سیروس(1393). «بررسی وضعیت اشتغال دانش‌آموختگان جامعه‌شناسی و عوامل مرتبط با آن». جامعه‌شناسی اقتصادی و توسعه، ش 3(1): 23-1. ##-       بیگدلی، مژگان؛ محمدرضا کرامتی و عباس بازرگان(1391). «بررسی رابطۀ بین رشتۀ تحصیلی با وضعیت اشتغال دانش‌آموختگان دانشکدۀ روان‌شناسی و علوم تربیتی دانشگاه تهران». پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی در آموزش عالی، ش 65: 131-111. ##-       پورکاظمی، محمدحسین(1388). «وضعیت راهیابی فارغ‌التحصیلان رشته‌های علوم‌انسانی و اجتماعی دانشگاههای دولتی به بازار کار(ورودی سالهای 75-1374‌)». پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی در آموزش عالی، ش 2: 127-15. ##-       جمیری، وحیده؛ جواد حاتمی، اسکندر فتحی آذر و محمود کرامتی(1389). «بررسی میزان انطباق برنامۀ درسی رشتۀ کارشناسی مهندسی معماری با نیازهای بازار کار در ایران». مطالعات برنامۀ درسی آموزش، ش 1(2): 133-111. ##-       حاجیان، محبوبه(1388).شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر اشتغال و بیکاری دانش‌آموختگان رشته‌های روان‌شناسی و علوم‌تربیتی دانشگاه الزهرا. پایان‌نامه کارشناسی‌ارشد. دانشگاه دانشگاه الزهرا، دانشکده روان‌شناسی و علوم تربیتی. ##-       سعیدی رضوانی، محمود؛ معصومه محمدحسین‌زاده و حسین باغگلی(1389). «سرنوشت شغلی فارغ‌التحصیلان دانشکدۀ علوم تربیتی و روان‌شناسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد». مطالعات تربیتی و روان‌شناسی، ش (11)2: 86-57. ##-       شرفی، محمد و عباس عباسپور(1394). «شناساییقابلیتهایاشتغال‌پذیریدانش‌آموختگاندانشگاهها بر اساس نظریۀ داده‌بنیاد». نوآوری و ارزش‌آفرینی، ش (7)3. ##-       شرفی، محمد و مینا مقدم(1393). «واکاویوضعیتاشتغالدانش‌آموختگانرشته‌هایعلوم‌تربیتی: یک مطالعه موردی». پژوهشهایرهبری و مدیریتآموزشی، ش (2)1. ##-     عقابی، محبوبه(1391). بررسی رابطۀ رشتۀ تحصیلی با وضعیت اشتغال دانش‌آموختگان کارشناسی ارشد دانشکده‌های روان‌شناسی و علوم تربیتی و علوم اجتماعی طی سالهای 86-1383. پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد. دانشکدۀ روان‌شناسی و علوم تربیتی دانشگاه تهران. ##-       عیسی‌زاده، سعید و سعیده‌السادات حسینی(1393). «بررسیتطبیقیبیکاریفارغ‌التحصیلان دانشگاهی در ایران در مقایسه با دیگر کشورها». کار و جامعه، ش 176. ##-       کرامتی، محمدرضا(1393). «وضعیت اشتغال دانش‌آموختگان رشتۀ‌ روان‌شناسی در ایران و کانادا: مورد دانشگاه تهران و دانشگاه آلبرتا». پژوهشهای کاربردی روان‌شناختی، ش (3)5: 70-55. ##-       کیان‌مهر، محمدولی(1382). «ملاحظاتیپیرامونمعضلبیکاریباتأکیدبرموضوععدم اشتغال دانش‌آموختگان در کشور». تعاون و کشاورزی، دورۀ جدید، ش 148. ##-       محمودیان، حسین و مرجان رشوند(1389). «وضعیت اشتغال فارغ‌التحصیلان آموزش عالی شهر تهران با تأکید بر عوامل جمعیتی و اجتماعی مؤثر بر آن». نامۀ انجمن جمعیت‌شناسی ایران، ش (3)5. ##-       ملک‌پور، علی و فواد محمدی(1392). «بررسی زمینه‌ها و موانع اشتغال فارغ‌التحصیلان دانشگاهی مقطع کارشناسی رشته‌های علوم انسانی شهرستان بیجار». کار و جامعه، ش 157: 37-24. ##-       وقاری زمهریر، زهرا؛ ساناز عبیری و محمود سعیدی رضوانی(1389). «نقش‌آفرینی دانشگاه در اشتغال، از نظر تا عمل، مطالعۀ موردی». دانشکدۀ علوم تربیتی و روان‌شناسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد. مهارت‌آموزی، ش (12)3. ##-       Ahmadi, Sirous (2014). “Study of Employment Status of Graduates of Sociology and its Related Factors”. Sociology of Economics and Development, 3(1): 1-23. ##-       Ali Marouani, M. (2010). “More Jobs for University Graduates: Some Policy Options for Tunisia”. Applied Economics Letters, 17(10): 933-937. ##-       Austin, A. (2010). Graduate Employment Gap: Students of Color Losing Ground. Economic Policy Institute Brief. ##-       Ball, D.A. (2016). Exploring Leadership&#039;s Business Cultural Assumptions and Practices within the Higher Education Industry Influencing Graduate Employment Success in the 21st Century: An Exploratory Qualitative Inquiry. Doctoral Dissertation, Capella University. ##-       Bernhard, M. (2007). Examining Brain Drain: Demographic, Educational and Employment Factors Influencing Lehigh University Graduates to Stay Or Leave the Region. ProQuest.‏ ##-       Bigdeli, Mojgan; Mohammad Reza Keramati &amp; Abbas Bazargan (2012). “Study of Relationship between Graduates and Graduates of the Faculty of Psychology and Educational Sciences of Tehran University”. Quarterly Journal of Research and Planning in Higher Education, 65: 111-131. ##-       Blackmore, J.; C. Gribble, L. Farrell, M. Rahimi, R. Arber &amp; M. Devlin (2014). Australian International Graduates and the Transition to Employment. ##-       Brooks, R. (2015). An Exploration of the Influences of Class, Gender and Ethnicity on Student Engagement with Graduate Employment Opportunities. ##-       Burke, C.; T. Scurry, J. Blenkinsopp &amp; K. Graley (2017). “Critical Perspectives on Graduate Employability”. In: Graduate Employability in Context (P. 87-107). Palgrave Macmillan UK. ##-       Calota, George &amp; Gabriela Ilie (2013). “The Lost Generation. An Analysis on the Employability of Higher Education Graduates in Europe. Case Study: Romania”. Internal Auditing &amp; Risk Management, Anul VIII, Nr. 2 (30). ##-       Chan, S.J. &amp; L.W. Lin (2015). “Massification of Higher Education in Taiwan: Shifting Pressure from Admission to Employment”. Higher Education Policy, 28(1): 17-33. ##-       Finn, K. (2016). “Relational Transitions, Emotional Decisions: New Directions for Theorising Graduate Employment”. Journal of Education and Work, 1-13. ##-       Gartell, M. (2012). “The College-to-Work Transition during the 1990s: Evidence from Sweden”. Applied Economics, 44(11): 1449-1469. ##-       Gassab, M. &amp; H.B.O. Jamoussi (2011). Determinants of Graduate Unemployment in Tunisia (Almalaurea Working Papers No. 16). ##-       González-Romá, V.; J.P. Gamboa &amp; J.M. Peiró (2016). “University Graduates’ Employability, Employment Status, and Job Quality”. Journal of Career Development, 0894845316671607. ##-       Graduate Unemployment in Post-Apartheid South Africa: Nature and Possible Policy Responses (2006). Research Report Compiled for Standard Bank and Business Leadership South Africa. Development Policy Research Unit School of Economics, University of Cape Town. ##-       Green, A. &amp; K.H. Mok (2013). “Expansion of Higher Education, Graduate Employment and Social Mobility: An Asia and Europe Dialogue. In: Hong Kong Educational Research Association Annual Conference. ##-       Hajian, Mahboubeh (2009). Identifying the Factors Affecting Employment and Unemployment of Graduates of Psychology and Educational Sciences at Alzahra University. Thesis Undisclosed Master. University of Al-Zahra University, Faculty of Psychology and Educational Sciences. ##-       Harvey, L. (2001). “Defining and Measuring Employability”. Quality in Higher Education, 7(2): 97-109. ##-       Hennemann, S. &amp; I. Liefner (2010). “Employability of German Geography Graduates: The Mismatch between Knowledge Acquired and Competences Required”. Journal of Geography in Higher Education, 34(2): 215-230. ##-       Isazadeh, Saeed &amp; Saiedalesadat Hosseini (2014). “Comparative Study of Unemployment Graduates in Iran Compared to Other Countries”. Social, Economic, Scientific and Cultural Monthly Work and Society, No. 176. ##-       Jackson, D. &amp; G. Michelson (2015). “Factors Influencing the Employment of Australian PhD Graduates”. Studies in Higher Education, 40(9): 1660-1678. ##-       Jamiri, Vahideh; Javad Hatami, Alexander Fathi Azar &amp; Mahmoud Keramati (2010). “Assessing the Degree of Adaptation of the Bachelor&#039;s Degree in Architecture Engineering to the Needs of the Labor Market in Iran”. Two Quarterly Studies in Curriculum, (1) 2: 111-133. ##-       Joshua, S.; D. Azuh, F. Olanrewaju &amp; I. Biao (2015). “Multi-Faceted Training and Employment Approaches as Panacea to Higher Education Graduate Unemployment in Nigeria”. Contemporary Journal of African Studies, 3(1). ##-       Keller, S.E. (2009). New Graduate Employment in New Zealand: The Influence of Fieldwork Experiences. ##-       Keramati, Mohammad Reza (2014). “The Employment Status of Graduates in the Field of Psychology in Iran and Canada: The Case of the University of Tehran and the University of Alberta”. Psychological Applied Research, (3)5: 55-70. ##-       Kianmehr, Mohammad Vali (2003). “Concerns about the Unemployment Problem, with an Emphasis on the Issue of Unemployed Graduates in the Country”. New Course, No. 148. ##-       Liu, D. (2016). “Parental Involvement and University Graduate Employment in China”. Journal of Education and Work, 29(1): 98-113. ##-       Livanos, I. (2010). “The Relationship between Higher Education and Labour Market in Greece: the Weakest Link?”. Higher Education, 60(5): 473-489. ##-       Mahmudian, Hossain &amp; Marjan Rashvand (2010). “The Employment Status of Graduates of Higher Education in Tehran with an Emphasis on the Demographic and Social Factors Affecting it”. Journal of Iranian Society of Demography, (3)5. ##-       Malekpour, Ali &amp; Fouad Mohammadi (2013). “Study of the Bases and Barriers of Employment of Graduates of the University of Bijar Bachelor of Science”. Social, Economic, Scientific and Cultural Monthly Work and Society, 157: 24-37. ##-       Mok, K.H. &amp; J. Jiang (2017). “Massification of Higher Education: Challenges for Admissions and Graduate Employment in China”. In: Managing International Connectivity, Diversity of Learning and Changing Labour Markets (P. 219-243). Springer Singapore. ##-       Mok, K.H. (2016). “Massification of Higher Education, Graduate Employment and Social Mobility in the Greater China Region”. British Journal of Sociology of Education, 37(1): 51-71. ##-       Mok, K.H., &amp; X. Han (2016). “From ‘Brain Drain’ to ‘Brain Bridging’: Transnational Higher Education Development and Graduate Employment in China”. Journal of Higher Education Policy and Management, 38(3): 369-389. ##-       Næss, T. (2011). Graduate Employment in the Knowledge Society Norwegian Master Grade-Level Graduates (No. 21). ##-       Nunley, J.M., A. Pugh, N. Romero &amp; R.A. Seals (2014). “Unemployment, Underemployment, and Employment Opportunities: Results from a Correspondence Audit of the Labor Market for College Graduates”. Auburn University Department of Economics Working Paper Series, (2014-04). ##-       Oghabi, Mahboubeh (2012). Study of the Relationship between the Student&#039;s Degree and the Employment Status of Graduate Students in Psychology and Education Sciences and Social Sciences Schools in 2007-2008. Thesis Undisclosed Master. University of Tehran, Faculty of Psychology and Educational Sciences. ##-       Peake, J.; B. Par &amp; J. Roberts (2013). “College of Agriculture Satellite Campus Student Demographics and Alumni Level of Satisfaction”. NACTA Journal, 57(3): 10.‏ ##-       Pecora, P.J.; R.C. Kessler, K. O&#039;Brien, C.R. White, J. Williams, E. Hiripi, … &amp; M.A. Herrick (2006). “Educational and Employment Outcomes of Adults Formerly Placed in Foster Care: Results from the Northwest Foster Care Alumni Study”. Children and youth Services Review, 28(12): 1459-1481. ##-       Pour Kazemi, Mohammad Hossein (2009). “The Status of Graduate Studies in Social Sciences and Social Sciences in Government Universities to the Labor Market (Entrance from 1374-75)”. Research and Planning in Higher Education, 2: 15-127. ##-       Rothwell, A. &amp; F. Rothwell (2017). “Graduate Employability: A Critical Oversight”. In” Graduate Employability in Context (P. 41-63). Palgrave Macmillan UK. ##-       Saeedi Rezvani, Mahmoud; Masoomeh Mohammad Husseinzadeh &amp; Hossain Baggolli (2010). “Job Fate Graduates of the Faculty of Educational Sciences and Psychology of Ferdowsi University of Mashhad”. Educational Studies and Psychology, (11) 2: 57-86. ##-       Sharafi, Mohammad &amp; Abbas Abbaspour (2015). “Identifying the Employment Abilities of University Graduates, Based on the Foundation&#039;s Data Theory”. Two Issues of Innovation and Value Creation, No. (7)3. ##-       Sharafi, Mohammad &amp; Mina Moghadam (2014). “Examination of Employment Status of Graduates in Business Studies: A Case Study”. Leadership Research and Educational Management, (2)1. ##-       Snell, E.B. (2009). Examining the Career Choices and Civic Engagement Activities of Teach for America Alumni. ProQuest LLC. 789 East Eisenhower Parkway, PO Box 1346, Ann Arbor, MI 48106.‏ ##-       Stowe, K.; J. Von Freymann &amp; L. Schwartz (2012). “Assessing Active Learning and Skills Training Through Alumni and Current Student Views”. Journal of Case Studies in Accreditation and Assessment, 2, 1.‏ ##-       Tomlinson, M. (2005). Higher Education and Graduate Employability: Student and Academic Attitudes to Graduate Work, Careers and Employability. Doctoral Dissertation, Cardiff University. ##-       Vagary Zamharir, Zahra; Sanaz Abiri &amp; Mahmoud Saeedi Rezvani (2010). “University Role in Employment: From the Case of Case Study”. Faculty of Education Sciences and Psychology, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad. Skill Training, (12)3. ##-       Vedder, R.; C. Denhart &amp; J. Robe (2013). “Why Are Recent College Graduates Underemployed? University Enrollments and Labor-Market Realities”. Center for College Affordability and Productivity (NJ1). ##-       Ward, L.J. (2006). Graduate Employment Links to Sandwich Year Work Placements. ##-       Wei, B. &amp; L. Binglong (2014). “Who is Unemployed, Employed or Admitted to Graduate School; An Investigation of the Employment Situation of College Graduates in China between 2003 and 2009”. Chinese Education &amp; Society, 47(6): 36-58. ##-       Wright, E.T.M. &amp; Y. MA (2016). “Graduate Employment in China: Emerging Tensions and Policy Solutions”. In: Annual Meeting of the American Educational Research Association, AERA 2016. ##-       Yang, S.L.; N. Wang &amp; S.W. Teng (2011). Comparative Analysis on the Graduate Employment Service Systems of USA, Germany and Japan [J]. Economic Research Guide, 28: 061.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>آسیب‌شناسی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی با استفاده از روش فراترکیب</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Pathological Characteristics of Culture and Jihady Management by Using Meta-Synthesis Method</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف مؤلفان در این مقاله، شناسایی شاخصهای آسیب‌شناسی مدیریت جهادی بود. روش: با روش تحقیق فراترکیب، داده‌های اصلی مقالات منتخب، تفسیر و دسته‌بندی و به صورت شبکۀ مضامین نمایش داده شد. این تحقیق از نظر نتایج، در زمرة تحقیقات توسعه‌ای و از حیث داده‌ها، کیفی است. یافته‌ها: یافته‌های تحقیق در دو گروه آسیبهای درونی و بیرونی عبارتند از: آسیبهای درونی، شامل دوری از خدا، وابستگی به دنیا و تغییر هدف؛ آسیبهای بیرونی، شامل دوری از شایسته‌سالاری، حاکمیت روابط به جای ضوابط، بوروکراسی، نفوذ فرصت‌طلبان و سست‌عنصران، جدایی و برون‌رفت سرمایۀ اصلی، ضعف نظارت و ارزشیابی، سستی در کادرسازی، بی‌توجهی به جایگاه نمایندگی ولی فقیه، عدم مشارکت مردم، عدم هماهنگی در امور و اهداف، عدم پایبندی به قانون و قانون‌گریزی، عدم تدوین مبانی و شاخصهای فرهنگ جهادی و سانسور. نتیجه‌گیری: یافته‌های پژوهش بیانگر این است که در تقسیم‌بندی منطقی می‌توان آسیبهای مدیریت جهادی را به دو دسته آسیبهای درونی و بیرونی تقسیم کرد. با توجه به ماهیت آفات درونی و بیرونی، آفات درونی نسبت به آفات بیرونی اهمیت بیشتری دارند؛ در میان ابعاد آفات بیرونی نیز بوروکراسی از بیشترین اهمیت برخوردار است. آسیبهای شناسایی شده در این مقالات در دو دسته آفات درونی و بیرونی، شامل 16 بُعد و 122 شاخص است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: In this paper, with the purpose of identifying the pathological characteristics of Jihady management, after searching, we found 12 related articles. Method: By using Meta-Synthesis method we interpreted and categorized original data of selected studies then showed them in content network. In terms of the results, this article is developing research and in terms of data is qualitative research.  Results : The findings of this study are divided into two groups of internal and external damages, Three kinds of internal damages: being away from God, the dependence on the world and change of purpose, and thirteen kinds of external damages: Stay away from meritocracy, the rule of relationships rather than rules ( favouritism), bureaucracy, the Influence of opportunists and spinelessness, loss of the original human capital, weak monitoring( observation)  and evaluation, weakness in making qualified staffs, regardlessness  to the position represented by the supreme leader, lack of public participation, lack of coordination in affairs, lack of adherence to the law and illegality, lack of defining the principles and indicators of jihady culture and censorship were identified as the most important findings of this study. Conclusion: Research findings indicate that in logical division, the jihady management damages can be divided into two categories of internal and external damages. Regarding the nature of internal and external damages, internal damages are more important than external damages and among the dimensions of external damages, bureaucracy is of the highest importance that the majority of research in previous years has focused on the destructive impact of bureaucracy on jihady culture and jihady management. The damages which are identified in these articles are divided into two categories of internal and external damages including 16 dimensions and 122 indicators.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>253</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>274</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>معصومه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>الماسی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی- رفتار سازمانی، دانشکده مدیریت حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی. تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی- رفتار سازمانی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>almasi.fm@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عبدالله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>توکلی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکترای مدیریت دولتی. دانشیار مدیریت پژوهشگاه حوزه و دانشگاه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکترای مدیریت دولتی. دانشیار مدیریت پژوهشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abtavakkoli@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرهنگ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرهنگ جهادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت جهادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آسیب‌شناسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فراترکیب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-             ازکیا، مصطفی و محمود توکلی(1385). «فراتحلیل مطالعات رضایت شغلی در سازمانهای آموزشی». علوم اجتماعی، ش 26: 27-1. ##-      الماسی، محسن(1386). «آسیب‌شناسی و ارزیابی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی». مجموعه مقالات اولین همایش ملی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی. [بی‌جا]: [بی‌نا]. ##-      ایروانی، محمدجواد(1377). نهادگرایی و جهاد سازندگی. تهران: اداره کل روابط عمومی وزارت جهاد. ##-      جهان‌تیغ، منصور(1386). «آسیب‌شناسی و ارزیابی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی». مجموعه مقالات اولین همایش ملی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی. [بی‌جا]: [بی‌نا]. ##-      خامنه‌ای، سید علی(1383). بیانات هفدهم تیر. ##-      زواره، علیرضا(1386). «آسیب‌شناسی و ارزیابی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی». مجموعه مقالات اولین همایش ملی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی. [بی‌جا]: [بی‌نا]. ##-      سهرابی، بابک، امیر اعظمی و حمیدرضا یزدانی(1390). «آسیب‌شناسی پژوهشهای انجام شده در زمینۀ مدیریت اسلامی با رویکرد فراترکیب». چشم‌انداز مدیریت دولتی، ش 6: 24-9. ##-      سلطانی، محمدرضا(1393). «مدیریت جهادی، چالشها و الزامات». مدیریت اسلامی، سال بیست و دوم، ش 2: 39-9. ##-      شیخی، عبدالمجید(1386). «درآمدی بر آسیب‌شناسی فرهنگ جهادی». مجموعه مقالات اولین همایش ملی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی. [بی‌جا]: [بی‌نا]. ##-      فرهادی، محمدرضا؛ فتحعلی نوری و برومند چهارآئین(1387). «بررسی علل تأثیر‌پذیری فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی از نظام بوروکراسی». مجموعه مقالات دومین همایش ملی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی. [بی‌جا]: [بی‌نا]. ##-      فرهی، علی؛ محمد ابراهیم سنجقی، محمدرضا سلطانی و یدالله محمدیان(1395). «طراحی الگوی فرهنگ جهادی یکی از نهادهای انقلاب اسلامی». پژوهشهای مدیریت منابع انسانی دانشگاه جامع امام حسین(ع)، سال هشتم، ش 2: 83-53. ##-      قلی‌پور، آرین و علی‌اصغر پورعزت(1387). «چالشهای شالوده‌شکنی مدیر جهادی در ساختار بوروکراتیک رسوب‌گذاری شدۀ غربی». مجموعه مقالات دومین همایش ملی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی. [بی‌جا]: [بی‌نا]. ##-      لیاقتی، محمدباقر(1386). «آسیب‌شناسی و ارزیابی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی». مجموعه مقالات اولین همایش ملی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی. [بی‌جا]: [بی‌نا]. ##-      مرتضوی، سید میرمحمود و جلال عراقی(1387). «عنصر مراقبت در فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی». مجموعه مقالات برگزیدۀ همایش فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی. [بی‌جا]: [بی‌نا]. ##-      مرتضوی مهدی و فضل‌اله زارع‌پور نصیرآبادی(1391). «فرهنگ سازمانی جهادی؛ عامل کلیدی مدیریت جهاد». مهندسی فرهنگی، سال هفتم، ش 72-71. ##-      مقیم، حسن(1386). «آسیب‌شناسی و ارزیابی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی». مجموعه مقالات اولین همایش ملی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی. [بی‌جا]: [بی‌نا]. ##-      مودی، علی‌محمد؛ اسماعیل نصر اصفهانی و علی هلالی(1386). «آسیب‌شناسی و ارزیابی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی». مجموعه مقالات اولین همایش ملی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی. [بی‌جا]: [بی‌نا]. ##-      میر، سید جواد(1386). «بررسی تهدیدات و آفات فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی». مجموعه مقالات اولین همایش ملی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی. [بی‌جا]: [بی‌نا]. ##-      نژادمحمد نامقی، علیرضا(1388). نهادینه کردن فرهنگ جهادی به منظور توسعه و حفظ روحیۀ جهادی در راستای تشکّلهای غیر دولتی. تهران: جهاد کشاورزی. ##-      نعمتی پیرعلی، دل‌آرا(1393). «مدیریت جهادی از منظر قرآن کریم». بصیرت و تربیت اسلامی، دورۀ یازدهم، ش 31: 93-7. ##-      هاشمی‌کیا، سید جمال(1387). «بررسی علتهای تأثیر‌پذیری فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی از نظام بوروکراسی». مجموعه مقالات دومین همایش ملی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی. [بی‌جا]: [بی‌نا]. ##-       Attride-Stirling, J. (2001). “Thematic Networks: An Analytic Tool for Qualitative Research”. Qualitative Research, Vol. 1, No. 3: 385-405. ##-       Almasi, Mohsen (2007). “Pathology and Evaluation of Jihady Culture and Management”. Proceedings of the First National Conference on Culture and Jihadi Management. ##-       Attride-Stirling, J. (2001). “Thematic Networks: An Analytic Tool for Qualitative Research”. Qualitative Research, Vol. 1, No. 3: 385-405. ##-       Azkia, Mustafa &amp; Mahmoud Tavakoli (2006). “A Meta-Analysis of Job Satisfaction Studies in Educational Organizations”. Journal of Social Sciences. No. 26: 1-27. ##-       Farhadi, Mohammad Reza; Fathali Nouri &amp; Broumand Chahar Ayin (2008). “Investigating the Causes of the Impact of Jihady Culture and Management of the Bureaucracy”. Proceedings of the 2nd National Conference on Jihady Culture and Management. ##-       Farrahi, Ali; Mohammad Ibrahim Sanjaghi, Mohammad Reza Soltani &amp; Yadollah Mohammadian (2016). “Designing a Jihady Cultural Model for One of the Institutions of the Islamic Revolution”. Quarterly Journal of Human Resource Management Research at Imam Hossein University, Vol. 8, No. 2: 53-83. ##-       Gholipour, Aryan &amp; Ali Asghar Poor-Ezzat (2008). “The Challenges of Breaking the Jihady Manager in the Westernized Sedimentary Bureaucratic Structure”. Proceedings of the 2nd National Conference on Jihady Culture and Management. ##-       Hashemi Kia, Seyyed Jamal (2008). “Investigating the Causes of the Impact of Jihady Culture and Management of the Bureaucracy”. Proceedings of the Second National Conference on Jihady Culture and Management. ##-       Iravani, Mohammad Javad (1998). Institutionalism and Jihad Sazandegi. Tehran: General Directorate of Public Relations of Ministry of Jihad. ##-       Jahantigh, Mansoor (2007). “Pathology and Evaluation of Jihady Culture and Management”. Proceedings of the First National Conference on Culture and Jihady Management. ##-       Khamenei, Seyyed Ali. (2004). Statements. July 17th. ##-       Liaqati, Mohammad Baqer (2007). “Pathology and Evaluation of Jihady Culture and Management”. Proceedings of the First National Conference on Jihady Culture and Management. ##-       Mir, Seyyed Javad (2007). “Investigating the Threats and Damages of Jihady Culture and Management”. Proceedings of the First National Conference on Jihady Culture and Management. ##-       Moghim, Hasan (2007). “Pathology and Evaluation of Jihady Culture and Management”. Proceedings of the First National Conference on Jihady Culture and Management. ##-       Mortazavi, Mehdi &amp; Fazlollah Zarepour Nasirabadi (2012). “The Jihady Organizational Culture; the Key Factor of Jihad Management”. Journal of Cultural Engineering, Vol. 7. No. 71-72. ##-       Mortazavi, Seyed Mir Mahmoud &amp; Jalal Iraqi (2008). “Element of Care in Jihady Culture and Management”. Proceedings of the Conference on Jihady Culture and Management. ##-       Moudy, Ali Mohammad; Ismail Nasr Esfahani &amp; Ali Helali (2007). “Pathology and Evaluation of Jihady Culture and Management”. Proceedings of the First National Conference on Jihady Culture and Management. ##-       Nemati Pirali, Delara (2014). “Jihady Management from the Perspective of the Holy Qur&#039;an”. Quarterly Journal of Scientific-Promotion of Islamic Insight and Education, Vol. 11, No 31: 7-93. ##-       Nezhad Mohammad Nameqi, Alireza (2009). Institutionalizing the Jihady Culture In Order to Develop and Maintain a Jihady Spirituality towards Non-Governmental Organizations. Tehran: Jihad Agriculture. ##-       Sheikhi, Abdul-Majid (2007). “An Introduction to the Pathology of the Jihady Culture”. Proceedings of the First National Conference on Jihady Culture and Management. ##-       Sohrabi, Babak; Amir Azami &amp; Hamid Reza Yazdani (2011). “Pathology of Researches in the Field of Islamic Management with a Meta-Synthesis Approach”. The Perspective of Public Administration, No. 6: 9-24. ##-       Soltani, Mohammad Reza (2014). “Jihady Management, Challenges and Requirements”. Two Quarterly Journal of Scientific - Research of Management. Vol. 22, No. 2: 9-39. ##-       Zavareh, Alireza (2007). “Pathology and Evaluation of Jihadist Culture and Management”. Proceedings of the First National Conference on Culture and Jihadist Management.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مفهوم‌شناسی هسته‌های علمی و تبیین مختصات و ویژگی‌های آن در نظام آموزش عالی (دانشگاهی) از طریق کاربست مطالعۀ تطبیقی هسته‌های علمی منتخب جهان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Philology of Scientific Groups in University Suprime Educational System by Applying Comparative Study of World Selected Scientific Groups</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هسته‌های علمی مفهوم جدیدی است که در حوزۀ آموزش عالی شکل گرفته است. فهم مختصات و ویژگی‌های هسته‌های علمی و کارکردهای آن، هدف اصلی پژوهش حاضر بود. روش: این پژوهش در بستر رویکرد تطبیقی انجام شد. با انجام نمونه‌گیری هدفمند، 17 هستۀ علمی منتخب در جهان، شناسایی و با روش تحلیل محتوا، اطلاعات آنها تحلیل شد. برای اعتبارسنجی نتایج تحلیلی نیز از روش دلفی فازی استفاده شد. یافته‌ها: با تحلیل محتوای هسته‌های علمی منتخب و به منظور تبیین مختصات و کارکردهای هسته‌های علمی، نتایج در قالب هفت بُعد و 38 مؤلفه و شاخص طبقه‌بندی و اعتبار آنها با روش دلفی فازی تأیید شد. نتیجه‌گیری: تشکیل هسته‌های علمی مختص دانشجویان دورۀ کارشناسی، یکی از اقدامات رایج و گسترده در نظام آموزش عالی است. تشکیل این هسته‌ها باعث می‌شود دانشجویان مستعد از لحاظ آموزشی، پژوهشی، اجتماعی و فرهنگی نسبت به سایر دانشجویان برتری خاص داشته باشند.
 </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives:The present survey aims at clarifying the features of scientific groups in suprime educational system by applying comparative study of world selected scientific groups. Method: The method of the study is a comparative study and sampling. In this way 17 world scientific groups are selected, identified and analysed by content analysis and Delphy fuzzy method is used to validate the results. Results: Through the content analysis   of selected scientific groups and in order to clarify the features and function of scientific groups the results are confiremed in seven dimentions and are classified in 38 components and indicators and the validity is conformed by Delphy fuzzy method.  Conclusion: Stablishing the scientific group among undergraguate university students is a widespread measure in suprime educational system and provides an atmosphere for the talented students to develop their ability in comparison with other students.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>275</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>292</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>میثم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>لطیفی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشیار گروه معارف اسلامی و مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده معارف اسلامی و مدیریت، دانشگاه امام صادق(ع).</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشیار گروه معارف</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>latifi@isu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نصرت‌الله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ضرغام</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری جنگلداری، دانشیار گروه جنگلداری و اقتصاد جنگل، پردیس کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری جنگلداری، دانشیار گروه جنگلداری و اقتصاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عبدالحسین‌زاده</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، گرایش تصمیم‌گیری و خط مشی‌گذاری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، گرایش تصمیم‌گیری</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هستۀ علمی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آموزش عالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دانشگاه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مطالعۀ تطبیقی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل محتوا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-       Adams, J.D.; G.C. Black, J.R. Clemmons &amp; P.E. Stephan (2005). “Scientific Teams and Institutional Collaborations: Evidence from U.S. Universities, 1981-1999”. Research Policy, 34(3): 259-285. ##-       Berrill, D. (1991). “Exploring Underlying Assumptions: Small Group Work of University Undergraduates”. Educational Review, 43(2): 143-157. ##-       Chang, Y. H. (1998). Transportation plan appraisal and decision making-discussion and application of the fuzzy theory, Hwatai, Taipei. ##-       Cole, R.E. (1989). Strategies for Learning: Small-Group Activities in American, Japanese, and Swedish Industry. Berkeley: University of California Press. ##-       Crenshaw, John (1978). “Team Projects in the Undergraduate Curriculum: What they should Contain and how to Obtain Funding”. Acm Sigcse Bulletin, 10(1): 203-205. ##-       Davies, M.A.P. (1994).“A Multicriteria Decision Model Application for Managing Group Decisions”. The Journal of the Operational Research Society, 45(1): 47-58. ##-       Delucchi, M. (2006). “The Efficacy of Collaborative Learning Groups in an Undergraduate Statistics Course”. College Teaching, 54(2): 244-248. ##-       Draskovic, I.; R.S.G. Holdrinet, J.A. Bulte, S.M. Bolhuis &amp;, J.F.J. Van. Leeuwe (2004). “Modeling Small Group Learning”. Instructional Science. 32(1): 447-473. ##-       Ferris, H. (2015). “The Use of Small Group Tutorials as an Educational Strategy in Medical Education”. International Journal of Higher Education, 4(2): 225-228. ##-       Fransen, J.; A. Weinberger &amp; P.A. Kirschner (2013). “Team Effectiveness and Team Development in CSCL”. Educational Psychologist, 48(1): 9-24. ##-       Gatfield, T. (1999). “Examining Student Satisfaction with Group Projects and Peer Assessment”. Assessment &amp; Evaluation in Higher Education, 24(4): 365-377. ##-       Hsu, P.F. &amp; B.Y. Chen (2007). “Developing and Implementing a Selection Model for Bedding Chain Retail Store Franchisee Using Delphi and Fuzzy AHP”. Quality and Quantity, 41(2): 275-290. ##-       Jones, B.F.; S. Wuchty &amp; B. Uzzi (2008). “Multi-University Research Teams: Shifting Impact, Geography, and Stratification in Science”. Science, 322(4): 1259-1262. ##-       Li, M., C. Zheng, X. Tang &amp; G. Sang (2015). “Exploring the Nature of Teacher-Student Interaction in Small-Group Discussions in a Chinese University Setting”. Journal of Computers in Education, 2(4): 475-491. ##-       Mariana, L.; S. Liberman &amp; J.M. Russell (2005). “Scientific Group Cohesiveness at the National University of Mexico. Scientometrics: an International Journal for All Quantitative Aspects of the Science of Science”. Communication in Science and Science Policy, 64(1): 55-66. ##-       Micari, M.; P. Pazos, B. Streitwieser &amp; G. Light (2010). “Small-Group Learning in Undergraduate STEM Disciplines: Effect of Group Type on Student Achievement”. Educational Research and Evaluation, 16(3): 269-286. ##-       Mikhailov, L. (2003). “Deriving priorities from fuzzy pairwise comparison judgements”. Fuzzy Sets and Systems, 134(3): 365-385. ##-       Milojević, S. (2014). “Principles of Scientific Research Team Formation and Evolution”. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 111(11): 3984-9. ##-       Minei, E.M. (2016). “Teaching Small Group Communication: The Do Good Project”. Insight: a Journal of Scholarly Teaching, 11(1): 73-80. ##-       Neondorf, Kimberly A. (2002). The Content Analysis Guidebook. London, Sage Pub. ##-       Neuman, W.L. (2014). Social Research Methods: Qualitative and Quantitative Approaches. Boston [U.A.: Pearson]. ##-       Pratt, M. &amp; T.A.E.C. Pratt (1976). “A Study of Student-Teacher Grading Interaction Process”. Improving College and University Teaching, 24(2): 73-81. ##-       Schustereit, R.C. (1980). “Team-Teaching and Academic Achievement”. Improving College and University Teaching, 28(2): 85-89. ##-       Springer, L., S.S. Donovan &amp; M.E. Stanne (1999). “Effects of Small-Group Learning on Undergraduates in Science, Mathematics, Engineering, and Technology: A Meta-Analysis”. Review of Educational Research, 69(1): 21-51. ##-       Steen Van der, M.; P. Danskin Englis &amp; B.G. Englis (2013). Scientific Team Effectiveness and the External CEO: A Study of Biotechnology. University Spin-Offs. ##نشانی هسته‌های علمی ##-       A Collaborative National Center for Fusion &amp; Plasma Research (2016). Science Undergraduate Laboratory Internship (SULI), from: http://www.pppl.gov/education/science-education/programs/suli ##-       Boston University (2016). Undergraduate Student Groups. From: http://www.bu.edu/ece/undergraduate/student-groups/ ##-       Brandeis University (2016). UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH group, from: https://www.brandeis.edu/departments/physics/undergraduate/research.html ##-       Carnegie Mellon University (2016). Undergraduate Research Office, from: https://www.cmu.edu/cheme/education/undergraduate/undergraduate-research.html ##-       Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory (CSAIL) (2016). Science group, From: https://www.csail.mit.edu/research/groups ##-       Cornell University (2016). Association of Computer Science Undergraduates (ACSU), from: https://www.cs.cornell.edu/undergrad/ugroups ##-       Department of Zoology, Cambridge University (2016). Science Group, from: Florida College System(2016).The All-Florida Academic Team, from: https://www.floridacollegesystem.com/news_events/fcs_events/all-florida_academic_team.aspx ##-       Indiana University (2016). Undergraduate Research Program, from: http://www.chem.indiana.edu/undergraduate/opportunities/research.asp ##-       Michigan State University (2016). Undergraduate Research, from: https://natsci.msu.edu/academics/undergraduate/research/ ##-       MIT Sloan School of Management (2016). Academic Groups, from: http://mitsloan.mit.edu/faculty/group/ ##-       National Institutes of Health (2016). What is the Team Science? From: http://www.teamsciencetoolkit.cancer.gov/public/WhatisTS.aspx ##-       Penn Engineering, University of Pennsylvania (2016). Undergraduate Student Groups, from: http://www.cis.upenn.edu/current-students/undergraduate/groups.php ##-       Tokyo Institute of Technology(2016).Schools, departments, graduate majors, and academic groups, from: http://www.titech.ac.jp/english/education/groups/ ##-       Toronto University (2016). Art &amp; Science Undergraduate Research Group, from: https://ulife.utoronto.ca/organizations/view/id/77337 ##-       University of Alberta (2016). Student Groups, from: https://uofa.ualberta.ca/science/student-services/student-life/student-groups ##-       University of California (2016). Undergraduate Research in UCSC Divisions. from: https://ugr.ue.ucsc.edu/join_a_lab ##-       University of Central Florida (2016). Office of Undergraduate Research, from: https://www.our.ucf.edu/opportunities/smart.php ##-       University of lowa (2016). Team Science: Building Successful Research Collaborations, from: http://research.uiowa.edu/team-science-building-successful-research-collaborations ##-       University of Memphis (2016). Undergraduate Educational Research Team, from: http://www.memphis.edu/cepr/research/ug_ed_research_team.php ##-       University of Minnesota (2016). student groups, from: https://cse.umn.edu/r/student-groups/ and, http://sua.umn.edu/about/ ##-       University of Missouri(2016).Undergraduate Research Teams, from: https://mizzouadvantage.missouri.edu/education/undergraduate-research-eams/ ##-       University of New Mexico (2016). The Scientific Core, from: http://hsc.unm.edu/nmarc/research/scientific-core.html ##-       University of Rochester (2016). Office of Undergraduate Research, from: https://www.rochester.edu/college/ugresearch/started.html##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی و تحلیل لبۀ تاریک رفتارهای سازمانی از دیدگاه امیرالمؤمنین(ع)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluation and Analysis of Dark Side of Organizational Behavior from the Viewpoints of Amir Almomenin (PBUH)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف محقق در این مقاله، بررسی مفهوم لبۀ تاریک رفتار سازمانی از نگاه اسلامی با مطالعۀ مدلها و الگوهای جهانی آن و تأکید بر نامه‌های امیرالمؤمنین علی(ع) بوده است. روش: تحلیل محتوای کیفی. بر اساس پژوهشهای انجام شده، رفتارهای انحرافی به دو دستۀ مثبت و منفی دسته‌بندی می‌شوند. پدیدۀ لبۀ تاریک رفتارسازمانی در دستۀ رفتارهای انحرافی منفی قرار دارد که به دلیل ایجاد هزینه‌های مالی و غیر مالی هنگفت سالیانه برای سازمانها، مورد توجه و بررسی قرار گرفته است. یافته‌ها: در متون دینی به ویژۀ متون اسلامی و نامه‌های نهج‌البلاغه که اغلب خطاب به فرماندهان و مدیران است، این رفتارها به طور مکرر توسط امیرالمؤمنین گوشزد شده است که در مطالعۀ انجام‌شده، 49 کد شناسایی و در دو سطح فردی و سازمانی طبقه‌بندی شد. نتیجه‌گیری: حضرت برای پیشگیری از این رفتارها، راهکارهایی همچون: شفافیت، عدالت سازمانی، عدم ایجاد اصطکاک اجتماعی، جلوگیری از رقابتهای ناسالم، شایسته‌سالاری و ایجاد فرهنگ سازمانی را بیان می‌کنند که برای این رهنمودها به مصداقهایی برگرفته از نامه‌های امیرالمؤمنین اشاره شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives: Considering the letters of Amir Almomenin (PBUH), current research aims at investigating and understanding the concept of dark side of organizational Behavior from the Islamic perspective through the utilization of international models and patterns. Method: The method of the present research is based on using qualitative content analysis. According to previous research, deviant Behaviors are divided into two groups of positive and negative Behaviors. The phenomenon of dark side of Behavior is considered a negative deviant Behavior which imposes tremendous annual expenses and has been the center of attention by many organizations. Results: The results of the survey indicate that religious texts, especially Islamic contents and letters of Amir Almomenin that are mostly directed toward commanders and managers, this Behavior has been repeatedly notified. In this research, 49 indicators of such Behavior are identified and categorized in two indivual and organizational categories. Conclusion:  In addition to preventing such Behavior, solutions like clarification, organizational justice, lack of social negative contacts, prevention of adverse competition, meritocracy, and organizational culture development have been provided for which the instances of Amir Almomenin sayings in differnet letters are also noted and discussed. </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>293</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>310</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ریحانه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فروزنده جونقانی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، گرایش مدیریت منابع انسانی؛ دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، گرایش مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>r.forouzandeh@atu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عبدالله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>توکلی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکترای مدیریت و دانشیار گروه مدیریت پژوهشگاه حوزه و دانشگاه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکترای مدیریت و دانشیار گروه مدیریت پژوهشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abtavakkoli@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رفتار سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>لبه‌های تاریک رفتار سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انحرافات فردی و سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نامه‌های نهج‌البلاغه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-       نهج‌البلاغه. ترجمه و شرح ناصر مکارم شیرازی. ##-       امیری، علی‌نقی(1394). الگوی اداره در نهج‌البلاغه. قم: پژوهشگاه حوزه و دانشگاه. ##-       ایمان، محمدتقی و محمودرضا نوشادی(1390). «تحلیل محتوای کیفی». پژوهش، ش 2: 44-15. ##-       سید نقوی، میرعلی؛ کبری رفعتی و زینب خانزاده(1393). مدیریت رفتار سازمانی پیشرفته. تهران: مهکامه، چ سوم. ##-       شفیعی، عباس؛ ابوطالب خدمتی و علی آقا پیروز(1391). رفتار سازمانی با رویکرد اسلامی. قم: پژوهشگاه حوزه و دانشگاه، چ سوم. ##-       “nahjol balagheh”. Translated and interpreted by naser makarem shirazi. ##-       Ammiri, alinaghi. ( )“ management pattern in nahjol balagheh”. Ghom: seminary and university research school ##-        Appelbaum, S.; G. David Iaconi &amp; A. Matousek (2007). “Positive and Negative Deviant Workplace Behaviors: Causes, Impacts, and Solutions”. Corporate Governance, 5(9): 586-598. ##-       Bowling, N.A. &amp; M.L. Gruys (2010). “Overlooked Issues in the Conceptualization and Measurement of Counterproductive Work Behavior”. Human Resource Management Review, 20(1): 49-61. ##-       Giacalone, R.A. &amp; J. Greenberg (1997). Antisocial Behavior in Organizations. Sage. ##-       Greenberg, J. (1986). “Determinants of Perceived Fairness of Performance Evaluations”. Jornal of Applied Psychology, 71(2): 340. ##-       Griffin, R.W. &amp; Y.P. Lopez (2005). “Bad Behavior in Organizations: A Review and Typology for Future Research”. Journal of Management, 31(6): 988-1005. ##-       Gruys, M.L. &amp; P.R. Sackett (2003). “Investigating the Dimensionality of Counterproductive Work Behavior”. International Journal of Selection and Assessment, 11(1): 30-42 ##-        Iman , mohammad taghi and m. noshadi.(   ) “The analysis of quality content”. Research, N: 2, P: 15-44. ##-       Klotz, A.C. &amp; M.R. Buckley (2013). “A Historical Perspective of Counterproductive Work Behavior Targeting the Organization”. Journal of Management History, 19(1): 114-132. ##-       Kumi, E. (2013). “Are Demographic Variables Predictors of Work Deviant Behavior?”. International Journal of Management Sciences, 1(1): 1-10. ##-       MacKenzie, C.; T.N. Garavan &amp; R. Carbery (2011). “Understanding and preventing Dysfunctional Behavior in Organizations: Conceptualizing the Contribution of Human Resource Development”. Human Resource Development Review, 10(4): 346-380. ##-       Neuman, J.H. &amp; R.A. Baron (1998). “Workplace Violence and Workplace Aggression: Evidence Concerning Specific Forms, Potential Causes, and Preferred Targets”. Journal of Management, 24(3): 391-419. ##-       Palaiou, K.; A. Zarola &amp; A. Furnham (2016). “The Dark Side of Personality Predicts Positive and Negative Work Attitudes”. Personality and Individual Differences, 88: 12-16. ##-       Robinson, S.L. &amp; R.J. Bennett (1995). “A Typology of Deviant Workplace Behaviors: A Multidimensional Scaling Study”. Academy of Management Journal, 38(2): 555-572. ##-       Sackett, P.R. (2002). “The Structure of Counterproductive Work Behaviors: Dimensionality and Relationships with Facets of Job Performance”. International Journal of Selection and Assessment, 10(1‐2): 5-11. ##-       Seyyed naghavi and others ( ). “ progressive organizational bahaviour  management”. Tehran : mahkameh. ##-       Shafiee , abbas and others. ( )“ organizational bahaviour  with an Islamic approach ”. Ghom: seminary and university research school ##-       Spector, P.E.; S. Fox, L.M. Penney, K. Bruursema, A. Goh &amp; S. Kessler (2006). “The Dimensionality of Counterproductivity: Are All Counterproductive Behaviors Created Equal?”. Journal of Vocational Behavior, 68(3): 446-460. ##-       Spreitzer, G.M. &amp; S. Sonenshein (2004). “Toward the Construct Definition of Positive Deviance”. American Behavioral Scientist, 47(6): 828-847. ##-       Thomas, Jr C. (2014). The Darker Side of Workplace Behavior: A Phenomenological Exploratory Study. Doctoral Dissertation, Creighton University. ##-       Weitz, E.; Y. Vardi &amp; O. Setter (2012). “Spirituality and Organizational Misbehavior”. Journal of Management, Spirituality &amp; Religion, 9(3): 255-281. ##-       Yıldız, B.; L. Alpkan, B. Sezen &amp; H. Yıldız (2015). “A Proposed Conceptual Model of Destructive Deviance: The Mediator Role of Moral Disengagement”. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 207: 414-423.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر تقوای الهی بر عدالت سازمانی مدیران (مورد مطالعه: کارکنان دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Impact of Virtue on Organizational Justice 
(Case Study: Staff of Mohaghegh Ardebili University)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: پژوهش حاضربه منظور بررسی تأثیر تقوای الهی بر عدالت سازمانی مدیران دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی انجام شد. روش: در این پژوهش تعداد 104 نفر از کارکنان دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی، به روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی ساده انتخاب شدند. برای سنجش عدالت سازمانی، از پرسشنامۀ استاندارد عدالت سازمانی(مورمن و نیهوف، 1993) و برای سنجش تقوا، از پرسشنامۀ محقق‌ساخته که روایی آن توسط اساتید و صاحب‌نظران تأیید و پایایی آن با استفاده از آلفای کرونباخ 78/0 تعیین شد، بهره گرفته شد. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها از روشهای آماری، ضریب همبستگی و رگرسیون استفاده شد. یافته‌ها: بین تقوای مدیران با عدالت سازمانی همبستگی مثبت معنادار وجود دارد و فرضیۀ اصلی پذیرفته شد. نتیجه‌گیری: تقوا با عدالت مراوده‌ای، بر خلاف عدالت توزیعی و رویّه‌ای، رابطۀ همبستگی مثبت و معنادار دارند و فرضیۀ آن نیز تأیید شد. با تحلیل نتایج مقاله می‌توان نتیجه گرفت که تقوای مدیران در دانشگاهها چنان‌که باید به تقویت و گسترش سازمانی کمک کند ، مورد توجه قرار نگرفته است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives: The aim of the present research is to examine the role of virtue on organizational justice. Method: This study is descriptive and correlational. In this study, 104 employees of mohaghegh Ardabili University were selected by simple random sampling. To measure organizational justice, questionnaire (Niehoff and Moorman 1993) was used and to measure virtue, questionnaire was used which its validity was confirmed by experts and its reliability by using Cronbach&#039;s alpha / 78 was approved. In order to analyze the data of statistical methods, correlation and regression were used. Results: The results showed that there is a significant correlation between managers’ virtue with organizational justice, and the main research hypothesis was confirmed. Conclusion: The author of the article concluded that there is a significant relationshop between the virtue of God and justice, and the main research hypothesis was confirmed. On the other hand, managers’ virtue in universities should be considerd as an important factor to be developed and streghtened in universities</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>311</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>326</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شجاعی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری علوم قرآنی و تفسیر- حوزه علمیه قم- دانشیار گروه معارف اسلامی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری علوم قرآنی و تفسیر- حوزه علمیه قم-</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shojaei.ahmad50@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ناصر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رحمانی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه محق اردبیلی.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>naserrahmani690@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پریسا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بقال اصغری</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه محق اردبیلی.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>parisa.asgari3@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عدالت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رفتار مدیران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تقوای الهی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-       قرآن کریم. ##-       نهج‌البلاغه. ترجمۀ محمد دشتی(1381). قم: خوش‌رو. ##-       آمدی، عبدالواحد بن محمد، غررالحکم و دررالکلم، ترجمه: سیدهاشم رسولی محلاتی، تهران، دفتر نشر فرهنگ اسلامی، 1377. ##-       ابزری، مهدی(1385). مدیریت رفتار سازمانی. اصفهان: ارکان. ##-       ابن­بابویه القمّی، ابوجعفر محمد بن علی ­بن الحسین (1403ق). معانی الأخبار. تحقیق: علی­اکبر غفاری. قم: دفتر انتشارات اسلامی وابسته به جامعه مدرسین حوزه علمیه قم. چاپ نخست.بحار الانوار، علامه محمد باقر مجلسی، تحقیق و تعلیق: سید جواد علوی، ناشر: دارالکتب اسلامیة، تهران، 1362 ق. ##-       دانایی فرد، حسن؛ سیدمهدی الوانی و عادل آذر (1386) روش شناسی پژوهش کمی در مدیریت: رویکردی جامع، تهران، انتشارات صفار، چاپ اول ##-       دهقانیان ، حامد؛ صبور ، الهام ؛ حجتی، علیرضا (1390) بررسی رابطه بین مولفه های عدالت سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی در یک شرکت بیمه ؛ پژوهشنامه بیمه – سال بیست و هشتم –شماره 2- شماره مسلسل 110- صفحات 153-180 ##-       رابینز، استیفن(1387). رفتار سازمانی: مفاهیم، نظریه‌ها، کاربردها. ترجمۀ علی پارساییان و سید محمود اعرابی. تهران، دفتر پژوهشهای فرهنگی، چ دوم. ##-       راغب‌ اصفهانی، حسین بن محمّد. (1412ق.). مفردات ألفاظ القرآن. چاپ اوّل. بیروت: دارالقلم. ##-       رضاییان، علی(1383). مدیریت رفتارهای سیاسی در سازمان. تهران: سمت. ##-       ﺳﻄﻮت، ﺣﺴﻴﻦ(1379). ﺑﺮرﺳﻲ ﻋﻮاﻣﻞ ﻣﺮﺗﺒﻂ با وجدان ﻛﺎری از دﻳﺪﮔﺎه ﻛﺎرﻛﻨﺎن داﻧﺸﮕﺎه ﺗﻬﺮان. پایان‌نامه ﻛﺎرﺷﻨﺎﺳﻲ ارﺷﺪ. داﻧﺸﻜﺪه ﻣﺪﻳﺮﻳﺖ، داﻧﺸﮕﺎه ﺗﻬﺮان. ##-       سیدجوادین، (1386). «شناخت نحوۀ تأثیرگذاری ابعاد عدالت سازمانی بر جنبه‌های گوناگون رضایت شغلی و سازمانی»، نشریۀ مدیریت بازرگانی. دورۀ 1، ش 1، ص 70-55. ##-       شریفی، مهین(1390): «در ژرفای تقوا؛ تأملی دیگر در واژۀ تقوا». بینات، سال هجدهم، ش 71. ##-       صادقی، محمدتقی(1390). عدالت: انسجام بخش سازمانها (عدالت: نیاز اساسی سازمانها). میثاق مدیران ، شماره 53 عطاران، جواد؛ سید مهدی الوانی، حسن زارعی متین، علی نقی‌امیری و علی راد(1395). «تبیین تقوا به عنوان معیار سنجش در خط‌مشی‌گذاری فرهنگی در پرتو آیات قرآن». پژوهشهای مدیریت عمومی، سال نهم، ش 33: 23-5. ##-       علامه، سید محسن؛ بوستانی،حمیدرضا (1393).بررسی رابطه عدالت سازمانی ادراک شده مبتنی بر آموزه های نهج البلاغه با رفتار شهروندی سازمانی .دو فصلنامه علمی- پژوهشی مدیریت اسلامی ، سال 22، شماره 2، 185-205 ##-       عبد علی ، غزاله (1391)تحلیل رابطه عدالت سازمانی ادارک شده با الگوی کیفیت زندگی کاری مبتنی بر آموزه های نهج البلاغه در میان کارکنان شرکت فکور ، پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی ، دانشگاه اصفهان ##-       کاظمی، بهرام(1382). عدالت در اندیشه‌های سیاسی اسلام. قم: بوستان کتاب. ##-       مطهری ، مرتضی  (1379) سیری در نهج البلاغه نشر صدرا ، تهران – ایران -199-203 ##-       مطهری، مرتضی(1384). عدل الهی. تهران: صدرا. ##-       موسوی گیلانی ، سید رضا ؛ موسوی ، سید جعفر ؛ اصلی ، محمد مهدی (1395) بررسی ارتباط بین عدالت سازمانی و هوشمندی رقابتی با اثر بخشی کارکنان اداره ورزش و جوانان استان سیستان و بلوچستان ، دوره 3، شماره 1 - شماره پیاپی 9، صفحه 39-46 ##-       نادری قمی، محمدمهدی(1357). «درآمدی بر ارتقای وجدان کاری». فرایند مدیریت و توسعه، ش 1: 7-1. ##-       نوری ، حسین؛ خلیلی، مجید (1394) . ﻧﻘﺶ ﻓﺮﻫﻨﮓ اﺳﻼﻣﯽ ﺳﺎزﻣﺎﻧﯽ در ﺳﻼﻣﺖ اداری ﺳﺎزﻣﺎﻧﯽ (ﻣﻄﺎﻟﻌﮥ ﻋﻘﯿﺪﺗﯽ ﺳﯿﺎﺳﯽ ﻓﺮﻣﺎﻧﺪﻫﯽ اﻧﺘﻈﺎﻣﯽ اﺳﺘﺎن آذرﺑﺎﯾﺠﺎنﺷﺮﻗﯽ).فصلنامه دانش انتظامی آذربایجانشرقی ،  سال پنجم ، شماره چهارم (پیاپی 19)57-94 ##-       یعقوبی ، مریم، سقاییان نژاداصفهانی ، سکینه،  ابوالقاسم گرجی حسن،  نوروزی محسن، رضایی فاطمه (1388) رابطه عدالت سازمانی بارضایت شغلی و تعهد سازمانی در بین کارکنان بیمارستان های منتخب دانشگاه علوم پزشکی اصفهان ، مدیریت سلامت  ، دوره12 ،  شماره  35 ؛ از صفحه 25 تا صفحه 32 . ##-       هنری، حبیب(1382). طراحی و تبیین نظام اطلاعاتی و سیستم بهره‌وری منابع انسانی در سازمان تربیت‌بدنی، فدراسیون‌های ورزشی منتخب و کمیته المپیک. رسالۀ دکتری مدیریت ورزشی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس. ##-       Holly quran  ##-       Nahjolbalagheh;(2002 ) translated by m. dashti; ghom:khoshroo ##-       Abde ali ,GH . ( 2012  ). “The relation between perceived organizational justice and worklife quality pattern based on nahjolbalagheh among facoor company employees”.; M.A. thesis ;business management; Isfahan  university . ##-       Abzari , m. ( 2006  ). “Organizational behavior management”. Isfahan: arkan. ##-       Allameh ,S and Boostani, H. ( 2014  ). “The relation between perceived organizational justice based on nahjolbalagheh and organizational citizenship bahaviour”.; Islamic management journal : N:2: 185-205 . ##-       Amadi , A. ( 1998  ). “gherarol hekam and dorarol kalam”.translated by rasooli mahalati; Tehran: Islamic culture office . ##-       Attaran,J and others ( 2016  ). “Godfearing as a criteria in cultural policy making based on holly quran ”.; public management researches: N:33: 5-23 . ##-       Blakely, G.L.; M.C. Anderns &amp; R.H. Moorman (2005). “The Moderating Effects of Aquity Sensitivity on the Relationship between Organizational Justice and Organizational Citizenship Behaviors”. Journal of Business and Psychology, 20(2): 259-273. ##-       Cohen, V.; Y. Charash Y &amp; P.E. Spector (2001). The Role of Justice in Organizations: A Meta-Analysis”. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes, Vol. 80: 278. ##-       Colquitt, J.A. (2001). “On the Dimensionality of Organizational Justice: A Construct Validation of a Measure”. Journal of Applied Psychology, 86/3: 386-400.De Coninck, J.B. (2010). The Effect of Organizational Justice. Perceived Organizational. ##-       Danaee fard, H. and others ( 2007  ). “Quantitative research methodology in management”.; Tehran: saffar pub . ##-       Dehghanian ,H. and others (2011   ). “the relation between organizational justice and    organizational commitment in an insurance company ”.insurance research bulletin ; Tehran: Islamic culture office, No.2.P: 153-180. ##-       Ebne baboyeh , A. ( 1982  ). “maaniol akhbar”.; ghom : Islamic publication  office . ##-       Fischer, Ronald  (2005) Rewarding employee loyalty: An organizational justice approach international Journal of Organisational Behaviour, Volume 8 (3), 486-503Gomes, D.R. (2009). Organizational Change and Job Satisfaction: the Mediating Role of Organizational Commitment. Exedra, 1. Junho. ##-       Greenberg, J &amp; Linda F.A (2000). The pursuit of organizational justice: From conceptualization to implication to application “in C.L cooper &amp; E.A Locke (Eds). Journal of Business Research, Vol 63, No 12, pp1349-1355 ##-       Greenberg, J. (1990). Organization Justice: Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow. Handbook of Industrial and Organizational Psychology, Chicago: Rand McNally. ##-        Honari, habib. (2003). “Planning the information system and human rescorces productivity system in sport organization, selected sport federations and Olympic commity; PH.D. Thisis in sport management; tarbiat Modarres University. ##-       kazemi, bahram. (  2003 ). “Justice in islam political thoughts ”.; ghom: boostane ketab pub . ##-        Majlesi , m.b. ( 1943  ). “baharol anvar”.reseached by seyyed javad alavi; Tehran: Islamic books office ##-       Moosavi gilani, Seyyed reza and others. (2016   ). “The relation between organizational justice and competitive intelligence with the effectiveness of youth and sport office employees  of sistan and baloochestan province;   N:1: 39-46 . ##-       Motahhari, morteza (2000  ), a review of nahjolbalagheh, sadra pub. ; Tehran: P: 199-203.    ##-       Motahhari, morteza (2005  ), Divine justice, sadra pub. ; Tehran.    ##-       Naderi ghomi, mohammad mahdi ( 1978 ), a survey to develop the Work ethic , management and development process  ; N: 1; 1-7.    ##-       Niehoff BR, Moorman R H. (1993) Justice as a mediator of the relationship between methods of monitoring and organizational citizenship behavior. Acad Manage J.  36(3): 527-57Nurmaya, E. (2012). Perceived Organizational Justice and Workplace Deviance: The Mediating Role of Psychological Contract Breach and Psychological Contract Violation. Doctor of Business Administration UKM, Malaysia. ##-       Noori, hossein and khalili, majeed (2015  ), the role of organizational Islamic culture in organizational health  , azarbayjan sharghi police knowledge quarterly   ; N: 4; 57-94.   ##-       Orlando, C. Richard (2002). “Procedural Voice and Distributive Justice”. Journal of Business Research, Vol. 55, issue 9. ##-       Parker, I. (2005) Qualitative Psychology: Introducing Radical Research. Open University Press, Maidenhead. ##-       Rabbins, p. Stephen ( 2008  ). “Essentials of organizational behavior”.translated by A. Parsayan and S.M.A. arabi. Tehran: cultural research bureau  . ##-       Ragheb isfahani, H. ( 1991  ). “Mofradate Alfaze Ghoraan”.; Beirut : darol ghalam pub . ##-       Rezaian, A. (  2004 ). “Political behavior management in organization”.; Tehran: samt pub . ##-       Sadeghi , mohammad taghi ( 2011  ). “Justice: organizational integration”; misaghe modiran: N:53 . ##-       Satvat,H. (  2000 ). “Work ethic factors from the viewpoint of Tehran university staff”.; M.A. thesis ; management faculty ; Tehran university . ##-       Seyyed javadin (2007). “The effectiveness of organizational justice on job and organizational satisfaction”.; business management magazine; N:1 ; P: 55-70. ##-       Sharifi, mahin ( 2011  ). “about Godfearing”.; bayyenat: N:71 . ##-       Taylor, A.G.W. (2003). “Justice as a Basic Human Need”. New Ideas in Psychology, Vol. 21: 209-219. ##-       Yaghoobi, maryam and others. ( 2009  ). “The relation between organizational justice and job satisfaction and organizational commitment among the employees of Isfahan medical sciences university selected hospitals  ; health management ;   N:35: 25-32 . ##-       Zapata, C.; J.A. Phelan, B.A. Colquitt &amp; B.L Scott (2008). “Procedural Justice, Interactional Justice and Task Performance: The Mediating Role of Intrinsic Motivation”. Organizational Behavior &amp; Human Decision Process.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مطالعۀ نقش هویت مذهبی در شکل‌گیری هویت ملی دانشجویان هوادار تیمهای ملی (مورد مطالعه: تیم ملی فوتبال و بسکتبال)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Role of Religious Identity in the Formation of National Identity in Student fans of National Teams (Case Study: National Football and Basketball Team)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف محققان از اجرای این پژوهش، بررسی نقش هویت مذهبی در شکل‌گیری هویت ملی دانشجویان هوادار تیمهای ملی فوتبال و بسکتبال بود. روش: این پژوهش از نظر هدف، کاربردی و از نوع توصیفی پیمایشی است. جامعۀ آماری پژوهش، کلیۀ دانشجویان هوادار پسر دانشگاه تهران بودند که 597 نفر از آنان به طور در دسترس پرسشنامۀ تحقیق را تکمیل کردند. ابزار پژوهش، پرسشنامه‌های طراحی‌شدۀ هویت مذهبی و ملی بر اساس چارچوب بوگدانوو بود که روایی آن توسط 12 نفر از خبرگان تأیید و ضریب آلفای کرونباخ برای دو پرسشنامه، به ترتیب 93/0 و 91/0 محاسبه شد. داده‌ها با معادلات ساختاری در نرم‌افزار وارپ پی.ال.اس. نسخۀ پنج تحلیل و شاخصهای برازش مدل اندازه‌گیری تأیید شدند. یافته‌ها: هویت مذهبی بر هویت ملی دانشجویان شیعه و سنی، دارای اثر مثبت معنادار است. همچنین در حالت کلی هویت مذهبی بر هویت ملی دانشجویان اثر مثبت معنادار دارد. مقدار ضریب تعیین نشان داد هویت مذهبی تنها می‌تواند 8/27 درصد از واریانس هویت ملی را تبیین کند. نتیجه‌گیری: با توجه ضعیف بودن هویت مذهبی در شکل‌گیری هویت ملی، محیط‌های ورزشی می‌توانند با کاهش محدودیتهای ساختاری، احساسات و تجارب مشترک را افزایش داده، منجر به تقویت هویت ملی شوند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives:The purpose of this study is to investigate the role of religious identity in the formation of the national identity of national football and basketball fans. Method: The research is an applied and descriptive survey. The statistical population of this research is all students of Tehran University, which 597 volunteers completed the research questionnaire. The research instrument is a questionnaire for the national and religious identity of Bogdanov (2011), whose validity was confirmed by 12 experts. Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient for both questionnaires was 0.93 and 0.91, respectively. Data were analyzed by structural equations in Warp pls 5 and fit index of the model was confirmed. Results: The results showed that the religious identity had a positive effect on the national identity of Shiite and Sunni students, respectively, equal to 0.591 and 0.432, respectively. In general, religious identity had a positive effect on students&#039; national identity of 52.88. The R2 also showed that religious identity can only explain 27.8% of the variance of national identity. Accordingly, other effective variables in the student&#039;s national identity should be considered. Conclusion: Due to the weakness of religious identity in the formation of a national identity, sports environments can increase common constraints by reducing structural constraints and lead to the strengthening of national identity.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>327</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>340</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهنام</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نقی پور گیوی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت ورزشی، دانشکده تربیت بدنی و علوم ورزشی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت ورزشی، دانشکده تربیت بدنی و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>behnam.naghipour@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ستاره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اسکندری</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت راهبردی در سازمانهای ورزشی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت راهبردی در سازمانهای</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>eskandari.s7091@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احسان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی ترکمانی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت ورزشی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ehsan.mohamadi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عباس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نظریان مادوانی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار مدیریت ورزشی، دانشگاه تربیت دبیر شهید رجایی تهران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار مدیریت ورزشی، دانشگاه تربیت دبیر</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abbasnazarian@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هویت ملی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هویت مذهبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دانشجویان ایرانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تیمهای ملی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-       امینی، محمد؛ حمید رحیمی و حمید نعمت‌اللهی(1396). «بررسی ابعاد هویت ملی و دینی دانشجویان (مورد مطالعه: دانشگاه کاشان)». نامۀ آموزش عالی، دورۀ دهم، ش 39: 182-157. ##-       ایمان، محمدتقی و علی روحانی(1392). «ﻫﻮﻳﺖ ﺍﺳﻼﻣﻰ ﻭ ﻫﻮیتهای ﺭﻗﻴﺐ(هویت جهانی، ملی و قومی)؛ مطالعۀ موردی: دانشجویان دانشگاه شیراز». تحقیقات فرهنگی، دورۀ ششم، ش 1: 148-127. ##-       حسینی، فریده سادات؛ محمد مزیدی و مسعود حسین چاری(1389). «پیش‌بینی سبکهای هویت بر اساس جهت‌گیری‌های مذهبی در میان دانشجویان دانشگاه شیراز». اندیشه‌های نوین تربیتی، دورۀ ششم، ش 1: 71-53. ##-       خواجه‌نوری، بیژن؛ ماندانا کریمی و سما خجسته(1394). «بررسی رابطۀ فرایند جهانی شدن فرهنگی و هویت مذهبی در ایران(مطالعۀ موردی: گروههای قومی لر شهر نورآباد ممسنی و عرب شهر کنگان و توابع)». تحقیقات فرهنگی ایران، دورۀ هشتم، ش 1: 45-23. ##-       درویشی، لیلا و پروین احمدی(1391). «تحلیل محتوای برنامه‌های فرهنگی دورۀ متوسطه بر اساس نمادهای ملی و مذهبی». پژوهش در برنامه‌ریزی درسی، دورۀ نهم، ش 35: 32-15. ##-       رضایی، احمد؛ سیروس منصوری بککی و میمنت عابدینی بلترک(1390). «جایگاه برنامه‌های درسی دانشگاهی در تقویت هویت ملی دانشجویان». مطالعات ملی، دوره دوازدهم، ش 1: 71-53. ##-       زاهد، سعید(1384). «هویت ملی ایرانیان». راهبرد توسعه، ش 4: 138-129. ##-       طباطبایی، سید محمدحسین(1362). تفسیر المیزان. ترجمه ناصر مکارم شیرازی. تهران: بنیاد علمى و فکرى علامه طباطبایى با همکارى مؤسسه نشر فرهنگى رجاء و مؤسسه امیرکبیر. ##-       گل‌محمدی، احمد(1380). «جهانى شدن و بحران هویت». مطالعات ملی، دورۀ سوم، ش 10: 49-13. ##-       گنجی، محمد؛ زهرا نعمت‌الهی و زهره طاهری(1389). «هویت دینی و سرمایۀ اجتماعی در بین مردم شهر کاشان». جامعه‌شناسی کاربردی، دورۀ بیست و یکم، ش 4: 144-123. ##-       گودرزی، محمود؛ ابوالفضل فراهانی، ابراهیم علیدوست قهفرخی و امین جلال‌منش(1389). «بررسی هویت دینی و ملی جوانان کشتی‌گیر و فوتبالیست شهر تهران». المپیک، سال هجدهم، ش 3: 31-21. ##-       محسنین، شهریار و محمدرحیم اسفیدانی(1393). معادلات ساختاری مبتنی بر رویکرد حداقل مربعات جزئی. تهران: مهربان. ##-       هاشمی، سید ضیاء و محمدرضا جوادی یگانه(1386). «فوتبال و هویت ملی». مطالعات ملی، دورۀ هشتم، ش 2: 124-107. ##-       Bogdanov, D. (2011). Influence of National Sport Team Identity on National Identity. Doctor of Philosophy. The Florida State University. ##-       Cronin, M. (2003). “Projecting the Nation through Sport and Culture: Ireland, Aonach Tailteann and the Irish Free State, 1924-32”. Journal of Contemporary History, 38(3): 395-411. ##-       Elena, S. (2016). “National Identity as Core Concept for the European Standardization Procedure”. Procedia Economics and Finance, 39: 458-468. ##-       Gelisli, Y. &amp; L. Beisenbayeva (2015). “Opinions of the University Students Studying in Kazakhstan about National Identity”. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 197: 486-493. ##-       Heere, B. &amp; J.D. James (2007). “Stepping Outside the Lines: Developing a Multi-Dimensional Team Identity Scale Based on Social Identity Theory”. Sport Management Review, 10(1): 65-91. ##-       Keaton, S.A. &amp; C.C. Gearhart (2014). “Identity Formation, Identity Strength, and Self-Categorization as Predictors of Affective and Psychological Outcomes: A Model Reflecting Sport Team Fans’ Responses to Highlights and Lowlights of a College Football Season”. Communication &amp; Sport, 2(4): 363-385. ##-       Kersting, N. (2007). “Sport and National Identity: A Comparison of the 2006 and 2010 FIFA World Cups™”. Politikon, 34(3): 277-293. ##-       Lau, P.W.; M.H. Lam, B.W. Leung, C.r. Choi &amp; L.B. Ransdell (2012). “The Longitudinal Changes of National Identity in Mainland China, Hong Kong and Taiwan before, During and after the 2008 Beijing Olympics Games”. The International Journal of the History of Sport, 29(9): 1281-1294. ##-       Mariya, Y.L. (2018). “On Identity and Sport Conduct of Student-Athletes: Considering Athletic and Academic Contexts”. Psychology of Sport and Exercise, 34: 10-19. ##-       Smith, A.D. (1991). National Identity(Reprint Ed.). London: Penguin. ##-       Stryker, S. &amp; P.J. Burke (2000). “The Past, Present, and Future of an Identity Theory”. Social Psychology Quarterly, 63(4): 284-297. ##-       Tonts, M. &amp; K. Atherley (2010). “Competitive Sport and the Construction of Place Identity in Rural Australia”. Sport in Society, 13(3): 381-398. ##-       Amini, M.; H. Rahimi &amp; H. Nematolahi (2017). “Investigating the Dimensions of Students’ Religious and National Identity (the Case of University of Kashan)”. Higher Education Letter, 10(39): 157-182. ##-       Darvishi, L. &amp; P. Ahmadi (2012). “Content Analys of the Cultural Activities in the Secondary Education Based on National and Relious Symbols”. Research in Curriculum Planning, 2(8): 15-32. ##-       Ganji, M., Z. Nematolahi &amp; Z. Taheri (2011). “Relationship between Religious Identity and Social Capital in Kashan the kashan City”. Journal of Applied Sociology, 21(4): 123-144. ##-       Gol-Mohammadi, A. (2001). “Globalization and Crisis o Identity”. National Studies Quarterly, 10(1): 13-49. ##-       Goudarzi, M.; A. Farahani, I. Alidoust Qahfarhi &amp; A. Jalal Manesh (2010). “Investigating the Religious and National Identity of the wrestler and Footballers of Tehran City”. Olympics, 18(3): 21-31. ##-       Hashemi, S.Z. &amp; M. Javadi Yeganeh (2006). “Football and National Identity”. National Studies Quarterly, 2(1): 107-124. ##-       Hosseini, F.S.; M. Mazidi &amp; M. Hosseinchari (2010). “Prediction Identity Styles by Religious Orientation in Shiraz University Students”. New Thoughts on Education, 6(1): 53-72. ##-       Iman, M. &amp; A. Rouhani (2013). “Islamic Identity and Competitive Identities (Global, National and Ethnic Identity); A Case Study of Shiraz University Students”. Journal of Iran Cultural Research, 6(1): 127-148. ##-       Khajeh Noori, B.; M. Karimi &amp; S. Khojaste (2015). “The Study of the Relationship between Cultural Globalization Process and Religious Identity in Iran; (Case study: Lur Ethnic Groups of Noorabad e Mamasani City and Arabs of Kangan City and Environs)”. Journal of Iran Cultural Research, 8(1): 23-45. ##-       Mohsenin, S. &amp; M.R. Esfidani (2014). Structural Equations Based on Partial Least Squares Approach. Tehran: Mehraban Publication. ##-       Rezaei, A., S. Mansouri Bakaki &amp; M. Abedini Baltork (2011). “The Status of Collegiate Hidden Curriculum on the Fortification of Student’s National Identity”. National Studies Quarterly, 12(1): 53-71. ##-       Tabatabai, M.H. (1983). Al-Mizan: Tafsir Al-Quran. Tehran: Allameh Foundation. ##-       Zahed, S. (2005). “Iranian National Identity”. Development Strategy, 4(1): 129-138.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>طراحی الگوی مفهومی اسلام برای عدالت در نظام جبران خدمات، مبتنی بر آموزه‌های نهج‌البلاغه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Planning the Islamic Conceptual Pattern for Justice in Compensation for Services System Based on the Teachings of Nahj Al-Balaghah</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: نیروی انسانی از مهم‌ترین ارکان سازمان در پیشبرد اهدافش است؛ لذا در ازای خدمتی که به سازمان ارائه می‌دهد، سازمان وظیفه دارد خدمت او را به نحوی شایسته جبران کند. هدف از نگارش پژوهش حاضر، استخراج الگوی عدالت در جبران خدمات در ادبیات مدیریت اسلامی بود. روش: روش تحقیق، تحلیل مضمون بود. با کمک نرم‌افزار Maxqda، از بین 473 عبارت، 196 کد بدون تکرار انتخاب شد که منجر به تولید 17 مضمون پایه و در نهایت، در سه مضمون سازمان‌دهنده جمع‌بندی شد. یافته‌ها: با تأکید بر مفهوم فراگیر و گستردۀ جبران خدمات(اعم از مؤلفه‌های مادی و معنوی)، مؤلفه‌های جبران خدمت عادلانه از متن نامه‌ها و خطبه‌ها و حکمتهای نهج‌البلاغه استخراج شد و الگوی شبکۀ مفهومی آن شکل گرفت.  نتیجه‌گیری: نگاه امیرالمؤمنین(ع) در نهج‌البلاغه به جبران خدمت، در پرداخت خلاصه نمی‌شود. برای ایجاد نظام جبران خدمات عادلانه، باید همۀ ابعاد جبران خدمت اعم از رفتارها و تعاملات و همچنین رویّه‌های سازمانی نیز عادلانه باشند تا عدالت در جبران خدمت برای زیردستان به طور کامل محقق شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives:Human resource is one of the main pillars of an organization in advancing its goals. Therefore, in return for the service it provides to the organization, it is the duty of the organization to properly compensate for its service. Different dimensions of compensation in the conventional management literature have been highly researched. However, the present study has been formed in the context of Islamic studies and aims at extracting the model of justice in compensation for services in Islamic management literature. Method: To do this, by means of thematic analysis method and with the help of Maxqda software, out of 473 selected terms, 196 non-repetitive codes were selected, which resulted in the production of 17 basic themes and finally was summarized in 3 organizer themes. Results: By emphasizing the widespread and comprehensive concept of compensating for services, which includes material and spiritual components, the elements of fair compensation were extracted from the text of the letters and sermons and the wisdom of Nahj al-Balaghah. And its conceptual network pattern was formed. Conclusion: The viewpoint of Amir al-Mu&#039;minin (as) in the Nahj al-Balaghah toward compensation is not summarized to payment. In order to establish a fair compensation system, all aspects of compensation, including behaviors and interactions, as well as organizational procedures, should be fair, so that justice in compensating for subordinates would be completely realized.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>341</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>358</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حکاک</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت استراتژیک،‌ دانشیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی و اداری، دانشگاه لرستان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت استراتژیک،‌ دانشیار گروه مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hakak.m@lu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صالحی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت رفتارسازمانی، دانشگاه لرستان.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت رفتارسازمانی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hasan_salehi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>یونس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فرقانی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت خط مشی گذاری عمومی، دانشگاه تهران- پردیس فارابی.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت خط مشی گذاری عمومی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جبران خدمت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عدالت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نهج‌البلاغه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل مضمون</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-       نهج‌البلاغه. سید رضی(1379). ترجمۀ محمد دشتی. قم: مشرقین، چ ششم. ##-       آرمسترانگ, مایکل. (1390). مدیریت جبران خدمات. (س. ر. سید جوادین, مترجم) تهران: انتشارات ارگ. ##-       بروکنر، جوئل و فیلیپس سی‌گل(1382). «سیر تاریخی نظریه‌ها و تحقیقات دربارۀ عدالت سازمانی». ترجمۀ محمد ازگلی. مصباح (علوم انسانی)، ش46: 134-115. ##-       توسلی، حسین(1386). «رابطۀ حق و عدالت». پژوهشهای فلسفی کلامی دانشگاه قم، ش 8 (1): 109-91. ##-       دانایی‌فرد، حسن و مظفری(1387). «ارتقاء روایی و پایایی در پژوهشهای کیفی مدیریتی: تأملی بر استراتژی‌های ممیزی پژوهشی». پژوهشهای مدیریت منابع انسانی، سال اول، ش 1: 23-1. ##-       دانایی‌فرد، حسن؛ سید مهدی الوانی و عادل آذر(1388). روش‌شناسی پژوهش کیفی در مدیریت: رویکردی جامع. تهران: صفار، چ سوم. ##-       دشتی، محمد(1379). روشهای برداشت از نهج‌البلاغه. قم: مؤسسۀ تحقیقاتی امیرالمؤمنین. ##-       دلشاد تهرانی، مصطفی(1379). ارباب امانت: اخلاق اداری در نهج‌البلاغه. تهران: دریا. ##-       دلشاد تهرانی، مصطفی(1389). «حقوق و عدالت در نهج‌البلاغه». پژوهشهای نهج‌البلاغه، ش 29: 91-67. ##-       دلشاد تهرانی، مصطفی(1392). دلالت دولت: آیین‌نامه حکومت و مدیریت در عهدنامه مالک اشتر. تهران: انتشارات دریا. ##-       رابینز, استیفن. پی. وتیموتی, ای. جاج. (1389). مبانی رفتار سازمانی. (سید. محمد. اعرابی, &amp; سید. محمد. تقی زاده مطلق, مترجم) تهران: دفتر پژوهشهای فرهنگی. ##-       رضائیان، علی و لیلا میرزاده(1389). «تأثیر برداشت کارکنان از عدالت سازمانی بر رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی آنان». اخلاق در علوم و فنّاوری، ش 5 (2): 102-94. ##-       سیدجوادین، سید رضا(1387). مبانی مدیریت منابع انسانی. تهران: دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران. ##-       سیدجوادین، سید رضا؛ محمدمهدی فراحی و غزاله طاهری عطار(1387). «شناخت نحوۀ تأثیرگذاری ابعاد عدالت سازمانی بر جنبه‌های گوناگون رضایت شغلی و سازمانی». مدیریت بازرگانی، ش 1(1): 70-55. ##-       سیدعلیپور، سید خلیل(1383). «نقش تشویق و تنبیه در مدیریت اسلامی». مدیریت، ش 1: 106-94. ##-       شعبانی، احمد؛ و محمدمهدی نجفی علمی(1392). «نگاهی تحلیلی- تطبیقی به نظامهای دستمزد با تأکید بر الگوی اسلامی دستمزد در سطح کلان». مطالعات اقتصاد اسلامی، ش 10: 64-36. ##-       علامه، سید محسن و حمیدرضا بوستانی(1393). «بررسی رابطۀ عدالت سازمانی ادراک شده مبتنی بر آموزه‌های نهج‌البلاغه با رفتار شهروندی سازمانی». مدیریت اسلامی، ش 8: 206-185. ##-       قلیچ، وهاب(1389). «معیارهای عدالت توزیعی؛ مقایسۀ تطبیقی دیدگاه‌های جان راولز و شهید مطهری». مطالعات اقتصاد اسلامی، ش 1 (3): 163-145. ##-       قوامی, سید. صمصام الدین., و قریب, غلامرضا. (1392). بررسی نظام جبران خدمات در اسلام. اسلام و پژوهشهای مدیریتی , 7 (1), 77-90. ##-       نقی پورفر، ولی الله. و جعفرپور، محمود. (1389). مطالعه ی تطبیقی شاخص های تأثیر گذار بر تحقق عدالتمراوده ای درسازمانمقایسه ی دو دیدگاه مدیریت اسلامی و مدیریت غربی. مدیریت اسلامی. ش 81: 37-86 ##-       Nahj al-Balagheh. Seyyed Razi (1379). Translator: Mohammad Dashti. Qom: The Mashreqin Publication, Sixth Edition. ##-       Adams, J. &amp; Stacey (1965). “Inequity in Social Exchange”. Advances in Experimental Social Psychology, 2: 261-299. ##-       Armstrong, M. (2010). Hand Book of Reward mManagement. London: Koganpage. ##-       Armstrong, M. &amp; M. Helen (2007). Reward Management, Hand Book fo Remuneration Strategy and Practice. London: Koganpage. ##-       Aryee, S. (2004). “Exchange Fairness and Employee Performance: An Examination of the Relationship between Organizational Politics and Procedural Justice”. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes, 94 (1): 1-14. ##-       Braun, V. &amp; V. Clarke (2006). Using Thematic Analysis in Psychology (Vol. 2). Qualitative Research in Psychology. ##-       Chan, M. (2000). “Organizational Justice and Land Mark Cases”. International Journal of Analysis, 8(1): 68-88. ##-       Cropanzano, R.; D. Brown &amp; S. Gilliland (2007). “The Management of Organizational Justice”. Academy of Management Perspectives, 21(4): 34-48. ##-       Folger, R. &amp; R. Cropanzano (1998). Organizational Justice and Human Resource Management. Sage Publication. ##-       Heneman, R.L.; D.B. Greenberger &amp; J.A. Fox (2002). “Pay Increase Satisfaction”. Human Resource Management Review, 12: 63-74. ##-       King, N. &amp; C. Horrocks (2010). Interviews in Qualitative Research. London: Sage. ##-       Lambert, E. (2003). “The Impact of Organizatinal Justice on Correctional Staff”. Journal of Criminal Justice, 31(2): 4-5. ##-       Manne, H. (2009). Enterpreneurship, Compensation and Corporation. Second Annual Research Symposiom in Economics and Low of the Entrepreneur. ##-       Milcovich, G. &amp; J. Newman (2008). Compensation. Irwin Professional Pub. ##-       Nowakowski, J.M. &amp; D.E. Colon (2005). “Organizational Justice: Looking Back Looking Forward”. The International Journal of Conflict Management, 1. ##-       Parker, D. &amp; J. Kohlmeyer (2005). “Organizational Justice and Turnover in Public Accounting Firms: A Research Note”. Organization and Society, 30: 357-367. ##-       Sinkovics, R.R. (2008). “Enhancing the Trustworthiness of Qualitative Research in International Business”. MIR, 48(6): 689-714. ##-       Twining, J. (2000). A Naturalistic Journey into the Collaboratory: In Search of Understanding for Prospective Participants. Denton: Texas Woman’s University. ##-       Allameh, Seyyed Mohsen &amp; Hamid Reza Boustany (2014). “The Study of the Relationship between Perceived Organizational Justice Based on Nahj Balbaragh&#039;s Teachings and Organizational Citizenship Behavior”. Islamic Management, 8: 185-206. ##-       Bruckner, Joel &amp; Phyllis Siegel (2003). “Historical History of Theories and Researches on Organizational Justice”. Translator Mohammad Ozgoli. Mesbah (Humanities), 46: 115-134. ##-       Danaeefard, Hasan; Seyyed Mahdi Alvani &amp; Adel Azar (2009). Qualitative Research Methodology in Management: A Comprehensive Approach. Third Edition. Tehran: Saffar. ##-       Danaeefard, Hasan &amp; Mozaffari (2008). “Improvement of Validity and Reliability in Qualitative Management Researches: Reflection on Research Audit Strategies”. Quarterly Journal of Human Resource Management Research, 1 (1): 1-23. ##-       Dashti, Mohammad (2000). Methods of Extraction Point from Nahj al-Balagheh. Qom: Amir Al-Momenin Research Institute. ##-       Delshad Tehrani, Mustafa (2013). Government Implication: the Rules of Government and Administration in the Malik Ashtar Treaty. Tehran: Darya Publishing. ##-       Delshad Tehrani, Mustafa (2000). Master of Safekeeping: Administrative Ethics in Nahj al-Balagheh. Tehran: Darya Publishing. ##-       Delshad Tehrani, Mustafa (2010). “Rights and Justice in Nahj al-Balagheh”. Researchs of Nahj al-Balagheh, 29: 67-91. ##-       Qelich, Wahhab (2010). “Criteria of Distributed Justice: Comparative Comparison of John Rawls and Martyr Motahhari&#039;s Views”. Quarterly Journal of Islamic Studies, 1(3): 145-163. ##-       Rezaeian, Ali. &amp; Leila Mirzadeh (2010). “The Effect of Employees&#039; Perception of Organizational Justice on Their Citizenship Organizational Behaviors”. Journal of Ethics in Sciences and Technology, 5 (2): 94-102. ##-       Seyyed Alipour, Seyyed Khalil (2004). “The Role of Encouragement and Punishment in Islamic Management”. Quarterly Journal of Management, 1: 94-106. ##-       Seyed Javadin, Seyed Reza (2008). Fundamentals of Human Resources Management. Faculty of Management of University of Tehran Publication. ##-       Seyyed Javadin, Seyed Reza; Mohammad Mehdi Farahi &amp; Ghazaleh Taheri Attar (2008). “Understanding the Manner of Effect of Organizational Justice Dimensions on Various Aspects of Job Satisfaction and Organizational”. Business Management, 1 (1): 55-70. ##-       Sha&#039;bani, Ahmad &amp; Mohammad Mehdi Najafi Alami (2013). “An Analytical-Comparative Look at Wage Systems with an Emphasis on the Islamic Model of Wages at a Macro Level”. Half Year Journal of Islamic Economy Studies, 10: 36-64. ##-       Tavassoli, Hosein (2007). “The Relationship of the Right and Justice”. Quarterly Journal of Philosophical Theological Studies, University of Qom, 8 (1): 91-109. ##-       Boyatzis, R. E. (1998). Transforming qualitative information:thematic analysis and code development. Virginia: Sage Braun. ##-       Nazir, T., Shah, S. F., &amp; Zaman, K. (2014). Review of Literature on Expatriate Compensation and its Implication for Offshore Workforce. Iranian Journal of Management Studies (IJMS , 7, 203-221.(2) ##-       Robbins, S. P. (2002). Essentionals of organizational behavior seventh edition. New jersey: Prentice Hall. ##-       M Forret, M Sue Love, (2008). Employee justice perceptions and coworker relationships. Leadership &amp; Organization Development Journal 29 (3): 248-260 ##-       Armstrong, M. (1390). Reward Management(translaror: Seyyed Javadin, Seyed Reza). Tehran : Arg publication ##-       stephen p robbins timothy a judge. (1389). Organizational Behavior (translator: arabi sm &amp; taghizadeh motlagh sm). Tehran. The Office of cultural research. ##-       Ghavami  ss &amp; gharib gh. (1392). Study of compensation system in islam. Islam &amp; managerial research, 7 (1), 77-90 ##-       Naghi poorfar v &amp; Jafarpoor, M (1389). Comparative Study of Indicators Affecting the Realization of Interational Justice in the Organization Comparing the Two Views of Islamic Management and Western Management. Islamic management. 81: 37-86##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مسجد و نماز جماعت، استعاره‌ای از سازمان از دیدگاه اسلام؛: تفسیرها و برداشتهای مدیریتی و سازمانی از مسجد و نماز جماعت در مورد دانشگاه اسلامی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Mosque and Congregational Prayer Metaphors of the Organization from the View of Islam: Managerial and Organizational Concepts from the Mosque and Congregational Prayer for the Islamic University</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف از انجام این مقاله، بررسی جوانب مختلف مسجد و نماز جماعت و استنباط برداشتهای مدیریتی و سازمانی در خصوص دانشگاه اسلامی بود. روش: برای دستیابی به هدف، ابتدا سعی شد با رجوع به منابع مختلف اسلامی، با احکام و مسائل مربوط به مسجد و نماز جماعت آشنا شویم و سپس با دیدگاه جامع شکل‌گرفته، ابعاد دانشگاه اسلامی تبیین شود. یافته‌ها: با توجه به تعالیم اسلامی و احکام مطرح شده راجع به مسجد، ابعاد و کارکردها و مدل مطلوب دانشگاه اسلامی بیان شد. ویژگی‌ها و ابعاد وجودی امام جماعت و معیارهای انتخاب امام جماعت، مبنای مناسبی برای تعیین ملاکهای انتخاب افراد در دانشگاه اسلامی است. ایجاد رضایت در نیروی انسانی در مسجد و دانشگاه اسلامی برای اثربخشی و دستیابی به اهداف ضروری به نظر می‌رسد. احکام مسجد و نماز جماعت می‌تواند در ادارۀ امور و چگونگی انجام فعالیتها و فرایندها دانشگاه اسلامی راهگشا باشد. نتیجه‌گیری: تجزیه و تحلیل تطبیقی نماز جماعت، مسجد و دانشگاه اسلامی، ما را در شناخت ابعاد دانشگاه اسلامی و دستیابی به مدل مطلوب یاری می‌دهد. برداشتهای مدیریتی و سازمانی از احکام مسجد و نماز جماعت، اصول کاربردی دقیقی را به دست می‌دهد که می‌توانند روند توسعه و تعالی را در دانشگاه اسلامی تسهیل کنند و تسریع بخشند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives:Our goal in this article is to deduce the managerial and organizational findings for the Islamic University by examining the various aspects of the mosque and congregational prayer. Method: In order to achieve the goal, we first tried to get acquainted with the rulings and issues related to the mosque and congregational prayer, and in the next step we explained the dimensions of the Islamic University. Results: According to Islamic teachings dimensions, functions and optimal model of Islamic University were presented. The characteristics of the imam of the congregation are the basis for determining the criteria for selecting individuals in the Islamic University. The satisfaction of employees in the mosque and the Islamic University seems necessary for the effectiveness. As the paper shows, the rules of the mosque and congregational prayer can be used to manage affairs and carry out activities at the Islamic University. Conclusion: Comparative analysis of congregational prayer and mosque, and the Islamic University helps us to understand the dimensions of the Islamic University. The managerial and organizational concepts of the mosque and congregational prayer provide the exact application principles that can facilitate and accelerate the process of development and excellence at Islamic University.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>359</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>376</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عربشاهی کریزی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت دولتی. استادیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت دولتی. استادیار گروه مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.modares199@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مسجد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نماز جماعت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اسلام</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دانشگاه اسلامی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-       الوانی، مهدی(1379). مدیریت عمومی. تهران: نی. ##-       الوانی، سیدمهدی و محمدحسین رحمتی(1386). «شناخت سازمان با رویکرد استعاره‌ای: سازمان به مثابۀ کانون طیفهای متقاطع». روش‌شناسی علوم انسانی. سال سیزدهم، ش 53. ##-       الهامی‌نیا، علی‌اصغر(1389). «نماز و مدیریت بر خویش». حصون، ش 24. ##-       امام خمینی، سید روح‌الله(1377). رسالۀ توضیح المسائل. قم: قدر ولایت، چ پنجم. ##-       حسینی شاه‌ترابی، سید مرتضی(1391). «احیای کارکردهای مسجد». ماهنامه مسجد. ش 163. ##-       عابدی جعفری، حسن؛ محمدصابر جعفری، نسیبه‌سادات شبیری، منا فخریان نجفی‌کاشانی، راحیل شمس و نگار عرب(1388). «طراحی مدل مطلوب کارکرد و مدیریت مساجد به عنوان یک سازمان داوطلبانۀ مذهبی». مجله دانشکده علوم انسانی، سال چهاردهم. ش 60. ##-       عباسی، رسول؛ غلامرضا طالقانی، حسن عابدی جعفری و ابوالحسن فقیهی(1393/الف). «تدوین الگوی اقدامات اثربخش در مساجد». مطالعات مدیریت(بهبود و تحول)، سال بیست و سوم، ش 75. ##-       عباسی، رسول؛ حسن عابدی جعفری، غلامرضا طالقانی و ابوالحسن فقیهی(1393/ب). «تدوین الگوی کیفیت خدمات در مدیریت مسجد». مدیریت اسلامی، سال بیست و دوم، ش 2. ##-       عبداللهی، علی(1391). «مسجد نمونه؛ تجزیه و تحلیل سیستمی فرایند پرورش منابع انسانی». ماهنامه مسجد، ش 163. ##-       فجری، محمدمهدی(1388). «ویژگی‌های امام جماعت موّفق». مبلّغان، ش 118. ##-       قرائتی، محسن(1390). پرتوی از اسرار نماز. تهران: مرکز فرهنگی درسهایی از قرآن. ##-       کاشانی‌زاده، امیر مسلم(1391). «آسیب‌شناسی عملکرد امام جماعت از منظر نخبگان حوزوی و دانشگاهی». ماهنامه مسجد، ش 162. ##-       مصدق، هادی؛ محمدحسین سیّاح طاهری و جواد پورکریمی(1393). «دانشگاه اسلامی: مروری بر فعالیتها و ارائۀ الگویی برای تحقق». سومین کنفرانس الگوی اسلامی ایرانی پیشرفت. اردیبهشت و خرداد. ##-       منطقی، محسن و سید محمدرضا میرصانع(1394). «تبیین نظری نقش اقامۀ نماز در ارتقای رفتار کارکنان در سطح سازمان». اسلام و پژوهشهای مدیریتی، ش 11. ##-       Abbasi, R.; H. Abedi Jaafari, G. Taleghani &amp; A. Faghihi (2014). “Modeling the Quality of Services in Mosque Management”. Islamic Management, Vol. 22, No. 2. ##-       Abbasi, R.; G. Taleghani, H. Abedi Jaafari &amp; A. Faghihi (2014). “Formulating a Model of Effective Practices in Mosques”. Management Studies, Vol. 23, No. 75. ##-       Abdollahi, A. (2012). “Sample Mosque; Systematic Analysis of the Process of Training Human Resources”. Masjed, No. 163. ##-       Abedi Jaafari, H.; M.S. Jaafari, N.S. Shobeiri, M. Fakhrian Najafi Kashani, R. Shams &amp; N. Arab (2009). “Designing an Optimal Model for the Functioning and Management of Mosques as a Voluntary Religious Organization”. Journal of Human Science, Vol. 14, No. 60. ##-       Alvani, M. (2000). Public Management. Tehran: Ney. ##-       Alvani, M. &amp; M.H. Rahmati (2007). “Organizational Recognition with a Metaphorical Approach Organization as the Focal Point of Intersecting Spectrums”. Methodology of Social Sciences and Humanities Journal, Vol. 13, No. 53. ##-       Elhaminia, A.A. (2010). “Prayer and Community Management”. Morabbian, Vol. 10, No. 37. ##-       Elhaminia, A.A. (2010). “Prayer and Self-Management”. Hosun, No. 24. ##-       Fajri, M.M. (2009). “Features of a Successful Imam of the Congregation”. Moballeghan, No. 118. ##-       Hoseini Shah Torabi, S.M. (2012). “Reviving the Functions of the Mosque”. Masjed, No. 163. ##-       Imam Khomeini, S.R.A. (1998). Tawzih al-Masail. Qom: Ghadr Velayat. ##-               Kashahnizadeh, A.M. (2012). “Pathology of the Function of the Imam of the Congregation from the Perspective of the Seminary and Academic Elites”. Masjid, No. 162. ##-       Manteghi, M. &amp; S.M.R. Mirsane (2015). “Theoretical Explanation of the Role of Prayer in Promoting the Behavior of Employees at the Organization Level”. Islam and Management Researches, No. 11. ##-       Mosaddegh, H.; M.H. Saiyah Taheri &amp; J. Pourkarimi (2014). “Islamic University: Activities Review and Design for Establishment”. 3th Conference of Islamic-Iranian Model of Progress. ##-       Qaraati, M. (2011). The Radiance of the Secrets of Prayer. Tehran: Cultural Center of Lessons from the Qur&#039;an.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>شناسایی مؤلفه های شناختی سرمایه اجتماعی از دیدگاه امام خمینی(ره)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Identifying Cognitive Components of Social Capital from Imam Khomeini Point of View</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: پژوهش حاضر با هدف شناسایی مؤلفه های سرمایه اجتماعی در بعد شناختی(ذهنی) از دیدگاه حضرت امام خمینی(ره) در کتاب صحیفه نور انجام گرفت. روش: روش پژوهش کیفی، از نوع تحلیل محتوای استقرایی بود. بدین منظور از مجموع کتاب22 جلدی صحیفه امام خمینی(ره)، تعداد 15 جلد انتخاب و  با استفاده از فیش برداری به روش کتابخانه ای از طریق فرایندهای طبقه بندی نظام مند، کدبندی، و تم سازی مورد تحلیل قرار گرفت. یافته ها: نتایج نشان داد که &quot;خدا محوری&quot;، &quot;اسلام محوری&quot;، &quot;اعتماد&quot;، &quot;قانون گرایی&quot; و &quot;خدمت برای خدا و اعتقاد به نظارت الهی&quot;، مهمترین مؤلفه های بعد شناختی(ذهنی) سرمایه اجتماعی در بیانات امام خمینی(ره) بود که در این مقاله بدان پرداخته شده است. نتیجه گیری: نتایج این پژوهش نشان داد که حضرت امام(ره) همواره مردم و مسؤولان را به خدمت به خلق و توجه به دستورات الهی و سیره پیامبر(ص) و ائمه(ع) سفارش و بر ضرورت افزایش اعتماد و انسجام در پرتو عمل به قوانین تأکید نموده بود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives:This study aims to identifying components of social capital in cognitive and mental dimensions from Imam Khomeini point of view, in Sahifa Noor book. Method: Research method is qualitative and consists of inductive content analysis. For this purpose, from 22 volumes of Sahifa Noor book, 15volumes are selected and in order to make a relation between these books and social capital concepts, and by taking notes from library resources through classification processes, Coding and theme making, they have been analyzed. Results:  Results show &quot;god centeredness&quot;, &quot;Islam centeredness&quot;, &quot;trust&quot;, &quot;reliability&quot;, &quot;rule orienting and believeing  that god monitors us&quot;, are important factors of social capital&#039;s cognitive components from Imam Khomeini point of view. Conclusion: The authors of the article concluded that Imam Khomeini has recommended people and officials according to the commands of God and emphasis on the necessity of increasing trust and social integration and the practice of the laws.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>377</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>392</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عباس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زمانی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری تخصصی مدیریت رسانه ای، باشگاه پژوهشگران و نخبگان، واحد اصفهان(خوراسگان)، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، اصفهان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری تخصصی مدیریت رسانه ای، باشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zamani_abbas1000@yaho.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>اکبر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رستمی خوراسگانی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت امور  فرهنگی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان(خوراسگان).</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت امور  فرهنگی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abspress@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید‌هاشم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گلستانی</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری فلسفه و حکمت اسلامی، استاد گروه مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی آموزشی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان(خوراسگان)، اصفهان، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری فلسفه و حکمت اسلامی، استاد گروه مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آذر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قلی زاده</Family>
						<NameE>a</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>a</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مردم‌شناسی اجتماعی، استادیار گروه مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی فرهنگی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان (خوراسگان)، اصفهان، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مردم‌شناسی اجتماعی، استادیار گروه مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>azargholizade@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>امام خمینی(ره)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایه اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اعتماد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انسجام اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مشارکت اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نهادهای اجتماعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>-       اعتصامی، منصور و حامد فاضلی کبریا(1388). «درآمدی بر مدیریت امام علی(ع) از منظر مؤلفه‌های سرمایۀ اجتماعی». اندیشۀ مدیریت راهبردی، سال سوم، ش 2(پیاپی 6): 128-101. ##-       امام خمینی، سید روح الله(1369). صحیفه نور. تهران: مؤسسه تنظیم و نشر آثار امام خمینی (ره). ##-       پیریایی، صالحه و مرتضی منادی(۱۳۹۵). «بررسی منابع و پیامدهای سرمایۀ اجتماعی از دیدگاه دبیران دبیرستانهای دخترانه شهر اصفهان». قم: اولین کنفرانس بین‌المللی پژوهشهای نوین در حوزۀ علوم تربیتی و روان‌شناسی و مطالعات اجتماعی ایران. تاریخ مشاهده: 20/01/96، قابل دسترس در: http://www.civilica.com/Paper-ESCONF01-ESCONF01_064.html ##-       پیران، پرویز؛ میرطاهر موسوی و ملیحه شیانی( 1385 ) «کارپایه مفهومی و مفهوم سازی سرمایه اجتماعی(با تأکید بر شرایط ایران)»، فصلنامه علمی  پژوهشی رفاه اجتماعی، سال 6، شماره 23:  49-9. ##-       توکلی، عبدالله؛ علی پوربهروزان و دانیال محمدیانی(1396). «اعتماد به مثابۀ رکن اصلی سرمایۀ اجتماعی: ارائۀ الگویی مبتنی بر تعالیم اسلامی(مطالعۀ موردی: کتاب شریف میزان‌الحکمه)». مدیریت سرمایۀ اجتماعی، انتشار آنلاین در تاریخ 7/4/1396. تاریخ مشاهده: 27/04/96،  قابل مشاهده در: https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_62099.html ##-       توکلی، عبدالله؛ عبدالصمد عزیزپور لیندی، الهام رضایی و اشرف میرزایی(1393). «بررسی تأثیر سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر مؤلفه‌های سرمایۀ فکری(مورد مطالعه: اداره کل امور مالیاتی استان قم)». مدیریت سرمایۀ اجتماعی، دورۀ اول، ش 2: 287-265. ##-       تونکیس، فران(1387). اعتماد و سرمایۀ اجتماعی. ترجمه محمدتقی دلفروز. تهران: پژوهشکده مطالعات فرهنگی و اجتماعی. ##-       جعفری هرندی، رضا؛ احمدرضا نصر و سیدابراهیم میرشاه جعفری(1387). «تحلیل محتوا، روشی پرکاربرد در مطالعات علوم اجتماعی، رفتاری و انسانی با تأکید بر تحلیل محتوای کتابهای درسی». حوزه و دانشگاه، سال چهاردهم، ش 55: 58-33. ##-       جعفری، محمد؛ فتاح شریف‌زاده، وجه‌اله قربانی‌زاده، بهروز رضایی‌منش و ابوالقاسم دلخوش کسمایی(1391). «الگوی سرمایۀ اجتماعی، ابعاد و شاخصهای آن در کلانتری‌های تهران بزرگ». پژوهشهای مدیریت انتظامی‌، سال هفتم، ش 3: 396-370. ##-       جمشیدی‌ها، غلامرضا(1383). پیدایش نظریه‌های جامعه‌شناسی. تهران: دانشگاه تهران. ##-       حمیدی‌زاده، علی؛ فریبا شهیدزاده و عرفان موحدی‌فر(1393). «بررسی تأثیر مؤلفه‌های سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر نوآوری سازمانی (مورد مطالعه: اداره‌کل مخابرات شهرستان قم)». مدیریت سرمایۀ اجتماعی، دورۀ اول، ش 2: 223-203. ##-       رجایی، سیدعباس؛ احمد پوراحمد و وحید عباسی فلاح(1395). «بررسی رابطۀ سرمایۀ اجتماعی با احساس امنیت اجتماعی(مطالعۀ موردی شهر ورامین)». انجمن جغرافیای ایران، سال چهاردهم، ش 48: 50-31. ##-       رحمت‌اللهی، حسین؛ احسان آقامحمد آقایی و مهدی بالوی(1395). «کاهش سرمایۀ اجتماعی، دولت و مشارکت مردم». مدیریت سرمایۀ اجتماعی، دورۀ سوم، ش 3: 461-435. ##-       روشه، گی(1389). تغییرات اجتماعی. ترجمه منصور وثوقی. تهران: نی، چ بیست و یکم. ##-       رهبر، عباسعلی و فاطمه حیدری(1390). «تأثیر سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر ارتقاء سیاستگذاری».مطالعات روابط بین‌الملل، دورۀ چهارم، ش 14(پیاپی 15): 253-219. ##-       شجاعی باغینی، محمدمهدی(1387). مبانی مفهومی سرمایۀ اجتماعی. تهران:‌ پژوهشکده مطالعات فرهنگی و اجتماعی. ##-       صالحی امیری، سیدرضا(1388). مدیریت و سرمایۀ اجتماعی. تهران: مجمع تشخیص مصلحت نظام، پژوهشکده تحقیقات استراتژیک، گروه پژوهشی مطالعات بین‌الملل. ##-       عباس‌زاده، محمد؛ محمدباقر علیزاده اقدم و سیدرضا اسلامی بناب(1391). «بررسی رابطۀ بین سرمایۀ اجتماعی و آنومی اجتماعی». مطالعات و تحقیقات اجتماعی در ایران، دورۀ اول، ش 1: 172-145. ##-       فقیه خلجانی، سید فاطمه(1392). سرمایۀ اجتماعی در اندیشه و عمل امام خمینی(ره). تهران: مؤسسه تنظیم و نشر آثار امام خمینی و عروج. ##-       فقیهی، ابوالفضل و طاهره فیضی(1384). «سرمایۀ اجتماعی در سازمان». پیک نور، سال سوم، ش 3: 21-11. ##-       فوکویاما، فرانسیس(‌1379). پایان نظم. ترجمه غلامعباس توسلی. تهران: جامع ایرانیان. ##-       گنجی، محمد و مینا هلالی ستوده(1390/الف). «رابطه گونه‌های دینداری و سرمایۀ اجتماعی (رویکردی نظری و تجربی در بین مردم شهرستان کاشان)». جامعه‌شناسی کاربردی، دورۀ بیست و دوم، ش 2(پیاپی 42): 120-95. ##-       گنجی، محمد و مینا هلالی ستوده(1390/ب). شناسایی عوامل مدیریتی مؤثر بر جانشین‌پروری (مورد مطالعه: سازمانهای فرهنگی استان قم). پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد رشته تحول سازمانی. پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران. ##-       گیدنز، آنتونی(1380). پیامد‌های مدرنیته. ترجمه محسن ثلاثی. تهران: مرکز. ##-       محمودی، سمیرا؛ عبدالرضا رکن‌‌الدین افتخاری، غلامرضا غفاری و مهدی پورطاهری(1394). «تبیین اثرات انواع سرمایه‌های توسعه‌ای بر سرمایۀ اجتماعی(مورد: روستاهای استان خراسان رضوی)». اقتصاد فضا و توسعه روستایی، سال چهارم، ش 14: 190-169. ##-       مصطفی‌زاده، معصومه و محمدرضا صادقی(1393). «طراحی مدل توسعۀ سرمایۀ اجتماعی در دانشگاهها و مراکز آموزش عالی». مدیریت سرمایۀ اجتماعی، دورۀ اول، ش 2: 182-161. ##-       موسوی مقدم، سیدمحمد و مروّت محمدی(1395). «بررسی نقش مسجد در افزایش سرمایۀ اجتماعی بر اساس نماگرهای اصلی آن در قرآن و حدیث». مدیریت سرمایۀ اجتماعی، دورۀ سوم، ش 1: 162-139. ##-       نظرپور، محمدنقی و مصطفی منتظری مقدم(1389). «سرمایۀ اجتماعی و توسعۀ اقتصادی؛ مطالعه‌ای دربارۀ مشارکت اجتماعی از منظر اسلام». اقتصاد اسلامی‌، سال دهم، ش 37: 87-57. ##-       Abbaszadeh, M.; M.B. Alizadeh Eghdam &amp; S.R. Eslami Naab (2012). “&quot;The Relationship between Social Capital and Social Anomie”,Journal of Social Studies and Research in Iran, 1(1), spring 2012: 145-172. ##-       Bourdieu, P. (1983). Okonomisches Kapital, Kulturelles Kapital, Soziales Kapital. In Soziale Ungleichheiten (Soziale Welt, Sonderheft 2). R. Kreckel (Eds). Goettingen, Otto Schartz &amp; Co.: 183-198. ##-       Coleman, J. S. (1988). “SOCIAL‌ CAPITAL‌ in the Creation of Human Capital”. American Journal of Sociology, 94: 95-120. ##-       Earney, S. &amp; A. Martin (2009). “Job rotation at Cardiff University Library Service: A pilot study”. Journal of Librarianship and Information, 41(4): 213-226. ##-       Eetesami, M. &amp; H. Faseli Kebrya (2009).“An Overview of Imam Ali&#039;s Management from the Point of View of the Components of Social Capital”,Journal of Strategic management, 6(3), Autumn and Winter 2009: 101-128. ##-       Ette, A.; B. Heb &amp; L. Sauer (2015). “Tackling Germany’s Demographic Skills Shortage: Permanent Settlement Intentions of the Recent Wave of Labour Migrants from Non-European Countries”. Journal of International Journal of International Migration and Integration, May 2016, 17(2): 429–448. ##-       Faghihe Khaljani, S.F. (2013). Social Capital in the Thought and Practice of Imam Khomeini, Tehran: Imam Khomeini Institute, Orouj Pub. ##-       Faghihi, A. &amp; T. Feisi (2005). “Social Capital in Organization”,Journal of light Mailer, 3(3), Autumn 2005:11-21.  ##-       Foster, K.A; R.J. Smith,  B.A. Bell &amp; T.C. Shaw (2017). “Testing the Importance of Geographic Distance for Social Capital Resources”. Urban Affairs Review, June 2017, Article first published online: https://doi.org/10.1177/1078087417714895 ##-       Fukuyama, F .(1995). Trust: the Social Vitues and the Creation of Prosperity. New York: Free Press, 1995.xv. ##-       Fukuyama, F. (1999).The Institute of Public. George Mason University. ##-       Fukuyama, F. (2000) The End of Order, G.A Tavassoli, First edition, Tehran: Jamee Iranian pub. ##-       GanjiA, M. &amp; M. Helali Sotodeh (2011). “Identification of Management Factors Affecting the Prouri Replacement (Case study: Cultural Organization of Qom)”,Thesis Master of Organizational Transformation, Farabi, Tehran University. ##-       GanjiB, M. &amp; M. Helali Sotodeh (2011). “The Relationship of Religion and Social Capital (Theoretical and Experimental in Kashan&#039;s People)”,Journal of Journal of Applied Sociology, 22(2), Summer 2011:95-120. ##-       Garrec, G. Le. (2015). “Increased longevity and social security reform: questioning the optimality of individual accounts when education matters”. Journal of Population Economics, April 2015, 28(2): 329-352. ##-       Geber, S.; H. Scherer &amp; D. Hefner .(2016). “Social capital in media societies: The impact of media use and media structures on social capital”. International Communication Gazette, June 2016, 78 (6): 493-513: Article published online: https://doi.org/10.1177/1748048516640211. ##-       Giddens, A. (2001) Consequences of Modernity, translation M. Thalathi, Tehran: Markaz Pub. ##-       Habibov, N. &amp; E. Afandi (2015). “Pre- and Post-crisis Life-Satisfaction and Social Trust in Transitional Countries: An Initial Assessment”. Social Indicators Research, April 2015, 121( 2): 503-524. ##-       Hamidizadeh, A.; F. Shahidzadeh &amp; A. Movahedifar (2014). “The Effect of Social Capital on Organizational Innovation (Case study: Telecom General Administration City of Qom)”,Journal of Social capital management, 2(1), Winter2014: 203-223. ##-       Hanifan, L.J. (1916). “The rural school community center”. Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 67, New Possibilities in Education (Sep, 1916):130-138. ##-       Imam Khomeini, S.R. (1990). Sahifa Noor. Tehran: The Setting and Publishing Institute of Imam Khomeini works. ##-       Jafari Harandi, R.; A.R. Nasr &amp; S.A. Mir Shah Jafari (2008).  “Content Analysis, A Method Widely Used in Social Science Studies in Social Sciences, Humanities &amp; Behavioral, With Emphasis on the Analysis of the Content of the lesson Book”,Seminary &amp; University  Journal, 55(14), summer 2008: 33-58. ##-       Jafari, M.; F. Sharif Zadeh, V. Ghorbani, B. Rezaei Manesh &amp; A. Delkhosh Kasmaei (2012).“The Pattern of Social Capital, Dimensions and Indicators in Police Station of Tehran”,Journal of Police Management Studies Quarterly, 3(7), Autumn 2012: 370-396. ##-       Jamshidiha, GH.R. (2004). The Genesis of Sociological Theory, Tehran: University of Tehran Pub. ##-       Johnson, C.A. (2012).“How do public libraries create social capital? An analysis of interactions between library staff and patrons”. Library and Information Science Research, 34 (1): 52-62. ##-       Kitchen, P. (2012). “Measuring Social Capital in Hamilton,Ontario”. September 2012, 108(2): 215–238. ##-       Kovalcikova, I. &amp; M.Lacny (2016). “The case of trust-research on social capital in 4 countries”. Studies of Transition States and Societies, 8(3): 78-96 ##-       Mahmoudi, S.; A.R. Rokaldin Eftekhari, G.R. Ghafari &amp; M. PourTaheri (2015). “Explanation of the Effects of Types of Capital Development on the Social Capital (Case Study: The Villages of Khorasan Razavi)”,Journal of Economics and Rural Development, 14(4): 169-190. ##-       Mintchev, N. &amp; H.L. Moore (2016). “Community and prosperity beyond social capital: The case of Newham, East London”. Critical Social Policy, December 2016, Article published online: https://doi.org/10.1177/0261018316683461. ##-       Mostafa Zadeh, M. &amp; M.R. Sadeghi (2014). “The Design of the Model of Social Capital Development in Universities”, Journal of Social Capital Management, 2(1), Winter 2014: 161-182. ##-       Mousavi Moghadam, S.M. &amp; M. Mohammadi (2016). “A Study on the Role of the Mosque in the Increase of Social Capital Based on the Qur&#039;an and Hadith”, Journal of Social Capital Management, 3(1), Spring 2016:139-162. ##-       Nazar Pour, S.M. &amp; M. Montaseri Moghadam (2010). “Social Capital and Economic Development”, Journal of  Islamic Economy, 37(10), Spring 2010: 57-87. ##-       Onyx, J. &amp; P.Bullen (2000). “Measuring social capital in five communities”. The Journal of Applied Behavioural Science, 36(1): 23-42. ##-       Piran, P.; M.T. Mousavi &amp; M. Shiani (2006). “The Concept of Social Capital (Whith Emphasis on Iran&#039;s Conditions)”,Journal of Social Welfare, 23(6): 9-49. ##-       Piriaei, S. &amp; M. Monadi (2016). “Study of the Sources and Consequences of Social Capital from Point of View Teachers of high schools girls in Isfahan”,The First International Conference on new Research in the Educational Sciences, Psychology and social studies, Iran, Qom, Article first published online: http://www.civilica.com/Paper-ESCONF01-ESCONF01_064.html ##-       Putnam, R. (1993). Making Democracy Work: Civic Traditions in Modern Italy. Princeton: Princeton University Press. ##-       Putnam, R. (2001). Bowling Alone: The Collapse and Revival of American Community. New York: Touchstone Books by Simon &amp; Schuste. ##-       Rahbar, A.A. &amp; F. Heidari (2011). “The Effect of Social Capital on the Importance of Promotion”,Journal of  International Relations Studies, 14(4), Spring 2011: 219-253. ##-       Rahmatollahi, H.; E. Agha Mohammad Aghaei &amp; M. BalVi (2016), “The Reduction of Social Capital, the Government and the people&#039;s participation”, Journal of Social Capital Managemen, 3(3), Autumn 2016: 435-461. ##-       Rajaei, S.A.; A. Pour Ahmad &amp; V. Abbasi (2016). “&quot;The Relationship Between Social Capital with Social Security(case study: City of Varamin)”,Journal of Geographical Society of Iran , 48(14), spring 2016: 31-50. ##-       Roche, G. (2010) Social Changes, Translation M. Vosoughi, Edition 21, Tehran: Ney Pub. ##-       Salehi Amiri, S.R. (2009). Management and Social Capital, Strategic research institute, Department of international studies. ##-       Shojaee Baghini, M.M. (2008). Conceptual Foundations of Social Capital, Tehran: Social and cultural studies Institute. ##-       Tavakoli, A.; A. Pourbehrvarsan &amp; D. Mohammadiani (2017). “Trust, The Main Pillar of Social Capital: Resentation Templates are based on Islamic Teachings (Case Study: Book of Mizanoal Hekmah)”, Journal of Social Capital Management, 28 June 2017, Article first published online: https://jscm.ut.ac.ir/article_62099.html. ##-       Tavakoli, A.; A.S. Azizpour Lindi, E. Rezaei &amp; A. Mirzaei (2014). “The Effect of Social Capital on the component of intellectual capita (Case Study: Tax Administration of Qom Province)”,Journal of Social capital management, 2(3), Winter 2014: 265-287. ##-       Tonkiss, F. (2008).  “Trust and Social Capital”, Translate M.TG. Delfrose, Tehran: Social and Cultural Studies Institute Pub. ##-       Yang, J.; T.G. Brashear Alejandro &amp; J.S. Boles (2011).“The role of social capital and knowledge transfer in selling center performance”. Journal of Business &amp; Industrial Marketing, 26(3):152-161.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>سخن فصل</TitleF>
				<TitleE>سخن فصل</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT></CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مفهوم حکمرانی خوب در سه دهۀ اخیر به طور جدّی مدّ نظر محققان بوده است؛ به طوری که زمینه‌ساز بروز پارادایم جدیدی در مدیریت دولتی شده است. حکمرانی خوب تسهیل‌کنندۀ مدیریت منابع یک کشور در راه رسیدن به اهداف تعیین‌شده است. پیش‌تر، مفهوم حکمرانی خوب به اِعمال قدرت سیاسی برای مدیریت امور ملت اطلاق می‌شد؛ اما تقریباً پس از سه دهه و بر اساس جدیدترین تعاریف ارائه‌شده، این مفهوم در اتخاذ سیاستهای پیش‌بینی‌شده، آشکار و صریح دولت(با تأکید بر شفافیت فعالیتهای دولت)، بروکراسی شفاف، پاسخگویی دستگاههای اجرایی در قبال فعالیتهای خود، مشارکت فعال مردم در امور اجتماعی و سیاسی و نیز برابری همۀ این افراد در برابر قانون تبلور می‌یابد. در واقع؛ اگر هدف رهبری سازمان یا یک جامعه بالا بردن کیفیت زندگی افراد آن باشد، سنجش عملکرد حکمرانی خوب یکی از ابزارهای مهم در این راستاست.
طیف وسیعی از بازیگران در تحقق حکمرانی خوب نقش‌آفرینی می‌کنند؛ از افراد عادی و شهروندان گرفته تا سازمانها و مقامات دولتی. دانشگاهها نیز به مثابۀ موتور محرّک علمی کشور، نقش بسزایی در این اتفاق دارند. بنابر این، یکی از نقشهای اصلی آموزش عالی و دانشگاهها، تسهیل و ارائۀ زمینه‌های لازم برای اجرای حکمرانی خوب است. در این راستا، از دانشگاهها انتظار می‌رود نوعی تفکر اصلاحی در خود ایجاد کنند که مجموعه‌ای از اقدامات مختلف را در بر گیرد. این اقدامات، شامل افزایش پاسخگویی دانشگاهها در قبال نیازهای اصلی جامعه، مواجهه با چالشهای جدید اجتماعی و اقتصادی و داشتن راهکار برای مدیریت اثربخش و حل آنها، تقویت فرهنگ سالم و نیز افزایش بهره‌وری و مدیریت خردمندانه منابع مادی و انسانی است. بدین منظور، بایستی تحولی بنیادی در شاخصهای ارزیابی عملکرد دانشگاهها در راستای موضوعات مطرح‌شده ایجاد شود. لذا از جامعۀ علمی انتظار می‌رود در کنار سایر موضوعات مهم، به این مفهوم نیز بپردازند و ضمن بومی‌سازی آن، توجه سایر بخشهای جامعه را به آن معطوف دارند.
نشریۀ «مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی» آمادگی خود را برای چاپ پژوهشها و مقالات دانشگاهی و حوزوی در زمینه‌های مرتبط با حکمرانی خوب اعلام می‌دارد. به امید آنکه این توجه، زمینه‌ساز تحرکات علمی بیشتر شود.
 
حسن زارعی متین
سردبیر</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>213</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>214</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>چکیده لاتین</TitleF>
				<TitleE>چکیده لاتین</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT></CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>-</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>402</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>412</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نمایه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>نمایه</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT></CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>-</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>395</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>401</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نمایه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				