<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Just Organization (Analysis of Organizational Justice Based on Holy Quran and Islamic Traditions)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">habib</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammad Nejad Chavooshi</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار گروه معارف اسلامی دانشگاه علوم پزشکی ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">abdolhosein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khosropanah</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و اندیشه اسلامی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">ali asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Pour Ezzat</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objectives: The present study aims at using Islamic recourses andtraditions to define theorganizational justice. Justice has always been the core concern of divine religions. In this research justice in an organization as a social system is studied throughIslamic recourses andtraditions. Method: The method of the research is library with exploring approach and the Quran interpretation by referring to holly Quran and referring to sacred traditions and prophetic sayings and inductive study ofholy Quran and Islamic traditions and in some rare cases the content analysis is performed. Results: The results of the present survey indicatethat the organizational justice refers to the integration of organization components based on Devine Commandments. Conclusion: The authors of the research conclude the just organization is a devotee, pious and faithful organization and believes in the authority and guardianship of the perfect Man {anthropos teleios}(some one who is appointed by Allah in each era and time) and rejects the authority of oppressors and unbelievers and develops the behaviors leading to sovereign power of Devine Presence.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>10</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>147</start>
					<end>166</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_297_337d399891845fee33893f72cb495325.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Role of Interpretive Structural Modeling Approach in Ethical Fundamentals in Strategic Management of Production (From Islamic View)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mehrdad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Madhooshi</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد دانشکدۀ علوم اقتصادی و اداری، دانشگاه مازندران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shameli</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت تولید و عملیات، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی و اداری دانشگاه مازندران و عضو هیئت علمی پژوهشکده سیاست‌پژوهی و مطالعات راهبردی حکمت</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت تولید و عملیات، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی و اداری دانشگاه مازندران و عضو هیئت علمی پژوهشکده سیاست‌پژوهی و مطالعات راهبردی حکمت</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objectives: Nowadays the problem of production is the use of resources in order to provide more products and services. The questions raised in this context are: whether in production the following dimensions are considered or not : society, customer, environment, purchasing power, the real needs of the community and etc, so the problem of this research is the following  question: what is the components of Islamic morality issues related to the production and how are the communication of this components, that finally causes the design  of a conceptual model of &quot; Islamic ethics in the production&quot; based on the religious teachings and doctrine. Method: In Designing a Model, the interpretive structural modeling approach is used. After determining the basic concepts from authoritative religious texts such as the Quran, Nahjolbalagheh and other books, these components in the paired comparison matrix is  presented to 10 experts in the field of Islamic scholars and production management that are non- randomly chosen. Results:  The findings presented in a model that consists of ten criteria in five levels. Relationship between components extracted is also determined. Conclusion: The results of the present research indicate  that if Islamic teachings regarding to the production be considered and implemented then it can provide aproper basis for managers to change the attitudes and morality’s behavior in the filed of production</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>10</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>167</start>
					<end>180</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_298_094cc0c89c92d19ea21b17e5e45333b3.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Effect of Structural and Behavioral Factors on Science Production Culture in Universities
 (Case Study: Shiraz University)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">moslem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bagheri</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه شیراز</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">ghasem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Salimi</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه شیراز</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه شیراز</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tayyebi Khorrami</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت منابع انسانی اسلامی، دانشگاه شیراز</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Global leading higher education institutions have recognized that their growing success key is the organization of new science production systems. Promotion of science production has a significant role in the efficiency of knowledge production system of these institutions. As a result, conceptualization about the factors influencing it and the identity of this issue in higher education, serves a great importance. Objective: This research has tried to explore and explain the factors influencing this phenomenon through the usage of mixed exploratory method. Method: This research has used qualitative content analysis method at the qualitative stage and survey strategy at the quantitative stage. The population of the study consists of faculty members of Shiraz University which were 15 professors in the qualitative stage and 139 in the quantitative one. Results: The authors of the survey  have recognized 13 factors influencing the promotion of science production, which could be categorized into structural factors (coordination between different scientific and research parts of university, promotion and continuous revision of training contents, avoid of politicization and instability of managers, targeted planning about the promotion of scientific culture, continuous communication between training and research centers in the country and out of it, paying attention to the quality and application of researches in solving the society problems, formulation and establishment of the integrated system of talent management in higher education system, providing and developing research facilities) and behavioral factors (creating the true culture of criticizing and accepting criticisms, creating demanding culture in the university, promotion of free and liberal thinking in the university, alignment between training and research, paying attention to the training and research standards). Conclusion: The authors of the article concludefor promotion of science production culture, universities have topay moreattention to these factors and attempt to implement them</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>10</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>181</start>
					<end>206</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_299_f687c5911d2832e7973e46c84cf430cc.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Cause-Effect Diagram for Prophet Moses' Managerial Competencies by Using Grey DEMATEL</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">seyed reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Seyed Javadin</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد گروه مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">bahareh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mahbanooei</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت رفتار سازمانی، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">roohollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghasemi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت تولید و عملیات، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objectives: This study aims to identify the managerial competencies of Moses and their causal relationships for students and administrators. Method: The method usedto identify the competencies is strategy Grounded Theory which is used to determine the causal effects of these competencies and was carried out on each onewith gray DEMATEL. Results: The results of the first eight management competencies include communication skills, decision-making, spiritual-intelligence, talent management, power, discipline, leadership, crisis management and management characteristics as the merits of Moses were extracted and The results of gray DEMATEL method, Dimensions &quot;personality characteristics&quot; and &quot;leadership&quot; influential, and of &quot;crisis management&quot; and &quot;decision-making&quot; competencies  are the most affected. Conclusion: The author of the survey concludes Managerial competencies of Moses and their relations can be identified by appropriate guidance for management education in university and its usage by managers in the Islamic community یافته‌ها: بر اساس نتایج بخش اول، هشت شایستگی مدیریتی؛ شامل مهارت ارتباطی، قدرت تصمیم‌گیری، هوش معنوی، مدیریت استعداد، قدرت تنبیه، قدرت رهبری، مدیریت بحران و ویژگی‌های شخصیتی به عنوان شایستگی‌های مدیریتی حضرت موسی(ع) استخراج شدند و بر اساس یافته‌های روش دیماتل خاکستری، ابعاد «ویژگی‌های شخصیتی» و «قدرت رهبری»، تأثیرگذارترین و ابعاد «مدیریت بحران» و «قدرت تصمیم‌گیری»، تأثیرپذیرترین شایستگی‌ها معرفی شدند. نتیجه‌گیری: شایستگی‌های مدیریتی حضرت موسی(ع) و روابط شناسایی شدۀ آنها می‌توانند راهنمای مناسبی برای آموزش مدیریتی اسلامی در دانشگاه‌ها و کاربرد آن توسط مدیران در جامعۀ اسلامی باشند.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>10</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>207</start>
					<end>226</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_300_d93112fb99aeda5c7971b7b236a875b3.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Strategic Planning for Universities Based on Organizational Life Cycle: a Case Study</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">hamzeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khastar</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه خوارزمی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohammad amin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Batmani</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت دانشگاه تهران؛ عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه آزاد کنگاور</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohsen</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Omidian</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objectives: The aim of this study is to apply the concept of organizational life cycle in the University&#039;s strategic plan. The constant changes in the institutional and technical colleges and their strong relationship with the external environment, such institutions are required to meet the demands of the environment and its strategic actions. Methods: In this study, the combination of organizational life cycle model with SWOT matrix, using the concept triradiate, SWOT matrix dimensions into three categories of factors: structural, content and context were classified. Results: The results of the present survey indicate that   Due to the university at maturity, strategic leverage changes in underlying factors are (T = 13, O = 59, W = 79, S = 99). The dimensions are in moreimportance (T = 35, O = 20, W = 158, S = 18). The structural dimension (T = 50, O = 23, W = 42, S = 17) is in the third place of importance. The importance of the strengths in the field of land (S = 99), weaknesses in the area of ​​content (W = 158), opportunities in the areas of (O = 59) and threats to the structural dimension (T = 50) of Most are paramount. Conclusion:  The authors of the article conclude the strategy of minimizing the weaknesses and maximizing the opportunities should be used. Organizations should seek to avoid saturation and declining acts of initiative and take advantage of innovations in the organization.the paper suggests the development of relationship between industry and university research unit at the Institute</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>10</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>227</start>
					<end>240</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_301_6912855503160881d4c1f7f9b7d6f5fb.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Selecting Suitable Educational Institutes for Outsourcing Process Based on Comprehensive Approach of ANPBOCR (Case Study: Qom University)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">abolfazl</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bahrami</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohammad hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Maleki</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه قم</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objectives: This study attempts in identifying and prioritizing effective criteria in outsourcing of organizational training, dealing with prioritizing educational institutions and finally selecting the educational institutions in order to outsourcethe organizational training in an academic environment. Method: In this research, with using comprehensive approach of ANPBOCR, first, by surveying literature and interviews with experts, effective criteria were identified and then by identifying dependencies between criteria, and forming the pairwise comparison matrices, priorities of effective criteria and relative scores of educational institutions on the basis of identified criteria were identified and finally, rates of educational institutions were calculated. Results: The findings of the present study indicate Respectively, criteria of appropriate organizational behavior and culture, holding on-time training courses on the base of schedule provided in the contract, lack of control over the training process, cost of transportation of personnel, cost of courses and the cost of re-test are considered as the most important factors of decision making. Conclusion: The authors of the article conclude When using outsourcing strategy of staff training, managers must first evaluate the benefits, costs, opportunities and risks of the outsourcing and then with regard to these cases, in case of usefulness of this strategy for their organization, do further actions in order to implement it</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>10</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>241</start>
					<end>260</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_302_c0457544c3d01bf8c5ab804085d505ad.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identification and Prioritizing of the Whole Country Universities’ Cultural Fund Allocation Indicators in the Ninth and Tenth Government</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Doostar</namePart>
				<affiliation>هیئت علمی دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه گیلان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">nafiseh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Foroughi</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازاریابی دانشگاه گیلان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">khalil</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Norouzi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای رشته سیاستگذاری علم و فنّاوری دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mojtaba</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Javadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد رشته معارف اسلامی و مدیریت دولتی و سیاستگذاری عمومی دانشگاه امام صادق(ع).</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abdolhosseinzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد رشته معارف اسلامی و مدیریت دولتی و سیاستگذاری عمومی دانشگاه امام صادق(ع).</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hajari</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی مدیریت تکنولوژی دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Objectives:The aim of this study is to identify and prioritize thewhole country universities’ cultural fund allocation indicators in the ninth and tenth government. Method: The method of the study is mixed. The research community comprised of 150 experts. 75 returned questionnaires was used for statistical analysis and AHP method, based on 8 cultural experts of the Ministry of Science, Research and Technology, was used to rank the components. Results: The results of the research indicate both cultural-political and administrative structure dimensions, which considered in this study, have a significant impact on universities’ cultural fund allocation. In experts view, the cultural-political dimension has more priority than administrative structure. Conclusion: The article concludes cultural activities implementation with leader statement, commitment to religious activities, prayer, benediction and Islamic Awakening, prioritizing Islamic-Iranian culture, level of relation between universities’ cultural deputies and managers with Staffarea and cooperation with staff in activitiesare indicators which have priority in universities’ cultural fund allocation in ninth and tenth governments onclusion: The authors of the article conclude When using outsourcing strategy of staff training, managers must first evaluate the benefits, costs, opportunities and risks of the outsourcing and then with regard to these cases, in case of usefulness of this strategy for their organization, do further actions in order to implement it</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2345-5713</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>10</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>261</start>
					<end>280</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_303_526f431d64f2e00c13a6f0f966f0901b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>