<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2345-5713</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>16</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation and Analysis of Dark Side of Organizational Behavior from the Viewpoints of Amir Almomenin (PBUH)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی و تحلیل لبۀ تاریک رفتارهای سازمانی از دیدگاه امیرالمؤمنین(ع)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>293</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>310</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">589</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ریحانه </FirstName>
					<LastName>فروزنده جونقانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، گرایش مدیریت منابع انسانی؛ دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالله </FirstName>
					<LastName>توکلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترای مدیریت و دانشیار گروه مدیریت پژوهشگاه حوزه و دانشگاه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Objectives:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Considering the letters of Amir Almomenin (PBUH), current research aims at investigating and understanding the concept of dark side of organizational Behavior from the Islamic perspective through the utilization of international models and patterns. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Method:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The method of the present research is based on using qualitative content analysis. According to previous research, deviant Behaviors are divided into two groups of positive and negative Behaviors. The phenomenon of dark side of Behavior is considered a negative deviant Behavior which imposes tremendous annual expenses and has been the center of attention by many organizations. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Results:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The results of the survey indicate that religious texts, especially Islamic contents and letters of Amir Almomenin that are mostly directed toward commanders and managers, this Behavior has been repeatedly notified. In this research, 49 indicators of such Behavior are identified and categorized in two indivual and organizational categories. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  In addition to preventing such Behavior, solutions like clarification, organizational justice, lack of social negative contacts, prevention of adverse competition, meritocracy, and organizational culture development have been provided for which the instances of Amir Almomenin sayings in differnet letters are also noted and discussed.&lt;/em&gt; </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;هدف:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; هدف محقق در این مقاله، بررسی مفهوم لبۀ تاریک رفتار سازمانی از نگاه اسلامی با مطالعۀ مدلها و الگوهای جهانی آن و تأکید بر نامه‌های امیرالمؤمنین علی(ع) بوده است. روش: تحلیل محتوای کیفی. بر اساس پژوهشهای انجام شده، رفتارهای انحرافی به دو دستۀ مثبت و منفی دسته‌بندی می‌شوند. پدیدۀ لبۀ تاریک رفتارسازمانی در دستۀ رفتارهای انحرافی منفی قرار دارد که به دلیل ایجاد هزینه‌های مالی و غیر مالی هنگفت سالیانه برای سازمانها، مورد توجه و بررسی قرار گرفته است. یافته‌ها: در متون دینی به ویژۀ متون اسلامی و نامه‌های نهج‌البلاغه که اغلب خطاب به فرماندهان و مدیران است، این رفتارها به طور مکرر توسط امیرالمؤمنین گوشزد شده است که در مطالعۀ انجام‌شده، 49 کد شناسایی و در دو سطح فردی و سازمانی طبقه‌بندی شد. نتیجه‌گیری: حضرت برای پیشگیری از این رفتارها، راهکارهایی همچون: شفافیت، عدالت سازمانی، عدم ایجاد اصطکاک اجتماعی، جلوگیری از رقابتهای ناسالم، شایسته‌سالاری و ایجاد فرهنگ سازمانی را بیان می‌کنند که برای این رهنمودها به مصداقهایی برگرفته از نامه‌های امیرالمؤمنین اشاره شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لبه‌های تاریک رفتار سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انحرافات فردی و سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نامه‌های نهج‌البلاغه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_589_ea16bf9c92a7d1db0031dd4079c52310.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>