<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2345-5713</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>9</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Developing and Accreditation of a Framework for Evaluatin University Managers Competencies, Based on  Islamic Teachings</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تدوین و اعتباریابی چارچوبی برای ارزیابی شایستگی‌های مدیران دانشگاهی با توجه به آموزه‌های اسلامی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>3</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>22</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">269</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جعفر </FirstName>
					<LastName>ترک‌زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سمیه </FirstName>
					<LastName>انصاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Objectives:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The present reseach aims at  developing and accreditation of a framework for evaluating university managers&#039; competencies, regarding to Islamic teachings. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Method:&lt;/span&gt; This study consisted of sequential exploratory mixed methods. In qualitative stage, using aligning multiple sources approach holding three dimensions: a) collecting literature reviews, underlying principles related to the research variable b) the studies done in the scope of managers’ competencies c) surveying of the key informants’ views, the first framework was developed and evaluated. Then in the quantitative stage, the reliability and validity of the formulated framework was scrutinized and confirmed using confirmatory factor analysis and Cronbach’s Alpha. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Result:&lt;/span&gt; In this research a framework was formulated consisting of tripartite dimensions; Value-manner, knowledge – insight, and skill – method; and their components to evaluate university managers’ competencies based on the Islamic teachings. Value-manner dimension including virtue, commitment, munificence, justice, and orientation to the Islamic Leadership Pattern (Velayat) components; knowledge – insight dimension including; awareness of the religious trainings and ordinances, awareness of the public rules and regulations and tasks limitations and job authorities, to have management specialized and professional knowledge and recognizing relevant organizations’ internal and external status and the skill – method dimension; including technical, human and conceptual skills. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/span&gt;  As a whole we could conclude that Evaluating University Managers Competencies in three dimensions (Value-manner, knowledge – insight, and skill – method) could result in changes in recruitment and development of human resources and the appointment of managers in higher education system of Islamic Republic of Iran&lt;/em&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;هدف:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; این پژوهش در پی تدوین و اعتباریابی چارچوبی برای ارزیابی شایستگی‌های مدیران دانشگاهی با توجه به آموزه‌های اسلامی بوده است. &lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;روش:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; روش پژوهش، ترکیبی و از نوع اکتشافی متوالی است. در مرحلۀ کیفی با استفاده از روش همسوسازی منابع چندگانه مشتمل بر سه ضلعِ الف) جمع‌آوری مبانی نظری، اصول زیربنایی مربوط به متغیّر پژوهش، ب) تحقیقات انجام شده در حوزۀ شایستگی مدیران و ج) پیمایش نظرات آگاهی‌دهندگان کلیدی، چارچوب نظری اولیه تدوین و اعتباریابی شد. سپس در مرحلۀ کمّی، روایی و پایایی چارچوب تدوین شده با استفاده از روشهای آماری تحلیل عامل تأییدی و آلفای کرونباخ بررسی و تأیید شد. &lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;یافته‌ها:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; در این پژوهش چارچوبی مشتمل بر ابعاد سه‌گانۀ ارزشی- منشی، دانشی- بینشی و مهارتی- روشی و مؤلفه‌های مربوط به هر بعد برای ارزیابی شایستگی‌های مدیران دانشگاهی با توجه به آموزه‌های اسلامی، تدوین و اعتباریابی شد. بعد ارزشی- منشی شامل مؤلفه‌های تقوا، تعهد، کرامت، عدالت و ولایتمداری؛ بعد دانشی- بینشی شامل مؤلفه‌های آگاهی از احکام و آموزه‌های دینی، آگاهی از قوانین و مقررات عمومی و حدود وظایف و اختیارات شغلی، برخورداری از دانش تخصصی و حرفه‌ای مدیریت، شناخت وضعیت درونی و بیرونی سازمان مربوطه و بعد مهارتی- روشی شامل مؤلفه‌های مهارتهای فنی، انسانی و ادراکی می‌باشد. &lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;نتیجه‌گیری:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; ارزیابی شایستگی‌های مدیران در ابعاد سه‌گانۀ ارزشی- منشی، دانشی- بینشی و مهارتی- روشی می‌تواند باعث ایجاد تحول در جذب و بهسازی نیروی انسانی در نظام آموزش عالی جمهوری اسلامی و انتصاب مدیران آن شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت اسلامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شایستگی مدیران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دانشگاهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهسازی مدیریت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_269_41cb08658255c3cf3d3424bfa4594543.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>