<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2345-5713</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>16</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Mosque and Congregational Prayer Metaphors of the Organization from the View of Islam: Managerial and Organizational Concepts from the Mosque and Congregational Prayer for the Islamic University</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مسجد و نماز جماعت، استعاره‌ای از سازمان از دیدگاه اسلام؛: تفسیرها و برداشتهای مدیریتی و سازمانی از مسجد و نماز جماعت در مورد دانشگاه اسلامی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>359</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>376</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">593</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد </FirstName>
					<LastName>عربشاهی کریزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت دولتی. استادیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Objectives:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our goal in this article is to deduce the managerial and organizational findings for the Islamic University by examining the various aspects of the mosque and congregational prayer. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Method:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; In order to achieve the goal, we first tried to get acquainted with the rulings and issues related to the mosque and congregational prayer, and in the next step we explained the dimensions of the Islamic University. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Results:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; According to Islamic teachings dimensions, functions and optimal model of Islamic University were presented. The characteristics of the imam of the congregation are the basis for determining the criteria for selecting individuals in the Islamic University. The satisfaction of employees in the mosque and the Islamic University seems necessary for the effectiveness. As the paper shows, the rules of the mosque and congregational prayer can be used to manage affairs and carry out activities at the Islamic University. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Comparative analysis of congregational prayer and mosque, and the Islamic University helps us to understand the dimensions of the Islamic University. The managerial and organizational concepts of the mosque and congregational prayer provide the exact application principles that can facilitate and accelerate the process of development and excellence at Islamic University&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;هدف:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; هدف از انجام این مقاله، بررسی جوانب مختلف مسجد و نماز جماعت و استنباط برداشتهای مدیریتی و سازمانی در خصوص دانشگاه اسلامی بود. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;روش:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; برای دستیابی به هدف، ابتدا سعی شد با رجوع به منابع مختلف اسلامی، با احکام و مسائل مربوط به مسجد و نماز جماعت آشنا شویم و سپس با دیدگاه جامع شکل‌گرفته، ابعاد دانشگاه اسلامی تبیین شود. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;یافته‌ها:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; با توجه به تعالیم اسلامی و احکام مطرح شده راجع به مسجد، ابعاد و کارکردها و مدل مطلوب دانشگاه اسلامی بیان شد. ویژگی‌ها و ابعاد وجودی امام جماعت و معیارهای انتخاب امام جماعت، مبنای مناسبی برای تعیین ملاکهای انتخاب افراد در دانشگاه اسلامی است. ایجاد رضایت در نیروی انسانی در مسجد و دانشگاه اسلامی برای اثربخشی و دستیابی به اهداف ضروری به نظر می‌رسد. احکام مسجد و نماز جماعت می‌تواند در ادارۀ امور و چگونگی انجام فعالیتها و فرایندها دانشگاه اسلامی راهگشا باشد. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;نتیجه‌گیری:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; تجزیه و تحلیل تطبیقی نماز جماعت، مسجد و دانشگاه اسلامی، ما را در شناخت ابعاد دانشگاه اسلامی و دستیابی به مدل مطلوب یاری می‌دهد. برداشتهای مدیریتی و سازمانی از احکام مسجد و نماز جماعت، اصول کاربردی دقیقی را به دست می‌دهد که می‌توانند روند توسعه و تعالی را در دانشگاه اسلامی تسهیل کنند و تسریع بخشند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مسجد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نماز جماعت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اسلام</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشگاه اسلامی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_593_824da8df1a120db35b7f4c08c797d416.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>