<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2345-5713</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>18</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Organizational Barriers of Vigor-Creating in the University; Providing a Grounded Model
 (A Case Study of Alzahra University) </ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کاوشی داده‌بنیاد بر موانع سازمانی نشاط‌آفرینی در محیط دانشگاه(مورد مطالعه دانشگاه الزهرا)* </VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>329</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>350</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">728</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهنوش </FirstName>
					<LastName>جووری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، گرایش منابع انسانی. دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی. تهران شمال. تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یوسف </FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه علوم انتظامی امین، تهران، ایران. (نویسنده مسئول)/ نشانی: تهران، همت غرب، دانشگاه علوم انتظامی امین</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سوسن </FirstName>
					<LastName>قهرمانی قاجار</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری سوادآموزی و آموزش زبان دوم، دانشیار دانشگاه الزهرا. تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نرگس </FirstName>
					<LastName>حسن مرادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تهران شمال. تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The present study is practical in terms of objective and it attempts to discover organizational barriers with vigor in the university based on the Grounded Model by an interpretive approach. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Method:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Data collection was done using semi-structured interview method during 2016-2018. The research methodology is a qualitative method. In the qualitative section, using the purposive sampling and theoretical saturation index, 20 experts from Alzahra University in the field of human resource management and organizational psychology were interviewed as research experts.The codes derived from the propositions text were recorded using a Colaizzi method and then, based on them, the paradigm model of organizational barriers of vigor-creating in the university was identified using the grounded method.In order to examine the reliability and validity of the model, a questionnaire was developed using the Cohen&#039;s kappa agreement coefficient method and five experts were asked to comment on their agreement on the coding in the model. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Results:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; According to the research findings, from the viewpoint of the experts of Alzahra University, in the model of organizational non-vigor in the university, the conditions of inefficiency of laws and regulations as the causative conditions affect the desired phenomenon, that is, barriers to organizational vigor-creating in university.In the meantime, the obscurity of university abilities as intervening conditions and the emergence of work-family conflicts act as the underlying conditions for exacerbating the organizational non-vigor of the members, which these three-dimensional (causal-underlying-intervening) conditions in interaction and action together led to create the negative and anti-productive psychological reactions of the organization in the competitive atmosphere of the university will result in the creation of organizational non-vigor.After calculating Cohen&#039;s kappa agreement coefficient of the experts opinions, the arithmetic mean of the coefficients was approximately 0.8 using the SPSS software. This means, according to the standard table of criteria for the agreement severity, the reliability and validity of the model found in this grounded research has been approved by experts. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Conclusion: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Based on the research findings, the theoretical narrative of this research will be as follows: University can cause to create organizational vigor through establishing strategic resource management and by influencing the three supporting necessary and sufficient conditions for removing the working-family conflicts, university&#039;s capabilities branding in a targeted society, empowerment of rules and regulations by removing organizational barriers through the development of positive psychological and organizational productive capacities.So that their reflection will be displayed in form of the flourishing of the talent and the educational, research-executive dynamics of the university member (production and sharing of science) and the response to the environmental and surrounded needs (quality, expertise, knowledge, monetizing).&lt;/em&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;هدف:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; تحقیق حاضر در پی آن بود تا با رویکرد تفسیرگرایانه، موانع سازمانیِ با نشاطی در محیط دانشگاه را بر مبنای مدل داده‌بنیادکشف کند. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;روش:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; این تحقیق از نظر نوع هدف، کاربردی و به روش زمینه‌ایِ نظریه‌پردازی داده‌بنیاد انجام شده است. جمع‌آوری داده‌ها با روش مصاحبۀ نیمه ساختاریافته در محدودة زمانی سالهای 97-95 صورت پذیرفته است. با استفاده از نمونه‌گیری هدفمند و بر مبنای شاخص اشباع نظری، با 20 نفر از صاحب‌نظران دانشگاه الزهرا در حوزۀ مدیریت منابع انسانی و روان شناسی سازمانی مصاحبه صورت گرفت. کدهای حاصل از متن گزاره‌ها، با روش کلایزری احصا شدند و بر مبنای آنها، مدل پارادایمی موانع سازمانی نشاط‌آفرینی در محیط دانشگاه با روش داده‌بنیاد شناسایی شد. برای بررسی پایایی و اعتبارسنجی مدل، با روش ضریب توافقات کاپای کوهن، پرسشنامه‌ای تهیه و از پنج خبره خواسته شد در خصوص توافقاتشان بر نسبت به کدگذاری‌های انجام شده در مدل، اعلام نظر کنند. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;یافته‌ها:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; در مدل پارادایمی کشف شده، شرایط ناکارامدی قوانین و مقررات، به عنوان شرایط علّی، بر موانع نشاط‌آفرینی سازمانی در دانشگاهها اثرگذار است. در این بین، مهجور ماندن توانمندی‌های دانشگاه به عنوان شرایط مداخله‌گر و بروز تعارضهای کار-خانواده، به عنوان شرایط زمینه‌ای، در جهت تشدید پدیدۀ بی‌نشاطی سازمانی اعضا عمل می‌کنند که این شرایط سه بُعدی(علّی- زمینه‌ای- مداخله‌گر) در تعامل و کنش متقابل با هم موجب بروز واکنشهای روان‌شناختی منفی و ضدِّ بهره‌ور سازمانی در فضای رقابتیِ دانشگاه می‌شود که پیامد آفرینش بی‌نشاطی سازمانی را به همراه خواهد داشت. در ادامه، با نرم‌افزار اس.پی.اس.اس، میانگین حسابی ضرایب توافقی خبرگان به صورت تقریبی 8/0 به دست آمد که به معنی تأیید پایایی و اعتبار مدل یافت‌شده از نظر خبرگان است. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;نتیجه‌گیری:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; دانشگاه می‌تواند با استقرار مدیریت راهبردی منابع و تحت تأثیر سه شرط لازم و کافیِ حمایت دررفع تعارضهای کار- خانواده، برندسازی توانمندی‌های دانشگاه در جامعۀ هدف، بالنده‌سازی قوانین و مقررات با رفع موانع سازمانی از طریق پرورش ظرفیتهای روان‌شناختی مثبت و بهره‌ور سازمانی، زمینه‌ساز نشاط سازمانی اعضا شود؛ به گونه‌ای که بازتاب آن در قالب شکوفایی استعدادها و پویایی آموزشی- پژوهشی- اجرایی عضو دانشگاه(تولید و اشتراک علم) و پاسخ به نیازهای محیطی و محاطی(کیفیت، تخصص، دانش، درآمدزایی) دانشگاه به نمایش گذاشته خواهد شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نشاط سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشگاه الزهرا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش کلایزری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش داده‌بنیاد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضریب توافقات</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_728_0cfa408a06907a6055e08a64fd88615c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>