<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1396</YEAR>
<VOL>6</VOL>
<NO>14</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>171</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارائۀ چارچوب توسعۀ دیپلماسی علمی ج.ا.ایران مبتنی بر قابلیتهای دانشگاههای علوم انسانی (نمونۀ مطالعه: دانشگاه امام صادق(ع))</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Development of Science Diplomacy of the Islamic Republic of Iran based on the Capabilities of Human Sciences Universities (Case Study: Imam Sadiq (A.S.) University)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف از انجام این پژوهش، ارائۀ مدل پارادایمی و نظام‌مند توسعۀ دیپلماسی علمی کشور، مبتنی ‌بر مصاحبه‌های اساتید، خبرگان و متخصصان حوزۀ دیپلماسی علمی در دانشگاههای علوم انسانی بود. روش: این پژوهش مبتنی ‌بر راهبرد پژوهشی داده‌بنیاد و بر اساس رویکرد نظام‌مند استراوس و کوربین به دنبال استخراج مدل پارادایمی توسعۀ دیپلماسی علمی است. بدین‌منظور ابتدا 18 نفر از اساتید، خبرگان و متخصصان حوزۀ دیپلماسی علمی در دانشگاه امام صادق(ع) شناسایی و با آنان مصاحبه شد و در مرحلۀ بعد، با فرآوری داده‌ها و مفاهیم، مقوله‌های سطح 1 و سطح 2 مدل پارادایمی استخراج شد. یافته‌ها: با طی مراحل پژوهشی داده‌بنیاد، هرکدام از مقوله‌های سطوح 1و2 شناسایی‌شده، با توجه به سنخیت موضوعی ذیل مقوله‌های پارادایمیِ شرایط علّی، شرایط زمینه‌ای، شرایط واسطه‌ای، راهبردها و مقوله محوری دسته‌بندی شدند. نتیجه‌گیری: حرکت به سمت توسعۀ دیپلماسی‌علمی، در دانشگاه امام صادق(ع) با توجه به قابلیتهای پویای آن، شرایط و عوامل ویژه‌ای دارد و ظرافتهای خاصی را در طراحی‌ها می‌طلبد. ارتقای قابلیتهای دانشگاه، تقویت جایگاه بین‌المللی ج.ا.ایران، مقابله با کژکارکردهای دیپلماسی علمی در دانشگاههای علوم انسانی و تحقق مأموریت ج.ا.ایران نسبت به مستضعفین جهان اسلام، از جمله پیامدها و نتایج پیاده‌سازی چارچوب توسعۀ دیپلماسی‌علمی در دانشگاههای علوم انسانی است.
 </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives: The aim of this study is to provide a paradigmatic and systematic model for the science diplomacy (SD) development of the country based on the interviews with professors, experts and specialists. Method: This study is based on the data-based management strategy and according to the systematic approach of Strauss&amp; Corbin and intends to obtain the paradigmatic model of the SD development. For this purpose, 18 professors, experts and professionals have been identified and interviewed. In the next stage, by processing the data and concepts, the Level 1 and Level 2 concepts of the paradigmatic model have been obtained. Results: During the data-based research process, both of the Level 1 and Level 2 concepts have been identified and according to the thematic relevance, they have been classified into the following paradigmatic categories: causal terms, underlying terms, intermediating terms, strategies, and finally the pivotal concept. According to the taken steps, it has become clear that moving towards the development of science diplomacy at the Imam Sadiq University due to its dynamic capabilities needs special qualifications. Conclusion: Some of the results of implementing the science diplomacy at the Human Sciences Universities are as follows: enhancing the capabilities of the university, strengthening the international position of the Islamic Republic of Iran, and fulfilling the mission of the Islamic Republic of Iran towards the poor people of Muslim world.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>159</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>176</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدسعید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تسلیمی</Family>
						<NameE>MS</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Taslimi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت و استاد گروه آموزشی مدیریت دولتی دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران. تهران- ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت و استاد گروه آموزشی مدیریت دولتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>taslimi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>خلیل</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نوروزی</Family>
						<NameE>KH</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Noruzi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری سیاستگذاری علم و فنّاوری دانشگاه تهران(نویسنده مسئول)/ نشانی: تهران؛ کارگر شمالی، جنب پل نصر(گیشا)، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران / نمابر: 88006477 /  Email: k.noruzi@ut.ac.ir</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری سیاستگذاری علم و فنّاوری دانشگاه تهران(نویسن</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>vtarvirdizadeh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>وحید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تارویردی زاده</Family>
						<NameE>V</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tarvirdizadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد معارف اسلامی و مدیریت بازرگانی دانشگاه امام صادق(ع). تهران- ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد معارف اسلامی و مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>tarvirdizadeh@isu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دیپلماسی علمی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارتباطات بین‌المللی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قابلیتهای پویا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دانشگاه امام صادق(ع)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>منابع ##-       آشنا، ح. و ن. جعفری هفتخوانی(1386). «دیپلماسی عمومی و سیاست خارجی؛ پیوندها و اهداف». دانش سیاسی، ش 5: 206-179. ##-       دانایی‌فرد، ح. و س.م. امامی(1386). «استراتژی پژوهش کیفی: تأملی بر نظریه‌پردازی داده‌بنیاد». اندیشه مدیریت، ش 2: 97-69. ##-       قوام، ع.(1384). «از دیپلماسی مدرن به دیپلماسی رسانه‌ای». پژوهش حقوق و سیاست، ش 17: 18-7. ##-       گنجی‌دوست، م.(1387). «تحولات دیپلماسی در عصر اطلاعات». سیاست، ش 38(1): 212-185. ##-       میرعمادی، ط.(1394). «مدل تحلیل دیپلماسی علم و فنّاوری در یک کشور». رهیافت، ش 59: 16-1. ##-       نوروزی، خ.؛ ج. آزادی احمدآبادی، م. جوادی، م. اکبرزاده و ا. اکبرزاده(1393). «تأمین مالی خیرانه دانشگاهها: شناسایی الزامات و کژکارکردها(مطالعۀ موردی دانشگاه امام صادق)». تحقیقات مالی- اسلامی، ش7: 196-167. ##-       نوروزی، خ.؛ م. باقری کنی، ج. آزادی احمدآبادی و م. نوروزی(1391). «ارتقای قابلیتهای پویا در دانشکده‌های مدیریت جمهوری اسلامی ایران- مورد مطالعه: دانشکده معارف اسلامی و مدیریت دانشگاه امام صادق(ع)». مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی، ش 3: 446-423. ##-       Ashena, H. &amp; N. Jafari (2007). “Public Diplomacy and Foreign Policy, Links and Objectives”. Political Knowledge, 5: 179-206. ##-       Barston, R. (2014). Modern Diplomacy (Fourth Edition ed.). New York: Routledge. ##-       Charmaz, C. (2000). Grounded Theory: Objectivist and Subjectivist Methods. Sage. ##-       Danaeefard, H. &amp; S.M. Emami (2007). “Qualitative Research Strategies: Meditations on Grounded Theory”. Management thought Quarterly, 2: 69-97. ##-       Davis, L.S. &amp; R.G. Patman (Eds.) (2015). Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn?. World Scientific. ##-       Eisenhardt, K.M. &amp; J.A. Martin (2000). “Dynamic Capabilities: What Are They?”. Strategic Management Journal, 1105-1121. ##-       Ghanjidoost, M. (2008). “Diplomacy Developments in the Information Age”. Politics Quarterly, 38(1): 185-212. ##-       Ghavam, E. (2005). “From Modern Diplomacy to Media Diplomacy”. Law and Politics Research, 17: 7-18. ##-       Glaser, B. &amp; A.L. Strauss (1967). The Discovery of Grounded Theory: Strategies for Qualitative Research. Berlin: Aldine de Gruyter. Retrieved from http://books.google.de/books?id=rtiNK68Xt08C ##-       Grant, R.M. (2010). Contemporary Strategy Analysys. Seventh Edition. United Kingdom: John Wiley &amp; Sons. ##-       Harold, N. (1960). Diplomacy. New York: Oxford University Press. ##-       Levitt, T. (1960). “Marketing Myopia”. Harvard Business Review, 24-47. ##-       Mir Emadi, T. (2015). “A Model for Analyzing the Diplomacy of Science and Technology in a Country”. Approach, 59: 1-16. ##-       Norouzi, Kh.; J. Azadi, M. Javadi, M. Akbarzadeh &amp; A. Akbarzadeh (2014). “Beneficial Financing of Universities: Identifying Requirements and Dangers (Case Study of Imam Sadiq University)”. Islamic Finance Research,7: 167-196. ##-       Norouzi, Kh.; M. Bagheri, J. Azadi &amp; M. Norouzi (2012). “Promoting a Dynamic Capabilities of the Islamic Republic of Iran Business Schools: the School of Management and Islamic thought, Case Study: University of Imam Sadiq”. Management in Islamic University, 3: 423-4 ##-       Royal Society (n.d.). New Frontiers in Science Diplomacy. London: Royal Society. ##-       Strauss, A.L. &amp; J. Corbin (1990). Basics of Qualitative Research: Grounded Theory Procedures and Techniques. Los Angeles: Sage. ##-       Strauss, A.L. (1994). Qualitative Analysis for Social Scientists. England: Cambridge University Press. ##-       Streubert, H.J. &amp; D.R. Carpenter (2011). Qualitative Research In Nursing Advancing Humanistic Imperative. Philadelphia: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins. ##-       Teece, D.J.; G. Pisano &amp; A. Shuen (1997). “Dynamic Capabilities and Strategic Management”. Strategic Management Journal, 509-533. ##-       Zollo, M. &amp; S.G. Winter (2002). “Deliberate Learning and the Evolution of Dynamics”. Organization Science, 339-351.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تحلیل نقش معنویت در محیط کار در رشد رفتار اخلاقی کارکنان دانشگاه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Role of Spirituality in the Workplace on the Growth of Ethical Behavior of University Employees</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف محققان در پژوهش حاضر، بررسی نقش معنویت در محیط کار بر رفتار اخلاقی کارکنان بوده است. معنویت در محیط کار بر اساس مدل میلیمن و همکاران(2003) و رفتار اخلاقی بر اساس مدل لوزیر(1993) در سه بُعد بررسی شده است. روش: تحقیق حاضر از لحاظ هدف، کاربردی و از نوع توصیفی- پیمایشی با ابزار پرسشنامۀ استاندارد است. جامعۀ آماری پژوهش، کارکنان دانشگاه پیام‌نور استان اردبیل و نمونۀ آماری آن، شامل 160 نفر از آنان بود. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها از ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و رگرسیون چند متغیّره استفاده شده است. یافته‌ها: یافته‌های تحقیق نشان داد که معنویت در محیط کار و ابعاد آن بر رفتار اخلاقی کارکنان تأثیر مثبت و معناداری دارند و کار با معنا 27/0، احساس همبستگی 43/0، همسویی ارزشها 63/0 و معنویت در محیط کار 37/0 از تغییرات مربوط به رفتار اخلاقی کارکنان را پیش‌بینی می‌کنند. نتیجه‌گیری: با بهره‌گیری و تقویت معنویت در محیط کار، می‌توان بستر مناسبی برای رشد رفتارهای اخلاقی کارکنان فراهم آورد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives: This study aimed to examine the role of spirituality in the workplace on the ethical behavior of employees. Spirituality in the workplace has been studied in three dimensions based on Milliman et al.(2003) model and the ethical behavior by Lussier (1993) model. Method: This study is an applied one by the objective and a descriptive survey by using standard questionnaire. The statistical population were the Payamnoor university staffs of Ardabil and the sample included 160 people. To analyze the data, Pearson correlation and multivariate regression were used. Results: The results showed that spirituality in the workplace and its dimensions; significantly and positively impact on the ethical behavior of employees. Meaningful work 0/27, sense of unity 0/4, the convergence of values 0/63 and the spirituality in the workplace could anticipate 0/37 of variation related to the ethical behavior of employees. Conclusion: Using and strengthening the spirituality in the workplace, could provide the appropriate ground for the growth of the ethical behavior of employees.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>177</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>192</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حبیب</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ابراهیم پور</Family>
						<NameE>H</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ebrahimpour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکترای مدیریت دولتی و دانشیار گروه مدیریت و اقتصاد، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی(نویسنده مسئول)/ نشانی: اردبیل؛ دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی/ نمابر: 04515516402 / Email: ebrahimpourh@yahoo.com</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکترای مدیریت دولتی و دانشیار گروه مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ebrahimpourh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>طاهر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>روشندل اربطانی</Family>
						<NameE>T</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Roshandel Arbatani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکترای مدیریت رسانه و استاد گروه مدیریت رسانه، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکترای مدیریت رسانه و استاد گروه مدیریت رسانه،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>arbatani@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>الناز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سخندان</Family>
						<NameE>E</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sokhandan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>. کارشناس ارشد مدیریت جهانگردی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>. کارشناس ارشد مدیریت جهانگردی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sokhandan1400@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>معنویت در محیط کار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رفتار اخلاقی کارکنان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کار با معنا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>احساس همبستگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>همسویی ارزشها</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>منابع ##-       الوانی، سید مهدی(1383). «مدیریت دولتی و ضرورت تقویت زیرساختهای اخلاقی». مطالعات مدیریت، ش 42-41. ##-       تولایی، روح‌ا...(1388). «عوامل تأثیرگذار بر رفتار اخلاقی کارکنان». توسعۀ انسانی پلیس، ش 25. ##-       صالح‌نیا، منیره و زینب اله‌توکلی(1388). «اخلاق سازمانی با تأکید بر منشور اخلاقی». اخلاق در علوم و فنّاوری، سال چهارم، ش 4-3. ##-       صباغ ملاحسینی، ایمان(1392). «بررسی تأثیر نقش معنویت سازمانی بر رفتارهای اخلاقی کارکنان در سازمانهای دولتی». اولین کنفرانس ملی حسابداری و مدیریت. شیراز: مؤسسه بین‌المللی آموزشی و پژوهشی خوارزمی. ##-       عابدی جعفری، حسن و عباسعلی رستگار(1386). «ظهور معنویت در سازمانها، مفاهیم، تعاریف، پیش‌فرضها، مدل مفهومی». علوم مدیریت ایران، سال دوم، ش 5. ##-       عبدالهی، بیژن؛ حیدر کریمیان و مهدی نامداری پژمان(1393). «ارتباط تعهد سازمانی و معنویت در محیط کار با رفتار اخلاقی». اخلاق در علوم و فنّاوری، سال نهم، ش 4. ##-       قربان‌زاده، امّ لیلا(1392). «تأثیر هوش معنوی بر عملکرد کارکنان در سازمان». مدیریت منابع انسانی، 5 (22): 59-52. ##-       کرد تمینی، بهمن؛ زهرا نیک‌منش، و مریم قبرپور(1393). «بررسی رابطۀ معنویت سازمانی با فرسودگی شغلی در بین پرستاران بیمارستانهای دولتی زاهدان». پژوهشهای مدیریت عمومی، سال هفتم، ش 24: 152-141. ##-       ﮐﺮﯾﻤﯽ، ﻣﻬﺪی؛ ﺳﻌﯿﺪ رﺟﺎﯾﯽ‌ﭘﻮر و رﺿﺎ ﻫﻮﯾﺪا(1389). «ﺑﺮرﺳﯽ راﺑﻄۀ ﺑﯿﻦ اﺑﻌﺎد ﺟﻮّ ﺳﺎزﻣﺎﻧﯽ و رﻓﺘﺎر اﺧﻼﻗﯽ در ﺑﯿﻦ ﮐﺎرﮐﻨﺎن داﻧﺸﮕﺎهﺎی اﺻﻔﻬﺎن و ﻋﻠﻮم ﭘﺰﺷﮑﯽ اﺻﻔﻬﺎن». رﻫﺒﺮی و ﻣﺪﯾﺮﯾﺖ آﻣﻮزﺷﯽ، ﺳﺎل چهارم، ش 1. ##-       لاوتن، آلن(1384). مدیریت اخلاقی در خدمات دولتی. ترجمه محمدرضا ربیعی و حسن گیوریان. تهران: یکان. ##-       یزدانی، حمیدرضا؛ محمدرضا کاظمی نجف‌آبادی و غلامرضا سلیمی(1389). «بررسی نقش میانجی معنویت در رابطۀ بین ابعاد عدالت سازمانی و پیامدهای معنویت». چشم‌انداز مدیریت بازرگانی، ش 3. ##-       Abdollahi, Bizhan; Heidar Karimian &amp; Mahdi Namdari Pezhman (2014). “The Relationship between Organizational Commitment and Spirituality in the Workplace and Ethical Behavior”. Ethics in Science and Technology, Year 9, Issue 4. ##-       Abedi Jafari, Hasan &amp; Abbasali Rastgar (2007). “The Emergence of Spiriuality in Organizations, Concepts, Definitions, Assumptions, Conceptual Model”. The Journal of Management Sciences of Iran, Year 2, No. 5. ##-       Altaf, A. &amp; M. Atif Awan (2011). Moderating Affect of Workplace Spirituality on the Relationship of Job Overload and Job Satisfaction. Springer Science+Business. Media B.V. ##-       Alvani, Seyd Mehdi (2004). “Governmental Management &amp; the Necessity of the Optimization of the Ethical Infrastructure”. Managemet Studies Quarterly, No, 41-42. ##-       Ashmos, D.P. &amp; D. Duchon (2000). “Spirituality at Work: Aconceptualization and Measure”. Journal of ManagementInquiry, 9(2): 134-145. ##-       Baker, T.L.; T.G. Hunt &amp; M.C. Andrews (2006). “Promoting Ethical Behavior and Organizationalcitizenship Behaviors: The Influence of Corporateethical Values”. Journal of Business Research. 59: 489-857. ##-       Bradley, J. &amp; S.K. Kauanui (2003). “Comparing Spirituality on Three Southern California College Campuses”. Journal of Organizational Change Management, 16(4): 448-462. ##-       Cavanagh, G.F. &amp; M.R. Bandusuch (2002). “Virtue as Abenchmark for Spirituality in Business”. Journal of Business Ethics, 38(1-2): 109-117. ##-       Chand, Piar &amp; Hemange Koul (2012). “Organizational Emotional Ownership, Workplace Spirituality and Job Satisfaction as Moderators of Job Stress”. International Journal of Humanities and Applied Sciences(IJHAS), 1(2). ##-       Clark, A.L. (1998). Perceptions and Validation of Ethics in Public Schools. Project for the Degree of Doctor of Education. Saint Louis University. Available at:http://proquest.umi.com/login. ##-       Claude, J. &amp; G. Zamor (2003). “Workplace Spirituality and Organizational Performance”. Public Administration Review, 63 (3): 355-364. ##-       Diane, L. Wilde (2002). Determinants of Ethical Behavior of Public Administrators: Profession, Position, and Organizational Climate. Tennessee State University. ##-       Ghorbanzadeh, Om Leila (2013). “The Effect of Spiritual Intelligence on the Performance of Employees in the Organization”. Human Resources Management Journal, 5 (22): 52-59. ##-       Gibbons, P. (2001). Spirituality at Work: A Pre-Theoritical. Overview, MSC. Thesis- Birnbeck College, University of London, Aug. ##-       Gotsis, G. &amp; Z. Kortezi (2008). “Philosophical Foundations of Workplace Spirituality: A Critical Aroach”. Journal of Business Ethics, 78: 575-600. ##-       Karakas, F. (2010). “Spirituality and Performance in Organizations: A Literature Review”. Journal of Business Ethics, 94: 89-106. ##-       Karimi, Mahdi; Saeed Rajayipour &amp; Reza Hoveyda (2010). “The Examination of the Relationship between Organizational Climate Dimensions and the Ethical Behavior among the Employees of Isfahan Universities and Medical Sciences of Esfahan”. The Leadership and Training Management Quarterly, Year 4, Issue 1. ##-       Kennedy, M.H. (2002). Spirituality in the Workplace: An Empirical Study of this Phenomenon … DBA. Nova Southeastern University Press. ##-       Kinjerski, V.M. &amp; Berna J. Skrypnek (2004). “Defining Spirit at Work: Finding Common Cround”. Journal of Organizational Change Management, 17(1): 26-42. ##-       Kord Tamini, Bahman; Zahra Nikmanesh &amp; Maryam Ghabrpour (2014). “The Examination of the Relationship between Organizational Spirituality and Job Burnout among Nurses of Governmental Hospitals of Zahedan (2014)”. Public Management Research, Vol. 7, No. 24: 141-152. ##-       Krahnke, Keiko; Robert A. Giacalone &amp; Carole L. Jurkiewicz (2003). Journal of Organizational Change Management, 16(4): 396-405. ##-       Krishnakumar, S. and C.P. Neck (2002). “The &quot;what&quot;, &quot;why&quot; and &quot;how&quot; of Spirituality in the Workplace”. Journal of Managerial Psychology, 17(3): 153-164. ##-       Ledbetter, C.M. (2005). The Relationship of Knowledge Management and Ethics Managemen to Perceved Wise Leadership: Anempirical Investigation. Unpublished Doctoral Dissertation, Capettal University. ##-       Loutan, Allen (2005). Ethical Management in GovernmentalServices. Translation by Mohammad Reza Rabiei and Hasan Giroian, Tehran: Yekan Publication. ##-       Lupuleac, Z.L.; S. Lupuleac &amp; C. Rusu (2012). “Changingethical Behavior in Times of Economic Crisis Inorganizations”. Procedia Economics and Finance, 3: 921-927. ##-       Lussier, R.N. (1993). Human Relations in Organizations. A Skill-Building Approach. 2 end Edition Homewood, Boston: IRWIN. ##-       Lussier, R.N. (2000). Human Relations in Organizations: a Skillbuilding Approach, 2 nd ed,Homewood, il: Richarod D. Irwin. ##-       Mackie, J.L. (1990). Ethics: Inventing Right and Wrong. London: Penguin Books. ##-       Marques, J. &amp; S. Dhiman &amp; R. King (2007). Spirituality in the Workplace: What it is, Why it Matters, How to Make it Work for you. Published by Personhood Press. ##-       Marques, J.; S. Dhiman &amp; R. King. (2005). “Spirituality in the Workplace: Developing an Integral Model and a Comprehencive Definition”. Journal of American Academy of Business, Cambridge, Vol. 7. No. 1: 81-92. ##-       Marschke, E.; R. Preziosi &amp; W. Harrington (2009). “Professionals and Executives Suort a Relationship Between Organizational Commitment and Spirituality In The Workplace”. Journals Cloteomlone Com, 7(8): 33-48. ##-       Mckee, M. &amp; C. Driscoll (2012). Transformation Leadership and Employee Well-being: Insights from Leaders Participating in Training. Proceedings of the 2012 Atlantic Schools of Business Ethics. Boston, MA, Aug. 3-5. ##-       Mehta, Y. &amp; S. Joshi (2010). “Impact of Workplace Spirituality on Organization Culture through Improved Employee Productivity”. AIMS International Conferenceon Value-based Management. August 11-13: 221-226. ##-       Milliman, J.; A.J. Czaplewski &amp; J. Ferguson (2003). “Workplace Spirituality Andemployee Work Attitudes, An Exploratory Empirical Assessment”. Journal of Organizational Change Management, Vol. 16, No. 4: 426-447. ##-       Naran, F. (1992). “Your Role in Shaping Ethics”. Executive Excellence, 9: 11-13. ##-       Sabbagh Mollahoseini, Iman (2013). “The Examination of the Effects of the Organizational Spirituality on the Ethical Behavior of the Employees in Governmental Organizations”. The First National Conference on Accounting &amp; Management. Shiraz: Kharazmi International Institute for Educational and Research. ##-       Saleh Nia, Monireh &amp; Zeinab allah Tavakoli (2009). “Organizational Ethics with Emphasis on the Ethical Charter”. Journal of Ethics in Science and Technology, Year 4, Issue 3 and 4. ##-       Sass, J. (2000). “Characterizing Organizational Communication Culture Aroach”. Communication Studies, 51(3): 195-217. ##-       Sheep, M.L. (2004). Nailing Down Gossamer: A Valid Measure of the Person OrganizationFit of Workplace Spirituality. Academy of Management. Best Conference Paper MSR. ##-       Tavallayi, Rohollah (2009). “The Effective Factors on the Ethical Behaviour of the Employees”. Police Human Development Monthly, No. 25. ##-       Vallabh, P. (2010). “Workplace Spirituality- Relationship with Organizational Culture and Organizational Effectiveness”. AIMS International Conference on Value-based Management, August 11-13: 881-891. ##-       Weihui, F. (2013). “The Impact of Emotionalintelligence, Organizational Commitment, and Jobsatisfaction on Ethical Behavior of Chineseemployees”. Journal of Business Ethics, 114 (2): 355-366. ##-       Yazdani, Hamidreza; MohammadReza Kazemi Najaf Abadi &amp; Gholamreza Salimi (2010). “The Study of the Mediating Role of Spirituality in the Relationship between the Dimensions of Organizational Justice and the Consequences of Spirituality”. The Vision of Business Management Journal, No. 3. ##-       Zsolnali L. (2010). Spirituality and Business. Germany: Springer Berlin Heidelberg. P. 87-90.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>طراحی مدل دانشگاه پایدار، مبتنی بر مطالعات صورت گرفته در ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Planning a Sustainable University Model Based on the Researches in Iran</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف از این پژوهش، مطالعۀ نظام‌مند و سنتزپژوهی بر الگوهای نظری و پژوهشهای صورت‌گرفته در ایران با موضوع دانشگاه پایدار به منظور تلخیص، طبقه‌بندی و تلفیق مؤلفه‌های آن بود. روش: پژوهش حاضر از نظر هدف، کاربردی با رویکرد کیفی و راهبرد آن، سنتزپژوهی است. بدین منظور، تعداد 15 مقالۀ داخلی، بررسی و برای جمع‌آوری و تحلیل داده‌ها، از روش تحلیل محتوای کیفی استقرایی مبتنی بر کدگذاری باز، محوری و انتخابی، به وسیلۀ نرم‌افزار Nvivo-10 استفاده شد. یافته‌ها: پس از کدگذاری، 203 مؤلفۀ دانشگاه پایدار در 25 مقوله و هشت بُعد سازماندهی شدند. ابعاد به ترتیب نزولی تعداد ارجاع و منابع عبارتند از: مدیریت زیست‌محیطی فضای دانشگاهی؛ آموزش پایدار؛ مشارکت‌کنندگان؛ مدیریت پایدار؛ سرمایۀ اجتماعی؛ پژوهش پایدار؛ نظارت، ارزیابی و گزارش‌دهی؛ اداری و مالی. نتیجه‌گیری:در الگوهای داخلی ارائه شده برای دانشگاه پایدار، به بُعد اجتماعی، فرهنگی و اقتصادی توسعۀ پایدار در مقابل بعد زیست‌محیطی کمتر توجه شده است. لزوم توجه بیشتر به حوزه‌های اجتماعی، پژوهش، نظارت و ارزیابی و اداری و مالی در خصوص پایداری دانشگاهها، در کنار توجه به مدیریت زیست‌محیطی فضای دانشگاهی، آموزش پایدار، مشارکت‌کنندگان و مدیریت پایدار تأکید می‌شود. طراحی الگویی جامع و کل‌نگر در خصوص پایداری دانشگاه توسط هر یک از دانشگاههای بزرگ کشور، مطابق با فرهنگ ایران اسلامی و متناسب با توانایی‌ها و مأموریتهای آنها توصیه می‌شود.
 </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objective: Sustainable development and balanced in all economic, social, cultural, political and environmental dimensions of the community depends on the development of human resources, the continuous development of higher education institutions and the establishment of sustainable universities. The purpose of this research is to systematically study and synthesize research on theoretical models and researches conducted in Iran with the subject of sustainable university in order to summarize, classify and integrate the components of the University. Method: Using qualitative method of Meta-Synthesis, 15 papers were studied and data collection and analysis data was done by open, axial and selective coding and using Nvivo-10 software.Results: 203 of the University&#039;s sustainability indicators were organized in 25 components and 8 dimensions. Dimensions in terms of number of referrals and number of sources in descending order are: campus environmental management, sustainable education, contributors, sustainable management, social capital, sustainable research, monitoring, evaluation and reporting, and administrative and financial. Conclusion: The results of the findings showed that: less research has been done with a native and comprehensive approach to sustainable higher education, The environmental dimension of sustainable development has been considered more than social and economic, cultural as well as key and infrastructure of other aspects of sustainable development, have been neglected. Designing a comprehensive and holistic model of sustainability universities, according to Iran&#039;s culture and Islamic-Iranian model of progress for future research is recommended.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>193</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>216</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سبد ابراهیم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>راد</Family>
						<NameE>E</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری برنامه ریزی درسی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اراک، اراک، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری برنامه ریزی درسی، دانشگاه آزاد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فقیهی</Family>
						<NameE>A</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Faghihi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اراک(نویسنده مسئول) / نشانی: اراک، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اراک ، گروه علوم تربیتی / نمابر: 086۴۱۳۲۴۵۱/ Email: a-faghihi@iau-arak.ac.ir</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sib_ra@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فائزه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ناطقی</Family>
						<NameE>F</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nateghi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری برنامه ریزی درسی، استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اراک</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری برنامه ریزی درسی، استادیار گروه علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>f-nateghi@iau-arak.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>معینی کیا</Family>
						<NameE>M</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moeini Kia</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری برنامه ریزی آموزش از راه دور، دانشیار گروه علوم تربیتی دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی. اردبیل-ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری برنامه ریزی آموزش از راه دور، دانشیار</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m_moeinikia@uma.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>: مد آموزش عالی پایدار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دانشگاه پایدار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توسعۀ پایدار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سنتزپژوهی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>منابع ##-      آراسته، ح و امیری،ا. (1391). نقش دانشگاه در توسعه پایدار. مجله نشاء علم. سال دوم. شماره دوم. خردادماه. ##-      افتخاری و دیگران(1389). «راهبردهای توسعۀ آموزش توسعۀ پایدار در ایران». جغرافیا (فصلنامه علمی- پژوهشی انجمن جغرافیای ایران)، دوره جدید، سال هشتم، ش 25. ##-      ایروانی، هـ.؛ ح. شعبانعلی فمی، ا. علی‌بیگی، خ. کلانتری و س. میرایی آشتیانی(1385). الگویی برای تلفیق پایداری در آموزش عالی کشاورزی. مجله علوم کشاورزی ایران. دوره 2-37. شماره 1 (ویژه اقتصاد و توسعه کشاورزی). صص 47-35. ##-      پروین، ا.؛ س. غیاثی ندوشن و ش. محمدی(1394). «ارائۀ مدل مفهومی رابطۀ بین کیفیت برونداد آموزش عالی و توسعۀ پایدار بر اساس رویکرد سیستمی». پژوهشهای رهبری و مدیریت آموزشی، ش 1 (1): 117-97. ##-      پورآتشی، م.(1393). «تلفیق پایداری در آموزش عالی: مبانی و چالشها». مجموعه مقالات دومین همایش آموزش عالی و توسعۀ پایدار. تهران: مؤسسۀ پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی آموزش عالی. 35-23. ##-      جاودانی، ح. و ج. میلی منفرد(1393). «دانشگاه پایدار گذرگاهی برای برزیستی با کیفیت». مجموعه مقالات دومین همایش آموزش عالی و توسعۀ پایدار. تهران: مؤسسۀ پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی آموزش عالی. 727-717. ##-      جکسون، ر. و گ. سورنسون(1385). درآمدی بر روابط بین‌الملل. ترجمۀ م. ذاکریان. تهران: میزان. ##-      رضایی، م.(1390). «دانشگاه فرهنگیان، پاسخی به نیاز معلمان برای افزایش دانش حرفه‌ای در دنیای متحول امروز». پژوهشنامۀ فرهنگیان، شماره 1. ص 32. ##-      روشن، ا.ر.؛ ا. زمانی و س. ابراهیمی(1393). «توسعۀ پایدار، سود سه‌وجهی و آموزش عالی». مجموعه مقالات دومین همایش آموزش عالی و توسعۀ پایدار. تهران: مؤسسۀ پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی آموزش عالی. 702-681. ##-      سازمان ملل متحد(1394). دگرگون ساختن جهان‌مان: دستور کار 2030 برای توسعۀ پایدار. ترجمۀ م. پیروز نیک. کمیسیون ملی یونسکو ایران. ##-      سهرابی، ا.؛ ح. بردبار و ح. نوری(1391). «بررسی وضعیت همگامی دانشگاههای دولتی ایران با توسعۀ پایدار بر اساس الگوی FLA؛ مطالعۀ موردی دانشگاه قم و پردیس قم دانشگاه تهران)». مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی، ش 1: 193-171. ##-      شورت(1387). روش‌شناسی مطالعات برنامۀ درسی. ترجمۀ مهرمحمدی و همکاران. تهران: سمت و پژوهشگاه مطالعات آموزش و پرورش. ##-      صادقی، م.؛ پ. جعفری و ن. قورچیان(1393). «ارائۀ الگویی برای دانشگاه پایدار در دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی». مجموعه مقالات دومین همایش آموزش عالی و توسعۀ پایدار. تهران: مؤسسۀ پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی آموزش عالی. 174-147. ##-      صالحی، غ.(1393). «آموزش عالی در گذار از توسعۀ پایدار به پساپایداری». مجموعه مقالات دومین همایش آموزش عالی و توسعۀ پایدار. تهران: مؤسسه پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی آموزش عالی. 22-1. ##-      عطافر، علی؛ محمد اسماعیل انصاری، هوشنگ طالبی و سید اکبر نیلی‌پور طباطبایی(1387). «الگوی مطلوب دانشگاه پایدار در نظام آموزش عالی ایران». ششمین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت. ##-      عظمتی، حمیدرضا و م. باقری(1387). «آموزش مفاهیم توسعۀ پایدار با طراحی معماری و منظر دانشگاه». فنّاوری و آموزش، سال دوم، ش 3: 292-283. ##-      علوی مقدم، محمدرضا؛ رضا مکنون و احمد طاهر شمسی(1387). «ارتقای آموزش و پژوهش مهندسی در راستای توسعۀ پایدار؛ راهبردها». فنّاوری و آموزش، سال دوم، ج 2، ش 3. ##-      علی‌بیگی، حسین و رضوان قمبرعلی(1389). «ارائۀ الگوی مفهومی برای آموزش عالی پایدار». پژوهش در نظامهای آموزشی، ش 9. ##-      محب حسینی، م.(1395). آموزش ۲۰۳۰: ابزار اساسی برای دستیابی به اهداف توسعۀ پایدار ۲۰۳۰ سازمان ملل متحد. گروه آموزش کمیسیون ملی یونسکو. ##-      مدهوشی، م.؛ ع. نوروزی و م. تجری(1393). «جایگاه دانشگاه در توسعۀ پایدار». مجموعه مقالات دومین همایش آموزش عالی و توسعۀ پایدار. تهران: مؤسسۀ پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی آموزش عالی. 600-579. ##-      مرندی، ع.(1381). «توسعۀ پایدار در دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)». مدیریت نظامی، ش 7: 76-67. ##-      ملکی‌نیا، ع.؛ ع. بازرگان، م. واعظی و م. احمدیان(1393). شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی مؤلفه‌های دانشگاه پایدار. تهران: فصلنامه پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی در آموزش عالی. دوره 20. شماره 3.صص.26-1. ##-      نوری، جعفر؛ مجید عباس‌پور و آ. یوسفی(1380). «مدیریت زیست‌محیطی سایت واحد علوم و تحقیقات دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی در راستای توسعۀ پایدار». علوم و تکنولوژی محیط زیست، ش 8-7: 89-73. ##-       Alavi Moghaddam. M.  and others  ( 2008), “ development strategies of engineering  the education and training of sustainable development ”. Technology and education. Second year, vol: 2. N.3 ##-       Alibeigi . H. and Rezvan Ghambarali ( 2010), “ a conceptual pattern for a sustainable  higher education”. Research in educative systems,N:9. ##-       Arasteh H. and Amiri( 2011), “ the role of university in Sustainable Development”. Journal of neshae elm, second year N.2. ##-       Atafar . A. and others ( 2008), “the ideal pattern of sustainable university in Iran  higher education system  ”. The sixth management international Conference. ##-       Azemati. H. and M.  Bagheri  ( 2008), “ teaching the concepts of sustainable development by academic planning and university perspective  ”. Technology and education. N.3: 283-292. ##-       Beynaghi, A.; G. Trencher, F. Moztarzadeh, M. Mozafari, R. Maknoon &amp; W. Leal Filho (2016). “Future Sustainability Scenarios for Universities: Moving beyond the United Nations Decade of Education for Sustainable Development”. Journal of Cleaner Production, 112: 3464-3478. ##-       Branje, M. (2013). The Sustainable Uuniversity Campus. An Analysis of the Transition Process of Universities in Their Endeavor to Become More Sustainable. Master of Science in Innovation Sciences. ##-       Calder, W. &amp; J. Dautremont-Smith (2009). Higher Education: More and More Laboratories for Inventing a Sustainable Future. Agenda for a Sustainable America: 93-107. ##-       Eftekhari and others ( 2010), “ the strategies of  Sustainable Development education in Iran ”. joghrafia quarterly magazine, eight  year ,N.25. ##-       Irvani and others ( 2006), “ a Sustainable pattern  in agriculture higher education”. Iran agriculture sciences magazine, N.1.( especial issue : economy and agriculture development) .P: 35-48. ##-       Jackson, R. and G. Sorensen ( 2006), “ Introduction to International Relations”. Translation by M.Zakerian.Tehran   : Mizan. ##-       Javdani, H. and J , milimonfared( 2014), “sustainable university as a ground for a qualitative life   ”. The second conference of higher education and sustainable development, Tehran: research and higher education planning institute   : 717-727 ##-       Larrán Jorge, M.; J. Herrera Madueño, Y. Calzado &amp; J. Andrades (2016). “A Proposal for Measuring Sustainability in Universities: a Case Study of Spain”. International Journal of Sustainability in Higher Education, 17(5): 671-697. ##-       Lozano, R.; K. Ceulemans, M. Alonso-Almeida, D. Huisingh, F.J. Lozano, T. Waas &amp; J. Hugé (2015). “A Review of Commitment and Implementation of Sustainable Development in Higher Education: Results from a Worldwide Survey”. Journal of Cleaner Production, 108: 1-18. ##-       Lozano, R.; R. Lukman, F.J. Lozano, D. Huisingh &amp; W. Lambrechts (2013). “Declarations for Sustainability in Higher Education: Becoming better Leaders, through Addressing the University System”. Journal of Cleaner Production, 48: 10-19. ##-       Malekinia, A. and others ( 2014), “ recognition and prioritizing the components of sustainable university”. Tehran: research and planning in higher education quarterly N:3 : 1-26 ##-       Marandi . A. (2002), “Sustainable Development in Imam Ali Officers Academy” military management, N7:67-76. ##-       Mdhooshi. M. and others ( 2014), “ the place of university in   sustainable development”. The second conference of higher education and sustainable development, Tehran: research and higher education planning institute   : 579-600 ##-       Moheb Hosseini,M. (2016) , “ teaching  2030 document : a fundamental process to enhance the aims of  2030 sustainable development of the united nations ”. education group of UNESCO National Commission. ##-       Noori, J. and others ( 2001), “ Environmental  Management of Islamic Azad University ( Sciences and researches branch site ) along with sustainable development”. Environment sciences and technology N:7-8 : 73-89 ##-       Parvin , A . and others ( 2015), “the conceptual model of the relation between higher education quality and Sustainable Development based on systematic approach  ”. Leadership and educative management researches ,N.1.(1): 9-117 ##-       Pour atashi, M. ( 2014), “ the principles and challenges of sustainability in higher education”. The second conference of higher education and sustainable development, Tehran: research and higher education planning institute   : 239-35 ##-       Rezaee M. ( 2011), “ Cultural University , a necessity  to develop  teacher&#039;s  professional knowledge in modern world”.  Teacher&#039;s Research journal [pezhohesh nameh farhangian], N.1.P: 32. ##-       Roshan. A and others ( 2014), “sustainable development ; three dimension benefit and higher education  ”. The second conference of higher education and sustainable development, Tehran: research and higher education planning institute   : 681-702. ##-       Sadeghi. M. and others ( 2014), “ a pattern for sustainable university in Islamic Azad University”. The second conference of higher education and sustainable development, Tehran: research and higher education planning institute   : 147-174. ##-       Salehi. Gh. ( 2014), “ higher education; from  sustainable development to post sustainability  ”. The second conference of higher education and sustainable development, Tehran: research and higher education planning institute   : 1-22. ##-       Salonen, A.O. &amp; S. Tast (2013). “Finish Early Childhood Educators and Sustainable Development”. Journal of Sustainable Development, 6(2): 70. ##-       Sandelowski, M. &amp; J. Barros (2007). Handbook for Synthesizing Qualitative Research. Springer Publishing Company Inc. ##-       Short (2008). “Forms of Curriculum Inquiry” Translation by Mehrmohammadi and others . Tehran: Samt and education and training studies research school. ##-       Sohrabi , A . Bordbar H. and H. Noori. ( 2012), “ Synchronicity of Iran State Universities and Sustainable Development based on FLA Model ”.  Management in Islamic University journal, N.1.P: 171-193. ##-       United  Nations (2015), , “ Transforming our world: the 2030 Agenda for sustainable development ”. Translation by M. pirouz nik , Iranian National Commission for UNESCO.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>شناسایی چالشهای جانشین‌پروری در محیط دانشگاهی (مورد مطالعه:کارکنان دانشگاههای استان ایلام)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Challenges of Succession in Iran&#039;s Higher Education&#039;s Centers
 ( Case Study: Universities of Ilam Province)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: تحقیق حاضر با هدف شناسایی چالشهای پیشروی جانشین‌پروری در محیط دانشگاهی، در میان کارکنان دانشگاههای استان ایلام انجام شد.روش:این پژوهش به روش داده‌بنیاد و انجام مصاحبه با 12 نفر از خبرگان مدیریت منابع انسانی با استفاده از روش گلوله‌برفی در دانشگاههای استان ایلام صورت گرفت. برای بررسی و تحلیل داده‌ها از روش کد‌گذاری باز، محوری و انتخابی استفاده شد. در مرحلۀ کمّی نیز 360 نفر از مدیران و کارکنان برای تکمیل پرسشنامۀ محقق‌ساخته مشارکت داشتند.یافته‌ها:ابهام در نقش، آموزش نامناسب کارکنان، عدم توجه به شایسته‌سالاری، ارزیابی عملکرد نامناسب و فرهنگ بی‌تفاوتی، در زمرۀ عوامل علّی ایجاد چالش برای جانشین‌پروری و پدیده محوری جانشین‌‌پروری مشتمل بر ضعف کارراهۀ شغلی و عدم فرصت برابر برای ارتقا می‌شود که تحت تأثیر عوامل زمینه‌ای و عوامل مداخله‌گر، منجر به پیامدهایی برای جانشین‌پروری می‌‌شود. نتیجه‌گیری:آموزش صحیح و تدوین دستورالعمل جانشینی، مسیر ارتقای مناسب را فراهم می‌سازد و نبود آن، چالش محسوب می‌شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives:The aim of the present study is to identify challenges facing succession planning within academic environments among employees of Ilam Universities. Method: This study has carried out using database method and making interviews to 12 experts in the field of human resource management through snowball method in universities of Ilam province. In order to analyze data, open, axial, and selective coding ways were applied. At quantitative stage, 360 managers and employees participated in completing questionnaire provided by researcher. Results: Research findings indicated that ambiguity in role, inappropriate training for employees, lack of respect to meritocracy, inappropriate performance evaluation,indifferenceculture, regarded among causal central factors emerging challenges of succession and succession include weakness in career path of equal opportunities for improvement, which can lead to some consequences for succession influenced by field factors and intervener factors. Conclusion: The authors of the research concluded that appropriate training and formulating succession instructions would provide a path for appropriate improvement and lack of which is regarded as a challenge.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>217</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>236</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ستاره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عباسی</Family>
						<NameE>S</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Abbasi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه ایلام. ایلام- ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه ایلام.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>setarehabbasi95@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>اردشیر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شیری</Family>
						<NameE>A</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shiri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی و دانشیار گروه مدیریت دانشکده علوم انسانی دانشگاه ایلام. ایلام- ایران(نویسنده مسئول) / نشانی: ایلام، بلوارپژوهش، دانشگاه ایلام، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی / نمابر: 08432227014 / Email: Shiri_Ardeshir@yahoo.com</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی و دانشیار گروه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shiri_ardeshir@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تابان</Family>
						<NameE>M</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Taban</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی و استادیار گروه مدیریت دانشکده علوم انسانی دانشگاه ایلام. ایلام</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی و استادیار گروه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.taban@ilam.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جانشین‌پروری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>برنامۀ جانشین‌پروری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>برنامه‌ریزی نیروی انسانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>منابع ##-       ابوالعلایی، بهزاد و عباس غفاری(1385). «سرمایۀ انسانی مزیت رقابتی سازمانها درعرصۀ جهانی‌سازی». گزیده مقالات سی و هفتمین کنفرانس جهانی منابع انسانی(ص 132-1). تهران: آهار. ##-       اشتراوس، آنسلم و جولیت کوربین(1385). اصول روش تحقیق کیفی. ترجمۀ بیوک محمدی. تهران: پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی. ##-       افاضلی، محمد اسماعیل (1387). مدیریت استعداد، توسعه منابع انسانی، ششمین کنفرانس بین المللی مدیریت، تهران. ##-       امین بیدختی، علی‌اکبر؛ سیدمجتبی زرگر و نوید شرفی(1391). «بررسی راهکارهای دستیابی به تعالی در دانشگاهها و مؤسسات آموزش عالی». مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی. دوره اول، ش3:484-465. ##-       پورصادق، ناصر؛ شهریارپیری و بهزادخاتمی(1391). «بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر اجرای موفق جانشین‌پروری مدیران». مطالعات منابع انسانی، سال دوم، ش 7: 36-19. ##-       روث ویل، ویلیام جی، (1393). برنامه ریزی جانشین پروری اثربخش،ترجمه سیدرضا سید جوادین و دیگران. تهران: نشر نگاه دانش. زبردست، محمدامجد(1392). «چالش برنامه‌ریزی و مدیریت جانشینی در ادارات آموزش و‌پرورش کردستان». رفتار سازمانی در آموزش و‌پرورش،سال اول، ش 2: 94-77. ##-       زین الدینی بیدمشکی، زهره (1393). سنجش میزان آمادگی آموزش عالی برای اجرای برنامه جانشین پروری و مدیریت استعدادها، پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد دانشگاه الزهرا. ##-       طباطبایی مقدم، فرشته(1389). بررسی کژکارکردهای جانشین‌پروری در سطح مدیریت ارشد. پایان‌نامۀ کارشناسی ارشد. دانشگاه تهران. ##-       عیدی، اکبر و محمد دیانتی(1387). «مراکز ارزیابی روش نوین جانشین‌پروری». تدبیر، ش3:31-26. ##-       غریب، عباس(1394). ارائۀ الگوی تبیین سوءرفتار گروهی با استفاده از نظریۀ سرایت اجتماعی. پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد. دانشگاه ایلام. -      کارترایت، راجر. (1387). مدیریت استعداد: نگاهی نو به توسعه سرمایه انسانی، ترجمه علی محمد گودرزی و سید جمال حسینی. تهران: نشر رسا. ##-       گای، ماتیو و دوریس سیمز(1388). توسعۀ استعدادهای آتی(راهنمای کاربردی مدیریت استعداد و برنامه‌ریزی جانشین‌پروری). ترجمۀ نسرین جزنی. تهران: سرآمد. ##-       هادی‌زاده مقدم، اکرم و فرزانه سلطانی(1390). «معرفی مدل جامع و سیستمی مدیریت جانشین‌پروری برای سازمانها». نهمین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت. ص 454-345. ##-       Abdollah,Z.(2009).“Succession Planningin Malaysian Institution of Higher Education”. International Education Studies,2(1). ##-       Abol&#039;Alaei, Behzad&amp;Abbas Ghaffari (2006). “Human Capital: Organizations&#039; Competitive Advantage in Globalization”.Selected Articles of 31stInternational Conference of Human Resource: P. 1-132. Tehran: Ahar Publications. ##-       Afazeli, M. (2008). Talent management, developing the human resources. Tehran: 6thinternational management conference (in Persian). ##-       Amin Beidokhti, Ali Akbar&amp; Forouzan Karimi (2012). “The Moderating Role of Organizational Commitment in the Relationship between Organizational Learning and Survivor Management (Case Study: Selected Universities of Tehran)”.Executive Management Research Journal, 5th year, No. 10: 35-58. ##-       AminBeidokhti, Ali Akbar; S.Mojtaba Zargar&amp; Navid Sharafi (2012).“Examining the Solutions for Excellence in Universities and Higher Education Institutions”.Journal of Management in Azad University, 1st issue, No.3: 465-484. ##-       Bagley, Tracy L. (2008). Employee Retention and Succession Planning for a Department of the Navy Program Office. ##-       Barnett, R. &amp;S. Davis (2008). “Creating Greater Success in Succession Planning”. Advances in Developing Human Resources, 10 (5): 721-739. ##-       Clunies, J.P. (2007). “Benchmarking Succession Planning and Executive Development in Higher Education: Is the Academy Ready Now to Employ these Corporate Paradigms?”.Academic Leadership the Online Journal, 2(4): 13. ##-       Collings, D.G. &amp; Mellahi, K. (2009). “Strategic Talent Management: A Review and Research Agenda”. Human Resource Management Review, 19: 304-313. ##-       Collins, S.K. &amp; Collins, K.S. (2007). “Succession Planning and Leadership Development: Critical Business Strategies for Health care Organizations”. Radiology Management, 29(1): 16-21. ##-       Diane Osterhaus, Neefe (2009). Succession Planning in a Two-Year Technical CollegeSystem. A Dissertation: Submitted to the Faculty of the Graduate School of the Universityof Minnesota. ##-       Eidi, Akbar&amp; Muhammad Dianati (2008). “Centers for Evaluation of Modern Method of Succession”.Tadbir, No.3: 26-31. ##-       Fulmer, R.M.&amp;J.A. Conger (2004). Growing your Company’s Leaders: How Great Organizations Use Succession Managementto Sustain Competitive Advantage. AMACOM.New York. ##-       Gharib, Abbas (2015). Offering a Pattern for Explaining Group Misconduct by Using the Theory of Social Contagion. A Master&#039;s Thesis. Ilam State University. ##-       Gharib, Abbas; AliYasini&amp;ArdeshirShiri (2015). “Examining the Impact of Social Information Components on Organizational Misbehaviors, Mediating Role of Organizational Justice”.4th National Conference and 2nd International Conference of Accounting and Management. ##-       Greasley, K. &amp; King, N. (2005). Employee Perceptions of Empowerment. Emerald Group Publishing. 27 (4):351-368. ##-               Greer, C. &amp; M. Virick (2008). “Diverse Succession Planning: Lessons from the Industry Leaders”. Human Resource Management, 47(2): 351-367..Guy, M. and Doris, S. (2009). Development of Future Talent (Applied Guide to Talent Management and Planning for Succession). Translated by Nasrin Jazani. Tehran: saramad publication. ##-       Groves, K.S. (2007). “Integrating Leadership Development and Succession Planning Best Practices”.Journal of Management Development, 239-260. ##-       HadizadehMoghadam, Akram&amp; Farzaneh Soltani (2011).“Introducing a Comprehensive and Systematic Model of Succession Management for Organizations”.9th International Conference of Management, P.345-454. ##-       Helton, Kimberly A. &amp; Robeti D. Jackson (2007). “Navigating Pennsylvania&#039;s Dynamic Workforce: Succession Planning in a Complex Environment”.Public Personnel Management, Vol. 36, No. 4: 335-47. ##-       Hunte-Cox, D.E. (2004). Dissertation: Organization Succession Planning and the Organizational Learning Capacity. Doctor of Education in Human Resource Development. George Washington University.United State: ProQuest Information and Learning Company. ##-       Jerusalem, B.R. (2008). “Succession Management: The Next Generation of Succession Planning”.Human Resource Planning, 19/3: 1-29. ##-       Kartwright, R. (2008). Managing Talent.Translated by A.M.Goudarzi&amp; et al. Tehran: Rasaa Publication. ##-       Kezar, A. &amp; P.D. Eckel (2004). “Meeting Today&#039;s Governance Challenges”. Journal of Higher Education,Vol. 75,No. 4: 371-399. ##-       Mandi, Abdulla Rashed (2008). A Case Study Exploring Succession Planning: Supported by Quantitative Analysis of Governmental Organizations in the Kingdom of Bahrain. Dissertation Submitted to The George Washington University. ##-       Mateso,E.E.P.(2010).Understanding Succession Planning and Management Effortsat Midwestern University .Doctoral Dissertation. Retrieved from http://etd.ohiolink.Ed. ##-       Mohan,N.(2008).Talent Management of Indian Industry. Doctoral Dissertation. Retrieved from www.scribd.com. ##-       Porsadegh, Nasser;Shahryar Piri&amp;Behzad Khatami (2012). “Examining Influencing Factors on Successful Implementation of Managers&#039; Succession”. Quarterly Journal of Human Resource Studies, 2nd year, NO.7, Spring2013, pp. 19-36 ##-       Richards, CherylL.(2009). A New Paradigm: Strategies for Succession Planning in Higher Education. Capella University. ##-       Rothwell, W.J. (2005). Effective Succession Planning: Ensuring Leadership Continuity and Building Talent from within. New York: AMACOM. 3 rd Edition. ##-       Rothwell, W.J. (2006). Effective Succession Planning: Insuring Leadership Continuity and Building Talent from within. Translated by Seyyed Javadin, S. et al. Tehran: Negah danesh Publication. (In Persian). ##-       Slan, R.S. (2005).Leadership Succession: The Justice Perceptionsof High Potential, Identification Practices. Dissertation for M.A. Degree. University of Guelph. ##-       Strauss, Anselm &amp;Juliet Corbin (1985). “Principles of Qualitative Research Methodology: Basic Theory, Procedures and Practices”.Translated by BiuckMohammadi. Tehran: Institute of Humanities and Cultural Studies. ##-       TabatabaeiMoghadam, Fereshteh (2010). Examining Dysfunctions of Succession at Senior Level of Management. A Master&#039;s Thesis. Tehran University. ##-       Zainuddini Bidmeshki, Z. (2014). Assessment of Higher Education Preparedness for Implementation of Succession and Talent Management Programs, Master&#039;s thesis at Alzahra University.Zebardast, MuhamadAmjad (2013). “The Challenge of Succession Planning and Management in Kurdistan Departments of Education”.Journal of Organizational Behavior in Education, 1st year, No.2:77-94.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اثر قابلیتهای چابکی راهبردی و‌ عاطفی سازمان بر کارآفرینی‌گرایی دانشگاه (مطالعۀ موردی: دانشگاههای شهر قم و کاشان)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Impact of Strategic Agility and Organization Emotional Capabilities on University’s Entrepreneurship-Orientation
(Case Study: Universities of Qom and Kashan Cities)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: این پژوهش، درصدد کاوش اثر قابلیتهای چابکی راهبردی و عاطفی سازمان بر کارآفرینی‌گرایی دانشگاه بود. روش: روش پژوهش، توصیفی- همبستگی است. جامعۀ پژوهش را پرسنل دانشگاههای دولتی قم و کاشان تشکیل می‌دهند که 572 نفر از آنان به شیوۀ نمونه‌برداری غیر احتمالی در دسترس در پژوهش شرکت کردند. داده‌های پژوهش‌ به وسیلۀ پرسشنامه‌ جمع‌آوری شد و با آزمونهای‌آماری توصیفی و استنباطی تحلیل شدند. یافته‌ها: الف) قابلیت چابکی راهبردی بر قابلیت عاطفی و کارآفرینی‌گرایی، تأثیر مستقیم، مثبت و معنادار دارد. ب) قابلیت عاطفی بر کارآفرینی‌گرایی، تأثیر مستقیم، مثبت و معنادار دارد. ج) طبق نتایج تحلیل مسیر، قابلیت چابکی راهبردی از طریق قابلیت عاطفی بر کارآفرینی‌گرایی اثر غیر مستقیم مثبت دارد. نتیجه‌گیری: موفقیت و مزیت رقابتی دانشگاهها در اقتصاد دانش‌بنیان به توانش پاسخگویی آنها به تقاضاهای در حال تغییر ذی‌نفعان درون و برون سازمانی و در نتیجه، تولید دانش و فنّاوری و تجاری‌سازی آنها با هدف ارتقای بهروزی اقتصادی، اجتماعی، فرهنگی و معنوی جامعۀ بشری در سطح محلی، ملی و بین‌المللی است. به علت اینکه عواطف مبیّن الگوهای اجتماعی- فرهنگی تجربه و رفتارند که در پاسخ به اقدامات اصلاحی/ بازآفرینی پویای دانشگاه با تأکید بر تفکر راهبردی و تبیین چشم‌اندازی روشن برای دانشگاه کارآفرین، از سوی منابع انسانی آشکار می‌شوند، لذا تیم مدیریت ارشد به اتفاق سایر سطوح مدیریت بایستی عواطف سازمانی را در سبک رهبری دانشگاه نهادینه کرده، با برجسته‌سازی تعهد جمعی/ وحدت رهبری در گسترۀ دانشگاه به وسیلۀ ایجاد وابستگی متقابل، کار با همدیگر، تغییرات در تیم مدیریت ارشد، سبک رهبری و قابلیتهای مدیران اجرایی ارشد، الگوهای عاطفی حامی و پشتیبان ارزشهای کارآفرینی نوجویی، استقلال، ریسک‌پذیری، فعالانه عمل کردن و رقابت‌جویی تهاجمی را در میان همۀ اجزای دانشگاه تشویق و ترویج کنند و با ارتقای سطح حساسیت راهبردی از طریق فرایند استراتژی باز، افزایش هوشیاری راهبردی، گفتگوی درونی با کیفیت بالا؛ و بهبود قابلیت سیّالی منابع سازمان با تحرک‌بخشی بیشتر منابع فیزیکی و ادراکی، دسترسی بیشتر به منابع و ایجاد ساختارهای مدولار؛ همۀ اجزای دانشگاه را در جهت تولید دانش و فنّاوری مورد نیاز ذی‌نفعان برونی و درونی و تجاری‌سازی دانش و فنّاوری تولیدشده هدایت کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives: This research intends to explore the impact of the strategic agility and organization emotional capabilities on University entrepreneurship-orientation. Method: Research method is descriptive-correlation. The statistical population consists of personnel of Public Universities in Qom and Kashan cities, which 572 of them participated through available Non-probability sampling. The data was collected by a questionnaire, and was analyzed by the descriptive-inferential statistical tests. Results: This research showed that: A) the strategic agility capability has a significant, positive, and direct effect on the emotional capability and the entrepreneurship orientation. B) The emotional capability has a significant, positive direct impact on the entrepreneurship-orientation of universities. C) According to the results of path analysis, the strategic agility has a positive indirect impact on entrepreneurship orientation through the emotional capability. Conclusion: The success and competitive advantage of universities in knowledge-based economy depend on their responsibility ability to internal and external stakeholders changing demands; and as a result, create knowledge and technology, and commercializing of them in order to enhance the economic, socio-cultural, spiritual well-being of human society in the local, national, and international level. Because emotions indicate socio-cultural patterns of experience and behavior, that are unfolded in response to corrective actions/dynamic renew of university, with emphasizing on strategic thinking and explaining a clear vision for entrepreneurship university by human resources, therefore, the senior management team with one accord other levels of management should institutionalize the organizational emotions as the part of university leadership style, and with highlighting the leadership/ collective commitment in  throughout university by creating interdependent, working together, changes in the senior management team, leadership style and senior executives capabilities create, and promote emotional patterns that supporting  the entrepreneurial values of innovativeness, autonomy, risk-taking, proactive, and aggressive competitiveness among all parts of university; and with enhancing the level of strategic sensitivity through the process of open strategy, increasing strategic consciousness, and high-quality internal dialogue, and  as well, improving the capability of resources fluidity through the greater mobility of physical and conceptual resources provides greater access to resources, and creating modular structures, all university parts lead and encourage towards creating knowledge and technology required external and internal stakeholders, and the commercializing of created science and technology. </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>237</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>262</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>صدیقه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خورشید</Family>
						<NameE>S</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khorshid</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت سیستم و دانشیار گروه مدیریت دانشگاه  قم(نویسنده مسئول) / نشانی: قم؛ بلوار امین، دانشگاه قم، مجتمع آموزشی امام خامنه ای،  دانشکده مدیریت /  نمابر: 44219451-021/ Email: khorshidseddigheh@ymail.com</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت سیستم و دانشیار گروه مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>seddighehkhorshid@semnan.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چابکی راهبردی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قابلیت عاطفی سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارآفرینی‌‌گرایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تغییر راهبردی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دانشگاه کارآفرین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>منابع ##-       ابراهیمی نژاد، مهدی؛ جلایی، سید عبدالعظیم، خسروی، سعید(1392). بررسی رابطه بیم کارآفرینی گرایی و چابکی در شرکت های تولیدی(مطالعه موردی: شرکت های تولیدی استان کرمان). مجموعه مقالات دومین کنفرانس بین المللی مدیریت، کارآفرینی و تولید ملی، قم، دانشگاه پیام نور قم، 23 و 24 شهریور. ##-       امیری، یاسر(بهمن 1389)، بررسی رابطه بین هوش عاطفی و کارآفرینی شرکتی(مطالعه موردی: کارکنان دستگاه های اجرایی شیراز)، محموعه مقالات اولین کنفرانس بین المللی مدیریت و نوآوری، شیراز، دانشگاه شیراز. ##-       خورشید، صدیقه، و پاشازاده، عاطفه(1392). مطالعه تاثیر هوش سازمانی بر روی قابلیت عاطفی و قابلیت یادگیری سازمانی، فصل نامه مطالعات مدیریت تحول، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، 69، ص ص. 25-58. ##-       خورشید، صدیقه، و همتی،  مریم(1392). مطالعه تطبیقی چابکی استراتژیک در صنایع تولیدی شهر سمنان،  فصلنامه فرآیند مدیریت و توسعه (موسسه عالی آموزش و پژوهش مدیریت و  برنامه ریزی)، 26(1). ص ص. 29-60. ##-       Agility in Turbulent Times: http://www.colonialtdc.com/images/THINK_AGILE Chapter_1.pdf. ##-       Akgun, A.E.; H. Keskin &amp; J. Byrne (2009). “Organizational Emotional Capability, Product and Process Innovation, and Firm Performance: an Empirical Analysis”. Journal of Engineering and Technology Management, 26: 103-130. ##-       Amiri, Y. (2010). “Investigating the Relationship between the Emotional Intelligence and the Corporate Entrepreneurship (Case Study: Employees in Shiraz Executive Agencies)”. First International Conference on Management, Innovation and Entrepreneurship. 16 and 17 February- Shiraz, In Persion. ##-       Amit, R. &amp; P.J. Schoemaker (1993). “Strategic Assets and Organizational Rent”. Strategic Management Journal, 14: 33-46. ##-       Ashforth, B.E. &amp; R.H. Humphrey (1995). “Emotion in the Workplace: a Reappraisal”. Human Relations, 48: 97-125. ##-       Baron, R. and G. Markman (2003). “Beyond Social Capital: the Role of entrepreneurs’ Social Competence in their Financial Success”, Journal of ##-       Baron, R.A. &amp; J. Tang (2011). “The Role of Entrepreneurs in Firm-Level Innovation: Joint Effects of Positive Affect, Creativity, and Environmental Dynamics”. Journal of Business Venturing, 26(1): 49-60. ##-       Baron, R.A. (2008). “The Role of Affect in the Entrepreneurial Process”. Academy Management Review, 33: 323-340. ##-       Barsade, S.G. (2002). “The Ripple Effects: Emotional Contagion and its Influence on Group Behavior”. Administrative Science Quarterly, 47(4): 644-675. ##-       Blenker P.; P. Dreisler &amp; J. Kjeldsen (2006). Entrepreneurship Education – the New Challenge Facing the Universities, A Framework or Understanding and Development of Entrepreneurial University Communities. Working Paper, Department of Management, Aarhus School of Business and University of Aarhus, Denmark. ##-       Blyler, M. &amp; R. Coff (2003). “Dynamic Capabilities, Social Capital, and Rent Appropriation: Ties the Split Pies”. Strategic Management Journal, 24: 677-686. ##-       Boren, A. (2010). “Emotional Intelligence: The Secret of Successful Entrepreneurship?”. Leadership in Agriculture, 2: 55-61. ##-       Brown, S. &amp; K. Eisenhardt (1998). Competing on the Edge Strategy as Structured Chaos. Harvard Business School Press, Boston. Business Venturing,18, pp.41-60. ##-       Cardon, M.S.; C. Zietsma, P. Saparito, B. Matherne &amp; C. Davis (2005). “A Tale of Passion: New Insights into Entrepreneurship from a Parenthood Metaphor”. Journal of Business Venturing, 20(1): 23-45. ##-       Cardon, M.S.; M.D. Foo, D. Shepherd &amp; J. Wiklund (2012). “Exploring the Heart: Entrepreneurial Emotion Is a Hot Topic”. Enterepreneurship Theory and Practice, 36(1): 1-10. ##-       Damasio, A.R. (1994). Descartes’s Error. Emotion, Reason and the Human Brain. New York: Quill (reprint). ##-       Diaconn, M. &amp; A. Dutu (2015). “The Role of the Modern University in Supporting the Entrepreneurial Ecosystem”. European Journal of Interdisciplinary Studies, 7(2): 11-24. ##-       Doz, Y.L. &amp; M. Kosonen (2008). “The Dynamics of Strategic Agility: Nokia&#039;s Rollercoaster Experience”. California Management Review, 50(3): 95-118. ##-       Doz, Y.L. &amp; M. Kosonen (2010). “Embedding Strategic Agility: a Leadership Agenda for Accelerating Business Model Renewal”. Long Range Planning, 43: 370-382. ##-       Drucker, P.F. (1998). “The Discipline of Innovation”. Harvard Business Review, 76(6): 149-157. ##-       Duck, J.D. (1993). “Managing Change: The Art of Balancing”. Harvard Business Review, November-December, 109-118. ##-       Ebrahimi Nejad, M.; A. Jalaee &amp; S. Khosravi (2013). “Investigating the Relationship between Entrepreneurial Orientation and Agility in Manufacturing Enterprises Case Study: Manufacturing Enterprises of Kerman Province”. 2nd International Conference on Management, Enterpreneurship and Economic Developmen. https://www.civilica.com/EnPaper-EME02-EME02_1655.html, In Persion. ##-       Elfenbein, I.A. (2007). “Emotion in Organizations: A Review in Stages”. RLE Working Paper, No.144-07. http://irle.berkeley.edu/workingpapers/144-07.pdf. ##-       Fineman, S. (1993). Emotions in Organizations. Sage Publications, London. ##-       Foo, M.D.; H. Sin &amp; L. Yiong (2006). “Effects of Team Inputs and Intra-Team Processes on Perceptions of Team Viability and Member Satisfaction in Nascent Ventures”. Strategic Management Journal, 27(4): 389-399. ##-       Foo, M.D.; M. Uy &amp; R.A. Baron (2009). “How do Feelings Influence Effort? An Empirical Study of Entrepreneurs’ Affect and Venture Effort”. Journal of Applied Psychology, 94(4): 1086-1094. ##-       Fornell, C. &amp; D.F. Larcker (1981). “Evaluating Structural Equation Models with Unobservable Variables and Measurement Error”. Journal of Marketing Research, 18: 39-50. ##-       Garcia-Morales, V.J.; F. Matias-Reche &amp; N. Hurtado-Torres (2008). “Influence of Transformational Leadership on Organizational Innovation and Performance Depending on the Level of Organizational Learning in the Pharmaceutical Sector”. Journal of Organizational Change Management, 21(2): 188-212. ##-       Giddens, A. (1984). The Constitutions of Society: Outline of the Theory of Structuration. California Press, Berkeley, 417p. ##-       Hair, J. F. Jr., Anderson, R. E., Tatham, R. L. and Black, W. C.(1998).  Multivariate Data Analysis (5thed.), New Jersey, Prentice-Hall. ##-       Hair, J.F.; W.C. Black, B. Babin, R.E. Anderson &amp; R.L. Tathum (2006). Multivariate Data Analysis. Sixth Ed., Prentic-Hall, New Jersey. ##-               Hamel, G. (2007). The Future of Management. Harvard Business School Press, Boston ##-       Hamel, G., &amp; Valikangas, L. (2003). “The quest for resiliency”. Harvard Business Review,81(9), pp.52-63 ##-       Herbig, P., Golden, E.J. and Dunphy, A. (1994), “The relationship of structure to entrepreneurial and innovative success”, Marketing Intelligence &amp; Planning, 12(9), pp.37-48. ##-       Hornsby, J.S.; D.W. Naffziger, D.F. Kuratko &amp; R.V. Montagno (1993). “An Interactive Model of the Corporate Entrepreneurship Process”. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice, 17: 29-37. ##-       Hughes, M. &amp; R.E. Morgan (2007). “Deconstructing the Relationship between Entrepreneurial Orientation and Business Performance at the Embryonic Stage of Firm Growth”. Industrial Marketing Management, 36: 651-661. ##-       Hult, G.T.M.; R.F. Hurley &amp; G.A. Knight (2004). “Innovativeness: its Antecedents and Impact on Business Performance”. Industrial Marketing Management, 33: 429-438. ##-       Huy, Q.H. (1999). “Emotional Capability, Emotional Intelligence, and Radical Change”. Academy of Management Review, 24(2): 325-345. ##-       Huy, Q.N. (2002). “Emotional Balancing of Organizational Continuity and Radical Change: the Contribution of Middle Managers in Radical Change”. Administrative Science Quarterly, 47: 31-69. ##-       Huy, Q.N. (2008). How Contrasting Emotions Can Enhance Strategic Agility. http://faculty.insead.edu/quy-huy/documents,https://www.researchgate.net/ publication/290805798, 546-560. ##-       Jordan, P.J. (2005). “Dealing with Organizational Change: Can Emotional Intelligence Enhance Organizational Learning?”. International Journal of Organizational Behavior, 8(1): 456-471. ##-       Kelly, J.R. &amp; S.G. Barsade (2001). “Mood and Emotions in Small Groups and Work Teams”. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes, 86: 99-130. ##-       Khorshid, S. &amp; M. Hemmati (2013). “The Comparative Study of Strategic Agility in Manufacturing Industries of Semnan City”. Development Management Process, 26(1): 29-60, In Persion. ##-       Khoshid, S. &amp; A. Pashazadeh (2013). “The Impact of Organizational Intelligence on Organizational Learning and Emotional Capabilities”. The Quaertly of Management Studies (Development and Change), 69: 25-85, In Persion. ##-       Kiefer, T. &amp; W.R. Müller (2003). “Understanding Emotions in Organizational Change: The Role of Identity in Ongoing Processes”. The Academy of Management, Seattle. https://www.Researchgate.net/publication/228589121_ Understanding_emotions_in_organizational_change_The_role_of_identity_in_ongoing_change_processes. ##-       Kim, Kong-Hee (2012). “Emotion and Strategic Decision-Making Behavior: Developing a Theoretical Model”. International Journal of Business and Social Science, 3(1): 105-113. ##-       Kuratko, D.F. &amp; R.M. Hodgetts (2001). Entrepreneurship: A Contemporary Approach. Third Edition, Fort Worth: Dryden Press. ##-       Lewis, M.W.; C. Andriopoulos &amp; W.K. Smith (2014). “Paradoxical Leadership to Enable Strategic Agility”. California Management Review, 56(3): 58-77. ##-       Locke, E.A. &amp; G.P. Latham (2004). “What Should We do about Motivation Theory? Six Recommendations for the Twenty-First Century”. Academy Management Review, 29: 388-404. ##-       Macheridis, N. (2009). “Agility in Entrepreneurial Projects”. Working Papers are Published and Distributed as a Professional Service of the Institute of Economic Research: http://www.lri.lu.se/media/lri/workingpapers /2009-3.pdf, http://www.lri.lu.se. ##-       McGrath, R.G. (2001). “Exploratory Learning, Innovative Capability and Managerial Oversight”. Academy of Management Journal, 44: 118-131. ##-       Mikolajczak, M.; O. Luminet &amp; C. Menil (2006). “Predicting Resistance to Stress: Incremental Validity of Trait Emotional Intelligence over Alexithymia and Optimism”. Psicothema, 18: 79-88. ##-       Min, S. &amp; J.T. Mentzer (2004). “Developing and Measuring Supply Chain Management Concepts”. Journal of Business Logistics, 25: 63-99. ##-       Morgan, R.E. &amp; K. Page (2008). “Managing Business Transformation to Deliver Strategic Agility”. Strategic Change, 17(5/6): 155-168. ##-       Mumby, D.K. &amp; L.L. Putnam (1992). “The Politics of Emotion: a Feminist Reading of Bounded Emotionality”. Academy of Management Review, 17: 465-486. ##-       Nasution, H.N.; F.T. Mavondo, M.J. Matanda &amp; N.O. Ndubis (2011). “Entrepreneurship: It’s Relationship with Market Orientation and Learning Orientation and as Antecedents to Innovation and Customer Value”. Industrial Marketing Management, 40: 336-345. ##-       Neqabi, S.S. &amp; M. Bahadori (2012). “Relationship between Emotional Intelligence and Entrepreneurial Behavior”. Iranian Journal of Military Medicine, 14(2): 123-128. ##-       Ngah, R. &amp; Z. Salleh (2015). “Emotional Intelligence and Entrepreneurs’ Innovativeness towards Entrepreneurial Success: A Preliminary Study”. American Journal of Economics, 5(2): 285-290. ##-       Overby, E.; A. Bharadwaj &amp; V. Sambamurthy (2006). “Enterprise Agility and the Enabling Role of Information Technology”. European Journal of Information Systems, 15: 120-131. ##-       Perlovsky, L.I. (2006). “Toward Physics of the Mind: Concepts, Emotions, Consciousness, and Symbols”. Physics of Life Reviews, 3: 23-55. ##-       Peterka, S.O. (2011). “Entrepreneurial University as the Most Important Leverage in Achieving Knowledge-Based Society”. The Ninth International Conference: Challenges of Europe: Growth &amp; Competitiveness - Reversing Trend (P. 547): http://connection.ebscohost.Com/c/articles/72069954/ entrepreneurial-university-as-most-important-leverage-achieving-knowledge-based-society. ##-       Pitt, L.F.; P.R. Berthon &amp; M.H. Morris (1997). “Entrepreneurial Pricing: the Cinderella of Marketing Strategy”. Management Decision, 35(5): 344-350. ##-       Rafaeli, A. &amp; M. Worline (2001). “Individual Emotion in Work Organizations”. Social Science inFormation, 40(1): 95-123. ##-       Rafaeli, A. &amp; R.I. Sutton (1989). “The Expression of Emotion in Organizational Life”. Research in Organisational Behaviour, 11: 1-42. ##-       Rauch, A.; J. Wiklund, G.T. Lumpkin &amp; M. Frese (2009). “Entrepreneurial Orientation and Business Performance: an Assessment of Past Research and Suggestions for the Future”. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice, 33(3): 761-787. ##-       Sajdak, M. (2015). “Entrepreneurship in the Development of an Agile Enterprise: Theoretical and Practical Aspects”. International Journal of Management and Applied Research, 2(4): 144-155. ##-       Sambamurthy, V.; A. Bharadwaj &amp; V. Grover (2003). “Haping Agility through Digital Options: Reconceptualizing the Role of Information Technology in Contemporary Firms”. MIS Quarterly, 27(2): 237-263. ##-       Santala, M. (2009). Strategic Agility in a Small Knowledge Intensive Business Services Company: Case SWOT Consulting. Organization and Management Master&#039;s Thesis. Department of Marketing and Management, Helsingin Kauppakorkeakoreakoulu Helsinki School of Economics, 123p. http://epub.lib.aalto.fi/en/ethesis/pdf/12159/hse_ethesis_12159.pdf ##-       Schein, E.H. (1992), Organizational Culture and Leadership. 2nd edn, San Francisco, CA: Jossey-Bass. ##-               Schindehutte, M.; M. Morris &amp; J. Allen (2006). “Beyond Achievement: Entrepreneurship as Extreme Experience”. Small Business Economics, 27(4): 349-368. ##-       Schneider, S. &amp; P. Spieth (2012). “Enabling Business Model Innovation: Strategic Agility’s Role within Opportunity Exploration”. This Paper was presented at The XXIII ISPIM Conference – Action for Innovation: Innovating from Experience. In Barcelona: Spain, on 17-20 June. The Publication is Available to ISPIM, www.ispim.org. ##-       Sekaran, U. (2002). Research Methods for Business: A Skill Building Approach (Second Eds.). Translated by M. Saebi, M. Shirazi. Tehran: Research and Training Institute for Management and Development Planning. ##-       Shane S. &amp; S. Venkataraman (2000). “The Promise of Entrepreneurship as a Field of Research”. Academy of Management Review, 25(1): 217-226. ##-       Shepherd, D.A. (2003). “Learning from Business Failure: Propositions of Grief Recovery for the Self-Employed”. Academy of Management Review, 282: 318-329. ##-       Shepherd, D.A. (2004). “Educating Entrepreneurship Students about Emotion and Learning from Failure”. Academy of Management Learning and Education, 3(3): 274-287. ##-       Shepherd, D.A. (2009). “Grief recovery from Family Business Failure: A Multi and Meso-Level Theory”. Journal of Business Venturing, 24(1): 81-97. ##-       Shepherd, D.A.; H. Patzelt &amp; M. Wolfe (2011). “Moving Forward from Project Failure: Negative Emotions, Affective Commitment, and Learning from the Experience”. Academy of Management Journal, 54(6): 361-380. ##-       Shepherd, D.A.; J. Wiklund &amp; J. Haynie (2009). “Moving Forward: Balancing the Financial and Emotional Costs of Business Failure”. Journal of Business Venturing, 24(2): 134-148. ##-       Sull, D. &amp; B. Bryant (2006). Discussion for Strategic Agility, the Financial Times. Stratovation Consulting. ##-       Swafford, P.M.; S. Ghosh &amp; N. Murthy (2006). “The Antecedents of Supply Chain Agility of a Firm: Scale Development and Model Testing”. Journal of Operations Management, 24(2): 170-188. ##-       Totterdell, P. (2000). “Catching Moods and Hitting Runs: Mood Linkage and Subjective Performance in Professional Sport Teams”. Journal of Applied Psychology, 85: 848-859. ##-       Tsaousis, I. &amp; I. Nikolaous (2005). “Exploring the Relationship of Emotional Intelligence with Physical and Psychological Health Functioning”. Stress and Health, 21(2): 77-86. ##-       Zampetakis, L.A.; K. Kafetsios, N. Bouranta, T. Dewett &amp; V.S. Moustakis (2009). “On the Relationship between Emotional Intelligence and Entrepreneurial Attitudes and Intentions”. International Journal of Entrepreneurial Behavior and Research, 15(6): 595-618. ##-       Zhou, J. &amp; J.M. George (2003). “Awakening Employee Creativity: the Role of Leader Emotional Intelligence”. The Leadership Quarterly, 14: 545-568.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>شناسایی مؤلفه‌های معنویت اثرگذار بر تاب‌آوری در افراد کارآفرین</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Spirituality Components on Resiliency in Entrepreneurs</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف محققان در این پژوهش، شناسایی مؤلفه‌های معنویت اثرگذار بر تاب‌آوری در افراد کارآفرین بوده است. روش: پژوهش حاضر به لحاظ نوع، کیفی به شیوۀ توصیفی و از نظر رویکرد، استقرایی است. جامعۀ آماری پژوهش، شامل کارآفرینان شهر قم بود و نمونۀ پژوهش به روش نمونه‌گیری هدفمند از بین آنان انتخاب شد. برای جمع‌آوری داده‌های کیفی، از ابزار مصاحبه و برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌های حاصل از مصاحبه، از تکنیک تحلیل مضمون استفاده شده است. یافته‌ها: سؤال اصلی پژوهش با استفاده از تکنیک تحلیل مضمون بررسی و 11 مضمون اصلی به عنوان مؤلفه‌های معنویت اثرگذار بر تاب‌آوری در افراد کارآفرین شناسایی شد. نتیجه‌گیری: نتایج حاصل از تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها نشان داد که 11 مؤلفۀ اثرگذار بر تاب‌آوری در افراد کارآفرین به ترتیب عبارتند از: ارزش‌مداری، خودآگاهی، فرزانگی، هدف متعالی، رضایتمندی فردی، توکل و توسل، اخلاق‌مداری، فعالیتهای داوطلبانه، آخرت‌گرایی، امیدواری و سعۀ صدر.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives:This study was carried out to identify spirituality components affecting resiliency in entrepreneurs. Method: This study was based on practical purposes in qualitative and descriptive method and it is a deductive approach. The study population include entrepreneurs in Qom city and the study sample was purposeful sampling From among them. For data collection we have used interview and for analysis the data taken from interviews, the thematic analysis technique was used. Results: The main research question using the technique of thematic analysis reviews and 10 main concepts are as the spirituality components affecting resiliency in entrepreneurs were identified. Conclusion: The results from analysis of the data showed that 10 main concepts are as the spirituality components affecting resiliency in entrepreneurs which include: value orientation, self-awareness, wisdom, sublime goals, personal satisfaction, trust in God and patience, volunteer activities, believing in hereafter, hopefulness and Tolerance.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>263</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>280</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آصف</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کریمی</Family>
						<NameE>A</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Karimi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت کسب و کار و استادیار گروه مدیریت کارآفرینی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت کسب و کار و استادیار گروه مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>asef.karimi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>معصومه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>M</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی. پردیس فارابی دانشگاه تهران، ایران(نویسنده مسئول)/ نشانی: زنجان؛ شهرستان خدابنده / نمابر 02434328325/ Email: mohammadi69@ut.ac.ir</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی. پردیس فارابی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تاب‌آوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارآفرینی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>معنویت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مؤلفه‌های معنویت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل مضمون</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF> منابع ##-       احمدپور داریانی، محمود(1384). کارآفرینی، تعاریف، نظریات، الگوها. تهران: پردیس. ##-       احمدپور داریانی، محمود و آصف کریمی(1394). کارآفرینی سازمانی؛ از نظریه تا عمل. تهران: دانشگاه تهران. ##-       احمدی، علی‌اکبر و عبدالصمد خدامی(1390). «مدلی برای مطالعۀ رفتار شهروندی عمومی، معنویت و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی در بخش دولتی ایران(پژوهشی در شرکت سهامی بیمه ایران)». پژوهشنامه مدیریت عموی، سال چهارم، ش 4: 128-107. ##-       تقی‌زاده، محمد احسان و مرضیه‌السادات میرعلائی(1392). «مطالعۀ اثربخشی معنویت درمان گروهی بر تاب‌آوری زنان مبتلا به مالتیپل اسکلروزیس اصفهان». روان‌شناسی سلامت، سال دوم، ش 2: 96-86. ##-       حسین­زاده، امیرعلی و سهراب یزدانی (1392). «شناسایی و اولویت­بندی مولفه­های معنویت سازمانی در بین کارکنان و اعضاء علمی منطقه 13 دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی در سال1392 ». فصلنامه زن و مطالعات خانواده، سال پنجم، ش20: 87-73. ##-       حناآبادی، حسین(1394). «بررسی اثربخشی آموزش راهبردهای معنوی بر میزان تاب‌آوری و امیدواری دانشجویان جدیدالورود». فصلنامه علوم پزشکی زابل، سال ششم، ش 4. ##-       شاکری‌نیا، ایرج و مهری محمدپور شاطری(1388). «رابطۀ استرس شغلی و تاب‌آوری با فرسودگی شغلی در بین پرستاران زن». مجله علوم پزشکی دانشگاه کرمانشاه، سال چهاردهم، ش 2: 169-161. ##-       شفیع‌زاده، رقیه(1391). «رابطۀ تاب‌آوری با پنج عامل بزرگ شخصیت». دانش و پژوهش در روان‌شناسی کاربردی، سال سیزدهم، ش3: 102-95. ##-       عابدی جعفری، حسن؛ سعید تسلیمی، ابوالحسن فقیهی و محمد شفیع‌زاده(1390). «تحلیل مضمون و شبکۀ مضامین: روشی ساده و کارامد برای تبیین الگوهای موجود در داده‌های کیفی». اندیشۀ مدیریت راهبردی، ش 2: 198-151. ##-       فرج‌اله حسینی، سید جمال و فاطمه کاظمی میانرودی(1390). «نقش فنّاوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات ((ITC در توسعۀ کارآفرینی». ماهنامه کارآفرینان امیرکبیر، سال دوم، ش 68: 20-12. ##-     گل‌پرور، محسن؛ مریم جعفری و زهرا جوادیان(1392). «پیش‌بینی سرمایۀ روان‌شناختی از طریق مؤلفه‌های معنویت در پرستاران». روان‌پرستاری، سال اول، ش 3: 44-35. ##-       نادی، محمدعلی و محسن گل‌پرور(1390). «روابط ساده و ترکیبی مؤلفه‌های معنویت با وفاداری در محیط کار». اخلاق در علوم و فنّاوری، سال ششم، ش 4. ##-       هاشمی، لادن و بهرام جوکار(1390). «بررسی رابطۀ بین تعالی معنوی و تاب‌آوری در دانشجویان دانشگاه». مطالعات روان­شناسی تربیتی، دوره8، ش 13: 140-125. ##-       یزدانی، امین(1391). «بررسی رابطۀ ویژگی‌های شخصیتی سرسختی و تاب‌آوری با موفقیت تحصیلی در دانشجویان دانشگاه علوم پزشکی ارتش در سال 1391». پایان‌نامه دکترای علوم پزشکی. دانشگاه علوم پزشکی ارتش جمهوری اسلامی ایران. ##-       Abedi Jafari, H.; S. Taslimi, A. Faghihi &amp; M. Shafi&#039; Zadeh (2011). “Content Analysis and Content Network: Simple and Efficient Way to Explaining Patterns in Data Quality”. Strategic Management Thought, 2: 151-198. ##-       Ahmad Pour Dariyani, M. &amp; A. Karimi (2015). Entrepreneurship; From Theory to Practice. Tehran: Tehran University Press. ##-       Ahmad Pour Dariyani, M. (2005). Entrepreneurship, Definitions, Views, Patterns. Tehran: Paradise Press. ##-       Ahmadi, A. &amp; A. Khoddami (2011). “A Model to Study the Behavior of Public Citizen, Spirituality and Organizational Citizenship Behavior in the Public Sector in Iran (Iran Insurance Company management firm)”. 4(4): 107-128. ##-       Burke, R.J.; M. Koyuncu &amp; L. Fiksenbaum (2010). “Burnout, Work Satisfactions and Psychological Well-being among Nurses in Turkish Hospitals”. Europe’s Journal of Psychology, 6(1): 63-81. ##-       Campbell-Sills, L.; S.L. Cohan &amp; M.B. Stein (2006). “Relationship of Resilience to Personality, Coping, and Psychiatric Symptoms in Young Adults”. Behaviour Research and Therapy, 44(4): 585-599. ##-       Farajollah Hosseini, S.J. &amp; F. Kazemi Mianroodi (2011). “Role of Information Technology andCommunications (ITC) on Development of Entrepreneurship”. Journal of Amir Kabir Entrepreneurs, 2: 12-20. ##-       Gol Parvar, M.; M. Jafari &amp; Z. Javadian (2013). “Anticipating the psychological Capital through the Psychological Components of Spirituality in Nursing”. Journal of Psychiatric Nursing, 1(3): 35-44. ##-       Hana Abadi, H. (2015). “Spiritual Resiliency Evaluate the Effectiveness of Teaching Strategies and Hopes for New Students”. JournalZabol Medical, 6(4). ##-       Hashemi, L. &amp; B. Joker (2011). “The Relationship between Intellectual Excellence and Resilience in Students”.  Educative psychology studies, N.13.125-140. ##-       Homeward, R. (2011). “Reviewing the Literature on”. Australian Journal of Teacher Education, 36(2): 16-29. ##-       Hossin zadeh, A. and Yazdani, S. (2014), “recognition and prioritizing the components of organizational spirituality among employees and faculty members of Islamic Azad university (District 13) in 2014”.  Women and family studies quarterly. Fifth year .N:20: 73-87. ##-       Kvale, Steinar (1996). Interviews: An Introduction to Qualitative Research Interviewing. Thousand Oaks: sage. ##-       Lamond, A.J.; C.A. Depp, M. Allison, R. Langer, J. Reichstadt, D.J. Moore ... &amp; D.V. Jeste (2008). “Measurement and Predictors of Resilience among Community-Dwelling Older Women”. Journal of Psychiatric Research, 43(2): 148-154. ##-       Luthans, F.; B.J. Avolio, J.B. Avey &amp; S.M. Norman (2007). “Positive Psychological Capital: Measurement and Relationship with Performance and Satisfaction”. Personnel Psychology, 60(3): 541-572. ##-       Martin, A.J. &amp; H.W. Marsh (2006). “Academic Resilience and its Psychological and Educational Correlates: A Construct Validity Approach”. Psychology in the Schools, 43(3): 267-281. ##-       Mehrinejad, S.A.; M. Tarsafi &amp; S. Rajabi Moghadam (2015). “Predictability of Students’ Resiliency by Their Spirituality”. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 205: 396-400. ##-       Nadi, M. &amp; M. Gol Parvar (2011). “Simple Relationships and Spirituality Combined with Loyalty in the Workplace”. Journal of Ethics in Science and Technology, 6(4). ##-       Peres, j; A.M. Almeida, A.G. Nasello &amp; H.G. Koenig (2006). “Spirituality and Resilience in Trauma Victims”journal of Religion and Health, 46(3): 343–350. ##-       Robert, C; R. Hallak &amp; S.R. Sardeshmukh (20016). “Innovation, entrepreneurship, and restaurant performance: A higher-order structural model”. Journal homepage 53(3): 215-228. ##-       Shafi’ Zadeh, R. (2012). “Relationship between Resiliency and Five Factor Model of Personality”. Science and Research in Applied Psychology, 13(3): 95-102. ##-       Shakeri Nia, I. &amp; M. Mohammad Pour Shateri (2009). “The Relationship between Job Stress and Resiliency with Burnout among Nurses”. Journal of Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences, 14(2): 161-169. ##-       Taghizadeh, M. &amp; M. Mir Alaei (2013). “Study the Effectiveness of Group Therapy on Resiliency Spirituality of Women with Multiple Sclerosis”. Journal of Health Psychology, 2(2). ##-       Yazdani, A (2012). “The Relationship between Personality Characteristics of Hardiness and Resilience with Academic Success in Arthritis Medical Students in Year 2012” Medical Sciences Doctoral thesis, Medical Sciences University of the Islamic Republic of Iran&#039;s Army. ##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نقش مدیران گروههای آموزشی در ایجاد و تقویت تسهیم دانش در میان استادان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Role of Heads of the Departments in Establishing and Improving Knowledge Sharing Among Professors</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف از انجام پژوهش حاضر، شناسایی نقش یا نقشهای مدیران گروههای آموزشی در ایجاد و تقویت تسهیم دانش در میان استادان دانشگاهها بود تا از این طریق بتوان نقش مدیران گروهها را در این امر به طور بارزتر و شفاف‌تر پیدا و هشدار‌های لازم را ارائه کرد. روش: جامعۀ آماری پژوهش را اعضای هیئت علمی و مدیران گروههای آموزشی کلیۀ دانشگاههای مازندران تشکیل دادند. بدین منظور، 15 نفر از استادان با تجربه، به روش نمونه‌گیری در دسترس، انتخاب شدند و با آنان مصاحبه شد. داده‌های پژوهش به شیوۀ مصاحبۀ عمیق با پرسشهای مختلف و بازپاسخ جمع‌آوری شد. یافته‌ها: 120 عبارت شاخص و بارز بیان‌شده از سوی مصاحبه‌شوندگان، استخراج و پس از کدگذاری باز، در قالب 18 بُعد از نقشهای مدیران گروههای آموزشی در رابطه با تسهیم دانش که ابعاد مهم فردی، عاطفی، علمی، اجتماعی، سیاسی، فرهنگی و مذهبی آنان را شامل می‌شد، گنجانده شد. نتیجه‌گیری: مصاحبه‌شوندگان بیشترین نقش مدیران گروهها را در برگزاری مناسب جلسات گروههای آموزشی در راستای تسهیم دانش اعلام کردند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives:The purpose of the present study is to identify role(s) of heads of the departments in establishing and improving knowledge sharing among professors in order to clarify their role and provide appropriate recommendations. Methods: Statistical sample of the present study includes faculty members and heads of the departments of governmental / Azad / Non-profit / Fanni-Herfe’i Universities of Mazandaran Province. Fifteen experienced professors were selected and interviewed through available sampling method. Study data were sampled using deep interview with different questions and open-response method. Results: Finally, 120 titles and prominent phrases were extracted from interviewees that were coded with 120 open codes. These were embodied in 18 dimensions of the roles of heads of the departments related to knowledge sharing including individual, emotional, scientific, social, political, and religious aspects. Conclusion: Interviewees determined suitable execution of department sessions to be the most important role of heads of the departments along knowledge sharing.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>281</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>296</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مرزه حاجی آقایی</Family>
						<NameE>M</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Marzeh Hajiaghaee</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزش عالی دانشگاه خوارزمی و عضو هیئت علمی مؤسسه آموزش عالی شفق تنکابن. مازندران- ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزش عالی دانشگاه خوارزمی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mohsenhajiaghaee@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زین آبادی</Family>
						<NameE>H</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zeinabadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت آموزشی و دانشیار گروه مدیریت آموزشی دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه خوارزمی (نویسنده مسوول)/ نشانی: تهران؛ خیابان مفتح، شماره 49، دانشگاه خوارزمی /  02188807213 / Email: zeinabadi‌‌_hr@khu.ac.ir</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت آموزشی و دانشیار گروه مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zeinabadi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تسهیم دانش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیرگروه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>استادان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>منابع ##-       امیری، مجتبی؛ نوروزی سیدحسینی، سید رسول (1395). درآمدی بر روش­های تحقیق کیفی در ورزش. جلد دوم، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه تهران. ##-       پالی، سمیرا(1394). ارائۀ مدل مناسب جهت پیاده‌سازی مدیریت دانش در دانشگاههای آزاد استان مازندران. پایان نامه دکتری. ساری: دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی. ##-       جباری، نگین و مهرداد مدهوشی(1393). «اکتشاف عوامل مؤثر بر رفتار به اشتراک‌گذاری دانش در میان اعضای هیئت علمی دانشگاهها». پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی در آموزش عالی، ش 3(20): 65-45. ##-       خلخالی، علی، مصاحبه 1395 ##-       رجایی، عباس؛ سعید رجائی‌پور و رضا هویدا(1393). «تعیین روابط چندگانه بین تسهیم دانش و قابلیت جذب دانش با بهبود کیفیت علمی از دیدگاه اعضای هیئت علمی». پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی در آموزش عالی، ش 4(20): 144-123. ##-       زین‌آبادی، حسن‌رضا؛ بیژن عبدالهی و زینب محمودی(1392). بررسی نقش مدیران مدارس در رفتارهای تسهیم دانش تدریس معلمان مدارس ابتدایی شهر تهران. پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد. دانشکده علوم تربیتی و روان‌شناسی دانشگاه تربیت معلم تهران. ##-       سلیمی، قاسم؛ حسن دانایی‌فرد و محمود ابوالقاسمی(1390). «تسهیم دانش بین اعضای هیئت علمی در محیط‌های دانشگاهی؛ نگاهی میان‌رشته‌ای». مطالعات میان‌رشته‌ای در علوم انسانی، دورۀ سوم، ش 3-2: 74-51. ##-       علیپور درویشی، زهرا(1391). «ارائۀ مدل عوامل مؤثر بر تسهیم دانش گروههای آموزشی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی(پیمایشی پیرامون واحد تهران شمال و علوم و تحقیقات)». مدیریت فنّاوری اطلاعات، ش 4(10): 118-93. ##-       کریمی، صدیقه و احمدرضا نصر(1391). «روشهای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌های مصاحبه». عیار پژوهش در علوم انسانی، دورۀ هفتم، ش 4(1): 94-71. ##-       وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فنّاوری(1389). آیین‌نامه جامع مدیریت. ##-       Alipour Darvishi, Zahra (2012). “Presenting a Model of Effective Factors for Knowledge Sharing In Azad Universities”. Information Technology Management Quarterly, 4(10): 93-118. ##-       Alsharo, M.; G. Dawn &amp; R. Ramirez (2017). “Virtual Team Effectiveness: The Role of Knowledge Sharing and Trust”. Information &amp; Management, 54(4): 479-490. ##-       Amiri, M., &amp; Norozi, S. R (2014). Introduction on qualitative research methods in sport. 2nd edition, Tehran: University of Tehran press. ##-       Ansari, M., Rahmany Youshanlouei, H., &amp; Mood, M. (2012). A conceptual model for success in implementing jnowledge management: A case study in Tehran Municipality. Journal of Service Science and Management, 5 (2): 212-222. ##-       Darr, E.D. &amp; T.R. Kurtzberg (2000). “An Investigation of Partner Similarity Dimensions Knowledge Transfer”. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes, 82(1): 28-44. ##-       Drucker, P. (1993). Post-Capitalist Society. New York: Harper Collins. Nonaka, I kujiro. 1994. A Dynamic Theory of Organizational Knowledge Creation. Organization Science, 5 (1): 14-37. ##-       Jabbari, Negin &amp; Mehrdad Madhoushi (2014). “Detecting Effective Factors in Knowledge Sharing Behavior among Faculty Members”. Research And Planning In Higher Education Quarterly, 3(20): 45-65. ##-       Jung Kang, Y.; J. Young Lee &amp; H.W. Kim (2017). “A Psychological Empowerment Approach to Online Knowledge Sharing”. Computers in Human Behavior, 74: 175-187. ##-       Karimi, Sedigheh &amp; Ahmad Reza Nasr (2012). “Analysis of Interview Data Method”. Research in Human Sciences Quarterly, 4(1): 71-94. ##-       Kim, S. &amp; H. Lee (2006). “The Impact of Organizational Context and Information Technology on Employee Knowledge-Sharing Capabilities”. Public Administration Review, 66(3): 370-385. ##-       Ministry of Sciences, Research &amp; Technology (2010). Management Comprehensive Regulation. ##-       Pali, Samira (2015). Presenting a Model for Implementing Knowledge Management in Azad Universities of Mazandaran. PhD Dissertation. Sari Azad University. ##-       Rajaee, Abbas; Saeed Rahaee Pour &amp; Reza Hoveyda (2014). “Identification of Multiple Relations between Knowledge Sharing and Knowledge Attraction Capability with Improvement of Scientific Quality from Faculty Members’ Point of View”. Research And Planning In Higher Education Quarterly, 4(20): 123-144. ##-       Rismark, M. &amp; A.M. Solvberg (2011). “Knowledge Sharing in Schools: A Key to Developing Professional Learning Communities”. World Journal of Education, I920: 150-160. ##-       Salimi, Ghasem; Hassan Danaei Fard &amp; Mahmoud Abolghasemi (2011). “Knowledge Sharing Among Faculty Members in Academic Settings: An Interdisciplinary Approach”. Research And Planning In Higher Education Quarterly, 3(2-3): 51-74. ##-       Zein Abadi, Hassan Reza; Bijan Abdollahy &amp; Zeinab Mahmoudi (2013). Role of School Principals in Knowledge Sharing Behavior of Elementary School Teachers in Tehran, MA Thesis. Tarbiat Moallem University.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی عوامل فراسازمانی مؤثر بر مدیریت پژوهش و فنّاوری در ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Supra-Organizational Affecting Factors on the Management of Research and Technology in Iran</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف: هدف اصلی محققان در این مقاله، بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر مدیریت پژوهش و فنّاوری در ایران با رویکرد فراسازمانی بوده است. روش: روش این پژوهش از نوع کیفی است. ابزار گردآوردی اطلاعات از طریق مصاحبه با کارشناسان و صاحب‌نظران عرصۀ مدیریت پژوهش و فنّاوری است. تحلیل داده‌های مصاحبه نیز از روش تحلیل مضمون صورت گرفته است. یافته‌ها: عوامل فراسازمانی را در قالب چهار دستۀ کلی می‌توان تقسیم کرد: عوامل مربوط به مسئولان، عوامل مربوط به جامعۀ سازمانهای دانش‌بنیان، عوامل ناظر به محیط و عوامل ناظر به صنعت. در هر یک از این عوامل، هم عوامل موفقیت‌ساز و هم عوامل شکست‌زا ذکر شده است. نتیجه‌گیری: عوامل موفقیت‌ساز، عواملی‌اند که باعث موفقیت و بهبود مدیریت پژوهش و فنّاوری می‌شوند و لازم است تقویت شوند. عوامل شکست‌زا، عواملی‌اند که مانع موفقیت و بهبود مدیریت پژوهش و فنّاوری می‌شوند و ضرروری است اقداماتی در جهت رفع آنها انجام شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Objectives:The main objective of this paper is to investigate factors affecting the management of research and technology in Iran with the supra-organizational approach. Method: The method of this research is qualitative. The tool is a collection of information through interviews with experts and experts in the field of research and technology management. The method of analyzing interview data was analyzed through thematic analysis. Results: According to the findings of this research, the transactional factors can be divided into four general categories: factors related to the authorities, factors related to the society of knowledge-based organizations, environmental factors and industry observers. In each of these factors, both the success factors and the failure factors are mentioned. Conclusion: Success factors are factors that contribute to the success and improvement of management of research and technology that need to be strengthened and failure factors are factors that hinder the success and improvement of research and technology management, which requires action to be taken to eliminate them.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>297</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>311</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدصادق</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تراب زاده</Family>
						<NameE>M</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Torabzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>. دانشجوی دکتری معارف اسلامی و مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه امام صادق(ع) و پژوهشگر مرکز رشد دانشگاه امام صادق(ع). تهران: ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>. دانشجوی دکتری معارف اسلامی و مدیریت دولتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سجادیه</Family>
						<NameE>AR</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sajadieh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری معارف اسلامی و مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه امام صادق(ع) و پژوهشگر مرکز رشد دانشگاه امام صادق(ع). تهران: ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری معارف اسلامی و مدیریت دولتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حجازی فر</Family>
						<NameE>S</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hejazifar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>. دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی و پژوهشگر دانشگاه جامع امام حسین(ع) (نویسنده مسئول) / نشانی: تهران؛ بزرگراه بابایی، دانشگاه جامع امام حسین(ع)، دانشکده مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی راهبردی/ نمابر: 73828714 / Email: saeedhejazifar@gmail.com</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>. دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی و پژوهشگر دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>saeedhejazifar@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت پژوهش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>علم و فنّاوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شرکتهای دانش‌بنیان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عوامل فراسازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>منابع ##-       بندریان، رضا(1396). «تبیین ارکان و فرایند مدیریت راهبردی پژوهش و فنّاوری». رهیافت، ش 66. ##-       بندریان، رضا و مهدی بندریان(1392). «بازارگرایی راهبردی در سازمانهای پژوهش و فنّاوری». سیاست‌نامه علم و فنّاوری، سال دوم، ش 3. ##-       تقوی، مصطفی؛ مهدی پاکزاد و محسن محقق(1389). «تبیین الگویی برای تعیین اولویتهای پژوهش و فنّاوری». روش‌شناسی علوم انسانی، ش 63. ##-       دانایی‌فرد، حسن(1383). «اقتصاد دانش‌محور و حفظ تمامیت نهادی دانشگاه». پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی در آموزش عالی، ش 33. ##-       ضیایی بیگدلی، محمدتقی(1381). «دستگاههای اجرایی و نقش آن در توسعۀ تحقیقات با نگاهی به وزارت امور اقتصادی و دارایی». پژوهشنامه اقتصادی، ش 5. ##-       طالبی، کاظم؛ ‌هادی ثنائی‌پور و ناصر حیدری(1390). «تبیین نقش پارکهای علم و فنّاوری در رشد شرکتهای فنّاورانه‌محور». توسعۀ کارآفرینی، سال سوم، ش 11. ##-       عابدی جعفری، حسن؛ محمدسعید تسلیمی، ابوالحسن فقیهی و محمد شیخ‌زاده(1390). «تحلیل مضمون و شبکۀ مضامین: روشی ساده و کارامد برای تبیین الگوهای موجود در داده‌های کیفی». اندیشۀ مدیریت راهبردی، سال پنجم، ش 2. ##-       فرجادی، غلامعلی و پریسا ریاحی(1386). «بررسی بازار محلی پارکهای علم و فنّاوری ایران». پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی در آموزش عالی، ش 44. ##-       کزازی، ابوالفضل؛ حبیب‌اله طباطباییان، محمدتقی تقوی‌فرد و امیر ناظمی(1390). «دیدگاههای توسعۀ فنّاوری اطلاعات کشور مبتنی بر خوشه‌بندی دیدگاههای خبرگان». سیاست علم و فنّاوری، سال چهارم، ش 2. ##-       کهن، فرحناز(1384). «مدیریت بر دانش منابع انسانی: چرا و چگونه؟». اطلاع‌شناسی، ش 2-1. ##-       محمدی، علیرضا و نسرین بیگدلو(1391). «ابزارهای حمایتی برای شرکتهای دانش‌بنیان مستقر در پارکهای علم و فنّاوری؛ مورد مطالعه: پارک علم و فنّاوری دانشگاه فنی خاورمیانه ترکیه». رهیافت، ش 50. ##-       مخملی، حسن(1384). «مدیریت دانش، محور توسعۀ منابع انسانی». مدیریت فردا، ش 10-9. ##-       میگون‌پوری، محمدرضا و الهه میگون‌پوری(1389). «نقش تعاونی‌های دانش‌بنیان بسیجی در توسعۀ کارآفرینی». مطالعات بسیج، سال سیزدهم، ش 49. ##-       نیرومند، پوراندخت؛ فاطمه میرجلیلی و جهانیار بامداد صوفی(1391). «مؤلفه‌های ضروری برای شکل‌گیری شرکتهای نانو فنّاوری در ایران». سیاست علم و فنّاوری، سال چهارم، ش 3. ##-       Abedi Jafari, Hassan; Mohammad Saeed Taslimi, Abolhassan Faghihi &amp; Mohammad Sheikh Zadeh (2011). “Thematic Analysis and theme Network: a Simple and Efficient Way to Explain Patterns in Qualitative Data”. Two Strategic Management Thoughts Quarterly, 5(2). ##-       Bandarian, Reza &amp; Mehdi Bandarian (2013). “Strategic Market Orientation in Research and Technology Organizations”. Science and Technology Policy, 2(3). ##-       Bandarian, Reza (2017). “Explaining the Bases and Process of Strategic Management of Research and Technology”. Rahyaft, 66th. ##-       Danaei Fard, Hassan (2004). “Knowledge-Based Economics and Preservation of Institutional Integrity of the University”. Quarterly Journal of Research and Planning in Higher Education, N. 33. ##-       Farjadi, Gholam Ali &amp; Parisa Riahi (2007). “A Survey of the Local Market of Iranian Science and Technology Parks”. Quarterly Journal of Research and Planning in Higher Education, 44. ##-       Kazzazi, Abolfazl; Habibollah Tabatabaeean, Mohammad Taghi Taghavi Fard &amp; Amir Nazemi (2011). “Perspectives on the Development of Country Information Technology Based on Clustering Views of Experts”. Quarterly Journal of Science and Technology, 4(2). ##-       Kohan, Farahnaz (2005). “Manage the Knowledge of Human Resources: Why and How?”. Informatics, N. 1-2. ##-       Makhmali, Hasan (2005). “Knowledge Management, the Axis of Human Resource Development”. Managing Tomorrow, N. 9-10. ##-       Maygoon Puri, Mohammad Reza &amp; Elaheh Maygoon Puri (2010). “The Role of Basij Knowledge Cooperatives in the Development of Entrepreneurship”. Basij Studies Quarterly, 49th. ##-       Mohammadi, Alireza &amp; Nasrin Bigdlu (2012). “Supportive Tools for Knowledge Based Companies Based in Science and Technology Parks: Science and Technology Park of the Middle East Technical University of Turkey”. Approach, N. 50. ##-       Niroomand, Pourandokht; Fatemeh Mir Jalili &amp; Jahanyar Bamdad Sufi (2012). “Essential Components for the Formation of Nanotechnology Companies in Iran”. Quarterly Journal of Science and Technology, 4th year. N. 3. ##-       Taghavi, Mostafa; Mehdi Pakzad, &amp; Mohsen Mohaqeq (2010). “Explaining a Model for Prioritization of Research and Technology”. Methodology of Humanities, N. 63. ##-       Talebi, Kazem; Hadi Sanaei Pour &amp; Naser Heidari (2011). “Explaining the Role of Science and Technology Parks in the Growth of Technology-driven Companies”. Entrepreneurship Development, 3 (11). ##-       Ziaee Bigdeli, Mohammad Taqi (2002). “The Executive Apparatus and its Role in Developing Research with a Look at the Ministry of Economic Affairs and Finance”. Economic Research, 5th.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				