<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2345-5713</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>10</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identification and Prioritizing of the Whole Country Universities’ Cultural Fund Allocation Indicators in the Ninth and Tenth Government</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی شاخص‌های تخصیص اعتبارات فرهنگی دانشگاه‌های سراسرکشور در دولت‌های نهم و دهم</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>261</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>280</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">303</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد </FirstName>
					<LastName>دوستار</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیئت علمی دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه گیلان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نفیسه </FirstName>
					<LastName>فروغی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازاریابی دانشگاه گیلان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خلیل </FirstName>
					<LastName>نوروزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای رشته سیاستگذاری علم و فنّاوری دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی </FirstName>
					<LastName>جوادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد رشته معارف اسلامی و مدیریت دولتی و سیاستگذاری عمومی دانشگاه امام صادق(ع).</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد </FirstName>
					<LastName>عبدالحسین‌زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد رشته معارف اسلامی و مدیریت دولتی و سیاستگذاری عمومی دانشگاه امام صادق(ع).</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی </FirstName>
					<LastName>هاجری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی مدیریت تکنولوژی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Objectives:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;The aim of this study is to identify and prioritize thewhole country universities’ cultural fund allocation indicators in the ninth and tenth government. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Method:&lt;/span&gt; The method of the study is mixed. The research community comprised of 150 experts. 75 returned questionnaires was used for statistical analysis and AHP method, based on 8 cultural experts of the Ministry of Science, Research and Technology, was used to rank the components. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Results:&lt;/span&gt; The results of the research indicate both cultural-political and administrative structure dimensions, which considered in this study, have a significant impact on universities’ cultural fund allocation. In experts view, the cultural-political dimension has more priority than administrative structure. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/span&gt; The article concludes cultural activities implementation with leader statement, commitment to religious activities, prayer, benediction and Islamic Awakening, prioritizing Islamic-Iranian culture, level of relation between universities’ cultural deputies and managers with Staffarea and cooperation with staff in activitiesare indicators which have priority in universities’ cultural fund allocation in ninth and tenth governments&lt;/em&gt; onclusion: The authors of the article conclude When using outsourcing strategy of staff training, managers must first evaluate the benefits, costs, opportunities and risks of the outsourcing and then with regard to these cases, in case of usefulness of this strategy for their organization, do further actions in order to implement it</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;هدف:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt; هدف این مطالعه، شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی شاخصهای تخصیص اعتبارات فرهنگی دانشگاههای سراسر کشور در دوره‌های نهم و دهم ریاست جمهوری بوده است. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;روش:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt; این پژوهش به صورت آمیخته انجام شده است. جامعۀ تحقیق مشتمل بر 150 خبره بودند. برای تحلیلهای آماری، از 75 پرسشنامۀ عودت داده شده و برای رتبه‌بندی مؤلفه‌ها، از مقایسات زوجی در تکنیک AHP براساس نظرات هشت تن از خبرگان فرهنگی در وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فنّاوری استفاده شد. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;یافته‌ها:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt; هر دو بُعد در نظر گرفته شده در پژوهش(فرهنگی- سیاسی و ساختار اجرایی) تأثیر معنادار در تخصیص اعتبارات فرهنگی دانشگاههای کشور دارند. از دید خبرگان، ابتدا بُعد فرهنگی- سیاسی و سپس ساختار اجرایی در اولویت قرار دارند. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;نتیجه گیری:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt; شاخصهای میزان تطبیق فعالیتهای فرهنگی با منویات رهبری، اهتمام به فعالیتهای دینی و نماز و نیایش و بیداری اسلامی، اولویت قراردادن فرهنگ اسلامی- ایرانی، میزان ارتباط معاونان و مدیران فرهنگی دانشگاه با حوزۀ ستادی و همکاری در برنامه‌ها با ستاد برای تخصیص اعتبارات فرهنگی دانشگاهها در اولویت شاخصهای تخصیص اعتبارات فرهنگی در دولتهای نهم و دهم قرار داشته است&lt;/em&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تخصیص اعتبارات فرهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بودجه دانشگاه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بودجه‌بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تکنیک تاپسیس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل سلسله‌مراتبی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_303_526f431d64f2e00c13a6f0f966f0901b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>