<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2345-5713</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>8</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Determining the Bases of Organizational Behavior in the Life of the Holy Prophet (B.G.U.H.)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تبیین مبانی رفتار سازمانی در سیرة نبی اکرم(ص)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>199</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>222</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">203</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امین </FirstName>
					<LastName>نیک‌پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد کرمان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رستم </FirstName>
					<LastName>پوررشیدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترای مدیریت؛ استادیار دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد کرمان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سمیه </FirstName>
					<LastName>نوبری آیدیشه</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;em&gt;Complexities of human behavior, human different needs and how to compliance them in organization, each is a separate issue that today, back at the aid of management science and has been called organizational behavior. Respecting the customers, applying correct techniques, work satisfaction, and customer orientation and ... including the principles that are considered the imperatives of this occupation (organizational behavior) and the organization’s administrators are committed to be faithful in their activities. However, the study of the life of the Holy Prophet (blessing of god be upon him) demonstrates the application of these principles to complete and sublime form in the behavioral activities of Holy Prophet (BGUH), it is hoped the study of the life of the Holy Prophet (BGUH) relieves us from the negligence that has been become a burden for us in dealing with its scientific study.&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt; Objectives:&lt;/span&gt; Aim of this research is identifying the components of organizational behavior in the life of the Holy Prophet (BGUH). &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Method:&lt;/span&gt; Method of this research is Analysis of the documents through the Descriptive-analytical method that for this purpose, we have studied holly Quran, hadith and other resources on life of the Holy Prophet (BGUH). &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Results:&lt;/span&gt; 42 components were identified in this research related organizational behavior at three levels of individual, group and organization. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/span&gt; After summarizing contents; a model of organizational behavior based on life of the Holy Prophet (BGUH) is suggested&lt;/em&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پیچیدگی‌های رفتار انسان، نیازهای گوناگون بشری و نحوۀ برآوردن آنها در سازمان، هر یک موضوع جداگانه‌ای است که امروزه به یاری علم مدیریت شتافته و رفتار سازمانی نام گرفته است. تکریم مخاطب، کاربست روشهای درست، رضایت از کار، دوستی با مشتری و ... از جمله اصولی‌اند که جزء بایدهای این حرفه (رفتار سازمانی) محسوب می‌شوند و دست‌اندرکاران سازمان موظفند که در فعالیتهای خود به آنها مؤمن و عامل باشند. حال آن که بررسی سیرة پیامبر اعظم(ص) مبیّن کاربرد این اصول به شکلی کامل و متعالی در فعالیت‌های رفتاری ایشان بوده و امید است بررسی سیرة پیامبر اعظم(ص) ما را از غفلتی که تاکنون در پرداختن به بررسی علمی آن دامنگیرمان شده است، رهایی بخشد.&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;هدف:&lt;/span&gt; هدف از این پژوهش، شناسایی عناصر رفتار سازمانی در سیرة نبی اکرم(ص) است. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;روش:&lt;/span&gt; روش انجام این پژوهش، تحلیل اسنادی به شیوۀ توصیفی- تحلیلی بوده است و برای این منظور، از قرآن کریم، منابع حدیثی و سایر منابع معتبر در زمینه سیرة نبی اکرم(ص) استفاده شده است. &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;یافته&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;‌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;ها:&lt;/span&gt;در این پژوهش، 42 مؤلفه رفتار سازمانی در سه سطح فرد، گروه و سازمان شناسایی شد.&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;نتیجه&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;‌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;گیری:&lt;/span&gt; در این پژوهش بعد از جمع‌بندی مطالب، الگوی رفتار سازمانی برگرفته از سیرۀ نبی اکرم(ص) ارائه شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیرة نبوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گروه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_203_fd87b36afe1ab7338e91e7bd239ddc8f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>