<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2345-5713</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>17</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Reflection Upon Imam Ali’s Management and Leadership Behavior based on His Assertions in Nahj-Al-Balagheh on Their Comparison with Managerial Insights and Principles of Holy Quran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأملی بر منش رهبری امام علی(ع) به استناد سیرۀ حضرت در نهج‌‌البلاغه و تطبیق آن با مبانی فکری رهبری در قرآن کریم</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>25</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>42</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">643</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباداله </FirstName>
					<LastName>بانشی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترای مدیریت بازرگانی(منابع انسانی). استادیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه هرمزگان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالحسین </FirstName>
					<LastName>خسروپناه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترای فلسفه. استاد گروه فلسفه پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و اندیشه اسلامی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن </FirstName>
					<LastName>بیابانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترای مدیریت بازرگانی(بازاریابی). استادیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه هرمزگان.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Objectives:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; The current study intends to explore Imam Alis’s management and leadership behaviors by analyzing his assertions in Nahj-al-Balagheh, investigating his words and conduct and also matching the resultant style with the organizational management principles in Holy Quran. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Method:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; This research can be categorized as a theoretical research in terms of its nature and a qualitative study in terms of data collection procedures employed; in fact, a qualitative content analysis of Nahj-al-Balagheh is performed which provide the required data for the current study. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Results:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; In this analysis, 430 propositions in line with the objectives of the study were selected and explored. Totally, 216 indexes, 34 concepts, 8 variables and four aspects were identified. The results of this analysis indicated that Imam Ali’s managerial conduct is influenced by four main aspects: Principles (attitudinal and legislative), Objectives (mediational and optimal), Values (dos and don’ts) Frameworks/Grounds (human resources and structural strategies) with a frequency of 36%, 4%, 26% and 34%, respectively. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Generally, the findings revealed that attitudinal and legislative principles form the basis of all his behaviors and he has always considered them as fundamental beliefs and fixed guidelines. Leadership and management objectives in the society, which are indicative of motivations for accepting responsibility, and also the dos and don’ts of leadership (values) are the results of these principles. Accordingly, the objectives and values of the management (similar to an umbrella) overshadow and govern the development of strategies and determination of methods, policies, laws and regulations to the extent that the aforementioned fundamental principles, which are considered as strategic principles, regulate the management behaviors in the society. Based on the findings of this study it can be maintained that the principles derived from Imam Ali’s conduct and behavior are in line and consistent with the principles (i.e., attitudinal and behavioral principles) of Holy Quran.&lt;/em&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;هدف:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; هدف از انجام این پژوهش، بررسی منش و سبک مدیریت و رهبری امام علی(ع) به استناد سیرۀ آن حضرت در نهج‌‌البلاغه و تفحص در اقوال و سلوک ایشان، همچنین تطبیق سبک مستخرجه با مبانی رهبری سازمانی موجود در قرآن کریم بود. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;روش&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; این پژوهش از حیث هدف، جزء تحقیقات بنیادی طبقه‌بندی شده و از حیث جمع‌آوری داده‌ها، کیفی است و با روش تحلیل محتوا و از طریق واکاوی متن نهج‌‌البلاغه انجام شده است. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;یافته‌ها&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; در این بررسی، 430 گزارۀ متناسب با موضوع، انتخاب و مطالعه شد و در نهایت، 216 شاخص، 34 مفهوم، هشت مقوله و چهار بُعد کلی شناسایی شد. نتایج نشان داد می‌توان منش مدیریتی امام علی(ع) را متأثر از چهار بُعدِ اصول(نگرشی و حقوقی)، اهداف(واسطه‌ای و غایی)، ارزشها(بایدها و نبایدها) و بسترها(راهبردهای ساختاری و انسانی) دانست. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;نتیجه‌گیری&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; اصول نگرشی و حقوقی زیربنای همۀ رفتارهای حضرت بوده و در حکم اعتقادات بنیادین و اصول ثابت، همواره مدّ نظر ایشان بوده‌اند و اهداف رهبری و مدیریت در جامعه و نیز بایدها و نبایدهای رهبری(ارزشها) منبعث از این اصول‌اند. اهداف و ارزشهای رهبری نیز بر تدوین راهبردها و بر وضع همۀ رویّه‌ها، خط مشی‌ها، سیاستها و قوانین و مقرارت سایه انداخته، حاکمیت می‌کنند؛ به طوری که اصول زیربنایی مطروحه به عنوان اصول راهبردی، نقش هماهنگ‌کنندگی در رفتارهای مدیریتی جامعه را ایفا می‌کنند. بر اساس نتایج این تحقیق، اصول برگرفته از سیرۀ حضرت با اصول منبعث از قرآن کریم(اصول بینشی و اصول منشی) مطابقت دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منش رهبری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نهج‌‌البلاغه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">امام علی(ع)</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_643_133dbc208689be0334b313dce92e648d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>