<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و معارف اسلامی وابسته به نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه‌ها</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2345-5713</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>16</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Pathological Characteristics of Culture and Jihady Management by Using Meta-Synthesis Method</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آسیب‌شناسی فرهنگ و مدیریت جهادی با استفاده از روش فراترکیب</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>253</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>274</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">587</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>معصومه </FirstName>
					<LastName>الماسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی- رفتار سازمانی، دانشکده مدیریت حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی. تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالله </FirstName>
					<LastName>توکلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترای مدیریت دولتی. دانشیار مدیریت پژوهشگاه حوزه و دانشگاه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Objective:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; In this paper, with the purpose of identifying the pathological characteristics of Jihady management, after searching, we found 12 related articles. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Method:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; By using Meta-Synthesis method we interpreted and categorized original data of selected studies then showed them in content network. In terms of the results, this article is developing research and in terms of data is qualitative research.  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Results :&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The findings of this study are divided into two groups of internal and external damages, Three kinds of internal damages: being away from God, the dependence on the world and change of purpose, and thirteen kinds of external damages: Stay away from meritocracy, the rule of relationships rather than rules ( favouritism), bureaucracy, the Influence of opportunists and spinelessness, loss of the original human capital, weak monitoring( observation)  and evaluation, weakness in making qualified staffs, regardlessness  to the position represented by the supreme leader, lack of public participation, lack of coordination in affairs, lack of adherence to the law and illegality, lack of defining the principles and indicators of jihady culture and censorship were identified as the most important findings of this study. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Research findings indicate that in logical division, the jihady management damages can be divided into two categories of internal and external damages. Regarding the nature of internal and external damages, internal damages are more important than external damages and among the dimensions of external damages, bureaucracy is of the highest importance that the majority of research in previous years has focused on the destructive impact of bureaucracy on jihady culture and jihady management. The damages which are identified in these articles are divided into two categories of internal and external damages including 16 dimensions and 122 indicators.&lt;/em&gt;</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;هدف:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; هدف مؤلفان در این مقاله، شناسایی شاخصهای آسیب‌شناسی مدیریت جهادی بود. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;روش:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; با روش تحقیق فراترکیب، داده‌های اصلی مقالات منتخب، تفسیر و دسته‌بندی و به صورت شبکۀ مضامین نمایش داده شد. این تحقیق از نظر نتایج، در زمرة تحقیقات توسعه‌ای و از حیث داده‌ها، کیفی است. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;یافته‌ها:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; یافته‌های تحقیق در دو گروه آسیبهای درونی و بیرونی عبارتند از: آسیبهای درونی، شامل دوری از خدا، وابستگی به دنیا و تغییر هدف؛ آسیبهای بیرونی، شامل دوری از شایسته‌سالاری، حاکمیت روابط به جای ضوابط، بوروکراسی، نفوذ فرصت‌طلبان و سست‌عنصران، جدایی و برون‌رفت سرمایۀ اصلی، ضعف نظارت و ارزشیابی، سستی در کادرسازی، بی‌توجهی به جایگاه نمایندگی ولی فقیه، عدم مشارکت مردم، عدم هماهنگی در امور و اهداف، عدم پایبندی به قانون و قانون‌گریزی، عدم تدوین مبانی و شاخصهای فرهنگ جهادی و سانسور. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;نتیجه‌گیری:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; یافته‌های پژوهش بیانگر این است که در تقسیم‌بندی منطقی می‌توان آسیبهای مدیریت جهادی را به دو دسته آسیبهای درونی و بیرونی تقسیم کرد. با توجه به ماهیت آفات درونی و بیرونی، آفات درونی نسبت به آفات بیرونی اهمیت بیشتری دارند؛ در میان ابعاد آفات بیرونی نیز بوروکراسی از بیشترین اهمیت برخوردار است. آسیبهای شناسایی شده در این مقالات در دو دسته آفات درونی و بیرونی، شامل 16 بُعد و 122 شاخص است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ جهادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت جهادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آسیب‌شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراترکیب</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://miu.nahad.ir/article_587_700232989700372bf51ad10c3b949e63.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>