<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Making Predictions of the Academic Achievement of the Students of Imam Ali Military University Based on Thinking Styles]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sadeghi, Jahanbakhsh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ejei, Javad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Gholamali Lavasani, Masoud]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Abaszadeh, Naser]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Thinking Styles]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[academic achievement]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Military Students]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Abstract
This study was an attempt to predict the academic achievement of the students of Imam Ali Military University students based on thinking styles. For this purpose and also in an attempt to assess the thinking styles, the study was conducted through administering Sternberg and Wagner thinking styles questionnaire among a sample of 705 students affiliated to the Imam Ali Military University who were selected based on stratified random sampling method. To conduct this study, in terms of making measurement of the students’ academic achievement, data collection procedures were run through utilizing correlation coefficient and stepwise multiple regression methods. The findings revealed that in terms of thinking styles including hierarchical, global, external, legislative, and judicial, there is a significant positive relationship among thinking styles, type I thinking styles and the students’ academic achievement. Meanwhile, there is a significant negative relationship between internal thinking styles and students’ academic achievement. Furthermore, the findings of stepwise regression analysis revealed that the correlation coefficient of multiple regression between thinking styles and students’ academic achievement releasing 0.19. Moreover, in terms of academic achievement variance, the thinking styles including legislative (type I), local (type II) and external (type III) releasing 3.7% of academic achievement variance. The findings of data analysis of freshman and sophomore also revealed that the correlation coefficient of multiple regressions between thinking styles and students’ academic achievement releasing 0.29 and 0.28 respectively. Moreover, in terms of the academic achievement variance of freshman and sophomore, the thinking styles including global and hierarchical releasing 8.2% and external thinking style releasing 7.4% respectively. Meanwhile in juniors, there was no significant relationship between thinking styles and academic achievement.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_27701_bfb605bbe3a6d3ca648246b22adef2e5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Proposing a Model of the Effective Technological Forecasting in Defense Sector for Implementing Strategic Planning]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[amiri, hassan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Defensive Technology]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technological Forecasting]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Probability Analysis]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Defensive Strategies]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[ 
Abstract
This study was an attempt to predict the academic achievement of the students of Imam Ali Military University students based on thinking styles. For this purpose and also in an attempt to assess the thinking styles, the study was conducted through administering Sternberg and Wagner thinking styles questionnaire among a sample of 705 students affiliated to the Imam Ali Military University who were selected based on stratified random sampling method. To conduct this study, in terms of making measurement of the students’ academic achievement, data collection procedures were run through utilizing correlation coefficient and stepwise multiple regression methods. The findings revealed that in terms of thinking styles including hierarchical, global, external, legislative, and judicial, there is a significant positive relationship among thinking styles, type I thinking styles and the students’ academic achievement. Meanwhile, there is a significant negative relationship between internal thinking styles and students’ academic achievement. Furthermore, the findings of stepwise regression analysis revealed that the correlation coefficient of multiple regression between thinking styles and students’ academic achievement releasing 0.19. Moreover, in terms of academic achievement variance, the thinking styles including legislative (type I), local (type II) and external (type III) releasing 3.7% of academic achievement variance. The findings of data analysis of freshman and sophomore also revealed that the correlation coefficient of multiple regressions between thinking styles and students’ academic achievement releasing 0.29 and 0.28 respectively. Moreover, in terms of the academic achievement variance of freshman and sophomore, the thinking styles including global and hierarchical releasing 8.2% and external thinking style releasing 7.4% respectively. Meanwhile in juniors, there was no significant relationship between thinking styles and academic achievement.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_27703_cc58fa0fe92fee6c30ffa48b3d4a8f48.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Utilization of the Artificial Neural Networks in Financial Management of Research Processes on Defensive Studies
(Case Study: Theoretical Researches of Iranian Army)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Fathnejad, Faramarz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[basiri, mahdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Financial Management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Research Processes]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Artificial neural networks]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Iranian Army Defensive Studies Centers]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Hapfield Networks]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Abstract Making decisions as to how to make an investment in modern technologies is taken as the crucial necessities of defensive industries in developing countries and this phenomenon attracted a great deal of significance due to the chronic shortage of funds and also huge expenditure on research and technological developments. Moreover, proposing an effective model of technological forecasting is among the main requirements for any structure of defense system and is also identified as a contributing factor especially in designing interactional structures as well as laying the foundation for strategic choices. Meanwhile, a deficient model could lead into the total failure of defensive policies in achieving the pre-identified goals. building Specifications of an effective model of technological forecasting received a great deal of attention in many industrial centers in defense sector and in an attempt to identify these specifications, policy makers and planners have encountered serious questions including how to propose an effective model for technological forecasting and how to identify its specifications. This study was an attempt to identify the effective factors enhancing the capabilities of technological forecasting in defense sector and is also aimed at proposing a comprehensive model for implementing defensive strategies through selecting and developing appropriate and effective technologies. The study was also conducted through library study including analyzing the national policies in defense sectors, exploiting the potential of studies conducted to identify an effective model and also investigating the experienced expert’s consultation and elite interview. Then, some specifications of an effective model for technological forecasting were emerged as a result of library study and expert consultation. Thereupon, in a bid to identify probable result of selecting and applying technological forecasting model, probability analysis was also run in this study. At the final stage of investigation, the effects of the effective components building an effective model of technological forecasting were identified through running probability analysis.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_27704_c3f3c1e9283800383bf58254c1e996ac.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[An Investigation and the Estimation of the Livelihood Level of the Retirees of Iranian Armed Forces: A Prospect for 2025]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rasoulian, mohsen]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Low Affordability Line]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty Line]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Income]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Livelihood]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Retirees of Iranian Armed Forces]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[As an extracted study from the comprehensive research conducted in the year 2016, this study was an attempt to investigate and also estimate the livelihood level of the retirees of Iranian armed forces and is also aimed at comparing the retirees’ livelihood level and income with affordability line in the prospect for 2025. For this purpose and also in terms of statistical population, the study was conducted through engaging the population of 111604 annuitant, 5022279 retirees of Iranian armed forces and also 14258 pensioners. As a quantitative field study and in terms of data collection procedures, the required data was collected through investigating the theories about livelihood level of retirees as well as utilizing the data obtained from Iranian official statistic center and Iranian central bank. Having analyzed the data, retirees’ pension of Iranian armed forces are classified as seven groups and the growth of retirees’ pension is also estimated in the prospect of 2025. Thereupon, as a prospect for 2025, the study made a comparison between low affordability line and the retirees’ income in each identified groups. The findings revealed that in terms of comparing appropriate affordability of retirees with life expenses, 90 percent of retirees including groups 1 to 4 will fail to afford life expenses, if current situation continues.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_27705_a6394ad2371e93b9163f377c2f291ad0.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Proposing a Strategic Model for Transference of the Defensive Organizations in Cloud Computing Environment]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Valavi, Mohammad-Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[movahedisefat, mohammadreza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bagheri Koshalshah, Iman]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[cloud computing]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Defensive Organizations]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Information Technology Security]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Information technologies have a significant impact on all parts of an organization. Cloud computing is identified as a new technology which creates flexibility and robustness in an organization through sharing applied applications and resources among users in an organization. Moreover, most organizations throughout the world, especially defensive organizations are planning to migrate to cloud computing environment. Despite all the advantages of utilizing cloud computing environment in defensive organizations, security is taken as the most crucial challenges posed by cloud computing environment. As an applied and descriptive field study, this research aims at proposing a strategic model for transference of the defensive organizations in cloud computing environment. For this purpose, the study was also conducted through engaging the statistical population of commanders, managers and IT experts affiliated to the information technology organizations of the Iranian armed forces. Additionally, as research experts and elites, PhD candidates who pursued cyberspace strategic managements also participated in this study. The findings revealed that indentifying the infrastructure of defensive organizations in various sphere as well as proposing a strategic model for migrating in cloud computing environment are among the determining strategies investigated in this study. Finally, in terms of research findings, the measures associated with each strategy are also explicated in this study.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_27706_12524b1f0b5d6ca7e4a0c6991abc333b.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Effectiveness of the Short-Term Group Counseling on Increasing Adjustment of Soldiers Residing in Barracks through Utilizing Solution-Focused Approach]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Iranmehr, Moslem]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Solution-Focused Approach]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Solution-Focused Group Counseling]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Adjustment]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Soldiers]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Military Service]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[maladjustment of some Soldiers is causing enduring concern among commanders in military context. In line with this, solution-focused group counseling is identified as a modern approach in reducing maladjustment of soldiers. This approach is of crucial significance due to the factors including simplicity, short-term treatment, and emphasis on the identification of soldiers as well as utilization of group counseling in group training in military context. As an experimental study including Pretest-Treatment and Posttest, This research aims at investigating the effectiveness of the short-term group counseling on increasing the adjustment of soldiers residing in barracks through utilizing solution-focused approach. For this purpose and also in terms of statistical population, the study was conducted through engaging sample population of 28 soldiers residing in one of the barracks of Iranian armed forces who were selected based on simple random sampling method creating two groups including experimental and control group. Thereupon, adjustment test was administered among participants and they were scored below the average level. For data collection procedures, this study was also conducted through administering Sinha and Singh adjustment questionnaire including 60 components among statistical population. Moreover, the experimental group enjoyed ten eighty-minute sessions of solution-focused group counseling treatment. The findings revealed that solution-focused group counseling can significantly improve the adjustment level including social, emotional and educational adjustment in soldiers residing in the barracks. The findings also revealed that solution-focused group counseling is an effective way of increasing the adjustment level in soldiers. However, soldiers’ maladjustment can be reduced and also prevented in the light of utilizing solution-focused group counseling approach]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_27707_f088ed4b888fa2c136776fd1a543234c.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>