<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Effect of Transformational Leadership on Facilitating Organizational Innovation with Respect to the Mediating Role of Knowledge Management and Psychological Empowerment among Military Personnel</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali- Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tashakorian Jahromi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Noor Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Yaghoubi</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه زاهدان دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sajjad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hojat Doust</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sadraldin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jahanbin</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه یاسوج</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Nowadays, in changing dynamic environments, continuous organizational changes require strategic and transformational leadership. This study was an attempt to investigate the effect of transformational leadership on facilitating organizational innovations with respect to the mediating role of psychological empowerment and knowledge management among military personnel, namely Iranian disciplinary forces. This study is an applied in terms of purpose and it was also conducted through engaging the total population of 250 employees affiliated to the police command center of Boyerahmad city who were selected based on simple random sampling method. Moreover, in terms of data collection procedures, the study was also run through administering different questionnaires including organizational innovation questionnaire (16 items), knowledge management questionnaire (19 items), transformational leadership questionnaire (19 items) and psychological empowerment questionnaire (15 items). Having collected the data, 148 questionnaires were analyzed in smart PLS software.  The findings revealed that transformational leadership has a direct effect on both psychological empowerment and knowledge management, while had an indirect effects on organizational innovations. Additionally, knowledge management entails direct and significant effects on organizational innovation, while playing a mediating role between transformational leadership and organizational innovation. However, the role of psychological empowerment mediator was not confirmed in this study. Finally, in a bid to enable the personnel to identify and analyze the current situations as well as helping them set themselves some clear goals, preventive police mangers should make their attempts to clearly and precisely design and set specific goals for personnel. Furthermore, enhancing the personnel satisfaction through creating supportive and friendly atmosphere and increasing the effectiveness was among the main attempts made by preventive police mangers.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>17</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>66</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>22</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29076_77d884b33917e8fafe959d247918fbb0.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Utilization of GIS in Analyzing Optimal Military Sites for Deployment of Military Units based on Defensive–Security Observations ((Case Study: Ardabil Province))</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">manouchehr</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">pashazadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی شهری، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Afshar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sayyedin</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی شهری، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Parsay Moghaddam</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی شهری، دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Selecting appropriate military site for deployment of a military unit is identified as determining factor in defense preparedness due to the special geographical and geostrategic situation of Iran, especially Ardabil province which is highly significant province in terms of its close proximity to the border of Iran. Moreover, selecting appropriate military sites for deployment of military units is capable of increasing the efficiency and effectiveness of military units for dealing with military threats and crisis. Defensive-security observations are among the most important factors affecting the appropriate selection of military sites. Additionally, security and defensive components and criteria are also taken as the most determining factor in selecting appropriate military sites as well as establishing military units. As an analytical- descriptive study, this research was an attempt to analyze the optimal site for military establishment in Ardabil province based on defensive–security observations. To collect the required data, the study was conducted through investigating the defensive and security observations as well as utilizing the current resources and expert consultation. Having collected the data and weighing them in super decision software through running ANP model, the appropriate military site of military units were selected on the map in ARC GIS environment through utilizing the overlapping method of effective layers of site selection. Having analyzed the data, the optimal sites for military establishment were identified and zoned in this study. The findings revealed that from among total area of 17953 km of Ardabil province, 26.07 percent of total area of this region is totally inappropriate and  30.50 % of this area is inappropriate in terms of military site selection for military establishment in Ardabil province. The findings also revealed that 25.53 percent of Ardabil province is pretty appropriate, 13.12% of this region is appropriate and finally 4.76 percent of this province is wholly appropriate for military establishment.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>17</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>66</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>23</start>
					<end>51</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29077_6bf240c37114f912c72c3cc3f2a2d507.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Hybrid Warfare in Complex-Chaotic International System</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Farhad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghasemi</namePart>
				<affiliation>International Relations Branch, Law and Political Science, Tehran University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Iraj</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Esmaeili Farzin</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری روابط بین‌الملل دانشگاه تهران.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The breakup of the soviet union led to the fundamental changes in international order including entrance of new actors in systematic interactions, structural transformation in dynamism and the balance of power as well as intensification of complexity and chaos in international system. Moreover, the ways of warfare has undergone massive changes and deeply affected by modern systematic transitions. Consequently, a new notion of warfare, namely hybrid which is extremely complicated and thoroughly resistive against conventional solutions was emerged as a result of systematic changes permeating in international context. The hybrid warfare is identified as a prevalent method of warfare in Middle East and this phenomenon have already had a major impact on regional security environment of Middle East. Additionally, hybrid warfare poses contemporary threats to the countries of the region. The continuance in this crisis revealed that in terms of the theories of international relations and strategic studies, no explanations of power is provided for hybrid warfare and therefore providing an explanation of modern models of hybrid warfare based on complexity and chaos theory is taken as the most crucial questions in strategic studies and international relations. The hypothesis of this study is to identify the components of hybrid warfare as well as providing answers to the questions of what kind of war the hybrid warfare is and how the hybrid warfare fights.  In terms of research hypothesis, this study was also an attempt to identify the strategies for dealing with hybrid warfare based on the theories of complex- chaotic system. Having analyzed the theories, research hypothesis is also proved by the research findings. This study is also aimed at expanding the boundaries of knowledge in terms of theory, and also helping the researcher to theorize on warfare in terms of strategy as well as developing an applied and analytical model for dealing with threats posed by modern warfare especially hybrid warfare. Finally, as a developmental-descriptive study and in terms of data collection procedures and analysis, this research was conducted through library study and content analysis. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>17</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>66</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>52</start>
					<end>92</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29078_3b2611be4673b0c46eb52b2086a522d8.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A study of the Environmental Analysis of the Championship and Professional Sport in the Iranian Armed Forces</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abbas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shabani</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار مدیریت ورزشی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد رودهن</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Nowadays, sporting events and activities has received a lot of attention in all sectors of Iranian armed forces due to the significance of sporting activities on enhancing the both physical and mental preparedness. Moreover, the significance of the enhancement of military preparedness was among the main reason for developing sporting activities as well as providing physical education in Iranian armed forces. As an analytical–descriptive study, this study was an attempt to investigate the environmental analysis of professional sport in the Iranian armed forces through utilizing SWOT analysis. This study was also conducted through running SWOT analysis for analyzing the internal and external environmental factors of sporting activities in Iranian armed forces. This study was also conducted through engaging the sample population of 171 active managers, coaches and the athletes affiliated to the Iranian armed forces. In terms of data collection procedures, the required data was collected through library study and also researcher- made questionnaire.  The reliability of the questionnaire was estimated using Cronbach Alpha method releasing 90% through SPSS analysis and its content validity was confirmed by the experts. To analyze the data, descriptive statistics including Kolmogorov-Smirnov test and Friedman test were also run in this study. The findings revealed that the situation of championship sport of Iranian armed forces are achieving the stability level in terms of conservative strategy and the situation of professional sport of Iranian armed forces is also taking steps toward development in terms of offensive strategies. Additionally, some crucial factors were orderly prioritized in this study including main strength, weaknesses of professional sports, opportunities provided by this sport and also the threats made against championship and professional sport. Finally, in a bid to develop championship and professional sport of Iranian armed forces, some practical suggestions were made according to the research findings</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>17</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>66</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>93</start>
					<end>114</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29080_2a0c775a74dca0bdf6f7275cf45cd7ee.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Analysis of Knowledge Management and Information Technology from the Viewpoint of Commanders and Managers in Military Organizations</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohsen</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rahimi</namePart>
				<affiliation>عضو هئیت علمی دانشگاه خاتم الانبیاء(ص)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Yaghub</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kalani Mehr</namePart>
				<affiliation>عضو هئیت علمی دانشگاه خاتم الانبیاء(ص)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Knowledge management is identified as the most important strategy for creating knowledge-based organizations.  As a result, in terms of organizational prospect, many of the organizations willing to create knowledge-based situations should make organizational attempts to compare the concepts of Knowledge management with new organizational concepts and also internalize the theories and the concepts of KM among staff and managers. As an applied and descriptive-field study, this research was conducted through library and field study to collect the required data. Moreover, in terms of statistical populations, this study was also conducted through engaging sample population of 139 managers and commanders affiliated to the different managerial levels of military organizations who were expert in KM and IT issues and selected based on non-random sampling method.  This study was also run through administering researcher-made questionnaire among statistical population. The reliability of the questionnaire was estimated using Cronbach Alpha method releasing 0.875 through SPSS analysis and its content validity was confirmed by the experts. To analyze the data, descriptive statistics including Kolmogorov- Smirnov test and variance analysis were also run in this study. The findings revealed that from the viewpoint of managers and commanders, the situation of KM and IT of military organizations is pretty appropriate but it still stood below the appropriateness level. The research findings also revealed that there are significant differences among operational, senior, and middle mangers and commanders in terms of their viewpoints.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>17</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>66</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>115</start>
					<end>138</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29081_8e3bb68ccb1751b3ab9cad3ce98a20d3.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Identification of the Effective Factors Affecting the Personnel’s Intentions of Voluntary Turnover ((Case Study: Military Organization</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">samad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">barani</namePart>
				<affiliation>management, shahid sattari air university,tehran,iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Naser</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Asgari</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hadi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Afzali</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The voluntary turnover of the expert staff is an indication of serious loss of human capital in an organization and the process of personnel replacement imposes a huge cost on the organizations. This study was an attempt to identify the effective factors affecting the personnel’s intention of voluntary turnover and leave in military organizations. This study is an applied and also descriptive in terms of purpose and data collection procedures. For this purpose and in terms of statistical population, the study was conducted through engaging total population of 245 staff members affiliated to the case study organization and thereupon 150 participants were randomly selected out of statistical population based on simple random sampling method and Cochran formula.  To collect the research required data, the study was also conducted through administering a researcher- made questionnaire among participants. Having collected the data and analyzing them through SPSS software analysis, exploratory-factor analysis, student t-test and Fredman test were also run in this study. The findings revealed that the factors such as 4 factors in the domain of individual factors, 8 factors in the domain of organizational factors and 3 factors in the domain of environmental factors have been identified as the most effective factors affecting the personnel voluntary turnover. The findings also revealed that in terms of affecting the personnel voluntary turnover, the factors including individual and organizational factors are more effective than environmental factors.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>17</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>66</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>139</start>
					<end>165</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29082_53cb0bdb28a8f32528752729292e4c8c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>