<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Designing a Model for Classifying Targets and Identifying the Conflict Scenarios in Combat Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amir-Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Okhravi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">poya</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shamsoddin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nazemi</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد مدیریت استراتژیک، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mostafa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kazemi</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد مدیریت سیستم و بهره‌وری، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In the defensive environment, making the right and precise decision is taken as one of the key issues that could change the situation for all groups who are in conflict with each other. Additionally, utilizing appropriate weapons for hitting the enemy’s targets is of crucial significance for operation commanders. This study was run in a bid to design a model for classifying the targets as well as identifying the conflict scenarios in combat management and also made an attempt to assess the significance of targets with regard to the magnitude of the threats and also the existence of dynamic battlefield. On the other hand, this study is aimed to provide an overview of target classification for operation commanders through investigating the capabilities of our own headquarters in defeating and destroying the enemy’s targets as well as investigating the risk of conflict with the potential targets. To address this issue, the conflict scenarios were emerged as the result of two-dimensional plot investigation which provides four axes identifying the conflict scenarios. Thereupon, the scenarios were analyzed through running a mixed method of fuzzy decision making techniques and two-dimensional matrix analysis. In a bid to test this model, the study was also conducted through investigating the operational expert’s consultation and elite interview in which 3 military sites of hypothetical combat situation including 7 targets were emerged as a result of expert consultation. Moreover, the excel software was designed to study these hypothetical situation permanently through using the data obtained from the same distribution of 10 military sites including 20 targets. Finally, according to the data analysis which emerged as a result of elite consultation and also the investigation of hypothetical combat situation , in terms of output model , each of targets were assigned to 3 hypothetical military sites.   </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>60</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>33</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_21924_3b44a156028ecea896567c714c4e15b8.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Proposing a Model of Personnel Human Dignity in Iranian Governmental Organizations 
((A Case Study; a Model for the Units of Iranian Army Ground Force in the Special City of Maragheh))</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Gholam-Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Memarzadeh Tahrani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor in Public Administration, IAU, Ghazvin  Branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mosakhani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor in System Administration, Tehran University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sayyed Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Alvani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor in Public Administration, Allame Tabatabaee University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Falsafi</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD in Human Resources Management , IAU, Ghazvin  Branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Human dignity is identified as the backbone of human right and its preservation is also taken as the key of permanent progress and development in every society. Therefore, internalization of organizational culture in light of Islamic values, human dignity and reverence for human and social capital is considered as the main and crucial policy in organization’s administration system and the implementation of such a planning is the primary purpose of many organizations. To delve into this issue in this study, as a qualitative study including meta-synthesis method, this study was an attempt to propose a comprehensive model of personnel human dignity in government agencies. To do so, the components of this phenomenon were identified in the early stages of investigation. Thereupon, the concepts and the components of personnel human dignity were emerged as a result of elite and expert consultation and also the analysis of primary conceptual model. In a bid to apply the exploratory model in terms of meta- synthesis method, the study was conducted through administering a questionnaire among population of 218 personnel affiliated to the department of real estate and registration office in Azerbaijan who was randomly selected based on stratified sampling method. To analyze the data, the confirmatory factor analysis and LISREL software analysis were also run in this study. Thereupon, the components and the parameters of human dignity model were emerged as the result of analysis. Moreover , in an attempt to identify the optimized dimensions of human dignity, 40 questionnaires were also administered among personnel of the Iranian army ground force in Maragheh who were randomly selected based on purposeful sampling method. Moreover, data analysis was run through fuzzy modeling in Matlab software. The findings revealed that in terms of significance of human dignity components, if the personnel pay more attention to the components of human dignity including performance dimension (33%), behavioral dimension (31%), mental and intellectual dimension (30%) and physical dimension (6%), consequently, human dignity of an organization will possess the highest rank in terms of value (62.1).</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>60</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>34</start>
					<end>76</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_21925_a8a2e8c529cdb7eec9cfb225727c1b8a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Proposing a Model of Management and leadership from the Perspective of Nezami Ganjavi Based on the Strategies of Grounded Theory</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Yahya</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hosseinaei</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Candidate in Persian Language and Literature , Urmia  University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Bahman</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nozhat</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor in  Persian Language and Literature , Urmia University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Learning and exploiting the leadership and managerial indicators are of crucial significance in terms of scientific studies and investigation. This study was an attempt to investigate the leadership and management components from the perspective of Nezami Ganjavi and was also aimed at proposing a model of management and leadership for high ranking commanders and military managers. Sharafname poems are identified as an impressive masterpiece and poetic work of Nezami Ganjavi which makes an attempt to describe the adventures and massive militarization of Alexander. The main thought of poet is revealed through investigating and scrutinizing the verses of poems. Moreover, many thought of poet is also communicated through using direct speech or king’s discourse in terms of advice and aphorism and then transferred to the readers. This study was qualitative research in terms of purpose and data collection procedures and it was conducted through data-based analysis and grounded theory. For this purpose, in terms of sample population, the study was conducted through investigating 4500 verses of Sharafname poems.  Finally, 22 components were emerged as the result of poetic investigation which leads to the five dimensions including beliefs, relations, personality, wisdom and human mental condition and spirituality. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>60</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>77</start>
					<end>104</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_21926_36438f23a38288288d1af84ed27f2c2e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Model of Implementing Capabilities of Command and Control System in the Army Ground Force of the Islamic Republic of Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kheirandish</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor in Public Administration; Human Resources Management , Shahid Sattari University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdiye</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rashidi</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in Public Administration, IAU, Ghazvin  Branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Due to the great significance of informational dominance in military organizations and also in an attempt to enhance the effectiveness of their measures, many military organizations were encouraged to utilize the high-level of information technologies. Command and control system is of crucial significance due to the penetration of information systems in accomplishing military missions ,therefore , identifying the implementing capabilities of command and control system has received a great deal of attention in military organizations. As an applied and descriptive study, this study was an attempt to identify the implementing capabilities of command and control system in the armed forces. The study was conducted through administering a researcher-made questionnaire among population of 140 commanders and managers affiliated to the Iranian army ground force which were randomly selected based on Morgan table. To analyze the data, the confirmatory factor analysis was also run in this study. Thereupon 6 sub-commanding and controlling capabilities were emerged as a result of investigation. The controlling capabilities including; 1. Financial capabilities which lead to the development of strategies and allocation of financial resources, 2. Optimized infrastructural capabilities which lead to the eight sub-capabilities of optimized and dynamic systems, maintaining the preparedness of control system, designing the mobile and stationary systems and disrupting the defensive filters, 3. Building the structural capabilities of internal and futuristic policies as well as designing flexible model and structural patterns of control system. Moreover, the commanding capabilities including; 1. Human capabilities which lead to the capabilities of taking mental measures and psychological protection , sharp guidance and leadership of military forces as well as morale enhancement of forces, 2. Cultural capabilities including feeling of cooperation among personnel, sharing of information and having a personnel commitment, and 3. Informational capabilities including three sub-capabilities of undergoing sufficient training in network disruption and receiving updated information continuously as well as setting different scenarios. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>60</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>105</start>
					<end>146</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_21927_bfd7f211a6bdcc5a95072e297e523983.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Performance Assessment of the Educational Groups of Imam Ali Military University through Utilizing Data Envelopment Analysis</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Lotfi</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in Operation Research ,Lecturer at Imam Ali Military University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abbasiraee</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Candidate in Industrial Engineering , Lecturer at Imam Ali Military University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Heshmattollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Gazori</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in Mechanic Engineering , Academic Member at Imam Ali Military University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Assessment and the evaluation of effectiveness are taken as the crucial concerns of managers in many organizations. Therefore, in an attempt to delve into this issue many methods and techniques have been used many years. The technique of data envelopment analysis is of crucial significance and is also used widely in scientific studies dealing with assessment and the evaluation. Moreover, In terms of efficiency assessment, the mathematical models of operation research are widely used in the techniques of DEA in academic centers. In this model, the activities affiliated to the education, research and services are taken as the input and output parameters. Thereupon, based on the significance and the effectiveness of each performance parameters, the ratio of weighted sum of inputs and the outputs were analyzed and also identified as the efficiency parameters of decision –making units. This study was an attempt to assess the technical efficiency of 17 educational groups of Imam Ali military university through utilizing data envelopment analysis in yearly assessment. Additionally, the statistical analysis was run in terms of constant and variable scales outputs. The findings revealed that among 17 educational groups, 14 groups enjoyed efficiency while 3 educational groups have suffered inefficiency. Finally, the educational groups were ranked in terms of performance and their strong and the weak points were also investigated in this study.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>60</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>147</start>
					<end>175</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_21928_98ea287613ab56970f66012acc2b4a0f.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Determination of the Optimal Level of Defense Sector in Iran from Economic Perspective</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abolghasem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Golkhandan</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Candidate in Economy, Faculty of Economy, Lorestan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Defense expenditure is identified as a major part of total public expenditure in Iran. Therefore, determining the optimal level of defense expenditure plays an important role in the efficient allocation of financial resources in the public sectors which could lead to the national economic growth. For this purpose, this study was an attempt to investigate the non-linear effect of defense expenditure on economic growth and is also aimed to determine the optimal level of defense sector in Iran between the years of 1959 and 2012. To address this issue, the study was conducted through running a logistic smooth transition regression model (LSTR). The findings of this model revealed that defense expenditure are non-linearly affecting the economic growth. Moreover, the place of defense expenditure in gross domestic production was emerged in terms of two main components including infrastructures which effectively affecting the average income per capita with the optimal level of 21%. Additionally, in terms of defense expenditure place in GDP, the first factor has received the positive effect while the second factor has suffered the negative effect. Finally, the hypothesis of an inverse U-shaped effect of defense expenditure on economic growth was confirmed in this study.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>60</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>176</start>
					<end>212</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_21929_63840252f24a54784214802e6d8afeba.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>