<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1398</YEAR>
<VOL>19</VOL>
<NO>76</NO>
<MOSALSAL>76</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>193</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>درک نقش میانجی مالکیت روان‌شناختی در رابط بین رهبری اخلاقی و عملکرد کارکنان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Understanding the Role of Psychological Ownership on the Relationship between Ethical Leadership and Employee Performance</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی تأثیر رهبری اخلاقی بر روی عملکرد کارکنان با نقش میانجی مالکیت روان‌شناختی انجام شده است. این پژوهش از نظر هدف؛ کاربردی، از نظر چگونگی گردآوری داده‌ها از دستۀ پژوهش‌های توصیفی - همبستگی و از شاخة مطالعات میدانی به شمار می‌رود. جامعة آماری پژوهش حاضر، کارکنان دانشی یکی از دانشگاه‌های نظامی است. بر اساس جدول مورگان و کرجسی، حجم نمونه 210 نفر تخمین زده شد. روش نمونه‌گیری در این پژوهش، روش تصادفی طبقه‌ای است. برای سنجش رهبری اخلاقی از پرسش‌نامه براون و همکاران (2005)، مالکیت روان‌شناختی از پرسش‌نامه ون داین و پیرس (2004) و عملکرد شغلی از پرسش‌نامه پترسون (2006) استفاده شد. داده‌های به دست آمده با استفاده از مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری (نرم‌افزار لیزرل 54/8) تجزیه و تحلیل شد. یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد رهبری اخلاقی به صورت مستقیم و غیر مستقیم از طریق مالکیت روان‌شناختی بر عملکرد کارکنان تأثیرگذار است. رهبران اخلاقی می‌توانند با تغییر نگرش و تقویت حس مالکیتی نسبت به سازمان، آگاهی فردی را افزایش دهند و با ایجاد دلبستگی شناختی و عاطفی بین فرد و هدف بر رفتار  فرد تأثیر بگذارند و زمینۀ لازم برای تسهیل فرآیند سازمانی و افزایش عملکرد شغلی را فراهم نمایند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of ethical leadership on employee performance with the role of psychological ownership mediator. The present study is applied and descriptive-correlational, and the data were collected in the field survey. The statistical population of the study was the knowledge personnel of a military university. According to the Morgan and Karjets table, the sample size was estimated to be 210, selected through random-cluster sampling. To assess ethical leadership, psychological property, job performance, the questionnaires by Brown and et al. (2005), Van Dyne and Pierce (2004), and Patterson’s (2006) were used respectively. The data were analyzed using structural equation modeling (LISREL 8.54), and the findings showed that ethical leadership directly and indirectly influences employee performance through psychological ownership. Ethical leaders can increase individual awareness by changing the attitude and strengthening the sense of ownership toward the organization, and by providing emotional and cognitive attachment between the individual and the aim, they can influence an individual’s behavior to prepare the necessary basis for facilitating organizational process and increasing job performance.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>28</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>داورزنی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Davarzani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت کارآفرینی، مدرس دانشگاه علوم و فنون هوایی شهید ستاری</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت کارآفرینی، مدرس دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.davarzani@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>صمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بارانی</Family>
						<NameE>Samad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Barani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه علوم و فنون هوایی شهید ستاری (نویسنده مسئول)، samdbarani@ssau.ac.ir</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه علوم و فنون</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sbaranb@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رهبری اخلاقی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد کارکنان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مالکیت روان‌شناختی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>آذرنوش، فاطمه، نیسی، عبدالکاظم، مرادی، سمیرا و دریکوند، طیبه (1391). رابطه مالکیت روان‌شناختی با تعهد عاطفی و میل به ماندن در شغل در کارکنان شرکت ملی مناطق نفت خیز جنوب، مجله دانش و پژوهش در روان‌شناسی کاربردی، 47، 82-74.##ابزری، مهدی، رنجبریان، بهرام، فتحی، سعید و قربانی، حسن (1388). تأثیر بازاریابی داخلی بر بازارگرایی و عملکرد سازمان در صنعت هتلداری، چشم انداز مدیریت(پیام مدیریت)، 31، 25-42.##روح‌اللهی، احمدعلی (1394). رابطه مالکیت روان‌شناختی با عملکرد شغلی کارکنان، فصلنامه مشاوره شغلی و سازمانی، 25، 131-120.##عباس‌زاده، رضا، صالحی، مهدی و بهمنش، محمد رضا (1394). تأثیر متغیر میانجی (جو اخلاقی) بر رابطه بین رهبری اخلاقی با نوآوری و رفتار اخلاقی کارکنان، مجله پژوهش های اخلاقی، 22، 47-27.##کوهستانی، روزبه، رشیدی النگه، مهدی (۱۳۹۵). تأثیر رهبری اخلاقی در خلاقیت و نوآوری بر اساس نظریه یادگیری اجتماعی، چهارمین کنفرانس بین المللی حسابداری و مدیریت با رویکرد علوم پژوهشی نوین، تهران، ایران.##میرکمالی، سیدمحمد و کرمی، محمدرضا (1395). بررسی رابطه بین ادراک سبک رهبری اخلاقی مدیران و عملکرد کارکنان، مجله مدیریت توسعه و تحول، 24، 22-11.##Ambrose, M. L., &amp; Schminke, M. (2003). Organization structure as a moderator of the relationship between procedural justice, interactional justice, perceived organizational support, and supervisory trust. Journal of applied psychology, 88(2), 295.‏##Ahn, J., Lee, S., &amp; Yun, S. (2018). Leaders’ core self-evaluation, ethical leadership, and employees’ job performance: The moderating role of employees’ exchange ideology. Journal of Business Ethics, 148(2), 457-470.‏##Ahmad, I., Donia, M. B., Khan, A., &amp; Waris, M. (2019). Do as I say and do as I do? The mediating role of psychological contract fulfillment in the relationship between ethical leadership and employee extra-role performance. Personnel Review, 48(1), 98-117.‏##Ahmed, H. T. (2014). Impact of Organizational justice on affective commitment: Mediating role of psychological ownership and organizational identification. IOSR Journal of Business and Management, 16(1), 58-63.‏##Avey, J. B., Avolio, B. J., Crossley, C. D., &amp; Luthans, F. (2009). Psychological ownership: Theoretical extensions, measurement and relation to work outcomes. Journal of Organizational Behavior: The International Journal of Industrial, Occupational and Organizational Psychology and Behavior, 30(2), 173-191.‏##Avey, J. B., Avolio, B. J., Crossley, C. R., &amp; Luthans, F. (2008). Psychological ownership: Theoretical extensions and analysis of a multi-dimensional theory-based measure. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 29(1), 1-19.‏##Avey, J. B., Wernsing, T. S., &amp; Palanski, M. E. (2012). Exploring the process of ethical leadership: The mediating role of employee voice and psychological ownership. Journal of Business Ethics, 107(1), 21-34.‏##Bernhard, F., &amp; O’driscoll, M. (2011). Psychological ownership in small family-owned businesses: leadership style and nonfamily employees’ work attitudes and behaviors. Group &amp; Organization Management, 36, (3), 345-384.##Blader, S. L., Shirako, A., &amp; Chen, Y. R. (2016). Looking out from the top: Differential effects of status and power on perspective taking. Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin, 42(6), 723-737.‏##Brown, M. E., Treviño, L. K., &amp; Harrison, D. A. (2005). Ethical leadership: A social learning perspective for construct development and testing. Organizational behavior and human decision processes, 97(2), 117-134.‏##Brown, G., Crossley, C., &amp; Robinson, S. L. (2014). Psychological ownership, territorial behavior, and being perceived as a team contributor: The critical role of trust in the work environment. Personnel Psychology, 67(2), 463-485.‏##Brumback, G. B. (1988). Some ideas, issues and predictions about performance management. Public Personnel Management, 17(4), 387-402.‏##Currie, G., Dingwall, R., Kitchener, M., &amp; Waring, J. (2012). Let’s dance: organization studies, medical sociology and health policy. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 74(3), 273-280.‏##Daft, R. L. (2014). The leadership experience. Cengage Learning. ‏##Dawkins, S. (2014). New directions in Psychological Capital research: A critical analysis and theoretical and empirical extensions to individual-and team-level measurement.‏##Dawkins, S., Tian, A. W., Newman, A., &amp; Martin, A. (2017). Psychological ownership: A review and research agenda. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 38(2), 163-183.‏##Dust, S. B., Resick, C. J., Margolis, J. A., Mawritz, M. B., &amp; Greenbaum, R. L. (2018). Ethical leadership and employee success: Examining the roles of psychological empowerment and emotional exhaustion. The Leadership Quarterly, 29(5), 570-583.‏##Furby, L. (1978). Possession in humans: An exploratory study of its meaning and motivation. Social Behavior and Personality: an international journal, 6(1), 49-65.‏##Ghafoor, A., Qureshi, T. M., Khan, M. A., &amp; Hijazi, S. T. (2011). Transformational leadership, employee engagement and performance: Mediating effect of psychological ownership. African journal of business management, 5(17), 7391-7403.‏##Griffin, R. W., Welsh, A., &amp; Moorhead, G. (1981). Perceived task characteristics and employee performance: A literature review. Academy of management Review, 6(4), 655-664.‏##Hersey, P., Blanchard, K. H., &amp; Johnson, D. E. (2007). Management of organizational behavior (Vol. 9). Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice hall.##Mensah, J. K. (2015). A “coalesced framework” of talent management and employee performance: For further research and practice. International Journal of Productivity and Performance Management, 64(4), 544-566.‏##Mayhew, M. G., Ashkanasy, N.M., &amp; Bramble, T., Gardner, J. (2007). A study of antecedents and consequences of psychological ownership in organizational settings. The Journal of Social Psychology, 147 (5), 477-500.##Mehmood, Q., Nawab, S., &amp; Hamstra, M. R. (2016). Does Authentic Leadership Predict Employee Work Engagement and In-Role Performance? Journal of Personnel psychology. ‏##Mohammad Mosadegh Rad, A., &amp; Hossein Yarmohammadian, M. (2006). A study of relationship between managers&#039; leadership style and employees&#039; job satisfaction. Leadership in Health Services, 19(2), 11-28.‏##Motowidlo, S. J., &amp; Kell, H. J. (2012). Job performance. Handbook of Psychology, Second Edition, 12.##Jussila, I., Tarkiainen, A., Sarstedt, M., &amp; Hair, J. F. (2015). Individual psychological ownership: Concepts, evidence, and implications for research in marketing. Journal of Marketing Theory and Practice, 23(2), 121-139.‏##Kim, M., &amp; Beehr, T. A. (2017). Self-efficacy and psychological ownership mediate the effects of empowering leadership on both good and bad employee behaviors. Journal of Leadership &amp; Organizational Studies, 24(4), 466-478.‏##Knapp, J. R., Smith, B. R., &amp; Sprinkle, T. A. (2014). Clarifying the relational ties of organizational belonging: Understanding the roles of perceived insider status, psychological ownership, and organizational identification. Journal of Leadership &amp; Organizational Studies, 21(3), 273-285.‏##Lee, H., Yang, S. B., &amp; Koo, C. (2019). Exploring the effect of Airbnb hosts&#039; attachment and psychological ownership in the sharing economy. Tourism Management, 70, 284-294.‏##Liu, H. (2017). Reimagining ethical leadership as a relational, contextual and political practice. Leadership, 13(3), 343-367.‏##O&#039;Reilly, C. (2002). The wrong kind of&#039;ownership&#039;. Across the board, 39(5), 19-20.‏##Piccolo, R. F., Greenbaum, R., Hartog, D. N. D., &amp; Folger, R. (2010). The relationship between ethical leadership and core job characteristics. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 31(2‐3), 259-278.‏##Ozler, H., Yilmaz, A., &amp; Ozler, D. (2008). Psychological Ownership: an empirical study on its antecedents and impacts upon organizational behaviors. Problems and Perspectives In Management, 6, Issue 3.##Park, C. H., Kim, W., &amp; Song, J. H. (2015). The Impact of Ethical Leadership on Employees’ In‐Role Performance: The Mediating Effect of Employees’ Psychological Ownership. Human Resource Development Quarterly, 26(4), 385-408.‏##Piccolo, R. F., Greenbaum, R., Hartog, D. N. D., &amp; Folger, R. (2010). The relationship between ethical leadership and core job characteristics. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 31(2‐3), 259-278.‏##Pierce, J. L., Kostova, T., &amp; Dirks, K. T. (2003). The state of psychological ownership: Integrating and extending a century of research. Review of general psychology, 7(1), 84-107.‏##Pierce, J. L., Kostova, T., &amp; Dirks, K. T. (2001). Toward a theory of psychological ownership in organizations. Academy of management review, 26(2), 298-310.##‏Pierce, J. L., Kostova, T., &amp; Dirks, K. T. (2003). The state of psychological ownership: Integrating and extending a century of research. Review of general psychology, 7(1), 84-107.‏##Pittino, D., Martínez, A. B., Chirico, F., &amp; Galván, R. S. (2018). Psychological ownership, knowledge sharing and entrepreneurial orientation in family firms: The moderating role of governance heterogeneity. Journal of Business Research, 84, 312-326.‏##Ruiz, P., Ruiz, C., &amp; Martínez, R. (2011). Improving the “leader–follower” relationship: Top manager or supervisor? The ethical leadership trickle-down effect on follower job response. Journal of Business Ethics, 99(4), 587-608.‏##Salancik, G. R., &amp; Pfeffer, J. (1978). A social information processing approach to job attitudes and task design. Administrative science quarterly, 224-253.‏##Schein, E. H. (2010). Organizational culture and leadership (Vol. 2). John Wiley &amp; Sons.‏##Shahhosseini, M., Silong, A. D., Ismaill, I. A., &amp; Uli, J. N. (2012). The role of emotional intelligence on job performance. International Journal of Business and Social Science, 3(21).‏##Shin, Y., Sung, S. Y., Choi, J. N., &amp; Kim, M. S. (2015). Top management ethical leadership and firm performance: Mediating role of ethical and procedural justice climate. Journal of Business Ethics, 129(1), 43-57.‏##Shepherd, D. A., Wiklund, J., &amp; Haynie, J. M. (2009). Moving forward: Balancing the financial and emotional costs of business failure. Journal of business venturing, 24(2), 134-148.‏##Slavin, S., Matheson, W., Millar, K., &amp; Van Dyk, C. (2014). Performance evaluation in the human services. Routledge. ‏##Spreitzer, G. M. (1995). Psychological empowerment in the workplace: Dimensions, measurement, and validation. Academy of management Journal, 38(5), 1442-1465.‏##Stouten, J., Baillien, E., Van den Broeck, A., Camps, J., De Witte, H., &amp; Euwema, M. (2010). Discouraging bullying: The role of ethical leadership and its effects on the work environment. Journal of Business Ethics, 95(1), 17-27.‏##Treviño, L. K., Brown, M., &amp; Hartman, L. P. (2003). A qualitative investigation of perceived executive ethical leadership: Perceptions from inside and outside the executive suite. Human relations, 56(1), 5-37.‏##Toor, S. U. R., &amp; Ofori, G. (2009). Ethical Leadership: Examining the Relationships with Full Range Leadership Model, Employee Outcomes, and Organizational Culture. Journal of Business Ethics, 90(4).‏##Tutar, H., Altınöz, M., &amp; Çakıroğlu, D. (2011). Is ethical leadership and strategic leadership a dilemma? A descriptive survey. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 24, 1378-1388.‏##Van Gils, S., Van Quaquebeke, N., van Knippenberg, D., van Dijke, M., &amp; De Cremer, D. (2015). Ethical leadership and follower organizational deviance: The moderating role of follower moral attentiveness. The Leadership Quarterly, 26(2), 190-203.##Van Dyne, L., &amp; Pierce, J. L. (2004). Psychological ownership and feelings of possession: Three field studies predicting employee attitudes and organizational citizenship behavior. Journal of Organizational Behavior: The International Journal of Industrial, Occupational and Organizational Psychology and Behavior, 25(4), 439-459.‏##Viswesvaran, C., &amp; Ones, D. S. (2017). Job performance: Assessment issues in personnel selection. The Blackwell handbook of personnel selection, 354-375.‏##Viswesvaran, C., &amp; Ones, D. S. (2000). Perspectives on models of job performance. International Journal of Selection and Assessment, 8(4), 216-226.‏##Wang, H., Law, K. S., &amp; Chen, Z. X. (2008). Leader-member exchange, employee performance, and work outcomes: An empirical study in the Chinese context. The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 19(10), 1809-1824.##Yang, Q., &amp; Wei, H. (2017). Ethical leadership and employee task performance: examining moderated mediation process. Management Decision, 55(7), 1506-1520.‏##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>شناسایی موانع کلیدی مدیریت دانش و درس‌آموخته‌ها در سازمان‌های پروژه‌محور نظامی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Identifying the Key Barriers to Knowledge Management and Lessons Learned in the Project-Based Military Organizations</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در سازمان‌های پروژه‌محور، ویژگی موقتی بودن پروژه‌ها باعث ضعف حافظه، فراموشی تجارب ارزشمند و درس‌های آموخته‌شده از پروژه می‌شود. با توجه به ساختار و اهداف سازمان‌های پروژه‌محور نظامی می‌توان به نقش حیاتی دانش کسب‌شده از پروژه‌ها برای بقای سازمان پی برد. هدف این پژوهش شناسایی موانع کلیدی مدیریت دانش و درس آموخته‌ها در سازمان‌های پروژه‌محور نظامی و پاسخ به این پرسش است که «موانع کلیدی مدیریت دانش و درس آموخته‌ها در سازمان‌های پروژه‌محور نظامی چیست و اهمیت و اولویت این موانع به چه ترتیبی است؟» جامعه آماری این پژوهش، 53 نفر از مدیران دانش سازمان‌های پروژه‌محور نظامی دارای بخش مدیریت دانش مستقر در شهر تهران می­باشد که در حوزه ساخت فعال هستند. شناسایی این سازمان­ها بر اساس سه شاخص پروژه‌محور بودن، داشتن بخش مستقل مدیریت دانش و داشتن فعالیت عمرانی صورت گرفته است. ابزار این پژوهش، پرسش‌نامه و مصاحبه ساختاریافته بود. روایی پرسش‌نامه از طریق استادان مدیریت نظامی مورد تأیید قرار گرفت و پایایی نیز با محاسبه آلفای کرونباخ 0.834 به دست آمد. برای تحلیل استنباطی داده‌ها از آزمون t تک نمونه‌ای و آزمون فریدمن استفاده شد. آزمون تی نشان داد هر پنج عامل تأثیر معناداری داشتند. در بین عوامل محتوایی بیشترین  تأثیر را داشت. بعد از آن عوامل سازمانی قرار داشت. در نهایت موانع مدیریت دانش و درس آموخته‌ها در سازمان‌های پروژه‌محور نظامی شناسایی و در 5 بخش طبقه‌بندی‌شده و در نهایت 12 گام در سه لایه‌ برای کاهش و بهبود موانع مدیریت دانش و درس آموخته‌ها در سازمان‌های پروژه‌محور نظامی ارائه گردید.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In project-based organizations, the temporary nature of the projects leads to memory weakness, forgetfulness of valuable experiences, and lessons learned from the project. Given the structure and objectives of the project-based military organizations, the milestone can be seen in the vital role of knowledge gained from projects for the survival of the organization. The purpose of this study is to identify the key barriers to knowledge management and lessons learned in the project-based military organizations. This research answers the question that “what the key barriers to knowledge management and lessons learned in project-based military organizations are and what the importance and priority of these obstacles is.” The sample population of this research contains 53 knowledge managers of the project-based military organizations with a knowledge management department based in Tehran, active in the field of manufacturing. The identification of these organizations is based on three indicators: being project-based, having independent knowledge management department, and having developmental activities. The study instrument was a questionnaire and a structured interview. The questionnaire was validated through military management experts and the reliability was calculated using Cronbach’s alpha (0.834). For inferential analysis, one-sample t-test and the Friedman test were used. The t test showed that 5 factors are statistically significant, and among these factors, content ones were more influential than the organizational factors. Finally, the barriers to knowledge management and lessons learned were identified in the project-based military organizations and classified in five sections. In addition, 13 steps in three layers were presented to reduce and improve the barriers of knowledge management and lessons learned in the project-based military organizations.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>29</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>68</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زاهدی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammadreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zahedi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر(نویسنده مسئول)  zahedy182@gmail.com</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر(نویسنده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zahedy182@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پیمان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اخوان</Family>
						<NameE>Peyman</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Akhavan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>peyman_akv@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شایان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نقدی خناچاه</Family>
						<NameE>Shayan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Naghdi Khanachah</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shayan.en24@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت دانش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>موانع</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سازمانهای پروژه‌محور نظامی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>درس آموخته</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>اخوان، پیمان، نقیان فشارکی، مهدی، (1391)، «طراحی چارچوبی مفهومی برای مدیریت دانایی»، نشریه تدبیر، شماره 239 .##Abdullah, R., Selamat, M., Jaafar, A., Abdullah, S. and Sura, S. (2018), ”An Emprical Study of Knowledge Management System Implementation in Public Higher Learning Institution“, IJCSNS International Journal of Computer Science and Network Security, Vol. 8, No. 1, pp. 281-290.##Acar, M. F., Tarim, M., Zaim, H., Zaim, S., &amp; Delen, D. (2019). Knowledge management and ERP: Complementary or contradictory?. International Journal of Information Management, 37(6), 703-712.##Ahmad, N. &amp; Daghfous, A. (2010). Knowledge Sharing through Inter-Organizational knowledge Networks. European Business Review,VOL 22,NO 2, 153-174.##Argote, L. &amp; Ingram, P. (May 2000). Knowledge transfer: a basis for competitive advantage in firms. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Processes, Vol. 82, No. 1, 150-169.##Barson, R. Struck, T. Ratchev, S. Pawar, K. Weber, F. &amp; Wunram, M. (2000). Inter- and Intra-Organisational Barriers to Sharing Knowledge in the Extended Supply-Chain. e2000 Conference Proceedings, The University of Nottingham, University Park, Nottingham NG7 2RD, UK.##Buys, L., Mengersen, K., Johnson, S., Buuren, N.V., Chauvin, A., (2014). Creating a sustainability scorecard as a predictive tool for measuring the complex social, economic and environmental impacts of industries, a case study: assessing the viability and sustainability of the dairy company A. J. Environ. Manag. 133, 184C192.##Chen, C. J., Liu, T. C., Chu, M. A., &amp; Hsiao, Y. C. (2017). Intellectual capital and new product development. Journal of Engineering and Technology Management, 33. 154-173.##Chournazidis, A. J (2015). Functionality and feasibility of knowledge management in enterprises. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 73, 327-33Functionality and feasibility of knowledge management in enterprises. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 73, 327-336.##Forcada, N. Fuertes, A. Gangolells, M. Casals, G. &amp; Macarulla, M. (2013). Knowledge management perceptions in construction and design companies. Automation in Construction 29, 83 –91.##Gunjal, B. (2019). Knowledge management: Why do we need it for corporates. Malaysian Journal of Library &amp; Information Science (ISSN: 1394-6234).##Ganesh D, B. (2001). Knowledge management in organizations: examining the interaction between technologies, techniques, and people. Journal of Knowledge Management, Vol. 5 Issue. 1, 5(1), 68-75.##Hasnain, S. &amp; Jasimuddin, S. M. (2012). Barriers to Knowledge Transfer: Empirical Evidence from the NGO (Non-Governmental Organizations) - Sector in Bangladesh. World Journal of Social Sciences, Vol 2, No 2, 135 – 150.##Hobday, M. (2000). he Project-Based Organisation: An ideal form for managing complex products and systems? Research Policy, 29 (7-8), 871-893.##Hong, T. Y., Chien, C.-F., Wang, H. K., &amp; Guo, H. Z. (2018). A two-phase decoding genetic algorithm for TFT-LCD array photolithography stage scheduling problem with constrained waiting time. Computers &amp; Industrial Engineering, 125, 200-211.##Kaj U, K. (2010). Organisational memories in project-based companies: an autopoietic view. Learning Organization,Vol. 17 Iss: 2, 149-162.##Kaj U, K. (2010). Recursive view of the project-based companies&#039; knowledge production. Journal of Knowledge Management, Vol. 14, Iss: 2, 258 – 268.##Kaj U, K. &amp; Pekka, P. (2008). Knowledge Management in Project-Based Companies:An Organic Perspective. Printed and bound in Great Britain by CPI Antony Rowe, Chippenham and Eastbourne.##Kim, T.W. &amp; Joh, H. W. (2005). Key barriers and their strategic respons to activate knowledge sharing in construction organizations. 1st Annual ICCEM (International Conference on Construction Engineering and Management), Jamsil Lotte Hotel, Seoul,Korea, October 16-19.##Kotnour, T. (1999). A learning framework for project management. Project Management Journal, Vol. 30, No. 2, 32-38.##Kurt, M. L. &amp; Herbert, K. (2001). Mastering The human Barriers In Knowledge Management. Journal of universal science,Vol7, No 6, 488-497.##Laal, M. (2015). Knowledge Management in Higher Education. Procedia Computer Science, 3,544- 549.##Lam, W. &amp; Chua, A. (2005). The mismanagement of knowledge management. Aslib Proceedings: New Information Perspectives,Vol 57, No 5, 424-433.##Lin, C. Wu, J.C. &amp; Yen, D. C. (2012). Exploring barriers to knowledg e ﬂow at different knowledge mana gement mat urity stages. Information &amp; Management,Volume 49, Issue 1, 10-23.##Lokshina, I. &amp; Lanting, C. (2019). A qualitative evaluation of IoT-driven eHealth: knowledge management, business models and opportunities, deployment and evolution. In Data-Centric Business and Applications (pp. 23-52). Springer, Cham.##Massaro, M., Dumay, J. &amp; Garlatti, A. (2017). Public sector knowledge management: a structured literature review. Journal of Knowledge Management, 19(3), 530-558.##Nuria, F. Alba, F. Marta, G. Miquel, C. &amp; Marcel, M. (January 2013). Knowledge management perceptions in construction and design companies. Automation in Construction, Volume 29, 83-91.##Park, M. Jang, Y. Lee, H. s. Ahn, C. &amp; Yoon, Y. S. (2013). Application of Knowledge Management Technologies in Korean Small and Medium-sized Construction Companies. KSCE Journal of Civil Engineering, 17(1),22-32.##Polyaninova, T. (2010). Suitable Knowledge Management in Project Environment. Masters Dissertations. Dublin, Dublin Institute of Technoly, 72.##Prusak, L. (1997). Knowledge in organizations. Boston: Butterworth-Heinemann.##Ramachandran, S. D., Chong, S. C., &amp; Wong, K. Y. (2013). Knowledge management practices and enablers in public universities: a gap analysis. Campus-Wide Information Systems, 30(2),76-94.##Riege, A. (2005). Three-dozen knowledge-sharing barriers managers must consider. Journal of Knowledge management, VOL9, NO3, 18-25.##Rivera, G., &amp; Rivera, I. (2016). Design, Measurement and Analysis of a Knowledge Management Model in the Context of a Mexican University. Innovar, 26(59), 21-34.##Schindler, M. &amp; Eppler, M. J. (2003). Harvesting project knowledge: a review of project learning methods and success factors. International Journal of Project Management, Volume 21, Issue.3, 219-228.##Sharma, B. Singh, M. &amp; Neha. (2012). Modeling the Knowledge Sharing Barriers using an ISM approach. International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management,IPCSIT vol.45, IACSIT Press, Singapore.##Shen, F. Y. (2018). Knowledge management mechanisms-empirical study. Unpublished master thesis, National Tsing Hua University, Hsinchu, Taiwan.##Singh, M. D. &amp; Kant, R. (2008). Knowledge management barriers: An interpretive structural modeling approach. International Journal of Management Science and Engineering Management,Vol 3, No 2, 141-150.##Szulanski, G. (1996). Exploring Internal Stickiness: Impediments to the Transfer of Best Practice Within the Firm. Strategic Management Journal, Vol. 17, Special Issue: Knowledge and the Firm, 27-43.##Tan C. N. L. (2017). Enhancing knowledge sharing and research collaboration among academics: the role of knowledge management. Journal of Higher Education, 71, 525-556.##Walker, D. (2004). The Knowledge Advantage (K-Adv): Unleashing Creativity and Innovation Guide for the Project 2001-004. Delivering Improved Knowledge Management and Innovation Diffusion project for advice and collaboration on CRC CI project.##Wiewiora, A. Trigunarsyah, B. Murphy, G. &amp; Liang, C. (2009). Barriers to effective knowledge transfer in project-based organisations. International Conference on Global Innovation in Construction Proceedings, Loughborough University UK, Holywell Park, Loughborough University, 220-230.##Wong, K. (2009). Critical success factors for implementing knowledge management in small and medium enterprises. Industrial Management and Data Systems, 261-279.##Yao, L. Kam, T. &amp; Chan, S. (2007). Knowledge sharing in Asian public administration sector: the case of Hong Kong. Journal of Enterprise InformationManagement, Vol. 20, No. 1, 51-69.##Yuan-Feng, W. (2009). An effectiveness measurement model for knowledge management, Knowledge-Based Systems. Volume 22, Issu 3.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مفهوم‌پردازی همپایی فناورانه در صنایع دریایی بخش دفاع</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Technological Catch-up Conceptualization Processing in the Maritime Defense Sector</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>توسعه اقتصادی در کشورهای درحال‌توسعه، درگرو توسعه علمی است که از طریق فرآیند همپایی محقق می‌شود. همپایی فرآیندی است که طی آن، ‌یک کشور دیر توسعه‌یافته با کاهش شکاف درآمدی و یا افزایش قابلیت فناورانه، سعی درکاهش فاصله با کشورهای توسعه‌یافته از جنبه­های مختلف، همچون بخش دفاع و سازمان‌های نظامی دارد. در این امتداد، هدف از پژوهش حاضر، مفهوم‌پردازی همپایی فناورانه در صنایع دریایی بخش دفاعی می‌باشد. پژوهش از نظر هدف، اکتشافی و نحوه انجام آن کیفی است. داده­ها از  طریق مصاحبه با خبرگان دانشگاهی و به شیوه تحلیل محتوا و با استفاده از نرم‌افزار MAXQDA، احصا شده است. یافته­ها نشان می­دهد در راستای مفهوم همپایی فناورانه، نه عامل اصلی «یادگیری»، «پایه دانش»، «نظام‌ها و شبکه نوآوری»، «رژیم فناورانه»، «رژیم نهادی»، «رژیم بازار»، «تدوین و پیاده‌سازی الگوی بومی توسعه سازوکارهای حمایتی حاکمیت» و «نیروی انسانی» به‌عنوان ابعاد همپایی فناورانه قابل‌توجه هستند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Scientific development is the prerequisite for economic development in developing countries and is fulfilled through the catch-up process. It is a process in which a late-developed country, in attempt to reduce its income gap or increasing technological capabilities, attempts to lessen the technological gap with developed countries in different aspects, such as defense section and military organizations. In this path, the goal of this study is to conceptualize the technological catch-up processing in the defense maritime defense sector. Regarding the objective, this research is exploratory and qualitative. The data were obtained through interview with academic experts and the content analysis was performed using MXQDA software. The findings show that, considering the technological catch-up concept, nine main factors are ‘learning’, ‘knowledge base’, ‘systems and innovation network’, ‘technological regime’, ‘institutional regime’, ‘market regime’, ‘explanation and implementation of local development model’, ‘governmental supportive mechanisms’, and ‘human resource’.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>69</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>102</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ملکی کرم آباد</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Maleki Karam Abad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، مدیریت، گرایش سیاستگذاری علم و فناوری، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی و اداری، دانشگاه مازندران، بابلسر، مازندران، (نویسنده مسئول): mehdi_maleki15@yahoo.com</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، مدیریت، گرایش سیاستگذاری علم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehdi_maleki15@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسنعلی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آقاجانی</Family>
						<NameE>Hassanali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aghajani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی و اداری، دانشگاه مازندران، بابلسر، مازندران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده علوم اقتصادی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aghajaniumz@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>منوچهر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>منطقی</Family>
						<NameE>Manochehr</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Manteghi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد دانشگاه مالک اشتر، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد دانشگاه مالک اشتر، تهران، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>manteghi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهنام</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عبدی</Family>
						<NameE>Behnam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Abdi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه افسری امام علی (ع)، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>babdi@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>همپایی فناورانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قابلیت فناورانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>صنایع دریایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بخش دفاع</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>یادگیری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>افخم نیا، رضا و بهارلو، مهدی (1394)، «شناسایی عوامل کلیدی موفقیت در مدیریت نوآوری»، پنجمین کنفرانس بین‌المللی و نهمین کنفرانس ملی مدیریت فناوری، تهران.##استراوس، انسلم و جولیت کوربین(1390). مبانی پژوهش کیفی، فنون و مراحل تولید نظریه زمینه‌ای، ترجمه ابراهیم افشار، تهران: نشر نی##الیاسی، مهدی، منطقی، منوچهر، بامدادصوفی، جهانیار، میرباقری، سید محمد. (1397). «بررسی راهبردهای همپایی شرکت‌های نوظهور در صنعت هوایی و دلالت‌هایی برای صنعت هوایی ایران». بهبود مدیریت، 12(4)، 121-139.##بازرگان، عباس. (1387). مقدمه‌ای بر روش‌های تحقیق کیفی و آمیخته تهران: نشر دیدار.##حبیبا، سعید؛ کلانتری، اسماعیل (1396). «بررسی نقش سیاست حقوق مالکیت فکری در همپایی فناورانه کشورهای درحال‌توسعه»، فصلنامه علمی - پژوهشی سیاست‌گذاری عمومی، 3(2)، 152-135.##دانایی فر، حسن، الوانی، سیدمهدی، آذر، عادل (1398). روش‌شناسی پژوهش کیفی در مدیریت: رویکردی جامع: تهران: نشر صفار## طهماسبی، سیامک، فرتوک‌زاده، حمیدرضا، بوشهری، علیرضا، طبائیان، سید کمال، قیدر خلجانی، جعفر. (1395). مراحل شکل‌گیری و توسعه قابلیت‌های فناورانه؛ مطالعه یک سازمان صنعتی صنایع دریایی. سیاست علم و فناوری، 8(4)، 19-33.##میری‌مقدم، مژده (1394). &quot; ارائه مدلی برای شکل‌گیری نظام بخشی یادگیری در صنعت نفت &quot; رساله دکتری، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس ایران##وزیری، جواد (1394) &quot; الگوسازی مسیر گذار نظام اجتماعی-فنی صنعت دفاعی کشور&quot;، رساله دکتری، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس ایران##Amsden, Alice H and Wan-wen Chu (2003), Beyond late development: Taiwan&#039;s upgrading policies, U.S.: MIT Press##Araujio de, B. (2017), Market leadership in Brazil’s ICT sector: the cases of Totvs and Positivo. In F. Malerba, S. Mani, and P. Adams, editors The rise to market leadership.##BMI (2014), Iran Defence and Security Report Includes 5-Year Forecast to 2018 (Q4), BUSNESS MONITOR INTERNATIONAL.##Bell, R.M. and Pavitt, K. (1993), ‘Technological accumulation and industrial growth: Contrasts between developed and developing countries’, Industrial and Corporate Change 2 (1): 157-210.##Breznitz, Dan (2007), &#039;Industrial R&amp;D as a national policy: Horizontal technology policies and industry-state co-evolution in the growth of the Israeli software industry&#039;, Research Policy, 36 (9): 1465-1482.##Chandra, V.(2006); Technology, Adaptation and Exports, how some developing countries got it right, The World Bank, 2006.##Chen, L. (2009). “Learning through informal local and global linkages: The case of Taiwan’s machine tool industry”. Research Policy, 38(3): 527 –535.##Choung, Jae-Yong, Hwang, Hye-Ran, and Song, Wichin. (2014). Transitions of innovation activities in latecomer countries: An exploratory case study of South Korea. World Development,v. 54, p.156-167.##Cimoli, Mario, Annalisa Primi, and Sebastián Rovira, (2011), &#039;National innovation surveys in Latin America: Empirical evidence and policy implications.&#039; In: National innovation surveys in Latin America: empirical evidence and policy implications. Santiago: ECLAC, 2011. p. 7-14. LC/W. 408.##Fagerberg, J. and Godinho, M. (2005), Innovation and catching-up, in: Fagerberg, J. Mowery, D. Nelson, R, (Eds.), Oxford Handbook of Innovation, Chapter 19, Oxford: Oxford University Press.##Freeman, C. and J. Hagedoorn (1994). &quot;Catching up or falling behind: patterns in international interfirm technology partnering.&quot; World Development 22(5): 771-780.##Fu, X. Pietrobelli, C. and Soete, L. (2011). “The role of foreign technology and indigenous innovation” in the emerging economies: Technological change and catching-up. World development, 39(7):1204–1212.##Guo, B. (2017), The Rise to Market Leadership of Chinese Leading utomotive Firms: A Case of Geely Group from the Sectoral Innovation System Perspective, in The rise to market leadership, edited by F. Malerba, S. Mani and P. Adams.##Hayami, Yujiro and Vernon W. Ruttan (1985), Agricultural development: An international perspective, Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press.##He, Xiyou and Mu, Qing. (2012). How Chinese firms learn technology from transnational corporations: A comparison of the telecommunication and automobile industries. Journal of Asian Economics,v. 23(3), p.270-287.##Hobday, M., (١٩٩٧). Innovation in East Asia: The Challenge to Japan. Edward Elgar,Cheltenham &amp;  yme.##Kim, l and. Nelson R R,(2000). Technology, Learning and Innovation: Experiences of Newly Industrialising Economies.New York: Cambridge University Press,##Lall, S. (2000). “The technological structure and performance of developing country manufactured exports, 1985–98”. Oxford Development Studies, 28(3)##Lall, s. (1989), Learning to Industrialise: the Acquisition of Technology Capability by India, London: macmillan##Lee, K. and C. Lim (2001). &quot;Technological regimes, catching-up and##leapfrogging: findings from the Korean industries.&quot; Research policy 30(3): 459-483.##Lee, K. (2013). &quot;How Can Korea be a Role Model for Catch-up Development? A ‘Capability-based View’.&quot; Achieving Development Success: Strategies and Lessons from the Developing World: 25.##Lee, J. Park, S. H. Ryu, Y. and Baik, Y.S. (2010). “A hidden cost of strategic alliance under Schumpeterian dynamics”. Research Policy, 39(2): 229–238.##Lee, Keun &amp; Malerba, Franco, 2017. &quot;Catch-up cycles and changes in industrial leadership:Windows of opportunity and responses of firms and countries in the evolution of sectoral systems,&quot; Research Policy, Elsevier, vol. 46(2), pages 338-351.##Lee, K. and F. Malerba (2016). &quot;Catch-up cycles and changes in industrial leadership: Windows of opportunity and responses of firms and countries in the evolution of sectoral systems.&quot; Research Policy.##Lee, K. X. Gao and X. Li (2017). &quot;Industrial catch-up in China: a sectoral systems of innovation perspective.&quot; Cambridge Journal of Regions, Economy and Society 10(1): 59-76.##Lee, T. and V. Tunzelmann (2005). &quot;A dynamic approach to national innovation systems: The IC industry in Taiwan.&quot; Research Policy 34: 425-440.##Li, Z. and C. Wang (2013). One-dimensional nanostructures: electrospinning technique and unique nanofibers, Springer.##Lundvall, Bengt-Åke (2014), &#039;Deteriorating quality of work undermines Europe’s innovation systems and the welfare of Europe’s workers&#039;, http://portal.ukwon.eu/guest-essay.##Malerba, Franco and Luigi Orsenigo (1996), &#039;Schumpeterian patterns of innovation are technology-specific&#039;, Research Policy, 25 (3): 451-478.##Majidpour, M. (2016), International technology transfer and the dynamics of complementarity: A new approach, Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 11- 21, Doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.techfore.2016.03.004.##Mani, s (2017). &quot;Market leadership in India’s pharmaceutical industry: the case of Cipla Limited,&quot; Chapters, in: Franco Malerba &amp; Sunil Mani &amp; Pamela Adams (ed.), The Rise to Market Leadership, chapter 5, pages 99-123, Edward Elgar Publishing.##Mazzoleni, R. and R. R. Nelson (2007). &quot;Public research institutions and##economic catch-up.&quot; Research Policy 36(10): 1512-1528.##Miao, Y. Song, J. Lee, K. Jin, Ch. (2018). Technological Catch-up by East Asian firms: Trends, es, and future Research Agenda. Asia Pac J Manag https://doi.org/10.1007/s10490-018-9566-z.##Military Balance (2016), the Annual Assessment of Global Military Capabilities and Defense Economics, the International Institute for Strategic Studies, Routledge.##Moreira, M. M. (1995). Industrialization, trade and market failures: the role of government intervention in Brazil and South Korea: St. Martin&#039;s Press.##Mytelka,l. 1978. Licensing and technological dependence in the Andean Group, World Development,6: 447-59##Nelson, R.R., 2008. Economic development from the perspective of evolutionary economic theory. Oxford Dev. Stud. 36, 9–21.##Nelson, R. R. and S. G. Winter (1982). An Evolutionary Theory of Economic Change, Belknap Press of Harvard University Press##Park, K.H. and K. Lee (2006). &quot;Linking the technological regime to the technological catch-up: analyzing Korea and Taiwan using the US patent data.&quot; Industrial and Corporate Change 15(4): 715-753.##Perez, c. (2001),Technological change and opportunities for development as a moving target, CEPAL Rev., 75: 109-130.##Odagiri, H. Goto, A. Sunami, A. and Nelson, R. R. (Eds). (2012). Intellectual property rights, development, and catch up: An international##comparative study. Oxford: Oxford University Press.##Ramani, Shyama V and Samira Guennif (2012), &#039;Catching up in the pharmaceutical sector: Lessons from case studies of India, Thailand and Brazil&#039;, in F. Malerba and R. R. Nelson (eds.), Economic Development as a Learning Process, Edward Elgar Publishing, Northampton: 157-193.##Sohn, E., Chang, S., &amp; Song, J. (2009). Technological Catching-up and Latecomer Strategy: A Case Study of the Asian Shipbuilding Industry. Seoul Journal of Business,15(2) :25-57##Stewart, f. (1977). Technology and Underdevelopment, London: Macmillan##Xiao, Y. Tylecote, A. and Liu, J. (2013). “Why not greater catch-up by Chinese firms? The impact of IPR, corporate governance and technology intensity on late-comer strategies”. Research Policy, 42(3):749–764.##Wang, Y. Zhou, Z. Ning, L. and Chen, J. (2015). “Technology and external conditions at play: A study of learning-by-licensing practices in China”. Technovation, 43 –44: 29–29.##Wang, J. H. and Tsai, C.-j. (2010).“ National model of technological catching up and innovation: Comparing patents of Taiwan and South Korea”. Journal of Development Studies, 46(8): 1404–1423.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اثر عوامل زمینه‌ای بر بروز رفتارهای انحرافی کارکنان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Effect of Contextual Factors on Employees’ Deviant Behaviors</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف اصلی تحقیق حاضر بررسی تأثیر عوامل زمینه ای بر بروز رفتارهای انحرافی کارکنان است. این تحقیق بر اساس هدف، کاربردی و بر اساس ماهیت روش یک تحقیق توصیفی- پیمایشی می باشد. جامعه آماری تحقیق حاضر شامل پرسنل یک سازمان نظامی در شهر تهران می باشد که تعداد آنها 280 نفر می باشند. برای انتخاب نمونه تحقیق با استفاده از جدول مورگان تعداد 162 نفر و بر اساس روش نمونه گیری تصادفی ساده انتخاب شده‌اند. ابزار گردآوری اطلاعات در این تحقیق پرسشنامه‌های استاندارد در زمینه متغیرهای تحقیق می‌باشد. روایی محتوایی پرسشنامه های تحقیق به وسیلۀ اساتید خبره و پایایی آنها نیز با استفاده از ضریب آلفای کرونباخ مورد تأیید قرار گرفت. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها نیز از نرم افزار لیزرل استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان دادند که عوامل زمینه‌ای بر بروز رفتارهای انحرافی کارکنان تأثیر معناداری دارند. همچنین وابستگی سیاسی(82/0)، پیچیدگی قوانین و مقررات(79/0)، فرهنگ کار ضعیف(76/0) و شرایط نامناسب بازار کار(73/0) نیز بر بروز رفتارهای انحرافی کارکنان تأثیر معناداری دارند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The main purpose of the present study is to investigate the effect of contextual factors on employees’ deviant behaviors. Considering purpose, the research is applied and based on the nature, it is a descriptive survey. The statistical population of the study is consisted of 280 personnel in a military organization in Tehran. To select the sample, using the Morgan table, 162 individuals were selected through simple random sampling. The data collection tools were standard questionnaires on research variables. The content validity of the questionnaires and their reliability were confirmed by experts and Cronbach’s alpha coefficient respectively. The data were analyzed using LISREL software. The results showed that the underlying factors have significant effects on employees’ deviant behaviors. Also, political affiliation (0.82), complexity of laws and regulations (0.79), poor working culture (0.76), and inappropriate labor market conditions (0.73) significantly impact on employees’ deviant behaviors.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>103</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>126</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فرهاد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فتاحی</Family>
						<NameE>Farhad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Fatahi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری  مدیریت دولتی، گروه مدیریت ، واحد فیروزکوه، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، فیروزکوه، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری  مدیریت دولتی، گروه مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ff_fatahi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جهانگیرفرد</Family>
						<NameE>Majid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jahangirfard</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار،گروه مدیریت واحد فیروزکوه دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی ، فیروزکوه، ایران. (نویسنده مسئول)؛ Dr.jahangirfard@gmail.com</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار،گروه مدیریت واحد فیروزکوه دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>dr.jahangirfard@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مهدیزاده</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mahdizadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار،گروه مدیریت واحد فیروزکوه دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی ، فیروزکوه، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار،گروه مدیریت واحد فیروزکوه دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehdizadeh297@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رفتارهای انحرافی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>وابستگی سیاسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پیچیدگی قوانین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرهنگ کار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازار کار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ارشدی، نسرین؛ پیریایی، صالحه(1391) اعتمادپذیری کارکنان، قابلیت اعتماد سرپرست و اعتماد بین فردی به عنوان پیشایندهای رفتارهای انحرافی محیط کار، مشاوره شغلی و سازمانی، 4(13)، 83-100.##بهرامی، حمیدرضا؛ داستانی، معصومه و پورامینی، زهرا(1395). رابطه امنیت شغلی با رفتار سیاسی با نقش میانجی رفتار شهروندی سازمانی، فصلنامه رسالت مدیریت دولتی، 24(3)، 32-15.##فرهادی نژاد، محسن؛ لگزیان، محمد (1390) پیمایش طولی در زمینه علل فساد اداری و روش­های کنترل آن در دستگاه­های اجرایی خراسان رضوی، فصلنامه چشم انداز مدیریت دولتی شماره ۸، ۶۰-۴۵##رهنورد، فرج اله؛ طاهرپور کلانتری، حبیب اله؛ رشیدی، اعظم (۱۳۸۹) شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر فساد مالی در بین کارکنان دستگاه­های اجرایی، پژوهشنامه مدیریت ۶ (۱)، ۵۲-۳۵##قدرتی پور، مرتضی؛ حسن مرادی، نرگس (1393) بررسی میزان تأثیر عوامل سازمان و مدیریت در بروز رفتارکاری انحرافی، فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، 6(2)، 354-333##گل پرور، محسن؛ سلحشور، آزاده. (1395). الگوی ساختاری رابطه رهبری مخرب با تمایل به خشونت و رفتارهای انحرافی در کارکنان. مجله پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع سازمانی، 6(2)، 93-123.‎##منتخب یگانه، محمد؛ بشلیده، کیومرث؛ شمسی، مرجان؛ هزاریان؛(1395) بررسی رابطه رهبری اخلاقی با رفتارهای انحرافی در محیط کار: نقش میانجی تعهد عاطفی و جو اخلاقی، مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی، 14 (1)، 137- 153 .##موسوی، سید نجم الدین؛ زارع، فرجاد(1396). بررسی نقش رفتارهای سیاسی بر بروز رفتارهای منافقانه با توجه به نقش میانجی معنویت، فصلنامه مطالعات رفتار سازمانی، 6(4)، 187-161.##واعظی؛ رضا؛ حسین­پور؛ داود؛ رنجبرکبوترخانی؛ مصطفی؛(1395) تأثیر عدالت سازمانی در بروز رفتار انحرافی بر اساس نقش میانجی ادراک از عدالت سازمانی، فصلنامه مطالعات رفتارهای سازمانی،شماره3، 85-112##هادوی‌نژاد، مصطفی؛ بهارلویی، الهه (۱۳۹۴). رفتارهای منافقانه در ارتباطات بین فردی در سازمان: پیشایندها و پیامدهای سازمانی، فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، شماره ۲۲##Bennett, R. J. and Robinson, S.L. (2000). Development of a measure of workplace deviance. Journal of Applied Psychology, 85(3), 349-360.##Chen, Y., Li, S., Xia, Q., &amp; He, C. (2017). The Relationship Between Job Demands and Employees’ Counterproductive Work Behaviors: The Mediating Effect of Psychological Detachment and Job Anxiety. Frontiers in psychology, 8, 1890.##Clark, O. L., &amp; Walsh, B. M. (2016). Civility climate mitigates deviant reactions to organizational constraints. Journal of Managerial Psychology, 31(1), 186-201.##Di Stefano, G., Scrima, F., &amp; Parry, E. (2017). The effect of organizational culture on deviant behaviors in the workplace. The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 1-22.##Ferris, G. R. (2017). Politics in organizations: theory and research considerations. New York, NY: Routledge publisher.##Galperin, B. Loka, Y. Peti, R. (2012). Exploring the nomological network of workplace deviance: Developing and validating a measure of constructive deviance. Journal of Applied Social Psychology, 42(12), 2988-3025.##Harvey, P., Martinko, M. J., &amp;Borkowski, N. (2017). Justifying deviant behavior: The role of attributions and moral emotions. Journal of business ethics, 141(4), 779-795.##Juan, R. &amp;Jusepe, P. F. (2016). The Political Consequences of Economic Shocks: Implications for Political Behavior in Russia. Problems Of Post-Communism, No,63, pp. 221–240.##Kim, T., Atkin, D. J. &amp; Lin, C. A. (2016). Investigating the role of education in the incidence of political citizenship behavior. Journal Of Broadcasting &amp; Electronic Media, No, 60, pp. 23–39.##Kura, K. M. (2016). Re-examining the relationship between perceived workgroup norms, self-regulatory efficacy and deviant workplace behaviour. African Journal of Economic and Management Studies, 7(3), 379-396.##Pulich, M. (2014). Workplace deviance: strategies for modifying employee behavior. The Health Care Manager, 23(4), 290-301.##Pacu, L. (2017). Organizational and Innovation Policies. Journal Of Information Technology &amp; Politics, No, 9, pp. 352–369.##Robinson, S. L &amp; Bennett, R. J. (1995). A typology of deviant workplace behaviors: A multidimensional scaling study. Academy of Management Journal, 38(2), 555-572.##Silva, H. M. S., &amp;Ranasinghe, R. M. I. D. (2017). The Impact of Job Stress on Deviant Workplace Behaviour: A Study of Operational Level Employees of Comfort Apparel Solutions Company in Sri Lanka. International Journal of Human Resource Studies, 7(1), 74-85.##Treadway ،Darren C. ،Breland،Jacob W. ،Williams ،Lisa M. ،Cho ،Jeewon،Yang ،Jun Ferris ،Gerald R. (2013). Social influence and interpersonal power in organizations: Roles of performance and political skill in two studies. Journal of Management. No, 39, pp. 1529- 1533.##Tuclea, C. E., Vrânceanu, D. M., &amp; Filip, A. (2015). Dimensions of Deviant Workplace Behavior in Small and Medium-Sized Enterprises. Revista de Management Comparat International, 16(1)##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>طراحی الگوی رهبری اثربخش در آجا مبتنی بر تکنیک دلفی فازی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Designing an Effective Leadership Model in AJA based on Fuzzy Delphi Technique</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>رهبریِ‌اثربخش در سازمان، عامل اصلی و اساسی در ایجاد هم‌فکری و هم‌دلی است و رهبران مؤثر کسانی هستند که بتوانند افراد متفاوت را در زیر چتر فکری خود و نظر واحد گرد آورند. پژوهش حاضر به بررسی ابعاد، مؤلفه‌ها و شاخص‌های رهبریِ‌اثربخش در ارتش جمهوری اسلامی ایران از دیدگاه خبرگان این سازمان پرداخته است. پژوهش، ازنظر نتیجه، توسعه‌ای، از نظر اهداف، کاربردی و ازنظر داده‌ها، کیفی است. جامعه‌ی پژوهش را همه‌ی خبرگان در حوزه‌ی فرماندهی ارتش که شناخت کاملی از سازمان و اهداف و وظایف آن داشته‌اند، تشکیل می‌دهند. روش نمونه‌گیری هدفمند بود و تعداد افراد نمونه تا حد اشباع نظری، ادامه یافت (در این پژوهش، اشباع نظری در حد 10 خبره به دست آمد). ابزار سنجش، یک پرسش‌نامه‌ی 80 سؤالی نیمه‌ساختمندِ پژوهشگر ساخته بود که با بررسی یافته‌های پیشین، گردآوری و سپس به کمک فن دلفی‌فازی در دو مرحله، برای خبرگان ارسال شد و درنهایت 81 سؤال نهایی حاصل شد. یافته‌های پژوهش حاکی از آن است که رهبریِ‌اثربخش در ارتش، مشتمل بر 3 بعد فردی، سازمانی، فرا سازمانی و 11 مؤلفه‌ی صفات فردی، سلامت روان، اعتقادی، اخلاقی، توانایی‌های ویژه، توانایی‌های مدیریتی، توانایی‌های تخصصی سازمانی، فرهنگی – اجتماعی، اقتصادی، سیاسی – قانونی و فناورانه است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Effective leadership in an organization is a key factor in creating compassion and empathy, and effective leaders are those who can gather different people under their umbrella and a unified vision. The present study examines the dimensions, components, and indicators of effective leadership in the Islamic Republic of Iran’s Army from the perspective of its elites. In terms of outcome, this research is developmental, and is qualitative and applied in terms of its data and nature. The sample population consists of experts in the field of military commandment that have a comprehensive understanding of the organization, its goals, and tasks. The sampling method was purposeful and the selection of the participants was continued to be saturated with theoretical content (in this research, theoretical saturation was obtained by 10 elites). The instrument was a researcher-made 80-question questionnaire compiled by reviewing previous findings and confirmed by experts through using fuzzy Delphi technique in two stages. Ultimately 81 final questions were obtained. The findings show that the effective leadership in army includes three dimensions of individual, organizational, meta-organizational, and eleven components of individual traits, mental health, beliefs, ethics, special capabilities, managerial capabilities, along with technical organizational, cultural-social, economic, political -legal and technological capabilities.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>127</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>162</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Ahmad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکده‌ی علوم انسانی،دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد رفسنجان، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکده‌ی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ahmadmohammadi1217@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ملیکه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بهشتی فر</Family>
						<NameE>Melike</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>BeheshtiFar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکده‌ی علوم انسانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامى، واحد رفسنجان، ایران. (نویسنده مسئول)؛ m.beheshtifar@yahoo.com</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکده‌ی علوم انسانی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.beheshtifar@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کاظمی</Family>
						<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kazemi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ علوم ادارى و اقتصاد، دانشگاه ولى عصر(ع)، رفسنجان، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشکدۀ علوم ادارى</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hkazemi1384@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رهبریِ‌اثربخش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دلفی‌فازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارتش جمهوری اسلامی ایران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>احمدی، م (1390). مدیریت اسلامی، چاپ ششم، تهران: انتشارات پژوهش‌های فرهنگی،##آدیزس، ا (1373). دوره عمر سازمان، ترجمه: کاوه محمد سیروس، انتشارات اشراقیه، 250-233.##افجه‌ای، س‌ع‌ا (1390). رهبری سازمانی، تهران: سازمان مدیریت صنعتی.##افجه‌ای، س‌ع‌ا (1385). مبانی فلسفی و تئوری‌های رهبری و رفتار سازمانی، تهران: سمت، چ پنجم.##افجه‌ای، ع ا. بانشی، ع. خسروپناه، ع و امیری، م (1393). طراحی الگوی رهبری اثربخش سازمانی به استناد سیره پیامبر اسلام (ص)، فصل‌نامه مطالعات راهبردی بسیج، سال هفدهم، شماره 64.##الوانی، س م (1378). مدیریت عمومی، نشر نی، 137.##الوانی، س. م. اردلان، ا و محمدی فاتح، ا (1395). طراحى و تدوین الگوی مناسب شایستگی‌های مدیران و فرماندهان در سازمان ارتش ج.ا.ا با بهره‌گیری از دیدگاه امام خامنه­ای (مدظله‌العالی)، فصلنامه پژوهش­های مدیریت منابع انسانی، سال هشتم، شماره 1، 30-1.##براندن (1376). روانشناسی حرمت نفس، ترجمه جمال‌الدین هاشمی، شرکت سهامی انتشار.##حریری، نجلا (1385). اصول و روش‌های پژوهش کیفی، تهران، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی – واحد علوم و تحقیقات.##خان احمدی، ا و مدنی، م (۱۳۹۲). منشور فرماندهی کارآمد برگرفته از نهج­البلاغه، مدیریت اسلامی، 21(۲)، ۲۵۳-۲۲۳.##دانایی‌فرد، ح. مؤمنی، ن. 1388، تئوری رهبری اثربخش از دیدگاه امام علی (ع)، مطالعات انقلاب اسلامی، ش 4(14)، 110-75.##دراکر، پیتر (مدیریت اثربخش). ترجمه فضل‌الله امینی، تهران، فرا.##دینانی، مریم. کوزه چیان، هاشم. نظریان مادوانی، عباس (۱۳۹۶). طراحی الگوی هوشمندیهای مورد نیاز رهبری اثربخش مدیران ورزشی.  فصلنامه علمی - پژوهشی پژوهش­های کاربردی در مدیریت ورزشی.6(1).88-73.##رجب پور، مجید (۱۳۹۸). اصول و مبانی مدیریت در سازمان، تهران: انتشارات دافوس آجا، ۲۹-۲۸.##رضاییان، علی (1379). مدیریت رفتارسازمانی، تهران: سمت.##سارلی، زبیده. صفایی، طیبه (1396). ویژگی های رهبری اثربخش در مدیریت آموزشی مدارس. مجله مطالعات روانشناسی و علوم تربیتی، شماره 20.##ساعتچی، م (1376). روانشناسی بهره‌وری، تهران: نشر ویرایش،##سپهوند، رضا. چکشیان، محمد. اسماعیلی، محمودرضا. نظرپوری، امیرهوشنگ (1397). رتبه بندی مؤلفه­های رهبری اثربخش در سازمانهای فرهنگی هنری با رویکرد اسلامی ایرانی و بااستفاده از روش دلفی فازی. نشریه مدیریت فردا، شماره 54.##شکوه، زهرا (1394). طراحی یک الگوی اثربخش برای رهبری اصیل در سازمان بهزیستی کشور، پایان‌نامه دکتری.##شیرخانی، نسیم. سوسن لائی، ۱۳۹۴، ارائه مدل رهبری اثربخش برای مدیران مدارس ابتدایی، همایش ملی سیمای مدیریت آموزشی در عصر تکنولوژی اطلاعات و ارتباطات، کرمانشاه، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد کرمانشاه.##صادق زاده قمصری، علیرضا (1391). «الگوهای نظری با سبغه‌ی ایرانی-اسلامی: مروری بر روش‌شناسی بر تدوین سند تحول بنیادین آموزش‌وپرورش»، نخستین کنفرانس الگوی اسلامی-ایرانی پیشرفت: نقشه راه طراحی و تدوین الگو، تهران: کتابخانه ملی، 10-11 خرداد.##صدقی بوکانی، ناصر. سیدعباس زاده، میرمحمد. قلاوندی، حسن. حسنی، محمد (1397). تحلیل روابط چندگانه­ی رهبری اثربخش و برنامه­ریزی راهبردی با بهره­وری نیروی انسانی در مراکز آموزش­عالی استان آذربایجان غربی، مجله­­ی مدیریت بهره وری، شماره­ی 45، 31-69.##فیدلر، ف. شمرز، م (1391). رهبری اثربخش، ترجمه خلیلی شوروینی، چاپ اول، تهران: مرکز انتشارات علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی.##قلی‌پور، آ و حضرتی، م (1388). تبیین ابزار سنجش رهبری خدمتگزار در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران، مجله پژوهش‌های مدیریت عمومی، 2(3)، 47-30.##کریتز، ر. کینیکی، آ (1386). مدیریت رفتار سازمانی، ترجمه دکتر علی‌اکبر فرهنگی و حسین صفرزاده، تهران: پیام پویا، چ دوم.##کریمی دشتکی، احمد (1394). طراحی الگوی رهبری اثربخش آموزشی در آموزش عالی از دور بر پایه تجاری­سازی دانش، نظام ارزش ها و ادراک فرهنگ سازمانی، رساله دوره دکتری. دانشگاه پیام نور، مرکز تحصیلات تکمیلی.##کلاتـه‌سـیفری، معصـومه و عموزاده، زهرا (1393). ارتباط جامعه پذیری سازمانی با اثربخشی رهبری در ادارات ورزش و جوانان استان گلستان، پژوهشنامه مدیریت ورزشی و رفتار حرکتی، 9(20)، 163-155.##کوایمان، ج، الیاسن، ج، ا (1370). مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی، ترجمه: عباس منوریان، انتشارات مرکز آموزش مدیریت دولتی، 192-191.##لطفی، فرشاد. سلیمانی، مهیار. کاظمی، محمدتقی (۱۳۹۷). بررسی تأثیر رهبری اثر بخش بر توانمندی کارکنان سازمان تامین اجتماعی استان مرکزی، پنجمین کنفرانس ملی پژوهش‌های کاربردی در مدیریت و حسابداری، تهران: انجمن مدیریت ایران##ماکسول، ج (1386). رهبری، ترجمه فضل اله امینی، چاپ سوم، تهران: فرا.##ماکسول، ج (1387). 21 قانون انکارناپذیر رهبری، ترجمه مهدی قراچه داغی، تهران: پیکان.##مدنی، س.م. آبسالان، م (1394). تأثیر رهبری تحول‌آفرین بر ارتقای توان رزمی در یک سازمان دفاعی، فصلنامهمدیریتنظامی، 15(59)، 58-32.##مقیمی، م (1380). سازمان و مدیریت رویکردی پژوهشی، تهران:  انتشارات ترمه، 285-284.##مطهری، م (1389). یادداشت‌های استاد مطهری، چاپ شصت و یکم، تهران: صدرا.##هرسی، پ. بلانچارد، ک. (1371). مدیریت رفتار سازمان، ترجمۀ قاسم کبیری، تهران: انتشارات جهاد دانشگاهی، 571-203.##Akyuz, E. and Celik, E. (2015). A fuzzy DEMATEL method to evaluate critical Operational hazards during gas freeing process in crude oil tankers. Journal of LossPrevention in the Process Industries, 38, 243-253.##Bass, B.M and B.J. Avolio, (1993), Multifactor Leadership Questionnaire, Consulting Psychologist Press, Palo Alto, CA.## Borden, N and Baneta, F. (2008). Using Performance Indicators to Guide Strategic Decision Making, sanfrancisco: Josswy publishers.##Boyatzis, R.E. (1982), The Competent Manager: A Model for Effective Performance, Wiley, New York, NY##Boyatzis, R. E. (1998), Transforming qualitative information: thematic analysis andcode development, Sage.##Braun, V. &amp; Clarke, V. (2006), “Using thematic analysis in psychology&quot;, Qualitative Research in Psychology, Vol. 3, No. 2, Pp. 77-101##Chemers, M. (1985), the Social, Organizational and Cultural Context of Effective Leadership, in Barbara Kellerman, Ed, and Leadership: Multidisciplinary Perspectives, Englewood Cliffs, N. J. Prentice-Hall, pp. 91-112.##Costigan, R. D. Ilter, S. E. Berman, J. J.(1998), A multi-dimensional study of trust in organizations, Journal of Managerial Issues, Vol. X, No. 3, 303-317.##Cunningham, Alann Dawn, (2003), Leadership development in catholic: A study on several leadership, Doctoral Dissertation, Saint Louis University (UMI NO AAT 3102886).##Davenport, T. &amp; Prusak, L. 1998, Working Knowledge, Boston: Harvard Business School Press.##Ditcher, E. (1987), How Hot A Manager Are You? NewYork: McGraw–Hill.##Dufault, K. (1985), Hope, its spheres and dimensions, Nursing Clinics of North America, Vol. 2, No. 2, 379-391.##Dunham R. The Delphi technique.(1996). [Cited 2002 Mar 24]. Available from:http://www.medsch.wisc.edu/adminmed/2002/orgbehav/delphi.pdf##Ellonen, R. &amp; Blomqvist, K.(2008), The role of trust in organizational innovativeness, European Journal of Innovation Management, Vol. 11, No. 2, 160-181.##Educational Resources Information Center. (2010). Volunteer Management. Www. ERIC. Com.##Fiedler, F, e. (1967), A Theory of Leadership Effectiveness, Mc Grawhill, New York, p, 147.##Fiedler, F, e. &amp; Chemers, M, 1974, Leadership and Effective Management, Scott Foresman and Company, p. 5.##Fernald, L. W. Solomon, G. T. &amp; Tarabishy, A. 2005, A new paradigm: Entrepreneurial    leadership, Southern Business Review, Vol. 30, No. 2, 1–10.##Fry, L. W. Vitucci, S. &amp; Cedillo, M. 2005, Spiritual leadership and army transformation: Theory, measurement, and establishing a baseline, The Leadership Quarterly, Vol. 16, 835–862.##Hersey, P &amp; Blanchard, K. 1983, Management of Organizational Behavior, Pretical, p. 94.##Hersey, P. and Blanchard, H. K. 1977, Management of organizational Behavior, Englewood Cliffs, Prentice Hall.##Hersey, P &amp; Blanchard, K &amp; Dewey, J. 1996, Management of Organization Behavior, 6thed, Euglewood Cliffs, N, J, Prentice-Hall, p 91.##Holloway, I. &amp; Todres, L. (2003), “The Status of Method: Flexibility, Consistencyand Coherence”, Qualitative Research, Vol. 3, No. 3,##Imani Jajarami H. [Ashnaie ba ravesh Delphi va karborde an dar tasmimgiri]. Faslnameh Modiriat Shahri,2000; 1(1): 35-9. Persian##Katz, D and kahn, R,L. (2009). The Social Psychology of Organization, New York: Willey.##Kennedy HP. Enhancing Delphi research: methods and results. J Adv Nurs 2004 Mar; 45(5): 504-11.##Kohlbacher, F. The use of qualitative content analysis in case study research.in Forum Qualitative Sozialforschung/Forum: Qualitative Social Research.2006##Mitchell, T, R. (2007). People In Organization Understanding Their Behavior. www. ERIC. com.##Pentagon. (2007). Comandering. www. Pentagon-usa- comiservo3. html.##Pounder, J, S. 2001, New Leadership and Unniversity Organizational Effectiveness Exploring the Relationship, Leadership &amp; Organization Development, Journal 22(6), pp, 281-290.##Powell C. The Delphi technique: myths and realities. J Adv Nurs 2003 Feb; 41(4): 376-82.##S Bekesiene, S Hoskova-Mayerova, 2018, -Decision tree-based classification model for identification of effective leadership indicators. Journal of Mathematical and …, 2018 - journals.itb.ac.id##Spisak, B. R. O’Brien, M. J. Nicholson, N &amp; Van Vugt, M. 2015, Niche constructionand the evolution of leadership, Academy of Management Review, Vol. 40, No. 2, 291–306.##Tannenbaum, R. Weschler, I. Massarik, F. 1959, Leadership and Organization: A Behavioral Science Approach, Mc Grawhill.##Yu, H &amp; Leithwood, K &amp; Jantiz, D. 2002, the Effects of Teachers’Commitment to Chang in Hong Kong, Journal of Educational Administration, 40(4), p, 40.##Yukl, G. A.1971. Leadership in Organization: Englewood cliffs: NJ. Prentice Hall Ince.##Waltz, C.F. O. Strickland, and E.R. Lenz, Measurement in nursing and health research. 2010, New York: Springer Pub.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارائه مدلی جهت پیاده سازی دفتر مدیریت پروژه (PMO) درسازمان‌های تحقیقاتی نظامی (مطالعه موردی: یکی از سازمان‌های تحقیقاتی نظامی )</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Model for Implementing Project Management Office (PMO) in Military Research Organizations 
(Case Study: One of the military research organizations)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>بسیاری از سازمان‌‌ها و شرکت‌‌ها به دنبال یافتن راه‌کارهایی برای ایجاد فرآیندهای منظم و رسمی مدیریت پروژه هستند که منجر به نظم‌دهی هر چه بیشتر سازمان در انجام پروژه‌های جاری در قالب زمان، بودجه و سطح کیفی مورد نظر می‌شود. شرح وظایف و اهداف متنوع و گوناگونی را می‌توان بر اساس نیاز‌ها و ویژگی‌های سازمان، از راه‌اندازی و استقرار دفتر مدیریت پروژه انتظار داشت. مهم‌ترین انتظاری که از دفتر مدیریت پروژه سازمان می‌رود، ایجاد فرآیندهای منظم و یکپارچه مدیریت پروژه در قالب ساختار واحد مدیریت پروژه می‌باشد. پژوهش حاضر نیز قصد دارد با بهره‌‌گیری از تحقیقات انجام گرفته به شناسایی و توضیح ابعادی بپردازد که هدایت‌گر سازمان‌ها در بکار گیری دفاتر مدیریت پروژه هستند. ابعاد شناسایی شده تحت عنوان الزامات پیاده‌سازی مدل دفتر مدیریت پروژه ارائه شده‌اند. در این پژوهش ابتدا اهمیت و ضرورت دفتر مدیریت پروژه بیان شده و پس از بیان مبانی نظری و مدل های مفهومی دفتر مدیریت پروژه، ساختار دفتر مدیریت پروژه تشریح می‌گردد. سپس در پاسخ به سؤال ‌های تحقیق، مدل مفهومی پژوهش ارائه می‌شود و عناصر این مدل مفهومی توضیح داده می‌شوند. اطلاعات پژوهش از طریق مطالعات کتابخانه ای و اینترنتی گردآوری شده و جهت تأیید مدل با استفاده از پرسشنامه طیف لیکرت از خبرگان سازمانی نظرسنجی شده است. به منظور تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها، یکی از سازمان‌های تحقیقاتی نظامی به عنوان مورد مطالعه انتخاب شده است و بوسیله نرم افزار spss، ابتدا فرض نرمال بودن متغیرها با استفاده از آزمون کلموگروف-اسمیرنوف مورد آزمون قرار گرفته و سپس با استفاده از آزمون تی-استودنت وضعیت هریک از مؤلفه‌های دفتر مدیریت پروژه ارزیابی شده است. به‌طور خلاصه، مؤلفه های تأیید شده‌ی دفتر مدیریت پروژه با سه مؤلفه اصلی با عناوین برنامه‌ریزی (سبد پروژه)، تحویل(طرح و پروژه) و مرکز تعالی و در قالب 17 مؤلفه فرعی ارائه شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Many organizations and companies are looking for solutions to create regular and formal processes for project management that leads to higher discipline in conducting current projects in terms of time, budget, and quality level. Task description and various goals can be expected based on the needs and characteristics of an organizations, from setup to the project management office deployment. The most important expectation from the project management office is to create regular and integrated processes for project management in the form of a unified project management structure. Accordingly, the present study, using the previous research, aims to identify and explain the dimensions that guide organizations in using project management offices. The identified dimensions are presented as the requirements for the implementation of the project management office project model. In this research, the importance and necessity of the project management office was firstly stated and after expressing theoretical and conceptual models of the project management office, the project management office structure was described. The conceptual model of the research was presented and the elements of the conceptual model was identified. The Likert-scale questionnaire was composed using library and online studies, and was confirmed by the organization experts. To analyze the data, a military research organizations was selected as the case study. Using SPSS software, first the assumption of normal variables was tested using the Kolmogorov-Smirnov test and then using the t-student’s test, the status of each of the components of the project management office was evaluated. The approved components of the project management office presented in three main components of planning (project portfolio), delivery (plan and project) and the center of excellence in the form of 17 sub-components.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>163</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>193</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>میرباقری</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mirbagheri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشگاه علم و صنعت، seyyedmohsen.mirbaghery@yahoo.com</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشگاه علم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>seyyedmohsen.mirbaghery@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عطاءالله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رفیعی آتانی</Family>
						<NameE>Ata Ollah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rafiei Atani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار و عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه علم و صنعت، دانشکده مهندسی پیشرفت (نویسنده مسئول)، rafeei@iust.ac.ir</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار و عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه علم و صنعت،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rafiei.at@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>دشتی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Dashti</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار و عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه علم و صنعت، دانشکده فناوری های نوین</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار و عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه علم و صنعت،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rdashti@iust.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دفتر مدیریت پروژه (PMO)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کنترل پروژه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سبد پروژه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سازمان‌ تحقیقاتی نظامی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>احمدوند، علی محمد، رزگرپور، حمید، ارسنجانی، محمدعلی، ارشادی، محمود، (۱۳۹۰)، &quot;نقش رویکرد مدیریت سبد پروژه در گسترش سطح عملکرد دفتر مدیریت پروژه&quot;، هفتمین کنفرانس بین المللی مدیریت پروژه، تهران، انجمن مدیریت پروژه ایران.##اربابی، هانی، کاشف حقیقی، محمدعلی، صبحیه، محمدحسین، نظر، احد، (۱۳۸۷)، &quot;بررسی موجودیت دفتر مدیریت پروژه(PMO)  در ایران: رویکرد توصیفی&quot;، چهارمین کنفرانس بین المللی مدیریت پروژه، تهران: گروه پژوهشی آریانا.##امانی زاده، اویستا، حسینعلی بیگی، مرتضی، تبریزیان، زهرا، کیوانلو، علی، (۱۳۹۵)،&quot; تعیین عملکرد دفتر مدیریت پروژه در پروژه‌های عمرانی کشور&quot;، دومین همایش بین المللی معماری، عمران و شهرسازی در آغاز هزاره سوم، تهران.##اسلامی، سعید، (1393)، &quot; ارائه مدل کاربردی جهت استقرار مؤثر دفتر مدیریت پروژه (PMO) در پروژه‌های عمرانی&quot; پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، دانشکده عمران.##حمید زاده، احسان، (1393)، &quot;طراحی و پیاده‌سازی دفتر مدیریت پروژه (PMO) و تعیین بلوغ و کارکردهای آن در سازمان‌های پروژه‌محور&quot;، پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد.دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، دانشکده عمران.##زیدی، حسن، الفتی، علی، مفتح زاده، الهام، (۱۳۹۸)، شناسایی و رتبه بندی عوامل مؤثر بر عملکرد دفتر مدیریت پروژه با رویکرد کارت امتیازدهی متوازن، چهارمین کنفرانس بین المللی مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه یزد.##زین العابدین، بهزاد، (۱۳۹۰)، &quot; دفتر مدیریت پروژه (PMO) در شرکت‌های هلدینگ پروژه‌محور&quot;، کنفرانس‌ سازمان‌های هلدینگ، سالن همایش رازی.##صالحی طالشی، محمد جواد، اربابی، هانی، حسینعلی پور، مجتبی، (1396)، بررسی دفتر مدیریت پروژه در سازمان های پروژه‌محور صنایع بالادستی نفت و گاز ایران و رابطه ی آن با موفقیت پروژه، فصلنامه بهبود مدیریت، پیاپی ۳۶، ۱۱۹ -۱۴۳.##فعال، شاهین، (1393)، &quot;دفتر مدیریت پروژه در سازمان های پروژه‌محور &quot;، چهارمین کنفرانس مدیریت پروژه.##میرهادی، محمد حسین، زارع اشکذری، جلال الدین، (۱۳۸۳)، &quot;دفاتر مدیریت پروژه، مفاهیم و کارکردها&quot;، اولین کنفرانس بین المللی مدیریت پروژه، تهران: گروه پژوهشی آریانا.##Amer, Magdi, Elayoty, Noha, (2018), Roadmap to Project Management Office (PMO) and Automation using a Multi-Stage Fuzzy Rules System, International Journal of Advanced Computer Science and Applications (IJACSA), Vol. 9, No. 10.##Andersen, Bjorn. Henriksen, Bjornar. Aarseth, Wenche, (2007), Benchmarking of Project Management Office Establishment: Extracting Best Practices. Journal of Management in Engineering. Vol. 23, No.2, 97-104.##Aubry, M., Müller, R., Hobbs, B., &amp; Blomquist, T, (2010), Project management offices in transition. International Journal of Project Management, 28(8), 766-778.##Aubry, M., Hobbs, B., &amp; Thuillier, D, (2008), Organisational project management: An historical approach to the study of PMOs. International Journal of Project Management, 26(1), 38-43.##Aubry, M., Hobbs, B., &amp; Thuillier, D, (2007), A new framework for understanding organisational project management through the PMO. International journal of project management, 25(4), 328-336.##Dai, C. X., &amp; Wells, W. G, (2004), An exploration of project management office features and their relationship to project performance. International Journal of Project Management, 22(7), 523-532.##Dsouza, Kevin C. Evaristo, J. Roberto, (2006), Project management offices: A case of knowledge-based archetypes. International Journal of Project Management. Vol. 26, No.5, 414-423.##Englund, R. L, Graham R. J. &amp; Dinsmore P.C., (2003), Creating the project office. A manager’s guide to leading organizational change. San Francisco: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.##Farmer, Charlotte Mitcham, Mazzuchi, Thomas A., Sarkani, Shahram, (2014). Integrating acquisition strategy and PMO capability: A catalyst for defense systems engineering transformation. Procedia Computer Science, 28, 744-753.##Gestao, F., (2015) Terzieva, M. &amp; Morabito, V ,The path towards discovering PMO: an exploratory analysis of the Italian banking sector. International Journal of Information Systems and Project Management, pp. 27–40.##Hill, G. M, (2008), The Complete Project Management Office Handbook, 2nd ed. Auerbach Publications, Boca Raton.##Hill, G. M, (2004), Evolving the project management office: a competency continuum, Information Systems Management, 21(4), 45-51.##Hobbs, B., Aubry, M. &amp; Thuiller, D, (2014), The project management office as an organizational innovation. International Journal of Project Management, 547–555.##Hofman, D. G. &amp; Bolles, D., (2015), PMO Framework and PMO Models for Project Business Management. Project Management World Journal. IV(I).##Julian, Jerry. Group, Julian Advisory, (2008), How project management office leaders facilitate cross‐project learning and continuous improvement. Project Management Journal. Vol. 39, No. 3, 43–58.##Kendall, G. I., &amp; Rollins, S. C., (2003), Advanced project portfolio management and the PMO: multiplying ROI at warp speed. Florida: J. Ross Publishing.##Oliveira, Ronielton Rezende, Martins, Henrique Cordeiro, (2018), Strategy, People and Operations as influencing agents of the Project Management Office performance: an analysis through Structural Equation Modeling, Gest. Prod., São Carlos Journal, V. 25, N. 2, Pp. 410-429.##Patona, Steve, Andrew, Barrie, (2019), The role of the Project Management Office (PMO) in product lifecycle management: A case study in the defence industrym, International Journal of Production Economics, Volume 208, Pp. 43-52.##Pemsel, Sofia. Wiewiora, Anna, (2013), Project management office a knowledge broker in project-based organizations. International Journal of Project Management. Vol. 31, No.1. pp. 31–42.##Rad, P. F., &amp; Levin, G. (2002), The Advanced Project Management Office: a comprehensive look at function and implementation. CRC press.##Robert K.Wysocki, (2009), &quot;Effective Project Management&quot;; Fifth Edition, Wiely Publishing,Inc Gerard M.hill, The complete PMO handbook.##Santos, V. &amp; Varajão, J., (2014), PMO as a Key Ingredient of Public Sector Projects’ Success - Position Paper. Procedia Computer Science, 1190–1199.##Unger, Barbara Natalie. Gemünden, Hans Georg. Aubry, Monique, (2012), The three roles of a project portfolio management office: Their impact on portfolio management execution and success. International Journal of Project Management. Vol. 30, No.5, 608-620.##Vitor,S, (2015), Project Management Office Models – a review. Conference on ENTER prise Information Systems / International Conference on Project MANagement / Conference on Health and Social Care Information Systems and Technologies, CENTERIS.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				