<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Effect of Organizational Citizenship Behavior on Enhancing the Organizational Agility by Emphasizing the Mediating Role of the Success of Organizational Resource Planning System (Case Study: One of the Industrial Organizations in Defense Field)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">zakeri</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Esmaeel</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Asadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Nasrin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rostami</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد، گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران جنوب</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Davarzani</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت کارآفرینی، دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The agile organization is designed to understand and anticipate changes in the business environment; it focuses on its own structure. Agility means successful identification of the basics of competition, coherence of resources and appropriate measures in the workplace. This research aims to analyze the effect of organizational citizenship behavior of employees on organizational agility and mediating the role of organizational resource planning system in one of the industrial organizations in defense field. In this applied-survey study, data analyze through structural equation model. 255 participants randomly selected from among 330 experts (based on Cochran formula) working in one of the industrial organizations in defense field. The content validity of the instrument was confirmed by the experts, and the Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient of all variables in the questionnaire was more than 70%. Hypotheses of the research through analyzing the coefficients of the structural model path show that the organizational citizenship behavior has a significant and positive effect on the success of the organizational resource planning system. Also, success of the organizational resource planning system has a significant effect on the components of organizational agility capability (including responsiveness to changes, competence, flexibility, and operational speed). It is concluded that managers of defense organizations, in order to enhance organizational agility, should pay attention to the enhancement of organizational resource planning system as well as organizational citizenship behaviors of employees.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>17</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>68</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>31</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_30627_4a2da4cb5c90026348502337188d8776.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Contextual, Structural and Behavioral Determinants of Psychological Empowerment</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Naser</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Asgari</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Samad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Barani</namePart>
				<affiliation>دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Maleki</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد حسابداری دانشگاه اسلامی آزاد واحد شهری ری، حسابرس دیوان محاسبات کشور</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Arasteh</namePart>
				<affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت MBA، دانشگاه پیام نور واحد دماوند</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Many managers and scholars have found that the availability of capable human resources is the only sustainable competitive advantage of the organization. Therefore, the main purpose of this research is to identify, rank and explain the contextual, structural and behavioral factors facilitating psychological empowerment. In this applied, descriptive and correlational study 270 participants selected from among 745 employees of a military organization randomly. Data analyzed through a confirmatory factor analysis to confirm the relationship between indices and components. Path analysis examines the assumed relationships, and one-sample T test examines the status quo of empowerment triple determinants in the aforementioned organization. Findings reveal that all three determinants have a significant effect on the empowerment of the staff. Accordingly, improving the status quo of these factors can help to facilitate the empowerment of staff. Also, the status quo of components of organizational culture, motivation, social dignity and employee training needs improvement in the organization</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>17</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>68</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>32</start>
					<end>52</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_30628_a62c6251e3bef4df89e0ccb506c57042.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Quality of Working Life of Military Organizations' Staff and Its Relationship with Defense Development (Case Study: A Military Organization)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Farhadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sheikh</namePart>
				<affiliation>دکتری مدیریت راهبردی دانشگاه عالی دفاع ملی</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In today&#039;s complex world, concept of quality of working life as one of the important variables in management has attracted attention of human resources specialists. Improvement of the indices of this area has increased job satisfaction, organizational commitment, development and growth of staff, as well as has reduced absenteeism, displacement and job quit of staff. It also leads to improving the performance and ability of organization to provide appropriate services to stakeholders; therefore, this research aims to examine the quality of working life of military organizations&#039; staff and its relationship with defense development. In this descriptive-applied study in purpose and survey in terms of data collection, a questionnaire was administered among 140 staff clerks of a military organization selected based on stratified sampling. Research data analyzed through descriptive and inferential statistical methods. Findings reveal that the characteristics of the occupational environment with an average of 3.236 (P = 0.000&lt; 0.05) are desirable but occupational characteristics with an average of 2.807 (P = 0.000&lt; 0.05) have a significant difference with the desirable mean, and it is not in suitable condition. There is a significant difference between different educational groups and there is a positive correlation between the quality of working life of employees and defense development</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>17</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>68</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>53</start>
					<end>76</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_30629_86240e10d8c731e25bb31223524a3844.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Thematic Analysis of the Internal Construction of the Armed Forces Power for Future Wars from the Point of View of the Supreme Commander in Chief (May Extend his Shadow)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sayyed Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghazi Mirsaeed</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر و مربی دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamidreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fartoukzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشیار مجتمع مدیریت و فناوری‌های نرم، دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Valivand Zamani</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار علوم دفاعی راهبردی، دانشگاه فرماندهی و ستاد آجا</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sayyed Asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ja&#039;fari</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار مجتمع مدیریت و فناوری‌های نرم، دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abolfazl</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bagheri</namePart>
				<affiliation>استادیار مجتمع مدیریت و فناوری‌های نرم، دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Due to the complexity of the world&#039;s security system and the emergence of new actors in the field of military threats, changing the defensive approach from the threat-based to the capability-based through the establishment of basic preparation and internal construction strength in the country&#039;s defense capabilities against future threats and possible future wars is found more urgent in compare to the past. The Supreme Commander in chief, at various occasions, has always scrutinized and analyzed the hidden and obvious dimensions and angles of threats and future wars, by carefully observing events and regional and trans-regional developments. This research aims to explain the internal construction of the Armed Forces power for future wars from the point of view of the Supreme Commander in Chief (May Extend his Shadow). In this qualitative research by using the method of the thematic network, as one of methods in thematic analysis, four themes of empowerment in technology and manpower; firm commitment and national unity; knowledge-based military power, and velayat-based spiritual power as comprehensive themes of the internal construction of the Armed Forces power for future wars are presented.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>17</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>68</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>77</start>
					<end>100</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_30630_17898c46fa51f89193a491dd63867a0e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Strategy Benchmarking of Challenges and Opportunities of Kurdistan Province in Defense of the Homeland</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه مالک اشتر</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parviz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aghaee</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری در جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی شهری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>One of the main issues in the field of military geography is the ability to defend the homeland and maintain territorial integrity in times of crisis or war. The history of the country shows that it must always observe the defensive conditions of the country and prepare itself for defense of the country in the face of regional and global crises. Kurdistan province is one of the areas that has witnessed various crises over the past 40 years, and the counterrevolutionary terrorist parties and groups have tried to use various methods, including soft war, guerrilla attacks, running disputes among Kurdish tribes and so on, to turn the province into a tense region. In this regard, this research aims to identify the most important challenges and opportunities in Kurdistan province, provide appropriate strategies, and classify them to reduce the region&#039;s challenges in defense- security field. In this descriptive- analytic research in method and applied-developmental research in purpose, data collected in a library and via documents. Findings based on SWOT and QSPM indicate that Kurdistan province has offensive positioning. It means the desirable situation of the region and the domination of the power and opportunity points on its challenges. By utilizing the abundant abilities of the Kurdistan, it eliminates existing challenges. At the end of this research, strategies and solutions based on the status quo of the region are presented to eliminate the current challenges</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>17</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>68</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>101</start>
					<end>127</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_30631_f176f862e81a1ee14a889e7c6202d32c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Evaluation and Comparison of Multi-Objective Meta-Innovative Algorithms for Solving the Problem of Optimization of the Production Design (Case Study: Optimum Design of Military Equipment)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Farhad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hadinejad</namePart>
				<affiliation>دکتری مدیریت تحقیق در عملیات، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، مدرس دانشگاه امام علی(ع)،</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ramzi</namePart>
				<affiliation>عضو هیئت ‌علمی گروه علوم کامپیوتر، دانشگاه قم</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mostafa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khajeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>عضو هیئت ‌علمی گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد قم</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In today&#039;s tense world, the existence of a strong and effective military force is considered as the strategic asset of every nation. Meanwhile, designing and updating military equipment and increasing their reliability and durability are particularly important. On the one hand, the mathematical model of optimization of military equipment at the design stage, due to the complexity and high volume of computing is in the Np-hard problems group, and requires meta-innovative methods for solving, and on the other hand it is in the multi-objective problem group, thus requiring the use of multi-objective methods. But the growing development and variety of multi-objective meta-innovative methods have challenged the choice of the appropriate algorithm in solving the aforementioned model. Therefore, the present study aims to review the modern algorithms, as well as provide a suitable method for solving the problem of military equipment optimization with the help of the sample. Thus, the necessity of mathematical modeling in optimizing the design of military equipment problem and the study and selection of the appropriate solution are the main goal of this research. In this applied- experimental study four algorithms (NSGA-II, MOPSO, PESA-II and MALO) were investigated and results with the help of six different indices were analyzed and evaluated. Meanwhile, combination of Hierarchical Process and Entropy Analysis (AHP-Entropy) approach were used to weigh the indices and the PROMETHEE method was used to evaluate the algorithms. The results emphasize the importance of the &quot;Runtime&quot; and &quot;Pareto Response number&quot; indicators on the priority of the MOPSO algorithm in solving the research problem.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>17</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>68</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>128</start>
					<end>163</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_30632_ca5f51c1b2ae06b147095c8538badc6e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>