<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Desirable Drone Distributions in Asymmetric Battlefield for Intelligence Mission</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Given the facilities and equipment possessed, drones are capable of carrying out various intelligence, reconnaissance , protection , target locating , and electronic overhearing mission considering priority in the use of facilities , in particular human resources . in other words, unmanned aircrafts as sophisticated technologies will play crucial rule in prospective wars. On the other hand, considering the superiority of the countries opposing I.R of Iran in terms of weaponry and intelligence services, the prospective wars will be asymmetric in nature such that winning over the enemy will depend on tactical initiatives and advantages of appropriate equipment. To this end, desirable drone distributions can be highly affective for both the defensive policy and national security of I.R of Iran. This study was an attempt to elaborate on desirable drone distributions to carry out the aforementioned missions in asymmetric wars. As an applied developmental research, the study was conducted based on library sources, interview with authorities and administering multiple tests measuring the effective drone indices for intelligence services. Meanwhile, one sample tested, investigation of the current and desirable status, and professional meetings were included in the research in order to identify desirable distribution configuration.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>46</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2012</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>11</start>
					<end>34</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3387_6ba091f85f6acc8874e8e10ed4450f64.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Strengths and Challenges Ahead of the Educational System in Iranian Military Universities</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This study attempted to investigate the educational status quo of Iranian military universities in order to develop an educational pattern or model of efficiency and effectiveness enhancement in two areas of theory and practice. To this end, the study tried to explore the strengths, weaknesses and challenges dominant in these universities. As an applied research in methodology,  and based on observation, case and field study paradigms, the study involved 79 elites familiar with educational and military issues composed of commanders,  professors and operators who are involved in the current and future mission, decision, limitations, problems, barriers and challenges. They were selected based on purposeful sampling method. The findings revealed that according to the elites, social model of education can be the best model for such universities. A comparative analysis of the current educational process with the Iranian Army educational statutory suggest that the universities should be enriched in terms of taking the advantages of the eight year Iraqi imposed war in curriculum development, effect of the trainings on flourishing the talent and creativity of the cadets, up to date nature of the syllabi attention on the individual talents creativity and development of the cadets, aptitude.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>46</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2012</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>35</start>
					<end>64</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3388_d41d8cd98f00b204e9800998ecf8427e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>On the Relationship between Organizational Justice and Staff Job Satisfaction(A case study in a military setting)</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Aimed at studying the relationship between organizational justice and staff job satisfaction, this study tried to investigate such a possible relationship between the job satisfaction and three main components of organizational justice (i.e., distributional, procedural and interactional). The study is descriptive- co relational in nature for which a questionnaire was used to collect data from the military staff members composed of 300 participants selected based on stratified random sampling. Pearson- product correlation coefficient, chi-square analysis and Friedman test were used for data analysis. The findings strongly supported positive correlation among the variables such that all three hypotheses were supported.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>46</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2012</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>65</start>
					<end>102</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3389_e3819f93bb2f1ec0846d11a1c30362f5.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Role of Social Asset in the Effectiveness of Knowledge Management: A Case Study</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Particular economic conditions dominating organizations make their competitive advantages no longer based on their explicit assets. What nowadays makes organizations be economically competitive are effective knowledge management and constant emphasis on factors effective on their knowledge properties such as social assets. In line with this issue, this study attempted to answer the question whether higher social assets entail knowledge management efficiency. The sample was randomly selected from Shahid Sattari Aviation University attended in this descriptive- field study through answering a questionnaire. The analyses run based on correlation coefficient and structural equation model revealed statistically significant correlation between the variables.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>46</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2012</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>103</start>
					<end>130</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3390_74119eac72a3f2956644d0be5b765917.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Investigation into and Prioritization of the Effective Factors on Job stress among the Military Commanders and Managers (A Case Study in an Iranian Army Ground Force)</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Job Stress in organizations is among the current problems at the global level which has received attention since the industrial revolution, promotion of mass production and development of government institutions and organizations where issues such as health, human values, comfort, stress, failure, frustration, moral crisis and lack of sense of success. As an applied, descriptive and field study, this research involved military commanders and managers from an Iranian military setting (I.e. 03 Ajabshir), who answered a questionnaire. The data were analyzed based on Pearson-product correlation coefficient. The findings revealed that Job Stress is caused and mainly affected by: Job satisfaction, organizational factors (environmental factors, role contradiction, role ambiguity and work load), non-Job factors (family and social affairs), personal factors, and mental as well as physical pressures. Conclusively, Job stress and satisfaction correlated 0/78, while the highest correlation rate (I.e. %54) was related to personal stress and the lowest was that of Job stress. Meanwhile, there was positive correlation between organizational, non-Job, personal and behavioral factors of stress and the commanders and managers job stress. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>46</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2012</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>131</start>
					<end>154</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3391_bdf193485df079af6e4b5ef20e57cbe3.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Role of Internal Affairs in US- Imposed Preemptive war against Iraq in 2003</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2012</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Iraq has experienced various crises during recent decades which are commonly rooted in two sets of factors: internal and external. The atmosphere fouled following 11, September at global level, contributed the shaping of a foreign policy of emergence, threat, and force at the USA political atmosphere. The disintegration of USSR and introduction of a new threat called world terrorism made the USA exercise a preventive war doctrine against the suppression of international terrorist threats. To shed light to this issue, this developmental descriptive research was conducted. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>46</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2012</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>155</start>
					<end>186</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3392_bd83d7192db3ba6dec940804173f709a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>