<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[An Investigation of the Effective Factors Enhancing the Interactional Skills of Commanders with Soldiers Affiliated to the Military Training Centers of the Ground Force of Iranian Army]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Skandari, Karim]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghassabi Khushe mehr, Naghi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Interactional Skills]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Discourse Skill]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Listening Skill]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Feedback Skill]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This study was run in a bid to investigatethe effective factors enhancing the interactional skills of commanders with soldiers affiliated to the military training centers of the Ground Force of Iranian Army in Tehran. To do so, due to the limitation of statistical population, the study was conducted through engaging total population of 82 company and battalion commanders affiliated to the military training centers of the Ground Force of Iranian Army. This study was also run through administering a valid and reliable questionnaire for data collection. To analyze the data, both descriptive and inferential statistics were run. Descriptive statistic was run in terms of data reduction, stratification and interpretation. To test research hypothesis, the inferential statistic was run through Spearman test, Pearson r and Stepwise Regression Analysis. The findings revealed that there is no significant correlation between demographic characteristics and interactional skills of commanders with soldiers affiliated to the military training centers of the Ground Force of Iranian Army in Tehran. Meanwhile, there is significantly positive correlation between organizational, environmental and individual factors and interactional skills of commanders with soldiers. Moreover, in terms of variance in the first stage of analysis, individual factors (28%) and on the second stage, environmental and organizational factors 35 percent of total variance of interactional skills of commanders with soldiers were indicated.   ]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_14364_7b9209620cbd4b53660292196b70e1cc.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Obstacles Ahead of the Precise Performance Reporting of Operational Budgeting in the Army of the IRI]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohseni, Asghar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Maleki, Gholam Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Operational Budgeting]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[performance assessment]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Reporting Obstacles]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[the Army of the IRI]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Planning, making a cost calculation and performance assessment are identified as the three main elements of operational budgeting. Making an attempt to evaluate the operational progress and also to achieve their goals, the accurate and precise reporting in conformity with realities, precise, scientific and practical mechanism and procedures are taken as the basic and crucial necessities of a successful operational budgeting. This study was an attempt to identify obstacles ahead of the precise performance reporting of operational budgeting in Iranian army and also aimed to explain solutions to overcome the obstacles. These obstacles are classified in 4 groups including technical, skill, structural and mechanism obstacles. In this study, identification of obstacles’ indicators and evaluation of their significance was also investigated. This study was conducted in terms of mixed method. For data analysis, both qualitative and quantitative method including interview via expert consultation, document and library resources and mean test method were run. The mean tests of 131 questionnaires including 12 questions were estimated using Cronbach Alpha method releasing 0.887 The findings of the questionnaire and expert consultation revealed that the skill obstacles are of most significance while technical, structural and mechanism obstacles respectively enjoyed the significance. In a bid to overcome the obstacles, some suggestions are made based on the obtained results and academic elites ’consultation. These obstacles can be removed in the light of observing the suggestions made.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_14365_49cc333f963a1530eaca576d2ccb5a8d.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Sporting Requirements in Military Training Centers From Soldiers’ Point of View and the Explanation of Their Attitudes]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Saadat talab, Mohammad-Bagher]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghahreman Tabrizi, Korush]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Norayee, Tahmores]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sporting Activities]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Soldiers]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Military Training Centers]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The direct relationship between scientific development and practical improvement of physical preparedness of armed forces and martial power is an indication of today’s necessity of physical education in the armed forces. This study was an attempt to describe the attitudes and sporting requirements of the military training centers of the Ground Force of Iranian Army from soldier’s point of view. As an applied and descriptive field study, this study was conducted through engaging sample population of 510 soldiers affiliated to the military training centers of the Ground Force of Iranian Army who were selected based on stage cluster sampling method. This study was also run through administering researcher-made questionnaires consist of two elements including attitude towards sporting activities and need study of these activities which were adjusted based on Likert scale range of five values. The study was conducted in terms of exploratory- factor analysis and its content validity was assured via consultation with academic elite and sport managers of military training centers while the reliability was estimated using Cronbach Alpha method releasing (a=0.92). The findings orderly revealed that the soldier’s attitudes toward sporting activities are following desirability, respectively: sporting activities (4.32 ±0.60), optional sport (professional), and general sport (leisure), military, martial and compulsory sports. Moreover, these sports are chosen as appropriate and necessary exercises in military training courses. Findings also revealed that soldiers’ attitude is highly desirable toward sporting activities and their needs and interests are closer to exhilarating exercises far away from strict sports in military settings.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_14366_8be9935b62389efaacb61479f525ffdf.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Identification of Commanders’ Worthiness in the Units of Brigade of Student at Imam Ali Military University]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shabani, Raziye]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hojjati, Akram]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghorbani, Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[: Worthiness]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Commanders]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Imam Ali Military University]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[students]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This study was an attempt to identify the commanders ` worthiness in the units of brigade of student at Imam Ali Military University from senior students ` point of view. The study was conducted in terms of exploratory- factor analysis and descriptive study. For this purpose, 80 participants including senior students of Imam Ali Military University were selected based on accessible sampling method and formula of sample size determination. In a bid to identify commander`s worthiness in brigade of student of Imam Ali Military University from student`s point of view, questionnaires were administered among participants in order to collect required data for data analysis. Data analysis was run through exploratory- factor analysis and its validity was assured in terms of content while the reliability was estimated using Cronbach Alpha method releasing 0.86 The findings orderly revealed that the effective factors on commander`s worthiness are following priorities, respectively:  the first factor: logical thinking (7.222) with 15 indicators, the second factor: being open to criticism (4.233) with 4 indicators, the third factor: academic attitude (4.155) with 8 indicators, the fourth factor: innovation (3.983) with 7 indicators, the fifth factor: strategic management (3.412) with 3 indicators, the sixth factor: team work and joint management (2.639) with 3 indicators have been identified as the most effective factors affecting commander`s worthiness and these six factors indicated 64.11 percent of total variance.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_14367_cba641788e56db4558df0762b78378c5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Feasibility Study of the Implementation of Personnel Organizational Learning at Imam Ali Military University]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational learning]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Learning Organization]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Imam Ali Military University]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This study was an attempt to investigatefeasibility study of the implementation of personnel organizational learning at Imam Ali Military University. The study was conducted through a descriptive field study, to do so, 40 organizational learning questionnaires (Nif 2001) were randomly distributed among personnel of deputies of research and educational affairs and also faculties of Imam Ali Military University. The reliability of the questionnaire was estimated using Cronbach Alpha method releasing 83% through SPSS analysis and its validity was confirmed by the experts. As a descriptive statistic, both mean and standard deviation analysis were run to analyze the data. To generalize the data, both variance analysis and one sample t-test were run. The findings revealed that the obtained t is significant in the following components at the level of p<0.01 and it is significantly feasible to implement the personal organizational learning, these components including joint prospect (t=2.699), organizational culture (t=3.108) and development of staff worthiness (t=2.738). Moreover, the obtained t is not significant in the following components and it is not feasible to implement the personal organizational learning, these components including teamwork and group learning (t=.572), shared knowledge (t=1.462), systematic thinking (t=1.702) and joint leadership (t=.876). The findings also revealed that the obtained t (t=2.397) is significant at the level of p<0.05 and it can be concluded that it is feasible to implement the personal organizational learningat Imam Ali Military University.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_14368_3cef5b0586bf7fc815adcfdede0f60c2.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Obstacles Ahead of the Establishment of Internal Auditing Unit in Iranian State Universities]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rahmani, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghashghaei, Fatemeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Maddahi, Azadeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Internal Auditing System]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Obstacles Ahead of Establishment of Internal Auditing Unit]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[State universities]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This study was an attempt to investigate obstacles ahead of the establishment of internal auditing unit in Iranian State Universities. The study was conducted through engaging and investigating 193 sample population of auditors and expert’s opinions in academic settings and those professionals in non-academic settings. To identify the Obstacles, both statistical tests including one sample T test and factor analysis were run. The findings revealed that the obstacles ahead of establishment of internal auditing units were classified in 3 main groups including: 1. Legal, organizational and cultural obstacles, 2. Lack of knowledge, training and appropriate coordination, 3. Obstacles ahead of Internal Auditing personnel. Cultural, legal and organizational obstacles including restrictions related to the culture and rules governing the social and organizational context. Moreover, lack of knowledge, training and appropriate coordination indicated limitation of educational aspects affected by internal departments of an organization and professional institutions of community. In addition, the obstacles a head of personnel including shortage of specialists in auditing system of academic settings as well as unemployment of independent and experienced auditors in auditing units. The findings of this study are among determining factors of evolutionary planning of internal auditing units in public sectors and it may contribute to further developments and success.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_14369_2ea10ee2f220dd3cfdf544bbd42cc5cd.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>