<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Consequences of Managerial Stability in Iranian Public Organizations]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Danaee Fard, Hassan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Feizi, Azam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ahmadi, Hanieh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Managerial Stability]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Managerial Instability]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Politicization]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Public Organizations]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Public administration is identified as the means of implementation of public policy and is also taken as a crucial factor of success or failure of public administrators in implementing public policy making. The success or the failure of public administrators is deeply affected by the managerial stability or instability. Moreover, managerial stability is taken as the two-dimensional phenomenon which carries both positive and negative consequences. This study was an attempt to investigate the consequences of managerial stability in Iranian public organizations. For this purpose and also in a bid to identify the positive and the negative consequences of managerial stability, in terms of qualitative and quantitative investigation, the study was conducted through administering a questionnaire and also conducting an interview. As a mixed study, this study used a questionnaire and interview to collect the required data and its content validity was assured via expert and elite consultation while the reliability was estimated using Cronbach Alpha method releasing 0.98. Finally, 28 positive and 25 negative consequences of managerial stability were also identified in this study. Additionally, the crucial consequences of managerial stability in Iranian public organizations were respectively identified including implementation of long-term policies and planning as well as resistance to change.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_23755_bc46a6e1fd947acb7ed4f21f16c95a88.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Optimal Site Selection of a Military Encampment of Imam Ali Military University through Utilizing Mixed Method Including GIS and Linear Programming Model]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hanafi, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Lotfi, Ahmad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Abbaszadeh, Nasser]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[: Military Site Selection]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Military Encampment]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Optimal Sites]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Geographical Information System]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Imam Ali Military University]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Military site selection is identified as a technique for investigating military site capabilities in terms of a sufficiency and the appropriateness of ground, site relevancy with urban and rural utilities as well as appropriate selection of military sites. Moreover, selection of appropriate military sites requires precise assessment of ground through utilizing appropriate models and tools. This study was an attempt to select an appropriate site for military encampment of Imam Ali military university through utilizing a mixed method including GIS and LPM. For this purpose, this study was also aimed to identify and then prioritize the optimal sites of military encampment of Imam Ali military university. Additionally, in a bid to identify the effective factors affecting the site selection of military encampment, the study was also conducted through administering a questionnaire and also conducting an interview among geographical and military experts and elites. Moreover, the ARC GIS data base was obtained through digital and topography maps and then weighed through AHP decision making model. Thereupon, 10 military sites of encampment were emerged as a result of AHP and also ARC GIS data processing. Having collected the data and analyzing them based on AHP and also in an attempt to maximize the security coefficient of selected sites for military encampment, linear programming model was also run in this study. The factors including financial constrains and limitations, policies of university and commanders’ decision were also investigated in this study. Finally, from among 10 military sites of encampment including mountain, desert and jungle encampment, an appropriate site was identified and selected for military encampment.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_23756_39b426e15823c11ba63c10d4e50f8fd5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Information Resources Management against Attacks and Imperfect Equipment through Utilizing Quantum Physics]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[koranian, seyed isa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Parvizee, Ali-Asghar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quantum Paradigms]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quantum Management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mono-Photon]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quantum Cryptography]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Information Security]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Simulation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Q-Bit]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[A chemical warfare and weapons found an extensive use in the World War I, on the contrary, during the World War II; the creation of atomic physics world as well as the birth of molecular and atomic specialists and scientists had a great and wider significance to the world in terms of scoring victory against the enemies. Nowadays, future warfare is predicted to change to the information warfare by the military specialist and the experts. Moreover, the countries will gain the upper hand in terms of military superiority, providing they equip themselves with the experts and specialists in information technology sciences. This study aims at investigating the organizational management as well as storing and also transferring the information securely based on the latest scientific and technological developments in military organizations. In this study, paradigms changes in managerial issues were highly emphasized and the quantum paradigms were also investigated. Additionally, at the early stages of investigation, different protocols of quantum cryptography were also compared in this study. Thereupon, the weak and the strong points of each protocol were emerged as the result of physics analysis and stimulation techniques. Moreover, Quantum management is capable of optimally utilizing the quantum innate disorders. The findings revealed that in terms of enhancing the quality of communication equipment in confidential information management, the organizations should concentrate more on financial and human resources than confrontation with interception.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_23757_901f3bb785e5294e5c1f98e2a84582d7.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Relationship between Human Capital of Faculty Members and the Academic Achievement of Students at Shahid Sattari Air Force University]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Malek Por, Dariush]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mahjub, Hassan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[: Capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[human capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[academic achievement]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Shahid Sattari Air Force University]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[As an applied-developmental and also descriptive field study, this study aims at investigating the relationship between human capital of faculty members and the academic achievement of students at Shahid Sattari Air Force University. For this purpose, out of 940 participants from Shahid Sattari Air Force University, 274 students were selected based on stratified random sampling method through running Cochran formula (0.05). The study was also run through administering a Naderi Human Capital Questionnaire for data collection procedure. The reliability of the questionnaire was estimated using Cronbach Alpha method releasing 0.974, and its content validity was confirmed by the human capital experts. To analyze the data, both descriptive and inferential statistics including Kolmogorov-Smirnov test, one sample t-test, Anova test and also partial correlation coefficient were also run in this study. The findings revealed that in terms of comparison and ranking of human capital of faculty members at Shahid Sattari Air Force University, the faculty of electrical engineering stood below the average level, while the faculty of management, flight and aviation enjoyed the average level with no significant difference. The findings also revealed that in terms of comparison and ranking of academic achievement of students, the faculty of management stood at the top of the ranking while the faculty of electrical engineering, flight and aviation enjoyed the average level. Consequently, there is a significant relationship (r=0.223) between the total indicators of human capital and academic achievement at Shahid Sattari Air Force University. Finally, the academic achievement of students could be gained in the light of enhancing the components of human capital including cognitive competence, Meta-cognitive and interactional-emotional components among faculty members]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_23758_d345e1e1aeb6843e83f3d994b0066f12.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Identification and the Prioritization of the Effective Factors Affecting the Soldiers’ Satisfaction of Services Provided by Military Units Based on Kano Model]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tarin, Hamdollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rezaee, Bijan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[: Kano Model]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Customer Satisfaction]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Basic Requirements]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Motivational Requirements]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Performance Requirements]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[As an applied and exploratory-descriptive field study, this research aims at identifying and also prioritizing the effective factors affecting the soldiers’ satisfaction of the services provided by military units based on Kano model. For this purpose, the study was conducted through administering a questionnaire among population sample of 152 soldiers affiliated to the military units of Iranian army in the city of Kermanshah who were randomly selected based on stratified sampling method. The questionnaire includes 32 factors designed by the interviewers for data collection. The reliability of the questionnaire was estimated using Cronbach Alpha method releasing 0.89, and its content validity was confirmed by the experts. To analyze the data, in terms of classification and prioritization, both frequency distribution and non-parametric Friedman test were also run in this study. The findings revealed that all basic, motivational and performance requirements and factors are effectively affecting the soldiers’ satisfaction of the services provided by military units. These components and factors orderly including vacation incentives and encouragements for soldiers for their seriousness in military tasks, commanders’ attempts to solve the soldiers’ problems as well as meeting their needs, demands and requirements, and finally providing useful sporting equipment for soldiers]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_23759_dc79e726595138fbeacb85e9b1acd30b.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Developing a Model for Assessment and Ranking of the Construction Projects based on Occurrence Probability of Risk and its Effects on Construction Performance
(A Case Study; Department of Engineering and Construction Projects in Military Setting)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shafiei Nikabadi, Mojtaba]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shafiei Nikabadi, Mohsen]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hosseini, Sayyed Mohammad-Hassan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ranking]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Construction Projects]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Risk Management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[AHP]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[VIKOR]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Making a huge investment on construction projects in the armed forces could lead to the fulfillment of the basic requirement and also the achievement of strategic purposes. For this purpose, some risks must be identified at the early stages of construction projects. To do so, this study was run in a bid to identify and also assess the risk management of construction projects in the armed forces through utilizing a mixed approach including multi-criteria decision-making methods. This method is taken as an appropriate means of risk analysis of construction projects and is also aimed to identify the low risk construction projects. To do so, in the early stage of investigation, the risks of construction projects were emerged as a result of library study. Thereupon, in the initial stage of suggestive approach, the construction risks were identified and then weighed up based on occurrence probability through running analytical hierarchy process as well as interviewing with elites and experts. Additionally, in the second stage of investigation, low risk construction projects were identified through investigating the effects of identified risks on construction performance and also through running VIKOR method. The findings revealed that in terms of occurrence probability, the risks of supervision, design, and construction projects and also the risk of financial issues stood at the first and second rank of indicators with coefficient of 0.38 and 0.28 respectively. Moreover, the risks related to the geographical and economic events stood at the third rank of indicators with coefficient of 0.13. Finally, a list of ranked construction projects was made through investigating the effects of risk on construction performance.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_23761_441a3dbda9e50aa6e8e7acca786793df.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>