<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>41</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Proposing an Appropriate Model for the Establishment of Learner Organizations in the Army of the I.R. of Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائة الگوی مناسب شکل‌گیری سازمان‌های یاد‌گیرنده در ارتش جمهوری اسلامی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>11</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>42</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">3829</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Learning is taken as a competitive advantage of organizations to win over their rivals, and learner organization is the one which takes the advantages of continuous learning of all its staff members in order to create, share and apply knowledge so that it can suitably react to the environmental changes. Authorities characterize a learner organization as follows: personal capacities intellectual models, joint perspective, team-based learning, a disciplined thinking, leadership, organization culture and knowledge structure and management each of which is measurable based on a set of criteria
Generally this study aims at proposing an appropriate model for the establishment of learner organization in the Army of the I.R. of Iran. As an applied and case study, it first offers the nine-fold criteria of identifying learner organization along with the scales of each criterion. Then, the professors offering courses in the Army universities were questioned as to verifying the criteria. Subsequently the Army units were evaluated based on these validated criteria. The findings sustain that the Army can be considered as a learning organization and the affiliated units are characterized by the highest percentage of learner organization in terms of the following criteria: leadership, disciplined thinking, organizational culture, personal capacity, intellectual model, team-based learning, Joint perspective, and knowledge structure and management.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یادگیری، مزیّت رقابتی سازمان‌ها برای پیشی گرفتن بر رقبا است و سازمان یادگیرنده، سازمانی است که از یادگیری مستمر همة افراد سازمان، برای ایجاد، کسب، تقسیم و به کارگیری دانش استفاده می‌کند تا نسبت به تغییرات محیطی، واکنش مناسب نشان دهد. برخی از مهم‌ترین خصوصّیاتی که صاحب‌نظران برای سازمان یادگیرنده بیان نموده‌اند، عبارتند از: قابلیّت‌های شخصی، الگوهای ذهنی، چشم انداز مشترک، یادگیری تیمی، تفکّر نظام‌مند، رهبری، فرهنگ سازمانی، ساختار و مدیریت دانش و هر یک از این معیارها، با چند شاخص قابل ارزیابی  هستند. هدف کلّی این تحقیق، ارائة الگوی مناسب شکل‌گیری سازمان‌های یاد‌گیرنده در ارتش جمهوری اسلامی ایران است. تحقیق حاضر، از نوع کاربردی و به روش موردی زمینه‌ای  است. در این تحقیق ابتدا معیارهای 9 گانة تشخیص سازمان یادگیرنده و شاخص هر یک از معیارها ارائه شد و سپس استادانی که در دانشگاه‌های آجا مدیریت تدریس می‌نمایند، مورد پرسش قرار گرفتند و این معیارها تأیید شدند؛ آنگاه یگان‌های آجا با این شاخص‌ها مورد سنجش قرار گرفتند و مشخص شد که ارتش می‌تواند سازمان یاد‌گیرنده باشد و یگان‌های ارتش، معیارهای سازمان یادگیرنده را (با بالاترین درصد) بدین شرح دارا هستند: رهبری، تفکّر نظام‌مند، فرهنگ سازمانی، قابلیّت شخصی، الگوهای ذهنی، یادگیری تیمی، چشم انداز مشترک، ساختار و مدیریت دانش.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارتش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">یادگیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان یادگیرنده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چشم انداز مشترک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قابلیّت شخصی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوهای ذهنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تفکّر نظام‌مند</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3829_d9e3ff5e17bd71456b2b1b73457a5040.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
