<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A study of the effectiveness of parameters improving Technical legal  &amp; infrastructures of developing E – government in Iran based on G2G  Approach]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2010]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[E- government]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[technical infrastructure]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[legal &legislative infrastructures]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[organizational capacity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[open political – democratic atmosphere]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[E – government is the most controversial issues standing second the Industrial revolution as it is identified as a powerful instrument as to improving internal efficiency of governments, quality improvement in service rendering and encouraging public participation. As the biggest organization in each state, government covers many other bigger organizations. Development of E – government can facilitate   inter-sectoral relations and achievement of society objectives.
It seems that technical–legal barriers ahead of E–government development have caused Iran remain in the list of third world states. under development of E – government has had likely consequences such as deficiencies in  implementing coordinated democracy with the people's needs and also failure in decentralization of power and reorganization of servicing.
As an applied and analytic study, this research aims at measuring the effectiveness of parameters improving technical - legal infrastructures of developing E – government in Iran, ranking their and finally offering solutions to the development of it in Iran.
Dematel technique was employed to determine the effective and affected parameters. The data analysis show that "organizational capacity" and "open political- democratic atmosphere" should be given priority in the fields of technical and legal – legislative, respectively, so that, the process of E-  government development in Iran can be facilitated .]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3843_35928aabdd54b4a27811e255243c939d.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Role of Culture of Commanding Hierarchy in the Efficiency of Military Organizations (A Case Study: Imam Ali(PUH) Military University)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2010]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[culture of commanding hierarchy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[organizational efficiency]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[strategies of military & scientific training]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Organizational culture of commanding hierarchy in which hierarchical superiority is a norm and staff members are continuously observed and managed, they are obliged to obey the orders of the senior staff members. This study was an investigation into the role of culture of command hierarchy in the efficiency of military organization. For this purpose 340 senior cadets form Imam Ali Military University were randomly selected. Following data collection, the data was analyzed based on three-dimensional cross- table and regression [via SPSS], the findings revealed that strategies of military training and those of scientific education improve organizational efficiency about %4 and %2, respectively. It is, then, concluded that a culture of commanding  hierarchy coordinated with the strategies of both scientific and military training can lead to organizational efficiency.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3844_82442bd5ddc1aff963678a954d70b277.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Identification of Factors Affecting the Satisfaction of Web-Based Virtual Training Users Based on Kano's Model  (A Case Study in Two Virtual Universities in Tehran)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2010]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Web based virtual training]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Kano's model]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[user satisfaction]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Development of E-learning and E-teaching is a promise for realization of far-fetched aspiration of the last two decades in Iran. Wide spread skill needs of knowledge – based or IT– based societies along with the sustainment of traditional training system fail to be met thereby. To this end, this study was an attempt to identify factors affecting satisfaction of web-based virtual training users based on Kano's model. Then, a conceptual model of the factors based on two models including experimental and general ones was implemented among  the users in two virtual–training universities in Tehran, selected randomly factors such as training variables human specifications, user mediator, infrastructure, Content and interaction. chi – square analysis of the ideas of  71 students collected  through a "Likert" scale scored and already validated questionnaire via SPSS revealed that" user mediator  and interaction" has had the highest effect on their   dissatisfaction. ]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3845_0220ecfe2cb1ed639aa261efe2882f67.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Study of the Relationship between two Organizational Elements as Structure &amp;Culture and Knowledge Management in Imam Ali (PUH) Military University]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2010]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In the era of wisdom in which knowledge is identified as the most important capital of every organization and society, knowledge management is the main function of organization intending to act as learner organizations.
Many of the organizations willing to survive and protect their competitive situation follow knowledge management approach. Success of this approach depends on the fact that various organizational parameters including structure and culture can enjoy certain characteristics and be cohesive and coordinated. Existence of gap and lack of coordination between these factors prevent implementation of knowledge management. The study focused on two key variables: ''organizational structure'' and ''organizational culture'' in relation to knowledge management and ''knowledge creation'' and ''knowledge transfer'' as two key activities of knowledge management. Methodologically, the study is descriptive and field in nature and in order to collect the data, questionnaire and library materials were used. The participants were selected from among the commanders, managers and professors of the university holding at least BA or BS degrees.
The findings revealed significant relationship between the variables. Then organization should be looked at as a system and totality of the factors should be taken into account. Analysis of organizational factors in terms of requirement in relation to knowledge management is the first and most important measure which can have a strong ground for further studies.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3846_8adca2defc5b738551ae8708eacbc8df.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[On the Relationship between Emotional Intelligence and Dutifulness among the Cadets of Imam Ali (PUH) Military University]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2010]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[EQ]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[EIQ]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[dutifulness]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Imam Ali military university student]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Research findings support important role of artificial intelligence in the success and efficiency of organizations. Similarly, research shows that dutifulness is one of the variables affecting management and commanding. Preliminary studies sustain higher correlation between dutifulness and emotional quotation. Given the fact that the cadets are appointed to managerial positions in their official service lives, conducting study on the relationship between these two variables can entail practical and effective implications as to their commanding quality.
To this end, Barons' emotional quotation and Neopi-Rs' personality questionnaires were administered among 507 stratified- randomly selected cadets. The data were put into SPSS software and statistical analyses like pearson-product correlation, one–way ANOVA and linear regression were run. The findings sustained significant correlations (p <0.01) between the variables. However, the findings revealed negative correlation between the two variables and years of education. Regression analysis proved, U2 covariance between the two variables and then teaching on E1 can improve the rate of dutifulness to the extent that a cadet with higher E1 level is supposed to be characterized by planning power, highly active, purposeful, and determined and willful.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3847_9fd08c00da9b8897891a16e8511aea74.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Study of the Factors Improving Spirituality among Cadets (A Case Study:Imam Ali(PUH) Military University)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2010]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spirituality]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cadet]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Imam Ali Military University Repeat of a research project granted]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Quick growth of spirituality in academic setting, Work place, organizations and its implications for leaders, managers, and heads of human resource departments is of great significance. To this end, it was hypothesized that spread of spirituality in academic settings and work places can result in individual creativity and prosperity as well as in organizational coordination. This study was an attempt to study the factors contributing spirituality among the cadets of Imam Ali Military University .To this end, a set of variables including: behavior of idea - political staff members, communication with clergymen, Quranic education, attending congregational prayer, role of commanders and social values were investigated.
Descriptive correlation analysis of the data along with chi-square analysis by SPSS revealed following statistics as the rate of their effectiveness:
Behavior of idea – political staff members = %82.7
Communication with clergymen=% 86.2
Quranic  &amp; Nahjolblalaghe education =%82
Congregational prayer and other religious events = %78.4
Social value=%62.4]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3848_e958eee0d89184c9e1082d9f1c392fe9.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Study of Job Erosion Predictor Variables among the Personnel of the IRI Army]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2010]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[job erosion]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[emotional analysis]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[personality metamorphosis]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[sense of individual accomplishment]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[workplace- organisational atmosphere]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[job charectristics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[individual commitments]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In oder to investigate factors affecting job erosion among personnel, a sample of 300 staff members form the army of Iran was selected based on cluster sampling.
To collect the data, Maslach's job erosion questionnaire addressing variables such as emotional analysis, personality metamorphosis and individual sense of accomplishment and a researcher-made queslionnaire covering four factors including orgaisational atmosphere, workplace conditions, job characteristics, and individual commitments was validated, then employed. The data were run via SPSS .
The findings revealed that there is as significantly negative correlation between job erosion and its variables )emotional analysis personality metamorphosis and sense of individual accomplishment) with other parameters like organisational atmosphere workplace conditions, job characterstics and individual commitments simultaneous regression analysis also revaled that 28.4 of the erosion variance is attributed to the four sided- factors among which the work place conditions and indivdual commitments have had the highest effect.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3849_852d4cb0a67ff9e3dcb96307e5b6fd34.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>