<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Designing the Pathological Model of Implementation of Public Policy in Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ebrahim</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hajipoor</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Candidate in Policy Making Management, Tarbiat Moddares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Lotfollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Forozandeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor in Public Administration, Tarbiat Moddares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Danaei-Fard</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor in Public Administration, Tarbiat Moddares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor in Public Administration, Tarbiat Moddares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This study is an applied-developmental and also qualitative research in terms of purpose and data collection procedures. The study was conducted through data-based analysis and grounded theory. This theory is systematic approach and qualitative study in terms of developing theory in which rationality can be elicited in the light of selecting the method of taking advantages of the participants ’point of view as well as investigating them and reaching conclusions on those viewpoints. This study was an attempt to design the pathological model of implementation of public policy in Iran. For this purpose, the study was conducted through administering face to face interviewand posing some questionstaking 30 up to 90 minutes among 20 populations of policy makers, administrators and professors of policy making regarding the obstacles ahead of implementation of public policy making in Iran. The sampling was conducted in terms of theory. At first, the set of primary concepts were collected through encoding process and then some components were emerged as a result. In an axial coding step, the relationship among these components were determined in a coding paradigm and in the selective coding step, each of these components were explained respectively. In terms of comparison, the advantage of this study concerning the pathology of implementation of public policy making is that the presented model is comprehensive and action-based model. This model has worked on the most effective components of unsuccessful implementation of public policy making and also made an attempt to identify the obstacles ahead of it as well as the challenges ahead of implementation of public policy making. Finally, the consequences of unsuccessful implementation of public policy were also explained in this study.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>58</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>23</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_16809_8f626657a51acb7f5f372c7903fe42a6.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Investigation of the Effect of Authentic Leadership on Organizational Identification
(A Case Study of the Personnel of Defensive-Industrial Units)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mostafa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Lotfi Jalalabadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Candidate in Public Administration, Payame-noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali-Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mooghali</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor in Public Administration, Payame-noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Tahere</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Feizi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor in Public Administration, Payame-noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amir-Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Amirkhani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor in Public Administration, Payame-noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Sense of personnel identity in an organization exerts a powerful influence over the behavior and the attitudes of staff as well as enhancing non-physical martial power of the armed forces. In a bid to overcome the environmental challenges, managers should strengthen the organizational identity of personnel; therefore, understanding the effective factors affecting the Sense of personnel identity in an organization became the important duty of managers. As a causal research, this study aims to investigate the effect of authentic leadership style on organizational identification. For this purpose, the study was conducted through engaging randomly selected populations of 400 personnel affiliated to the defensive-industrial units in Tehran. The reliability and validity of the instrumentations were assured in the early stages and then data analysis was run in terms of structural equation modeling. The findings of the research hypothesis revealed that all dimensions of authentic leadership style are effectively affecting the organizational identification. Finally, some practical suggestions are made by researcher.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>58</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>24</start>
					<end>42</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_16810_9a9a8b787542b9d4eaecf8df9c094a8c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Risk analysis in Military Organizations
(Identification and Prioritization of Critical Risks in Air-Defense Bases)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali-Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mooghali</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor in Public Administration, Payame-noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Saeid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abdolmanafi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor in Business Administration, Payame-noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Salehi</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in Public Administration, Payame-noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shahnaz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mahmud Saleh</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in Public Administration, Payame-noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Risk management is taken as one of the basic requirement in modern armies. In a dynamic and technological environment,identification and prioritization of risks is not feasible unless we implement the scientific and logical processes. As an applied and descriptive field study, this study was an attempt to identify and prioritize the risk affecting the continuity of operations in radar and missile sites as well as electronic identification. This study was conducted in a military center. For this purpose, the study was also conducted through engaging 49 experts and specialist from commanding and management departments of air-defense bases in the provinces of Fars, Bushehr and Khuzestan. The study was also run through administering three types of RFMEA questionnaire for data collection procedures. To analyze the data, both descriptive and inferential statistics were run through SPSS analysis. The William fine technique was run for risk assessment while the error analysis was run to measure the effect of risk failure. The findings revealed that risks of maintenance and manpower management respectively enjoyed the highest potential risks in terms of significance with coefficient of 20, 15 percent. Moreover, the physical security and work safety stood at the lowest potential risks with coefficient of 9 percent. Consequently, possibility of occurrence is among the most important factor affecting the critical risk. Finally, ten components were identified and prioritized as the highest potential risk affecting the continuity of operations in air-defense bases</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>58</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>43</start>
					<end>69</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_17023_333a006f387a9909c5388c4d58249f42.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Military Site Selection of Deployment of Combat Service Supporting Units through Utilizing FIS in Nasrabad Region in Isfahan Province</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Keykhaei</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in Remote-Sensing and GIS, Lecturer at Imam Ali Military University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Kazem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rangzan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor in Remote-Sensing and GIS, Shahid Chamran University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Behrooz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bahram- Abadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in Geomorphology, Academic Member at Imam Ali Military University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ayyoub</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Taghizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in Remote-Sensing and GIS, Shahid Chamran University, Ahvaz</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>As a damage and casualty-alleviating measure, military site selection is among the key issues for military men and is of crucial significance for the military commanders. Logistic is taken as the most fundamental pillar for every military conflict and also known as the backbone of all warfare. Site selection and concentration are among the most important factors in any logistic designing. High capabilities of geographical information system including high-level of processing and managing the useful information helps planners and commanders in various stages of operational analysis. This study was an attempt to identify the suitable and appropriate sites for deployment of logistic units in front of martial and battlefield prior to any physical intervention by utilizing GIS and fuzzy multi-criteria decision making procedure. To do so, the region was checked in terms of slope, drainage, observation, concealment, soil, land utilities, road, and proximity to maneuvering units, structure, proximity to helicopter landing sites and distance from light artillery units of the enemy. Having collected the data and merging them based on fuzzy system, the fuzzy modeling operations were run in a MATLAB environment through applying the principles. Thereupon final output was obtained through defuzzification process and then run in GIS environment. According to the field assessment, the findings revealed that the foothill zones and areas, mountainous semi-high areas and militarily geomorphologically significance regions have been extracted successfully and it confirmed that the role of GIS and its integration into multi-criteria decision making procedures in running military analysis was effective in reducing expenditure, time and casualties</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>58</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>70</start>
					<end>94</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_17024_eaffb3e77c5bd114bc0b0663efa22d54.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Requirements of Financial Discipline from Viewpoint of the Supreme Leader-In-Chief; May His Shadow Extend</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Khosrow</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Esfandiyari Safa</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD in Defense Management , Supreme University of National Defense</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Habibollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Dehghan</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Candidate in Financial Administration, Lecturer at Imam Ali Military University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In the light of reducing unnecessary cost and expenditure and also avoiding luxury- oriented life and extravagance, the financial discipline is identified as an important requirement of every organization. As an applied study and data-based analysis, this study aims at investigating the financial discipline in which the desired results will not be achieved unless observing the financial discipline. For this purpose, in terms of sample population, the study was conducted through investigating the supreme leader’s discourse and statements (May his shadow extend) during the years of 1994 until 2015. Therefore, 20 components of financial discipline were identified. These components including: savings, lack of wastage and extravagance, reforms in judicial organizations, highlighting the role of supervisory organizations, coordination among the three forces, prioritization of cost and expenditure, utilization of financial resources in production rather than consumption, fighting against financial corruption, social discipline, trusting to God and having courage, having piety and righteousness, staying away from luxury-oriented life and avarice , identifying weak points and strong points , planning , coordination of actions with thought and beliefs , making a decisive and effective decisions , faithful and righteous managers , legal-oriented managers and lightening the size of government as well as avoiding the formation of private monopolies. The findings revealed that overall dimensions of data-based analysis resulted in requirements of financial discipline; these requirements are then prioritized through administering a questionnaire via AHP approach. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>58</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>95</start>
					<end>118</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_17025_a10b88d9bfb14d69f07ae19d59e1355a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Investigation of the Effective Factors Affecting the Organizational Agility of Imam Ali Military University (from Commanders’ Point of View in the Units of Student Brigade)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Akram</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hojjati</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Candidate in Educational Administration, IAU, Central Tehran Branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Roghaye</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hojjati</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Candidate in Educational Administration, IAU, South Tehran Branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghorbani</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in English Language Teaching, Lecturer at Imam Ali Military University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This study was an investigation of the effective factors affecting the organizational agility of Imam Ali military university from commanders ` point of view in the units of student brigade. To do so, 44 questionnaires were randomly distributed among commanders of student brigade. This study was also run through administering an organizational agility questionnaire for data collection. The questionnaire includes 32 questions and covers seven dimensions including flexibility, accountability, culture of change, integration and complexity, speed, mutual cooperation and managerial functions. To analyze the data, descriptive statistic was run through central and dispersion index and to test research hypothesis, the inferential statistic was run through Pearson correlational coefficient, T test of two independent groups, one-way analysis of variance and SPSS analysis. The reliability of the questionnaire was estimated using Cronbach Alpha method releasing 80% and its validity was assured in terms of content. The findings revealed total mean (4.89) which represented a relatively favorable situation of organizational agility of Imam Ali Military University. The findings also revealed the following effective factors affecting the organizational agility such as the dimension of managerial functions which stood at the highest average of belief indictors including commander’s awareness, Belief in transparency and belief in doing things through systematic ways and networking. Moreover, the dimension of mutual cooperation stood at the second rank of indicators including consultation with the others, increasing the skills and knowledge of commanders through using organizational technologies, having joint multiple capabilities of commanders as well as improving their relationship with soldiers.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>58</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>119</start>
					<end>144</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_17026_c825053a1856c4dcacae1160853b2068.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>