<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Mathematical Model for Managing Military Commodity Crisis and a Simple Numerical Method for Solving it]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Karamali, Gholam-Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hashemi, Amir]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[crisis management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Random Processes]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Partial Differential Integral Equation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Numerical Methods]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Recently many improvements have been achieved in modeling financial crisis management through mathematical models. Can it be possible to utilize the new improvements in modeling in managing the military crisis? This study aims to generalize this issue. The probability of zeroing the goods stock is true in a Volterra partial differential integral equation. The exact answer to the aforementioned model, often as an infinite expansion of known functions, exists; so solving this problem is possible by numerical methods. Hence, in this paper a new and simple method offers based on random processes to solve the aforementioned problem using the R &amp; D research method. To this end, we use the Lagrange expansion as an approximation of the answer. Then, using the same local methods, we can convert partial differential integral equation into an algebraic device and solved it. Provided examples indicate the efficiency and accuracy of proposed method. Finally, this method is used to analyze a model of military crisis management that the exact answer is not known]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29918_5dcc6026eba2889caa35d941706d27ef.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Analysis of the Interaction of Effective Factors on Innovation of Defense Organizations, Using Interpretative Structural Modeling (ISM) Approach]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Dehghani Poodeh, Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Pashaei Houlaso, Amin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation of Defense Organization]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Interpretative Structural Approach]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Because of the expanded missions in various areas such as operation, military, command and control, technology, construction and maintenance of military equipment and weapons, and even in logistics, administrative and financial services; innovation in defense departments is one of the key issues. This study aims to analyze the interaction of effective factors on innovation of defense organizations using the Interpretative Structural Modeling (ISM) approach and attempts to answer the main question which factors can be useful for innovation of defense organizations. In this applied study the method of research is analytical-survey in correlational type. A researcher-made and reliable questionnaire (r=0.980) containing 100 items were distributed among 150 purposefully selected academic experts who are familiar with the issues of innovation, organizational innovation, public administration, educational administration. Since the data were normal, collected data were analyzed via factor analysis through LISREL software and were leveled through Interpretative Structural Modeling Approach (ISM). The main results of the research are as follows: To achieve organizational innovation in defense organizations following items are important: proper working environment stimuli; internal organizational factors; common insights and goals among employees; motivational and supportive programs; IT administration; people administration; knowledge management; education and learning process of staff; research and development; management features; being process-oriented; foresightedness; creativity management; innovation in behavior; innovation in process; innovation in product; innovation in market and strategy.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29920_5eb883a89f76895d5f24c879dcd69a11.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Review and Analyze the Content of War, Jihad and Military Education in the Quran Emphasizing the Comparison with Divine Religions "Judaism, Christianity and Zoroastrianism"]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[ashrafi, abolfazl]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Akbar Hosseini, Sayyed Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quran]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Divine Religions]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[War and Jihad]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Militia]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Military Education]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In this article, the attitude of the Quran to the phenomenon of war, jihad and the explanation of the indices and functions of the military education of militia with a comparative view of the divine religions "Judaism, Christianity and Zoroastrianism" have been investigated. The main question is that considering the divine nature of the origin of the Qur'anic knowledge, especially in comparison with the aforementioned divine religions, what is the quantitative and qualitative approach of the Quran to war and jihad and what indices and functions were emphasized in the development of military men and militias? The answer of these questions could explain the false attitudes towards the Islamic and Qur'anic approach to war.In this descriptive research the methodology is library- documentary. It is done based on a mixed methodology (quantitative - qualitative), sociological approach and Holy Qur'an’s commentators. According to the research method, the statistical population includes the sacred books of divine religions. Data collected based on content analysis, categorization of concepts and quantitative statistical calculations such as comparing the frequency of war and violence with other divine religions. The main purpose is to present a realistic picture of the war and jihad related topics in the Qur'an. It is concluded that Qur'an presents a comprehensive, realistic, peaceful and excellent picture of war, as well as it considers dignity, authority, excellence and spiritual evolution of human in the structural principles and Qur'anic functions of the war. This view to the war leads to the training of militias in to jihad which are based on divine motives and the goal of developing the divine values,​away from inhuman violence. Other results of the research show that Quran has devoted to war and its corresponding concepts, quantitatively and qualitatively fewer than other divine religions. Statistical data express that the volume of the teachings of the divine books on the war 12.4 times in compare to the Qur’an. Accordingly, this research through a realistic interpretation of the Qur'anic doctrines related to war and jihad can reveal and eliminate biased, non-expert analysis and anti- Islam currents which have recently been prevalent in the world. In addition, this research will provide useful insights on the charge of violence and bellicosity in Islam]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29921_c90d7c498bebbb0f91b146bbb186c429.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Analyzing the Role of Joint-border Bazaar’s in Promoting Borderland’s Security. Case Study of Sardasht and 
Piranshahr Border Bazaars]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hamzepoor, Razgar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Fakhri, Siroos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Border]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Border Regions]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Security]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Welfare status]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Joint- border Bazaar]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[One of the characteristics of forming border bazaars as one of the important levers in creating employment and developing economic activities is the security issue. Border bazaars with respect to their structure have managed the issue of border security to some extent; and have affected on the economic conditions of the border regions considerably. This field article aims to study the effects of Sardasht and Piranshahr border bazaars in West Azerbaijan province on promoting the security of the borderlands’ regions using a quantitative research method. Theoretically, library and documentary method containing note, administrative reports, articles of the institutions and ministries and the relevant organizations were used; and in practice, survey method containing questionnaire, interview, and observation were applied to collect data. Findings reveal that in “kileh” and “Tomarchin” as two sample bazaar there is a significant, direct and two-way relationship between the security and development. According to security- development theories, areas with high economic development indicators have higher security coefficient than undeveloped regions; Thus paying attention to the development and security of the border regions and increasing the welfare and economic income of the border residents through the legal economic activities and support and investment of governments, have a positive effect on the security functioning of the border and border residents  ]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29925_f70fc55b9c4a4cc645e2441be79f17bf.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Measuring the Research Performance of Iranian State University through Utilizing Analytic Hierarchy Process and Network Data Envelopment Analysis]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghomi, Hamid Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rahmani, Morteza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khakzar, Morteza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Measurement of Research Performance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Analytic hierarchy process (AHP)]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Network Data Envelopment Analysis]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[( NDEA)]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Higher military education centers play a prominent strategic role in developing professional capabilities of Iranian society and consequently examining the performance of these centers have a wider significance for all mangers. This study was an attempt to measure the research performance of the Iranian state university through utilizing analytic hierarchy process and network data envelopment analysis. For this purpose, authentic research indicators were identified and selected through investigating related literature review and also interviewing with elites. Thereupon, in an attempt to weigh the indicators and also combine the research indicators with macro indicators, analytic hierarchy process was run in this study. Moreover, the research involves collecting data from university macro-indicators; the collected data were assessed and analyzed through running network data envelopment analysis. This study is an applied, descriptive and also qualitative in terms of purpose and data collection procedures and analysis. The findings of the research inputs and outputs revealed that there is a lack of relative research efficiency at two colleges of this university.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29931_8988f7112801d3187f431ebcf03d1f76.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the Motivational Factors of Imam Ali University Cadets for Participation in Sports and Physical Activities]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[beglari, samad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghaedi, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohammadyari, Sajjad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sports Motivation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sports Activities]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Imam Ali Military University]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This study aims to investigate the motivational factors of Imam Ali University cadets for participation in sports and physical activities. In this descriptive-analytic study, based on Morgan's table, 330 members were selected from among 2500 cadets of Imam Ali University randomly. To this end, Markland &amp; Ingledew Sports Motivation Questionnaire was distributed and 285 of them were returned. Although the validity and reliability of this questionnaire have been confirmed in several studies, it has been checked again to ensure that it is consistent. Confirmatory factor analysis was used to determine the structural validity and the experts’ opinions were used to determine the content and face validity. Based on factor loading and level of T statistics, all factors were considered as a suitable predictor for the considered index. The internal consistency of the research variables was examined using Cronbach's alpha through a preliminary study with 30 participants. In order to organize, categorize and summarize raw data, descriptive statistics and inferential statistics, one-sample T-test, and analysis of variance, were used. It is concluded that the motivation of power and motivation of medical coercion have the highest and lowest score, respectively. Therefore, students' motivational needs must be met in order to increase their willingness to participate in these activities.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29932_4a21c01609d5e935173cc0a259b6abe0.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>