<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>61</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Components of Resistive Economy from the Viewpoint of the Supreme Leader-In-Chief; May His Shadow Extend</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مؤلفه‌های اقتصاد مقاومتی از دیدگاه مقام معظم رهبری (حفظه الله تعالی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>60</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>84</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22376</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خسرو</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسفندیاری صفا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت دفاعی، دانشگاه عالی دفاع ملی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حبیب‌اللّه</FirstName>
					<LastName>دهقان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت مالی، مدرس دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In an attempt to explore the components of resistive economy from the perspective of Imam Khamenei (the Supreme Commander-In-Chief; May His Shadow Extend), this applied study was conducted based on data-based analysis and grounded theory. For this purpose and also in order to identify and explain the components of the resistive economy in thought of the supreme leader–in-chief, in terms of statistical population, the study was conducted through investigating the Imam Khamenei’s (May His Shadow Extend) discourse and statements between the years of 1993 and 2015. To address this issue, the features of components were identified and then classified through administering face to face interview with elites, experts and the commanders of Iranian army and also through library study. Thereupon, the conceptual model and paradigmatic pattern were emerged and developed as a result of data analysis. Moreover, 27 crucial components of resistive economy were emerged through investigating the viewpoint of the Supreme leader–in-chief; May His Shadow Extend. These components including knowledge-based atmosphere, making improvements to consumption model, the security of crucial and strategic issues, reducing the dependency on oil industry, advertising activities, reliance on national production, elimination of poverty, creating positive economic balance, growth and development, sovereignty of law, making attempts to pull the economic out of recession, privatization, self-sufficiency in agricultural products, extraction of mines and avoiding the crude selling, establishing the knowledge-based organizations, expurgation of the economic laws, building national and public self-confidence, consumption management, reducing the gap among people, consumptionism, extravagance, denunciation of luxury oriented-life, contentment in the life and making attempts to economize, appreciating the cultural value of work, building the developmental chain of science, scientism and finally providing comfort and protection for elites.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;این مقاله با هدف پاسخگویی به این سؤال صورت پذیرفته است که مؤلفه‌های اقتصاد مقاومتی از دیدگاه فرماندهی کل قوا چیست؟ این پژوهش از نوع کاربردی است که با روش داده‌بنیاد انجام گرفته است. به منظور احصاء مفاهیم، مؤلفه‌ها و تبیین مؤلفه‌های اقتصاد مقاومتی در اندیشه‌های مقام معظم رهبری، جامعه آماری تحقیق، بیانات حضرت آیت اللّه خامنه‌ای طی سال‌های 1372 تا 1394 در نظر گرفته شده است. تمامی بیانات بدون نمونه‌گیری مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. با استفاده از داده‌های کتابخانه‌ای و مصاحبه حضوری با خبرگان و فرماندهان نزاجا این ویژگی‌ها طبقه‌بندی شد. مدل (الگوی) مفهومی بر اساس تحلیل‌ها استخراج گردید و سپس با استفاده از تمام مراحل پژوهش الگوی پارادایمی طراحی شد. در شاخصه‌های اقتصاد مقاومتی از منظر فرماندهی معظم کل قوا، 27 شاخص کلیدی احصا شد که عبارت‌اند از: دانش‌محوری، اصلاح‌ الگوی ‌مصرف، امنیت اقلام راهبردی و اساسی، کاهش وابستگی به نفت، تبلیغات، تکیه بر تولید ملی، ریشه‌کنی فقر، ایجاد تراز اقتصادی مثبت، حاکمیت قانون، مبارزه با رکود اقتصادی، خصوصی‌سازی، خودکفایی در محصولات ‌کشاورزی، استحصال از معادن به دور از خام فروشی، فعال شدن شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان، تنقیح قوانین اقتصادی، اعتمادبه‌نفس ملی، مدیریت مصرف، کاهش فاصله طبقاتی، مصرف‌زدگی، اسراف، نکوهش تجمل‌گرایی، قناعت، ارج‌دهی فرهنگ کار، ایجاد زنجیره تولید علم، علم‌گرایی، ایجاد فضای آرامش برای نخبگان، و حمایت از نخبگان.&lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اقتصاد مقاومتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اقتصاد دانش‌بنیان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توسعه اقتصادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش داده‌بنیاد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حضرت امام خامنه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اقتصاد درون‌زا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_22376_8129e5387d159d775adc86e83cbbf435.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
