<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Evaluation of Educational program at military setting and a proposal of an Appropriate Model (Focusing on an evaluation of English language program at Imam Ali University)</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Evaluation of an educational program is of significance in that it can contribute to improvement of the program and achievement of its objectives. This study, to this end, aimed at evaluating academic educational programs at military setting in general and that of general English language at Imam Ali University as an example of the undergoing programs so that in light of exploring strengths and weaknesses it can be improved and can be generalized the findings in a bid to secure its external validity. The study accommodated both quantitative and qualitative research paradigms in design such that the qualitative data were collected through questionnaires, interview and observation and they all indicated poor concordance among three main components of an educational program including goal-setting, method and needs analysis. The quantitative side of the study implemented through administering various tests given the objectives of the program indicated non-significance academic achievements by freshmen, which sustains the findings of the qualitative side. Not only do the findings necessitate further studies in other educational areas but also they highlight significance of compatibility and balance among the three mentioned parameters in all educational areas on one hand and that of general English in Imam Ali University on the other.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>43</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>11</start>
					<end>42</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3405_a293249c26808844e4e70147d4c589e7.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Relationship between sound Enforcement of Law and Social Order</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This study purposed to investigate relationship between &quot;sound enforcement of the law and social order&quot; or better to say the possible effect of the former on the latter one. To do so, the study focused on identifying major criteria both variables and the nature of their relationship so that the significance of one of the most crucial variables affecting social order can be explored. As a field study based on Delphi technique, the study was conducted based on a three-phase questionnaire administered to 55 experts in social order and safety field holding at least MA degrees and enjoying 20 years job experiences. The finding indicated that the aspects of law enforcement including non-discriminatory enforcement, equality before law and law as a final arbiter have had respectively the highest effect on the aspects of social order such as public trust, effective social control, internalization of social rules and principles.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>43</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>43</start>
					<end>74</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3406_559786c2f7544ca54715a209f132f810.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Investigation of the Role of website of the Army of the I.R of Iran in term of selecting recruit for the Army universities based on Technology –based Recruitment Model</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>One of the main concerns of successful organizations nowadays is sound utilization of available digital facilities through internet as to the objectives and interests of an organization. Given the significance of such technological facilities, role of internet in the process of admission and recruitment of applicants is so crucial that addressing it can offer effective solutions and a lot of benefits for superb organizations including the Army of the I.R. of Iran. In line with this claim, this study was an attempt to investigate the website of the Army and its role in recruiting the applicants of the Army universities on the basis of technology-based recruitment model. The finding revealed that parameters such as “enjoyment”, “easy access”, and “perceived effectiveness” of the website bring about “self efficiency” for the applicant and his positive attitude as to technology. Along with such an attitude, totality of these variables enhances “organizational perception” and ultimately “organizational attractiveness” among the applicants. Consequently, increased numbers of applicants register for the entrance exams of the Army universities and show willingness to be recruited. To carry out this study, a sample of applicants for the Army universities attempted a questionnaire and the model was verified through testing the research hypotheses and administering accuracy, adjustment, homogeneity and divisibility tests.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>43</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>75</start>
					<end>102</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3407_cbd98273e9f720a83d7c154367712eca.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Enhancement of Equipment Efficiency in the Army through Applying predictive, forecasting and Comprehensively Productive Network-based maintenance and Repairment Methods</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Significance and exclusive specifications of military equipment, problems in finding access to them along with a highly costly access have drawn attention to their maintenance and repairment. Given the resultant damage and costs from applying inappropriate and unscientific maintenance and repairment methods, this study was conducted in order to explore factors enhancing their efficiency in the army and the distinctive effect of each factor on the efficiency. To this end, criteria of the efficiency were identified through library research, interview with authorities and administering a four-part questionnaire. Having estimated the reliability and the validity of the questionnaire, the researcher distributed it among the participants. The data were fed to SPSS 18 for processing whereby the effect of predictive, for casting and comprehensive network-based maintenance and repairment on the enhancement of the efficiency of was investigated. The findings entailed a set of constructive suggestions in line with the objective of the study. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>43</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>103</start>
					<end>134</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3408_1bab63acd24d7004288700346dc8fe62.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Reconsideration of the Distribution of the Depots of the Army in an Asymmetric War in terms of passive Defense Principles</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Support and logistics in asymmetric war purposes to render a comprehensive support to arm forces under all circumstances and military operations through employing equipment and method of any sorts matching the governing conditions and operations in order to minimize vulnerability and enhance sustainability. Parameters such as quickness, innovation, accuracy and quickest retaliation build foundations of logistics in asymmetric operations. Given the record of the deployment of the Ground Force depots which dates back to more than three decades and emerging axes of threat, this study aimed at investigating the extent of vulnerability of the current depots in order to suggest an appropriate deployment model. As an applied research in purpose and a case- field study in design, the study focused on the principles of passive defense. The findings based on data collected through a questionnaire and interview with experts revealed that the eastern part of the country requires establishment of depots.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>43</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>135</start>
					<end>164</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3409_617d6e74f20d717b86fce41d97242471.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Role of social Assets in Facilitating Knowledge management Process</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In a knowledge- based era, knowledge management is considered as the most prominent function for the organizations seeking for optimum utilization of these highly precious and intangible resources. Obviously, accomplishment of knowledge management projects necessitates proper and supportive grounds and circumstances among which human-social resources play a determining role which builds the rationale behind this study. As a descriptive and correlational research, this study was done to seek the involvement of 274 managers and experts from Iranian Oil Distribution Company. Being randomly selected out of a total population of 950members, the findings showed that the various dimensions of social assets play a very crucial and significant role in Knowledge management process. The findings also entailed in a number of practical suggestions for the experts and managers in charge.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>43</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>165</start>
					<end>188</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3410_7ad460dedc996d6a314642aaee07d12c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Reconsideration of the Distribution of the Depots of the Army in an Asymmetric War in terms of passive Defense Principles</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2011</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>43</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2011</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>189</start>
					<end>206</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3411_01892874c5227d8a2ba2ab00530662c7.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>