<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Comparison of the Effect of the Ranger and Commando Courses on Physical Readiness and Body Composition of Cadets at Imam Ali Military University</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hekmatollah Ehsanbakhsh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ehsanbakhsh</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in Physical Education, Lecturer at Imam Ali University, (Corresponding Author) Ehsanbakhshh@yahoo.com</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sajad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadyari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D in Physical Education, Imam Ali University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Passing the hard courses is one of the most important parts of military education. At present, there is no accurate information about the impact of Ranger and Commando courses on physical readiness indexes and body composition index of the cadets. Therefore, this study aimed to examine the effect of Ranger and Commando courses on physical readiness indexes and body composition index of the cadets at Military University. In this study, 75 cadets were selected randomly and divided into three groups: Ranger training group (25) and Commando training group (25) and a control group (25). Then they were compared in two stages of pre-test and post-test. The participants of the two groups took part in courses of Ranger and Commando for eight weeks, including 6 days a week. They were tested with a 1.6-mile running test for aerobic performance, a two-way running for agility measurement, and a sit up and pull up to measure muscular endurance. Body composition index was also obtained by dividing the weight into kilograms by height to meter. Both groups showed a significant increase in strength and endurance of shoulder girdle muscle, abdominal muscles, flexibility and agility and showed significant reduction in weight, body composition index in compare to control group. There was no significant difference in intra-group and inter-group variations between the Ranger and Commando training groups. The findings of this study showed that eight weeks of Ranger and Commando training improved aerobic performance, agility and muscular endurance, and body composition index of cadets.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>18</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>70</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>27</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_33759_ce377c472ef27cea91539658949f66d8.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identification and Clustering of the Indicators of Priority of New Defensive Product Development Projects by Main Components Analysis Method based on Data Mining</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sadegh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shahbazi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D Candidate in Industrial Engineering, Alborz Campus, Tehran University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bozorgi-Amiri</namePart>
				<affiliation>School of Industrial Engineering, College
of Engineering, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In Defensive R &amp; D centers due to resource constraints, there is no possibility for development of all new defensive products projects, so prioritizing these projects is considered as a necessity. Multi-dimensional decision making is one of the methods that can be used in this regard. To apply this method, one of the basic prerequisites for identifying the appropriate indicators, by taking into account the defense approach, is categorizing and eventually weighing them. In this applied study in terms of purpose, data collected through descriptive-survey method. The statistical population of this research were selected from among the directors and experts of the R&amp;D centers in Defense Industry as well as managers of the product design projects. In this paper, the indices used to prioritize development projects for new defense products explored after reviewing the background of the research and extensive field interview with experts from R&amp;D centers of several Defense Industries in five areas of defense, organization and strategy, knowledge and technology, risk and market. Since the number of identified indicators was widespread, this eventually increased the error of project selection. Therefore, in order to reduce the indicators, the Data Mining technique was used by the Main Component Analysis method. This method was applied on 42 identified indicators, with the help of scores given on 21 projects. Finally the number of indicators was reduced to 25 in 5 areas. Then the title of each cluster was determined according to clustering of the indicators. Also, after weighing, the defensive zone with the weight of 0.29, and the market area with a weight of 0.09, received the highest and lowest priority, respectively.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>18</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>70</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>28</start>
					<end>52</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_33760_e90f090d2ef23124d0c0c14c4b5886d7.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Jihad Administration Components in the statements of Imam Khamenei (May Extend his Shadow)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Eftekhari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate professor at Imam Sadiq(a.s) University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zargarzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D Candidate at Supreme National Defense University (Corresponding Author)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shamshiri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Political Science Researcher</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This research aimed to define the components of Jihad Administration based on the scholarly statements of the Supreme Leader (May Extend his Shadow) and provide them to the administration community of the country to implement and utilize his guidelines in the Islamic society. After the Islamic Revolution, especially in the years of the Holy Defense and at present, one of the administration practices specifically addressed by the Supreme Leader (May Extend his Shadow) has been the &quot;Jihad Administration&quot;. The jihad administration derived from Islamic teachings and utilized the energy and potential of human resources, which is based on the spiritual values ​​and beliefs. In this administration method, regardless of odd formalities, Managers try to align their capabilities with their subordinates&#039; potential power to achieve defined goals quickly. In fact Jihad administration is a style derived from indigenous thinking and in accordance with the cultural and social requirements of the Islamic Republic of Iran. This study examined the components of jihad management in the statements of Imam Khamenei (May Extend his Shadow). In this applied-developmental research, data collected by examining the existing records (in his website) and through library studies. In the case of Jihad administration, 18 statements, 4 components and 32 sub-components were considered as: The concept of jihad administration with 3 sub-components; Requirements for Jihad administration with 10 sub-components; Features of Jihad administration with 6 sub-components; Achievements of jihad administration with 13 sub-components.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>18</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>70</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>53</start>
					<end>87</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_33761_12ff54200cfca7ffb1ffdcfb3d7684cf.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identifying and Determining the Effective Factors in Assessment of Decision in C4I System</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parviz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">zeaghami nezhad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D Candidate at Supreme National Defense University, parvizz2020@gmail.com</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Elhami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professional Ph.D in Compound-joint Operations. Academic Member, Khatam al-Anbia Air Defense University.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Majid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rajabpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D Candidate at Supreme National Defense University, rajabpour51@gmail.com</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The assessment of the decision implies a comprehensive and systematic review and evaluation. It is achieved through the implementation and comparison of the decision with the defined standards and criteria. This study aimed to investigate the effective factors in assessment of decision in C4I system. As an applied research in purpose and descriptive-survey research in terms of data collection, 94 participants selected from among all employees of the Air Defense Integrated Network of the Country who served in Tehran Province in 2014 (N = 327) randomly by using the Cochran formula. The data were collected through a researcher-made questionnaire whose validity was confirmed by the experts. Reliability of the instrument was estimated based Cronbach alpha formula (r=86%). Data analysis was run using factor analysis method. Findings revealed, these factors were classified into five major groups. The first and the most important factor was the &quot;decision process&quot; by explaining 15.46% of the variance. This factor along with information, technology, communication, environment and individual factors explained totally, 50/71% of the variance. Finally, according to the results, the assessment of decision cycle is proposed for assessment in C4I system.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>18</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>70</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>88</start>
					<end>116</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_33762_e38e4c1880ccec7c16520b5e8d75ef2c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identifying and Determining the Effective Factors in Assessment of Decision in C4I System</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amir</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Valafar</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A student in M.B.A, Payame Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad-Taghi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Amini</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor in Strategic Administration, Payame Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahmood</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Gholami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor in Commercial Administration, Shahid Sattari Aeronautical University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The assessment of the decision implies a comprehensive and systematic review and evaluation. It is achieved through the implementation and comparison of the decision with the defined standards and criteria. This study aimed to investigate the effective factors in assessment of decision in C4I system. As an applied research in purpose and descriptive-survey research in terms of data collection, 94 participants selected from among all employees of the Air Defense Integrated Network of the Country who served in Tehran Province in 2014 (N = 327) randomly by using the Cochran formula. The data were collected through a researcher-made questionnaire whose validity was confirmed by the experts. Reliability of the instrument was estimated based Cronbach alpha formula (r=86%). Data analysis was run using factor analysis method. Findings revealed, these factors were classified into five major groups. The first and the most important factor was the &quot;decision process&quot; by explaining 15.46% of the variance. This factor along with information, technology, communication, environment and individual factors explained totally, 50/71% of the variance. Finally, according to the results, the assessment of decision cycle is proposed for assessment in C4I system.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>18</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>70</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>117</start>
					<end>145</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_33764_42232468f0b1614756839b316c220cad.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Performance Assessment of Graduates from a User's Perspective (In Case Study of a Military University)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abbasian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor in Industrial Engineering, Imam Ali University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shirmohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in TEFL, Lecturer at Imam Ali University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azizi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D candidate in Educational Administration, Shahid Beheshti University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Omid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Milani</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in Educational Administration, Shahid Beheshti University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This study aimed to &quot;assess the performance of graduates of a military university&quot;. In this applied and descriptive-survey study, 134 participants selected from among 240 users of the university (consisting of commanders of operational and educational battalions and parallel units) who have direct contact with university graduates through random cluster sampling. The data collection tool is a graduates&#039; abilities assessment questionnaire. This questionnaire is based on Rashidzadeh&#039;s (1391) model that includes six dimensions of graduates&#039; abilities in scientific-cognitive, spiritual, military-educational, social, intellectual and physical areas from the perspective of users. Validity of the questionnaire was confirmed by experts and its reliability was 0.86 using Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient. For fitting the model, LISREL software was used; and for analyzing the questions, Descriptive statistics including frequency, percentage, mean and standard deviation, and inferential statistics including one-way student t-test and Friedman test were used by SPSS software. The results of this research show that the performance of university graduates is significantly higher than the average and in a favorable situation. Also, the ranking of functional six-dimension abilities showed that the physical abilities and scientific-cognitive abilities have the highest and lowest rank among the abilities of their performance indicators, respectively.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">1735-5699</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>18</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>70</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>146</start>
					<end>180</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_33765_a0cf5c69289f4c4af87d4dae2df2955f.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>