<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>43</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Reconsideration of the Distribution of the Depots of the Army in an Asymmetric War in terms of passive Defense Principles</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بازبینی نحوه چیدمان آمادگاه‌های نزاجا در جنگ ناهمتراز با رعایت اصول پدافند غیرعامل</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>135</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>164</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">3409</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Support and logistics in asymmetric war purposes to render a comprehensive support to arm forces under all circumstances and military operations through employing equipment and method of any sorts matching the governing conditions and operations in order to minimize vulnerability and enhance sustainability. Parameters such as quickness, innovation, accuracy and quickest retaliation build foundations of logistics in asymmetric operations. Given the record of the deployment of the Ground Force depots which dates back to more than three decades and emerging axes of threat, this study aimed at investigating the extent of vulnerability of the current depots in order to suggest an appropriate deployment model. As an applied research in purpose and a case- field study in design, the study focused on the principles of passive defense. The findings based on data collected through a questionnaire and interview with experts revealed that the eastern part of the country requires establishment of depots.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف آماد و پشتیبانی در جنگ ناهمتراز، پشتیبانی همه‌جانبه نیروهای مسلح در کلیه حالت‌ها و در هر شرایط و هر نوع عملیات نظامی با هر نوع ابزار و روش، متناسب با شرایط و انواع عملیات به منظور کاهش آسیب‌پذیری و ارتقای پایداری است. عواملی همچون چالاکی، بدیع بودن، دقت و پاسخگویی با حداکثر سرعت مبنای شکل‌گیری و نقش آماد و پشتیبانی در پشتیبانی عملیات ناهمتراز هستند. با توجه به اینکه استقرار آمادگاه‌های فعلی به بیش از سه دهه باز می‌گردد و محورهای تهدید جدیدی به وجود آمده است؛ در این مطالعه سعی شده است با بررسی آسیب‌پذیری آمادگاهای موجود، پراکنش مناسبی برای آمادگاه‌ها پیشنهاد شود. در این پژوهش، نوع تحقیق کاربردی و روش تحقیق موردی- زمینه‌ای با هدف پراکنش آمادگاه‌های نزاجا با توجه به جنگ ناهمتراز با تأکید بر اصول پدافند غیرعامل می‌باشد. نتایج حاصل با استفاده از تهیه پرسش‌نامه و همچنین مصاحبه با تعدادی از کارشناسان و خبرگان این امر نشان می‌دهد که در نواحی شرقی کشور نیاز به احداث آمادگاه وجود دارد. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنگ ناهمتراز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پدافند غیرعامل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آماد و پشتیبانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پراکنش آمادگاه‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محورهای تهدید</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3409_617d6e74f20d717b86fce41d97242471.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
