<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>17</Volume>
				<Issue>65</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Proposing a Model of the Effective Technological Forecasting in Defense Sector for Implementing Strategic Planning</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی الگوی پیش‌بینی فناوری‌های مؤثر دفاعی به ‌منظور اجرای برنامه‌های راهبردی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>29</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>53</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">27703</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه سمنان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract> 
&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;
This study was an attempt to predict the academic achievement of the students of Imam Ali Military University students based on thinking styles. For this purpose and also in an attempt to assess the thinking styles, the study was conducted through administering Sternberg and Wagner thinking styles questionnaire among a sample of 705 students affiliated to the Imam Ali Military University who were selected based on stratified random sampling method. To conduct this study, in terms of making measurement of the students’ academic achievement, data collection procedures were run through utilizing correlation coefficient and stepwise multiple regression methods. The findings revealed that in terms of thinking styles including hierarchical, global, external, legislative, and judicial, there is a significant positive relationship among thinking styles, type I thinking styles and the students’ academic achievement. Meanwhile, there is a significant negative relationship between internal thinking styles and students’ academic achievement. Furthermore, the findings of stepwise regression analysis revealed that the correlation coefficient of multiple regression between thinking styles and students’ academic achievement releasing 0.19. Moreover, in terms of academic achievement variance, the thinking styles including legislative (type I), local (type II) and external (type III) releasing 3.7% of academic achievement variance. The findings of data analysis of freshman and sophomore also revealed that the correlation coefficient of multiple regressions between thinking styles and students’ academic achievement releasing 0.29 and 0.28 respectively. Moreover, in terms of the academic achievement variance of freshman and sophomore, the thinking styles including global and hierarchical releasing 8.2% and external thinking style releasing 7.4% respectively. Meanwhile in juniors, there was no significant relationship between thinking styles and academic achievement.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;چکیده&lt;/strong&gt;
یکی از مهم‌ترین نیازهای صنایع دفاعی کشورهای در حال توسعه، تصمیم‌گیری در رابطه با چگونگی سرمایه‌گذاری در عرصه دانش و فناوری است که با توجه به کمبود منابع از یک سو و هزینه‌های بالای پژوهش و توسعه فناوری از سوی دیگر، اهمیت روزافزونی یافته است. در صنعت هر سیستم دفاعی وجود یک مدل کارآمد پیش‌بینی فناوری، به‌منظور طراحی ساختار تعاملات و زمینه سازی جهت انتخاب‌های راهبردی الزامی است و عدم وجود چنین ساز و کاری، منجر به ناکامی سیاست‌های دفاعی در دستیابی به اهداف آن می‌گردد. مشخصات و ویژگی‌های الگوی کارآمد پیش‌بینی فناوری، از عمده مسائل هر مجموعه صنعتی، دفاعی می‌باشد که در این رابطه سیاستگذاران و برنامه ریزان امور دفاعی با سؤالاتی مانند چگونگی طراحی مدل پیش‌بینی فناوری و شاخص‌ها و ویژگی‌هایی که می‌بایست در طراحی این مدل مورد توجه قرار گرفته و ملاک ارزیابی قرار گیرند، مواجه می‌باشند. هدف این پژوهش بررسی سایر جنبه‌های تأثیرگذار بر ارتقای توانمندی سیستم پیش‌بینی فناوری‌های دفاعی و دستیابی به الگویی جامع در جهت اجرای راهبردهای دفاعی، از طریق انتخاب و توسعه فناوری‌های مناسب و مؤثر می‌باشد. این پژوهش از طریق انجام مطالعات کتابخانه‌ای گسترده و تحلیل سیاست‌های دفاعی کلان ملی و سایر اسناد بالادستی، بهره‌برداری از مطالعات و الگوهای ارائه شده موجود و نظرسنجی از کارشناسان باتجربه و برنامه ریزان صنایع دفاعی، اقدام به استخراج ویژگی‌های الگوی پیش‌بینی فناوری‌های دفاعی نموده است و ضمن به‌کارگیری روش تحلیل احتمالات به‌ منظور تشخیص سایر موقعیت‌های محتمل و ممکن، در زمینه نتایج حاصل از انتخاب و به‌کارگیری فناوری‌های دفاعی و تشریح نحوه تحلیل و ارزیابی فناوری‌ها، میزان تأثیرگذاری هر یک از عوامل تشکیل دهنده الگوی کارآمد پیش‌بینی فناوری‌های دفاعی را تعیین می‌نماید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فناوری دفاعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیش‌بینی فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل احتمالات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">راهبردهای دفاعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_27703_cc58fa0fe92fee6c30ffa48b3d4a8f48.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
