<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>43</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Relationship between sound Enforcement of Law and Social Order</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطه اجرای صحیح قانون و نظم اجتماعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>43</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>74</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">3406</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study purposed to investigate relationship between &quot;sound enforcement of the law and social order&quot; or better to say the possible effect of the former on the latter one. To do so, the study focused on identifying major criteria both variables and the nature of their relationship so that the significance of one of the most crucial variables affecting social order can be explored. As a field study based on Delphi technique, the study was conducted based on a three-phase questionnaire administered to 55 experts in social order and safety field holding at least MA degrees and enjoying 20 years job experiences. The finding indicated that the aspects of law enforcement including non-discriminatory enforcement, equality before law and law as a final arbiter have had respectively the highest effect on the aspects of social order such as public trust, effective social control, internalization of social rules and principles.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقاله حاضر با هدف بررسی رابطه و تأثیر «اجرای صحیح قانون» بر «نظم اجتماعی» انجام گرفته است تا با تعیین شاخص‌های اساسی اجرای صحیح قانون و نظم اجتماعی و شناخت این رابطه به اهمیت یکی از مهمترین عوامل تأثیرگذار بر نظم اجتماعی پی‌برده شود. روش تحقیق مطالعه حاضر، روش پیمایش با تکنیک دلفی است که با بهره‌گیری از داده‌های پرسش‌نامه در سه مرحله، نظر صاحب‌نظران این حوزه را در این مورد جمع‌آوری نموده است. نمونه مورد استفاده در این تحقیق 55 نفر شامل صاحب نظران حوزه نظم و امنیت با حداقل مدرک تحصیلی دانشجوی دکتری و با بیست سال سابقه کار، مستقر در شهر تهران است. یافته‌های تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که مؤلفه اجرای مناسب قانون بیشترین تأثیر را بر شاخص‌های نظم اجتماعی اعم از اعتماد عمومی، کنترل مؤثر اجتماعی، نهادینه شدن قواعد و هنجارهای اجتماعی دارد. شاخص‌های اجرای مناسب قانون شامل: اجرای بدون تبعیض قوانین، برابری در مقابل قانون، فصل الخطاب بودن قانون، به ترتیب بیشترین تأثیر را بر مؤلفه نظم اجتماعی داشته‌اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قانون</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اجرای صحیح قانون</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظم اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3406_559786c2f7544ca54715a209f132f810.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
