<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>17</Volume>
				<Issue>66</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Hybrid Warfare in Complex-Chaotic International System</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>جنگ هیبریدی در سیستم بین‌المللی پیچیده – آشوبی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>52</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>92</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">29078</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرهاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>قاسمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار روابط بین‌الملل دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ایرج</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسماعیلی فرزین</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری روابط بین‌الملل دانشگاه تهران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The breakup of the soviet union led to the fundamental changes in international order including entrance of new actors in systematic interactions, structural transformation in dynamism and the balance of power as well as intensification of complexity and chaos in international system. Moreover, the ways of warfare has undergone massive changes and deeply affected by modern systematic transitions. Consequently, a new notion of warfare, namely hybrid which is extremely complicated and thoroughly resistive against conventional solutions was emerged as a result of systematic changes permeating in international context. The hybrid warfare is identified as a prevalent method of warfare in Middle East and this phenomenon have already had a major impact on regional security environment of Middle East. Additionally, hybrid warfare poses contemporary threats to the countries of the region. The continuance in this crisis revealed that in terms of the theories of international relations and strategic studies, no explanations of power is provided for hybrid warfare and therefore providing an explanation of modern models of hybrid warfare based on complexity and chaos theory is taken as the most crucial questions in strategic studies and international relations. The hypothesis of this study is to identify the components of hybrid warfare as well as providing answers to the questions of what kind of war the hybrid warfare is and how the hybrid warfare fights.  In terms of research hypothesis, this study was also an attempt to identify the strategies for dealing with hybrid warfare based on the theories of complex- chaotic system. Having analyzed the theories, research hypothesis is also proved by the research findings. This study is also aimed at expanding the boundaries of knowledge in terms of theory, and also helping the researcher to theorize on warfare in terms of strategy as well as developing an applied and analytical model for dealing with threats posed by modern warfare especially hybrid warfare. Finally, as a developmental-descriptive study and in terms of data collection procedures and analysis, this research was conducted through library study and content analysis. </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;با فروپاشی اتحاد شوروی، نظم و به تبع آن نظام بین‌الملل در معرض تحولاتی بنیادین قرار گرفتند که مهمترین این تحولات ورود بازیگران جدید به عرصۀ تعاملات سیستمی، تغییر ساختار، ماهیت، پویش، مرکز ثقل و معادلات قدرت بود که در نتیجه آن به‌هم‌پیوستگی، پیچیدگی و آشوبناکی در سیستم تشدید شد. به تبع تحولات سیستمی، روش جنگ نیز متحول، و تحت تأثیر ویژگی‌های جدید سیستم، مبدل به پدیده‌ای تحت عنوان جنگ هیبریدی شد که به شدت پیچیده و مقاوم در برابر راه­حل‌های متداول می‌باشد. این روش جنگ که اکنون به روش رایج جنگ در منطقه تبدیل شده، به گونه­ای محیط امنیتی منطقه را تحت تأثیر خود قرار داده است که می‌توان آن را یکی از بزرگترین تهدیدات کنونی همۀ کشورهای منطقه از جمله جمهوری اسلامی ایران دانست. ولی تداوم بحران نشان می‌دهد که در حوزۀ نظریه­های موجود روابط بین‌الملل و مطالعات راهبردی و آثار مربوطه تبیین قدرتمندی در این خصوص وجود ندارد. به این جهت یکی از پرسمآنهای اساسی در روابط بین­الملل و مطالعات راهبردی این است که الگوهای نوین جنگ از جمله جنگ‌های هیبریدی در چارچوب نظریۀ پیچیدگی و آشوب چگونه تبیین می‌شوند؟ در این چارچوب فرضیۀ تحقیق این است که چیستی و چرایی جنگ هیبریدی و راهکارهای مقابله با آن با استفاده از اصول نظریۀ سیستم‌های پیچیده در محیط آشوبی قابل تعریف است و یافته‌های تحقیق نیز این فرضیه را تأیید می‌کند. اهداف انجام این تحقیق از لحاظ نظری دانش‌افزایی و کمک به نظریه‌پردازی در حوزه راهبردی و از نظر کاربردی نیز کمک به تدوین مدل تحلیلی-کاربردی در خصوص تهدیدات منبعث از جنگ‌های نوین به خصوص جنگ‌های هیبریدی می‌باشد. این تحقیق از نوع توسعه‌ای روش تحقیق به کار رفته توصیفی، روش جمع‌آوری اطلاعات کتابخانه‌ای، و روش تجزیه و تحلیل اطلاعات روش تحلیل محتوا می‌باشد&lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیستم‌های پیچیده و آشوبناک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش جنگیدن هیبریدی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کنترل آشوب</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29078_3b2611be4673b0c46eb52b2086a522d8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
