<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>61</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Assessment and the Prioritization of the Quality Dimensions of Educational Services based on the Servqual Model through Utilizing a Mixed Approach Including AHP and VIKOR
(Case Study; Imam Ali Military University)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی و اولویت‌بندی ابعاد کیفیت خدمات آموزشی مبتنی بر الگوی سروکوآل با بهره‌گیری از رویکرد ترکیبی AHP-VIKOR (مطالعه موردی: دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع))</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>113</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>134</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22381</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منصور</FirstName>
					<LastName>خیرگو</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت سیاست‌گذاری، عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ایمان</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوربخش</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه یزد، مدرس دانشگاه پیام نور اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، مدرس دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, the quality dimensions of services are taken as the most important aspects of management in organizations that provide services. Despite the increasing importance of the quality of services in the competitive environment, assessment of the quality of educational services is completely different from any other services and is an immensely difficult task due to its importance. Moreover, educational services are identified as the main distinguishing feature of universities and also bring students a great feeling of satisfaction. Imam Ali Military University is playing a significant role in training military forces of the Islamic Republic of Iran. To delve into this issue in this study, this study was an attempt to assess and prioritize the quality dimensions of educational services based on Servqual model through utilizing a mixed approach including AHP and VIKOR. Thereupon, the quality dimensions of educational services are weighed in terms of significance. The findings also revealed that in terms of prioritizing and ranking, the quality dimensions including tangibility, reliability, accountability and sympathy have been identified as the most effective factors affecting the ranking of educational services of three faculties including faculty of administration and military science, faculty of flight and engineering and also the faculty of basic science at Imam Ali Military University. &lt;br /&gt; </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه کیفیت خدمات یکی از مهم‌ترین جنبه‌های مدیریتی سازمان‌های خدماتی است. با وجود اهمیت روزافزون مقوله کیفیت خدمات در دنیای پیچیده، سخت و رقابتی حاضر، بنابر دلایل چندی، اندازه‌گیری کیفیت در آموزش متفاوت و بسیار مشکل‌تر از بخش‌های دیگر است. از سوی دیگر خدمات وجه تمایزی برای دانشگاه‌ها بوده و در نهایت رضایتمندی دانشجویان را به دنبال خواهد داشت. در این میان دانشگاه افسری امام علی‌&lt;sup&gt;(ع)&lt;/sup&gt; نقشِ ویژه‌ای را در تربیت نیروی انسانی متخصص و نظامی در کشور جمهوری اسلامی ایران دارد. به همین منظور در این مقاله به ارزیابی و رتبه‌بندی کیفیت خدمات (الگوی سروکوآل) در دانشگاه افسری امام علی‌&lt;sup&gt;(ع) &lt;/sup&gt;با به‌کارگیری تکنیک تلفیقی AHP/VIKOR، می‌پردازیم. یافته‌های پژوهش بیانگر ابعاد کیفیت خدمات بر اساس اهمیت آن‌هاست. ابعاد ملموس بودن، قابلیت اطمینان، پاسخگویی، تضمین و همدلی به ترتیب اهمیت و تأثیرگذاری بیشتری را در رتبه‌بندی کیفیت خدمات سه دانشکده مدیریت و علوم نظامی، دانشکده مهندسی و پرواز و دانشکده علوم پایه دانشگاه افسری امام علی&lt;sup&gt;(ع)&lt;/sup&gt; داشته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کیفیت خدمات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی سروکوآل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">AHP</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">VIKOR</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_22381_f9a85bdc453b6a24557e3d35ff9a9dbe.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
