<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>19</Volume>
				<Issue>76</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Understanding the Role of Psychological Ownership on the Relationship between Ethical Leadership and Employee Performance</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>درک نقش میانجی مالکیت روان‌شناختی در رابط بین رهبری اخلاقی و عملکرد کارکنان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>28</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">43076</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>داورزنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت کارآفرینی، مدرس دانشگاه علوم و فنون هوایی شهید ستاری</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>صمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>بارانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه علوم و فنون هوایی شهید ستاری (نویسنده مسئول)، samdbarani@ssau.ac.ir</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of ethical leadership on employee performance with the role of psychological ownership mediator. The present study is applied and descriptive-correlational, and the data were collected in the field survey. The statistical population of the study was the knowledge personnel of a military university. According to the Morgan and Karjets table, the sample size was estimated to be 210, selected through random-cluster sampling. To assess ethical leadership, psychological property, job performance, the questionnaires by Brown and et al. (2005), Van Dyne and Pierce (2004), and Patterson’s (2006) were used respectively. The data were analyzed using structural equation modeling (LISREL 8.54), and the findings showed that ethical leadership directly and indirectly influences employee performance through psychological ownership. Ethical leaders can increase individual awareness by changing the attitude and strengthening the sense of ownership toward the organization, and by providing emotional and cognitive attachment between the individual and the aim, they can influence an individual’s behavior to prepare the necessary basis for facilitating organizational process and increasing job performance.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی تأثیر رهبری اخلاقی بر روی عملکرد کارکنان با نقش میانجی مالکیت روان‌شناختی انجام شده است. این پژوهش از نظر هدف؛ کاربردی، از نظر چگونگی گردآوری داده‌ها از دستۀ پژوهش‌های توصیفی - همبستگی و از شاخة مطالعات میدانی به شمار می‌رود. جامعة آماری پژوهش حاضر، کارکنان دانشی یکی از دانشگاه‌های نظامی است. بر اساس جدول مورگان و کرجسی، حجم نمونه 210 نفر تخمین زده شد. روش نمونه‌گیری در این پژوهش، روش تصادفی طبقه‌ای است. برای سنجش رهبری اخلاقی از پرسش‌نامه براون و همکاران (2005)، مالکیت روان‌شناختی از پرسش‌نامه ون داین و پیرس (2004) و عملکرد شغلی از پرسش‌نامه پترسون (2006) استفاده شد. داده‌های به دست آمده با استفاده از مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری (نرم‌افزار لیزرل 54/8) تجزیه و تحلیل شد. یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد رهبری اخلاقی به صورت مستقیم و غیر مستقیم از طریق مالکیت روان‌شناختی بر عملکرد کارکنان تأثیرگذار است. رهبران اخلاقی می‌توانند با تغییر نگرش و تقویت حس مالکیتی نسبت به سازمان، آگاهی فردی را افزایش دهند و با ایجاد دلبستگی شناختی و عاطفی بین فرد و هدف بر رفتار  فرد تأثیر بگذارند و زمینۀ لازم برای تسهیل فرآیند سازمانی و افزایش عملکرد شغلی را فراهم نمایند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری اخلاقی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد کارکنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مالکیت روان‌شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_43076_5322bc11bfe3e461e118809a506c98f9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
