<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>42</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>C5I2 Command and Control System and Role of Computers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سامانة فرماندهی و کنترل C5I2 و بررسی نقش رایانه‌ها در آن</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>43</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>70</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">3459</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays nature of war has changed into information war in which information superiority plays a vital role. As a result, the main aim of military commanders and planners is to exercise superiority of command and control in information systems and computer and communication networks, which is called C4I. What makes C4I effective is the “cohesion” among its components in the light of “unity of efforts” which has resulted in a new system called C5I2. In a bid to offer a comprehensive concept of C5I2, this article addresses the role of computer, its necessities and also threats emanating from its application. As an applied and descriptive study, this article was developed employing library, internet and professional URLs. It could then be concluded that “all communication systems, automatic information and the equipment contributing to commander in planning, guiding and controlling forces in line with unity of efforts” are called C5I2. Any successful command and control efforts lie in their connection to computer systems capable of mass data processing as quickly and accurately as possible. That is why in major wars such as the Persian Gulf one control and command system played the major role. Application of IT specially computers in C5I2 infiltrates into the information systems of the enemy, which justifies further attention to the issues like security and customization in C5I2 and proposes a comprehensive customized architecture for the army of the I.R. of Iran. </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه ماهیت جنگ تفکرکرده و به شکل جنگ اطلاعات درآمده است پس برتری اطلاعاتی در چنین جنگی نقشی حیاتی ایفا می‌کند. لذا هدف اصلی فرماندهان و طراحان نظامی در این نوع جنگ‌ها، برتری در زمینة فرماندهی و کنترل مبتنی بر سامانه‌های اطلاعاتی، شبکه‌های رایانه‌ای و مخابراتی مرتبط با آن است که در اصطلاح به آن C4I می‌گویند. آنچه سامانة C4Iرا مفید جلوه می‌دهد، «همبستگی» اجزای این سیستم با همدیگر در سایة «یگانگی تلاش» است که منجر به تعریف سامانة جدیدی با شناسة C5I2گردیده است. این پژوهش با هدف ارائة مفهومی جامع از سامانة C5I2، نقش رایانه، ضرورت و تهدیدات ناشی از به کارگیری رایانه‌ها در سیستم مذکور صورت گرفته است. این پژوهش بر اساس هدف کاربردی و نیز ماهیت و روش، پژوهشی توصیفی است. برای جمع‌آوری اطلاعات از منابع کتابخانه‌ای، اینترنت و سایت‌های تخصصی استفاده شده است. می‌توان نتیجه گرفت که «کلیة سیستم‌های ارتباطی یا خبررسانی و اطلاعات خودکار و تجهیزاتی که در ارتباط با هم فرمانده را در طراحی، هدایت و کنترل نیروها در راستای وحدت تلاش‌ها، در صحنة نبرد یاری می‌دهد، C5I2 نامیده می‌شود. برای اینکه فرماندهان بتوانند در سطوح بالای فرماندهی و کنترل به طور موفق عمل نمایند، باید به نوعی از سیستم‌های رایانه‌ای متصل باشند که خاصیت پردازش انبوه داده را با سرعت و دقت بالا داشته باشند. به همین دلیل در جنگ‌های مهمی مانند جنگ خلیج فارس، رایانه بیشترین نقش را در سامانة کنترل و فرماندهی ایفا نمود. ورود فن‌آوری اطلاعات به ویژه رایانه‌ها در سامانة C5I2 باعث نفوذ و اختلال در سامانه‌های اطلاعاتی طرف مقابل شده است؛ از این رو توجه بیشتر به مقولة امنیت و لزوم بومی‌سازی در سامانة C5I2 و ارائة یک معماری جامع بومی شده برای آجا ضروری به نظر می‌رسد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیستم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">C5I2</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرماندهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کنترل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارتباطات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رایانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اطلاعات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همبستگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">یگانگی تلاش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3459_66e833826b22d6240206ede5f9ef87ae.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
