<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>17</Volume>
				<Issue>68</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation and Comparison of Multi-Objective Meta-Innovative Algorithms for Solving the Problem of Optimization of the Production Design (Case Study: Optimum Design of Military Equipment)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی و مقایسۀ الگوریتم‌های فراابتکاری چندهدفه برای حل مسئله بهینه‌سازی طراحی محصولات (مورد مطالعه: طراحی بهینۀ تجهیزات نظامی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>128</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>163</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">30632</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرهاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>هادی‌نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت تحقیق در عملیات، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، مدرس دانشگاه امام علی(ع)،</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رمزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت ‌علمی گروه علوم کامپیوتر، دانشگاه قم</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خواجه</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت ‌علمی گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد قم</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In today&#039;s tense world, the existence of a strong and effective military force is considered as the strategic asset of every nation. Meanwhile, designing and updating military equipment and increasing their reliability and durability are particularly important. On the one hand, the mathematical model of optimization of military equipment at the design stage, due to the complexity and high volume of computing is in the Np-hard problems group, and requires meta-innovative methods for solving, and on the other hand it is in the multi-objective problem group, thus requiring the use of multi-objective methods. But the growing development and variety of multi-objective meta-innovative methods have challenged the choice of the appropriate algorithm in solving the aforementioned model. Therefore, the present study aims to review the modern algorithms, as well as provide a suitable method for solving the problem of military equipment optimization with the help of the sample. Thus, the necessity of mathematical modeling in optimizing the design of military equipment problem and the study and selection of the appropriate solution are the main goal of this research. In this applied- experimental study four algorithms (NSGA-II, MOPSO, PESA-II and MALO) were investigated and results with the help of six different indices were analyzed and evaluated. Meanwhile, combination of Hierarchical Process and Entropy Analysis (AHP-Entropy) approach were used to weigh the indices and the PROMETHEE method was used to evaluate the algorithms. The results emphasize the importance of the &quot;Runtime&quot; and &quot;Pareto Response number&quot; indicators on the priority of the MOPSO algorithm in solving the research problem.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در دنیای پر‌تنش و پرآشوب امروزی، وجود نیروی نظامی قوی و کارآمد از سرمایه‌های راهبردی هر ملت محسوب می‌شود. در این میان، طراحی و به‌روزرسانی تجهیزات نظامی و افزایش قابلیت اطمینان و ماندگاری آنها اهمیت ویژه‌ای دارد. مدل ریاضی بهینه‌سازی تجهیزات نظامی در مرحله طراحی، از یک‌سو به دلیل پیچیدگی و حجم بالای محاسبات در گروه مسائل Np-hard قرار داشته و برای حل نیازمند روش‌های فرا ابتکاری است و از سوی دیگر در گروه مسائل چندهدفه قرار داشته، در نتیجه مستلزم بهره‌گیری از روش‌های چندهدفه است. اما توسعۀ روزافزون و تنوع زیاد روش‌های فرا ابتکاری چندهدفه، انتخاب الگوریتم مناسب را در حل مدل مذکور با چالش مواجه کرده است. لذا تحقیق حاضر تلاش دارد ضمن مرور الگوریتم‌های مدرن و پرکاربرد، با کمک نمونه مطالعاتی روشی مناسب برای حل مسئله بهینه‌سازی تجهیزات نظامی ارائه دهد. بنابراین ضرورت مدل‌سازی ریاضی در مسئله بهینه‌سازی طراحی تجهیزات نظامی و بررسی و انتخاب روش حل مناسب، انگیزه و هدف اصلی این تحقیق را شکل می‌دهد. تحقیق حاضر از منظر هدف در گروه تحقیقات کاربردی و از منظر روش در گروه تحقیقات آزمایشی قرار دارد. در این پژوهش چهار الگوریتم: NSGA-II، MOPSO، PESA-II و MALO بررسی شد و با کمک شش شاخص مختلف به تحلیل و ارزیابی نتایج پرداخته ‌شده است. ضمن آنکه برای وزن‌دهی شاخص‌ها از رویکرد ترکیبی فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی و آنتروپی (AHP-Entropy) و برای ارزیابی الگوریتم‌ها از روش پرامیتی (PROMETHEE) استفاده‌ شده است. نتایج حاصل ضمن تأکید بر اهمیت بالای شاخص‌های «زمان اجرا» و «تعداد پاسخ‌های پارتو»، بر اولویت الگوریتم «MOPSO» در حل مسئله تحقیق تأکید دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهینه‌سازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش‌های فرا ابتکاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طراحی تجهیزات نظامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قابلیت اطمینان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_30632_ca5f51c1b2ae06b147095c8538badc6e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
