<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>15</Volume>
				<Issue>58</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Investigation of the Effect of Authentic Leadership on Organizational Identification
(A Case Study of the Personnel of Defensive-Industrial Units)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر رهبری اصیل بر هویّت‌یابی سازمانی (مطالعه موردی کارکنان یکی از واحدهای صنعتی دفاعی کشور)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>24</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>42</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">16810</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>لطفی جلال آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>موغلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طاهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>فیضی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیرحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیرخانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Sense of personnel identity in an organization exerts a powerful influence over the behavior and the attitudes of staff as well as enhancing non-physical martial power of the armed forces. In a bid to overcome the environmental challenges, managers should strengthen the organizational identity of personnel; therefore, understanding the effective factors affecting the Sense of personnel identity in an organization became the important duty of managers. As a causal research, this study aims to investigate the effect of authentic leadership style on organizational identification. For this purpose, the study was conducted through engaging randomly selected populations of 400 personnel affiliated to the defensive-industrial units in Tehran. The reliability and validity of the instrumentations were assured in the early stages and then data analysis was run in terms of structural equation modeling. The findings of the research hypothesis revealed that all dimensions of authentic leadership style are effectively affecting the organizational identification. Finally, some practical suggestions are made by researcher.  </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">احساس هویّت کارکنان با سازمان تأثیر زیادی بر رفتارها و نگرش‌های کارکنان و افزایش توان غیر فیزیکی رزمی نیروهای مسلح دارد. مدیران برای غلبه بر چالش‌های محیطی بایستی هویّت‌یابی سازمانی کارکنان را تقویت کنند. بر این اساس، درک عوامل مؤثر بر احساس هویّت کارکنان با سازمان به وظیفة مهم مدیران تبدیل شده است. پژوهش حاضر به بررسی تأثیر سبک رهبری اصیل بر هویّت‌یابی سازمانی می‌پردازد. این پژوهش از نوع علی است. جامعة آماری پژوهش کارکنان یکی از واحدهای صنعتی دفاعی کشور مستقر در شهر تهران است و با استفاده از نمونه‌گیری تصادفی تعداد 400 نفر انتخاب گردید. پس از طراحی و تعیین روایی و پایایی ابزار پژوهش، به منظور تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها از الگوی معادلات ساختاری استفاده شد. نتایج به‌دست آمده از آزمون فرضیه‌های تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که کلیة ابعاد رهبری اصیل بر هویّت‌یابی سازمانی تأثیرگذار است. در پایان محققان پیشنهادهای کاربردی ارائه داده‌اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خود آگاهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پردازش متعادل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نهادینه کردن اخلاقیات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شفافیت روابط</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری اصیل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هویّت‌یابی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_16810_9a9a8b787542b9d4eaecf8df9c094a8c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
