<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>15</Volume>
				<Issue>60</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Proposing a Model of Personnel Human Dignity in Iranian Governmental Organizations 
((A Case Study; a Model for the Units of Iranian Army Ground Force in the Special City of Maragheh))</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائه الگوی کرامت انسانی کارکنان در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران (مورد مطالعه: یکی از یگان‌های نیروی زمینی مستقر در شهرستان ویژه مراغه)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>34</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>76</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21925</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلام‌رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>معمارزاده طهران</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد قزوین</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>موسی‌خانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت سیستم‌ها، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدمهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>الوانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فلسفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد قزوین</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Human dignity is identified as the backbone of human right and its preservation is also taken as the key of permanent progress and development in every society. Therefore, internalization of organizational culture in light of Islamic values, human dignity and reverence for human and social capital is considered as the main and crucial policy in organization’s administration system and the implementation of such a planning is the primary purpose of many organizations. To delve into this issue in this study, as a qualitative study including meta-synthesis method, this study was an attempt to propose a comprehensive model of personnel human dignity in government agencies. To do so, the components of this phenomenon were identified in the early stages of investigation. Thereupon, the concepts and the components of personnel human dignity were emerged as a result of elite and expert consultation and also the analysis of primary conceptual model. In a bid to apply the exploratory model in terms of meta- synthesis method, the study was conducted through administering a questionnaire among population of 218 personnel affiliated to the department of real estate and registration office in Azerbaijan who was randomly selected based on stratified sampling method. To analyze the data, the confirmatory factor analysis and LISREL software analysis were also run in this study. Thereupon, the components and the parameters of human dignity model were emerged as the result of analysis. Moreover , in an attempt to identify the optimized dimensions of human dignity, 40 questionnaires were also administered among personnel of the Iranian army ground force in Maragheh who were randomly selected based on purposeful sampling method. Moreover, data analysis was run through fuzzy modeling in Matlab software. The findings revealed that in terms of significance of human dignity components, if the personnel pay more attention to the components of human dignity including performance dimension (33%), behavioral dimension (31%), mental and intellectual dimension (30%) and physical dimension (6%), consequently, human dignity of an organization will possess the highest rank in terms of value (62.1).</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه کرامت انسانی محور و مبنای حقوق بشر تلقی شده و پیشرفت و توسعه‌ی پایدار در هر جامعه، مستلزم رعایت آن است. از این رو در بند اول سیاست‌های کلی نظام اداری کشور که توجه و اجرای برنامه‌های آن از ضرورت‌ها و اهداف هر دستگاه دولتی به شمار می‌رود، به برنامه نهادینه‌سازی فرهنگ سازمانی مبتنی بر ارزش‌های اسلامی و کرامت انسانی و ارج نهادن به سرمایه‌های انسانی و اجتماعی اشاره شده است. بر این اساس در تحقیق حاضر به‌منظور ارائه الگویی جامع از کرامت انسانی در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران، از روش پژوهش کیفی فراترکیب سندلوسکی و باروسو استفاده شده است. پس از شناسایی مقولات، مفاهیم و کدهای کرامت انسانی (الگوی مفهومی اولیه)، با استفاده از نظرهای خبرگان و انجام اصلاحات لازم، تبیین الگوی کرامت انسانی کارکنان میسر شد. در این پژوهش به منظور کاربردی کردن الگوی اکتشافی از فرایند فراترکیب، تعداد 218 پرسشنامه بین کارکنان یکی از سازمان‌های دولتی (اداره کل ثبت اسناد و املاک استان آذربایجان شرقی) به‌صورت نمونه‌گیری طبقه‌ای توزیع شد و با استفاده از روش تحلیل عاملی تاییدی و نرم افزار لیزرل تجزیه و تحلیل انجام گرفت. در نتیجه ابعاد، مولفه‌ها و شاخص‌های الگوی مورد تایید قرار گرفتند. همچنین برای محاسبه ترکیب بهینه ابعاد کرامت انسانی، تعداد 40 پرسشنامه بین کارکنان یکی از یگان‌های نیروی زمینی مستقر در شهرستان ویژه مراغه به صورت نمونه‌گیری هدفمند توزیع و با استفاده از روش الگوسازی فازی و نرم افزار مطلب مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. نتایج تحقیق در این مرحله نشان می‌دهد، چنانچه میزان توجه کارکنان به ابعاد عملکردی (33%)، رفتاری (31%)، ذهنی و روانی (30%) و جسمی (6%) باشد؛ آنگاه حداکثر میزان کرامت انسانی آنان در سازمان به میزان (1/62) خواهد بود. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کرامت انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش فراترکیب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منطق فازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاست‌های کلی نظام اداری کشور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نیروی زمینی ارتش جمهوری اسلامی ایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_21925_a8a2e8c529cdb7eec9cfb225727c1b8a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
