<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>18</Volume>
				<Issue>69</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying and prioritizing human resources management practices affecting organizational identification to enhance the combat power (A case study of a defensive industrial unit)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی موثر بر هویت‌یابی‌ سازمانی در راستای ارتقای توان رزمی (مورد مطالعه یک واحد صنعتی دفاعی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>82</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>103</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">32386</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>لطفی جلال‌آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خیراندیش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری، (نویسنده مسئول)، kheirandish@ssau.ac.ir</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>عسگری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داریوش</FirstName>
					<LastName>مهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزش عالی، دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Manpower and its management are among the non-physical factors that affect the combat power of the armed forces. Accordingly, this research was an attempt to identify and prioritize human resources management practices which affect organizational identification to increase the combat power of the armed forces. This research is descriptive-survey in terms of purpose, and is applied research in terms of its type of use. From among employees working in an industrial defense unit in Tehran, a sample of 350 were chosen through simple random sampling. After designing and determining the validity and reliability of the tool, a structural equation model was used to analyze the data. The findings revealed that identity making policies, ethical leadership styles, identity making tools and skills, and identity making policies are among human resource management practices that affect organizational identification. In addition, the findings showed that organizational identification affects the non-physical factors of combat power. Hence, managers and commanders must create organizational identification through employee engagement, empowerment, development of working groups, leadership ethical styles, and satisfactory communications, and through these practices they can increase the non-physical combat power of the armed forces.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;نیروی انسانی و مدیریت آن از مولفه‌های غیر فیزیکی موثر بر توان رزمی نیروهای مسلح &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;به‌شمار می‌رود. بر این اساس،&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;این&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;تحقیق به&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی موثر بر هویت‌یابی‌ سازمانی جهت افزایش توان رزمی نیروهای مسلح می‌پردازد. این پژوهش از نظر هدف، توصیفی- پیمایشی و از نظر نوع استفاده، کاربردی است. جامعة آماری پژوهش، شامل کارکنان یکی از واحدهای صنعتی دفاعی در شهر تهران بود که با استفاده از نمونه‌گیری تصادفی ساده تعداد 350 نفر از آنان انتخاب گردیدند. پس از طراحی و تعیین روایی و پایایی ابزار، برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌‌ها از الگوی معادلات ساختاری استفاده شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد که خط‌‌مشی‌های هویت‌ساز، سبک‌های اخلاقی رهبری، ابزارها و مهارت‌های هویت‌ساز و سیاست‌های هویت‌ساز از اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی موثر بر هویت‌یابی‌ سازمانی هستند. همچنین، یافته‌ها نشان داد که هویت‌یابی‌ سازمانی بر عوامل غیر فیزیکی توان رزمی تاثیر دارد. بر این اساس، مدیران و فرماندهان باید از طریق مشارکت کارکنان، توانمند‌سازی، توسعة گروه‌های کاری، سبک‌های اخلاقی رهبری، ارتباطات رضایت‌بخش موجب هویت‌یابی‌ سازمانی شده و توان غیر‌فیزیکی رزمی نیروهای مسلح را افزایش دهند.&lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هویت‌یابی‌ سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توان رزمی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_32386_a087479300861b71961b4fa9292b362b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
