<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>61</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Evaluation of the Academic Development of Faculty Members of University and Proposing Suitable Strategies for Its Enhancement (Case Study; A Military University)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی وضعیت بالندگی اعضای هیئت علمی و ارائه راهکارهای مطلوب برای ارتقای آن (مورد مطالعه: یک دانشگاه نظامی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>29</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>59</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22373</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امین</FirstName>
					<LastName>هماینی دمیرچی</LastName>
<Affiliation>. دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>محجوب عشرت‌آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت آموزش عالی، دانشگاه علوم و فنون هوایی شهید ستاری</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داریوش</FirstName>
					<LastName>مهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>. دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزش عالی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، مدرس دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالله</FirstName>
					<LastName>وثوقی نیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>. دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی (گرایش تصمیم‌گیری و خط‌مشی گذاری)، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study was an attempt to evaluate the academic development of faculty members of university and is also aimed to propose suitable strategies for its enhancement. Faculty members are identified as crucial human resources of higher education centers; therefore, the academic performances of universities are all deeply affected by their academic development. Faculty members are also identified as the most important human capital of every university and society and their academic enhancement is of crucial significance for universities and is also taken as an incontrovertible fact. Modern military education is an absolute necessity due to the rapid changes in military sciences in recent decades and the necessity for empowering the faculty members as a developmental approach and fundamental plan is sharply emphasized at universities. As an applied and descriptive field study, this study was conducted through engaging sample population of 94 faculty members of military universities who were selected based on stratified random sampling method. The findings revealed that the academic development of faculty members and its components including organizational, educational and individual development enjoys 0.05 rates of effectiveness and putting it at the top of the average level. The findings also revealed that in terms of academic development of faculty members, there is a significant difference among three faculties of Imam Ali military university at the level of 0.05. Moreover, in terms of mean score of faculty members, faculty of military management stood at the top of ranking among three faculties including military management, foreign languages and the faculty of flight and engineering. Additionally, the academic development of faculty members is confirmed by the factor analysis and its development is appropriately evaluated by its components. Finally, in a bid to enhance the academic development of faculty members, some practical suggestions are made according to the viewpoint of faculty members. &lt;br /&gt; </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span lang=&quot;FA&quot; dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;هدف از این پژوهش، ارزیابی وضعیت بالندگی اعضای هیئت علمی و ارائه راهکارهای مطلوب برای ارتقای آن است. اعضای هیئت علمی از عوامل زیربنایی آموزش عالی هستند که توسعه کیفی آن‌ها تأثیر بسزایی بر عملکرد دانشگاه‌ها دارد و توجه به بالندگی اعضای هیئت علمی به عنوان مهم‌ترین نیروهای متخصص کشور ضرورتی انکارناپذیر است. با توجه به تحولات سریع علوم نظامی در دهه‌های گذشته، ضرورت توجه به آموزش نظامی نوین بیش از سایر حوزه‌ها احساس می‌شود و توانمندسازی اعضای هیئت علمی به عنوان یک برنامه بنیادی و با رویکردی توسعه‌ای مورد توجه قرار گرفته است. روش پژوهش، توصیفی – پیمایشی و جامعه آماری آن کلیه اعضای هیئت علمی دانشگاه مورد مطالعه بود. تعداد 94 نفر با استفاده از روش تصادفی طبقه‌بندی شده به عنوان نمونه انتخاب شدند. نتایج به‌دست آمده نشان داد که وضعیت بالندگی اعضای هیئت علمی و مؤلفه‌های آن (بالندگی سازمانی، بالندگی آموزشی، بالندگی فردی) به‌جز مؤلفه بالندگی حرفه‌ای، در سطح 0.05 بالاتر از متوسط نظری قرار دارند. نتایج همچنین نشان داد بین دانشکده‌های دانشگاه مورد مطالعه از نظر بالندگی اعضای هیئت علمی در سطح 0.05 تفاوت معنی‌داری وجود دارد و میزان میانگین نمرات اعضای هیئت علمی دانشکده مدیریت بیشتر از دانشکده‌های زبان و پرواز است. نتایج تحلیل عاملی نیز برازش الگوی بالندگی اعضای هیئت علمی را تأیید کرد و نشان داد که مؤلفه‌های مطرح شده در پژوهش به خوبی بالندگی اعضای هیئت علمی را ارزیابی می‌کنند. در پایان، با توجه به نظرات اعضای هیئت علمی دانشگاه مورد مطالعه، راهکارهایی برای ارتقای بالندگی اعضای هیئت علمی ارائه گردیده است&lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بالندگی اعضای هیئت علمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بالندگی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بالندگی حرفه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بالندگی آموزشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بالندگی فردی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_22373_7c322de4c89cb38c5039a868ca59e34d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
