<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>17</Volume>
				<Issue>68</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Strategy Benchmarking of Challenges and Opportunities of Kurdistan Province in Defense of the Homeland</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>راهبردسنجی چالش‌ها و فرصت‌های استان کردستان در دفاع از سرزمین</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>101</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>127</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">30631</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پرویز</FirstName>
					<LastName>آقایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری در جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی شهری، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the main issues in the field of military geography is the ability to defend the homeland and maintain territorial integrity in times of crisis or war. The history of the country shows that it must always observe the defensive conditions of the country and prepare itself for defense of the country in the face of regional and global crises. Kurdistan province is one of the areas that has witnessed various crises over the past 40 years, and the counterrevolutionary terrorist parties and groups have tried to use various methods, including soft war, guerrilla attacks, running disputes among Kurdish tribes and so on, to turn the province into a tense region. In this regard, this research aims to identify the most important challenges and opportunities in Kurdistan province, provide appropriate strategies, and classify them to reduce the region&#039;s challenges in defense- security field. In this descriptive- analytic research in method and applied-developmental research in purpose, data collected in a library and via documents. Findings based on SWOT and QSPM indicate that Kurdistan province has offensive positioning. It means the desirable situation of the region and the domination of the power and opportunity points on its challenges. By utilizing the abundant abilities of the Kurdistan, it eliminates existing challenges. At the end of this research, strategies and solutions based on the status quo of the region are presented to eliminate the current challenges</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از مباحث محوری در حوزۀ جغرافیای نظامی، قابلیت دفاع از سرزمین و حفظ تمامیت ارضی کشور در زمان بروز بحران یا جنگ است. تاریخ کشور نشان می‌دهد که همواره باید شرایط دفاعی کشور را رصد کرد و در مقابل بحران‌های منطقه‌ای و جهانی آمادگی دفاع از خاک کشور را داشت. استان کردستان از جمله مناطقی است که در طول چهل سال گذشته دستخوش بحران‌های مختلفی بوده است و احزاب و گروهک‌های تروریستی ضد انقلاب اسلامی سعی کرده‌اند با شیوه‌های مختلفی از جمله جنگ نرم، حملات چریکی، اختلاف‌افکنی بین طوایف کردزبان و سایر موارد این استان را به منطقه‌ای پرتنش تبدیل نمایند. در این راستا، این پژوهش با هدف شناسایی مهمترین چالش‌ها و فرصت‌های استان کردستان درصدد ارائه راهبردهای مقتضی است تا با طبقه‌بندی آنها، از چالش‌های منطقه در حوزه دفاعی- امنیتی کاسته شود. روش پژوهش توصیفی-تحلیلی و از لحاظ هدف کاربردی-توسعه‌ای می‌باشد. داده‌ها به‌صورت کتابخانه‌ای (اسناد و مدارک) گردآوری شده است. یافته‌های پژوهش بر اساس SWOT و QSPM حاکی از آن است که استان کردستان دارای موقعیتی تهاجمی است. موقعیت تهاجمی به معنای وضعیت مطلوب منطقه و تسلط نقاط قوت و فرصت بر چالش‌های آن است؛ یعنی می‌توان با استفاده از قابلیت‌های فراوان استان کردستان چالش‌های موجود را برطرف کرد. در انتهای این پژوهش، راهبردها و راهکارهایی بر مبنای وضعیت موجود منطقه برای از بین بردن چالش‌های کنونی ارائه شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چالش‌ها و فرصت‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">راهبرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استان کردستان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل‌های SWOT و QSPM</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_30631_f176f862e81a1ee14a889e7c6202d32c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
