<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>17</Volume>
				<Issue>66</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Transformational Leadership on Facilitating Organizational Innovation with Respect to the Mediating Role of Knowledge Management and Psychological Empowerment among Military Personnel</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل رهبری تحول‌گرا در تسهیل نوآوری با توجه به نقش واسطه‌ای تواناسازی روان‌شناختی و مدیریت دانش در بین کارکنان نظامی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>22</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">29076</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>تشکریان جهرمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نورمحمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>یعقوبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه زاهدان دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سجاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>حجت‌دوست</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>صدرالدین</FirstName>
					<LastName>جهان‌بین</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس مدیریت دولتی، دانشگاه یاسوج</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, in changing dynamic environments, continuous organizational changes require strategic and transformational leadership. This study was an attempt to investigate the effect of transformational leadership on facilitating organizational innovations with respect to the mediating role of psychological empowerment and knowledge management among military personnel, namely Iranian disciplinary forces. This study is an applied in terms of purpose and it was also conducted through engaging the total population of 250 employees affiliated to the police command center of Boyerahmad city who were selected based on simple random sampling method. Moreover, in terms of data collection procedures, the study was also run through administering different questionnaires including organizational innovation questionnaire (16 items), knowledge management questionnaire (19 items), transformational leadership questionnaire (19 items) and psychological empowerment questionnaire (15 items). Having collected the data, 148 questionnaires were analyzed in smart PLS software.  The findings revealed that transformational leadership has a direct effect on both psychological empowerment and knowledge management, while had an indirect effects on organizational innovations. Additionally, knowledge management entails direct and significant effects on organizational innovation, while playing a mediating role between transformational leadership and organizational innovation. However, the role of psychological empowerment mediator was not confirmed in this study. Finally, in a bid to enable the personnel to identify and analyze the current situations as well as helping them set themselves some clear goals, preventive police mangers should make their attempts to clearly and precisely design and set specific goals for personnel. Furthermore, enhancing the personnel satisfaction through creating supportive and friendly atmosphere and increasing the effectiveness was among the main attempts made by preventive police mangers.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">لازمۀ تغییر و تحولات مستمر سازمانی در محیط‌های پویای امروز، وجود رهبرانی بصیر، راهبردی یا به عبارت روشن‌تر، رهبران تحول‌آفرین است. هدف از این پژوهش تعیین میزان اثرگذاری رهبری تحول‌گرا بر نوآوری سازمانی با توجه به نقش واسطه‌ای مدیریت دانش و تواناسازی روان‌شناختی در بین کارکنان ناجا است. پژوهش حاضر بر مبنای هدف از نوع کاربردی است. جامعۀ آماری پژوهش شامل کلیۀ کارکنان فرماندهی انتظامی شهرستان بویراحمد می‌باشد که از روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی ساده استفاده شده است. در این پژوهش از چهار پرسشنامۀ نوآوری سازمانی که شامل 16 گویه، پرسشنامه مدیریت دانش 19 گویه، پرسشنامه رهبری تحول‌گرا 19 گویه و پرسشنامه تواناسازی روان‌شناختی 15 گویه استفاده شده است. جامعه آماری این پژوهش کلیه کارکنان فرماندهی انتظامی شهرستان بویراحمد می‌باشند که 250 نفر می‌باشند. روش نمونه‌گیری در این تحقیق، تصادفی ساده است که برای جمع‌آوری اطلاعات تعداد 150 پرسشنامه توزیع شد و پس از جمع‌آوری پرسشنامه‌ها، 148 نسخه از آنها قابل استفاده بود که با نرم‌افزار Smart PLS تجزیه و تحلیل شد. یافته‌های این پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که رهبری تحول‌گرا بر مدیریت دانش و تواناسازی روان‌شناختی اثر مستقیم دارد، اما بر نوآوری سازمانی اثر مستقیم ندارد. مدیریت دانش ضمن اثر مستقیم بر نوآوری سازمانی در رابطه بین رهبری تحول‌گرا و نوآوری سازمانی نقش میانجی ایفا می‌کند، اما نقش میانجی تواناسازی روان‌شناختی تأیید نشد. مدیران پلیس پیشگیری ناجا باید اهداف یا آرمان خاصی را به‌ طور روشن و دقیق برای پیروان طراحی کنند تا آنان قادر به شناخت وضعیت موجود، تحلیل آن و حتی قادر به ایجاد انگیزه باشند. همچنین یک جو حمایتی و دوستانه جهت افزایش رضایت کارکنان و در نتیجه اثربخشی آنها فراهم آورند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهبری تحول‌گرا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تسهیل نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تواناسازی روان‌شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارکنان نظامی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_29076_77d884b33917e8fafe959d247918fbb0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
