<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>17</Volume>
				<Issue>65</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Investigation and the Estimation of the Livelihood Level of the Retirees of Iranian Armed Forces: A Prospect for 2025</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی و برآورد وضعیت معیشت بازنشستگان نیروهای مسلح در افق 1404</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>74</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>105</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">27705</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>رسولیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت تولید و عملیات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی،واحد نراق</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>As an extracted study from the comprehensive research conducted in the year 2016, this study was an attempt to investigate and also estimate the livelihood level of the retirees of Iranian armed forces and is also aimed at comparing the retirees’ livelihood level and income with affordability line in the prospect for 2025. For this purpose and also in terms of statistical population, the study was conducted through engaging the population of 111604 annuitant, 5022279 retirees of Iranian armed forces and also 14258 pensioners. As a quantitative field study and in terms of data collection procedures, the required data was collected through investigating the theories about livelihood level of retirees as well as utilizing the data obtained from Iranian official statistic center and Iranian central bank. Having analyzed the data, retirees’ pension of Iranian armed forces are classified as seven groups and the growth of retirees’ pension is also estimated in the prospect of 2025. Thereupon, as a prospect for 2025, the study made a comparison between low affordability line and the retirees’ income in each identified groups. The findings revealed that in terms of comparing appropriate affordability of retirees with life expenses, 90 percent of retirees including groups 1 to 4 will fail to afford life expenses, if current situation continues.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از انجام این تحقیق مطالعه وضعیت معیشتی بازنشستگان ن.م، مقایسه وضعیت معیشتی بازنشستگان ن.م با خط کم‌توانی مالی، تخمین و برآورد خط کم‌توانی مالی و درآمد بازنشستگان ن.م در افق 1404 می‌باشد. جامعه هدف این تحقیق از سه گروه وظیفه‌بگیران، مستمری‌بگیران و بازنشستگان ن.م و شامل 756841 نفر که خود دربرگیرنده 111604 نفر وظیفه‌بگیر، 502279 نفر بازنشسته و 142958 نفر مستمری‌بگیر می‌باشد. مواد و داده‌های مورد نیاز این پژوهش در حوزه نظری با استفاده از نظریه‌‌های مرتبط با معیشت و سطح زندگی و در حوزه میدانی با استفاده از اطلاعات مستند خروجی از بانک مرکزی و مرکز آمار ایران و همچنین گردآوری داده‌های میدانی حقیقی مربوط به جامعه بازنشستگان نیروهای مسلح انجام پذیرفته است. در این تحقیق وضعیت مستمری بازنشستگان ن.م به هفت گروه تقسیم شده و میزان رشد آن تا سال 1404 بر اساس همین روال جاری کشور تخمین زده شد. در انتها مقایسه‌هایی بین خط کم‌توانی مالی و وضعیت درآمدی بازنشستگان ن.م تا سال 1404 برای هر یک از گروه‌ها انجام گرفت. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که در صورت استمرار وضع موجود، گروه‌های اول تا چهارم از بازنشستگان که حدود 90 درصد بازنشستگان را تشکیل می‌دهند، از توانمندی مالی مناسبی در قیاس با هزینه‌های زندگی برخوردار نخواهند بود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کم‌توانی مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خط فقر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درآمد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معیشت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازنشستگان نیروهای مسلح</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_27705_a6394ad2371e93b9163f377c2f291ad0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
