<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>15</Volume>
				<Issue>58</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Requirements of Financial Discipline from Viewpoint of the Supreme Leader-In-Chief; May His Shadow Extend</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ملزومات انضباط مالی از دیدگاه مقام معظم رهبری (حفظه‌الله تعالی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>95</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>118</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">17025</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خسرو</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسفندیاری صفا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مدیریت دفاعی، دانشگاه عالی دفاع ملی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حبیب الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>دهقان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت مالی، مدرس دانشگاه افسری امام علی)ع(</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In the light of reducing unnecessary cost and expenditure and also avoiding luxury- oriented life and extravagance, the financial discipline is identified as an important requirement of every organization. As an applied study and data-based analysis, this study aims at investigating the financial discipline in which the desired results will not be achieved unless observing the financial discipline. For this purpose, in terms of sample population, the study was conducted through investigating the supreme leader’s discourse and statements (May his shadow extend) during the years of 1994 until 2015. Therefore, 20 components of financial discipline were identified. These components including: savings, lack of wastage and extravagance, reforms in judicial organizations, highlighting the role of supervisory organizations, coordination among the three forces, prioritization of cost and expenditure, utilization of financial resources in production rather than consumption, fighting against financial corruption, social discipline, trusting to God and having courage, having piety and righteousness, staying away from luxury-oriented life and avarice , identifying weak points and strong points , planning , coordination of actions with thought and beliefs , making a decisive and effective decisions , faithful and righteous managers , legal-oriented managers and lightening the size of government as well as avoiding the formation of private monopolies. The findings revealed that overall dimensions of data-based analysis resulted in requirements of financial discipline; these requirements are then prioritized through administering a questionnaire via AHP approach. </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">انضباط مالی در راستای کاهش هزینه‌های غیر ضروری و پرهیز از تجمل‌گرایی و اسراف در سازمان‌ها و دستگاه‌های  اداری الزامی به نظر می‌رسد. این مقاله با هدف تدوین ملزومات انضباط مالی صورت گرفته که بدون توجه به آن‌ها، فرایند انضباط مالی به نتیجه مطلوب رهنمون نخواهد شد. این پژوهش از نوع کاربردی بوده که با روش تحقیق تحلیل داده بنیاد صورت پذیرفته است. بر این اساس جامعة آماری شامل بیانات مقام معظم رهبری (حفظه‌الله‌تعالی)، در طول دورة 94-1373 بررسی و 20 مؤلفه برای انضباط مالی احصاء گشت که عبارتند از: صرفه‌جویی، عدم افراط و تفریط، اصلاحات در دستگاه قضایی، پررنگ شدن نقش نهادهای نظارتی، هماهنگی میان سه قوه، اولویت‌بندی مصارف، صرف منابع مالی در تولید به جای مصرف، مبارزه با فساد مالی، انضباط اجتماعی، توکّل به خدا و داشتن شجاعت، داشتن تقوا، دوری از تجمّل‌گرایی و مال‌اندوزی، شناسایی قوّت‌ها و ضعف‌ها، برنامه‌ریزی، هماهنگی کارکرد با افکار و عقاید، گرفتن تصمیمات قاطع و اجرا در عمل، مدیران مؤمن و معتقد، قانون‌گرایی مدیران، کوچک شدن اندازة دولت، جلوگیری از شکل‌گیری انحصار خصوصی. با جمع‌بندی کلی ابعاد تحلیل داده ‌بنیاد، الگویی مشتمل بر ملزومات انضباط مالی به‌دست آمد. در نهایت نیز با استفاده از توزیع پرسشنامه ‌و روش AHP این الزامات اولویت‌بندی گردیدند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">امام خامنه‌ای (حفظه‌الله‌تعالی)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انضباط مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل سلسله مراتبی (AHP)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ملزومات</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_17025_a10b88d9bfb14d69f07ae19d59e1355a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
