<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>44</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>On the relationship between Dutifulness, self-esteem, Discipline and Military Education (A case of Imam Ali University cadets)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رابطه وظیفه‌شناسی، عزت‌نفس و نظم ‌و ترتیب با پرورش نظامی دانشجویان دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>159</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>192</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">3404</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aimed at studying the relationship between three distinct variables including dutifulness, self-esteem, discipline and dimensions of military education (i.e. religiousness, organizational integrity and trust). As an applied research in purpose and field study in design and methodology, the study involved participation of 269 cadets selected based on stratified random sampling who attempted a questionnaire. The data were analyzed through pearson-product correlation and multi-variable linear regression techniques. The results revealed statistically significant correlation among discipline, self-esteem and dutifulness on one hand and religiousness, organizational integrity and trust on the other </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از انجام پژوهش حاضر، بررسی رابطة بین متغیرهای وظیفه‌شناسی، عزت‌نفس و نظم‌ و ترتیب دانشجویان و ابعاد پرورش نظامی(دین‌داری، همبستگی یگانی و اعتماد یگانی) بود. این پژوهش از حیث هدف، پژوهش کاربردی، از نقطه نظر زمان گردآوری، از نوع پیمایشی و از نظر روش‌های جمع‌آوری داده‌ها و اطلاعات، میدانی است. پرسش‌نامه‌ای محقق ساخته بین 269 نفر از دانشجویان دا.اف، به روش تصادفی طبقه‌ای، توزیع گردید. داده‌ها، توسط نرم‌افزار SPSS و به کمک روش‌های آماری همبستگی پیرسون و روش رگرسیون خطی چند متغیره تحلیل گردیدند. نتایج حاصل از تحلیل داده‌ها نشان دادند که در بین متغیرهای مستقل پژوهش، به‌ترتیب متغیر نظم‌ و ترتیب، عزت‌نفس و وظیفه‌شناسی و در بین ابعاد منتسب به پرورش نظامی به‌ترتیب متغیر دین‌داری، همبستگی و اعتماد یگانی، دارای بیشترین میانگین در بین دانشجویان دا.اف می‌باشند. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وظیفه‌شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عزت‌نفس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظم ‌و ترتیب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پرورش نظامی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3404_0ccf90552564502d92de4ea08c63147e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
