<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>42</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>War Strategies and Thoughts of Iranians in (Firdausi’s) Shahnameh</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>راهبردها و تفکرات جنگی ایرانیان در شاهنامه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>147</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>180</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">3484</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>As the greatest epic and national work composed by Firdausi, Shahnameh covers major parts of the affair and social life of the traditional Iranian ethnics. Epic mainly refers to wars and bravery of the past tribes. Explanations of wars in Shahnameh are interwoven with fictions such that they have changed into extraordinary and legendary picture. One of the main components of war is the way it is fought, which is identified as tactics. Shahnameh is rich in terms of war points and commands many of which are compatible with the provisions of codes of conduct and the current war manuals developed in the light of various wars in the world.
This study first offers definitions on war, epic, kinds and causes and nine principles of war and their compatibility with the similar notions in Shahnameh. Then, war and strategies of war in Shahnameh are elaborated. Then, those notions are renamed based on the current and common principles and strategies. Compatibility of these tactics is an indication of the strategic nature of war strategies in Shahnameh.   </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">بزرگترین اثر حماسی و ملی زبان فارسی شاهنامه حکیم ابوالقاسم فردوسی است که بخش مهمی از امور و کیفیات گذشته قوم ایرانی را در بر می‌گیرد. همان طور که می‌دانیم موضوع اصلی حماسه شرح نبردها و دلاوری‌های گذشته اقوام مختلف است. شرح نبردها در شاهنامه، با افسانه‌ها آمیخته شده و چهره‌‌ای اسطوره‌ای و خارق العاده پیدا نموده است. یکی از اجزاء مهم جنگ، شیوه‌های نبرد است که امروزه به آن تاکتیک گفته می‌شود.
شاهنامه مملو از نکات و دستورهای جنگی بوده که بیشتر آنها با مفاد نظام نامه‌ها و کتاب‌های شیوة کارزار فعلی که در نتیجة تجارب جنگ‌های متعدّد دنیا تدوین شده، مطابقت دارد.
در این پژوهش ابتدا تعاریفی از جنگ،حماسه، انواع، علل و اصول نه گانه جنگ و تطبیق آن با شاهنامه ارائه کرده، آنگاه به جنگ و روش‌های نبرد در شاهنامه می‌پردازیم. سپس این جنگ‌ها و روش‌ها مطابق اصول و روش‌های جنگی امروز نامگذاری می‌گردد. تطبیق این روش‌های تاکتیکی، نشان از راهبردی بودن روش‌های جنگی شاهنامه می‌دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاهنامه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حماسه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تاکتیک‌های‌نبرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">راهبردهای جنگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اصول‌جنگ</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_3484_9f18ec3d500f08aa20cf1b32f900bd68.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
