<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>1735-5699</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>62</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Consequences of Managerial Stability in Iranian Public Organizations</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>پیامدهای ثبات مدیریتی در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>22</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">23755</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>دانایی فرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اعظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>فیضی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت دولتی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هانیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری سیاستگذاری بخش عمومی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Public administration is identified as the means of implementation of public policy and is also taken as a crucial factor of success or failure of public administrators in implementing public policy making. The success or the failure of public administrators is deeply affected by the managerial stability or instability. Moreover, managerial stability is taken as the two-dimensional phenomenon which carries both positive and negative consequences. This study was an attempt to investigate the consequences of managerial stability in Iranian public organizations. For this purpose and also in a bid to identify the positive and the negative consequences of managerial stability, in terms of qualitative and quantitative investigation, the study was conducted through administering a questionnaire and also conducting an interview. As a mixed study, this study used a questionnaire and interview to collect the required data and its content validity was assured via expert and elite consultation while the reliability was estimated using Cronbach Alpha method releasing 0.98. Finally, 28 positive and 25 negative consequences of managerial stability were also identified in this study. Additionally, the crucial consequences of managerial stability in Iranian public organizations were respectively identified including implementation of long-term policies and planning as well as resistance to change.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مدیریت دولتی محمل اصلی اجرای خط‌مشی‌های عمومی و در نتیجه تضمین بهروزی افراد جامعه است. یکی از عوامل موفقیت یا شکست آن برای تحقق اهداف خط‌مشی‌ها، مدیران دولتی هستند. همچنین ثبات یا بی‌ثباتی مدیران دولتی نیز یکی از علل ناکامی یا توفیق آنها محسوب می‌شود. ثبات مدیریتی پدیده‌ای دو وجهی است که پیامدهای مثبت و منفی بر آن مترتب است. هدف این مقاله واکاوی این پیامدها در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران است. بدین منظور برای شناسایی پیامدهای مثبت و منفی ثبات مدیریتی از ابزار مصاحبه (مرحله کیفی) و پرسش‌نامه (مرحله کمّی) استفاده شده است؛ بنابراین، این پژوهش از نوع ترکیبی است. روایی مصاحبه و پرسش‌نامه بر اساس نظر خبرگان تأیید و پایایی پرسش‌نامه 98&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 به دست آمد. در مجموع، 28 پیامد مثبت و 25 پیامد منفی ثبات مدیریتی شناسایی شد. مهم‌ترین پیامد مثبت و منفی ثبات مدیریتی در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران به ترتیب عبارت‌اند از: اجرایی شدن برنامه‌ها و خط‌مشی‌های بلندمدت و مقاومت در برابر تغییر.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ثبات مدیریتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بی‌ثباتی مدیریتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاست‌زدگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان دولتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://jmm.iranjournals.ir/article_23755_bc46a6e1fd947acb7ed4f21f16c95a88.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
