<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The effect of extraction condition on Bio active compounds of saffron corm extract</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر شرایط استخراج بر میزان ترکیبات زیست فعال عصاره پیاز زعفران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>89</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>98</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">92890</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2019.170014.1336</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سودابه</FirstName>
					<LastName>عین افشار</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار پژوهش بخش تحقیقات فنی و مهندسی کشاورزی، مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی استان خراسان رضوی، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، مشهد، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پروین</FirstName>
					<LastName>شرایعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار پژوهش بخش تحقیقات فنی و مهندسی کشاورزی، مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی استان خراسان رضوی، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، مشهد، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron is a unique product of Iran and Saffron corm is one of the saffron producing ingredients that is produced annually in high volume in the country. It is shown that saffron corm is a low- cost material, contains some bioactive compounds that are extractable. The extraction method is effected on the kind and amount of bioactive material extracted from saffron corm. Therefore, this research was carried out to produce high value added materials from waste saffron onion. First, the saffron onion was prepared, dried and completely grinding. Extracting was performed using solvent (80% methanol, 80% ethanol and water) and ultrasound (100% intensity, 0, 20 and 40 minutes at room temperature). The extracts were dried at rotary evaporation. In each case, the extraction efficiency, determination of minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC) and minimum bactericidal concentration (MBC), phenolic compounds, iron regeneration strength III, and free radical receptivity were determined. In order to investigate the independent effect (type of solvent, ultrasound intensity) and interaction (solvent type and ultrasound intensity) on bioactive compounds of saffron onion extract, a factorial arrangement of 2 variables with completely randomized design was used in three replications. The mean comparison was done by Duncan method. The results showed that Ethanol solvent extracted 85.84 mg/ml of phenolic compounds with the highest reducing power of FeIII (594.7 μmol/ml) and radical receptivity (59.42%), and the ultrasound process at 100% for 40 minutes extracted the highest amount of phenolic compounds (82.23 mg/ml).</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زعفران محصول منحصر به فرد ایران است و پیاز زعفران از جمله مواد جانبی تولید زعفران است که همه ساله در حجم بالایی در کشور تولید می شود لذا به منظور تولید مواد با ارزش افزوده بالا ازپیاز زعفران ضایعاتی، این تحقیق صورت گرفت. ابتدا پیاز زعفران به مقدار لازم تهیه، خشک و کاملا آسیاب گردید. عملیات استخراج عصاره  با استفاده از حلال ( متانول 80%، اتانول 80% و آب) و دستگاه فراصوت (صوت­دهی با شدت 100 درصد به مدت، 0، 20 و 40 دقیقه در دمای اتاق) انجام ­شد. سپس عصاره­های حاصل، حلال­زدایی و خشک ­شدند. در هر مورد حداقل غلظت مهار­کنندگی (MIC) و حداقل غلظت کشندگی (MBC)، میزان ترکیبات فنلی،  قدرت احیا­کنندگی آهن III و قدرت گیرندگی رادیکال آزاد تعیین شدند. به منظور بررسی اثر مستقل ( نوع حلال، شدت فراصوت) و اثر متقابل (نوع حلال و شدت فراصوت) بر ترکیبات زیست فعال عصاره پیاز زعفران از طرح فاکتوریل 2متغیره با پایه کاملاً تصادفی در سه تکرار استفاده شد و مقایسات میانگین به روش دانکن انجام شد. نتایج نشان دادند حلال اتانول با استخراج   mg.ml&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;84/85 ترکیبات فنلی و دارا بودن بیشترین قدرت مهارکنندگی آهن (µmol.ml&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;74/594) و گیرندگی رادیکال (42/59 درصد) بود و فرایند فراصوت درشدت 100 درصد به مدت 40 دقیقه بالاترین میزان ترکیبات فنلی (mg.ml&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; 23/82) را استخراج نمود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیاز زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قدرت آنتی‌اکسیدانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضد میکروبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قدرت احیاکنندگی آهن</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_92890_f20e22c72977a4bab19719b37638d40c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
