<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Study of genetic variation in some Iranian saffron accessions using molecular markers of RAPD and ISSR</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Majid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shokrpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant professor, University College of Agriculture and Natural resources, University of Tehran, Karaj, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Zeinab</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abedi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Former MSc. Student, University College of Agriculture and Natural resources, University of Tehran, Karaj, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Siamak</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kalantari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate professor, University College of Agriculture and Natural resources, University of Tehran, Karaj, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Salami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant professor, University College of Agriculture and Natural resources, University of Tehran, Karaj, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) is one of the most valuable medicinal and spice herbs in the world. In spite of the ancient cultivation history in Iran, there are limited breeding studies on the plant due to its vegetative reproduction. In order to evaluation genetic diversity of Iranian saffron germplasm, sixty-five different saffron accessions from the main cultivation areas in Khorasan including Torbat heidarieh, Gonabad, Mahvelat, Ghaenat and Ferdows were collected and were studied by molecular markers. The used RAPD and ISSR primers produced 43 and 122 polymorphic markers loci, respectively, and totally 165 markers with average of 7.5 markers by each primer, totally. Diversity index ranged from 0.36 to 0.7 with average of 0.23. Also, marker index with the average of 0.16 varied in the range of 0.2 to 0.7. The accessions from Ghaenat and Mahvelat had the maximum (83.03%) and the minimum (52.73%) polymorphism, respectively. Grouping the studied saffron accessions using cluster analysis displayed four distinct groups which had little correspondence to their collection areas, while clustering for the main cultivation areas had relatively good correspondence to their geographical distances. So, it is expected to have nearly approaching improvements of qualitative and quantitative yields via the selection of superior clones of saffron. Key words: Saffron, Molecular variation, Germplasm, RAPD, ISSR, Khorasan region, clustering .</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>257</start>
					<end>265</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_38672_a12ecb6c22d7c3a653208249142ee923.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2016.38672</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Evaluation of Genetic Diversity in Some Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) Samples of Iran Using RAPD Marker</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fereshteh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Babaee</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc. student of Plant Breeding, Faculty of Agriculture, Ilam University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Zahra</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tahmasebi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, Faculty of Agriculture, Ilam University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Feyzi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Plant Production Department, Saffron Institute, Torbat Heydarieh University, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Arash</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fazeli</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, Faculty of Agriculture, Ilam University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Iran is one of the important distribution centers of medicinal species, including plant saffron (Crocus sativus L.). The presence or absence of genetic diversity in common native and commercial cultivars of saffron of the country has always been one of the important questions for researchers of this filed. In the present study, varioussaffronsamplesfrom different regions of Iran, including seventeen cultivated samplesfrom North Khorasan, Khorasan Razavi, South Khorasan, Lorestan and Ilam, eight wild types (C. haussknechtii) from Lorestan, Kermanshah and Ilam and one wild type (C. cancellatuse) from Kermanshah were collected and then their genetic diversity was obtained using random amplified polymorphism DNA (RAPD) marker. A total number of 161 DNA bands were produced by eight primers with an average of 14.3 bands; the primer Oligo 340 produced the most number of bands. The polymorphism percentage mean was 73.77%. Cluster analysis using UPGMA method divided the samplesinto four groups. In this grouping, there was a minimum distance between saffron populations collected from Kermanshah and Ilam. In other words, these two populations had the maximum genetic similarity with each other. The maximum similarity was observed between the samplescollected from Saleh-Abad and Lomar in Ilam and the minimum similarity was observed between ecotypes collected from Bisotoon in Kermanshah and Torbat-jam in the Khorasan Razavi province. In most cases, samples of different species were divided into different groups such that it can be said that this Genus has a great diversity. Although there are some samples of wild species (C. haussknechtii) that were with saffron crop species in a group in which there exists many molecular Genetics similarities between these species that is indicative of a common genetic background.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>267</start>
					<end>277</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_39230_4a434dfa1bf82c22a40023f14352b570.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2016.39230</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Modelling the Chemical and Microbial Changes of Saffron Flower during Storage Using Artificial Neural Networks and Genetic Algorithm</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Elham</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azarpazhooh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Agricultural Engineering Research Department, Khorasan Razavi Agricultural and Natural Resources Research Center, Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ehtiati</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student, Department of Food Science and Technology, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parvin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sharayei</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Agricultural Engineering Research Department, Khorasan Razavi Agricultural and Natural Resources Research Center, Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Saffron, as the most expensive agricultural and pharmaceutical product of the world, has a special value among plants. Since the Saffron harvesting period is short, its storage for later processing requires understanding the most effective factors affecting the quality of saffron and its deterioration. Therefore the effects of reposition thickness, storage temperature and storage time of saffron flowers on its chemical parameters including crocin, safranal and picrocrocin values of saffron stigma and its microbial quality indicators including total count, coliform and mold contamination were modelled. This was done using multi-layer perceptron artificial neural network (ANN) and its structure and the learning parameters were optimized using genetic algorithm technique. The optimized MLP neural networkwas capable to predict the saffron quality characteristics during storage with coefficient of determinations higher than %94 and low error values (RMSE lower than 3.5 for all responses). The ANN model showed that reposition thickness has the lowest impact on chemical and microbial parameters deterioration while increasing storage temperature and time drastically increased loss of quality although the effect of storage time is lower than that of storage temperature.  Overall, keeping fresh saffron flowers at a low temperature near zero degrees centigrade is necessary for maximum retention of valuable chemical compounds and minimum microbial contamination development during saffron flower storage for further processing.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>279</start>
					<end>289</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_38668_1976fd9779380b3b00c0ce95febc9730.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2016.38668</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identification of Apo- Carotenoids' Crocin and Crocetin Isomers in Saffron Crude Extracts by HPLC Coupled to Atmospheric Pressure Chemical Ionization and High Resolution Orbitrap Mass Spectrometry</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Noraddin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hosseinpour azad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assist. Prof. of Planr breeding-Genetic Engineering, Meshkinshahr Faculty of Agriculture, University of Mohaghegh Ardabili, Meshkinshahr, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ghorban Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nematzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Academic member at Department of Plant Breeding, Sari University of Agriculture, Sari, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Giovanni</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Giuliano</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof., Plant Biology, Department of Biotechnology, Italian National Agency for New Technologies, Rome, Italy.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Gholam Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ranjbar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Academic member at Department of Plant Breeding, Sari University of Agriculture, Sari, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Yamchi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assist. Prof. of Genetic Engineering and Molecular Genetics,Gorgan University of Agricultural Science and Natural Resources Golestan, Gorgan, Iran,</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The main metabolites in saffron are the Apo- carotenoids’ Crocin and Crocetin. Color intensity and quality of saffron mostly depend on the presence of Crocins that are glycosylated steric form of Crocetin by glycosyltransferase enzyme. The aim of this study is the characterization of these metabolites in methanolic and chloroformic extracts of saffron stigmas during anthesis stage by LC-APCI-MS. Identification of cis and trans isomers of Crocin and Crocetin was done by three parameters such as mass spectra registered in the negative ion mode, retention time and absorption ratio related to each metabolites. The variability of these parameters made it possible to detect the Crocins isomer with regard to the attached position and the number of UDP- glucose and Gentiobiosyl molecules to Crocetin structure. Crocins was the mainly detected components as there are polar components that are classified in the carotenoeids groups and the strified form of Crocetin Glucose (β-D-Glucopyranosyl) and Gentiobiose (β-D-Glucopyranosyl-D-Glucose). Also doubly charged ions were found for trans-isomers of Crocin-4, due to the high symmetry of their molecules. Based on the data gathered, the applied chromatograph Machin in this project is accurate and it is most sensitive tools to investigate about plants’ natural components like saffron, also the used APCI-MS in negative ions mode is the most efficient method to distinguish different steric forms of Crocin based on the ion’s fragments related to united reduction of glycosyl and gentiobiosyl as well as molecular fractions.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>291</start>
					<end>300</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_38670_9b56ee1718ee695e4491aee4eb75e89b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2016.38670</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Effect of saffron petal extract on retention quality of fresh-cut watermelon cubes</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">hamed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">kaveh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant professor, Department of Plant Production, University of Torbat Heydarieh,  Torbat Heydarieh, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Saffron is considered as a valuable produce by producers and traders. Unfortunately, the use of its floral by products like petal which have proven to be antioxidant, antimicrobial and nutritional value is limited. In order to investigate the application of saffron petal extracts as an ameliorative on postharvest and processing quality of fresh-cut ‘Crimson Sweet’ watermelon, a completely randomized designed investigation was done on watermelon cubes with 1cm diameter (1±0.5 gram mean weight). Prepared watermelon cubes were divided into four groups and treated with saffron petal extract (10 % V/V) for 10 minutes, UV irradiation (maximum wavelength 253.4 nm and 15W) for 5 minutes, 10 minutes of saffron petal extract then UV irradiation for 5 minutes and control. After the application of treatments, fresh-cut watermelon cubes were stored at 5±0.5 ºC for 14 days. Sampling and observation of the studied characteristics (physiological loss in weight, soluble solid content, lycopene, microbial load and color quality (Chroma Hue)) was done every two days to find the trend of changes during the retention period. The results of experiment showed that petal extract of saffron could not decrease weight loss but it was significantly effective in lowering microbial load and increasing color quality, and prevention of lycopene degradation (P≤5%). Although treatment of UV+SPE had better efficiency to suppress microbial load significantly (P≤5%).</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>301</start>
					<end>312</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_38667_7da9f53d1435856fcd1c446838429e4b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2016.38667</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Comparative Study of information searching behavior of elite saffron farmers with that of normal   saffron farmers in South Khorasan province</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">somaye</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">zadehrahim</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc in Information  and Knowledge Science, Imam Reza International University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">iraj</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">radad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of  Information and Knowledge science, Imam Reza International University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">behzadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of  Information and Knowledge science, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2016</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Saffron is one of export products which has a competitive advantage in Iran and saffron farmers need proper information in order to improve the quality of their agricultural performance. Thus, addressing and identification of their information behavior components, sources, and strategies as well as the challenges and problems would help the authorities to make proper policies and decisions. The present research has been conducted in order to compare elite saffron farmers’ information-searching behavior with that of normal saffron farmers in the South Khorasan province. The study population comprised of all the saffron farmers of South Khorasan province (N =17387). Using Morgan formula and cluster sampling, 375 people were selected for the purpose of this study. The results showed that saffron onion (M=3.58 of 5), pesticides and fertilizers (M=3.56) and farmland worker (3.54) were the main components of saffron farmers’ information-searching of the two groups, respectively. The sources of information for both groups included reference to past experience (M=2.68 of 5), neighboring saffron farmers (M=2.67), contact with informants (2.64) and other family members (M=2.64). The information available in local language (M=4 of 5), by native people (M=3.98), clear and intelligible information (M=3.98) and low cost (M=3.82) were among the main criteria that affect the behavior of the two groups in the use of information sources.  Also they are confronted with common problems such as lack of attention to the needs of farmers (M=3.57 of 5), and insufficient number of technical experts (M=3.42). It was also found that there was no significant relationship between information searching behavior of elite and normal saffron farmers and their performance (r= -0.08, p= 0.133). Regarding the “lack of attention to the needs of farmers by technical experts” as the most major problem, South Khorasan Organization of Agricultural Extension is advised to design and implement relevant training courses based on the information needs of saffron farmers.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2016</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>313</start>
					<end>334</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_39560_a8bfb06862da3347498e723873d75065.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2016.39560</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>