<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1398</YEAR>
<VOL>7</VOL>
<NO>3</NO>
<MOSALSAL>25</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تاثیر زمان قطع آخرین آبیاری و منابع مختلف کودی بر خصوصیات بنه زعفران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Influence of the last irrigation cut-off time and various fertilizer resources on corm characteristics of saffron</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>به‏منظور بررسی تأثیر زمان قطع آخرین آبیاری و منابع مختلف کودی بر خصوصیات بنه‌ زعفران (Crocus sativus L.)، آزمایشی به‌صورت اسپیلت‏پلات در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار در مزرعه‌ چهار ‌ساله تحقیقاتی جهاد کشاورزی واقع در روستای لاله‌زار، شهرستان بردسیر، استان کرمان در سال 95-1394 اجرا شد. تیمارهای آزمایشی شامل زمان قطع آخرین آبیاری (15 روز قبل از زمان عرف منطقه (اول اردیبهشت)، عرف (15 اردیبهشت) و 15 روز بعد از عرف (2 خرداد)) به عنوان عامل اصلی و منابع مختلف کودی (کود گاوی 40 تن در هکتار، کود مرغی 15 تن در هکتار، ورمی‏کمپوست 10 تن در هکتار، اسید هیومیک 2 کیلوگرم در هکتار و کود شیمیایی شامل 200 کیلوگرم در هکتار کود اوره و 140 کیلوگرم در هکتار فسفر و پتاسیم) به عنوان عامل فرعی بود. نتایج تجزیه واریانس نشان داد که تأثیر تیمار قطع آبیاری بر وزن تر و خشک بنه و متوسط وزن بنه معنی­دار (p≤0.05) بود، ولی تأثیر معنی­داری بر تعداد بنه در واحد سطح و تعداد جوانه در بنه نداشت. تأخیر در قطع آبیاری منجر به کاهش معنی‏دار صفات شد. به‏طوری‏که، بیشترین میزان وزن تر (5/516 گرم در متر مربع) و خشک (8/294 گرم در متر مربع) بنه و متوسط وزن بنه (21/4 گرم) در تیمار قطع زود هنگام آبیاری (قبل از عرف) حاصل شد. تأثیر منابع کودی نیز بر کلیه صفات مورد بررسی معنی‏دار بود. تمامی تیمارهای کودی به استثنای اسید هیومیک منجر به افزایش معنی‏دار وزن بنه نسبت به تیمار شاهد شدند. استفاده از ورمی‏کمپوست منجر به تولید بیشترین تعداد بنه در متر مربع (1/137)، وزن تر بنه (6/595 گرم در متر مربع)، وزن خشک بنه (341 گرم در متر مربع) و متوسط وزن بنه (30/4 گرم) شد. بیشترین تعداد جوانه در بنه (83/3) نیز در تیمار مصرف کود شیمیایی بدست آمد. بطورکلی، قطع آبیاری در اوایل اردیبهشت و استفاده از کود آلی ورمی‏کمپوست بهترین شرایط را برای تولید بنه زعفران در منطقه بردسیر کرمان دارا بودند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In order to evaluate the effect of last irrigation cut-off time and various fertilizer resources on corm of saffron (Crocus sativus L.), an experiment was conducted in a split-plot arranged as a randomized complete block design with three replications and 18 treatments in a four year research farm of Jihad ministry located in Lalezar village, Bardsir region, Kerman province, in 2015-2016. The experimental treatments were irrigation cut-off time  (conventional time  (5 May), 15 days before the conventional time (20 April) and 15 days after conventional time (20 May)) assigned to main plot, and nutritional resources (cow manure 40 t ha-1, hen manure15 t.ha-1, vermicompost 10 t.ha-1, humic acid 2 kg.ha-1, and chemical fertilizer containing 200 kg.ha-1 urea and 140 kg.ha-1 P and K) as subplot. The analysis of variance results showed that the effect of irrigation cut-off treatment was significant on corm fresh, dry weight and average weight (P≤0.05), but had no significant effect on the number of corm per area and number of buds per corm. The results showed that the delay in irrigation cut-off led to a significant decrease in traits. As such, the highest corm fresh (561.5 g.m-2) and dry (294.8 g.m-2) weight and average weight of the corm (4.9 gr) were found in earlier irrigation cut-off treatment (before the conventional time). The effect of fertilizer resources on all the studied traits was significant. All the fertilizer treatments with the exception of humic acid, resulted in a significant increase in corm weight compared to control treatment. Application of vermicompost led to the production of the highest number of corm in m-2 (137.1), the corm fresh weight (595.6 g.m-2), dry weight (341 g.m-2) and average weight (4.30 g). The highest number of buds in corm (3.83) was found in chemical fertilizer treatment. In general, the results showed that irrigation cut-off in April with the using vermicompost had the best conditions for producing saffron corm in the Bardsir region of Kerman.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>287</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>300</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>انیس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رضایی</Family>
						<NameE>Anis</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rezaei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی سابق کارشناسی ارشد تولیدات گیاهی، گروه تولیدات گیاهی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی سابق کارشناسی ارشد تولیدات گیاهی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>r.rezayi118@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>روح الله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مرادی</Family>
						<NameE>Rohollah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moradi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه تولیدات گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی بردسیر، دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه تولیدات گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>roholla18@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فیضی</Family>
						<NameE>Hassan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Feizi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hasanfeizi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ورمی‏ کمپوست</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کود گاوی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اسید هیومیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کود مرغی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آبیاری عرف</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Amini, S., Gharedaghi, M., and Sharghi, Y. 2013. Effect of PGPR and vermicompost on soil on saffron side. Third National Conference on Food Security. 5 p. (in Persian with English Summary).##Amiri, M.E. 2008. Impact of animal manures and chemical fertilizers on yield components of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). American-Eurasian Journal of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences 4 (3): 274-279.##Arancon, N.Q., Edwards, C.A., Bierman, P., Welch, C., and Metzeger, J.D. 2004. Influences of vermicomposts on field strawberries: effects on growth and yields. Bioresource Technology 93: 145-153.##Asadi, G.A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Hasanzadeh Aval, F. 2014. The effect of soil and foliarapplication of nutrients on corm growth flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in six- year- old farm. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (1): 31-44. (In Persian with English Summary).##Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A.R., Nassiri, M., and Rezvani Moghadam, P. 2005. Evaluation of quantitative relationships between saffron yield and nutrition (on farm trial). Iranian Journal of Field Crop Research 3: 1-14. (In Persian with English Summary).##Chen, S.Y., Zhang, Y.X., Pei, D., and Sun, H. 2005. Effect of corm straw mulching on soil temperature and soil evaporation of winter field. Transaction of Chinese Society of Agricultural Engineering 21: 171-173.##Farokh-Shahe, S. 2011. Effect of different levels of nitrogen and vermicompost organic fertilizer on onion yield. First National Conference on Environmental Conservation and Planning. 20 p. (In Persian with English Summary).##Feizi, H., Seyyedi, S.M., and Sahabi, H. 2015. Effect of corm planting density, organic and chemical fertilizers on formation and phosphorus uptake of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) replacement corms during phonological stages. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2: 289-301.(In Persian with English Summary).##Hardtke, C. 2003. Gibberllin signaling: Grass growing roots. Current Biology 13: 366-367.##Haynes, R.J. 1996. Labile organic matter fraction as central components of the quality of agricultural soils. Advances in Agronomy 85: 221-261.##Herrera-Pantoja, M., and Hiscock, K.M. 2015. Projected impacts of climate change on water availability indicators in a semi-arid region of central Mexico. Environmental Science and Policy 54: 81-89.##Ilan, I. 1971. Evidence for hormonal regulation of the selectivity of ion uptake by plant cells. Physiologia Plantrum 25: 230- 233.##Jasmi, K.H., Karduny, F., and Behdani, M. 2009. Evaluation of the use of fertilizers and its impact on the performance of farms. Congress&#039;s challenges fertilizer, fertilizer half a century. Tehran Olympic Hotel, 10-12 March 2009.##Khatamian, N., Nabavi Kalat, M., and Bakhsh Kalarestaghi, K. 2011. Effects of humic acid on morphological characteristics and grain yield of triticale cv. Javanilu. The first national conference on new issues in agriculture, Islamic Azad University, Sabzevar Branch.##Koocheki, A., Seyyedi, S.M., and Jamshid Eyni, M. 2014. Effect of irrigation levels and high corm density on growth and phosphorus uptake of daughter corms of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Crop Science 16: 222–235.##Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Mollafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2013. Effects of corm planting density and applying manure on flower and corm yields of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in the first year. Journal of Agroecology 8: 22-31. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Fallahi, H.R., and Aghhavani Shajari, M. 2016. Growth response of saffron replacement corms to planting date, irrigation management and associated crops. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 4: 3-18. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Tabrizi, L., Jahani, M., and Mohammad Abadi, A.A. 2011. Evaluation of high corm density and three methods planting on some agronomic traits of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) and corm situation. Horticulture Science 42 (4): 379-391. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A.R., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Fallahi, H.R. 2015. Effects of planting dates, irrigation management and cover crops on growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L). Agroecology 8 (3): 435-451. (In Persian with English Summary).##Martin, J.P., Black, J.H., and Hawthorne, R.M. 1997. Influence of earthworm-processed pig manure on the growth and yield of greenhouse tomatoes. Bioresource Technology 75: 175-180.##Masoomi, Z., Haghnia, Gh., and Lakzian, A. 2011. Influence of biological, chemical and organic fertilizer on saffron characteristics. MSc Thesis, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran. 87 p.##Mollafilabi, A. 2012. Effect of extensive range of corm weight on yield components and flowering characters of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) under greenhouse conditions. 4th International Saffron Symposium. Kashmir, India, 22-25 October 2012.##Moradi, R., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Nasiri Mahallati, M., and Nezhadali, A. 2011. Effects of organic and biological fertilizers on fruit yield and essential oil of sweet fennel (Foeniculum vulgare var. dulce). Spanish Journal of Agricultural Research 9 (2): 546-553.##Myers, B.J., Theiveyanathan S., O’brien, N.D., and Bond, W.J. 1996. Growth and water use of Eucalyptus grandis and Pinus radiata plantations irrigated with effluent. Tree Physiology 16: 211-219.##Nehvi, F.A., Khan, M.A., and Lone, A.A. 2010. Impact of microbial inoculation on growth and yield of saffron in Kashmir. Acta Horticulturae 850 (31):171-174.##Omidi, H., Naghdibadi, H.A., Golzad, A., Torabi, H., and Fotoukian, M.H. 2009. The effect of chemical and bio-fertilizer source of nitrogen on qualitative and quantitative yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Medicinal Plant 8: 98–109.##Rahimi, H., and Kamali, K. 1993. Laboratory studies on biology of bulb mite Rhizoglyphus robini (Acari: Acaridae) and its damages on saffron corm in Gonabad and Qaen. The Scientific Journal of Agriculture 16: 53-63. (In Persian with English Summary).##Rahimi, H., Mokhtarian, A., Bazoobandi, M., Rahimi, H., Kiani, M., and Behdad, M. 2008. Effects of sowing depth and summer irrigation on Rhizoglyphus robini (Acari: Acaridae) population in Gonabad. Applied Entomology and phytopathplogy 76 (1): 1-12. (In Persian with English Summary).##Rahimi, H., Dadmand, M., Torabi, E., Rahimi, H., Torabi, H., and Araghi, M. 2013. Investigating the effects of soil solarization on saffron field against bulb mite (Rhizoglyphus robini). Plant Protection (Scientific Journal of Agriculture) 36 (2): 1-15. (In Persian with English Summary).##Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Koocheki, A., Molafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2013. Effect of biological and chemical fertilizers on replacement corm and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 15: 234–246. (In Persian with English Summary).##Rezvani-Moghaddam, P, Mohammad-Abadi, A.A., Fallahi, H.R., and Aghhavani-Shajari, M. 2014. Effects of nutrient management on flower yield and corm characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Horticultural Science 28: 427–434.##Sabzevari, S., Khazaie, H.R., and Kafi, M. 2009. Effect of humic acid on root and shoot growth of two wheat cultivars (Triticum aestivum L.). Journal of Water and Soil 23: 87-94. (In Persian with English Summary).##Sadeghi, B., Aghamiri, A., and Negari, K. 2003. Effect of summer irrigation on saffron flowering. 3rd National Symposium on Saffron. 2-3 December 2009, Mashhad, Iran. (In Persian).##Samiran, R., Kusum, A., Biaman, K.D., and Ayyanadar, A. 2010. Efect of organic amendments of soil on growth and productivity of three common crops viz. Zea mays, Phaseolus vulgaris and Abelmoschus esculentus. Applied Soil Ecology 45: 78-84.##Sepaskhah, A.R., and Kamgar Haghighi, A.A. 2009. Saffron irrigation regime. International Journal of Plant Production 3 (1): 1-16.##Sharifi Ashoor Abadi, A. 1998. Evaluation of soil fertility in agroecosystems. Ph.D. Thesis. Islamic Azad Univesity of Oloum Tahghighat. Tehran, Iran. (In Persian).##Sharma, S., Pradhan, K., Satya, S., and Vasudevan, P. 2005. Potentiality of earthworms for waste management and in other uses: a review. The Journal of American Science 1: 4–16.##Shirani, H., Abolhasani Zeraatkar, M., Lakzian, A., and Akhgar, A. 2011. Decomposition rate of municipal wastes compost, vermincompost, manure and pistaco compost in different soil texture and salinity in laboratory condition. Iranian Journal of Agroecology 25: 84–93. (In Persian with English Summary).##Teimori, S., Behdani, M.A., Ghaderi, M.G., and Sadeghi, B. 2013. Investigation on the effect of organic and chemical fertilizers on morphological and agronomic of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm criteria. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (1): 36-47. (In Persian with English Summary).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اثر مقدار و زمان کاربرد مالچ بقایای گندم بر گلدهی و خصوصیات مرفولوژیکی بنه‌های دختری زعفران  Crocus sativus L</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Effect of amount and time of wheat straw application as mulch on flowering and morphological characteristics of replacement corms of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> به‌منظور بررسی تأثیر زمان پخش و مقادیر کاربرد کاه و کلش گندم بر عملکرد گل و بنه گیاه دارویی زعفران آزمایشی به‌صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح بلوک­­های­کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار در مزرعه ایستگاه تحقیقات کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی گناباد وابسته به مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی خراسان رضوی (بخش زعفران و گیاهان دارویی) در دو سال زراعی 95-94 و 96-95 اجرا شد. فاکتورهای آزمایش شامل مقدار کاربرد کلش گندم (2، 4، 6 و 8 تن در هکتار) و زمان کاربرد کلش گندم (اول خردادماه، 15تیرماه و اول شهریورماه به‌صورت پخش سطحی) بودند. نتایج تجزیه واریانس حاکی از تأثیر معنی­دار زمان پخش مالچ کلش گندم، مقادیر کاربرد مالچ و نیز اثر متقابل آن­ها بر تمامی شاخص­های گلدهی زعفران در سطح یک درصد بود. پخش مالچ کلش در اول خردادماه در مقایسه با اول شهریورماه بیشترین تأثیر را در افزایش تعداد گل، عملکرد گل و عملکرد کلاله خشک زعفران (به­ترتیب تا 7/41 ، 9/16و 50 درصد) داشت. همچنین تمامی شاخص­های موردمطالعه بنه­های دختری زعفران به‌طور معنی­داری تحت تأثیر زمان پخش مالچ کلش، سطوح کلش و نیز اثرات متقابل آن­ها در سطح یک درصد قرار گرفت. در بین تیمارهای موردبررسی، بیشترین افزایش در عملکرد بنه­های بیش از 8 گرم (7/687گرم) و عملکرد کل بنه­های دختری زعفران(4/1382گرم ) در نتیجه کاربرد 8 تن مالچ کلش در خردادماه مشاهده شدکه نسبت به تیمار مصرف 2 تن در هکتار بقایا در همان تاریخ به­ترتیب افزایش2/62 و 7/77درصدی را نشان می‌دهد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In order to investigate the effect of spreading time and application rates of wheat straw as mulch on Saffron corm and flower yield, a field experiment was conducted as factorial layout based on randomized complete block design with three replications at Gonabad Agricultural and Natural Resources Research Station, Center for Research and Agricultural Education and Natural Resources of Khorasan Razavi in years 2015-16. The treatments were all combination of wheat straw in four levels (2, 4, 6 and 8 t.ha-1) and time of wheat straw spreading in three dates (22 June, 6 July and 23August). The results showed that the rate and time of straw application and their interaction had significant effect on all studied characteristics of saffron flower. Spreading of wheat straw at 22 June compared to 6 July and 23August had the highest significant effect on increasing flower number, fresh flower yield, dry stigma and style yield (up to 41.7, 16.9 and 50 percent, respectively). In addition, all studied criteria of saffron replacement corms were significantly affected by the time of wheat straw spreading, different levels of wheat straw application and their interactions. Among the studied treatments, the highest corm yield in terms of more than 8g (595.65 g) and total saffron replacement corms yield were obtained in applying 8 t.ha-1 wheat straw at 22 June (1163 g). Compared to the treatment of 2 tons per hectare, the remnants on the same date show an increase of 112.2 and 12.9 percent, respectively.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>301</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>318</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>هریوندی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohhamad Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hrivandi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری اگروتکنولوژی، گرایش اکولوژی گیاهان زراعی، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری اگروتکنولوژی، گرایش اکولوژی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.harivandi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پرویز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رضوانی مقدم</Family>
						<NameE>Parviz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rezvani Moghaddam</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rezvani@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سرور</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خرم دل</Family>
						<NameE>Surur</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khorramdel</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khorramdel@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی اکبر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مویدی</Family>
						<NameE>A. A.</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moayedi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیات علمی مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی خراسان رضوی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیات علمی مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>moayediali@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بنه دختری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تعداد گل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خامه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلاله خشک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مالچ کلش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aghaei, M., and Rezagholizadeh, M. 2011. Iran&#039;s comparative advantage in production of saffron. Journal of Agricultural Economics and Development 25: 121–132. (In Persian).##Alizadeh, A., Sayari, N., Ahmadian, J., and Mohamadian, A. 2009. Study for zoning the most appropriate time of irrigation of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Khorasan Razavi, north and southern provinces. Journal of Water and Soil 23 (1): 109-118. (In Persian with English Summary).##Amirshekari, H., Sorooshzadeh, A., Modaress Sanavy, A.M., and Jalali Javaran, M. 2007. Effects of root-zone temperature, corm size, and gibberellin on vegetative##growth of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Agricultural Science and Natural Resources 14 (5): 96-104.##Arsalani, F., Rasouli, S.J., and Asgharzadeh, K. 2015. The effect of meteorological factors (rainfall, temperature, relative humidity, freezing days and sunny hours) on yield of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Kashmar and Ghaenat Towns. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 3 (1): 66-75. (In Persian with English Summary).##Azizi-Zohan, A., Kamgar Haghighi, A.A., and Sepaskhah, A.R. 2008. Crop and pan coefficients for saffron in a semi-arid region of Iran. Journal of Arid Environments 72: 270-278.##Basereh, A., Eslami, S.V., and Aghajani, M. 2015. Evaluating theimpact of type and amount of plant stubble mulch on temperature fluctuations of the soil surface. 6th Iranian Weed Science conference, Birjand, 10-12 September 2015, pp. 551-554. (In Persian with English Summary).##Bastian, F., Bouziri, L., Nicolardot, B., and Ranjard, L. 2009. Impact of wheat straw                  decomposition on successional patterns of soil microbial community structure. Soil Biology and Biochemistry 41: 262–275.##Behboodi, B.S., and Samadi, L. 2004. The morphological study of amyloplast distribution in Saffron(Crocus sativus L.)fibrous roots. ISHS Acta Horticulturae. First International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Biotechnology 650 (3): 49–54.##Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A., Nassiri, M., and Rezvani Moghaddam, P. 2006. The evaluation of quantitative relationships between saffron yield and nutrition (on farm trial). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 3 (1): 1–14. (In Persian with English Summary).##Chen, S.Y., Zhang, X.Y., Pei, D., Sun, H.Y., and Chen, S.L. 2007. Effects of straw mulching on soil temperature, evaporation and yield of winter wheat: Field experiments on the North China Plain. Annals of Applied Biology 150 (3): 261–268.##Cheraghi, S., Rafiei, M., and Khorgami, A. 2011. The effect of foliar application of nitrogen at different dates, planting method on grain yield, and yield components of mung bean in the environmental conditions of Khoramabad. Journal of Crop Physiology 3 (9): 15-29. (In Persian with English Summary).                  ##Du Prezz, C.C., Steyn, J.T., and Kotze, E. 2001. Long-term effects of wheat residue management on some fertility indicators of a semi-arid plinth sol. Soil and Tillage Research 63 (1-2): 25–33.##Danga, B.O., and Wakindiki, I.I.C. 2009. Effect of placement of straw mulch on soil conservation, nutrient accumulation, and wheat yield in a humid Kenyan highland. Journal of Tropical Agricuture 47 (1): 30–36.##Gresta, F., Avola, G., Lombardoa, G.M., Siracusa, L., and Ruberto, G. 2009. Analysis of flowering, stigma yield and qualitative traits of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) as affected by environmental conditions. Horticultural Sciences 119 (3): 320–324.##Jamshidian, R., and Khajehpoor, M.R. 1999. Effects of seedbed preparation methods on soil nutrition, compaction and mungbean establishment after wheat harvesting. Journal of Agricultural Sciences and Natural Resources 2 (3): 35-46. (In Persian with English Summary).##Jorabloo, A., ghoshchi, F., Morteza, A., and Silispoor, M. 2009. Effect of seedbed preparation and barley residue on corn forage yield and quality. Crop Ecophysiology 1 (3): 44-53. (In Persian with English Summary).##Kafi, M., Rashed Mohassel, M.H., Koocheki, A., and Mollafilabi, K. 2002. Saffron, Production and Processing. Zaban va Adab Publication, Mashhad. 276 p. (In Persian).##Kamkar, B., and Mahdavi Damghani, A. 2008. Principle of Sustainable Agriculture. University Jihad of Mashhad Press. 316 p.##Khan, I.A. 2004. Induced mutagenic variability in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). ISHS Acta Horticulture. First International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Biotechnology 650: 281–284.##Koocheki, A., Nassiri Mahallati, M., and Jafari, L. 2016. Study of the impact of climate change on agriculture in Iran: 1- anticipating agro-climatic status of the future. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 13 (4): 651-664. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Siahmarguee, A., Azizi, G., and Jahani, M. 2011b. Effect of high density planting and sowing depth on agronomic characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)##and corms behavior. Journal of Agroecology 1 (3): 36-49. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Jahani, M., Tabrizi, L., and Mohammad Abadi, A.A. 2011. Investigation on the Effect of biofertilizer, chemical fertilizer and plant density on yield and corm criteria of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Water and Soil 25: 196–206. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Alizadeh, A., and Ganjali, A.S. 2010. Effect of temperature increase on flowering behavior of saffron. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 8 (2): 324-335. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Fallahi, H.R. 2010. Effects of planting time and irrigation on quantitative indices of saffron. In: Fifth National Symposium of Red Gold (Saffron), Qayen, Iran, November. (In Persian).##Koocheki, A., Nassiri Mahallati, M., Alizadeh, A., and Ganjali, A. 2010. Modelling the impact of climate change on flowering behaviour of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal Field Crops Research 7 (2): 583–594. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Gholami, A., Mahvadi Damghani, A., and Tabrizi, L. 2007. Organic Field Crop Handbook. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Press, Iran. 385 p. (In Persian).##Koocheki, A., Nassiri Mahallati, M., Kamali, G.A., and Shahandeh, H. 2006. Potential impacts of climate change on agroclimatic indicators in Iran. Arid land Research and Management 20 (3): 245-259.##Kumar, R., Singh, V., Devi, K., Sharma, M., Singh, M.K., and Ahuja, P.S. 2008. State of art of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)agronomy: A comprehensive review. Food Reviews International 25 (1): 44-85. ##Limon-Ortega, A., Govaerts, B., and Sayre, K.D. 2008. Straw management, crop rotation, and nitrogen source effect on wheat grain yield and nitrogen use efficiency. European Journal of Agronomy 29 (1): 21-28.##JafarBiglo, M., and Mobaraki, Z. 2009. Land suitability of Qazvin province for saffron cultivation based on multi-criteria decision-making pproach. Physical Geography Research 66: 101-119. (In Persian with English Summary).##Molina, R.V., Garcıa Luis, A., Coll, V., Ferrer, C., and Valero, M. 2004. Flower formation in the saffron Crocus (Crocus sativus L.). The role of temperature. Acta Horticulture 650: 39–47.##Molina, R.V., Valero, M., Navaro, Y., Garcia Luis, A., and Guardiola, J.L. 2004. The effect of time of corm lifting and duration of incubation at inductive temperature on flowering in the saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Scientia Horticulturae 103 (1): 79-91.## Molina, R., Valero, M., Navarro, Y., Guardiola, J., and Garcıa-Luis, A. 2005. Temperature effects on flower formation (Crocus sativus L.). Spain: Scientia Horticulturae 103: 361-379.##Monzon, J.P., Sadras, V.O., and Andrade, F.H. 2006. Fallow soil evaporation and water storage as affected by stubble in sub-humid (Argentina) and semi-arid (Australia) environments. Field Crops Research 98: 83–90##Naderi Darbaghshahi, M.R., Khajebashi, S.M., Banitaba, S.A., and Dehdashti, S.M. 2009. Effects of planting method, density and depth on yield and production period of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Isfahan region. Seed and Plant Production 24 (4): 643–657. (In Persian with English Summary).##Najafinezhad, H., Javaheri, M.A., Ravari, S.Z.A., and Azad Shahraki, F.A.D. 2009. Effect of crop rotation and wheat residue management on grain yield of maize cv KSC704 and some soil properties. Seed and Plant Production Journal 25 (2): 247–260. (In Persian with English Summary).##Nassiri Mahallati, M., Koocheki, A., Boroomand Rezazadeh, Z., and Tabrizi, L. 2007. Effects of corm size and storage period on allocation of characters of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) under assimilates in different parts of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 5 (1): 155-166. (In Persian with English Summary).##Nehvi, F.A., Lone, A.A., Khan, M.A., and Maghdoomi, M.I. 2010. Comparative study on effect of nutrient management on growth and yield of saffron under temperate conditions of Keshmir. Acta Horticulturae. Third International Symposium on Saffron: Forthcoming Challenges in Cultivation, Research and Economics, 850: 165–170.##Pandey, D., Pandey, V.S., and Srivastava, R.P. 1979. A note on the effect of the size of corms on the sprouting and flowering of saffron. Progressive Horticulture 6: 89-92.##Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Koocheki, A., Molafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2013. Effect of biological and chemical fertilizers on replacement corm and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Crop Sciences 15: 234–246. (In Persian with English Summary).##Sadeghi, B. 1993. Effect of corm weight on saffron flowering. Iranian Research Organization for Science and Technology pp. 52-53. (In Persian).##Sadeghi, B. 1996. Effects of corm size on flower production in saffron. Annual Report Scientific and Industrial Research Organization of Khorasan, Mashhad, Iran. (In Persian).##Sadeghi, B., Razavi, M., and Mohajeri, M. 1987. Effect of Chemical Elements on Saffron Cultivation Improvement. Khorasan Agricultural Research Center Publication. (In Persian). ##Shabahang, J., Khorramdel, S., Amin Ghafori, A., and Gheshm, R. 2013. Effects on management of crop residues and cover crop planting on density and population of weeds and agronomical characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Saffron Research 1: 57–72. (In Persian with English Summary).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مطالعه برهمکنش کود بیولوژیک نیتروکسین و مدیریت آبیاری بر عملکرد کمی و کیفی زعفران Crocus sativus L</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Study of the interaction of nitroxin biological fertilizer and irrigation management on quantitative and qualitative yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در راستای افزایش عملکرد کیفی و کمی زعفران، در اثر برهمکنش کود بیولوژیک نیتروکسین و مدیریت آبیاری، آزمایشی در سال زراعی 96-1395 در استان البرز (اشتهارد) اجرا شد. آزمایش به صورت کرت‌های یک بار خرد شده (اسپلیت پلات) در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با 3 تکرار انجام شد. فاکتورهای آزمایشی شامل روش آبیاری (آبیاری به‌صورت نوارهای تیپ سطحی، زیر سطحی (عمق 15 سانتی‌متری) و آبیاری معمول (عرف منطقه) در کرت اصلی) و کود بیولوژیک نیتروکسین (عدم مصرف (شاهد)، دو، چهار و شش لیتر در هکتار در کرت فرعی) بود. یافته‌های این تحقیق نشان داد که اثر ساده و برهمکنش کاربرد کود بیولوژیک نیتروکسین و مدیریت آبیاری در تمام صفات مورد اندازه‌گیری معنی‌دار بود. به منظور استفاده‌ی بهینه از منابع آب، جهت کاهش تلفات آبیاری و دست‌یابی به عملکرد بالا در تولید زعفران، از روش آبیاری قطره‌ای (تیپ زیر سطحی) می‌توان استفاده کرد. اعمال مدیریت آبیاری قطره‌ای نوار تیپ زیرسطحی به همراه کود بیولوژیک نیتروکسین 4 لیتر در هکتار نسبت به سایر تیمارهای مورد آزمایش برتری داشته است به‌طوری‌که بیشترین عملکرد کلاله زعفران نیز در این تیمار با 08/5 کیلوگرم در هکتار مشاهد شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In order to increase the quality and yield of saffron, an experiment was conducted in the Alborz province, (Eshtehard), in the year 2016-2017 through the interaction of nitroxin biological fertilizer and irrigation management. The experiment was conducted as split plot in randomized complete block design with 3 replications. The experimental factors included irrigation method (Surface drip Irrigation, Subsurface drip Irrigation (15 cm depth) and Irrigation is Common (conventional area) in the main plot) and biological fertilizer of nitroxin (no fertilizer (control), 2, 4 and 6 lit.ha-1 in the Subplot). The results of this study showed that simple and interaction effects of biological fertilizer application of nitroxin and irrigation management were significant in all measured traits. In order to use optimal water resources, diamond irrigation method (Subsurface drip Irrigation) can be used to reduce irrigation losses and achieve high yield in saffron production. The effects of irrigation management of Subsurface  drip Irrigation diameters with biological fertilizer of nitroxin 4 lit.ha-1 were superior to other treatments, so that the highest yield of saffron stigma was observed in this treatment with 5.8 kg.ha-1.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>319</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>330</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احسان اله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جلیلی</Family>
						<NameE>Ehsan Ollah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jalili</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری گروه زراعت و کارشناس ارشد حفظ نباتات مدیریت جهاد کشاورزی شهرستان اشتهارد، البرز، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری گروه زراعت و کارشناس ارشد حفظ</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>dr.jaliliehsan59@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فرناز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گنج آبادی</Family>
						<NameE>Farnaz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ganjabadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری گروه زراعت، واحد شهر قدس، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری گروه زراعت، واحد شهر قدس، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>fganjabadi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>داود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حبیبی</Family>
						<NameE>davod</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>habibi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هئیت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی کرج، البرز، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هئیت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی کرج، البرز،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>d_habibi2004@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عیوضی</Family>
						<NameE>alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>eivazi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار پژوهشی بخش تحقیقات نهال و بذر، مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی استان آذربایجان غربی، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، ارومیه، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار پژوهشی بخش تحقیقات نهال و بذر، مرکز</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>alirezaeivazi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پیکروکروسین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سافرانال</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کروسین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روش آبیاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abdullaev, F.I. 2009. Cancer chemopreventive and tumoricidal properties of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Experimental Biology and Medicine 227: 20–25.##Bhaskara, K.V., and Charyulu, P.B.N. 2005. Evaluation of effect of effecty of inoculation of Azospirillum on yield of Setaria italica. African Journal of Biotechnology 9: 989-995.##Cakmakc, R., Donmez, M.F., and Erdogan, U. 2007. The effect of plant growth promoting Rhizobacteria on barley seeding growth, nutrient uptake, some soil properties, and bacteria counts. Turkish Journal of Agriculture and Forestry 31: 189-199.##Ghamarnia., H., Khosravi, H., Jalili, Z., and Bahrami naghad, A. 2015. Investigating different irrigation and water management methods on yield and water use efficiency of grains. Journal Water and Irrigation Management 5 (1): 55-67. (In Persian).##Ghavi., M., and Haghighi, R. 2015. Effect of spraying biological fertilizers, biological and chemical stimulants on growth characteristics and saffron performance. Journal of Crop Production 8 (3): 139-158. (In Persian).##Glick, B.R. 1995. The enhancement of plant growth by free-living bacteria. Can. Journal of Microbiology 41: 109–127.##Gresta, F., Lombardo, G.M., Siracusa, L., and Ruberto, G. 2008. Saffron, an alternative crop for sustainable agricultural systems. A review. Agronomy for Sustainable Development 21: 88-91.##Gutierrez-Manero., FJ, Ramos-Solano, B., Probanza, A., Mehouachi, J., Tadeo, F.R., and Talon, M. 2001. The plant-growth promoting rhizobacteria Bacillus pumilus and Bacillus licheniformis produce high amounts of physiologically active gibberellins. Journal of Plant Physiology 11: 206–211.##Hamedi, F., Jafari, H., Ghaderi, J., and Zanganeh, R. 2005. Comparison of drip irrigation (tape) with surface irrigation methods in the different levels of irrigation on corn yield. Journal Water Research in Agriculture 3: 120-131. (In Persian).##Han, H.S., Supanjani, B., and Lee, K.D. 2006. Effect of coin coculation with phosphate andpotassium solubilizing bacteria on mineral uptake and growth of pepper and cucumber. Plant, Soil and Environment 52: 36-46.##Iran National Standard. 1996. Determination of moisture in dried fruit, ISIRI NUMBER: 672. Institute of Standards and Industrial Research of Iran. 5st. Edition.##Jin, L., and Yong, W. 2001. Water use in agriculture in China; importance, challenges, and implications for policy. Journal of Water Policy 3: 215-228.##Kapoor, R., Giri, B., and Mukerji, K.G. 2004. Improved growth and essential oil yield and quality in Foeniculum vulgare mill on mycorrhizal inoculation supplemented with P-fertilizer. Bioresource Technology 93: 307–311.##Kafi, M., Rashed Mohassel, M.H., Koocheki, A., and Mollafilabi, A. 2002. Saffron Production and Processing. Zaban va Adab Press, Iran. pp. 50-60. (In Persian).##Kucey, R.M.N. 1988. Effect of penicillium bilaji on the sail and uptake of P and, micronutrients from soil by wheat. Canadian Journal of Soil Science 68: 261-270.##Kumar, V., Behl, R.K., and Narula, N. 2009. Effect of phosphate solubilizing strains of Azotobacter chroococcum on yield traits and their survival in the rhizosphere of wheat genotypes under field conditions. Acta Agronomica Hungarica 49: 141–149.##Lamm., F.R., and Trooien, T.P. 2003. Subsurface drip irrigation for corn production: a review of 10 years of research in Kansas. Journal of Irrigation Science 22: 195–200.##Mahdavi, A. 2000. Supporting collaborative design via integrated building performance computing. 12th International Conference on Systems Research, Informatics and Cybernetics, Baden-Baden, Germany. 23–25 August 2000. pp. 91–96.##Mardani Booldaji, E. 2006. Water resources management and beard against drought. Journal of Jihad July and Agust 27: 202-210. (In Persian).##Naderi Darbaghshahi, M.R., Khajeh-bashi, S.A., banitaba, S.A., and Dehdashti, S.M. 2008. Effects of planting method, density and depth on yield and production period of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Isfahan region. Seed Seedling 24: 643-657. (In Persian with English Summary).##Nassiri Mahallati, M., Koocheki, A., Boroumand Rezazadeh, Z., and Tabrizi, L. 2008. Effects of corm size and storage period on allocation of assimilates in different parts of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 1: 155-166. (In Persian with English Summary).##Nieto, K.F., and Frankenberger, W.T. 1989. Biosynthesis of cytokinins produced by Azotobacter chroococcum. Journal Soil Biology and Biochemistry 21: 967-972.##Nieto, K.F, and Frankenberger, W.T. 1991. Influence of adenine, isopentyl alcohol and Azotobacter chroococcum on vegetative growth of Zea mays. Plant, Soil and Environment 135: 213-221.##Osareh., G.H., Motamedi, B., and Aalkhaszadeh., H. 2006. Irrigation efficiency of the irrigation network of integrated and non-integrated Dez. National Conference on Irrigation And Drainage Systems Management Collection, Shahid Chamran University, Faculty of Water Sciences Engineering, 12-14 May 2006.##Ríos, J.L., Recio, M.C., Giner, R.M., and Manez, S. 1996. An update review of saffron and its active constituents. Journal Phytotherapy Research 10: 189-193.##Rawia, A.S. Eid, A., Abo-sedera, A., and Attia, M. 2006. Influence of nitrogen fixing bacteria incorporation with organic and/or inorganic nitrogen fertilizers on growth, flower yield and chemical composition of Celosia argentea. World Journal of Agricultural Sciences 2: 450-458.##Roze., I.W., Felton, W., and Banks, L. 2012. Response of soybean varieties to foliar zinc fertilizer. Australian Journal of Experimental Agriculture and Animal Husbandry 21 (109): 236-240.##Rojas, A., Holguin, G., Glick, B., and Bashan, Y. 2001. Synergism between Phyllobacterium sp. (N2 – Fixer), and Bacillus licheniformis (P-Solubilizer), both from a Semiarid mangrove rhizosphere. Journal FEMS (Federation of European Microbiological Societies) Microbiology Ecology 35: 181-187.##Temperini, O., Rea, R., Temperini, A., Colla, G., and Rouphael, Y. 2009. Evaluation of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) production in Italy: Effects of the age of saffron fields and plant density. Food, Agriculture and Environment 7: 19-23.##Wang, S.H., Yang, Z.M., Yang, H., Lu, B., Li, S.Q., and Lu, Y.P. 2004. Copper-induced stress and antioxidative responses in roots of Brassica juncea. Botanical Bulletin of Academia Sinica 45: 203-212.##Zabihi, H., Rezayain, S., Ghasemzadeh-Ghanji, M., and Passban, M. 2016. Tempeoral changes of nutrient element in leaf saffron. 12th Iranian Soil Science Congress, Tabriz, Iran. May 2016. (In Persian).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تنوع ژنتیکی قارچ Alternaria alternata عامل پوسیدگی زعفران با استفاده از نشانگرهای ملکولی در استان‌های خراسان رضوی و جنوبی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Genetic Diversity of Alternaria alternata the Causal Agent of Saffron Rot in Southern and Razavi Khorasan Provinces Using Molecular Markers</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>بیماری لکه موجی با عامل Alternaria alternata یکی از مهمترین بیماری‌های گیاهی در دنیا به شمار می‌رود. برای تعیین تنوع ژنتیکی در جمعیت‌های قارچAlternaria 50 نمونه در سطح مزارع زعفران در استان‌ خراسان رضوی (کاشمر، تربت‌جام، تربت حیدریه، مه ولات، بردسکن) و استان خراسان جنوبی (قائنات، سرایان، بیرجند) جمع آوری گردید. در نهایت 50 جدایه قارچ A. alternata از نمونه‌های آلوده با استفاده از محیط کشت سیب زمینی، دکستروز، آگار جداسازی گردید. آزمایش مولکولی جدایه‌ها بعد از خالص سازی و شناسائی با استفاده از پنج جفت آغازگر ریز ماهواره انجام گرفت. در مجموع 22 آلل با میانگین 11.1 آلل در تمام جمعیت ها توسط آغازگرهای ریزماهواره تولید شد. بیشترین مقدار آلل مربوط به جمعیت مه ولات با 14 آلل و و کمترین جمعیتهای سرایان، بیرجند و قائن با 10 آلل بود. مقایسه پارامترهای تنوع ژنتیکی در هشت جمعیت نشان داد که جمعیت تربت جام بیشترین تنوع ژنتیکی را دارند. اما مقادیر پایینی برای قائنات محاسبه شده است. بیشترین و کمترین فاصله ژنتیکی بین قائن- مه ولات (328/0) و بردسکن- مه ولات (054/0) دیده شد. بر اساس دندروگرام جمعیت ها، دو گروه از همدیگر متمایز شدند؛ یک گروه شامل قائنات و دیگری بیرجند، مه ولات، سرایان، بردسکن، کاشمر، تربت جام و تربت حیدریه بود. تجزیه واریانس ملکولی نشان داد که میزان تنوع ژنتیکی در درون جمعیت 71% و بین جمعیت‌ها 29% می‌باشد. شباهت ژنتیکی بالایی بین جدایه ها از مناطق مختلف وجود داشت. نتایج به دست آمده از این مطالعه می‌تواند در اصلاح ارقام مقاوم زعفران و گسترش اقدام قرنطینه‌ای بسیار مفید باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Alternaria leaf spot caused by Alternaria alternata is one of the most important plant diseases in world. In order to determine genetic diversity, 50 samples were collected from saffron farms of different regions in Razavi Khorasan province (Kashmar, Torbatjam, Torbathaidaryeh, Mahvellat, Bardeskan) and South Khorasan province (Qaen, Saraian, Brjand). A. alternata isolates were isolated with Potato Dextrose Agar media, Molecular test was carried out with a set of five pairs of SSR primers after purification and identification of isolates. A total of 22 alleles were produced by SSR primers with an average of 11.1 alleles in all populations. The highest amounts of alleles were related to locus Mavellat with 14 alleles and lowest of Saraian, Birjand and Qaen with 10 alleles. A Comparison of genetic diversity parameters in eight population showed that Torbatjam population has the highest genetic diversity but lower values were estimated for Qaenat. The highest and lowest genetic distance was detected between Qaen-Mahvellat (0.328) and Bardaskan-Mahvellat (0.054), respectively. Based on dendrogram of populations revealed two distinct groups, one group contained Qaen and the other Birjand, Mavellat, Saraian, Bardaskan, Kashmar, Torbatjam and Torbat hidaryeh. Analysis of molecular variance showed that 71 percent of the genetic diversity belongs to within populations and 29% is located among populations. There was the high genetic similarity between isolates from different regions. Results in this study will be useful in breeding for saffron resistant cultivars and developing necessary control measures.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>331</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>346</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>قاسم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نجاری</Family>
						<NameE>Ghasem</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Najari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد بیماری شناسی گیاهی، گروه گیاهپزشکی، دانشگاه ایلام</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد بیماری شناسی گیاهی، گروه گیاهپزشکی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>najari70@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>خشنود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نوراللهی</Family>
						<NameE>Khoshnood</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nourollahi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه گیاهپزشکی، دانشگاه ایلام</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه گیاهپزشکی، دانشگاه ایلام</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>k.nourollahi@ilam.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تنوع ژنتیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>لکه موجی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>SSR</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تنوع ژنتیکی در زعفران های با بیش از سه کلاله با استفاده از نشانگرمولکولی SSR و ISSR</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluation of genetic variations in saffron with more than three stigmas using SSR and ISSR molecular markers</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران زراعی به عنوان با ارزش­ترین ادویه جهان از نظر ژنتیکی کلون مونومورفی بوده، ولی تفاوت­هایی نیز در فنوتیپ و کیفیت گزارش شده است که مهم­ترین تنوع فنوتیپی از نظر زراعی و اقتصادی، وجود گل­های با بیش از سه کلاله است، بنابراین هدف از این تحقیق استفاده از نشانگرهای مولکولی مختلف جهت مطالعه مولکولی زعفران های با بیش از 3 کلاله در منطقه و اندازه­گیری تنوع ژنتیکی بین آن­ها بود. در این تحقیق، کلون­های زعفران با بیش از سه کلاله به­طور کامل همراه با خاک اطراف ریشه از مزارع کشاورزان جمع­آوری و بطور کامل در جعبه­های پلاستیکی، جهت حفظ شرایط زیستی، مستقر گردیدند. استخراج DNA به روش CTAB از برگ­های گل دارای بیش از سه کلاله انجام شد. زعفران­های با بیش از سه کلاله در مقایسه با حالت معمولی دارای گل­های بزرگتر و تعداد گلبرگ­های به نسبت بیشتری بودند. بیشترین فراوانی تعداد کلاله در بین نمونه­های بیش از سه کلاله مربوط به چهار و پنج کلاله با 38 درصد بود. نمونه­های دارای شش کلاله با فراوانی 14 درصد مشاهده شد. در بین نمونه­های جمع­آوری شده تنها یک نمونه با تعداد کلاله هفت نیز مشاهده گردید. از مجموع 48 آغازگر ISSR آزمون شده روی نمونه DNAی بالک، تنها 16 آغازگر تشکیل نوار دادند. نتایج حاصل از الکتروفورز ژل آگاروز برای آغازگرهای ISSR نشان داد که محدوده نوارهای تشکیل شده در فاصله 100 تا 1000 جفت باز بود. با بررسی نوارهای تشکیل شده برای آغازگرهای ISSR‌، چندشکلی قابل ملاحظه­ای بین کلون­های مختلف زعفران مورد بررسی مشاهده نشد. لذا، براساس این سیستم نشانگری تنوع ژنتیکی بین کلون­های با تعداد کلاله متفاوت ملاحظه نشد. از بین نشانگرهای SSR‌ آزمون شده، 10 نشانگر چند شکلی را بین کلون ها نشان دادند. نتایج تجزیه همبستگی براساس ضریب همبستگی اسپیرمن نشان داد که ارتباط معنی­دار آماری بین هیچ کدام از آلل­های نشانگر ریزماهواره و تعداد کلاله­ها مشاهده نشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron is the most valuable spice in the world. It is genetically a monomorphic clone. However, differences in phenotype and quality have been reported. The most important agro-economically phenotypic variation is the appearance of flowers with more than three stigmas. The main objective of this study was to study the genetic variability of saffron clones with more than 3 stigmas using SSR and ISSR molecular markers. In this research, saffron clones with more than three stigmas were collected along with the corm and the root from Saffron fields of Qaen and Sarayan, South Khorassan province, then transferred as a whole to the Biotechnology Laboratory of the Faculty of Agriculture, the University of Birjand. The number of stigmas in each flower was counted. Genomic DNA was extracted according to the CTAB method from leaves of the flower with more than three stigmas. Flower with more than three stigmas was larger and had more petals than ordinary ones. The most frequent number of flowers with more than three stigmas was related to four and five stigmas with 38%. Six-spike samples with a frequency of 14% were observed. Among the collected samples, only one specimen with seven stigmas was observed. Of the 48 tested ISSR primers on the bulk of DNA, only 16 primers had amplified bands and selected. The results of agarose gel electrophoresis for ISSR primers amplified the bands ranged from 100 to 1000 bp. By examining the bands formed for ISSR primers, no significant polymorphism was observed between different clones of saffron. Therefore, based on this marker system, no sign of genetic diversity was observed between clones with different number of stigmas. Among the tested SSR markers, 10 primer pairs showed amplified band among the clones. The results of correlation analysis based on Spearman correlation coefficient showed that there was no statistically significant correlation between microsatellite marker alleles and number of stigmas.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>347</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>358</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بهدانی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Behdani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mabehdani@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ایزانلو</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Izanloo</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aizanir@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اپی ژنتیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تنوع ژنتیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چندشکلی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abdullaev, F.I., and Espinosa-Aguirre, J.J. 2004. Biomedical properties of saffron and its potential use in cancer therapy and chemoprevention trials. Cancer Detection and Prevention 28 (6): 426-432.##Agayev, Y., Fernandez, J.A., and Zarifi, E. 2009. Clonal selection of saffron (Crocus sativus L.): the first optimistic experimental results. Euphytica 169 (1): 81-99.##Babaei, S., Talebi, M., Bahar, M., and Zeinali, H., 2014. Analysis of genetic diversity among saffron (Crocus sativus) accessions from different regions of Iran as revealed by SRAP markers. Scientia Horticulturae 171 (0): 27-31.##Beiki, A.H., Keifi, F., and Mozafari, J. 2010. Genetic Differentiation of Crucus Species by Random Amplified Polymorphic DNA. Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology Journal 18: 1-10.##Bhandari, P.R. 2015. Crocus sativus L. (saffron) for cancer chemoprevention: A mini review. Journal of Traditional and Complementary Medicine 5 (2): 81-87.##Brandizzi, F., and Grilli Caiola, M. 1998. Flow cytometric analysis of nuclear DNA in Crocus sativus and allies (Iridaceae). Plant Systematics and Evolution 211 (3-4): 149-154.##Busconi, M., Colli, L., Sánchez, R. A., Santaella, M., De-Los-Mozos Pascual, M., Santana, O., Roldán, M., and Fernández, J.A. 2015. AFLP and MS-AFLP analysis of the variation within saffron Crocus (Crocus sativus L.) Germplasm. PLoS ONE 10 (4): e0123434.##Doyle, J.J., and Doyle, J.L. 1987. A rapid DNA isolation procedure for small quantities of fresh leaf tissue. Phytochemical Bulletin 19 : 11-15.##Estilai, A. 1978. Variability in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Experientia 34: 725.##Fluch, S., Hohl, K., Stierschneider, M., Kopecky, D., and Kaar, B. 2010. Crocus sativus L.-Molecular Evidence on Its Clonal Origin. Acta Horticulturae 850: 41-46.##Ghaffari, S.M., and Bagheri, A. 2009. Stigma variability in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). African Journal of Biotechnology 8 (4): 601-604.##Grilli Caiola, M., Caputo, P., and Zanier, R. 2004. RAPD Analysis in Crocus sativus L. accessions and related Crocus species. Biologia Plantarum 48 (3): 375-380.##Lim, T.K. 2014. Crocus sativus. Edible Medicinal and Non Medicinal Plants: Volume 8, Flowers. Springer Netherlands, Dordrecht, p. 77-136.##Magesh, V., Singh, J., Selvendiran, K., Ekambaram, G., and Sakthisekaran, D. 2006. Antitumour activity of crocetin in accordance to tumor incidence, antioxidant status, drug metabolizing enzymes and histopathological studies. Molecular and Cellular Biochemistry 287 (1-2): 127-135.##Mir, J.I., Ahmed, N., Khan, M.H., Mokhdomi, T.A., Wani, S.H., Bukhari, S., Amin, A., and Qadri, R.A. 2015. Molecular characterization of saffron-potential candidates for crop improvement. Notulae Scientia Biologicae 7 (1): 81-89.##Nemati, Z., Zeinalabedini, M., Mardi, M., Pirseyediand, S., Marashi, S., and Nekoui, S. 2012. Isolation and characterization of a first set of polymorphic microsatellite markers in saffron, Crocus sativus (Iridaceae). American Journal of Botany 99: e340–e343.##Nemati, Z., Mardi, M., Majidian, P., Zeinalabedini, M., Pirseyedi, S.M., and Bahadori, M. 2014. Saffron (Crocus sativus L.), a monomorphic or polymorphic species?. Spanish Journal of Agricultural Research 12 (3): 753-762.‏##Ng, D. W.K., Shi, X., Nah, G., and Chen, Z.J. 2014. High-throughput RNA-Seq for allelic or Locus-specific expression analysis in Arabidopsis -related species, hybrids, and allotetraploids. In: Spillane, C., McKeown, P. C., Eds.), Plant Epigenetics and Epigenomics: Methods and Protocols, Vol. 1112. Springer New York. pp. 33-48.##Rubio-Moraga, A., Castillo-López, R., Gómez-Gómez, L., and Ahrazem, O. 2009. Saffron is a monomorphic species as revealed by RAPD, ISSR and microsatellite analyses. BMC Research Notes 2 (1): 1-5.##Samarghandian, S., and Borji, A., 2014. Anticarcinogenic effect of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) and its ingredients. Pharmacognosy Research 6 (2): 99-107.##Sik, L., Candan, F., Soya, S., Karamenderes, C., Kesercioglu, T., and Tanyyolc, B. 2008. Genetic variation among Crocus sativus L. species from western Turkey as revealed by RAPD and ISSR marker. Journal of Applied Biological Science 2 (2): 73-78.##Siracusa, L., Gresta, F., Avola, G., Albertini, E., Raggi, L., Marconi, G., Lombardo, G. M., and Ruberto, G. 2013. Agronomic, chemical and genetic variability of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) of different origin by LC-UV–vis-DAD and AFLP analyses. Genetic Resources and Crop Evolution 60 (2): 711-721.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی عوامل اثرگذار بر مصرف کودهای شیمیایی در مزارع زعفران (مطالعه موردی: شهرستان گناباد)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigation of the Effective Factors on Use of Chemical Fertilizers in Saffron Farms (Case study: Gonabad County)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>یکی از مهم‌ترین محصولات تولیدی و صادراتی کشاورزی ایران زعفران است که تولید آن منبع اصلی درآمد بسیاری از مناطق روستایی در شرق کشور به­شمار می‌آید. با این وجود، عملکرد مزارع زعفران طی سال‌های 1394-1350 حدود 36 درصد کاهش یافته است. شهرستان گناباد در استان خراسان رضوی به­عنوان یکی از بزرگترین تولیدکنندگان زعفران در ایران نیز با این مشکل مواجه است. شواهد و بررسی‌های میدانی گویای این است که استفاده‌ زیاد از نهاده‌های شیمیایی به خصوص کودهای شیمیایی می‌تواند به­عنوان یکی از عوامل اصلی این کاهش عملکرد مطرح باشد. بنابراین هدف مطالعه‌ حاضر بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر مصرف کودهای شیمیایی با تأکید بر نقش نگرش و آگاهی زعفران‌کاران است. برای دستیابی به اهداف پژوهش، تعداد 105 پرسش­نامه بر اساس روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی نسبی تکمیل و از الگوی لاجیت ترتیبی استفاده شد. نتایج نشان داد که دو متغیر نگرش زعفران‌کاران نسبت به کشاورزی پایدار و آگاهی نسبت به عوامل کاهش‌دهنده عملکرد اثر منفی و معنی‌داری بر احتمال استفاده‌ کشاورزان از کود شیمیایی دارد. در حالی که متغیرهای درآمد کشاورزان، سن، سطح تحصیلات و بیمه کشاورزی اثر مثبت و معنی‌داری بر احتمال استفاده از کود شیمیایی توسط کشاورزان دارند. بنابراین اتخاذ سیاست‌های مناسب به منظور بهبود نگرش کشاورزان نسبت به فعالیت‌های کشاورزی پایدار و افزایش آگاهی زعفران‌کاران از آثار منفی و بلندمدت استفاده‌ بی‌رویه کودهای شیمیایی، جلب اعتماد کشاورزان معتمد و با تجربه برای کاهش استفاده از کودهای شیمیایی و تجدید نظر در محتوای کلاس‌های آموزشی و ترویجی نقش تعیین‌کننده‌ای در بهبود الگوی مصرفی کشاورزان از کود شیمیایی دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron is one of the most important agricultural and export products whose production is the main source of income in many rural areas in east of the country. However, the yield of saffron farms decreased by almost 36% during 1971-2015. The Gonabad county in the Khorasan Razavi province as one of the largest saffron producers in Iran also faces this problem. Evidences suggest that the high use of chemical inputs, especially chemical fertilizers, can be considered as one of the main causes of yield decrease. Therefore, this study aims to investigate the effective factors on use of chemical fertilizers with an emphasis on the role of attitude and awareness of saffron producers. In order to achieve the research objectives, 105 questionnaires were completed based on proportional random sampling and an ordered logit model was carried out. The results showed that two variables of farmers’ attitude towards sustainable agriculture and awareness about yield-reducing factors have negative and significant effects on the probability of chemical fertilizer use. While the variables of farmers’ income, age, education and agricultural insurance have positive and significant effect on the probability of chemical fertilizer use. Therefore, undertaking appropriate policies in order to boost farmers’ attitude towards sustainable agricultural practices and increase the awareness of farmers about the negative and long-term effects of excessive use of chemical fertilizers, encouraging trusted and experienced farmers to reduce the use of fertilizers and reconsidering the content of training courses have a decisive role in enhancing the pattern of chemical fertilizers use.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>359</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>376</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آرش</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>دوراندیش</Family>
						<NameE>Arash</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Dourandish</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>dourandish@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رمضانی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammadreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ramezani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mr.ramezani@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>میلاد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امینی زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Milad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aminizadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>milad.aminizadeh@mail.um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیستم ناپایدار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کاهش عملکرد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>لاجیت ترتیبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نهاده‌های بیرونی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی ریسک خشکسالی زعفران با استفاده از روش مونت کارلو</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Drought risk assessment of Saffron by Montcarlo method</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تغییرات اقلیمی و پدیده‌هایی از جمله خشکسالی در میزان عملکرد محصولات کشاورزی موثر هستند. یکی از راهکارهای مقابله با این پدیده‌ها، جایگزینی مدیریت ریسک به جای مدیریت بحران است، به­طوری­که با ارزیابی ریسک، قبل از وقوع بحران، میزان خسارت‌ها به حداقل می‌رسد. در این پژوهش نیز در جهت کاهش خسارت‌های ناشی از خشکسالی به­عنوان پدیده‌ای طبیعی و غیر قابل کنترل، بر روی محصول زعفران، به ارزیابی ریسک خشکسالی با استفاده از روش شبیه‌سازی مونت­کارلو پرداخته شد. شاخص خشکسالی بارش استاندارد شده (SPI) ماهانه و میانگین دمای ماهانه به عنوان متغیرهای مستقل در تابع توزیع عملکرد محاسبه می‌شود. با کمک روش فراابتکاری شبکه عصبی مصنوعی (ANN)، ارتباط بین متغیرهای مستقل (دما و SPI) و متغیر وابسته (عملکرد محصول زعفران) برقرار می‌شود. سپس داده‌‌ی تصادفی از متغیرهای مستقل ساخته می‌شود و با شبکه عصبی مصنوعی آموزش یافته، 2000 عملکرد شبیه‌سازی شده تولید می‌گردد. انتخاب یک ایستگاه مرجع و با استفاده از توزیع تجمعی به دست آمده، عامل ریسک محاسبه شد و با رسم نمودار عامل ریسک-عملکرد استاندارد، ریسک نسبی ایستگاه‌های مورد مطالعه بررسی شده است. نتایج به­دست آمده از این پژوهش نشان داد که بیشترین سال‌های مورد مطالعه در محدوده نرمال قراردارند و فراوانی خشکسالی در چهار ایستگاه خراسان جنوبی دو برابر ایستگاه‌های مورد مطالعه در خراسان رضوی می‌باشد. همین­طور شبکه عصبی مصنوعی با ضریب همبستگی 85/0 توانست به خوبی عملکرد را پیش‌بینی نماید. در پایان بر اساس نتایج به­دست آمده از نمودار ریسک-عملکرد استاندارد، ایستگاه‌های قاین، بیشترین و نهبندان کمترین ریسک نسبی نسبت به ایستگاه مرجع (تربت­حیدریه) را  داشتند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Climate changes and phenomena such as drought are effective in the yield of agricultural products. Replacing crisis management with risk management is one of the solutions for these phenomena. With risk assessment before crisis, the amount of damages will be reduced to the minimum amount. In this research, the risk assessment of drought by Monte Carlo method will be used in order to reduce the damages caused by drought as a natural and uncontrollable phenomenon on saffron product. The monthly Standardized Precipitation Index (SPI) of drought and the monthly average temperature are calculated as independent variables in the yield distribution function. The relationship between independent variables (temperature and SPI) and dependent variable (saffron yield) is established using Artificial Neural Network (ANN). After that, 2000 random data from independent variables are generated using MATLAB and 2000 simulated yields generated by a trained artificial neural network. Then, the cumulative distribution of the simulated yields are determined and these yields are standardized in order to unification of the yield data of each city. The risk factor is calculated by choosing a reference station and using the cumulative distribution. The relative risks of the stations are considered after drawing the diagram of Yield-Risk standard factor. The results of the research show that most of the studied years are in normal range and the drought frequency in the four stations of Khorasan Jonoobi province is twice the stations in Khorasan Razavi. Furthermore, the artificial neural network with a correlation coefficient of 0.85 could predict the yield of the product very well. The similarity of the cumulative distribution diagram of the real yield with the cumulative distribution of the yields simulated by Monte Carlo indicates that the results are correct. At the end The results of this research show that Ghayen has the highest relative risk compared to the reference station (Torbat-e- Heydariyeh) and Nehbandan has the lowest one.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>377</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>396</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سیبویه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اقا محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Seeboyeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aghamohamadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی منابع آب، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی منابع آب، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>seebooyeh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عباس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خاشعی سیوکی</Family>
						<NameE>abbas</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>khashei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مهندسی آب دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مهندسی آب دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abbaskhashei@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شهیدی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shahidi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مهندسی آب دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مهندسی آب دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ashahidi@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سیدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>هاشمی</Family>
						<NameE>Sayyed Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hashemi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مهندسی آب دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مهندسی آب دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>srezahashemi@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت ریسک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>باران استاندارد‌شده (SPI)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبکه عصبی مصنوعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبیه‌سازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Akbarpour, A., Khorashadizadeh, O., Shahidi, A., and, Ghochanian, E. 2013. Performance evaluation of artificial neural network models in estimate production of yield saffron based on climate parameters. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (1): 27-35. (In Persian with English Summary).##Alcamo, J., Dronin, N., Endejan, M., Golubev, G., and Kirilenko, A. 2007. A new assessment of climate change impacts on food production shortfalls and water availability in Russia. Global Environmental Change 17 (3-4): 429-444.##Barreto, H., and Howland, F. 2005. Introductory Econometrics: Using Monte Carlo Simulation with Microsoft excel. Cambridge University Press.##Coulibaly, P., Anctil, F., and Bobee, B. 1999. Hydrological forecasting with artificial neural networks: the State of the art. Canadian Journal of Civil Engineering 26 (3): 293-304.##Dutta, D., Kundu, A., Patel, N.R., Saha, S.K., and Siddiqui, A.R. 2015. Assessment of agricultural drought in Rajasthan (India) using remote sensing derived vegetation condition index (VCI) and standardized precipitation index (SPI). The Egyptian Journal of Remote Sensing and Space Science 18 (1): 53-63.##Agricultural Organization of South Khorasan. 2017. Agricultural organization of South Khorasan database. Available at Web site http://kj-agrijahad.ir/dbagri/baghebani.##Khashei, S.A., Kouchakzadeh, M., and Ghahraman, B. 2011. Predicting Dryland Wheat Yield From Meteorological Data Using Expert System, Khorasan Province, Iran.##McKee, T.B., Doesken, N.J., and Kleist, J. 1993. The relationship of drought frequency and duration to time scales. In Proceedings of the 8th Conference on Applied Climatology, 17 (22): 179-183. Boston, MA: American Meteorological Society.##Mirzaei Nadooshan, F., Morid, S., and Arshad, S. 2011. Agriculture drought risk in the cities of Kermanshah province. Journal of Agricultural Engineering Research 11 (3): 1-14. (In Persian with English Summary).##Moradi, A.R., Sharifi, M.A. 2016. The analysis of precipitation time series related to Iran’s main catchments using fourier and wavelet transforms. Geospatial Engineering Journal 7: 137-145.##Mosaedi, A., and Ghabaei Sough, M. 2012. Modification of standardized precipitation index (SPI) based on relevant probability distribution function. Journal of Water and Soil 25 (5): 1206-1216. (In Persian with English Summary).##Nekouei, N., Behdani, M.A., and Khashei Siuki, A., 2014. Predicting saffron yield from meteorological data using expert system, Razavi and South Khorasan province, Iran. Journal of Saffron Research 2 (1): 13-31. (In Persian with English Summary).##Quirogua, S., and Iglesias, A. 2007. Methods for drought risk analysis in agriculture. Options Méditerranéennes 58: 103-113.##Shaha, R., Bharadiya, N., and Manekar, V. 2015. Drought index computation using Standardized Precipitation Index (SPI) method for Surat district. Gujarat. Aquatic Procedia 4: 1243-1249.## Shahidi, A., and Dowlatabadi, S. 2017. Assessment of use of wastewater treatment of Birjand university in order to fulfill the objectives of the Green university. 1st National Conference on Green University, Bushehr, Iran.##Zare Abyaneh, H. 2013. Evaluating roles of drought and climatic factors on variability of  four dry farming yields in Mashhad and Birjand. Journal of   Water and Soil Science 23 (1): 39- 56.  (In Persian with English Summary).##Shahiyan, R., Jame, A., Ariyanfar, R.,  Haghighat, M., and Dehghan, H. 2009. Drought crisis density zone Fars province using Standardized Precipitation Index SPI and GIS. Jornal of Water Resources Engineering 2 (4): 33-42. (In Persian).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>الگوی برنامه ریزی توسعه کشت زعفران با تأکید بر مدیریت منابع آبی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Programming model of Saffron cultivation extension with emphasis on water resources management</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پایین بودن بازدهی آب مصرفی در بخش کشاورزی اتخاذ استراتژی‌های بهینه‌سازی الگوی کشت و لذا مصرف آب را، به‌خصوص در مناطق کم‌آبی همچون کشور ایران ضروری کرده است. زعفران می‌تواند محصولی مناسب ازنظر صرفه‌جویی در مصرف آب باشد. هدف از اجرای این مطالعه بررسی تأثیر توسعه کشت زعفران بر تخصیص منابع آب و افزایش درآمد کشاورزان از طریق به‌کارگیری الگویی مبتنی بر رهیافتی توسعه‌یافته از برنامه‌ریزی ریاضی مثبت است که در آن امکان اعمال توسعه کشت در آینده، به همراه برآورد تخصیص آب از طریق یک تابع تولید مبتنی بر مقدار آب آبیاری، وجود دارد. نمونه‌ موردبررسی را 200 نفر از بهره برداران زعفران در شهرستان‌های تربت‌حیدریه و زاوه دراستان خراسان رضوی در سال 94-1393 تشکیل می‌دهد. اطلاعات با استفاده از نرم‌افزار GAMS مورد تجزیه‌وتحلیل قرارگرفته است. نتایج سناریوهای افزایش در سطح زیر کشت زعفران، پیامدهای مثبت این سیاست را افزایش سود خالص و کاهش مصرف آب در سطح هر سه گروه مزارع کوچک، متوسط و بزرگ ارزیابی می کند که بیانگر تأثیر اجرای آن بر حفظ و پایداری منابع آب منطقه است. نتایج سناریوی افزایش منابع آب در دسترس که به بهره‌برداران امکان می‌داد بخشی از زمین‌های بالقوه خود را به کشت زعفران اختصاص دهند، نتایج یکنواختی برای گروه‌های مختلف مزارع نشان نمی‌دهد. به‌طوری‌که افزایش در سطح زیر کشت زعفران در مزارع کوچک به میزان 43/38 هکتار، در مزارع متوسط 11/52 هکتار و در مزارع گروه سوم 3/47 هکتار برآورد شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Low efficiency of water use in agricultural sector, make in nessesery to do strategies for optimization of cropping pattern and therefore water consumption, especially in dried areas such as Khorasan Razavi province. Principal selecting of these strategies needs that the results may be evaluated using relevant simulation models. Saffron can be the right product in terms of water saving. The aim of this study is to investigate the effects of saffron area expansion on the allocation of water resources and increase the income of farmers through the use of a model based on an extended Positive Mathematical Programming model that includes the possibility of future develop in cropping patterns, along with water allocation through a production function based on the amount of irrigation water. Required data are collected from 200 questionnaires completed by saffron producers in Torbat-e Heydarieh and Zaveh counties in year 2014. The data collected was analyzed using the software GAMS and imposing different senarios on three group of small, medium and large farms. Results of the increase in saffron cultivation shows change in cropping patterns from higher water demand products towards saffron. Positive results of this policy are increase in net income and decreasing water consumption in all three type of farms. Results of increase in available water resources that allow farmers to exploit part of the dedicated land to the cultivation of saffron, do not show uniformity results for different groups of farms. This implies that, in addition to pricing, other strategies such as investing in new technologies to improve water use and water resource management may improve economic statement and agricultural development, especially on small farms of this area.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>397</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>410</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهاره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زندی دره غریبی</Family>
						<NameE>Bahareh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zandi Darehgharibi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش‌آموخته کارشناسی ارشد، گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش‌آموخته کارشناسی ارشد، گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>b.zandi67@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کرباسی</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Karbasi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.rkarbasi2002@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>تکتم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محتشمی</Family>
						<NameE>Toktam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohtashami</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>t.mohtashami@torbath.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>برنامه‌ریزی کشت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>برنامه ریزی ریاضی مثبت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت آب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی عوامل موثر بر صادرات زعفران ایران به کشورهای بریکس (رهیافت پانل دیتا)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the Factors Affecting the Export of Iranian Saffron to BRICS Countries
( Panel  data approach )</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تحلیل عوامل موثر بر صادرات به‌ویژه در ارتباط با بازارهای جدید در بخش کشاورزی یکی از مهم‌ترین عوامل موثر بر رشد و توسعه صادرات محصولاتی مانند زعفران است. تحقیق حاضر باهدف بررسی عوامل اثرگذار بر صادرات زعفران ایران به کشورهای بریکس انجام‌یافته است. برای این منظور مدل داده‌های پانل در دوره زمانی 2015-1990 به کار گرفته‌شده است. نتایج برآورد الگوی تصادفی نشان می‌دهد که تولید ناخالص داخلی کشورهای بریکس، نرخ واقعی ارز و جمعیت اثر مثبت و قیمت صادراتی اثر منفی بر صادرات زعفران ایران به کشورهای بریکس دارند. با توجه به بالا بودن سطح درآمد سرانه در کشورهای بریکس و اثر مثبت آن بر میزان صادرات زعفران، انجام برنامه‌ریزی و سیاست‌گذاری در جهت تقویت روابط با این کشورها، عاملی مهم در زمینه توسعه صادرات محصول زعفران خواهد بود. از سویی با توجه به کشش‌ کم قیمت وارداتی زعفران در کشورهای مذکور، پیشنهاد می‌گردد، اقدامات لازم در جهت ارتقاء و بهبود سطح بسته‌بندی و فرآوری این محصول که ممکن است منجر به افزایش نسبی قیمت گردد، انجام شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Analysis of factors affecting exports, especially in relation to new markets in agriculture, is one of the most important factors affecting the growth and development of exports of products such as saffron . The purpose of this study was to investigate the factors affecting the export of Iranian saffron to the BRICS countries . For this purpose the panel for data approach for the period 2015-1990 has been used. The results of the randomized model estimation show that the gross domestic product of the BRICS countries, the real exchange rate and population have positive effects, and the export price has a negative effect on Iranian exports of saffron to the BRICS countries . Regarding the high level of per capita income in BRICS countries and its positive effect on the export rate of saffron, planning and policy making in order to strengthen relations with these countries is an important factor in the development of export of saffron crops. On the other hand, given the the low elasticity of imported saffron in these countries, it is suggested that measures be taken to upgrade and improve the packaging and processing of this product, which may lead to a relative increase in prices.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>411</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>420</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آقاپور صباغی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aghapour Sabbaghi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مدیریت کشاورزی، واحد شوشتر، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، شوشتر، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مدیریت کشاورزی، واحد شوشتر،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aghapour2000@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی تصادفی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازار هدف</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>صادرات کشاورزی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				