<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" "journalpublishing3.dtd">
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2014.7808</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7808_b8b3ca14b6f81d149d252eed8f885058.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تأثیر مصرف برخی کودهای شیمیایی و بیولوژیک بر خصوصیات کمی وکیفی زعفران زراعی</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حیدری</surname>
			            <given-names>زهرا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی کارشناسی ‌ارشد زراعت، گروه زراعت واصلاح نباتات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اسلامشهر</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بشارتی</surname>
			            <given-names>حسین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار موسسه تحقیقات خاک و آب</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>ملکی فراهانی</surname>
			            <given-names>سعیده</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه شاهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>10</month>
			        <year>2014</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>177</fpage>
			      <lpage>189</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>14</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>25</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2014, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7808.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7808.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>این مطالعه باهدف بررسی خصوصیات کیفی و کمی زعفران (.Crocus sativus L) تحت تأثیر مصرف کود شیمیایی نیتروژن و نیز تلقیح با باکتری‌های محرک رشد به‌صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح پایه بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار در سال زراعی 92-1391 در مزرعه تحقیقاتی زعفران دانشگاه شاهد انجام شد. فاکتورهای مورد بررسی شامل کود شیمیایی نیتروژن در سه سطح صفر، 25 و 50 کیلوگرم در هکتار و دو سطح کاربرد و عدم کاربرد کود زیستی شامل سودوموناس‌پوتیدا و باسیلوس‌لنتوس بودند. صفات مورد بررسی شامل وزن اندام هوایی، وزن تازه گل، تعداد گل در واحد سطح و وزن‌تر و خشک کلاله، میزان پروتئین، فسفر، آهن و روی‌،سطح و محتوی کلروفیل برگ، سافرانال، پیکروکروسین و کروسین کلاله بودند. نتایج نشان داد که تلفیق 50 کیلوگرم کود شیمیایی نیتروژن به‌همراه کود زیستی باعث افزایش حدود 217 درصدی عملکرد خشک کلاله نسبت به شاهد شد. با مصرف 25 کیلوگرم کود شیمیایی نیتروژن سافرانال و کروسین کلاله به‌ترتیب 13/5 و 9/10 درصد کاهش یافت. کاربرد تلفیقی 25 کیلوگرم کود شیمیایی نیتروژن و کود زیستی بر مقدار پیکروکروسین به میزان 90/11 درصد نسبت به تیمار شاهد افزود. مصرف همزمان 50 کیلوگرم کود شیمیایی نیتروژن و کود زیستی کارآمدترین تیمار در افزایش عملکرد کلاله و خصوصیات کیفی برگ زعفران بود. در این تیمار میزان فسفر، روی و مس برگ زعفران به ترتیب 05/83، 36/69 و 6/86 درصد نسبت به تیمار شاهد افزایش یافت. به‌طورکلی تلقیح بنه‌های زعفران با باکتری‌های سودوموناس و باسیلوس با اثر بر جذب عناصر غذایی باعث بهبود اکثر صفات کمی و کیفی زعفران شد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>باکتری‌های محرک رشد</kwd>
						<kwd>تلقیح</kwd>
						<kwd>سافرانال</kwd>
						<kwd>کود تلفیقی</kwd>
						<kwd>کروسین</kwd>
						<kwd>کلاله</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Asadi Rahmani, H., Asgharzadeh, A., Khavazi, K., Rejali, F., and Savaghebi, G. 2007. Soil biological fertility, a key to sustainable land use in agriculture. Jihade Daneshgahi Press. Tehran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Aytekin, A., and Acikgoz, A.O. 2008. Hormone and microorganism treatments in the cultivation of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) plants. Molecules13: 1135-1146.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Bacilio, M., Rodriguez, H., Mereno, M., and Hernandez, J.P. 2004. Mitigation of salt stress in wheat seedling by Azospirillum lipferum. Soil Biology 40: 188-193.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Berg, G., Roskot, N., Steidle, A., Eberl, L., Zock, A., and Smalla, K. 2002. Plant dependent genotypic and phenotypic diversity of antagonistic rhizobacteria isolated from different Verticillium host plants, Journal of Applied Environmental Microbiology 68: 3328-3338.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Cottenie A., Verloo, M., Kiekens, L., Velgh G., and Camerlynch, R. 1982. Chemical analysis of plants and soils, Lab, Anal Agrochem. State Univ. Ghent Belgium 63.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Daneshvar Kakhki, M., and Farahmand Gelyan, K. 2012. Review of interactions between e-commerce, brand and packaging on value added of saffron: A structural equation modeling approach. African Journal of Business Management 6: 7924-7930.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>DeChatelet, L., and Alpers, J.B. 1970. Phosphoribokinase from Pseudomonas saccharophila. Biological Chemistry 245: 3161-3166.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Douds, J.R., and Millner, D.D. 1999. Biodiversity of arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi in agroecosystem. Journal of Agriculture Ecosystem and Environment 74: 77-93.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Fiori, M., Falchi, G., Quaglia, M., and Cappelli, C. 2007. Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) diseases in Italy. Plant Pathology 89: 27-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Gastal, F., and Nelson. C.J. 1994. Nitrogen use within the growth leaf blade of tall fescue. Plant Physiology 15: 191-197.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Hartmann, A., and Bashan, Y. 2009. Ecology and application of Azospirillum and other plant growth-promoting bacteria (PGPB), European Journal of Soil Biology 45: 1-2.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Hernandez, A.N., Hernandez A., and Heydrich M. 1995. Selection of rhizobacteria for use in maize cultivation. Cultivos Tropicales 6: 5-8.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>INS (IRAN NATIONAL STANDARD). 2006. Research Institute of Standard and Iran. Saffron Bulletin, No. 259.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Kapulnik, Y., Sarig, S. Nur, A., Okon, Y., and Henis, Y. 1982. The effect of Azospirillum inoculation on growth and yield of corn. Israel Journal of Botany 31: 247-255.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Khoramdel, S., Amin Ghafoori, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Nasiri Mahalati, M. 2011. Evaluation different irrigation regimes along with biofertilizer on grain yield, Chlorophyll and relative water content of sesame. First congress of sustainable agriculture and healthy food. 10-11 November, Isfahan. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Kirmani, N.A. , Sofi, J.A., Bhat, M.A., and Ansar-Ul-Haq, S. 2014. Sustainable saffron production as influenced by integrated nitrogen management in typic hapludalfs of NW Himalayas. Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis 45: 653-668.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., and Jahan, M. 2009. Effect of biofertilizer and inorganic fertilizer on generative growth and yield of saffron under high corn density. 3rd International Symposium on Saffron: Forthcoming Challenges in Cultivation, Research and Economics. Krokos, Greece, 20-24 May.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Kumar, R., Singh, V., Devi, K., Sharma, M., Singh, M.K., and Ahuja, P.S. 2009. State of art of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) agronomy: A comprehensive review. Food Reviews International 25: 44-85.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Kumar, V., Behl, R.K., and Narula, N. 2001. Effect of phosphate solubilizing strains of Azotobacter chroococcum on yield traits and their survival in the rhizosphere of wheat genotypes under field conditions. Acta Agronomy Hungry 49: 141–149.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Loomis, W.D., and Corteau, 1972. Essential oil biosynthesis. Journal of Recent Advance in Phytochemistry 6: 147-185.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Loper, J.E., and Schroth, M.N. 1986. Influence of bacterial sources of indole-3-acetic acid on root elongation of sugar beet. Physiology and Biochemistry 76: 386-389.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Maleki Farahani, S., Chaichi, M.R., Mazaheri, D., Tavakkol Afshari, R., and Savaghebi, G. 2011. Barley grain mineral content as affected by different fertilizing systems anddrought stress. Journal of Agricultural Science and Technology 13: 315-326.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Moez Ardalan, M., and Savaghebi, G. 2002. Soil fertility management for sustainable agriculture, Tehran University Press. Tehran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Muscolo, A., Bovalo, F., Gionfriddo, F., and Nardi, F. 1999. Earthworm humic matter produces auxin-like effects on Daucus carota cell growth and nitrate metabolism. Soil Biology and Biochemistry 31: 1303-1311.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Nehvi, F.A., Khan, M.A., Lone, A.A., and Maqhdoomi, M.I. 2009. Impact of microbial inoculation on growth and yield of saffron in Kashmir. 3rd International Symposium on Saffron: Forthcoming Challenges in Cultivation, Research and Economics. Krokos, Greece, 20-24 May 2009.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Nieto, K.F., and Frankenberger, W.T. 1989. Biosynthesis of cytokinins in soil. Soil Science Society of America Journal 53: 735-740.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Omidi, H., Naghdi Buddy, H., Golzad, A. Torabi, H., and Fotokyan, M. 2010. Biological effects of nitrogen fertilizer on yield and quality and quantity of saffron. Journal of Medicinal Plants 30: 4-15. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Page, A.L., Miller, R.H., and Keeney, D.R. 1982. Methods of Soil Analysis. Part II - Chemical and Microbiological Properties, 2nd Edition. Agronomy Society of America. Madison, WI.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Parshad, R., 2009. Process development impact on industries and awards. Microbial Biotechnology Division, India.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Penuelas, J., Gamon, J.A. Freeden, A. Merino, J., and Field, C. 1994. Reflectance indices associated with physiological changes in N and water-limited sunflower leaves. Remote Sensing and Environment 46: 100-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Porra, R.J. 2002. The chequered history of the development and use of simultaneous equations for the accurate determination of chlorophylls a and b. Photosynthesis Research 73: 149-156.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Probanza, A., Lucas-García, J.A., Ruiz Palomino, M., Ramos, B., and Gutiérrez-Mañero, F.J. 2002. Pinuspinea L. seedlings growth and bacterial rhizosphere structure after inoculation with PGPR Bacillus (B. licheniformis CECT 5106 and B. pumilus CECT 5105). Applied Soil Ecology 20: 75–84.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Rojas, A., Holguin, G., Glick, B., and Bashan, Y. 2001. Synergism between Phyllobactterium sp. (N2-Fixer), and Basilus licheniformis (P-Solubilizer), both from a semiarid mangrove rhizospher, Journal of FEMS Microbial Ecology 35: 181-187.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Sharaf-Eldin, M.A., Elkholy, S., Fernández, J.A., Junge, H., Cheetham, R.D., Guardiola, J.L., and Weathers, P.J.  2008. The effect of Bacillus subtilis FZB24 on flowers quantity and quality of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Planta Medica 74: 1316-1320.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Sundara, B., Natarajan, V., and Hari, K. 2002. Influence of phosphorus solubilizing bacteria on the changes in soilavailable phosphor and sugar cane and sugar yields. Journal of Field Crops Research 3: 43-49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Unal, M., and Cavusoglu, A. 2005. The effect of various nitrogen fertilizers on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) yield. Akdeniz Üniv. Ziraaf Fak. Dergisi 18 (2): 257-260.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Wu, S.C., Cao, Z.H., Li, Z.G., Cheung, K.C., and Wong, M.H. 2005. Effects of biofertilizer containing N-fixer, P and K solubilizers and AM fungi on maize growth: a greenhousetrial. Geoderma1251 (2): 155-166.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, N., Wang, D., Liu, Y., Li, S., Shen, Q., and Zhang, R. 2013. Effects of different plant root exudates and their organic acid components on chemotaxis, biofilm formation and colonization by beneficial rhizosphere-associated bacterial strains. Plant and Soil 374: 689-700.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2014.7809</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7809_fefd190cd80cf181e444cd4514d44ed6.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>واکنش زعفران به مقادیر دو نوع کود پتاسیم</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>ذبیحی</surname>
			            <given-names>حمیدرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار بخش تحقیقات خاک و آب مرکز تحقیقات کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی خراسان رضوی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فیضی</surname>
			            <given-names>حسن</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار پژوهشکده زعفران، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>10</month>
			        <year>2014</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>191</fpage>
			      <lpage>198</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>13</day>
			          <month>11</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>04</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2014, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7809.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7809.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>به‌منظور بررسی عکس‌العمل زعفران به مقدار و زمان مصرف دو نوع کود پتاسه، آزمایشی به‌صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با سه فاکتور اجرا گردید. فاکتور اول، مقدار پتاسیم (صفر، 75/20، 5/41، 25/65، 83 و 75/103 کیلوگرم پتاسیم خالص در هکتار)، فاکتور دوم زمان مصرف (مصرف سالیانه کود و مصرف تجمعی کل کود موردنیاز چهار ساله در سال اول) در کرت‌های مصرف تجمعی بود. تمامی کود موردنیاز در طی چهار سال در همان سال اول به خاک اضافه گردید که بر این اساس این کرت‌ها به ترتیب مقادیر0، 83، 166، 249، 332 و 415 کیلوگرم پتاسیم خالص در هکتار دریافت داشتند. فاکتور سوم، نوع کود در دو سطح (سولفات پتاسیم (SOP) و کلرور پتاسیم (MOP)) بود. این آزمایش در سه تکرار و به‌مدت 4 سال در ایستگاه تحقیقات کشاورزی زعفران گناباد انجام گرفت. از آنجایی‌که گل‌دهی زعفران در سال اول کشت مربوط به اثر تیمارهای کودی نبود. مورد آنالیز آماری قرار نگرفت و نتایج مربوط به گل‌دهی سه سال بعد مورد تجزیه‌وتحلیل آماری قرار گرفت. نتایج نشان داد که اثر خالص مقدار پتاسیم بر عملکردکلاله خشک زعفران در سطح 5 درصد معنی‌دار بود و بیشترین کلاله خشک از تیمار مصرف 75/25 کیلوگرم پتاسیم خالص در هکتار به دست آمد. اثر خالص زمان مصرف کود پتاسیم بر عملکرد کلاله خشک زعفران معنی‌دار بود؛ به‌طوری‌که عملکرد کلاله خشک زعفران در تیمار مصرف هر ساله پتاسیم نسبت به تیمار مصرف تجمعی پتاسیم کل دوره، در سال اول افزایش معنی‌داری در سطح 5 درصد نشان داد. اثر خالص منبع کود پتاسیم بر عملکرد کلاله خشک زعفران نیز در سطح 5 درصد معنی‌دار بود؛ به طوری‌که مصرف پتاسیم به شکل سولفات پتاسیم باعث افزایش معنی‌دار عملکرد کلاله خشک نسبت به تیمار استفاده از کلرید پتاسیم شد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>تغذیه</kwd>
						<kwd>کلاله خشک</kwd>
						<kwd>سولفات پتاسیم</kwd>
						<kwd>عملکرد</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Avarseji. Z., Kafi, M., Sabet Teimouri, M., and Orooji, K. 2013. Investigation of salinity stress and potassium levels on morphophysiological characteristics of saffron. Journal of Plant Nutrition 36: 299–310.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Dilmaghani, M.R., Malakouti, M.J., Neilsen, G.H., and Fallahi, E. 2004. Interaction effect of K and Ca on K/Ca ratio and its consequence to apple fruit quality on calcareous soils of Iran. Journal of Plant Nutrition 27: 1149-1162.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Habibi, M.B., and Bagheri, A. 1989. Saffron.Iran Scientific and Industrial Organization. Khorasan Center. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Hosseini, M. 1999. Effect of foliar nutrition on saffron yield increase. Iran Scientific and Industrial Organization. Khorasan Research Center. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Kafi, M. 2002. Saffron, Production and Processing. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Press. 276 pp. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Kumar. A. R., and Kumar, N. 2008. Studies on the efficacy ofsulphate of potash (SOP) on the physiological, yield and quality parameters of banana CV. Robusta. Eurasian Journal of Biosciences12: 102-109.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Malakoti, M.J., and Homai, M. 2004. Dry Land Soil Fertility, Problems and Solutions. Tarbiat Modaress University Publications. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Malakoti, M.J., Shhabi, A.A., and Bazargan, K. 2005. Potash in Iran agriculture. Sana Publications. Tehran. Iran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Marschner, H. 1995. Mineral nutrition of higher plants. Second edition, Academic press, London.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Rezaian, S., and Pasban, M. 2002. Effect of nitrogen fertilizers (Urea, SCU) along with animal manure on the yield of saffron and nitrogen critical level. Khorasan Agriculture research center. Mashhad. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B., Razavi, M., and Mohajeri, M.1997. Effect of different rates of chemical fertilizer on increasing yield of saffron. Khorasan Agriculture research center.Mashhad. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B., Razavi, M., and Mollafilabi, A. 1989. Effect of chemical fertilizers and animal manure on the leaf and corm production of saffron. Khorasan Agriculture research center. Mashhad. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Shahandeh, H. 1990. Assessment of relation of soil physical and chemical properties with saffron yield in Gonabad region. Iran Scientific and Industrial Organization Khorasan Center. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2014.7810</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7810_8cb71eb9ca748c896b01f346c8dab531.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>دسته‌بندی و پیش‌بینی کلاله سه‌شاخه و چند‌‌شاخه زعفران با استفاده از ابزار‌های آماری یادگیری ماشینی بدون‌نظارت</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بیکی</surname>
			            <given-names>امیرحسین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیارگروه زیست شناسی، دانشکده علوم پایه، دانشگاه قم</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>10</month>
			        <year>2014</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>199</fpage>
			      <lpage>204</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>15</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>16</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2014, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7810.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7810.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>زعفران یک گیاه تریپلوئید و عقیم است که در همه کشورها به‌عنوان یک ادویه و گیاه دارویی مورد استفاده قرار می‌گیرد. کلاله مهم‌ترین قسمت گیاه زعفران می‌باشد. تاکنون هیچ روش مطمئن مولکولی برای شناسایی و پیش‌بینی گونه‌های دارای کلاله سه و چند‌شاخه ارائه نشده است. در‌ این بررسی بر ‌اساس نشانگر‌های مولکولی چندشکلی توالی مربوط تکثیر یافته و با استفاده از الگوریتم‌های بیوانفورماتیکی مختلف،روش‌های جدیدی برای پیش‌بینی کلاله زعفران ارائه شده است. پنج آلل M131400، M151200، M151100، M10850 و G6500 به‌عنوان مهم‌ترین دسته‌بندی کننده با دقت پیش‌بینی بالا بر اساس مدل‌های Attribute Weighting انتخاب شدند که دارای پتانسیل بالایی برای ‌خوشه‌بندی و تشخیص کلاله سه‌شاخه ازچند‌‌شاخه هستند. دسته‌بندی بدون یادگیری بر اساس الگوریتم‌های K-Means و K-Medoids قادر به ‌خوشه‌بندی صحیح کلاله زعفران هستند. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که برای اولین بار، روش‌های داده‌کاوی می‌توانند شیوه‌ای بسیار مؤثر، با دقت و صحت بالای 90 درصد برای تمایز ژنتیکی کلاله سه‌شاخه از چند‌‌شاخه مورد استفاده قرار گیرد. این روش‌ها می‌توانند در مکان‌یابی ژنی و انتخاب به کمک بیومارکرها مورد استفاده قرار گیرند.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>چندشکلی توالی مربوط تکثیر یافته</kwd>
						<kwd>مارکر مولکولی</kwd>
						<kwd>یاد‌گیری ماشینی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Beiki, A., Keify, F., and Mozafari, J. 2011. Rapid genomic DNA isolation from corm of Crocus species for genetic diversity analysis. Journal of Medicinal Plants Research 5: 4596-4600.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Beiki, A.H., Saboor, S., and Ebrahimi, M. 2012. A new avenue for classification and prediction of olive cultivars using supervised and unsupervised algorithms. PloS ONE 7: e44164.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Benešová, M., Holá, D., Fischer, L., Jedelský, P.L., Hnilička, F., Wilhelmová, N., Rothová, O., Kočová, M., Procházková, D., and Honnerová, J. 2012. The physiology and proteomics of drought tolerance in maize: early stomatal closure as a cause of lower tolerance to short-term dehydration? PloS ONE 7: e38017.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Bernardo, R. 2008. Molecular markers and selection for complex traits in plants: learning from the last 20 years. Crop Science 48: 1649-1664.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Bishop, C.M. 2006. Pattern recognition and machine learning.Springer New York, 738 pages.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Caiola, M.G., and Canini, A. 2010. Looking for saffron’s (Crocus sativusL.) parents. Saffron. Functional Plant Science and Biotechnology 4: 1-14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Caiola, M.G., Caputo, P., and Zanier, R. 2004. RAPD analysis in Crocus sativus L. accessions and related Crocus species. Biologia Plantarum 48: 375-380.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Chang, Y.-Y., Kao, N.-H., Li, J.-Y., Hsu, W.-H., Liang, Y.-L., Wu, J.-W., and Yang, C.-H. 2010. Characterization of the possible roles for B class MADS box genes in regulation of perianth formation in orchid. Plant Physiology 152: 837-853.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Duda, R.O., Hart, P.E.,and Stork, D.G. 1999. Pattern classification. John Wiley &amp; Sons, 680 pages.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Fukunaga, K. 1990. Introduction to statistical pattern recognition. Academic press, 592 pages.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Gentleman, R., and Carey, V. 2008. Unsupervised machine learning. Bioconductor Case Studies. Springer, pp. 137-157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Hall, M.A., and Holmes, G. 2003. Benchmarking attribute selection techniques for discrete class data mining. Knowledge and Data Engineering, IEEE Transactions on 15: 1437-1447.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Jannink, J.-L., Lorenz, A.J., and Iwata, H. 2010. Genomic selection in plant breeding: from theory to practice. Briefings in Functional Genomics 9: 166-177.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Keify, F., and Beiki, A.H. 2012. Exploitation of random amplified polymorphic DNA (RAPD) and sequence-related amplified polymorphism (SRAP) markers for genetic diversity of saffron collection. Journal of Medicinal Plants Research 6: 2761-2768.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Kohavi, R., and John, G.H. 1997. Wrappers for feature subset selection. Artificial Intelligence 97: 273-324.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Li, G., and Quiros, C.F. 2001. Sequence-related amplified polymorphism (SRAP), a new marker system based on a simple PCR reaction: its application to mapping and gene tagging in Brassica. Theoretical and Applied Genetics 103: 455-461.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Maenhout, S., De Baets, B., Haesaert, G., and Van Bockstaele, E. 2007. Support vector machine regression for the prediction of maize hybrid performance. Theoretical and Applied Genetics 115: 1003-1013.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Maenhout, S., De Baets, B., Haesaert, G., and Van Bockstaele, E. 2008. Marker-based screening of maize inbred lines using support vector machine regression. Euphytica 161: 123-131.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Mierswa, I. 2009. Open Source data mining Rapid Miner. KI 23: 62-63.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Mitra, S., and Acharya, T. 2005. Data mining: multimedia, soft computing, and bioinformatics. John Wiley &amp; Sons, 424 pages.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Negbi, M. 2003. Saffron: Crocus sativus L. CRC Press, 148 pages.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Ornella, L., Cervigni, G., and Tapia, E. 2012. Applications of Machine Learning in Breeding for Stress Tolerance in Maize. Crop Stress and its Management: Perspectives and Strategies. Springer, pp. 163-192.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Pang, B., Lee, L., and Vaithyanathan, S. 2002. Thumbs up?: sentiment classification using machine learning techniques. Proceedings of the ACL-02 Conference on EmpiricalMethods in Natural Language Processing-Volume 10. Association for Computational Linguistics, pp. 79-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Steinfath, M., Gärtner, T., Lisec, J., Meyer, R.C., Altmann, T., Willmitzer, L., and Selbig, J. 2010. Prediction of hybrid biomass in Arabidopsis thaliana by selected parental SNP and metabolic markers. Theoretical and Applied Genetics 120: 239-247.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Sun, S.-J., Gao, W., Lin, S.-Q., Zhu, J., Xie, B.-G., and Lin, Z.-B. 2006. Analysis of genetic diversity in Ganoderma population with a novel molecular marker SRAP. Applied Microbiology and Biotechnology 72: 537-543.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Tsaftaris, A., Pasentsis, K., Kalivas, A., Michailidou, S., Madesis, P., and Argiriou, A. 2012. Isolation of a CENTRORADIALIS/TERMINAL FLOWER1 homolog in saffron (Crocus sativus L.): characterization and expression analysis. Molecular Biology Reports 39: 7899-7910.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Tsaftaris, A., Pasentsis, K., Makris, A., Darzentas, N., Polidoros, A., Kalivas, A., and Argiriou, A. 2011. The study of the E-class SEPALLATA3-like MADS-box genes in wild-type and mutant flowers of cultivated saffron crocus (Crocus sativus L.) and its putative progenitors. Journal of Plant Physiology 168: 1675-1684.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Tsaftaris, A., Pasentsis, K.,and Polidoros, A. 2005. Isolation of a differentially spliced C-type flower specific AG-like MADS-box gene from Crocus sativus and characterization of its expression. Biologia Plantarum 49: 499-504.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Tsaftaris, A.S., Polidoros, A.N., Pasentsis, K., and Kalivas, A. 2006. Tepal formation and expression pattern of B-class paleo AP3-like MADS-box genes in crocus (Crocus sativus L.). Plant Science 170: 238-246.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Tsaftaris, A.S., Polidoros, A.N., Pasentsis, K., and Kalivas, A. 2007. Cloning, structural characterization, and phylogenetic analysis of flower MADS-box genes from crocus (Crocus sativus L.). The Scientific World Journal 7: 1047-1062.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Webb, A.R., 2003. Statistical pattern recognition. John Wiley &amp; Sons, 672 pages.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2014.7864</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7864_31ad2bdfd65c0548a790220f988aa1bf.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>شناسایی برخی از قارچ های عامل پوسیدگی بنه زعفران و کنترل آن‌ها</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>سعیدی زاده</surname>
			            <given-names>آیت اله</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه گیاه‌پزشکی، دانشکده علوم کشاورزی، دانشگاه شاهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>10</month>
			        <year>2014</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>205</fpage>
			      <lpage>213</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>21</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2014, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7864.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7864.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>جهت شناسایی عوامل قارچی پوسیدگی بنه زعفران و کنترل آن‌ها، از مزارع و محل‌های نگهداری بنه، واقع در بشرویه از توابع استان خراسان جنوبی، نمونه‌برداری صورت گرفت. پس از کشت بافت‌های آلوده، گونه‌های قارچیPenicillium digitatum، Aspergillus nigerو Rhizopus stoloniferجداسازی و شناسایی گردید. جهت کنترل این بیمارگرها از چهار غلظت از سوسپانسیون باکتری Pseudomonas fluorescens CHAO، قارچ Trichoderma harzianum Bi و قارچ‌کش‌های اکسی‌کلرورمس و بنومیل در چهار تکرار استفاده شد. بر اساس میزان قطر پرگنه رشد یافته از بیمارگر و مقایسه با شاهد، میزان اثر کنترلی عوامل کنترل زیستی و ترکیبات شیمیایی اندازه‌گیری شد. نتایج به‌دست‌‌آمده نشان داد که بیشترین میزان کنترل در مورد قارچ همستیز، مربوط به غلظت‌های7 10×1 و 8 10×1 و در مورد باکتری همستیز به ترتیب مربوط به غلظت‌های 9 10×1 و 1010×1 بوده است. در مورد ترکیبات شیمیایی به‌کار رفته بیشترین میزان اثر کنترلی در مورد بنومیل و اکسی‌کلرورمس به‌ترتیب در غلظت‌های3-10×3 و 3-10×4 به‌دست آمد. در مقایسه کلی تیمارها، قارچ T. harzianum بیشترین اثر را در کاهش رشد پرگنه قارچ‌های بیمارگر داشت.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کنترل زیستی</kwd>
						<kwd>قارچ‌های همستیز</kwd>
						<kwd>زعفران</kwd>
						<kwd>خراسان جنوبی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Coursey, D.G., and Booth, R.H. 1972. The post-harvest phytopathology of perishable tropical produce. Review of Plant Pathology 51: 751-765.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Dennis, C. 1983. Post-harvest pathology of fruits and vegetables. Academic Press, New York. Pp. 264.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Dubos, B. 1984. Biocontrol of Botrytis cinerea on grapevine by antagonistic strain of Trichoderma harzianum. Pages 370-374 in: Current Perspectives in Microbial Ecology. M.J. Klub and C.A. Reedy, eds. American Society for Microbiology, Washington, DC.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Dubos, B. Jailloux, F., and Bulit, J. 1982. Employing antagonistic properties of Trichoderma against Botrytis cinerea in the protection of vineyards against grey-mold. Phytoparasitica 10:134.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Forakinejad, Z. 2008. Saffron, red gold of Iran. Journal of Teaching Biology 22 (2): 62.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Frisvad, J.C., and Samson, R.A. 2004. Polyphasic taxonomy of Penicillium sungenus Penicillium. A guide to identification of food and air-borne terverticillate Penicillia and their mycotoxins. Studies in Mycology 49: 1-173.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Hassan, M. G., and Devi, L.S.  2003. Corm rot diseases of saffron in Kashmir valley. Indian Phytopathology 56 (1): 112.    </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Hebbar, K. P., Martel, M. H., and Heulin, T. 1998. Suppression of pre- and postemergence damping-off in corn by Burkholderia cepacia. European Journal of Plant Pathology 104: 29-36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Janisiewicz, W.j. 1987. Biological control of postharvest diseases of pome fruits. (Abstr.). Phytopathology 75: 1301.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Janisiewicz, W.J. 1988. Biocontrol of postharvest diseases of apples with antagonist mixtures. Phytopathology 78:  194-198.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Kalha, C. S., Gupta, V., Gupta, D., and Priya S. 2007. First report of sclerotial rot of saffron caused by Sclerotium rolfsii in India. Plant Diseases 91 (9): 1203-1203.   </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Kerry, B.R. 1998. Progress towards biological control strategies for plant-parasitic nematodes. The 1998 Brighton Crop Protection Conference: Pests and Diseases 3:739-746.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Lim, T.K., and Rohrbach K.G. 1980. Role of Penicillium funicoulosum starins in the development of pineapple fruit diseases. Phtopathology 70: 663-665.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Maleki Ziyarati H., Roostaei A., Sahebani N., Etebarian H.R., and Aminian H. 2009. Study on biological control of root-knot nematode Meloidogyne javanica (Trube) Chitwood by fungus Trichoderma harzianum Rifai in tomato at greenhouse and quantitative changes in phenolic compounds in plant. Seed and Agronomy 25 (3): 274- 261.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Moazami Goudarzi, M. 2008. Red gold of Iran, from production to process. Journal of Livestock, agro-industry 103: 56.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Primo, P., and Cappelli, C. 2000. Preliminary characterization of Fusarium oxysporum f.sp. gladioli causing Fusarium corm rot of saffron in Italy. Plant Diseases 84 (7): 806-806.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Pusey, P.L., and Wilson, C.I. 1984. Postharvest biological control of stone fruit brown rot by Bacillius subtilis. Plant Diseases 68: 753-756.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Rowe, R.C., Johnson, D.A., Beery, W.R., and Omer, M.A. 2000. Vegetative compatibility analysis of strains of Verticillium dahliae from potato seed tubers and plants from the western and eastern United States Pp 74-94 in: advances in verticillium research and disease management (E. Tjamas, R.C. Row, J.B. Heal and D. Fravel, eds.). The American Phytopathological Society, St. Paul, MN.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>SAS Institute. 1999. SAS/Stat User’s Guide, Version 8.0. SAS Institute, Cary, NC.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Schipper, M.A.A. 1984. A revision of the genus Rhizopus. I. The Rh.stolonifer-group and Rhizopusoryzae. CBS Studies in Mycology 25:1-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Schnathorst, W.C., and Mathre D.E. 1966. Host rang and differentiation of a severe form of Verticilliumalbo–atrum in cotton. Phytopathology 56: 1155-1161.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Shah, A., and Srivastava K.K. 1984. Control of corm rot of saffron. Progressive Horticulture 16(1/2): 141-143.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Sud, A.K., Paul, Y.S., and Thakur B.R. 1999. Corm rot of saffron and its management. Journal of Mycology and Plant Pathology 29(3): 380-382.    </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Thakur, R.N., Singh, C., and Kaul B.L. 1992. First report of corm rot in Crocus sativus. Indian Phytopathology 45  (2): 278.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Tronsmo, A. 1983. Trichoderma harzianum used as a biocontrol agent against Botrytis cinerea on apple. Colloq.  INRA 18: 109-113.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Tronsmo, A., and Raa J. 1977. Antagonistic action of Trichoderma pseudokoningii against the apple pathogen Botrytis cinerea. Phytopathologische Zeitschrift-Journal of Phytopathology 89: 216-220.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Van Tieghem, P.E.L. 1867. Aspergillus niger. Annual of Science of National Botany 5 (8): 240. </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Weller, D.M., and Cook R.J. 1983. Suppression of take-all of wheat by seed treatments with fluorescent  pseudomonads. Phytopathology 78: 463-469.   </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>White, D., Knox, G., Killham, K., and Leifert C. 1999. The application of lux-gene technology in the control of soilborne diseases.  227-248.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Wilson, C.L., Franklin, J.D., and Pusey, P.L. 1987. Biological control of Rhizopus rot of peach with Entrobacter cloacae. Phytopathology 77: 303-305.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Yuan, K.K., Guang, X.Z., Sheng, C.Q., Chong, H.D., Jun, Z.L., and Zhong, C. 2000. Study on occurrence and chemical control of saffron corm rot in Shanghai suburbs. Acta Agriculturae Shanghai 16: 41-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Zain, M.E., Razak, A.A., El-Sheikh, H.H., Soliman, H.G., and Khalil, A.M. 2009. Influence of growth medium on diagnostic characters of aspergillus and penicillium species. African Journal of Microbiology Research 3 (5): 280-286.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2014.7865</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7865_a83cf80c95eb026e323400281383fb26.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>اقتصاد و بازاریابی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>آزمون پیوستگی و فرضیه بازار مرکزی محصول زعفران در استان‌های خراسان رضوی، شمالی و جنوبی</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>کرباسی</surname>
			            <given-names>علیرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار دانشکده اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محمودی</surname>
			            <given-names>هاشم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه تبریز.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فکاری سردهایی</surname>
			            <given-names>بهزاد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فارسی علی آبادی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>10</month>
			        <year>2014</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>215</fpage>
			      <lpage>223</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>01</day>
			          <month>11</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>31</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2014, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7865.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7865.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>زعفران یکی از مهم‌ترین محصولات تولیدی کشاورزی کشور می‌باشد و استان‌های خراسان رضوی، جنوبی و شمالی از عمده‌ترین استان‌های تولیدکننده زعفران می‌باشند.‌ هدف از مطالعه حاضر سنجش فرضیه بازار مرکزی محصول زعفران در استان‌های خراسان شمالی، رضوی و جنوبی با استفاده از داده‌های ماهانه طی سال‌های 1385 تا 1390 می‌باشد. بدین منظور از فن آزمون هم‌جمعی برای سری‌های قیمت با استفاده از رهیافت یوهانسون بهره گرفته‌شده است. نتایج نشان‌داد که استان خراسان جنوبی نقش رهبری قیمت را در بین استان‌های مذکور بر عهده دارد. این در حالی است که از بین سه استان مربوطه، استان‌های خراسان رضوی و جنوبی تشکیل یک بازار واحد را می‌دهند که شرط LOP برای آن‌ها صادق می‌باشد. استان خراسان شمالی نیز بازاری است که در بلندمدت تحت تأثیر تغییرات قیمت دو استان خراسان رضوی و جنوبی قرار نمی‌گیرد و به‌صورت یک بازار مجزا رفتار می‌کند. لذا اتخاذ یک سیاست در بازار زعفران در هر یک از این سه استان‌، بازار این محصول در دو استان دیگر را تحت‌الشعاع قرار می‌دهد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>بازار مرکزی</kwd>
						<kwd>پیوستگی بازار</kwd>
						<kwd>محصول زعفران</kwd>
						<kwd>هم جمعی برداری</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2014.7866</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7866_0aa2e75baee5e2987600eadadef2cddb.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>علوم و صنایع دارویی و پزشکی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تأثیر مکمل‌دهی زعفران بر شاخص‌های استقامت قلبی-تنفسی دختران سالم غیرفعال</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>معمار باشی</surname>
			            <given-names>عباس</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حکیمی</surname>
			            <given-names>ویدا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد فیزیولوژی ورزشی دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>10</month>
			        <year>2014</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>225</fpage>
			      <lpage>230</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>03</day>
			          <month>08</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>19</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2014, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7866.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7866.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>هدف از پژوهش حاضر بررسی اثر مکمل زعفران بر فاکتورهای استقامت قلبی-تنفسی در زنان سالم غیرفعال بود. پس از تکمیل پرسش‌نامه تندرستی و فعالیت بدنی و اجرای تست یک مایل دویدن، از میان افراد واجد شرایط 14 نفر از دانشجویان دختر غیرفعال دانشگاه محقق (با میانگین سنی 38/1± 7/20 سال و شاخص توده بدنی 8/1±1/21) انتخاب شدند و 3 مرحله آزمون بروس را بر روی دستگاه نوارگردان متصل به دستگاه تجزیه‌وتحلیل گازهای تنفسی به فاصله یک هفته از یک‌دیگر اجرا کردند. در این تحقیق آزمودنی‌ها در مرحله اول یک هفته پس از مصرف دارونما و در مرحله دوم یک هفته پس از مصرف روزانه، 300 میلی‌گرم کلاله گل زعفران تست را اجرا نموده و متغیرهای مورد نظر اندازه‌گیری شد. برای تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌ها از آزمون تحلیل کوواریانس و تصحیح بونفرونی استفاده شد. نتایج نشان داد که مصرف 300 میلی‌گرم زعفران به‌مدت یک هفته باعث افزایش معنی‌داری دراکسیژن مصرفی (VO2)، حداکثر اکسیژن مصرفی (VO2max) و زمان واماندگی و کاهش معنی‌دار در فشارخون و ضربان قلب در حالت استراحت شد و همچنین در گروه تجربی افزایش معنی‌دار در اکسیداسیون چربی و کاهش معنی‌دار در مصرف کربوهیدرات طی اجرای تست بروس مشاهده شد (05/0 p&lt;). در نتیجه، مصرف زعفران اثر ارگوژنیکی بر عملکرد قلبی-تنفسی دانشجویان دختر غیرفعال دارد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>حداکثر اکسیژن مصرفی</kwd>
						<kwd>مکمل‌دهی زعفران</kwd>
						<kwd>عملکرد ورزشی</kwd>
						<kwd>گازومتری</kwd>
						<kwd>فشارخون</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Altman, D.G., Gore, S.M., Gardner, M.J., and Pocock, S.J. 1983.Statistical guidelines for contributors to medical journals British Medical Journal 286 (6376): 1489-93.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Emamghoreshi, M., and Ghasemi, F. 2011. The effect of subchronic administration of the aqueous and hydro-alcoholic extracts of Crocussativus from Estahbanat, Fars Province, on mice. Armaghane-danesh, Yasuj University of Medical Sciences Journal (YUMSJ) 6 (16): 527-536. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Fatehi, M., Rashidabady, T., and Fatehi-Hassanabad, Z. 2003. Effects of Crocus sativus petals extract on rat blood pressure and on responses induced by electrical field stimulation in the rat isolated vas deferens and guinea-pig ileum. Journal of Ethnopharmacology 84 (2-3): 199-203.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Grisolia, S.1974. Hypoxia, saffron and cardiovascular disease. Lancet 2: 41-42.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Herbold, N.H., Visconti, B.K., Frates, S., and Bandini, L. 2004. Traditional and nontraditional supplement use in collegiate female varsity athletes. International Journal of Sport Nutrition and Exercise Metabolism14: 586-593.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Hosseinzadeh,H.,Karimi, G., and Niapoor, M. 2004.Antidepressant effect of Crocus sativus L.stigma extracts and their constitutes, crocin and safranal, in mice.Journal of Medicinal Plants 11: 48-58. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Imenshahidi, M., Hosseinzadeh, H., and Javadpour, Y. 2010. Hypotensive effect of aqueous saffron extract (Crocus sativus L.) and its constituents, Safranal and Crocin, in normotensive and hypertensive rats. Phytotherapy Research 24: 990-4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Kemper, H., and Koppes, L. 2006. Linking physical activity and aerobic fitness: are we active because we are fit, or are we fit because we are active. Pediatric Exercise Science 18 (2): 173-181.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Meamarbashi, A., and Rajabi, A. 2014. Preventive effects  of 10-day supplementation with saffron and Indomethacin on the delayed-onset muscle soreness. Clinical Journal of Sport Medicine 18: 53-66. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Moghadam, MH., Shahabian, M., Esmaeili, H., and HosseinZadeh, H. 2008. Safety evaluation of saffron (Crocus sativus) tablets in healthy volunteers. Phytomedicine 15: 1032-1037. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Moradi,Z., Shemshaki, F., and Basami, M. 2012. The effects of saffron supaseandplementation on changes in superoxide dismutase and catalase during strenuous anaerobic exercise in young women. Sport physiology 14 (4): 119-130. (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Razavi, B., Imanshahidi, M., Abnus, K., and Hosseinzade, H. 2013. Cardiovascular effects of saffron and its active constituents: A review article. Saffron Agronomy &amp; Technology 1 (2): 3-13. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Sheng, L., Qian, Z., Zheng, S., and Xi, L. 2006. Mechanism of hypolipidemic effect of crocin in rats: crocin inhibits pancreatic lipase. European Journal of Pharmacology 543: 116-22.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Tartibian, B., Khorshidi, M. 2006. Predication of physiological indexes in exercise (field &amp; laboratory). Teimourzaddeh, Iran.p.109-111. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Tomas, J., and Nelson, J. 2001.  Research Methods in Physical Activity. (4lh ed.). Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی کوتاه" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2014.7867</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7867_78e4c5b48ab7e7d20d55b051b3e3374e.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>فرآوری، صنایع غذایی و بیوشیمی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی فعالیت آنتی اکسیدانی عصاره های آبی و الکلی (متانول، اتانول) گلبرگ زعفران</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>افرازه</surname>
			            <given-names>زهرا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد علوم و صنایع غذایی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد دامغان.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بلندی</surname>
			            <given-names>مرضیه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه مهندسی علوم وصنایع غذایی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد دامغان.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>خورشیدی</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار دانشکده زیست شناسی، دانشگاه دامغان.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محمدی نافچی</surname>
			            <given-names>عبدالرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه مهندسی علوم وصنایع غذایی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد دامغان.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>10</month>
			        <year>2014</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>2</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>231</fpage>
			      <lpage>236</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>04</day>
			          <month>08</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>21</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2014, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7867.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_7867.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>گیاهان دارویی یکی از منابع مهم آنتی‌اکسیدان‌هامی‌باشند، آنتی‌اکسیدان‌های طبیعی باعث افزایش قدرت آنتی‌اکسیدان‌های پلاسما و کاهش ابتلا به بعضی بیماری‌ها مانند سرطان، بیماری‌های قلبی و سکته مغزی می‌شوند. با توجه به سمی بودن و اثرات سوءتغذیه‌ای آنتی‌اکسیدان‌های سنتزی موجود در مواد غذایی، نیاز به آنتی‌اکسیدان‌های طبیعی از گیاهان با سمیت کمتر و اثربخشی بیشتر یک ضرورت جدی است. گلبرگ زعفران یک منبع گیاهی غنی از مواد پلی فنولی است که تاکنون موردتوجه قرار نگرفته است. لذا این پژوهش به‌منظور بررسی خواص آنتی‌اکسیدانی و ترکیبات فنولیک گلبرگ زعفران انجام شد. در این پژوهش ابتدا عصاره گلبرگ زعفران با حلال‌های الکلی اتانول و متانول 30، 70 و 90 درصد و آب به‌طور جداگانه استخراج شد. سپس میزان ترکیبات فنولی به روش فولین سیوکالتیو و فعالیت آنتی‌اکسیدانی آن به روش احیای رادیکال آزاد DPPH ارزیابی شد. نتایج نشان داد که نوع و میزان حلال بر میزان ترکیبات فنولی و آنتی‌اکسیدانی اثر دارد و ارتباط معنی‌داری بین میزان ترکیبات فنولی و خاصیت بازدارندگی مشاهده شد. همچنین با افزایش غلظت، خاصیت آنتی‌اکسیدانی و ترکیبات فنولی عصاره افزایش می‌یابد. در پایان عصاره اتانولی به‌عنوان بهترین حلال برای بیشترین استخراج ترکیبات فنولی و آنتی‌اکسیدانی مشخص شد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>ترکیبات فنولی</kwd>
						<kwd>DPPH</kwd>
						<kwd>فولین سیوکالتیو</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Amonrat, T., Soottawat, B., Wonnop, V., Eric, A., and Decker, C. 2008. The effect of antioxidants on the quality changes of cuttlefish (Sepia pharaonis) muscle during frozen storage. LWT- Food Science and Technology 41 (1): 161-169.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Andreja, H., Majda, H., Zeljko, K., and Davorin, B. 2000. Comparison of antioxidative and synergistic effects of rosemary extract with α - tocopherol, ascorbyl palmitate and citric acid in sunflower oil. Food Chemistry 71 (2): 233-229.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Bergamini, C.M., Gambetti, S., Dondi A., and Cervellati C. 2004. Oxygen, reactive oxygen species and tissue damage. Current Pharmaceutical Design10 (14): 1611-1626.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Chimi, H., Cillard, J., Cillar, P., and Rahmani, M. 1991. The peroxyl and hydroxyl radical scavenging activity of some natural phenolic antioxidant. Journal of the American Oil Chemists Society 68: 307.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Gil, M.I., Tomás-Barberán, F.A.,Hess-Pierce, B., and Kader, A.A. 2002. Antioxidant capacities, phenolic compounds, carotenoids, and vitamin C contents of nectarine, peach, and plum cultivars from California. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry 50: 4976-4982.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Hasani, M., Hagh Dost, A., and Nasiri, N. 2011. Antioxidant activity of methanol extract of some medicinal plants and their comparison with BHT.20th National Congress of Food Science and Technology, Tehran, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Hemmati Kakhki, A., and Rahimi, S.K. 1994. Extraction of anthocyanin from petals of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)  and its stability in a model beverage. Iranian Research Organization for Science.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Kosar, M., Bozan, B., Temelli, F., and Baser, K.H.C. 2007. Antioxidant activity and phenolic composition of sumac (Rhus coriaria L.) extracts. Food Chemistry 103: 952-959.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Kossah, R., Zhang, H., and Chen, W. 2011. Antimicrobial and antioxidant activities of Chinese sumac (Rhus typhina L.) fruit extract.Food Control 22: 128-132.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Mathew, S., and Abraham, T.E. 2006. In vitro antioxidant activity and scavenging effects of Cinnamomum verum leaf extract assayed by different methodologies. Food and Chemical Toxicology 44: 198-206.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Mirheidar, H. 1996. Herbal information, 2nd edition, Volume 2.Bureau of Islamic culture publication. Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Shahidi, F.,and Naczk M. 2004. Phenolic in Food and Nutraceuticals. Chemical Rubber Company press. 558 p</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Shrififar, F., Moshafi, M.H.,and Mansouri, S.H. 2007. In vitro evaluation of antibacterial and antioxidant of the essential oil and methanol extract of endemic Zatariamultiflora Boiss. Food Control 18: 800-805.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Singh, G., Maurya, S., and Delampasona, M.P. 2007. A comparison of chemical antioxidant and antimicrobial studies of cinnamon leaf and bark volatile oils, oleoresins and their constituents. Food and Chemical Toxicology 45: 1650-61.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Su L., Yin, J.J., Charles, D., Zhou, K., Moore, J., and Yu, L. 2007. Total phenolic contents chelating capacities and radical scavenging properties of black peppercorn, nutmeg, rosehip, cinnamon and oregano leaf. Food Chemistry 100: 990-7.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Velioglu, Y.S., Mazza, G., Gao, L., and Oomah, B.D. 1998. Antioxidant activity and total phenolics in selected fruits, vegetables and grain products. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry 46: 4113-4117.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>