<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Effects of corm origin, corm weight and nutrient foliar application on yield and qualitative traits of saffron (.Crocus sativus L)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">sahabi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری اکولوژی گیاهان زراعی دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohsen</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">jahan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Agronomy, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">kochaki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Agronomy, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nassiri Mahallati</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Agronomy, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In general, corm weight and nutrient management are considered as the most important factors in relation to quantitative and qualitative traits of saffron. In order to investigate the effects of mother corm origin, mother corm weight and nutrient foliar application on yield and qualitative traits of saffron, a field experiment was conducted as factorial layout based on a randomized complete block design with three replications at the Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran, during the years from 2012 to 2015. The mother corm origin (Iranian and Spanish corms), mother corm weight 8 g and lower (small), 8.1–15 g (medium) and 15.1-23 g (large) and nutrient foliar application (application and control) were considered as the first, second and third experimental factors, respectively. According to the results, the larger mother corms significantly resulted in a greater number of flowers per m2, increased fresh flower and dry stigma + style yields. However, the effect of nutrient foliar application was observed to be not significant on these traits. When Iranian mother corms were planted, the number of flowers per m2, fresh flower and dry stigma + style yields were higher, compared with Spanish mother corms. For instance, flower number, fresh flower and dry stigma + style yields increased by 17, 13 and 14%, respectively, when planting Iranian mother corms. Nonetheless, picrocrocin concentration was higher (up to 3.8%) in the Spanish planted corm treatment. Based on the results, beside the optimal nutrient foliar application, the importance of adapting the corms origin with environmental conditions of the site designated for planting is emphasized.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>269</start>
					<end>277</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_51720_66059426dec9cf2991430aad70b40c85.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2017.93779.1251</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Comparison of the effect of irrigation levels and methods on leaf area and replacement corm production of saffron (.Crocus sativus L)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Karimiferezgh</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD student in Crop Physiology, Department of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, College of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">حمیدرضا</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">خزاعی</namePart>
				<affiliation>استاد گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kafi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor Agronomy and Plant Breeding Department, College of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nezami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor Agronomy and Plant Breeding Department, College of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In order to compare the effect of irrigation levels and methods on leaf area and replacement corm production of saffron during 2013-2014 growing season, a split plot experiment was conducted in randomized complete block design with three replications in the Jolgeh Rokh District, in 35 km Torbat Heydarie. The main plot basin irrigation, drip and sprinkler irrigation and sub plot was three levels of irrigation (100, 75 and 50 percent water requirement of saffron). The traits studied were including dry weight, number, diameter and length of leaf, dry weight, size and number of replacement corms, weight and length sheath. Sampling for determining the characteristics of leaf and sheath was done on April 30, and for corm it was done on May 31, 2014. The results showed that in the irrigation method treatments, the most dry weight of corm, leaf and sheath weight, size and number of replacement corm, number, diameter and length of leaf were observed in the case of drip irrigation. In addition, the best yield was observed in drip irrigation and the lowest amount was seen in basin irrigation. Saffron irrigation with the drip method resulted in an increase of the number of replacement corms compared to the sprinkler and basin methods (10 and 34 percent, respectively). The effect of irrigation levels was significant on some of the traits that were studied and the most yield was related to 100 percent irrigation level and the lowest one was in the 50 percent water requirement. Reducing irrigation from 100 to 50% crop water requirement severely reduced replacement corms number and their weight (62 and 86 percent, respectively). Consequently, the most photosynthesis level of Saffron and also the maximum amount of total number and total weight of replacement corms were obtained in the drip irrigation case and 100 percent irrigation level. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>279</start>
					<end>290</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_57121_95204894b081a16d5e5832957a332858.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.46986.1137</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Study the effects of organic and chemical fertilizers on replacement corms and flower characteristics of Saffron  (Crocus sativus L.)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Zakieh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shariatmadari</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student, Department of Horticulter, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad international campus</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahmoud</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shoor</namePart>
				<affiliation>Department of Horticulter, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parviz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rezvani Moghaddam</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor of AgroEcology
Department of Agronomy
Faculty of Agriculture
Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tehranifar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Department of Horticulter, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad,</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">ahmadian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Plant Production Department, and Researcher of Saffron Institute, University of Torbat Heydarieh</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In order to study the effects of organic and chemical fertilizers on replacement cormsand flowercharacteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.), an experiment was conducted in a factorial layout based on randomized complete block design with three replications in a farm at Zaveh, Iran in the growing season of 2013-2014 The experimental treatments were all combination of six types of organic fertilizers (Sheep manure (10 t.ha-1), cow manure (30 t.ha-1), vermi compost (6 t.ha-1), hen manure (5 t.ha-1), urban compost (9 t.ha-1) and control and using and not using chemical fertilizer (Nitrogen (100 kg.ha-1)+Phosphate (80 kg.ha-1)). The studied criteria included: total weight  of cormper square meter, average number of buds per corm, diameter of corm and number of replacement cormsin each weight categories (0.1-4g,4.1-8g, 8.1-12g,12.1-16g and more than16.1g), number of flowers, fresh weight offlowers,stigmaandstyle dry weight per square meter, and harvest index of stigma. The results showed that the simple and interaction effects of  using and not using chemical fertilizers and organic fertilizers on all studied criteria were significant. Control+chemical fertilizer and hen manure+without chemical fertilizer treatments produced the highest and lowest total corm number (228 and 177 corm per in m2), respectively. The highest and lowest total corm weight (1876 and 1623 g.m-2, respectively), average single corm weight (10.94 and 7.75 g.m-2, respectively), average corm diameter (3 and 2.72 cm, respectively) and average number of buds (8 and 1.33 bud per corm, respectively) were obtained in hen manure+without chemical fertilizer and control+chemical fertilizer treatments, respectively. Control+chemical fertilizer produced the highest replacement corms at the weights of 0.1-4 (12.64%) and 4.1-8g (10.31%) categories. The highest percentage of number of replacement corms at 8.1-12 (16.77%), 12.1-16 (18.10%), and more than 16.1g (31.38%) weight categories were shown in the hen manure+ without chemical fertilizer treatment. Hen manure+without chemical fertilizer and control+ chemical fertilizer treatments produced the highest and lowest number of flowers (142 and 56 flower per square meter, respectively), fresh flower weight (50.20 and 17.60 g.m-2, respectively), stigma dry weight (0.405 and 0.169 g.m-2, respectively), style dry weight (0.685and 0.080 g.m-2, respectively), harvest index of stigma (0.0082, 0.0011, respectively), respectively. The results showed that flower yield in the second year was directly affected by the weight of replacement corms which were produced in the first year. Overall, the results of the present study revealed that the application of organic fertilizer compared with chemical fertilizers had superior effect on replacement corms and yield criteria of saffron.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>291</start>
					<end>308</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_51721_276449af18727b68b2d50999b97f0cd8.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2017.89478.1239</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Effect of bio-fertilizers and nitrogen on quantitative and qualitative characteristics of tepals in saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Azizollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kheiry</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Horticulture, Faculty of Agriculture, Zanjan University, Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hajar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Parsa</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc Student, Physiology and Medicinal Plants Breeding, Faculty of Agriculture, Zanjan University, Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohsen</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sani Khani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Horticulture, Faculty of Agriculture, Zanjan University, Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Farhang</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Razavi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Horticulture, Faculty of Agriculture, Zanjan University, Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In order to investigate the effect of different nitrogen sources on some quantitative and biochemical characteristics of Saffron Petals, an experiment was conducted based on randomized complete block design with three replications on the Research Farm of University of Zanjan. The treatments were Azotobarvar-1 bio-fertilizer (containing free-living nitrogen-fixing bacteria Azotobacter vinelandii) with two levels (0.1 and 0.2 percent), Nitrokara (containing symbiotic and free-living nitrogen-fixing bacteria Azorhizobium caulinodan) with two levels (1 and 2 percent) and combinations of both of them with four treatments (1percent Nitrokara + 0.1 percent Azotobarvar-1, 1 percent Nitrokara + 0.2 percent Azotobarvar-1, 2 percent Nitrokara + 0.1 percent Azotobarvar-1, 2 percent Nitrokara + 0.2 percent Azotobarvar-1) compared to control and one nitrogen level (40 kg/ha). The results showed that the highest yield of petals and stigma were obtained in 0.2 percent Azotobacter while the highest average dry flower weight resulted in 2 percent Azorhizobium treatment. The highest leaf nitrogen content and total chlorophyll were obtained in 0.2 percent Azotobacter and 40 kg/ha of nitrogen treatments. Also 40 Kg/ha nitrogen resulted in the highest leaf area. The highest antioxidant, total phenol and anthocyanin of tepal were achieved in 0.1 percent Azotobacter while the highest amount of flavonoid was observed in 1 percent Azorhizobium. The results showed that the application of all treatments increased yield of saffron petals. The 0.2 percent Azotobacter was the best treatment in terms of quantity of petal yield and 0.1 percent Azotobacter resulted in highest antioxidant content and therefore it can be recommended.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>309</start>
					<end>322</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_55639_129f78be2e83e7fa549c337d54c782aa.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2017.92549.1246</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigting the effects of some physical and cultural methods on the population of bulb mite (Rhizoglyphus robini) and yield of saffron (.Crocus sativus L)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rahimi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Agricultural and Natural Resources Research and Training Center of Khorassan Razavi</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ehssan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Torabi</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD student, Department of Plant Protection, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hossien</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rahimi</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc Agricultural and Natural Resources Research and Training Center of Khorassan Razavi</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Araghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>BSc Agricultural and Natural Resources Research and Training Center of Khorassan Razavi</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Roshnavandi</namePart>
				<affiliation>BSc Agricultural and Natural Resources Research and Training Center of Khorassan Razavi</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In this research, the effects of solarization by transparent plastics, planting time and the first irrigation after planting on the populations of saffron bulb mite (Rhizoglyphus robini) and yield (Crocus sativus L.) were investigated. A split plot experiment was conducted based on randomized complete block design with three replicates from 2011 to 2015 in Gonabad, Khorasan Razavi province. Solarization and non-solarization factors were placed in the main plots. Seven crop managing packages including 1- planting without irrigation in September, 2- irrigation immediately after planting in September, 3- planting without irrigation in June, 4- irrigation immediately after planting in June, 5- planting in June and irrigation in August, 6- planting without irrigation in September of the next year, and 7- irrigation immediately after planting in September of the next year were placed in sub-plots. The results showed that regardless of management package, solarization suppressed the mite populations and increased saffron yield. Package 4, Irrigation immediately after planting on June, increased the mite populations and decreased saffron yields. However, package 2, irrigation on September, reduces the mite populations and increases saffron yield. Planting Saffron in June (packages 3, 4, and 5) resulted in more yield compared to Planting at September (packages 1, 2, 6, and 7). The lowest reduction in the population of mites (94%) and the highest yield (77%) were achieved through solarization and by implementing package 3, treatment and cultivation in June of the next year with no irrigation after planting.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>323</start>
					<end>337</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_50899_08dece5571715ca8d28cda5a987157ab.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2017.62169.1195</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Study of flora and structure of weed communities of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) fields in Khorasan Razavi province</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali Asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Padarloo</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD student, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ebrahim</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Izadi Darbandi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Hassam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rashed Mohassel</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Feizi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Torbat Heydarieh, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>  The Khorasan Razavi province is the center of saffron production in Iran and the world. Among factors affecting saffron gap yield, weeds are the most important one. However there is no compiled information about saffron weed flora population and its structural characteristics in the Khorasan Razavi province. In order to identify and determine the density and frequency of weed species on saffron fields in the Khorasan Razavi province, 118 fields in 6 counties during two years (2014 and 2015) were selected based on the cultivation area and yield per area. In each field, weed species were counted in each sampling point and weed population indices including mean relative density, relative uniformity and frequently were calculated and latitude and altitude were recorded by GPS. By using recorded data, population indices of different weed species in the studied saffron farms including mean relative density and relative frequency of species were calculated.  During 2 years, a total of 52 weed species were identified and observed within the saffron fields. Between plant families, Brassicaceae, Asteraceae, Poaceae, Fabaceae and Charyophilaceae were the most abundant families, respectively. The results showed that the highest and lowest number of weed species belong to Kashmar and Gonabad counties, respectively. Based on the frequency index, the important annual weed species on saffron fields of the Khorasan Razavi province wereMouse Barle (Hordeum murinum) and London Roket (Sisymbrium septulatum) and perennial species were Hoary Cress (Cardaria draba) andCommon yarrow (Achillea millefoliam).</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>339</start>
					<end>353</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_54468_25f168269430688cde3dd806e91f1474.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2017.82782.1224</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Pricing strategies of saffron: strategic factors analytical</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rastegaripour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Msc Student of Agricultural Economics, University of Torbat  Heydarieh, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Karbasi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor of Agricultural Economic, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghorbani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rastegaripur</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of agricultural economics, university of Torbat Heydarieh and researcher of Saffron institute</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Saffron is considered as an important crop for farmers of the Khorasan Razavi province due to the ability to create high employment and generate appropriate income. Problems of saffron producers in marketing and export has caused this product not to be in a good position in the world market despite its high quality. Therefore, the study of marketing mix as one of the most important factors affecting marketing of saffron in the region seems to be necessary. In order to identify the strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats of marketing mix of saffron, a strategic factor analysis approach was used in this study. The required information was collected through face-to-face interviews and completing a questionnaire with managers and experts of saffron producing and exporting companies in Mashhad and Torbat Heydarieh cities in 2015. To investigate the validity of the questionnaire, the questionnaires were reviewed by supervisors and consultants and several experts. At first, some initial questions were completed and using the Cronbach&#039;s alpha method, the reliability coefficient was 0.79. The results of the internal factor matrix showed that the weaknesses overcome the strength and, according to the results of external factors matrix, the points of opportunity are superior to the threat. The results of the study showed that the increase in the value added due to saffron processing with a score of 0.57 and export value with a score of 0.54 are the most important strength and low purchase price of farmers with a score of 0.13 and a lack of knowledge of the price of competitors with a score of 0.11 are the most important weaknesses in marketing mix price. Also, the export of the product with different qualities based on the financial ability of target customers with a score of 0.32 and price determination based on the competitive and economic environment with 0.23 are most significant opportunities, and the volatility of the exchange rate with a score of 0.4 and a price fluctuation in the export market with a score of 0.36 are the most important current threats of saffron marketing. The general results obtained from the status analysis matrix indicate that the saffron processing factor strategies are defensive. Therefore, according to the results, the strategies of establishing a regional exchange market for saffron and long-term control of prices in export markets with the aim of paying attention to pricing and fair purchase are suggested.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>355</start>
					<end>366</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_55295_6aebc07772ea1a24c5e33932d37d8813.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2017.92171.1245</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Economic analysis of short-term and long-term effects of exchange rate uncertainty on the export of iranian saffron</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Esmaeil</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fallahi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Agricultural Economics, Shiraz University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mazraeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student of Agricultural Economics, Sari University of Agricultural Sciences and Natural Resources, Sari, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In order to get rid of single-product economy, trade of agricultural products is emphasized by the government. As Iran is the biggest producer and exporter of this strategic product in the world, the analysis of factors affecting export of Iran&#039;s saffron, can result in better policy making. Accordingly, this study is aim to investigate the short-term and long-term effects of exchange rate volatility beside the other factors affecting the export of this product using panel data for Iran&#039;s major trading partners during 1992-2014. For this purpose and to avoid the limitation of symmetric approaches to calculate instability indices, the exchange rate volatility index was firstly calculated by using asymmetric method of Exponential Generalized Auto-Regressive Conditional Heteroskedasticity (EGHARCH). Then, this index was used along with other variables to estimate of proposed model using the Fully Modified Ordinary Least Squares (FMOLS) method. The results showed that although countries income and real exchange rate have positive and significant effects on saffron export, exchange rate volatility has a negative and significant effect on export of this product. Therefore, if the government’s goal is to support the export of this product, it is vital to achieve stability in exchange rate market. Moreover, the results of estimating error correction model indicate that the speed of disequilibrium adjustment towards long-run equilibrium relationships is substantial. Therefore, policy-making would be hopeful in the short-term.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>367</start>
					<end>381</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_61827_9dec1623e9eb5e2a834132ad73fbdd02.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2017.83397.1226</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Effect of uncontrolled quality inputs on saffron fields efficiency (case study: Qaen County)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sargazi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Department of Agricultural Economics, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Zabol, Zabol, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdiyeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghavidel</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student of Department of Agricultural Economics, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Zabol</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The purpose of this paper is the impact of uncontrolled quality factors on the efficiency of saffron farms in the Qaen County. In this paper, we tried to study the impact of uncontrolled quality factors on the efficiency of saffron farms considering the importance of saffron in Qaen County. Information and data is collected through completion of 173 questionnaires in years 2015-16. The results of the research show that the efficiency of the scale with the value of 0.82 represents the highest mean. Also, the technical efficiency with constant and constant returns to the scale of 0.62 and 0.50 showed that the sample farms in terms of technical efficiency with variable and constant efficiency versus the scale have a potential of 38% and 50% in the amount of inputs and can reduce the inputs used without decreasing the production of the product. Also, the performance values ​​of the Bunker and Murray models (the model without considering the qualitative factors) did not show any difference compared with the new model (considering qualitative factors). Therefore, it seems that the role of activity scale does not appear only in the concepts of scale efficiency and type of return to scale, but it also has a relationship with technical efficiency. Thereby, doing complementary studies will focus on the activities of the scale.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>383</start>
					<end>391</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_57217_3e40211c390c313a242d036d4b2dc3da.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2017.72002.1209</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>