<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Saffron Agronomy and Technology (Book of Abstracts: 2013-2016)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rezvani Moghaddam, Parviz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Karbasi, Alireza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tosan, Moein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Gharari, Faezeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Feizi, Hassan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohtashami, Toktam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University Of Torbat Heydarieh]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Abstracts]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Book]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Saffron]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Khorasan province in Iran with a diverse climatic conditions has accommodated a wide range of plant communities particularly herbs, spices and medicinal plants. Among these Saffron (Crocus sativus L.), has been the most cultivated plant for thousands of years. These crop deliver unique interests and applications. The novel use of Saffron in recent years in cancer cure have been promenaded and stimulated more investigation on this crop. Almost 94% of the total world’s Saffron production (298 t) and 95% of the total Iran’s Saffron production (280 t) originates from Khorasan province. Saffron is unique for the area where water scarcity is the most limiting factor in crop productions for the farmer. Saffron is almost cultivated and harvested and also to some extent processed by family workers and community cooperation bases. These crop is not only the most important source of income for farmers but also historically strong socio-cultural activities have been formed within the local community. Cultivation area and its surrounding environment conditions and production volume of Saffron, has made Khorasan province a unique location in the world. The sustainable management of these traditionally cultivated and used plants not only helps to conserve nationally and globally important biodiversity but also provides critical resources to sustain livelihoods.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_39250_f2c5c707f539e2951e5aa4f001d6ad70.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22048/jsat.2016.39250]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Saffron agronomy and technology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>