<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1395</YEAR>
<VOL>4</VOL>
<NO>3</NO>
<MOSALSAL>13</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>0</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تاثیر سطوح مختلف کمپوست زباله شهری و وزن بنه مادری بر عملکرد و خصوصیات رشدی زعفران (.Crocus sativus L)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Effect of different levels of municipal waste compost and maternal corm weight on yield and vegetative characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مدیریت تغذیه و اندازه بنه مادری، از مهم‌ترین عوامل مؤثر بر رشد و عملکرد زعفران به شمار می‌روند. به منظور بررسی اثر کمپوست زباله شهری و وزن‌ بنه مادری بر شاخص‌های عملکرد گل و ویژگی‌های رشدی بنه زعفران، آزمایشی در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشگاه بیرجند، در سال زراعی 94-1393 اجرا شد. آزمایش به صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با 4 سطح کمپوست زباله شهری (0، 5، 10 و 20 تن در هکتار) و 3 سطح وزن بنه مادری (شامل گروه‌های وزنی 4-1/0، 8-1/4 و 12-1/8 گرم) و در 3 تکرار اجرا گردید. صفاتی نظیر تعداد و عملکرد گل تر، طول و وزن کلاله، وزن بنه، تعداد بنه دختری و تعداد جوانه در بنه مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفتند. نتایج نشان داد که کمپوست زباله شهری بر وزن بنه همراه با فلس، تعداد بنه دختری و عملکرد گل تر و کلاله تأثیر معنی‌داری داشت، بطوریکه بالاترین وزن بنه همراه بافلس و تعداد بنه دختری (به ترتیب، 33/21 گرم در بنه و 11/2 عدد) از تیمار 10 تن در هکتار و پایین‌ترین آنها (47/16 گرم در بنه و 66/1 عدد) در شاهد به دست آمد. وزن بنه‌های مادری نیز، عملکرد گل وکلاله، وزن بنه و قطر بنه دختری را تحت تأثیر معنی دار خود قرار داد، بطوریکه بالاترین وزن تازه و خشک کلاله (به ترتیب، 31/0 و 11/0 گرم در متر مربع) از بنه‌های 12-1/8 گرم و کمترین آن‌ها (06/0 و 03/0 گرم در متر مربع) از بنه‌های 4-1/0 گرم بدست آمد. همچنین، اثر بر‌همکنش وزن بنه و کمپوست زباله شهری بر عملکرد گل و کلاله زعفران معنی‌دار گردید، بطوریکه بیش‌ترین عملکرد گل و کلاله تر (به ترتیب 36/9 و 41/0 گرم در متر مربع) از تیمار 10 تن در هکتار کمپوست و بنه‌های 12-1/8 گرم بدست آمد. بر اساس نتایج این تحقیق، استفاده از کمپوست زباله شهری (10 تن در هکتار) و بنه‌های مادری درشت (12-1/8 گرم) به عنوان مؤثرترین تیمارها در این آزمایش، می‏توانند نقش مؤثری در افزایش رشد بنه و عملکرد گل زعفران داشته باشند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In order to investigate the effects of different municipal waste compost levels of and maternal corm weights on yield and vegetative characteristics of saffron, an experiment was conducted with a factorial arrangement based on randomized complete block design with three replications at the Agricultural Research Station, University of Birjand during the growing season of 2014-2015. The treatments were four levels of municipal waste compost (0, 5, 10 and 20 t.ha-1) and three mother corm weights (0.1- 4, 4.1- 8 and 8.1- 12 g). The traits included the number of flower, fresh weight of flower, stigma and fresh weight of corm with scale, weight and diameter replacement and number of buds. The results showed that the effect of municipal waste compost was significant on total weight corm with scale, diameter of center corm and replacement corm, weight of fresh flower and stigma. The highest corm weight and number of replacement corms were obtained for treatment 10 t. ha-1 compost (21.33 g. plant -1 and 2.33 number, respectively), while the control had the lowest values (with 16.4 g. plant -1 and 1.66 number). The effect of mother corm weight was significant on the vegetative characteristics of saffron. The highest corm weight with scale, diameter of replacement, flower yield and fresh weight of flower and stigma were observed for 8.1-12 g. The most fresh  and dry weight of stigma (0.31 and 0.11 g. m -1, respectively) were observed from treatment  mother corm weight 8.1-12 g, while the lowest values (0.06 and 0.03 g. m -1) were 0.1- 4g.  Interaction between municipal waste compost and corm weight had a significant effect on the weight of fresh flower, sepal, stigma and the number of lateral buds and the highest fresh weight of flower (9.36 g. m-2) and stigma (0.41 g. m-2) were observed for treatment 10 t. ha-1 and 8.1-12g. Generally, the findings of the current study revealed that the use of municipal waste compost (10 t. ha-1) and large mother corms (8/1-12 g) had positive effects on corm growth and flower yield of saffron.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>169</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>184</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قلی زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Zohre</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gholizade</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، رشته علوم باغبانی، گرایش فیزیولوژی گیاهان دارویی، ادویه ای و عطری، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، رشته علوم باغبانی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zgholizade@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امینی فرد</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aminifard</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه علوم باغبانی و مرکز پژوهشی گیاهان ویژه منطقه دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه علوم باغبانی و مرکز پژوهشی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aminifard_mh55@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سیاری زهان</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hassan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sayyari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه علوم خاک و مرکز پژوهشی گیاهان ویژه منطقه دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه علوم خاک و مرکز پژوهشی گیاهان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>msayari@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بنه دختری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تغذیه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلاله تر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کود آلی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Alavi Shari, J., Mohajeri, H., and Falaki, M.A. 1994. Effect of plant density on saffron yield. In: Proceedings of the Second Conference of Saffron and Medicinal Plants Cultivation, Gonabad, Iran, 8-9 Nov 1994, 13-20. (In Persian).##Alipoor Miandehi, Z., Mahmodi, S., Behdani, M. A., and Sayyari, M.H. 2013. Effect of manure, bio-and chemical-fertilizers and corm size on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) yield and yield components. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (2): 73-84. (In Persian with English Summary).##Amiri, M.E. 2008. Impact of animal manures and chemical fertilizers on yield components of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). American-Eurasian Journal of Agriculture and Environmental Science 4: 274-279.##Amirshekari, H., Sorooshzadeh, A., Modaress Sanavy, A., and Jalali Javaran, M. 2007. Study of effects of root temperature, corm size, and gibberellin on underground organs of saffron (Crocus sativus L.).  Iranian Journal of Biology 19 (1): 5-18. (In Persian with English Summary).##Azizi-Zohan, A.A., Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A., and Sepaskhah, A.R. 2008. Crop and pan coefficients for saffron in a semi-arid region of Iran. Journal of Arid Environments 72: 270-278.##Bybourdi, A., and Malakouti, M.J. 2006. Investigation effect of source of different organic manure (manure, compost and vermicompost) on quantitative and qualitative ghermez azarshahr onion in tow condition banab and khosroshahr. 2006. Journal Soil and Water Science 21 (1): 41-51. (In Persian).##Barker, A.V., and Bryson, G.M. 2006. Comparisons of composts with low or high nutrient status for  growth of plants in containers. Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis 37: 1303-1319.##Behdani, M. 2005. Agroecological zoning and monitoring of saffron yield fluctuations of in Khorasan. PhD disseration, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran.  (In Persian with English Summary).##Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A.R., Nassiri, M., and Rezvani Moghadam, P. 2005. Evaluation of quantitative relationships between saffron yield and nutrition (on farm trial).  Iranian Journal of Field Crop Research 3:1-14. (In Persian with English Summary).##Chen, S., Zhang, X., Pei, D., and Sun, H. 2005. Effects of corn straw mulching on soil temperature and soil evaporation of winter wheat field. Transactions of the Chinese Society of Agricultural Engineering 21: 171-173.##De Juan, J., Moya, A., Lopez, S., Botella, O., Lopez, H., and Munoz, R. 2003. Influence of the corm size and the density of plantation in the yield and the quality of the production of corms of Crocus sativus L. ITEA. Producción Vegetal 99: 169–180.##De-maastro, G., and Ruta, C. 1993. Relation between corm size and saffron (Crocus sativus L.) flowering. Acta Horticulturae 344: 512-517.##Ghobadi, F., Ghorbani Javid, M., and Sorooshzadeh, A. 2015. Effect of planting date and corm size on flower yield and physiology traits of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) under varamin plain climatic conditions. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (4): 265-276. (In Persian with English Summary). ##Ghiamati, G., Astaraei, A., and  Zamani, G.2009. Effect of urban solid waste compost and sulfur on sugar beet yield and soil chemical of properties. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 7 (1): 153-162. (In Persian with English Summary).##Gresta, F., Lombardo, G.M., Siracusa, L., and Ruberto, G. 2008. Saffron, an alternative crop for sustainable agricultural systems. Agronomy for Sustainable Development 28: 95-112.##Hassanzade Aval, F., Rezvani moghaddam, P., Bannayan aval, M.,  and KHorasani, R.  2013. Effects of maternal corm weight and different levels of cow manure on corm and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.).Saffron Agronomy and Technology 1: 22-39. (In Persian with English Summary).##Hassanzade Aval, F., Rezvani moghaddam, P., Bannayan aval,  M., and KHorasani, R.  2014. Effects of maternal corm weight and foliar application on replacement corm characteristics and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in the first year. Journal of Saffron Research 2 (1): 73-84. (In Persian with English Summary).##Hayes, A., Mancino, C., and Pepper, I. 1990. Irrigation of turfgrass with secondary sewage effluent: I. Soil and leachate water quality. Agronomy Journal 82: 939-943.##Hemmati Kakhki, A. 2003. A review on 15 years saffron research. Khorasan research institute for food science and technology. Mashhad, Iran. p.125. (In Persian).##Jahan, M., and Jahani, M. 2007. The effects of chemical and organic fertilizers on saffron flowering. Acta Horticulturae 739: 81-86.##Jami-alahmadi, M., Behdani, M.A., and Akbarpour, A. 2009. Analysis of agronomic effective factors on yield of saffron agroecosystems in southern khorasan. 3nd International  Symposium on Saffron. Krokos, Kozani, Greece, 20-23 May, 2009, p.14.##Kafi, M., Rashed Mohassel, M.H., Koocheki, A., and Mollafilabi, A. 2002. Saffron: Production and Processing. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Publication, Iran.(In Persian).##Khoshgoftarmanesh, A., and Kalbasi, M. 2002. Effect of municipal waste leachate on soil properties and growth and yield of rice. Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis 33: 2011- 2020.##Koocheki, A. 2013. Research on production of Saffron in Iran: Past trend and future prospects.Saffron Agronomy and Technology 1 (1): 3-21. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Ganjeali, A., and Abbassi, F. 2007. The effect of duration and condition of incubation, weight of mother corms and photoperiod on corm and shoot characteristics of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 4: 315–331. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Jamshid Eyni, M., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2015. The effect of mother corm size and type of fertilizer on nitrogen use efficiency in saffron. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (4): 243-254. (In Persian with English Summary).##Kumar, R. 2009. Calibration and validation of regression model for non-destructive leaf area estimation of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Scientia Horticulturae 122: 142-145.##Kumar, R., Virendra, S., Kiran, D., Sharma, M., Singh, M.K., and Ahuja P.S. 2009. State of art of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) agronomy: A comprehensive review. Food Reviews International 25: 44–85.##Mashayekhi, K., and Latifi, N. 1995. Investigation of the effect of corms weights on saffrons flowering. Iranian Journal of Agricultural Sciences 28 (1): 97-105. (In Persian with English Summary).##Molina, R.V., Valero, M., and Navarro, Y. 2005. Temperature effects on flower formation in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Scientia Horticulturae 103: 361–379.##Mollafilabi, A. 2004. Experimental finding of production and echo physiological aspects of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Acta Horticulter 650: 195-200.##Mollafilabi, A., and Shoorideh, H. 2009. The new methods of saffron production. The 4th National Festival of Saffron, Khorasan- Razavi, Iran, 27-28 October 2009. (In Persian).##Mohammad-Abadi, A., Rezvani-Moghaddam, P., and Sabori, A. 2006. Effect of plant distance on flower yield and qualitative and quantitative characteristics of forage production of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Mashhad conditions. International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Technology739: 151-153.##Munshi, A. 1994. Effect of N and K on the ﬂoral yield and corm production in saffron under   rain-fed condition. Indian Arecant Spices 18: 24-44.##Naghavi Maremati, A., Bahmanyar, M., Pirdashti, A H., and Salak Gilani, S. 2007. Effect of different rate and type of organic and chemical fertilizers on yield and yield components of different rice cultivars. Proceeding of 10th Iranian Soil Science Congress, Tehran, Iran, 26-28 Aug 2007, p. 766-767. (In Persian).##Nassiri Mahallati, M., Koocheki, A., Boroumand Rezazadeh, Z., and Tabrizi, L. 2007. Effects of corm size and storage period on allocation of assimilates in different parts of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 5:155-166. (In Persian with English Summary).##Nehvi, F.A., Lone, A.A., Khan, M.A., and Maqhdoomi, M.I. 2009. Comparative study on effect of nutrient management on growth and yield of saffron under temperate conditions of Kashmir. 3th International Symposium on Saffron: Forthcoming Challenges in Cultivation, Research and Economics. Acta Horticulture 850: 165-170.##Omid Beigi, R. 2000. Production Method and Processing Medicinal Plants. volume 1. Fekre Rooz Publication. (In Persian).##Pandy, D., and Srivastava, R.P.  1979. A note on the effect of size of corms on the sprouting and flowering of saffron. Progressive Horticulture 6: 89-92.##Patra, D., Anwar, M., and Chand, S. 2000. Integrated nutrient management and waste recycling for restoring soil fertility and productivity in Japanese mint and mustard sequence in Uttar Pradesh, India. Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment 80: 267-275.##Pedra, F., Polo, A., Ribero, A., and Domingues, H. 2006. Effect of municipal solid waste compost and sewage sludge on mineralization of soil organic matter. Soil Biology and Biochemistry 29: 1375-1382.##Rangahau, M.K. 2003. Growing saffron - The world’s most expensive spice. Crop and Food Research 20: 42-49.##Renau-Morata, B., Nebauer, S.G., Sanchez, M., and Molina, R.V. 2012. Effect of corm size, water stress and cultivation conditions on photosynthesis and biomass partitioning during the vegetative growth of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Industrial Crops and Products 39: 40-46.##Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Khorramdel, S., Amin Ghafori, A., and Shabahang, J. 2013. Evaluation of growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) affected by spent mushroom compost and corm density. Journal of Saffron Research 1: 13–26. (In Persian with English Summary).##Rezvani-Moghaddam, P., Huda, A.K.S., Parvez, Q., and Koocheki, A. 2007. Indigenous knowledge in agriculture with particular reference to medicinal crop production in Khorasan, Iran. World Association for Sustainable Development Conference Proceedings, Brisbane, Australia, 2007, p. 105-115.##Rezaian, S., and Paseban, M. 2007. The effect of micronutrients and manure fertilizers on the quantity and quality of Khorasan saffron. Second International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Technology. Available at Web site http://www.civilica.com/Paper-Saffron02-Saffron02-020.html.##Sadeghi, B. 1995. Effect of corm weight on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) flowering. Iranian Research Organization for Science and Technology-Khorasan, Mashhad Center, Iran. p.28. (In Persian).##Seyyedi, M., and Rezvani Moghaddam, P. 2011. Investigation yield and component yield and nitrogen use efficiency in use of spent mushroom compost, biologic fertilizer and our in Triticum aestivum L. Journal of Agroecology 3: 309-319. (In Persian with English Summary).##Sharifi Ashour Abadi,  A. 1998. Evaluation of soil fertility in agroecosystems. PhD disseration, Islamic Azad Univesity of Oloum Tahghighat, Iran. (In Persian with English Summary).##Singh, A., Bisen, S., Singh, R., and Biswas, S. 1998. Effectiveness of compost towards increasing productivity of some medicinal plants in skeletal soil. Advances in Forestry Research in India 18: 64-83.##Teimori, S., Behdani, M.A., Ghaderi, M.G., and Sadeghi, B. 2013. Investigation on the effect of organic and chemical fertilizers on morphological and agronomic of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm criteria. Journal of Saffron Research 1: 36–47. (In Persian with English Summary).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مطالعه تنوع ژنتیکی و برخی از صفات زراعی و کیفی در زعفران (.Crocus sativus L)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Study of genetic diversity and some of quality and agronomic traits in saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>به‌منظور مطالعه تنوع ژنتیکی و زراعی زعفران، شش اکوتیپ از نقاط مختلف استان خراسان (مشهد، تربت‌جام، گناباد، تربت‌حیدریه، قاین و بیرجند) جمع‌آوری و در طی دو سال زراعی 93-1391 در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه ارومیه مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفتند. نتایج مزرعه‌ای نشان داد که اختلاف معنی‌داری بین اکوتیپ‌ها از لحاظ اکثر صفات زراعی و کیفی مورد مطالعه وجود دارد. به‌طوری‌که تجزیه خوشه‏ای، اکوتیپ‏های تربت‌حیدریه، مشهد و تربت‌جام را در یک خوشه‏ و اکوتیپ‏های بیرجند، قاین و گناباد را در خوشه‏ دیگر گروه‌بندی نمود. همچنین نتایج حاصل از مقایسه میانگین نشان داد که اکوتیپ‏های تربت‌حیدریه و مشهد به ترتیب به‏‌عنوان بهترین‏ اکوتیپ‏های زعفران در ارومیه شناخته شدند. از طرفی نتایج ژنتیکی نشان داد که از بین 30 جفت آغازگر SSR مورد استفاده، 22 جفت آغازگر (73%)، در مجموع 44 آلل چندشکلی را شناسایی نمودند (میانگین 2 عدد). میانگین شاخص شانون (I)، تنوع ژنتیکی (h) و محتوی اطلاعات چندشکلی (PIC) به ترتیب 688/0، 424/0 و 402/0 تخمین زده شد که این نتایج از وجود تنوع ژنتیکی در بین اکوتیپ‌های زعفران خبر می‌دهد و این تنوع توسط تجزیه‌های دیگری از جمله تجزیه واریانس مولکولی مورد تأیید قرار گرفت. از طرفی نتایج حاصل از تجزیه خوشه‏ای داروین، هر کدام از اکوتیپ‏های بیرجند، مشهد و گناباد را در یک خوشه‏ و سه اکوتیپ تربت‌حیدریه، قاین و تربت‌جام را به‌دلیل شباهت بالا همگی را در یک خوشه‏ قرار داد و این گروه‌بندی توسط تجزیه به مؤلفه‏های اصلی مورد تأیید قرار گرفت. قابل ذکر است شباهت ژنتیکی بالایی بین اکوتیپ‏های زعفران (90-65 درصد) تخمین زده شد. در مجموع نتایج حاصل از این تحقیق ضمن بیان این موضوع که نشانگرهای ریزماهواره ابزار مفیدی برای ارزیابی تنوع ژنتیکی و گروه‏بندی اکوتیپ‌های زعفران هستند. این موضوع را نیز تأیید نمود که زعفران گیاهی منومورف نبوده و می‌توان تنوع مفیدی را جهت استفاده در برنامه‌های اصلاحی شناسایی کرد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In order to study genetic diversity and some of the quality and agronomic traits in saffron, six cultivated ecotypes were collected from different regions of the Khorasan province (Mashhad, Torbat-Jam, Gonabad, Torbat-Heydarieh, Qaen and Birjand) and they were evaluated during two cropping seasons in 2011-13 in the research farm of the agricultural faculty, Urmia University, Urmia-Iran. The farming results showed that there were significant differences between the ecotypes in the studied agronomic and qualitative traits. Thus,, the cluster analysis grouped ecotypes Torbat-Heydarieh, Mashhad and Torbat-Jam in a cluster and ecotypes Birjand, Qaen and Gonabad in the other cluster. The results of mean comparison also showed that ecotypes Torbat-Heydarieh and Mashhad were the best saffron ecotypes in the Urmia condition. On the other hand, the genetic results showed that 22 of 30 SSR primers (73%) detected a total of 44 polymorphic alleles (average 2). The average of Shannon index (I), genetic diversity (h) and polymorphic information content (PIC) were estimated to be 0.688, 0.424 and 0.402, respectively. These results not only clarified the existence of genetic diversities among saffron ecotypes, but also, the genetic diversities were proven with other analyses such as analysis of molecular variance. The results of cluster analysis of Darwin grouped each ecotype of Birjand, Mashhad and Gonabad in a cluster and three ecotypes. Torbat-Heydarieh, Qaen and Torbat-Jam were placed in the same cluster because of their high genetic similarity. This grouping was confirmed by principal coordinate analysis. It was notable that high genetic similarities were estimated between saffron ecotypes (65-90%). Overall, the results of this research not only introduced microsatellite molecular markers as useful tools for evaluating genetic diversity and grouping of saffron ecotypes, but also confirmed that saffron is not a monomorphic plant and we can identify useful genetic diversities for breeding programs.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>185</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>200</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بیات</Family>
						<NameE>mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>bayat</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش آموخته دکتری زراعت، اکولوژی گیاهان زراعی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه ارومیه.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش آموخته دکتری زراعت، اکولوژی گیاهان زراعی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mahdibayat971@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امیرنیا</Family>
						<NameE>reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>amirnia</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه ارومیه.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ramirnia@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تاجبخش</Family>
						<NameE>mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>tajbakhsh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه ارومیه.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mahditajbakhsh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهاتین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تانیولاچ</Family>
						<NameE>bahattin</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>tanyolac</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، دانشکده بیومهندسی، دانشگاه اگه، ازمیر، ترکیه.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، دانشکده بیومهندسی، دانشگاه اگه، ازمیر،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ترکیه</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>bahattin.tanyolac@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پارامترهای ژنتیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خوشه‏بندی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شباهت ژنتیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نشانگرهای ریزماهواره (SSR)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Agayev, Y.M.O., Fernandez, J.A., and Zarifi, E. 2009. Clonal selection of saffron (Crocus sativus L.): the first optimistic experimental results. Euphytica 169: 81–99.##Aghhavani Shajari, M., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Koocheki, A., Fallahi, H.R., Taherpour Kalantari, R. 2015. Evaluation of the effects of soil texture on yield and growth of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Saffron Agronomy &amp; Technology 2 (4): 311-322.(In Persian)##Alavi-Kia, S.S., Mohammadi, S.A., Aharizad, S., and Moghaddam, M. 2008. Analysis of genetic diversity and phylogenetic relationships in Crocus genus of Iran using inter-retrotransposon amplified polymorphism. Biotechnology &amp; Biotechnological Equipment 22: 795-800.##Anastasaki, E., Kanakis, C., Pappas, C., Maggi, L., del Campo, C.P., Carmona, M., Alonso, G.L., and Polissiou, M.G. 2010. Differentiation of saffron from four countries by mid-infrared spectroscopy and multivariate analysis. European Food Research and Technology 230: 571–577.##Babaei S., Talebi, M., Bahar M., and Zeinali, H. 2014. Analysis of genetic diversity among saffron (Crocus sativus L.) accessionsfrom different regions of Iran as revealed by SRAP markers. Scientia Horticulturae 171: 27–31.##Beiki, A.H., Keifi, F., and Mozafari, J. 2010. Genetic differentiation of Crocus species by random amplified polymorphic DNA. Journal of genetic engineering and biotechnology 18: 1- 10.##Beiki, A.H., Keify, F., and Mozafari, J. 2011. Rapid genomic DNA isolation from corm of Crocus species for genetic diversity analysis. Journal of Medicinal Plants Research 5 (18): 4596-4600.##Budak, H., Shearman, R.C., Parmaksiz, I., Gaussoin, R.E., Riordan, T.P., and Dweikat, I. 2004. Molecular characterization of Buffalograss germplasm using sequence-related amplified polymorphism markers. Theoretical &amp; Applied Genetics108: 328–334.##Caiola, M.G., and Zaier, R. 2004. RAPD analysis in Crocus sativus L. accessions and related Crocus species. Biologia Plantarum 48: 375-380.##Castillo, R., Fernandez, J.A., and Gomez-Gomez, L. 2005. Implications of carotenoid biosynthetic genes in apocarotenoid formation during the stigma development of Crocus sativus and its closer relatives. Plant Physiology 139: 674-689.##Cuc, L.M., Mace, E.S., Crouch, J.H., Quang, V.D., Long, T.D., and Varshney, R.K. 2008. Isolation and characterization of novel microsatellite markers and their application for diversity assessment in cultivated groundnut (Arachis hypogaea). BMC Plant Biology 10: 1186-1193.##Erol, O., Kaya, H. B., Şik, L., Tuna, M., Can, L., and Tanyolaç, M.B.  2014. The genus Crocus, series Crocus (Iridaceae) in Turkey and 2 East Aegean islands: a genetic approach. Turkish Journal of Biology 38: 48-62.##Fernandez, J. A. 2004. Biology, biotechnology and biomedicine of saffron. Recent Research Developments in Plant Science 2:127-159.##Indriyani, S., Arisoesilaningsih, E., Wardiyati, T., and Purnobasuki, H. 2011. A model of relationship between climate and soil factors related to oxalate content in porang (Amorphophallus muelleri Blume) corm. Biodiversitas 12 (1): 45-51.##Keify, F., and Beiki, A.H. 2012. Exploitation of random amplified polymorphic DNA (RAPD) and sequence-related amplified polymorphism (SRAP) markers for genetic diversity of saffron collection. Journal of Medicinal Plants Research 6 (14): 2761-2768.##Lage, M., and Cantrell, C.L. 2009. Quantification of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) metabolites crocins, picrocrocin and safranal for quality determination of the spice grown under different environmental Moroccan conditions. Scientia Horticulturae 121: 366–373.##Liu, K., and Muse, S.V. 2005. Power Marker: An integrated analysis environment for genetic marker analysis. Bioinformatics 21: 2128-2129.##Messmer, M.M., Melchinger, A.A., Boppenmair, J., Brunklaus-Jung E., and Hermann, R.G. 1992. Relationship among early European maize inbreds. I. Genetic diversity among flint and dent lines as revealed by RFLP. Crop Science 32: 1301- 1309.##Mohammadi, H., Ranjbar, F., and Soltani, M. 2011. Climatic potentials assessment for saffron cultivation in Marvdasht. Geography and Environmental Planning (University of Isfahan) 22 (3): 143-154. (In Persian).##Mollafilabi, A. 2004. Experimental finding of production and echo physiological aspects of saffron (crocus Sativus L.). International symposium on saffron biology and biotechnology. Albacete, Spain.##Moraga, A.R., Trapero-Mozos, A., Gomez-Gomez, L., and Ahrazem, O. 2010. Intersimplesequence repeat markers for molecular characterization of Crocus cartwright-ianus cv. albus. Industrial Crops and Products 32: 147–151.##Mueller, U.G., and Wolfenbarger, L. 1999. AFLP genotyping and fingerprinting. Tree 14: 389-394.##Namayandeh, A., Nemati, Z., Kamelmanesh, M.M., Mokhtari, M., and Mardi, M. 2013. Genetic relationships among species of Iranian crocus (Crocus spp.). Crop Breeding Journal 3 (1): 61-67.##Nehvi, F., Qadri, A., Henna, S., and Singh, P. 2008. Saffron in India and Iran: A Review of Production, Processing and Marketing. Indian Journal of Crop Science 3 (1): 156-162.##Nemati, Z., Zeinalabedini, M., Mardi, M., Pirseyediand, S.M., Marashi, S.H., and Khayam Nekoui, S.M. 2012. Isolation and characterization of a first set of polymorphic microsatellite markers in Saffron, Crocus Sativus (Iridaceae). American Journal of Botany 27: 340-343.##Omid Beygi, R., Sadeghi, B., and Ramezani, A.A. 2000. Effects of cultivation site on quality of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Horticultural Science and Technology 1 (3-4): 167-178. (In Persian).##Rubio-Moraga, A., Castillo-López, R., Gómez-Gómez, L., and Ahrazem, O. 2009. Saffron is a monomorphic species as revealed by RAPD, ISSR and microsatellite analyses. BMC Research Notes 2: 1-5.##Shokohian, A.A., and Asghari, A. 2008. Evaluation of saffron ecotypes adaptation to Ardabil weather condition. Iranian Journal of Field Crop Science (Iranian Journal of Agricultural Sciences) 38 (4): 563-570. (In Persian).##Yazdi Samadi, B., Rezaei, A.M., and Valyzadeh, M. 2001. Statistical designs in agricultural research. Tehran university publications. Second edition. 1-762. (In Persian).##Yeh, F.C., and Yang, R.C. 1999. POPGENE Version 1.31. University of Albert and Tim Boyle, Center for International Research.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اثر مقدار زئولیت و مدیریت آبیاری بر برخی خصوصیات بنه زعفران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Effect of Zeolite Rates and Irrigation Management on Some Properties of Saffron Corms</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران (Crocus sativus L.) گیاهی نیمه گرمسیری و گران‌بها است که توسط بنه تکثیر می‌شود. با توجه به اهمیت وزن بنه در عملکرد زعفران، بررسی اثر عوامل مختلف ازجمله تنش آبی بربنه اهمیت می‌یابد. بدین منظور تحقیقی به‌صورت فاکتوریل و در قالب طرح کاملاً تصادفی طی سال‌های‌ 1394-1392 در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند انجام شد. تیمار زئولیت در چهار سطح (Z0: صفر، Z1: 5/0، Z2: 1 و Z3: 2 درصد وزنی) و تیمار آبیاری در سه سطح (I1: آبیاری سنتی، I2: آبیاری با تخلیه 70 درصد رطوبتی و I3: آبیاری کامل) در سه تکرار در نظر گرفته‌شدند. نتایج نشان‌داد که سطح مصرف زئولیت اثر معنی‌داری بر متوسط وزن بنه، تعداد بنه با وزن کمتر از 2 گرم، تعداد بنه با وزن بین 6 تا 8 گرم و تعداد بنه خواهری داشت (P≤0.01). مدیریت آبیاری نیز اثر معنی‌داری بر متوسط وزن بنه (P≤0.01)، تعداد بنه با وزن بین 6 تا 8 گرم و تعداد بنه خواهری داشت (P≤0.05). وزن بنه در تیمارهای بدون کاربرد زئولیت (Z0I1، Z0I2 و Z0I3) نسبت به Z3I3 کاهش معنی‌داری داشتند (P≤0.05). همچنین تیمارهای Z3I3، Z3I2 و Z1I3 بیشترین و تیمارهای Z0I1 و Z0I2 کمترین تعداد بنه‌های خواهری را داشتند. با در نظر گرفتن کاهش مصرف زئولیت و آب آبیاری، تیمار Z2I1 را می‌توان به‌عنوان مناسب‌ترین تیمار پیشنهاد کرد به‌طوری‌که وزن بنه را نسبت به تیمارهای Z0I1، Z0I2 و Z0I3 به ترتیب 64/26، 88/23 و 81/17 درصد افزایش داد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) is a subtropical and valuable crop which is reproduced by corms. Due to the importance of corm weight in saffron yield, it is important to study the different factors that affect yield such as drought stress. For this purpose, this research was conducted as a factorial design based on completely randomized design (CRD) in the Agricultural Research Station of the University of Birjand during the period 2013-2015. The treatments consisted of Zeolite at four rates (0: Z0, 0.5: Z1, 1: Z2 and 2: Z3 as weight percentage) and irrigation management at three levels (traditional: I1, deficit irrigation as 70% moisture depletion: I2 and full irrigation: I3) with three replications. The results showed that zeolite rates has a significant effect on corm weight, number of corms less than 2gr, number of 6-8gr corms and number of replacement corms (P≤0.01). Irrigation management also has a significant effect on corm weight (P≤0.01), number of corms 6-8gr and number of replacement corms (P≤0.05). The treatments with no zeolite amended (Z0I1, Z0I2 and Z0I3) showed a reduction in corm weight compared to Z3I3 (P≤0.05). Z3I3, Z3I2 and Z3I3 showed an increase in the number of replacement corms while Z0I1 and Z0I2 had the least number of replacement corms. In conclusion, Z2I1 is recommended as the best treatment by considering the reduction in zeolite and water used, which increased corm weight by 26.64%, 23.88% and 17.81% compared to Z0I1, Z0I2 and Z0I3, respectively.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>201</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>213</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عباس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خاشعی سیوکی</Family>
						<NameE>Abbas</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khashei Siuki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مهندسی آب، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مهندسی آب، دانشگاه بیرجند</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abbaskhashei@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>احمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ahmadee</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری آبیاری و زهکشی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری آبیاری و زهکشی دانشگاه شهید</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.ahmadee@ymail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سیدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>هاشمی</Family>
						<NameE>Sayyed Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hashemi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری آبیاری و زهکشی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری آبیاری و زهکشی دانشگاه شهید</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>srezahashemi@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>چالاک</Family>
						<NameE>Amin</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Chaalaak</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی مهندسی آب، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی مهندسی آب، دانشگاه بیرجند</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aminchaalaak@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>برنامه‌ریزی آبیاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تنش آبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>وزن بنه و تغذیه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abdullaaev, F. 2006. Biological properties and medicinal use of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Proceedings of 2nd International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Technology. Mashhad, Iran, 28-30 October 2006. p. 339-345.##Agriculture Research, Education and Extentional Organization (AREEO). 1996. Technical Economic Evaluation of saffron production.##Ahmadee, M. 2014. Effect of zeolite on fertility and reducing nitrate leaching from saline soil under saffron cultivation. MSc Thesis, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Birjand, Iran. [In Persian with English Summary].##Ahmadee, M., Khashei Suiki, A., and Hashemi, S. R. 2014a. The effect of magnetic water and calcic and potasic zeolite on the yield of Lepiduim sativum L. IJABBR 2(6): 2051-2060.##Ahmadee, M., Khashei Suiki, A., and Sayyari, M. H. 2014b. Type and amount of evaluation of natural clinoptilolite zeolite impacts on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) emergence. Journal of Saffron Research 1(2): 97-109. [In Persian with English Summary].##Ahmadee, M., Khashei Suiki, A., and Shahidi, A. 2014c. Effect of magnetic water and natural clinoptilolite zeolite on growth of green been (Phaseolus vulgaris L.). Iranian Journal of Irrigation and Drainage 2(8): 393-401. [In Persian with English Summary].##Aitoubahou, A., and El-Otmani, M. 1999. Saffron cultivation in Morocco. PP. 87-94. In: M. Neghbi (Ed.), Saffron. Harwood Academic Pub. the Netherland.##Alipoor Miandehi, Z., Mahmodi, S., Behdani, M. A., and Sayyari, M. H. 2014. Effect of manure, bio-and chemicalfertilizers and corm size on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) yield and yield components. Journal of Saffron Research 1(2): 73-84. [In Persian with English Summary].##Amirshekari, H., Sorooshzadeh, A., Modaress Sanavy, A., and Jalali Javaran, M. 2006. Study of effects of root temperature, corm size, and gibberellin on underground organs of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Biology 19(1): 5-18. [In Persian with English Summary].##Azizi Zohan, A. A., Kamgar-Haghighi, A. A., and Sepaskhah, A. R. 2006. Effect of irrigation method and frequency on corm and saffron production (Crocus sativus L.). JWSS-Isfahan University of Technology. 10(1): 45-54. [In Persian with English Summary].##Bari Abarghoei, H., Ghalavand, A., Mazaheri, D., Noor Mohammadi, Gh., and Sanei, M. 2000. Pajouhesh Va Sazandgi 4: 65-69. [In Persian with English Summary].##Behnia, M. R. 1989. Saffron: botany. cultivation and production. Tehran University Publications, Tehran. 260 p. [In Persian].##Benschop, M. 1993. Crocus. In: A. de Hertogh, M. Le Nard (ed.), The Physiology of Flower Bulbs. 257-272. Elsevier, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.##Cavusoglu, A., and Erkel, E. I. 2009. Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) growing without removing of mother corms under greenhouse condition. Turkish Journal of Field Crops 1(2): 170-180.##Cavusoglu, A., Erkel, E.I., and Sulusoglu, M. 2009. Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) Studies with two mother corm dimensions on yield and harvest period under greenhouse condition. American-Eurasian Journal of Sustainable Agriculture 3(2): 126-129.##Ekaterina, G. F., and Christos. 2002. Influence of clinptilolite and compost on soil properties. Taylor and Francis Publishing 33(3): 595-607.##Gholizadeh, A., Amin, M. S. M., Anuar, A. R, Esfahani, M., and Saberioon, M. M. 2010. The study on the effect of different Levels of zeolit and water stress on growth, development and essential oil content of moldavian balm (Dracocephalum moldavica L.). American Journal of Applied Science 7: 33-37.##Goliaris, A. H. 1999. Saffron Cultivation in Greece. PP. 73-83. In: M. Neghbi (Ed.), Saffron. Harwood Academic. Pub., the Netherland.##Hassan, B., and Shah, M. H. 2002. Increased sustainability and yield of saffron in Kashmir. In: Proceeding of Seminar-cum-Workshop on Saffron (Crocus sativus). SKUAST-K. India. Pp 115.##Hassanzadeh Aval, F., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Bannayan Aval, M., and Khorasani, R. 2014. Effects of maternal corm weight and foliar application on replacement corm characteristics and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in the first year. Journal of Saffron Research 2(1): 73-84. [In Persian with English Summary].##Jazaeri Nushabadi, M. R., and Rezaei, A. M. 2007. Evaluation of relations between parameters in oat cultivars in water stress and non- stress conditions. Journal of Science and Technology of Agriculture and Natural Resources, Water and soil Science 11 (1): 265-279. [In Persian with English Summary].##Juana, J. A. D., Córcolesb, H. L., Muñozb, R. M., and Picornella, M. R. 2009. Yield and yield components of saffron under different cropping systems. Industrial Crop Production 30(2): 212-219.##Kafi, M. R., Rashed Mohasel, M. H., Koocheki, A., and Molafilabi, A. 2002. Saffron production and processing. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Publications, Mashhad. 279 p. [In Persian].##Kafi, M., and Showket, T. 2006. A Comparative Study of Saffron Agronomy and Production Systems of Khorasan (Iran) and Kashmir (India). Proceeding of 2nd international symposium on Saffron Biology and Technology. Mashhad, Iran, 28-30 October. Pp.123-132.##Karimi, S., Nasri, M., Ghooshchi, F., and Khalatbari, M. 2012. Effect of zeolite application on yield and yield component of sunflower under drought stress. 12th Iraninan Crop Sciences Congress, Islamic Azad University, Karaj. [In Persian].##Kaushal, S. K., and Upadhyay, R. G. 2002. Studies on variation in corm size and its effect on cormel production and flowering in Crocus sativus L. under midd hill conditions of H. P. Research on Crops 3(1): 126-128.##Kazemian, H. 2004. Introduction to zeolites, minerals Magic, Behesht Publication, Tehran. 126p. [In Persian].##Khashei Siuki, A., Hashemi, S. R., and Ahmadee, M. 2015. The effect of potasic zeolite and irrigation scheduling on saffron yield. Research project. University of Birjand, Iran. 67 pp. [In Persian with English Summary].##Khashei Siuki, A., Kochekzadeh, M., and Shahabifar, M. 2008. Effect of natural zeolite clinoptilolite and soil moisture on corn yield. Journal of Research of Soil Science (Soil and Water) 22(2): 235-241. [In Persian with English Summary].##Khashei Suiki, A., and Ahmadee, M. 2015. Zeolites: Introduction, properties and its application. In press. 139 pp. [In Persian].##Khorramdel, S., Gheshm, R., Amin Ghafori, A., and Esmaielpour, B. 2014. Evaluation of soil texture and superabsorbent polymer impacts on agronomical characteristics and yield of saffron. Journal of Saffron Research 1(2): 120-135. [In Persian with English Summary].##Koocheki, A. R., Fallahi, J., Amiri, M. B., and Ehyaei, H. R. 2012. Effect of humic acid application and mother corm weight on some quantitative characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) with emphasized on ecological operations. Proceedings of the 12th Iranian Crop Sciences Congress. Islamic Azad University, Karaj. Iran. [In Persian with English Summary].##Mohammad Abadi, A. A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Fallahi, J. 2011. Effects of planting pattern and the first irrigation date on growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Agroecology 3(1): 84-93. [In Persian with English Summary].##Molina, R. V., Valero, M., Navarro, Y., Guardiola, J. L., and Garcia-Luis, A. 2005. Temperature effects on flower formation in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Scientia Horticulturae 103: 361-379.##Mollafilabi, A. 2004. Experimental Findings of Production and Echophysiological Aspects of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Acta Horticulturae (ISHS) 650: 195-200.##Munshi, A. M., Wani, S. A., and Tak, G. M. 2002. Improved cultivation practices for saffron. In: Proceeding of Seminar-cum-Workshop on Saffron (Crocus sativus), SKUAST-K. India. Pp 83-88.##Nassiri Mahallati, M., Koocheki, A., Boroomand Rezazadeh, Z., and Tabrizi, L. 2008. Effects of corm size and storage period on allocation of assimilates in different parts of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crop Research 5(1): 155-166. [In Persian with English Summary].##Omidbaigi, R. 2005. Effects of corm weight on quality of Saffron (Crocus sativus Linn.). Natural Product Radinace 4: 193-194.##Polite, E., Karuca, M., Demire, H., and Naci Onus, A. 2004. Use of natural zeolite (clinoptilolite) in agriculture. Journal of Fruit and Ornamental Plant Research 12: 183-189.##Ranjbar, M., Esfahany, M., Kavousi, M., and Yazdani, M. R. 2004. Effect of irrigation and natural zeolite application on yield and quality of Tobacco (Nicotiana tabaccum var. Coker 347). Journal of Agricultural Science 1(2): 63-75. [In Persian with English Summary].##Rashed, M. H., Kafi, M., Koochaki, A., and Nassiri, M. 2006. Saffron (Crocus sativus) Production and Processing. Science Publications 87-96.##Rees, A. R. 1992. Ornamental Bulbs, Corms and Tubers, C.A.B. International, Wallingford, UK.##Sadeghi, B. 1993. Effect of Corm Weight on Saffron Flowering. Press of Iranian Research Organization for Science and Technology Center of Khorasan. pp. 52-53. [In Persian].##Teimori, S., Behdani, M. A., Ghaderi, M. G., and Sadeghi, B. 2013. Investigation on the effect of organic and chemical fertilizers on morphological and agronomic of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm criteria. Journal of Saffron Research 1: 36-47. [In Persian with English Summary].##Vurdu, H. 2004. Agronomical and biotechnological approaches for saffron improvement. Acta Horticulturae (ISHS) 650: 285-290.##Vurdu, H., Altu, Z., and Ayan, S. 2002. Crocus sativus L. (Safran)’un yetistirme teknigi. Gazi Uni. Orman Fak. Derg 2: 175-187.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مقایسه ترکیبات موثره و میزان فعالیت آنتی اکسیدانی زعفران تولید شده در شهرستان‌های کاشمر و مرند</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Comparison between metabolites ant antioxidant activity of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)  from Kashmar and Marand regions</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران (Crocus sativus L.) محصولی ارزشمند و نیمه مقاوم به خشکی است که می‌تواند در شرایط بسیار متفاوت آب و هوایی مورد کشت و کار قرار گیرد. مهم‌ترین ترکیب‌هاى شیمیایى زعفران ‌را کروسین و مشتق‌هاى کروستین تشکیل می‌دهند. زعفران موارد استفاده مختلفی دارد، از جمله در صنایع غذایی به عنوان عامل عطر و طعم و همچنین در صنایع دارویی به عنوان  ضد اسپاسم، ضد نفخ،‌ آرامبخش، ضد افسردگی و بیماریهای قلبی. در این پژوهش، نمونه‌های زعفران از شهرستان مرند با ارتفاع 1360 متر و کاشمر با ارتفاع 1000 متر از سطح دریا جمع‌آوری شدند و در شرایط مناسب و یکسان خشک گردیدند. همچنین نمونه تجاری از شرکت معروف بسته‌بندی زعفران در بازار نیز تهیه گردید. میزان ترکیبات مؤثره نمونه‌های زعفران شامل؛ کروسین، پیکروکروسین و سافرانال مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفت. بر اساس نتایج به دست آمده، در نمونه‌های جمع‌آوری شده از مرند، بیشترین میزان ترکیبات کروسین و پیکروکروسین مشاهده گردید (میزان جذب به ترتیب 306 و 118). همچنین  فعالیت آنتی‌اکسیدانی نمونه‌های زعفران نیز  به روش احیای رادیکال آزاد DPPH اندازه‌گیری شد. نتایج به‌دست آمده نشان داد که زعفران اکوتیپ مرند میزان ترکیبات مؤثره و فعالیت آنتی‌اکسیدانی بیشتری نسبت به اکوتیپ کاشمر دارد. بطور کلی با توجه به خشکی روزافزون و مسئله کم آبی در منطقه آذربایجان و کیفیت بالای زعفران برداشت شده از زعفران‌زارهای شهرستان مرند، زعفران می‌تواند به عنوان محصولی جهت کشت و کار وسیع در این منطقه قابل توصیه باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) is a valuable product that is moderately resistant to drought and is cultivated in environments with very different climatic conditions. The most important chemical compositions of saffron include crocin and crocetin derivatives. Saffron is used as a food colouring and flavouring agent in the food industry. Moreover, it is utilized in folk medicine as antispasmodic, carminative, sedative, anti-depression and for heart disease. In this study, saffron samples from different altitudes, i.e. Marand with altitude of 1360m and Kashmar with altitude of 1000m above sea level were collected and dried in the same conditions and compared with commercial samples. Three major metabolites (crocin, picrocrocin and safranal) were quantified in both altitudes by Spectrophotometry. The results obtained showed that saffron samples from Marand had the most amounts of crocin and picrocrocin (absorbance: 306 and 118). Also, after extraction, antioxidant activity was quantified by the DPPH free radical scavenging method. The results indicated that saffron samples from Marand had higher concentration of these constituents and antioxidant activity in comparison to that of samples from Kashmar. However, due to reduction of rain and increasing drought in the Azerbaijan region, cultivation of saffron in Marand is recommended on the basis of the results of this research and high yield and quality of saffron.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>215</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>224</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>معصومه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>وکیلی قرطاول</Family>
						<NameE>Masoumeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Vakili-ghartavol</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناسی ارشد علوم باغبانی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه تبریز.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناسی ارشد علوم باغبانی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>masume.vakili@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعیده</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>علیزاده سالطه</Family>
						<NameE>Saeedeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Alizadeh Salteh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه علوم باغبانی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه تبریز.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه علوم باغبانی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>s.alizadeh@tabrizu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کروسین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پیکروکروسین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سافرانال</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خاصیت آنتی اکسیدانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>استخراج وتعیین کروسین در نمونه های زعفران بااستفاده ازمیکرواستخراج مایع-مایع پخشی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Extraction and Determination of Crocin in Saffron Samples by Dispersive Liquid-Liquid Microextraction</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>اصلی‌ترین عامل ایجاد قدرت رنگی در زعفران ترکیبی به نام کروسین به فرمول شیمیایی C44H64O24 است. کروسین یکی از چند کاروتنویید محدود موجود در طبیعت است که به‌آسانی در آب حل می‌شود. این حلالیت یکی از دلایل کاربرد وسیع آن به‌عنوان رنگ دهنده در مواد غذایی و دارویی نسبت به سایر کاروتنوییدها می‌باشد. قدرت رنگی زعفران یکی از پارامترهای عمده تعیین کننده کیفیت زعفران می‌باشد که با اندازه‌گیری میزان کروسین موجود در آن مورد ارزیابی قرار می‌گیرد. روش میکرو استخراج مورد استفاده در این تحقیق از جدیدترین و ساده‌ترین روش‌های میکرو استخراج است که می‌تواند با موفقیت برای پیش تغلیظ و جداسازی کروسین در نمونه زعفران بکار رود. سرعت، ارزانی و آنالیز آسان در طیف سنجی UV-Vis مورد استفاده در اندازه‌گیری کروسین نسبت به سایر روش‌های اندازه‌گیری، از مزایای این روش است. بررسی‌ها نشان‌داد که نوع و حجم حلال پخشی و حلال استخراج در بازده استخراج تأثیر بسزایی دارد. در این پژوهش از استون به عنوان حلال پخشی و دی‌کلرو‌متان به عنوان حلال استخراج استفاده شد. تحت شرایط بهینه، منحنی کالیبراسیون در دامنه 00001/0-15/0 میکروگرم بر میلی‌لیتر خطی بوده و حد تشخیص روش 000008/0 میکروگرم بر میلی‌لیتر است. روش پیشنهادی تحت شرایط بهینه برای اندازه‌گیری کروسین نمونه‌های زعفران مناطق مختلف مورد استفاده قرار گرفته است و درصد بازیابی بسیار خوبی با خطای کم محاسبه شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The main component responsible for color in saffron is crocin with the chemical formula of C44H64O24. Crocin is one of several carotenoids in nature that is soluble in water. This solubility is one of the reasons for its widespread usage as a colorant in food and medicine compared to other carotenoids. The coloring strength of saffron is one of the major factors that determine the quality of the saffron stigma. It will be evaluated with measuring of crocin. Microextraction is the newest and easiest method that can be successfully applied for the preconcentration and separation of crocin in saffron samples. The advantages of this method are faster, cheaper and easier analysis by UV-Vis spectrophotometry in measurement of crocin compared to the chromatographic analysis methods. The studies showed that the type and volume of disperser and extractant solvent have a significant effect on the efficiency of crocin extraction. In this work, acetone as the disperser solvent and dichlorometane as the extractant solvent were found to be suitable combinations. Under the optimal conditions, the calibration curve was linear in the range of 0.15-0.00001 μg mL-1 and the limit of detection (LOD) was calculated based on 3 Sb/m (where, Sb and m are the standard deviation of the blank and slop ratio of the calibration curve respectively) was 0.000008 μg mL-1. The procedure was applied to saffron samples and the good recovery percent for the saffron samples was obtained.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>225</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>237</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سمیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حیدری</Family>
						<NameE>Somayeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Heydari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه شیمی، دانشکده علوم پایه، دانشگاه تربت جام و مدرس گروه گیاهان دارویی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه شیمی، دانشکده علوم پایه، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>s.heydari@tjamcaas.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مریم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خلیلی</Family>
						<NameE>Maryam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khalili</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش‌آموخته کارشناسی ارشد شیمی تجزیه، گروه گیاهان دارویی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش‌آموخته کارشناسی ارشد شیمی تجزیه، گروه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khalilimaryam5@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پیش تغلیظ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>میکرواستخراج</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اسپکتروفتومتری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کروسین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abdullaev, F. 2002. Cancer Chemopreventive and Tumoricidal Properties of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Experimental Biology Medicine 227: 20-25.##Ahmed, F.E. 2001. Analyses of pesticides and their metabolites in foods and drinks. TrAC, Trends Analytical Chemistry 20: 649-661.##Assimiadis, M.K., Tarantilis, P.A., and Polissiou, M.G., 1998. UV-vis FT-Raman and 1H NMR spectroscopies of cis–trans carotenoids from saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Applied Spectroscopy 52: 519–522.##Biparva, P., Ehsani, M., and Hadjmohammadi, M.R. 2012. Dispersive liquid–liquid microextraction using extraction solvents lighter than water combined with high performance liquid chromatography for determination of synthetic antioxidants in fruit juice samples. Food Composition and Analysis 27: 87–94.##Caballero-Ortega, H., Pereda-Miranda, R., and Abdullaev, F.I. 2007. HPLC quantification of major active components from 11 different saffron (Crocus sativus L.) sources. Food Chemistry 100: 1126–1131.  ##Dadfarnia, S., Haji Shabani, A.M., and Kamranzadeh, E. 2009. Separation/preconcentration and determination of cadmium ions by solidification of floating organic drop microextraction and FI-AAS,Talanta 79: 1061-1065.##Dadfarnia, S., and Haji Shabani, A.M. 2010. Recent development in liquid phase microextraction for determination of trace level concentration of metals, A review. Analytica Chimica Acta 658: 107-119.##Dadfarnia, S., Salmanzadeh, A.M., and Hajishabani, A.M. 2008. A novel separation/preconcentration system based on solidification of floating organic drop microextraction for determination of lead by graphite furnace atomic absorption spectrometry. Analytica Chimica Acta 623: 163-167.##Ghaedi, M., Shokrollahi, A., Kianfar, A.H., Pourfarokhi, A., Khanjari, N., Mirsadeghi, A.S., and Soylak, M. 2009. Preconcentration and separation of trace amount of heavy metal ions on bis(2-hydroxy acetophenone) ethylendiimine loaded on activated carbon. Hazardous Materials 162: 1408–1414.##Hosseinzadeh, H., Modaghegh, M.H., and Saffari, Z. 2009. Crocus sativus L. (saffron) extract and its active constituents (crocin and safranal) on ischemia-reperfusion in rat skeletal muscle. Evidence Based Complement Alternative Medicine 6: 343-50.##Khalili Zanjani, M.R., Yamini, Y., Shariati, S., and Jonsson J.A. 2007. A new liquid-phase microextraction method basedon solidification of floating organic drop. Analytica Chimica Acta 585 (2): 286-293.##Kocurova, L., Balogh, I.S., Sandrejova, J., and Andruch, V. 2013. Solvent microextraction: A review of recent efforts at automation. Microchemical Journal 110: 599-607.##Lozano, P., Castellar, M.R., Simancas, M.J., and Iborra, J.L. 1999. Quantitative highperformance liquid chromatographic method to analyse commercial saffron (Crocus sativus L.) products. Journal of Chromatography A 830: 477–483.##Ma, M., and Cantwell, F.F. 1999. Solvent microextraction with simultaneous back-extraction for sample cleanup and preconcentration: Preconcentration into a single microdrop. Analytical Chemistry 71: 388-393.##Mounira Lage, M., Charles, L., and Cantrell, C.L., 2007. Quantification of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) metabolites crocins, picrocrocin and safranal for quality determination of the spice grown under different environmental Moroccan conditions. Scientia Horticulturae 121: 366–373.##Narasimhan, S., Chand, N., and Rajalakshmi, D. 1992. Saffron: quality evaluation by sensory profile and gas chromatography. Journal of Food Quality 15: 303–314.##Rezaei, M., Assadi, Y., Milani Hosseini, M.R., Aghaee, E., Ahmadi, F., and Berijani. S. 2006. Determination of organic compounds in water using dispersive liquid-liquid microextraction. Journal of Chromatography A 1116: 1-9.##Sampathu, S.R., Shivashankar, S., and Lewis, Y.S., 1984. Saffron (Crocus sativus L.): cultivation, processing, chemistry and standardization. Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition 20 (2): 123–157.##Tarantilis, P.A., Tsoupras, G., and Polissiou, M., 1995. Determination of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) components in crude plant extracts using high-performance liquid chromatography–UV–Vis photodiode-array detection-mass spectrometry. Journal of Chromatography A 699: 107–117.##Tarantilis, P.A., and Polissiou, M.G. 1997. Isolation and identification of the aroma components from Saffron (Crocus sativus). Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry 45: 459–462.##Tarantilis, P.A., and Polissiou, M.G. 2004. Chemical analysis and antitumor activity of natural and semi-natural carotenoids of saffron. Proceedings of the 1st International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Biotechnology 2003. Acta Horticulturae 650: 447–461.##Xiaodong, W., Qiuling , Y., Zhidong, Y., and Qingwen,  D. 2011. Ultra-sensitive determination of cadmium in rice and water by UV-vis spectrophotometry after single drop microextraction. Spectrochimica Acta 97: 249–254##Zalacain, A., Ordoudi, S.A., Blazquez, I., Diaz-Plaza, E.M., Carmona, M., Blazquez, M.Z.I.,##Zgota- Grzeskowiak, A., and Grzeskowiak, T. 2011. Dispersive liquid-liquid microextraction. Trends Analytical Chemistry 30: 1382-1399.##Zougagh, M., Rios, A., and Valcarcel, M., 2005. An automated screening method for the fast, simple discrimination between natural and artificial colorants in commercial saffron products. Analytica Chimica Acta 535: 133–138.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مقایسه ی کاربردی لاجیت، پروبیت و توبیت در بررسی عوامل موثر بر پذیرش بیمه زعفران مطالعه موردی:شهرستان قاین</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Comparison of logit, probit and tobit in the factors affecting the adoption of saffron insurance
Case study: Qaen city</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>بیمه محصولات کشاورزی را می‌توان یکی از اهرم‌های توسعه کشاورزی دانست؛ زیرا با استفاده از آن هم می‌توان امنیت بیشتری برای تولیدکنندگان محصولات کشاورزی فراهم ساخت و هم شرایط مطلوبتری برای جلب و جذب سرمایه‌های خصوصی در بخش کشاورزی فراهم آورد. در این مطالعه تلاش شده است تا با استفاده اطلاعات حاصل از 118 کشاورز زعفران کار شهرستان قاین در سال 1392 و بهره‎گیری از سه الگوی لاجیت، پروبیت و دومرحله‌ای هکمن توبیت عوامل تأثیرگذار بر پذیرش بیمه زعفران مورد بررسی قرار گیرد. نتایج نشان داد که از بین الگوهای برآوردی، روش دو مرحله‌ای هکمن به دلیل اینکه می‌تواند میان عوامل مؤثر بر پذیرش بیمه و نیز عوامل مؤثر بر سطح بیمه‌گذاری تمایز قائل شود، از قوت بیشتری برخودار است. نتایج به دست آمده از متغیرهای الگو با هر سه مدل برآوردی نشان می‌دهد که متغیرهای تحصیلات کشاورز، درآمد سالیانه، استفاده از تسهیلات بانکی، سطح زیرکشت، استفاده از خدمات آموزشی مروجان، شاخص دانش بیمه‌ای و شاخص دانش فنی زراعی دارای تأثیر مثبت بر پذیرش و بیمه‌گذاری زعفران دارد و تنها متغیر سن دارای تأثیر منفی براقدام به بیمه‌گذاری و میزان بیمه‌گذاری زعفران دارد. با توجه به نتایج استفاده از دوره‎های آموزشی در خصوص مزایای بیمه محصول در مناطق روستایی و نیز افزایش سطح آگاهی کشاورز از انواع خدمات‎دهی صندوق‎های بیمه، زمان بیمه نمودن و میزان حق بیمه، توجه بیشتر مسئولان صندوق بیمه کشاورزی به سطوح درآمدی مختلف و تدوین راهکارهایی جهت گسترش استفاده از تسهیلات بانکی برای کشاورزان به عنوان پیشنهاد مطرح می‌گردد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Insurance for agricultural products can be considered to be one of the levers of agricultural development since its use can provide greater security for agricultural producers and provide more favorable conditions for attracting private investment in the agriculture sector. In this study, we used the data which was gathered in 2013 from 118 Qaeni Saffron farmers and examined the factors that affect the acceptance of Saffron insurance using Logit, Probit and Heckman two-stage Tobit. The results showed that among the estimated models, since Heckman two-stage can distinguish between the factors influencing the adoption of insurance and the factors affecting it, it is more strength paramount. The results of estimation of variables with the three models showed that farmer education, annual income, the usage of banking facilities, area under cultivation, educational services of agricultural demonstrators, insurance knowledge index and technical-crop knowledge index have a positive impact on the acceptance and insurance of saffron, and only the age variable has a negative impact on the insurance and the amount of the saffron insurance. According to the results, training courses on the benefits of crop insurance in rural areas and increasing farmers awareness of the types of insurance fund services, the insurance period and premium amount, consideration of the officials in charge of the agricultural insurance fund regarding the different income levels and development strategies to expand the use of banking facilities for farmers was suggested.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>239</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>254</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدزاده</Family>
						<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammadzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hoshos_1540@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کرباسی</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Karbasi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>arkarbasi2002@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مریم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کاشفی</Family>
						<NameE>Maryam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kashefi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>kashefid@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بیمه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شهرستان قاین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Agricultural Insurance Fund Performance Reports in Recent Years. 2013. Agricultural Insurance Fund. Available at Web site: http://www.sbkiran.ir/amaar. (verified October 2013).##Anderson, J.R. 2003. Impacts of climate variability in Australian agriculture. Review of Marketing and Agricultural Economics  49: 31- 42##Boon, T.K. 2005. Do Commercial Banks, Stock Market and Insurance Market Promote Economic Growth? An Analysis of Singapure Economy. Working Paper of the School of Humanities and Social studies. Nanyang Technological University.##Falco, S.D., and Perrings, C. 2005. Crop biodiversity, risk management and the implications of agricultural assistance. Journal of Ecological Economics 55: 459-466.##Farrokhnejad, M., and Mehrabi Boshrabadi, H. 2012. Investigating the impacts of crop insurance on production efficiency and risk management on reconstructed rice farms, case study: Lahijan city. Journal of agricultural insurance fund 9 (31-32): 33-44 (In Persian with English Summary).##Gharibi, K., Karimi, H., Mousavi, A. A., and Azarian, H. 2011. Study of effects of olive insurance on production &amp; cultivated area of olive in Iran (A glance at olive insurance plan in Iran 2002-2008). Journal of agricultural insurance fund 8 (27-28): 57- 70 (In Persian with English Summary).##Ghorbani, M., Koocheki, A.R., Lakzian, A., Kohansal, M.R., Tabaraei, M., Motallebi, M., Shokri, A., and Torshizi, M. 2008. Factors affecting on farmers investment in soil conservation of  Khorasan Razavi province. Journal of Agricultural Sciences and Industrial 21 (2): 11-22 (In Persian with English Summary).##Goodwin, B.K. 1993. An empirical analysis of the demand for multiple peril crop insurance. American Journal of Agricultural Economics 75: 425-434.##Grace, M.F., and Skipper, H.D. 2002. The Effect of Banking and Insurance on the Growth of Capital and Output. Center for Risk Management and Insurance Working Paper.##Greene, W.H. 1993. Econometric Analysis. 2nd Edition. New York: Macmillan, 791p.##Gujarati, D. 1999. Basic econometrics. Translation of hamid abrishami. Tehran University Publication.##Haiss, P., and Sumegi, K. 2006. The relationship of insurance and economic growth–A theoretical and empirical analysis. Economic Modeling conference. Hongkong. 28-30 June 2006.       ##Haq, A., Hartman, E., and  Myers, A. 2003. Agriculture and Green Insurance. Research Report. Available at www2.dnr.cornell.edu/saw44/NTRES431/Products/GCIessay.pdf .(accessed Feb 21, 2003).##Hayati, B., Ghahremanzadeh, M., Khodaverdyazdah, M., and Najafi, N. 2010. Factors affecting rural livestock insurance acceptance in Salmas city. Journal of Animal Science 4 (2): 27-38.##Judge, G.G. 1988. Introduction to the Theory and Practice of Econometrics. John Wiley and Sons Inc, 2nd Edition.##Khani Gharie Gapi, N.,  Fooladian, Z., and Ramezani, A. 2011. Study of effect of agricultural insurance on economic growth of Iran’s agriculture sector (using Hsiao method). Journal of agricultural insurance fund 8 (27-28): 5-29 (In Persian with English Summary).##Karbasi, A.R., Mosannan Mozaffari, M., and Shabani Rouchi, Z. 2012. The relationship of insurance premiums and value added of agriculture sector. Journal of Agricultural Insurance Fund 9 (31-32): 19-31 (In Persian with English Summary).##Kohansal, M.R., and Mohammadzadeh, S.H. 2011. Study of factors effective on demand of insurance for barberry farmers, case study: Qaen city. Journal of Agricultural Insurance fund 8 (27-28): 95-110 (In Persian with English Summary).##Kohansal, M.R., Mohammadzadeh, S.H., and Nemati, A. 2012. Application of artificial neural network in determining premium rate &amp; effective factors in adoption of wheat insurance, case study: Qaen city. Journal of agricultural insurance fund 9 (31-32): 45-67 (In Persian with English Summary).##Mahmoudi, M., Farhadian, H., and Noruzi, A. 2004. Agricultural Products Insurance strategy and its role in reducing the risk of agricultural activities. Journal of Agricultural and insurance (3-4): 63-77 (In Persian with English Summary).##Mir Salehpour, M., Mashreghi, N., Karimifard, S., Add-e Shahi, A., and Mashreghi, Gh. 2011. Study &amp; comparing the effects of insurance &amp; agricultural inputs on rice production in Gilan province. Journal of agricultural insurance fund 8 (27-28): 133-143 (In Persian with English Summary).##Paulson, D.N., Babcock, B.A., Hart, C.E., and Hayes, D.J. 2004. Insuring uncertainly in valu–added Agricultural: Ethanol Production, Center for Agricultural Rural development /lowa state university, Available at Web site: http: www.card.iastate.edu. (verified 5 October 2014)##Sadati, S.A., Rostami Ghobadi, F., Sadati, S.A., Mohamadi, Y., Sharifi, O., and Asakereh, A. 2010. Survey of effective factors on adoption of crop insurance among farmers: A case study of Behbahan County. African Journal of Agricultural Research 5 (16): 2237-2242. Available at Web site: http://www.academicjournals.org. (verified 5 september 2011)##Shokri, A., Ghorbani, M., Koochaki, A.R., and Danesh, SH. 2008. Environmental attitude on the role of water’ saffron insurance in the province of North Khorasan. Journal of Economics and Agricultural Development 22 (2): 15-29 (In Persian).##Tobin, J. 1958. Estimation  of  relationships  for  limited  dependent  variables. Econometrica 26: 29-36.##Vandeveer, M., and Young, C.E. 2001. The Effects of the Federal Crop Insurance Program on Wheat Acreage. Wheat situation and outlook yearbook. March. p. 21-30.##Zare Mehrjerdi, M.R., and Esmaeili, A. 2011. Determine the factors affecting the adoption of livestock insurance in Kerman city with parametric and non-parametric methods. Journal of Agricultural Research 2 (3): 1-16.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				