<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Evaluation of integrated management of soil fertilizers and summer irrigation on agronomic criteria and flower and stigma yield of saffron</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ghorban Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Asadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Agrotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">soror</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khorramdel</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghorbani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Agrotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Bahareh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bicharanlou</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD student in Agroecology, Department of Agrotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In order to evaluate the effects of organic, chemical and biological fertilizers and summer irrigation on growth characteristics, corm yield, flower yield and stigma yield of saffron, field experiment was conducted as factorial based on a randomized complete block design with three replications at Agricultural Research station, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad during three growing season of 2013-2014, 2014-2015 and 2015-2016. The first factor included of animal cow manure (a1), chemical fertilizer (such as Nitrogen, P and K) (a2), Thiobacillus (a3), sulfur (a4), a3+a4 and control (a5) and the second factor was summer irrigation in three levels such as conventional irrigation (A: without summer irrigation), A+ once summer irrigation (23 July), A+ twice summer irrigation (22 June+23 July). Studied characteristics were number and fresh weight of flower, dry weight of stigma, corm diameter, corm weight in four groups (16 g), corms with contractile roots, number of flowering buds per corm, leaf length, dry weight of leaf and dry weight of tunic of saffron. The results in the third of experiment revealed that the interaction effect between fertilizers and summer irrigation were significant (P≤0.01) on all studied traits of saffron except stigma dry weight, corms with weight more than 16 g and dry weight of daughter corms. The highest flower number (282.7 per m2), flower fresh weight (103.2 g/m2), stigma dry weight (1.73 g/m2), leaf dry weight (13.33 g/m2), buds dry weight (4.61 g/m2), flowering buds number per corm (2.627), corm percentage with cractile roots (58.41%), corm diameter (2.97 cm) and corms in different weight were obtained in animal manure and A+once summer irrigation. About simple effects, the highest stigma dry weight and dry weight of daughter corms were observed in animal manure and the highest amount of this traits were obtained in treatment A+once summer irrigation. It seems that summer irrigation increased the flower and stigma yield of saffron due to decreasing soil temperature.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>393</start>
					<end>414</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_58033_f400a811f856c267a7320bba51ef4219.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.70724.1205</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Effects of of fulvic acid and cow manure on stigma active components and petal Antiradical Activity of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aminifard</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Horticultural Science and Special Plants Regional Research centre, College of Agriculture, University of Birjand, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">faride</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">ahmadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc Student, Department of Horticultural Science, College of Agriculture, University of Birjand, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>components of saffron were evaluated under field conditions. Treatments were four levels cow manure (0, 10, 20 and 30 t.ha-1) and three fulvic acid (0, 5 and 10 kg.ha-1). This experiment was carried out as factorial based on randomized completely block design with three replications in research farm of Birjand University, Iran, during cropping year 2015-2016. Results showed that cow manure improved the active ingredients of stigma (picrocrocin, safranal and crocin) in first year of study. Also, results showed that petal antioxidant compounds (total phenol and anthocyanin) and active ingredients of stigma were influenced by cow manure in second year of study. The highest safranal was obtained in plants treated with 10 t.ha-1 cow manure in first year of experiment. Results also showed that fulvic acid has a positive effect active ingredients of stigma (picrocrocin and crocin), anthocyanin and total phenol in two years of experiment and the highest rate of anthocyanin and total phenol were obtained with 5 kg.ha-1 fulvic acid while the lowest values were recorded in control. Application of different levels of cow manure and fulvic acid had a positive effect on the active ingredients of stigma in two years of experiment and anthocyanin and phenol in second year of study. Thus, results showed that cow manure and fulvic acid have significant impact on antioxidant compounds and active ingredients of saffron under field conditions.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>415</start>
					<end>428</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_55269_df423e71f248887ac8fb9d5ab6789e03.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2017.99009.1260</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigation the effect of manure and planting pattern on some flower and corm quantitative traits of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Gonabad climatic conditions</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Yaser</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Esmaeilian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Department of Agriculture, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Gonabad, Gonabad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Behzad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Amiri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Department of Agriculture, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Gonabad, Gonabad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In order to study the response of saffron medicinal plant to planting density and different levels of manure, a two year experiment was conducted in split-plot as complete block design with three replications in 2015-16 and 2016-2017 in Gonabad area. Main factor consisted of 5, 10, and 15 cm plant spacing on row and sub factor was control (no manure application), and application of 0, 20, 40, and 60 t/ha cow manure. Experiment results showed that maximum value of fresh flower yield in first year (127.4 kg/ha) achieved in 60 t/ha and in second year (72.3 kg/ha) obtained from 40 t/ha manure application under 5 cm plant spacing in row. The highest fresh stigma yield in both years (10.300 and 5.383 kg/ha, respectively) was obtained due to high planting density (5 cm plant spacing in row) and 40 t/ha manure application. Also, dry stigma yield under this treatment with 2.300 and 1.770 kg/ha, respectively had more increase in both years than other treatments. The highest daughter corm number in both years (614 and 591 corm/m2, respectively) obtained from highest corm planting density. In first year, 40 t/ha manure treatment had the highest value (592 corm/m2) and in second year, 60 t/ha manure application showed the highest value (572 corm/m2). In first year, the highest corm yield with 22724 kg/ha achieved from 5 cm plant spacing in row and 40 t/ha manure. But, in second year the highest mean value (12429 kg/ha) obtained from the same planting density and use of 60 t/ha manure. Therefore, to achieve suitable economic yield in saffron cultivation, application of 40 t/ha cow manure in 20×5 cm planting density under climatic and edaphic conditions similar to this experiment location is suggested.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>429</start>
					<end>444</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_62312_a80ad347c15cfe876f8f96d08373e5f4.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.101708.1265</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Effects of Mother Corm Weight and Cow Manure on Saffron Flower and Corm Yield</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">ramin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Esmi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Agriculture &amp;amp;ndash; Jahad Organization khorasan razavi</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parviz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rezvani Moghaddam</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Agrotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Koocheki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Agrotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">ahmadian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Plant Production Department, and Researcher of Saffron Institute, University of Torbat Heydarieh</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In order to investigate the effects of mother corm weight (including 4.1-7, 7.1-10 and 10.1-13 g) and different levels of cow manure (including 30 (control), 60 and 90 t/ha) on flower characteristics and daughter corms of saffron, a factorial experiment based on randomized complete block design with three replications was conducted during two cropping years (2012-13, 2013-14) in Zaweh county. The results of variance analysis in the first and second years showed that there were significant differences between the simple effects and the interaction effects in terms of most of the studied traits, and these differences were higher in the second year. The highest (56.8 m-2) and the lowest (41.3 m-2) flower numbers were obtained in 90 t/ha cow manure with bigger corm size ( 10.1-13 g) and 60 t/ha cow manure with smaller corm size (4.1-7 g) treatments, respectively. 60 t/ha cow manure with bigger corm size (10.1-13 g) and 60 t/ha cow manure with smaller corm size (4.1-7 g) treatments produced the highest (0.347 g.m-2) and the lowest (0.220 g.m-2) dry weight of stigma, respectively. The highest and the lowest of total number of daughter corms (504.2 and 264.7 m-2), total daughter corm yield (2677.3 and 1582.9 g.m-2) were shown in 90 t/ha cow manure with bigger corm size ( 10.1-13 g) and 30 (control) t/ha cow manure with smaller corm size (4.1-7 g) treatments, respectively. In addition, the mean comparison of interaction effect in the second year showed that there were significant differences between most of treatments. The interaction effects of studied traits in the second year showed that 90 t/ha cow manure with bigger corm size (10.1-13 g) and 30 (control) t/ha cow manure with smaller corm size (4.1-7 g) treatments produced the highest and the lowest flower number (231.0 and 156.5 m-2), stigma dry weight (2.062 and 1.053 g.m-2), total number of daughter corms (1024.5 and 505.5 m-2) and total daughter corms yield (4486.6 and 2133.1 g.m-2), respectively. Finally, it can be concluded that by increasing the use of cow manure (more than 60 t/ha) and the use of more than 7 grams mother corms, it is possible to improve the number and yield of daughter corms and these traits will increase the saffron stigma yield in the next coming years.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>445</start>
					<end>460</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_55359_a629162e0f480fecf0eae70025b82c95.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2017.88165.1236</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Effects of Nitroxin bio-fertilizer, superabsorbent polymer and planting method on yield of flower and corm of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in rainfed-farming condition of Khorramabad, Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Saeid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Heidari</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD student, Department of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, Faculty of Agriculture, Lorestan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Khosrow</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azizi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, Faculty of Agriculture, Lorestan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ismaili</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, Faculty of Agriculture, Lorestan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In order to study the effect of bio-fertilizers, planting method and superabsorbent polymer on quantitative yield of saffron under rainfed condition, a factorial experiment based on randomized complete block design with three replications was conducted at the Agricultural Research Station of Khorramabad, Iran during 2015-2016 growing seasons. In this study, Nitroxin bio-fertilizer (consumption 5 Lit/ha and non-consumption), Stockosorb superabsorbent polymer (consumption 240 kg/ha and non-consumption) and planting method (streaking and cluster) was tested. Results showed that triple interactions was significant for number of corm/m2 in first and second year and combined treatment including non-Nitroxin in cluster culture method using superabsorbent with 80.67 corm/m2 for first year and with 183.67 corm/m2 for second year was the superior treatment. Results showed significant differences for number of produced flowers and for fresh and dry weight of stigma in both years; and in the first year, treatment included cluster method cultivation, consumption of superabsorbent and no consumption of Nitroxin was superior; while in the second year, superior treatment was use of superabsorbent, Nitroxin and cluster method. For stigma dry weight of saffron, triple interactions was significant and in the first year, cluster method and consumption of superabsorbent and no usage of Nitroxin was superior (with 0.6 kg/ha), and in the second year, use of Nitroxin and superabsorbent and cluster method was superior (with 0.719 kg/ha). In general, results of the present study in dry-farming conditions over the two years, cluster method cultivation with usage of superabsorbent and Nitroxin could be recommended. Reasons of this recommendation and introduction of the mentioned method are dry climate conditions in area of study and reduction in consumption of chemical fertilizers for development of sustainable agriculture.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>461</start>
					<end>472</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_55682_a532deab5dae5854f349fb69fa31ec21.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2017.81060.1221</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Water Deficit and the Effect of Silver Nanoparticles on Morphological Traits onSome Saffron Ecotypes (Crocus sativus L.) in South Khorasan</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sara</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sabertanha</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc Student, Department of Plant Breeding and Biotechnology, College of Agriculture, University of Zabol.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">BARAT ALI</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">FAKHERI</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Plant Breeding and Biotechnology, College of Agriculture,  University of Zabol</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Nafiseh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mahdinezhad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professors, Department of Plant Breeding and Biotechnology, College of Agriculture, University of Zabol</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Zohre</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Alizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professors, Department of Plant Breeding and Biotechnology, College of Agriculture, University of Birjand</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The present research was conducted to investigate the effect of water stress and silver nanoparticles on morphological traits of some saffron ecotypes. The experiment was done in form of split plot factorial in a randomized complete block design format in three replications at research farm of Birjand University with two levels including full and low water irrigation on 10 ecotypes of saffron and at three levels of silver nanoparticles including control treatment (distille water), 55 and 110 ppm. The traits such as germination date (germination), the number of germinated corm, the number of tillers, the number of leaves, leaf length, the pods length and leaf width were measured. The best date of emergence and the largest number of paws in complete irrigation treatment was observed under distilled water treatment (control). The highest number of corm germinated was observed in irrigated conditions at 55 ppm of silver nanoparticles in the Qaeen ecotype. The highest leaf length was observed under drought stress in the treatment with distilled water (control). The largest number of leaves and leaf width were observed under drought stress at 55 ppm of silver nanoparticles. According to the obtained results of this study, some of the traits at the conditions of drought stress under the silver nanoparticles with a concentration of 55 ppm and some of the traits in the full irrigation and lack of use of silver nanoparticles had the best performance, which it could be said that probably, in stress dryness, the amount of ethylene increases. Some of the obtained results of this study can be related to the effect of silver in preventing ethylene activity.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>473</start>
					<end>485</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_57305_170e854011d39f836525d5335b1f1de3.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.82080.1223</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigation acaricide of vegetative material and acaricide on control saffron mite Rhizoglyphus robini in the laboratory condition</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">fereshteh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">yousofzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Former MSc Student, Department of Plant Protection, Kashmar University of Science and Culture, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Isa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jabaleh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Department of Plant Protection, ACECR -Khorasan Razavi, Kashmar Higher Education Institute, Kashmar, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Olyaie torshiz</namePart>
				<affiliation>Msc Department of Plant Protection , ACECR_Khorasan Razavi Branch, Kashmar, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">ahmadian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Plant Production Department, and Researcher of Saffron Institute, University of Torbat Heydarieh</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>According to the export of saffron (Crocus sativus.L) and superiority of organic products in the market, this study performed in order to assessment natural methods in control of saffron mite which is a major pest of saffron, was conducted in the saffron institute of Torbat university in 2014. In this research has been studied effect of Bromopropylate and Propargite acaricides and Rosemary essential oil and Stinking assa resin on development steps of Rhizoglyphus robbini in four doases and six different times the peresence of acaricide (3, 6, 12,24,48,72 hours) in the factorial on complete randomized design and four replications. The laboratory condition was determined at photoperiod 16:8, humidity 65 ± 5 percentage and temperature 27 ± 2°C. Analysis results of data variance showed that the effects of treatments on mortality of egg ،larvae and mature mites were significant at the 1 percentage probability level. Also that Bromopropylate has maximum mortality percent among larvae and mature saffron mite. Also in this experiment time increasing and concentration increase mortality of larvae’s significantly. As well as the maximum percent of eggs failed to hatch related to Rosemary essential oil .Also larvae mortality percent was more than mature mite that had significant differences at 5% probability level .In this study was found Stinking assa resin has the greatest impact on the egg also Propargite and Bromopropilate have created the highest mortality on the larvae and adults respectively.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>487</start>
					<end>497</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_61866_9b2ae14084a835abd70a714d9877084c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.26623.1080</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Assessing the Role of Trade Sanctions and Global Economic Crisis on Iran’s Saffron Exports</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Arash</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Dourandish</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Agricultural Economics, Agricultural Economics Department, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Milad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aminizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>- PhD Student of Agricultural Economics, Agricultural Economics Department, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Andisheh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Riahi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Master of Agricultural Economics, Agricultural Economics Department, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Elham</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mehrparvar Hosseini</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student of Agricultural Economics, Agricultural Economics Department, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Saffron is one of Iran’s exports of agricultural products that it could not keep and strengthen its position in the world market at recent years. Two events such as European Union trade sanctions against Iran (2006-2014) and global economic crisis (2007-2009) have directly and indirectly impacts on Iran’s economy and trade flows, respectively. According to process uncertainty about the abolition or continuation of the European Union trade sanctions and the possibility of a new global economic crisis, the aim of this paper is assessing the role of these two factors on Iran’s saffron exports. For this purpose, saffron exports to trading partners were analyzed by using gravity model and poisson pseudo maximum likelihood estimator in 2001-2014 periods. Based on the results, economic size, importer’s income and regional trade agreement have positive effect and distance and difference in GDP per capita have negative and significant impacts on saffron exports. The Results indicated that EU trade sanctions and global economic crisis have significantly negative effects on Iran’s saffron exports. In other words, due to Iran’s trading partners, global economic crisis have important role in saffron exports. Therefore, it is suggested that role of trade sanctions and economic crisis and their importance be considered to adopt long run strategic plan in order to strengthen Iran’s position in saffron world market and optimal basket of trading partners to be selected.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>499</start>
					<end>511</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_54312_6373f23a97bd4a88db6c1c85f3352516.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2017.85769.1231</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>.Application of Risk Profile in Saffron Risk Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Elnaz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nejatianpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Researcher of  Saffron Institute, Invitee Lecturer in Agricultural Economics at University of Torbat Heydarieh</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">ghodoosi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Lecturer, Department of Industrial Engineering, Faculty of Technical and Engineering, University of Torbat Heydarieh</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">hasanpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Lecturer, Department of Industrial Engineering, Faculty of Technical and Engineering, Quchan University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Agriculture is a unique sector because of its dependence on the climate and biological variables. Therefore, in agriculture it is vital to identify and evaluate risks to be sure that decisions made on the farm will bring positive results. Torbat-e-Heydarieh is the most important center in saffron cultivation and production in Khorasan Razavi province and Iran. This city is famous for its Saffron lands. It has the first rank in the world for producing Saffron . So, in this paper, we employed risk profile analysis to saffron risk management. By using previous literatures, all of the risks of agricultural sector are identified and classified in nine categories. The information was collected from the university elite and Saffron union members. To design the risk profile, we used data from 67 saffron producers of Torbat Heydariyeh in 1395. For evaluating of losses related to each risk component, two indexes of frequency and severity of risk were calculated and based on that risk matrix were created. Results showed that the greatest area of risk is included all of the risk of pests, diseases and weeds (Different types of weeds, Micro pests (Fungi and bacteria), Macro pests( Mice, ant, insect, Grazing livestock)), economic risk (Brokers, market fluctuations, lack of liquidity of farmers), Climate risk (drought, frost and freeze) and damage risk (Reduce yield due to farm life).</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>513</start>
					<end>529</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_57181_afbb544b8cfe1a58670f11b607c2c0e3.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.92906.1249</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>