<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Assessing the effect of irrigation management on economic yield and production of active ingredients of saffron medicinal plant (Crocus sativus L.) by application of organic fertilizer and nanocomposite superabsorbent polymers]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ramezani, Amin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Aroiee, Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Azizi, Majid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ahmadian, Ahmad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University Of Torbat Heydarieh]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Bolourab A]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crocin]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Picrocrocin]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Safranal]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Terracottem]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vermicompost]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In order to find and recommend a method for improving vegetative and reproductive traits and economic yield of saffron using organic compounds of soil amendment, a split plot experiment including three irrigation intervals of 30, 50 and 70 days as main plots and three factors of vermicompost, Terracottem and Bolourab A, as well as control, as sub plots was carried out for three years (2014-2017) at Saffron Research Institute, Torbat-e-Heydarieh University. The results showed that the effects of treatments on all quantitative and qualitative traits, were significant (p]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_88178_aeb8fa2c59fa9bcba5b5ebf4a52cfae1.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22048/jsat.2019.135749.1304]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Saffron agronomy and technology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Assessing effect of cumin and saffron additive intercropping at various planting dates on quantitative and qualitative yield of the plants]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Moradi, Rooholla]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Pourghasemian, Nsibeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University Of Torbat Heydarieh]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Essential oil]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[irrigation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[LER]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Replacement corm]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stigma]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In order to study effect of various additive intercropping series of saffron and cumin on their yields, and yield components, an experiment was conducted as split-plot arrangement based on randomized complete block design with three replications in a two years saffron research farm in agricultural faculty of Bardsir at 2016-2017. The experimental treatments were planting dates (November 11, December 11, March 6 and April 4) assigned to main plot, and additive intercropping series (25, 50, 75 and 100% of optimum density of cumin (120 plant m-2), sole saffron (50 plant m-2), sole cumin) as subplot. The studied traits were including number of umbrella per plant, essential oil percentage, seed, biological and essential oil yield, and also saffron flower number, flower yield, stigma yield, number of replacement corm, corm weight and number of infected corm. The results showed that delaying in cumin planting date led to a notable decrease in cumin yield and yield components, in all the planting patterns. The reduction values of cumin seed yield in March and April planting dates compared to November were 39% and 64%, respectively. Cumin essential oil at November (2.79%), December (2.78%) and April (2.83%) planting dates were higher than March (2.42%). The experimental treatments had no significant effect on corm number, but cumin planting at spring contained greater infected corms than fall planting. The corm weight was declined as affected by delay in planting date and increase in cumin density. The saffron flower and stigma yield in fall intercropping was significantly higher than spring intercropping. Intercropping had negative impacts on saffron productivity, and the highest stigma yield (2.97 kg ha-1) was assigned to sole cropping. In general, the maximum (1.51) LER was related to fall intercropping of cumin and saffron.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_88165_3597c730847f8b84e6bce9bfc2323d5b.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22048/jsat.2019.156395.1325]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Saffron agronomy and technology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Studying the possibility of replacing manure with other organic amendments in saffron (Crocus sativus L.) cultivation at different mother corm weights]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ebrahimi, Mahdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Pouyan, Mohsen]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mahdi Nezhad, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University Of Torbat Heydarieh]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organic-mineral-based emulsion]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[linear regression]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cow manure]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Daughter corm]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This study was conducted to investigate the effect of different organic amendments (cow manure, humic acid (Humax® 95–WSG), an organic-mineral-based emulsion (Omic®) and unfertilized control) and mother-corm weight (0 to 4 g, 4.1 to 8 g and 8.1 to 12 g) on flower and corm yield of saffron. The experiment was conducted as factorial experiment in randomized complete block design with three replications in the Research Complex of Medicinal Plants, ACECR of Southern Khorasan Province, Iran in 2017-18. According the results, evaluating the main effect of nutrition factor revealed no significant impact on most studied traits in the first year. However, in the second year and during the 21-day period of saffron flowering, cow manure treatment increased stigma dry weight by 77.3, 71.7 and 58.9% compared with control, Humax and Omic treatments, respectively. By fitting the regression line between the cumulative dry weight of the stigma and days after flowering, it was found that stigma dry weight increased 19.1, 11.43, 10.92 and 10.65 mg.day-1 in cow manure, Omic, Humax and control treatments, respectively. In addition, the highest flower dry weight with 2858 mg.m-2 was recorded in cow manure treatment. The highest and lowest amount of the studeid tratis in both years belonged to big and small corm treatments, respectively. In the first year, stigma dry weight in big corm treatment with 22.28 mg.m-2 was about 190 times higher than that of small one. However the difference in the second year fell to less than 3 times. In addition, the highest number (466.36 m-2) and weight (936.559 g. m-2) of daughter corms were obtained in big mother corms treatment. In the second year however by the reduction of the differences between mother corm weight treatments, stigma dry weight, flower dry weight and number of flowers in big and medium corm treatments were not statistically significant. Overall, the results of this study showed that the advantages of using manure in saffron cultivation due to its unique characteristics, such as improving the physical conditions of the soil is not compensable by other organic amendments. Moreover, the avoidence of planting mother corms less than 4g because of their adverse effects on saffron yeild is of main importance in saffron cultivation and must be considered by farmers.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_87456_f9adc23901d85efe7b9ff47b77915675.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22048/jsat.2019.165266.1331]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Saffron agronomy and technology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Evaluation of planting date and corm weight effects on flower, stigma and doughter corms characters of saffron(Crocus sativus L.) under South Kerman climatic conditions]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Alavi Siney, Seid Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ahmadpour Jolgeh, Ahmad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Behroozeh, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Soltani, Majid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University Of Torbat Heydarieh]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[planting date]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[flower number]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stigma]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Corm size]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In order to investigate planting date and corm weight Effects on flower characters and saffron(Crocus sativus L.) yield, an experiment as a factorial was carried out based on randomized complete blocks design with three replications in research station of South Kerman Agricultural and Natural Resources Research and Education Center at Sfadagheh during 2017-2018 growing season Two factors, planting date (Jun, August and September) and corm size (6-8, 8-10, 10-12 and >12g) were evaluated in this experiment. Related traits with flower and Stigma and cormwere measured during growing season. Results showed that planting date have significant effect on all of traits except of dry weight of stigma. Also, the effects of corm weight and interaction of planting date×corm weight were significant on all of traits. So, the highest number of flower and the stigma yield were observed in the planting date of June and the corm weight more than 12 g. Therefore, for achieving high saffron yield, it is recommended planting date of June and the use of corms with more than12 g. Investigating the characteristics of the doughtercorms in the first year of the experiment showed that all studied traits were influenced by the planting date and the effect of the corm weight was not significant on the characteristics of the number of doughter corm over 6 g, the average weight of the doughter corm more and less than 6 g. According to the results of the traits related to the doughter corm, it can be anticipated that in the following year there is no difference in yield and its components among the different levels of maternal corm. Results in the second year showed that yield and yield components were only affected by the planting date and the corm weight had the same effect on them. The planting date of June 5th was the highest in the second year. According to the results and low price of saffron in June, in Southern Kerman foothill areas, cultivation of saffron should be done on June 5th. Since in the first year of the experiment, the yield don't achieved even from great mothernal corm, and given the fact that the mother corms of different weights in the second year have the same role in determining the stigma yield, in order to reduce the production costs, the 6 -8 g recommended for cultivation.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_88106_c45628c96735c725a16a8a12379812bc.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22048/jsat.2019.168153.1334]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Saffron agronomy and technology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Response of flower and corm yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) to nanobiologic fertilizer application in comparison to current cow manure and chemical fertilizer]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Feizi, Hassan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hosseini, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sahabi, Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nazarian, Ramin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University Of Torbat Heydarieh]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Corm inoculation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Corm yield]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Flower yield]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[foliar application]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[For evaluation of response of flower and corm yield of saffron to nanobiologic fertilizer application methods in comparison to cow manure and chemical fertilizer an experiment was conducted in Shadmehr region as randomized complete block design with 10 treatments with four replication during two years (2014-2015 and 1015-2016). The treatments were 1. Corm inoculation with nanobiofertilizer (Bioumik product of Biozar company), 2. Corm inoculation+use in irrigation water, 3. Corm inoculation+ foliar application 4. Corm inoculation+ foliar application+use in irrigation water, 5. In irrigation water, 6. Foliar application 7. Use of chemical fertilizer (Urea, Ammonium phosphate and Potassium sulphate) 8. Use of cow manure 9. Use of chemical fertilizer +Use of cow manure and 10. Control. Studied traits were corm dry yield, flower dry yield, stigma dry and fresh yield and flower number. Based on result from third year the highest stigma dry yield (about 14 kg/ha) and flower number were achieved in Corm inoculation+ foliar application+use in irrigation water treatment (by 176 % increase in comparison to control) and the highest corm yield was seen in corm inoculation treatment (by 41 more than control). Results showed that the best method for corm improvement was corm inoculation with nanobiofertilizer and for flower improvement it is recommend to use of Corm inoculation+ foliar application+use in irrigation water.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_95271_6f1ac2119347d8795e4923e7c6b6e7c0.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22048/jsat.2019.177567.1339]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Saffron agronomy and technology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The effect of extraction condition on Bio active compounds of saffron corm extract]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Einafshar, Soodabeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sharayei, Parvin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University Of Torbat Heydarieh]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA["Antioxidative ability"]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA["antimicrobial power"]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[" redusing power of FeIII"]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[" saffron corm"]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Saffron is a unique product of Iran and Saffron corm is one of the saffron producing ingredients that is produced annually in high volume in the country. It is shown that saffron corm is a low- cost material, contains some bioactive compounds that are extractable. The extraction method is effected on the kind and amount of bioactive material extracted from saffron corm. Therefore, this research was carried out to produce high value added materials from waste saffron onion. First, the saffron onion was prepared, dried and completely grinding. Extracting was performed using solvent (80% methanol, 80% ethanol and water) and ultrasound (100% intensity, 0, 20 and 40 minutes at room temperature). The extracts were dried at rotary evaporation. In each case, the extraction efficiency, determination of minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC) and minimum bactericidal concentration (MBC), phenolic compounds, iron regeneration strength III, and free radical receptivity were determined. In order to investigate the independent effect (type of solvent, ultrasound intensity) and interaction (solvent type and ultrasound intensity) on bioactive compounds of saffron onion extract, a factorial arrangement of 2 variables with completely randomized design was used in three replications. The mean comparison was done by Duncan method. The results showed that Ethanol solvent extracted 85.84 mg/ml of phenolic compounds with the highest reducing power of FeIII (594.7 μmol/ml) and radical receptivity (59.42%), and the ultrasound process at 100% for 40 minutes extracted the highest amount of phenolic compounds (82.23 mg/ml).]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_92890_f20e22c72977a4bab19719b37638d40c.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22048/jsat.2019.170014.1336]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Saffron agronomy and technology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Study of Farmers’ Attitude towards Sustainable Agriculture and Its Impact on the Total Factor Productivity (Case Study: Saffron Farms in Gonabad County)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Dourandish, Arash]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ramezani, Mohammadreza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Aminizadeh, Milad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University Of Torbat Heydarieh]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Productivity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Attitude]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Saffron]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ordered logit]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Increasing factor productivity in the agricultural sector is essential, and with the growing population, the need to invent more productive systems is highlighted. However, agronomic activities have always been accompanied by environmental impacts. Therefore, the two categories of productivity and agricultural sustainability should be considered simultaneously. The present study aimed at identifying factors affecting the total factor productivity of saffron farms in Gonabad County with an emphasis on the role of attitude towards sustainable agriculture. In order to achieve the research objectives, 110 questionnaires were completed and after calculating the total factor productivity using the Tornqvist-Theil index, an Ordered-logit model was used to identify factors affecting productivity. The results indicate that attitudes toward sustainable agriculture and income have positive and significant effects on farmers' access to higher levels of productivity, while variable of participation in training courses significantly reduces the probability of achieving higher levels of productivity. Variables of sown area, agricultural insurance and main job do not have significant effects on the probability of achieving different levels of productivity. Undertaking policies which improve attitude of saffron producers towards sustainable agricultural activities and informing them about the effects of unsustainable farming, a fundamental revision of the content of training courses, financial support of farmers for provision of agricultural inputs and reforming the structure of the agricultural insurance system are effective ways to improve productivity of saffron production.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_88105_b9e6978d3192d1724632143ca42c47fd.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22048/jsat.2019.169646.1335]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Saffron agronomy and technology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[(Identification Risk Factors on Saffron Producers in Qaenat by Genetic function Algorithm )]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hosseini, ُSeyyed Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Dadrasmoghadam, Amir]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Karbasi, Alireza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Vandaki, Ahmad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University Of Torbat Heydarieh]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[risk]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Saffron]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Genetic function algorithm]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[logit]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Identification Risk Factors on Saffron Producers in Qaenat by Genetic function Algorithm AbstractRisk in agriculture has a significant impact on agricultural production, and farmers' risk to household economies has an impact on the economy of society. Hence, identification of important factors and determinants affecting farmer risk management is of particular importance. The aim of this study to identify the factors affecting the risk of saffron Qaenat. The statistical sample was collected by using random sampling method from 120 saffron makers of this city in 2017. The results showed that there were positive relationships between 44 factors, yield factors, irrigation, sales time, expert guidance, water quality, younger seed, and money savings with saffron risk factors. Also, the factors of diversification Activities, dispute settlement, total sales, the cost of buying onions with the risk of saffron. In other words, ten fundamental factors were identified using the method of approximation of the genetic algorithm function. The results of the estimation with logit model also showed that sales time and money saving have a significant effect, but other variables in logit regression are not significant. In this regard, it is suggested that, in order to reduce the risk management of the saffron, experts should be promoted and the differences between saffron producers minimized, as well as by increasing the sales and saving time, the risk management of the saffron reduced.Keywords: Risk, Saffron, Genetic Function Algorithm, Logit]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_81717_d19ec6a9f72c2640dc50ac25315c0afb.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22048/jsat.2019.132153.1301]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Saffron agronomy and technology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Factors Affecting the Adoption of Saffron Cultivation Case Study of  Dashtkhak village in Kerman Province]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Poorkhaleghi Chatroodi, Mojdeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mehrabi Bashrabadi, Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khajepoor, Elham]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University Of Torbat Heydarieh]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[alternative cropping]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[crop replacement]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[water scarcity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Probit Model]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Logit Model]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[abstractOne of the alternative crops in Kerman province is saffron. This study aimed to investigate theeffective factors on Saffron cultivation in Dashtkhat during 1395. This is a practical and descriptive-inferential study. A questionnaire waS randomly distributed among 164 people and the reliability and validity of the gathered data was evaluated using Cronbach's α (0.76). Amonglogit and probit models, probit model was chosen based on the statistical results of Akaike and Bayesian criteria. Results of the study show that factors such as education, agronomic income, the drought level-based crop replacement and the replacement of crop based on the recommendation of other farmers had positive effects on farmers’ acceptance while dependency ratio factor had a negative effect on accepting any kind of alternation in crop cultivation. Since water scarcity is one of the most important factors influencing the acceptance level of crop replacement, all of the strategies designed for dealingwith water crisis should aim for the optimal management of groundwater aquifers. it is hoped that in the future, the Dashtkhas Village will become a prototype model for transforming crops, for other parts of the province of Kerman, which are facing the problem of dehydration in the development of their agricultural industry.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_94087_fd5ac5d25ef0b1afe03b48716492ffa0.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22048/jsat.2019.161331.1330]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Saffron agronomy and technology]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>