<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Effects of vermicompost and nitroxin on replacement corm characteristics and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in the second year</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohmmad Hosein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aminifard</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Horticultural Science and Special Plants Regional Research Center, College of Agriculture, University of Birjand, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Oftadeh Fadafen</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc. Student, Department of Horticulture, College of Agriculture of Medical plants Physiology, University of Birjand, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Farid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Moradi Nezhad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Horticultural Science and Special Plants Regional Research centre, College of Agriculture, University of Birjand, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Behdani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor Department of saffron Research, University of Birjand, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The effects of applications of vermicompost and nitroxin on corm characteristics and flower yield of saffron were evaluated under field conditions in the research farm of Birjand University, Iran, during the cropping year 2015-2016. Treatments were of four levels of vermicompost (0, 5, 10 and 15 t.ha-1) and three levels of nitroxin (0, 5 and 10 L.ha-1). This experiment was carried out as factorial based on randomized completely block design with three replications. The results showed that vermicompost improved the corm vegetative indices (total weight of corm, average fresh and dry weight of cormel and diameter of cormel). The highest total weight of corm was obtained in plants treated with 15 t.ha-1 vermicompost. Also results showed that vermicompost improved the saffron flower characteristics (flower number and fresh total yield, flower length, stigma fresh and dry yield) in second year of study. The highest stigma fresh (1.63 g.m-2) and dry (0.41 g.m-2) yield were obtained in plants treated with 10 t.ha-1 vermicompost, while the lowest values (0.77 and 0.21 g.m-2) were recorded in the control. Application of different levels of nitroxin has a positive effect on flower number and fresh total yield, stigma dry yield in the second year of the experiment. The highest stigma dry yield was observed in 10 L.ha-1 nitroxin (0.36 g.m-2), while the lowest value was recorded in control (0.24 g.m-2).  Application of different levels of vermicompost and nitroxin had a positive effect on the total weight of corm, average flower length and stigma fresh yield. Thus, the results showed that 5 L.ha-1  nitroxin and 10 t.ha-1 vermicompost had a significant impact on replacement corm characteristics and flower yield of saffron.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2019</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>139</start>
					<end>154</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75264_8f86cb5cc947176a20de3243676da9da.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.90069.1240</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Evaluation of saffron flower and corm yield affected by different maternal corm weight and sowing depth</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohsen</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Razavian</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc. of Agroecology, College of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parviz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rezvani Moghaddam</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Agrotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ghorban Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Asadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, College of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In order to study the effects of different weights of mother corm and sowing depth on flower and corm yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.), an experiment was conducted as a factorial layout based on complete randomized block design with three replications at the Agricultural Research Station, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran during 2015-2016 growing seasons. The experimental treatments were all combination of four mother corm weights (4-6, 6.1-8, 8.1-10 and 10.1-12 g) and three planting depths (10, 15 and 20 cm). In the first year, criteria such as flower and corms yield were evaluated, and in the second year only flower yield were recorded. The result revealed that in both years the interaction between corm weight and planting depths was significant on most traits of the studied flower. Flower, stigma and style yield significantly increased by increasing corm weight and planting depth. The maximum dry stigma yield was obtained in 10.1-12 g corm weight and 20 cm planting depth which was 0.1095 and 0.5393 g.m-2 in the first and the second year, respectively. The interaction between treatments was not significant on daughter corm but the individual effects of each treatment was significant. The higher corm yield (1181.6 g.m-2) was related to 10.1-12 g corm weight treatment. Deeper planting (20 cm) produced the high corm yield (938.86 g.m-2). Eventually, the high excellence of yield in corm weight and planting depth treatments of higher, we recommend corms with higher weight and deeper sowing depth for cultivating saffron.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2019</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>155</start>
					<end>170</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_62311_ac22b8e4e37eabd6add0f00de15cb6ed.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.93391.1250</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Effect of cow manure on yield and morphological and physiological characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) under salinity stress</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Asghari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Student, Department of Agronomy, Gorgan Branch, Islamic Azad University, Gorgan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammadreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Dadashi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Agronomy, Gorgan Branch, Islamic Azad University, Gorgan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">razavi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Seed and Plant Improvement Recearch Departement, Khorasan Razavi Agricultural and Natural Resources Research Center, Agricultural Research,Education &amp; Extension organization,mashhad,Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Feizi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor Crop Ecology Faculty of Agriculture and Natural Resource University of TorbatHeydarieh, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">saed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">bakhtiari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Agronomy, Neyshabur Branch, Islamic Azad University, Neyshabur, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In order to study the effects of salinity stress of irrigation water and different amounts of cow manure on morphological and physiological characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.), an experiment was conducted during 2015-16 in the Jalagh Rokh Torbat Heidarieh area. The treatments were consisted of four levels of irrigation water salinity as the main factor (1, 4, 7 and 10 dS.m-1) and cow manure (sub factor) in four levels including control (without fertilizer), 20, 40 and 60 (t.ha-1) that were split plot in a randomized complete block design with three replications. The studied traits included fresh weight and numbers of flowers, fresh and dry weights of stigma, leaf chlorophyll content, proline content, diameter, fresh and dry weights of corm. The results of analysis of variance showed that the effects of different amounts of cow manure and salinity stress levels on all traits were significant at 1% level. In this experiment, the highest fresh weight and numbers of flowers, fresh and dry weight of the stigma were obtained in the control salinity treatment (without salinity) and 60 (t.ha-1) of cow manure. With increasing salinity levels up to 7 dS.m-1, chlorophyll a, b and total chlorophyll increased and then decreased sharply. The results showed a significant increase in proline with increasing salinity levels. In addition, diameter and fresh and dry weights of the corms decreased with increasing salinity levels, so that their maximum and minimum values ​​were obtained in salinity control (without salinity) and 10 dS.m-1 respectively. The results showed that the use of cow manure reduces the effects of salinity stress on corm yield and yield of saffron flower.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2019</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>171</start>
					<end>184</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66475_5e5f1346a9d33a3d908937a82ac44e81.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.98710.1257</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Evaluation of environmental impacts of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) agroecosystems in the Khorasan province affected as field size by using life cycle assessment</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Soroor</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khorramdel</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Agrotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nassiri Mahallati</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Agrotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Moallem Banhangi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. student, Department of Agrotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abdollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mollafilabi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Research Institute of Food Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Life cycle assessment (LCA) is a well-known and accurate methodology for comparison of environmental impacts of activities including different agricultural management systems. Since the used inputs have an important role in environmental pollution and greenhouse gas emissions, LCA have been extensively applied for crop species. This study was conducted to assess the environmental impact of saffron production systems based on field area (&lt;0.5, 0.5-1 and &gt;1 ha) in the Khorasan-e Razavi province using LCA methodology. The amounts of utilized agricultural inputs from the first year to the sixth year were collected by means of a questionnaire (13 fields from each area). In this regard, four phases, which are goal and scope definition, inventory analysis, impact assessment and interpretation, were designed to assess life cycle index with ISO14044 procedure. Functional unit were considered as one kg of flower. Three main categories as impacts on environment including global warming, acidification and eutrophication (terrestrial and aquatic) were defined. Finally, an index -called environmental index (EcoX) was calculated. Cronbach&#039;s alpha was used assessing the reliability of the questionnaire. The results showed that the Cronbach&#039;s alpha was computed with α=%84. The average values for global warming, acidification and eutrophication terrestrial and aquatic categories were calculated with115.41±53.41 kg CO2 equiv. / one kg flower yield, 0.35±0.16 kg SO2 equiv./ one kg flower yield, 0.58±0.27 kg NOx equiv./ one kg flower yield and 0.20±0.09 kg PO4 equiv./ one kg flower yield, respectively. The largest share of greenhouse gas emissions in the global warming category was related to CH4. The maximum emission of pollutants in acidification, eutrophication terrestrial and eutrophication aquatic categories was related to NH3. The results revealed that, field area affected the amounts of utilized agricultural inputs and environmental impacts as flower yield. Eutrophication and climate change categories had more sensitivity and affected as intensification based on field area. Therefore, one of the appropriate approaches to mitigate and decline the environmental impacts of agricultural production is achieving higher economical yield per unit of area by increasing resource use efficiency.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2019</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>207</start>
					<end>225</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75281_2fecda66df5d8ced60885a16c70ef100.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.129172.1296</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Study the effects of some fertilizer and irrigation managements in adaptation and development of saffron cultivation in arid regions</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahmoud</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Gholami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Student of Agronomy - Crop Physiology Field, Department of Agronomy, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kafi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor Department of Agronomy, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamid reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khazaie</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor Department of Agronomy, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abarghouei</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Payam-e-Nour University. Daneshjoo BLV. Yazd.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In order to improve saffron yield and modify crop pattern in arid areas, a split plot experiment was conducted based on randomized complete block design with three replication in a research field in Charkhab village of Yazd province during 2013-2016. Main plots included; irrigation in three levels (100%, 75% and 50% of ETc), and sub plots were seven fertilizer management including; control (zero fertilization), applying 10 t/ha cow manure(10M), 10 t/ha vermicompost by spreading(10V), 10 t/ha vermicompost buried under planting corm rows (10RV), 5 t/ha vermicompost buried under planting corm rows(5RV), spraying 10 L/ha Humaster Saffron fertilizer for 1 (SH) or 2 (CH) times after flowering. Results showed that as water stress decreased from 75% to 50% ET, flower yield and its relative traits, bud number per plant, leaf dry weight, highest corm weight, total corm weight and effective corm weight decreased significantly in each treatment. Among fertilizer managements, 10M treatment increased growth characteristics of saffron plants in the first year while 10RV and CH treatments showed better performance in the second and third years. Generally, results showed that using Humaster-Saffron fertilizer showed advantages in comparison with other treatments due to its potassium and humic acid content and possibility of its easy application in every year and along with irrigation water.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2019</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>207</start>
					<end>225</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75221_d049fcaa314ac4612d0e49c13ae0789c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.106340.1272</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The effect of organic and biological fertilizers on the quantitative and qualitative characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) at the climate of Ardabil region</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Bagher</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Alizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Student in Agroecology, Dept. of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, Shahrood University of Technology. Shahrood,  Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Makarian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, College of Agriculture, Shahrood University of Technology. Shahrood, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ebadi Khazine Ghadim</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, University of Mohaghegh Ardabili. Ardabili, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ebrahim</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Izadi-Darbandi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad-IRAN</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Gholami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad-IRAN</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In recent years, in order to produce organic products and reduce environmental problems, organic and biological fertilizers are used to increase soil fertility, eliminate the nutritional needs and to improve of plants growth. In order to evaluate the effect of organic and biological fertilizers on qualitative and quantitative traits of saffron, a field experiment was carried out as split plots based on a randomized complete block design with three replications at the Research Farm of  Ardebil Agricultural Research Center during two growing seasons of 2015-2016 and 2016- 2017. Treatments included three levels of organic fertilizers: vermicompost (10 t.ha-1), manure (25 t.ha-1) and control in the main plots, and plant growth promoting rhizobacteria in four levels including, control, Azotobacter sp.PTCC 1658, Pseudomonas aeroginosa, Bacillus subtilis and the combination of biofertilizer (A. sp. PTCC 1658+ B. subtilis+ P. aeroginosa( in sub plots. Bio fertilizers were inoculated on the saffron corms before sowing in the first year and were applied mixed with irrigation water in the second year. The results indicated that the interaction effects of organic and biological fertilizers increased the fresh weight of flowers, dry and wet yield of stigma and style and qualitative compounds including crocin (Color factor), picrocrocin (Taste factor) and safranal (Perfume factor) compared to control. So that, the application of manure and vermicompost in combination with the total of bio-fertilizers (A. sp. PTCC 1658+ B. subtilis+ P. aeroginosa), increased the dry matter of stigma from 0.86 kg.h-1 to 2.93 and 2.7 kg.h-1 respectively. By using manure fertilizer with biofertilizers, picrocrocin, safranal and crocin, were increased 73, 77 and 83 percent compared to the control respectively. Based on this experiment results, the combined use of organic and biological fertilizers in addition to reducing the environmental pollution, can enhance qualities and quantities of yield of saffron through synergistic effects.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2019</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>227</start>
					<end>244</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_73904_1df7076806b2318e7d4baad968aa2f92.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.109405.1274</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Estimating environmental costs of greenhouse gas emissions in saffron production systems (case study: Torbat Hadiriyah)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nezamoleslami</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc. Student, Department of Agricultural Economics, Faculty of Agriculture,Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Lili</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abolhassani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate  Professor, Department of Agricultural Economics, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Naser</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shahnoushi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Agricultural Economics, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Karbasi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Agricultural Economics, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Dariush</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khezrimotlagh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Statistics, Miami University, United States of America.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The production of saffron as one of the most expensive agricultural and pharmaceutical products in the world has a high comparative advantage. Considering the importance of producing this product in Iran as an important non-oil export commodity and its role as a strategic, the estimation of the indirect environmental costs associated with the emission of its pollutants is necessary. The purpose of this study was to calculate the environmental costs of greenhouse gas emissions in Saffron farms in the Torbat Hadiriyah township. In order to collect  data (such as chemical fertilizers, irrigation, labor, animal manure and gasoline) a questionnaire and face-to-face interviews were used in the crop years 2017 and 2018.To investigate the relationship between good and bad output, the distance function is used as a parametric form of the translog. The results show that global warming potential (GWP) was calculated to be 369/24 kg equivalent to CO2 per kilogram of saffron straw. Also the environmental cost of greenhouse gases, methane, nitrous oxide and carbon dioxide per hectare, according to a seven-year period, are: 77/888/700, 212/742/820 and 76/289/200 Rials, respectively. In total, the production of saffron over a seven-year period imposes an expense of 366/920/720 million Rials on the environment regarding the emission of greenhouse gases. This is equal to 52/417/240 million Rials for a crop year in per one hectare. About 21% of the income earned per hectare. In the end, it is suggested that the tax policy on fertilizers and soil tillage systems be reviewed and analyzed to reduce the environmental impacts of the saffron production system.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2019</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>275</start>
					<end>283</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66473_4d09e265ba3f534874eda96b4f7d6411.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.101427.1264</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating the effective socioeconomic factors on unsustainable system of high-density planting of saffron (case study: Gonabad county)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammadreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ramezani</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc. Student of Agricultural Economics Discipline, Economics and Development Faculty, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rafiee</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Agricultural Economics Discipline, Economics and Development Faculty, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Norouzi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Student of Agricultural Economics Discipline, Economics and Development Faculty, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Gonabad township in the Khorasan Razavi province is one of the largest saffron producers in Iran. Unfortunately, the yield of saffron farms in Gonabad has decreased drastically in recent years. Evidence and the opinions of agricultural engineers suggest that high-density planting can be considered as one of the main reasons of yield decrease. With high-density planting, the operation period of saffron farms will start sooner. However, it will decrease the length of operation period tremendously. Furthermore, the farm will not be suitable for saffron cultivation for a long time. Therefore, the present study was conducted with the aim of investigating the effect of high-density planting on yield of saffron farms and determining the socio-economic factors affecting unsustainable system of high-density planting. Data of the first 6-years of farms (2011-2016) were collected and in order to analyze the data, a two-stage Heckman model which include a Probit model and a linear regression model was used. Our study findings show that farmers&#039; age, awareness towards factors that reduce yield of saffron farms, and attending training courses are three factors that have a negative and significant impact on planting density. In other words, these three factors could prevent planting of saffron in high density. Farmers&#039; income and their level of education are two factors which are considered to have a positive and significant impact on planting density. Finally, crop insurance does not have a significant impact in either one of the two models. Therefore, we strongly recommend that farmers should be warned of factors that cause yield decreases throughout training courses. Also, we recommend using of the experience of old and experienced farmers in order to prevent planting saffron in high densities.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2019</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>275</start>
					<end>283</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66474_c7d566c90c1acea7b76a7d8ad6e6eb05.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.100615.1261</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Analysis of social psychological effects (job security and quality of work life) on increasing job satisfaction of saffron farmers in Bafgh city</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Razieh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jamaati Ardakani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Lecturer, Department of Psychology, Ardakan University.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2019</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Job security and improving the quality of work life are among the factors that can affect the job satisfaction of saffron workers and increase their productivity. The present study aims to analyze the social psychological effects (job security and quality of work life) on increasing job satisfaction of saffron Farmers in Bafgh city, which is done using correlation analysis. The statistical population consists of all saffron Farmers in Bafgh city. Using Morgan table, a sample of 205 individuals is selected through simple random sampling and tested by job security, work life quality and job satisfaction questionnaires. Data are analyzed by Pearson correlation coefficient and linear regression. The results show that job security and quality of work life have a significant relationship with job satisfaction (p &lt; .01). Also, job security and quality of work life significantly predict job satisfaction (p &lt; .001). The results of the research indicate that these two variables (job security and quality of work life) are important variables for optimal job satisfaction among saffron farmers. Therefore, it is suggested that the relevant agricultural organizations try to create a safe, interesting and stimulating working environment to increase commitment, creativity and hard work. Keywords: job security, quality of work life, job satisfaction, saffron farmers.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2019</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>275</start>
					<end>283</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66476_60ba87740c2bd52c6b5df2b72dd3811e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2018.95424.1253</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>