<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1396</YEAR>
<VOL>5</VOL>
<NO>2</NO>
<MOSALSAL>16</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>88</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی برخی دلایل کاهش عملکرد زعفران در طی 30 سال اخیر (مقاله مروری)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Some reasons for saffron yield loss over the last 30 years period (Review Article)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران (Crocus sativus L.) گیاهی چند ساله است که اساساً در نواحی خشک و نیمه‌خشک کشور رویش دارد. علیرغم سازگاری زعفران به این نواحی، ارزیابی روند تغییرات سطح زیر کشت زعفران در طی 30 سال اخیر نشان می‌دهد که کشت این محصول افزایش قابل‌توجهی یافته است؛ به‌طوری که زعفران هم‌اکنون در 21 استان کشور در سطحی معادل 88 هزار هکتار کشت می­شود. با این وجود، در بین سال­های 1360 تا 1393 عملکرد زعفران به ازای هر واحد سطح زیر کشت کاهش محسوسی یافته است. به‌طوری که از 1/5 کیلوگرم در سال 1360 به 2/3 کیلوگرم در سال 1393 رسیده است. کاهش عملکرد زعفران از جنبه­های متفاوتی اتفاق افتاده و اساساً متأثر از عواملی مانند سوء مدیریت در بخش کشاورزی، اقتصادی، فرآوری پس از برداشت و نیز خشک‌سالی‌های اخیر بوده است. در صورت عدم توجه به عوامل ذکرشده، عملکرد زعفران در سال­های آینده نیز ممکن است بیش از پیش کاهش یابد. کاهش عملکرد زعفران در طی 30 سال اخیر، لزوم ارائه یک برنامه جامع از سوی نهادهای مرتبط با زعفران شامل دانشگاه­ها، مؤسسات تحقیقاتی و نیز سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی را بیش از پیش مورد تأکید قرار می­دهد. همچنین جهت تدوین و توسعه این برنامه، اتخاذ سیاست­های دولت جهت برنامه­ریزی و تصویب بودجه موردنیاز ضروری به نظر می­رسد. در این مقاله مروری ابتدا سعی بر آن است تا مجموعه دلایل مرتبط با کاهش عملکرد زعفران مورد مطالعه قرار گیرد. ارائه راهکارهای لازم در ارتباط با این دلایل، هدف بعدی در مقاله می­باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) is a perennial plant which grows basically in arid and semi-arid regions of Iran. Despite saffron’s adaptation to these regions, the assessment of changes in cultivation area over the last 30 years reveals that cultivation of this crop has sharply increased. According to the available statistics, there are 21 provinces where saffron is cultivated on about 84,000 hectares of land. Nonetheless, saffron yield per unit area has aggressively fallen from 5.1 kg ha-1 in 1982 to 3.2 kg ha-1 in 2015. Saffron yield loss can be caused by several factors, such as mismanagement in agriculture section, economics and post-harvest processing as well as the recent droughts. Lack of attention to these factors could lead to further decline in saffron yield in the future. The saffron yield loss over the last 30 years is an alert for saffron-related institutions such as the universities, research centers and Agricultural Research, Education and Extension Organization (AREEO) to pay more attention to this crop and prepare more comprehensive programs. In developing these programs, the importance of government policies for planning and approving enough budget is to be highlighted. In this review, first we focus on the reasons for saffron yield loss during the last 30 years and then we try to provide some solutions in relation to these reasons.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>107</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>122</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کوچکی</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Koocheki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>akooch@ferdowsi.um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کرباسی</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Karbasi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>arkarbasi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سیدی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Seyyedi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>پژوهشکده زعفران، دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>پژوهشکده زعفران، دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>se.seyyedi@stu-mail.um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تولید زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خشک‌سالی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سطح کشت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abasi, K, Almassi, M., Borghaei, A., and Minaee, S. 2014. Modeling of yield estimation for the main crops in Iran based on mechanization index. Journal of Agricultural Machinery 4: 344-351. (In Persian with English Summary).##Aghaei, M., and Rezagholizadeh, M. 2011. Iran&#039;s comparative advantage in production of saffron. Journal of Agricultural Economics and Development 25:121-132. (In Persian with English Summary).##Agricultural statistics. 2015. Department of Planning and Economy (from 2002 to 2015). http://www.maj.ir/.##Alizadeh, A., Sayari, N., Ahmadian, J., and Mohamadian, A. 2009. Study for zoning the most appropriate time of irrigation of saffron (Crocus Sativus) in Khorasan Razavi, north and southern provinces. Journal of Water and Soil 23: 109–118. (In Persian with English Summary).##Anonymous. 2015.  http://www.aftabir.com/news/view.##Atefi, M., Akbari Oghaz, A.R., and Mehri, A. 2013. Drying effects on chemical and sensorial characteristics of saffron. Iranian Journal of Nutrition Sciences and Food Technology 8: 201-208. (In Persian with English Summary).##Azizi-Zohan, A.A., Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A., and Sepaskhah, A.R. 2009. Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) production as influenced by rainfall, irrigation method and intervals. Archives of Agronomy and Soil Science 55: 547–555.##Badri, S.B., Eftekhari, A.R., Salmani, M., and Behmand, D. 2011. The role of family farming system on sustainable rural Development (Case study: Ghir and Karzin County - Fars province). Human Geography Research Quarterly 76: 33-48. (In Persian with English Summary).##Bani Asadi, M., and Varmaziyari, H. 2015. Investigation of effective factors on agricultural labor productivity, income distribution and poverty in rural areas of Iran. Journal of Village and Development 17: 1-23. (In Persian with English Summary).##FAO, 2014. Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations. http://www.faostat.fao.org.##Gresta, F., Lombardo, G.M., Siracusa, L., and Ruberto, G. 2008. Effect of mother corm dimension and sowing time on stigma yield, daughter corms and qualitative aspects of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in a Mediterranean environment. Journal of the Science of Food and Agriculture 88: 1144–1150.##Kafi, M., Rashed Mohasel, M.H., Koocheki, A., and Mollafilabi, A. 2002. Saffron, Production and Processing. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Press. (In Persian).##Keykhamoghadam, P., Kamgar Haghighi, A., Sepaskhah, A., and Zand Parsa, S. 2013. Determination of Single and dual crop coefficients and potential evapotranspiration of developed saffron. Journal of Agricultural Meteorology 1: 1–9. (In Persian with English Summary).##Khazaei, M., Monfared, M., Kamgar Haghighi, A.A., and Sepaskhah, A.R. 2013. The trend of change for weight and number of saffron corms as affected by irrigation frequency and method in different years. Journal of Saffron Research 1: 48–56. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki A., Nassiri Mahallati, M., Zarea Fizabadi, A., and Jahanbin, M. 2005. Diversity of cropping systems in Iran. Pajouhesh and Sazandegi 63: 70–83. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2015. Relationship between nitrogen and phosphorus use efficiency in saffron (Crocus sativus L.) as affected by mother corm size and fertilization. Industrial Crops and Products 71: 128–137.##Koocheki, A., Ganjeali, A., and Abbassi, F. 2007. The effect of duration and condition of incubation, weight of mother corms and photoperiod on corm and shoot characteristics of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 4: 315–331. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Nassiri, M., Alizadeh, A., and Ganjali, A. 2010. Modelling the impact of climate change on flowering behaviour of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 7: 583–594. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Mollafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2012a. Effects of high corm planting density and applying manure on flower and corm yields of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). 4th International Saffron Symposium: Advanced in Saffron Biology Technology and Trade. 22–25 October 2012.##Koocheki, A., Seyyedi, S.M., and Gharaei, S. 2016. Evaluation of the effects of saffron-cumin intercropping on growth, quality and land equivalent ratio under semi-arid conditions. Scientia Horticulturae 201: 190–198.##Koocheki, A., Seyyedi, S.M., and Jamshid Eyni, M. 2014. Irrigation levels and dense planting affect flower yield and phosphorus concentration of saffron corms under semi-arid region of Mashhad, Northeast Iran. Scientia Horticulturae 180: 147–155.##Koocheki, A., Siahmarguee, A., Azizi, G., and Jahani, M. 2011. The effect of high density and depth of planting on agronomic characteristic of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) and corms behavior. Journal of Agroecology 3: 36–49. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Tabrizi, L., Jahani, M., and Mohammad Abadi, A.A. 2012b.  An evaluation of the effect of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm planting rate and pattern on the crop&#039;s performance. Iranian Journal of Horticultural Science 42: 379-391.  (In Persian with English Summary).##Kumar, R., Singh, V., Devi, K., Sharma, M., Singh, M.K., and Ahuja, P.S. 2009. State of art of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) agronomy: a comprehensive review. Food Reviews International 25: 44–85.##Mazaheri, D., and Majnon Hoseini, N. 2007. Fundamental of Agronomy. Tehran University Press. (In Persian)##Mazloumi, M.T., Taslimi, A., Jamshidi, E., Atefi, M., Haj Seyyed Javadi, N., Komeili Phanoud, R., Seyyed Ahmadian, F., Falahatpishe, H., Chobdar, N., Hadian, Z., Golestan, B., and Shafighi, S.A. 2007. Comparison of the effects of vacuum oven-, freeze-, solar-, and microwave-drying with traditional drying methods on the qualitative characteristics of Ghaen saffron. Iranian Journal of Nutrition Sciences and Food Technology 2: 69-76. (In Persian with English Summary).##Ministry of Agriculture Jihad, 2015. Agriculture Jahad Mechanization Development Center. http://www.agmdc.ir.##Molina, R.V., García-Luis, A., Coll, V., Ferrer, C., Valero, M., Navarro, Y., and Guardiola, J.L. 2004. Flower formation in the saffron Crocus (Crocus sativus L.). The role of temperature. Acta Horticulturae 650 (First International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Biotechnology): 39–48.##Molina, R.V., Valero, M., Navarro, Y., Guardiola, J.L., and Garcia-Luis, A. 2005. Temperature effects on flower formation in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Scientia Horticulturae 103: 361–379.##Motiei Langroudi, S.H., Rezvani, M., Faraji Sabokbar, H.A., and Khajeh Shahkouhi, A. 2011. Analysis of sustainability of family and rural production cooperative farming systems (Case study: Agh-Ghala Township: Golestan province). Iranian Journal of Agricultural Economics and Development Research 41: 323-333. (In Persian with English Summary).##Naderi Mayoun, R. 2012. The influence of agricultural mechanization on yield and waste reduction production of rice (The Atrak village Shalikaran of Moneh and Samal ghan of north Khorasan). Quarterly Journal of Human Geography 3: 1-16. (In Persian with English Summary).##Nassiri Mahallati, M., Koocheki A., Rezvani Moghaddam P., and Beheshti A. 2008. Agroecology. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Press. (In Persian).##Nassiri Mahallati, M., Koocheki, A., Boroumand Rezazadeh, Z., and Tabrizi, L. 2007. Effects of corm size and storage period on allocation of assimilates in different parts of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 5: 155–166. (In Persian with English Summary).##Rabiei, H., Salarpour, M., and Sabouhi Sabon, M. 2013. Effect of macroeconomic variables on the Iran agricultural sector income. Journal of Agricultural Economics Researches 4: 65-85. (In Persian with English Summary).##Renau-Morata, B., Nebauer, S.G., Sánchez, M., and Molina, R.V. 2012. Effect of corm size, water stress and cultivation conditions on photosynthesis and biomass partitioning during the vegetative growth of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Industrial Crops and Products 39: 40–46.##Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Koocheki, A., Molafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2013a. Effect of biological and chemical fertilizers on replacement corm and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Crop Sciences 15: 234–246. (In Persian with English Summary).##Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Koocheki, A., Molafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2013b. The effects of different levels of applied wheat straw in different dates on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) daughter corms and flower initiation criteria in the second year. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 1: 55–70. (In Persian with English Summary).##Sabet Teimouri, M., Kafi, M., Avarseji, Z., and Orooji, K. 2010. Effect of drought stress, corm size and corm tunic on morphoecophysiological characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in greenhouse conditions. Journal of Agroecology 2: 323–334. (In Persian with English Summary).##Salimifar, M., and Norouzi, R. 2008. A changing trend of socio-economic inequalities in rural and urban areas in Iran (1966-2006). Knowledge and Development 24: 37-61. (In Persian with English Summary).##Sepaskhah, A.R., and Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A. 2009. Saffron irrigation regime. International Journal of Plant Production 3: 1–16.##Sepaskhah, A.R., Dehbozorgi, F., and Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A. 2008. Optimal irrigation water and saffron corm planting intensity under two cultivation practices in a semi-arid region. Biosystems Engineering 101: 452 – 462##Taslimi, A., Mazloumi, M.T., and Jamshidi, E. 2007. Comparison of the effects of solar drying and vacuum processes with traditional methods on properties of saffron. Iranian Journal of Nutrition Sciences and Food Technology 3: 9-18. (In Persian with English Summary).##Torkamani, J., and Azin Far, Y. 2006. The effect of exports and mechanization growth on labor employment in agriculture. Iranian Journal of Agricultural Sciences 36: 1223-1231. (In Persian with English Summary).##Yarami, N., Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A., Sepaskhah, A.R., and Zand-Parsa, S. 2011. Determination of the potential evapotranspiration and crop coefficient for saffron using a water-balance lysimeter. Archives of Agronomy and Soil Science 57: 727–740.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر وزن بنه مادری و محلول‌پاشی برگی بر عملکرد گل و بنه دو توده زعفران (.Crocus sativus L) ایرانی و اسپانیایی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Effect of mother corm weight and foliar application of nutrients on flower and corm yield of Spanish and Iranian saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>اندازه بنه مادری، مدیریت تغذیه­ای و نوع بنه از مهم‌ترین عوامل در تعیین عملکرد و کیفیت زعفران ((Crocus sativus L. به شمار می­روند. به‌منظور بررسینقش وزن بنه مادری و محلول­پاشی برگی بر عملکرد گل و بنه دو توده زعفران ایرانی و اسپانیایی آزمایشی طی دو سال زراعی (94-1393، 93-1392) در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد انجام شد. آزمایش به­صورت فاکتوریل و در قالب طرح بلوک­های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار انجام گرفت. تیمارهای آزمایش شامل نوع بنه در دو سطح (ایرانی و اسپانیایی)، وزن بنه مادری در سه سطح (8 - 1، 15- 1/8 و 23- 1/15 گرم) و محلول­پاشی برگی در دو سطح (صفر و 7 درصد کود ­کامل شامل فسفیت پتاسیم و بیومین) بود. بر اساس نتایج آزمایش، با افزایش وزن بنه مادری، تعداد گل در هر مترمربع، وزن گل­تر و عملکرد کلاله خشک زعفران به‌طور معنی­داری افزایش یافت. علاوه بر این، استفاده از بنه مادری بزرگ‌تر به‌طور معنی­داری منجر به افزایش تعداد بنه دختری و عملکرد کل بنه­های دختری شد. اثر محلول­پاشی برگی نیز بر تعداد گل در واحد سطح و عملکرد کلاله خشک زعفران معنی­دار بود، ولی بر تعداد کل بنه دختری در واحد سطح تأثیر معنی­داری نداشت. اثر نوع بنه بر تعداد گل در واحد سطح، وزن­تر گل، وزن خشک (کلاله + خامه) و وزن خشک بنه معنی­دار بود؛ بنابراین، بیشترین تعداد گل (6/48 در مترمربع)، وزن­تر گل (3/24 گرم در مترمربع) و وزن خشک کلاله + خامه (25/0 گرم در مترمربع) مربوط به اندازه بنه مادری 1/15 تا 23 گرم و کمترین مقدار مربوط به اندازه بنه کمتر از 8 گرم بود. همچنین بیشترین تعداد گل (7/43 در متر­مربع)، وزن‌تر گل (8/21 گرم در متر مربع) و وزن خشک گل (23/0 گرم در مترمربع) طی دو سال آزمایش مربوط به بنه­های ایرانی بود. بر اساس نتایج، استفاده از بنه­های مادری ایرانی با وزن مناسب جهت کاشت (بیش از 15 گرم) همراه با محلول­پاشی برگی می­تواند در افزایش عملکرد گل و بنه زعفران مفید باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The corm size, nutrient management and corm type are the most important factors that may affect the quantitative and qualitative characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). In order to study the effect of mother corm size and nutrient foliar application on flower and corm yield of Spanish and Iranian Saffron landrace, an experiment was conducted with factorial arrangement based on randomized complete block design with three replications during two growing seasons (2013-14 and 2014-15) at the Faculty of Agriculture of the Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran .The saffron corm type was considered in two levels (Iranian corm and Spanish corm), mother corm size were in three levels (1- 8g, 8.1- 15g, 15.1- 23g) and nutrient foliar application were in two levels (control and sprayed leaves with 7% micro and macro nutrients). The results showed that the effect of different mother corm size, corm type and nutrient foliar application on the number of flowers, flower fresh and dry weight (stigma + style) were significant. The highest number of flowers (48.6 flower.m-2), flower fresh weight (24.3 g.m-2) and saffron (stigma + style) dry weight (0.25 g.m-2) were obtained in 15.1-23g mother corm size, and the lowest were obtained in 8g &gt; mother corms. In contrast, nutrient foliar application had not significant effect on total produced daughter corms. However, the highest number of flowers (43.7 flower.m-2), flower fresh weight (21.8 g.m-2) and stigmas dry weight (0.23 g.m-2) were obtained from Iranian corms in the second year. Hence, the use of appropriate weight for planting Iranian corms (over 15 g) with nutrient of foliar application can be useful for increasing the performance of the flowers and saffron corms.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>123</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>131</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صحابی</Family>
						<NameE>hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>sahabi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری اکولوژی گیاهان زراعی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری اکولوژی گیاهان زراعی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hsahabi1351@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جهان</Family>
						<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jahan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>jahan@ferdowsi.um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کوچکی</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kochaki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>akooch@ferdowsi.um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نصیری محلاتی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nasiri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mnassiri@ferdowsi.um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بنه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تغذیه برگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلاله</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Amirshekari, H., Sorooshzadeh, A., Modaress Sanavy, A., and Jalali Javaran, M. 2007. Study of effects of root temperature, corm size, and gibberellin on underground organs of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Biology 19: 5-18. (In Persian with English Summary).##Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A., Nassiri Mahallati, M., and Rezvani Moghaddam, P. 2006. Evaluation of quantitative relationships between saffron yield and nutrition (on farm trial). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 3: 1-14. (In Persian with English Summary).##Ghobadi, F., Ghorbani Javid, M., and Sorooshzadeh, A. 2015. Effects of planting date and corm size on flower yield and physiological traits of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) under Varamin plain climatic conditions. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (4): 265-276. (In Persian with English Summary).##Gresta, F., Lombardo, G.M., Siracusa, L., and Ruberto, G. 2008. Effect of mother corm dimension and sowing time on stigma yield, daughter corms and qualitative aspects of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in a Mediterranean environment. Journal of Food Science and Agriculture 88: 1144-1150.##Hosseini, M., Sadeghi, B., and Aghamiri, S.A. 2004. Influence of foliar fertilization on yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Acta Horticulturae 650: 207-209.##Khorasani, R., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Hassanzadeh Aval, F. 2013. Effect of concentration, time and frequency of foliar applications on vegetative growth and production of replacement corms of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) by using a complete nutrient solution. In: Proceeding of the 2nd National Conference on the Newest Scientific and Research Findings on Saffron. Torbat Heydariyeh, Iran, October 30, 2013, p.40. (In Persian).##Koocheki, A., Ganjeali, A., and Abbassi, F. 2007. The effect of duration and condition of incubation, weight of mother corms and photoperiod on corm and shoot characteristics of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 4: 315–331. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Jahani, M., Tabrizi, L., and Mohammad Abadi, A.A., 2011. Investigation on the Effect of biofertilizer, chemical fertilizer and plant density on yield and corm criteria of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Water and Soil 25: 196-206. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A.R., Fallahi, H.R., Amiri, M.B., and Ehyaei, H.R. 2015. Effects of humic acid application and mother corm weight on yield and growth of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Agroecology. (In Press) (In Persian with English Summary).##Kumar, R., Singh, V., Devi, K., Sharma, M., Singh, M.K., and Ahuja, P.S. 2009. State of the art of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) agronomy: A comprehensive review. Food Review International 25: 44-85.##Molina, R.V., Valero, M., Navarro, Y., Guardiola J.L., and Garcia-Luice, A. 2005. Temperature effects on flower formation in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Scientia Horticulture 103: 361-379.##Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Koocheki, A., Molafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2013. Effect of biological and chemical fertilizers on replacement corm and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Crop Science 15: 234-246.##Sabet Teimouri, M., Kafi, M., Avarsaji, Z., and Orooji, K. 2010. Effect of drought stress, corm size and corm tunic on morphoecophysiological characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in greenhouse conditions. Journal of Agroecology 2: 323- 334. (In Persian with English Summary).##Sadeghi, B. 2012. Effect of corm weight on Saffron flowering. Proceedings of the 4th International Saffron Symposium. Keshmir, Iran.##Sadeghi, B., Hosseini, M., Masroori, M., and Mollafilabi, A. 2013. Effect of nutrition in bed on enlargement of saffron corm. Research Project for Institute of Food Science and Technology. Khorasan Razavi, Iran. 23p. (In Persian).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی خصوصیات رشدی بنه‌های دختری زعفران تحت تأثیر نظام‌های کشاورزی رایج و ارگانیک</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Evaluation of replacement corms growth criteria of saffron in response to different organic and conventional production systems</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در زراعت زعفران، تولید و استفاده از بنه­های مادریِ دارای وزن مناسب یکی از مهم­ترین عوامل تأثیرگذار بر میزان گلدهی گیاه می­باشد. در همین راستا این تحقیق با هدف بررسی تأثیر نظام­های مختلف کم­نهاده، متوسط نهاده و پرنهادة ارگانیک و رایج بر رشد بنه­های دختری زعفران در طی یک دورة رشد یک­سالة گیاه از مهرماه 1394 تا اردیبهشت ماه سال 1395 در قالب طرح بلوک­های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار به اجرا درآمد. به منظور انطباق تیمارهای آزمایشی با قوانین کشاورزی ارگانیک، طول دورة گذاری معادل با 24 ماه قبل از کاشت در این پژوهش در نظر گرفته شد و در طی آن از مصرف نهاده­های ممنوعه پرهیز شد. بر اساس نتایج تجزیة واریانس اثر تیمارهای آزمایشی بر اکثر صفات مربوط به رشد بنه­های دختری معنی­دار بود. مقایسة میانگین تیمارها نشان داد که میزان تفاوت­ها در درون هر نظام کاشت بسیار ناچیز، ولی مقدار تفاوت بین دو نظام کاشت رایج و ارگانیک قابل توجه بود. وزن کل بنه­های موجود در هر کلون و تعداد جوانه­های گل­دهنده به ازای هر بنه در نظام­های کاشت ارگانیک به‌طور متوسط حدود 40 درصد بیشتر از نظام­های کاشت رایج بود. مقادیر متوسط وزن تک­بنه نیز برای سیستم­های ارگانیک و رایج به ترتیب 75/4 و  54/2 گرم تعیین شد. در نظام کاشت ارگانیک درصد بنه­های دختری با وزن کمتر از 5 گرم کمتر از نظام کاشت رایج بود (70 درصد در مقابل 84 درصد)، در حالی­که در نظام کاشت مذکور درصد بنه­های دختری دارای وزن 5 تا 10 گرم (5/14 در مقابل 13 درصد) و بیش از 10 گرم (16 در مقابل 3 درصد) بیشتر از سیستم کاشت رایج بود. متوسط تعداد جوانة گل دهنده در هر بنه همبستگی معنی­داری با وزن کل بنه­های موجود در هر کلون (**58/0)، میانگین وزن تک بنه (**64/0) و نیز تعداد بنه­های ریز (**57/0-) و درشت (**61/0) موجود در هر کلون نشان داد. بر اساس ضرایب همبستگی، میانگین وزن تک بنه نیز ارتباطی قوی با تعداد بنة موجود در هر کلون (**55/0-)، وزن بنه­های موجود در هر کلون (**73/0) و نیز تعداد بنه­های ریز (**89/0-) و درشت (**81/0) موجود در هر کلون داشت. در مجموع، استفاده از مدیریت ارگانیک در مقایسه با نظام زراعی رایج تأثیر مطلوبی بر بهبود صفات رشدی بنه­های دختری زعفران به خصوص میانگین وزن بنه و تعداد جوانه­های دارای پتانسیل گلدهی اعمال نمود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The use of corms with appropriate weight is one of the main factors in the flowering of saffron. Thus, the impacts of six organic (OS) and conventional (CS) production systems on the growth of saffron replacement corms was studied during one growth cycle from October 2015 up to May 2016 in this experiment. The experiment was conducted based on a randomized complete block design with three replications and six treatments including low, medium and high input organic systems as well as low, medium and high input conventional systems. A transition period of 24 months was considered in the chosen field before corm planting. Based on the results of an analysis of variance, the effect of experimental treatments was significant on the growth properties of most replacement corms (RC). The results of means comparison revealed that the differences within each organic or conventional system were insignificant but they were found to be considerable between the two OS and CS production systems. Total RC weight per clone and the number of flowering buds per RC in the OS production system were on the average 40% more than that of the CS production system. The amount of mean RC weight for OS and CS was 4.75 and 2.54g, respectively. The percent of RC with weight of less than 5g in the CS production system was higher than that of the OS production system (70 vs. 84%), while the percent of RC in 5-10g (13 vs. 14.5%) and more than 10g (3 vs. 15.7%) categories in the OS production system were more than that of the CS production system. The mean value of flowering buds had a significant correlation with the total RC weights per clone (+0.58**), mean RC weight (+0.64**), number of small RC (-0.57**) and number of large corm per clone (+0.61**). In addition, there was a significant correlation between the mean RC weight with the number of RC per clone (-0.55**), the RC weight per clone (+0.73**), the number of small RC (-0.89**) and the number of large RC per clone (+0.81**). Overall, the employment of OS had a significant positive effect on the growth of saffron replacement corms especially on mean corm weight and the number of flowering buds.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>133</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>147</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدعلی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بهدانی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Behdani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه پژوهشی زعفران، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه پژوهشی زعفران، دانشکده کشاورزی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mabehdani@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زمانی</Family>
						<NameE>Gholamreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zamani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>gzamani@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمید رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فلاحی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamid-reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Fallahi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه پژوهشی زعفران، دانشکذه کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه پژوهشی زعفران، دانشکذه کشاورزی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hamidreza.fallahi@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدحسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سیاری زهان</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hassan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sayyari Zohan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه پژوهشی زعفران، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه پژوهشی زعفران، دانشکده کشاورزی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>msayari@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صمدزاده</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Samadzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مربی گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مربی گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>arsamadzadeh@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جوانة گل‌دهنده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کشاورزی رایج پرنهاده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گلدهی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظام ارگانیک کم‌نهاده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>وزن بنه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF></REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مدیریت آبیاری زعفران با استفاده از اعمال سیاست‌های قیمتی و مقداری آب (مطالعه موردی: حوضه آبریز نیشابور)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Irrigation management of saffron by using the price and quantity policies of water (case study: Naishabur basin)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>کاهش منابع آبی، روند افزایشی وقوع خشکسالی­ها و صدمات سنگین آن به کشور، بیش از پیش استفاده کارآمد از این منبع را ضرورت می­بخشد. هدف این مطالعه، ارزیابی اثرات سیاست­های گوناگون کاهش میزان آب مصرفی و افزایش قیمت هر مترمکعب آب بر الگوی­کشت محصول زعفران می­باشد. داده­های مورد نیاز پژوهش با مصاحبه­ی حضوری در میان100 بهره‌بردار مناطق کشاورزی دشت رخ و نیشابور سال 1391 به‌دست آمد. انتخاب مزارع نمونه  با استفاده از نمونه­گیری تصادفی، انجام و مدل برای هر دو منطقه محاسبه شد. نتایج حاصل از الگوی برنامه­ریزی ریاضی مثبت نشان داد که با 20 درصد صرفه‌جویی در مصرف آب در دشت رخ و 30 درصد در دشت نیشابور می­توان الگوی کشتی مشابه با مقادیر داده­ی واقعی در سطح مزرعه برای محصول زعفران دست یافت. همچنین با کاهش مقدار آب، ارزش اقتصادی آب افزایش نشان داد. دو برابر نمودن قیمت هر متر مکعب آب مصرفی نیز در میزان مصرف آب و سطح زیر کشت محصول تأثیری نشان­­ نداد و تنها منجر به کاهش سود شد. لذا پیشنهاد می­گردد برای صرفه جویی منابع آبی، علاوه بر تشخیص زمان دقیق آبیاری و میزان مناسب آن برای محصول زعفران که می­تواند اثرات منفی آبیاری بیش از حد و بی­موقع را بر عملکرد این محصول کاهش دهد و در مدیریت بهینه آب مؤثر باشد، سیاست­های کاهش مقدار آب در دسترس نیز در برنامه­ریزی سیاست­گذاران قرار بگیرد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The reduction in water resources, increased occurrence of droughts and heavy damages to the country make the more efficient use of this resource very important. The aim of this study is to evaluate the effects of various policies of reduction of water consumption and the effect of any increase in the price of each cubic meter of water on saffron cultivation pattern. The data for the research was obtained by interviews done with 100 farmers in agricultural areas of the Rokh and Naishabur plain in 2012. The sample farms were selected using random sampling, the study was conducted and the models were calculated for both areas. The results of positive mathematical programming model showed that by 20 percent savings in water consumption in the Rokh Plain and 30% in the Naishabur plain, we can achieve cultivating a pattern similar to those which have achieved the previous values at the farm level for saffron. Also, by reducing the amount of water, the economic value of water increased. Doubling the price per cubic meter of water used in crop cultivation and water consumption does not lead to lower profit. Therefore, it is recommended to save water resources. In addition, precise time detection irrigation and the right to saffron can have negative effects when excessive irrigation is done and reduce the performance of this product. Effective and optimal water management policies to reduce the amount of available water is also planned to be presented to the policy makers.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>149</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>160</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سمیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شیرزادی لسکوکلایه</Family>
						<NameE>somayeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>shirzadi laskookalayeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکترای اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه زابل</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکترای اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه زابل</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shirzady24@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صبوحی صابونی</Family>
						<NameE>mahmoud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>sabuhi sabuni</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>msabuhi39@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احمد علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کیخا</Family>
						<NameE>Ahmad Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Keikha</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه زابل</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه زابل</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>keikha@uoz.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>کامران</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>داوری</Family>
						<NameE>Kamran</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Davari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مهندسی آب، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مهندسی آب، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>kamran.davary@chmail.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>برنامه‌ریزی ریاضی مثبت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حوضه‌آبریز نیشابور</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت آبیاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Agricultural Jihad Organization of Khorasan Razavi Province. 2011. Statistical Yearbook 2010. Department of Planning and Economic Affairs Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Agricultural Statistics. Available at http:// http://www.koaj.ir .##Arfini, F., and Donati, M., and Paris, Q. 2003. &#039;A national PMP model for policy evaluation in agriculture using micro data anad administrative information, &#039;Contributed paper to international conference: Agricultural Policy Reform and The WTO: Where are we heading? Capri (Italy), 23-26 June 2003.##Bakhshi, d., and Paykani, Gh. 2011. Policy simulation support direct payments in agriculture subdivision (application programming approach and maximum entropy proof). Iran Agricultural Development Economics 42 (4): 501-511. (In Persian).##Balali, H., Khalilian, S., and Ahmadian, M. 2010. Evaluation examine the role of water pricing in the agricultural sector on the balance of groundwater resources. Journal of Agricultural Economics and Development 24 (2): 185-194. (In Persian with English Summary).##Barikani, A., and Khalilian, S. 2011. Dynamic management of groundwater in the agricultural sector: A case study of Qazvin Plain. The fourth conference of Iran Water Resources Management, Tehran. Iran. 3-4 May 2011, p. 50-63. (In Persian with English Summary).##Borges, k., Santana, D., Melo, B., and Santos, C. 2010. Rendimento de polpa e morfometria de frutos e sementes de pitangueira-do-cerrado. Revista Brasileira de Fruticultura, Jaboticabal 32 (2): 471-478.##Ehsani, M., Dashti, Gh., Hayati, B., and Ghahramanzade, M. 2010. Estimating the economic value of water Qazvin network. The use of the dual approach. Journal of Agricultural Economics and Development 25 (2): 237- 245. (In Persian with English Summary).##Howitt, R., Medellin-Azura, J., MacEwan, D., and Lund, J. 2012. Calibrating disaggregate economic models of agricultural production and water management. Environmental Modeling and Softaware 38: 244-258.##Howitt, R.E., Medellin-Azuara, J., and MacEwan, D. 2009. Estimation the economic impacts of agricultural yield related changes for California. Final Paper, a paper from California Climate Change Center 19 (3): 16-17.## Jitea, L.M. 2011. Appropriate methods for evaluating the agricultural policies, consequences at farm level. Notulae Botanicae Horti Agrobotanici Cluj-Napoca 39 (1): 126-133.##Karamatzade, A., Chizari, A.H., and Mirzaee, A. 2006. Determine the economic value of agricultural water by using an optimal combination of agriculture and horticulture cultivation pattern (case study: Barzou Shirvan dam). Journal of Agricultural Economics and Development  14 (54): 35-60. (In Persian).##Medellin-Azuara, J., Howitt, R.E., and Harou, J.J. 2012. Predicting farmer responses to water pricing, rationing and subsidies assuming profit maximizing investment in irrigation technology. Agricultural Water Management 108: 73-82.##Moghaddasi, R., Bakhshi, A., and Daneshvar, M. 2009. Analyzing the effect of water and agriculture policy strategies: An Iranian experience. American Journal of Agricultural and Biological Sciences 4 (3): 206-214.##Mohseni, A., and Zibaei, M. 2009. Analysing consequences of increasing acreage of colza in Namdan plain of Fars province: An application of positive mathematical programming. Science and Technology of Agriculture and Natural Resources 13 (47): 773-784. (In Persian).##Mohsenpour, R., and Zibaei, M. 2010. Determination of optimal crop patterns using nonlinear programming and deficit irrigation strategies under Dorudzan Dam. Journal of Agricultural Economics and Development 18 (71): 1-22. (In Persian with English Summary).##Paymozd, Sh., Morid, S., and Moghadasi, M. 2010. Comparison of non-linear optimization and a system dynamics approaches for agricultural water allocation (A case study: Zayande Rud Basin). Journal of Irrigation and Drainage 1 (4): 44-52. (In Persian with English Summary).##Razavi Khorasan Regional Water Company, 2011. Available at http://www.khrw.ir/SC.php? type.##Sabouhi, M., Soltani, Gh., and Zibaei, M. 2007. Effect of irrigation water price change on private and public interests by using positive mathematical programming model. Journal of Agricultural Science and Technology 21 (1): 53-71.( In Persian with English Summary).##Shajari, Sh., Barikani, A., and Amjadi, A. 2009. Water demand management with the use of water pricing policy in JAHROM groves, Case Study of Shahani date. Journal of Agricultural Economics and Development 17 (65): 72-55. (In Persian).##Trade Promotion Organization. 2009. Saffron red gold. By Babak Afqhahi. Available at http:// http:// http://farsi.tpo.ir/.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی امکان تولید زعفران (.Crocus sativus L) در سیستم کشت عمودی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Study a possibility of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) production in vertical culture</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>با وجود این­که زعفران یکی از گران­ترین گیاهان دارویی در جهان است، اما تاکنون در مورد تولید آن در کشت عمودی مطالعه­ای انجام نشده است. بنابراین رشد و تولید زعفران در دو سیستم کشت متفاوت (عمودی و افقی) در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس در سال زراعی 1393-1392 مورد مقایسه قرار گرفت. بنه­های زعفران در سیستم کشت عمودی در کیسه­های پارچه­ای در یک مکعب که ابعاد هر وجه آن 5/1 در 5/1 متر بود کشت شدند. در کشت افقی در مزرعه بنه­ها در سه کرت که مساحت هر کرت 25/2 مترمربع بود کشت شدند. نتایج نشان داد که در سال اول رشد تعداد گل، وزن خشک گل و وزن خشک کلاله در واحد سطح در سیستم کشت عمودی به ترتیب 10 گل، 34/347 و 56 میلی­گرم در مترمربع بود که به­طور معنی­داری تقریباً سه برابر بیشتر از کشت افقی بود. در مقابل در سیستم کشت افقی تعداد و وزن خشک بنه­های دختری (به ترتیب 4/2 عدد و 36/0 گرم در بوته)، وزن خشک بنه­های مرکزی (88/0 گرم در بوته) و وزن خشک برگ و ریشه به‌طور معنی­داری بیشتر از کشت عمودی بود، ولی حداکثر طول برگ در کشت عمودی نسبت به کشت افقی بیشتر بود. لذا می‌توان نتیجه‌گیری کرد که از سیستم کشت عمودی برای افزایش محصول زعفران در سال اول استفاده کرد؛ اما باید در مورد بهبود وزن خشک بنه­های دختری جانبی و وزن خشک بنه­های مرکزی در این سیستم تحقیق بیشتر انجام داد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In recent years many research studies have been carried out to use a vertical planting system for production of some plants. Although saffron is one of the most expensive spices in the word, there is no investigation about saffron production in a vertical planting system. Therefore, the growth and production of saffron plant in two different systems (vertical and horizontal) were studied in the agricultural research field of the Tarbiat Modares University during the 2013-2014 growing seasons. In the vertical system, saffron corms were planted in fabric bags containing potting soil. The fabric bags were hanged on a cube of metal with an area of each side of the cube being equal to 2.25 square meters. In the horizontal system, the corms were planted in three plots with the area of each plots being 2.25 square meters. The results showed that in the vertical planting system, the number of flowers, flower dry weight and dry weight of stigma per unit area of land (10 flower, 347.34 and 0.56 mg respectively) were significantly higher than those obtained in the horizontal culture (They were almost three times higher) .In contrast, the numbers and dry weight of lateral corms (2.4 corm and 0.36 g respectively) and the dry weight of apical corm (0.88 g) in the horizontal system were significantly greater than those obtained in the vertical system. Dry weight of leaf and root were significantly greater in the vertical system. The total number of buds and leaves were more in the horizontal culture. However, the maximum leaf length of the vertical planting system was higher than those of the horizontal system.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>161</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>173</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>لورین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>علی احمد</Family>
						<NameE>Lorin</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>ali ahmad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، گروه زراعت، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>lorin.ali55@ymail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سروش زاده</Family>
						<NameE>ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>sorooshzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>soroosh@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مختصی بیدگلی</Family>
						<NameE>ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>mokhtassi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mokhtassi@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تعداد بنه‌های دختری جانبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>وزن خشک بنه‌های دختری جانبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>وزن خشک بنه‌های مرکزی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Behnia, M. 2008. Effect of planting methods and corm density in saffron (Crocus sativus L.) yield in Damavand region. Pajouhesh and Sazandegi 79: 101-108. (In Persian with English Summary).##Behnia, M.R. 1991. Saffron Cultivation. University of Tehran Press, Iran. (In Persian).##Benschop, M. 1993. Crocus. In: A. De Hertogh and M. Le Nard, (eds.), The Physiology of Flower Bulbs. Elsevier Science Publishers, Amsterdam, Netherlands. p. 257–272.##De Villiers, J.J. 2008. The influence of different production systems, planting densities and levels of shading on the yield, quality and growth potential of ‘Chandler’ strawberry plants (Fragaria ananassa) grown in coir. M.S.C. Thesis of the Stellenbosch University, South Africa.##Despommier, D. 2009. The rise of vertical farms. Scientific American 301 (5): 80-87.##Durner, E.F. 1999. Winter strawberry production using conditioned plug plants. Horticultural Science 34: 615-616.##El Behairy, U.A., Abou Hadid, A.F., Medany, M.A., and Awad, M.M. 2001. The effect of different cultivars, orientation, and soilless culture systems on production and quality of strawberries. Acta Horticulturae (ISHS) 548: 59-64.##Javadzadeh, S.M. 2011. Prospects and problems for enhancing yield of saffron (Crocus sativus) in Iran. International Journal of Agriculture Research and Review 1 (1): 21–25.##Kafi, M., Rashed, M.H., Koocheki, A., and Mollafilabi, A. 2002. Saffron, Technology, Cultivation and Processing. Center of Excellence for Special Crops, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Publication, Iran. (In Persian).##Koocheki, A., Siahmarguee, A., Azizi, G., and Jahani, M. 2011a. The effect of high density and depth of planting on agronomic characteristic of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) and corms behavior. Journal of Agroecology 3 (1): 36–49. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Tabrizi, L., Jahani, M., and Mohammad Abadi, A.A. 2011b. An evaluation of the effect of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm planting rate and pattern on the crop&#039;s performance. Iranian Journal of Horticultural Sciences 42 (4): 379–391. (In Persian with English Summary(.##Koocheki, A., Tabrizi, L., Jahani, M., Mohammad Abadi, A.A., and Mahdavi Damghani, A. 2009. Peformance of saffron (Crocus sativus) under different planting patterns and high corm density. 3rd International Symposium on Saffron. Forthcoming Challenges in Cultivation, Research and Economics. Korokos, Kozani, Greece, 20-23th May 2009.##Moayedi Shahraki, E., Jami Al-Ahmadi, M., and Behdani, M.A. 2010. Study of energy efficiency of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Southern Khorasan. Journal of Agroecology 2 (1): 55–62. (In Persian with English English Summary).##Morgan, L. 2006. Hydroponic strawberry production (A technical guide to the hydroponic production of strawberries). Suntec (NZ) Limited, Tokomaru, Newzealand.##Nassiri Mahallati, M., Koocheki, A., Boroumand Rezazadeh, Z., and Tabrizi, L. 2007. Effects of corm size and storage period on allocation of assimilates in different parts of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 5 (1): 155-166. (In Persian with English Summary).##Perez, D.C. 2004. Effect of plant density and initial crown size on growth, development and yield in strawberry cultivars Elsanta and Bolero. Journal of Horticultural Science and Biotechnology 79 (5): 739-746.##Rostami, M., and Mohamadi, H. 2013. Effects of planting date and corm density on growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) under Malayer climatic conditions. Journal of Agroecology 5 (1): 27-38. (In Persian with English Summary).##Sepaskhah, A.R., and Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A. 2009. Saffron irrigation regime. International Journal of Plant Production 3 (1): 1–16.##Seyyedi, A., Ebadi, A., Babalar, M., and Saeedi, B. 2010. Effect of planting density on yield and fruit quality of strawberries Selva in soilless culture vertical. Journal of Horticultural Science 24 (1): 1-6. (In Persian with English Summary).##Tammaro, F. 1999. Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Italy. In: M. Negbi (ed.). Saffron: Crocus sativus L. Harwood Academic Publishers, Australia. p. 53–61.##Tavakkol-Afshari, J., Brook, A., and Mousavi, S.H. 2008. Study of cytotoxic and apoptogenic properties of saffron extract in human cancer cell lines. Food Chemical Toxicology 46 (11): 3443-3447.##Yanez, P., Ohno, H., and Ohkawa, K. 2005. Temperature effects on corm dormancy and growth of Zephyr elegant. Scientia Horticulture 105 (1): 127-138.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>رتبه‌بندی عوامل مؤثر بر بسته‌بندی زعفران از دید مصرف‌کنندگان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Ranking factors affecting the packing of saffron from the perspective of consumers</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>بسته­بندی به عنوان یک ابزار برای شناخت و تمایز محصول نقش بسیار مهمی در تصمیم خرید مصرف­کنندگان ایفا می­نماید و از آن می­توان برای ایجاد مزیت رقابتی استفاده نمود. زعفران یکی از محصولات مهم کشاورزی است که بسته­بندی مطابق با تقاضای مصرف­کنندگان موجب افزایش فروش و رضایت­مندی خریداران می­گردد. لذا هدف اصلی این مطالعه رتبه­بندی عوامل مؤثر بر بسته­بندی از دید مصرف­کنندگان زعفران در شهر مشهد می­باشد. اطلاعات این پژوهش، در قالب 99 پرسشنامه که در سال 1394 از سوی مصرف­کنندگان زعفران شهر مشهد پاسخ داده شده، جمع‌آوری شده است. برای رتبه­بندی عوامل مؤثر بر بسته­بندی این محصول، از روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی استفاده شده است. نتایج مطالعه نشان داد که ارائه اطلاعات مربوط به مواد مغذی زعفران و درج استانداردهای داخلی و بین­المللی، بر ترجیحات مصرف­کنندگان بیشترین تأثیر را دارند. همچنین، نتایج رتبه­بندی گزینه­ها نیز نشان داد که راهبرد توجه به نام تجاری درج شده روی بسته­بندی از نظر مصرف­کنندگان دارای بیشترین اهمیت است. لذا، درج عناصر اطلاعاتی روی بسته­بندی می­تواند شیوه مناسبی برای تمایز نام تجاری و افزایش ارزش آن باشد. با توجه به نتایج مطالعه، به تولیدکنندگان و عرضه­کنندگان زعفران پیشنهاد می­گردد که در طراحی بسته­بندی به ویژگی­ها و عناصر اطلاعاتی بیشترین توجه را داشته باشند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Packaging is a tool for recognition and differentiation of product and it plays a crucial role in consumers&#039; purchasing decisions, and it can be used to create competitive advantages. Saffron is one of the most important agricultural crops in Iran and its packaging in accordance with consumer demand increases sales and satisfaction of the consumers. Therefore, the main objective of this study is to rank the factors affecting the packaging from the perspective of consumers of saffron in Mashhad. Data was collected in the form of 99 questionnaires that have been answered by the consumers of saffron in Mashhad in 2015. Analytic hierarchy process (AHP) was used to rank these factors. The results showed that labeling information about internal and international standards and saffron nutrients on the package have the greatest impact on consumer preferences. Also, the results of the ranking alternatives indicated that attention to the brand labelled on the packing is the most important issue from the perspective of the consumers. Hence, labelling information elements on the package can be a good way for brand differentiation and increasing its value. According to the results, it is recommended that producers and suppliers of saffron pay more attention to features and information elements in package design.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>175</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>184</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آرش</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>دوراندیش</Family>
						<NameE>Arash</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Dorandish</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>adourandish@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امیر حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>توحیدی</Family>
						<NameE>Amirhossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tohidi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amirhossein_tohidi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پریسا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>علیزاده</Family>
						<NameE>Parisa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Alizadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>parisa.alizadeh67@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>استانداردهای داخلی و بین‌المللی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل سلسله مراتبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ترجیحات</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نام تجاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aday, M.S., and Yener, U. 2014. Understanding the buying behaviour of young consumers regarding packaging attributes and labels. International Journal of Consumer Studies 38 (4): 385-393.##Al-Harbi, K.M.A.S. 2001. Application of the AHP in project management. International Journal of Project Management 19 (1): 19-27.##Ampuero, O., and Vila, N. 2006. Consumer perceptions of product packaging. Journal of Consumer Marketing 23 (2): 100-112.##Cameron, K., Beare, M., McLaren, R., and Di, H. 1998. Selecting physical, chemical, and biological indicators of soil quality for degraded or polluted soils. In Proceedings of World Congress of Soil Science 16.##Ebadzadeh, H.R. 2015. Agricultural statistics: Ministry of Jihad Agriculture.##Eldesouky, A., Pulido, A.F., and Mesias, F.J. 2015. The Role of Packaging and Presentation Format in Consumers’ Preferences for Food: An Application of Projective Techniques. Journal of Sensory Studies 30 (5): 360-369.##Fernqvist, F., Olsson, A., and Spendrup, S. 2015. What’s in it for me? Food packaging and consumer responses, a focus group study. British Food Journal 117 (3): 1122-1135.##Gadioli, I.L., Pineli, L.D.L.D.O., Rodrigues, J.D.S. Q., Campos, A.B., Gerolim, I.Q., and Chiarello, M.D. 2013. Evaluation of packing attributes of orange juice on consumers&#039; intention to purchase by conjoint analysis and consumer attitudes expectation. Journal of Sensory Studies 28 (1): 57-65.##Ghodosi, M., Mohtashami, T., Motavalli, M., and Sheddati, Sh. 2016. Identification and prioritization of marketing mix elements affecting the export of saffron from the perspective of exports. Journal of Saffron Agronomy and Technology 3 (4): 285-296. (In Persian).##Gomez, M., Martin‐Consuegra, D., and Molina, A. 2015. The importance of packaging in purchase and usage behaviour. International Journal of Consumer Studies 39 (3): 203-211.##Koutsimanis, G., Getter, K., Behe, B., Harte, J., and Almenar, E. 2012. Influences of packaging attributes on consumer purchase decisions for fresh produce. Appetite 59 (2): 270-280.##Mohammadian, F., Shahnoushi, N., Ghorbani, M., and Aghel, H. 2009. Select potential crop pattern based on AHP model (case study: plain Torbatejam). Journal of Sustainable Agriculture 1 (19): 169-187. (In Persian).##Momeni, M., and Sharifi Salim, A. 2011. MADM Models and Softwares (AHP, ANP, TOPSIS and PROMETHEE). Publisher Authors, Tehran, 218pp. (In Persian).##Nasrollahzadeh, A., Jafari, S.M., and Akbari, E. 2014. Survey of challenges and problems of packaging Saffron. Iranian Journal of Science and Technology Packaging 5 (20):18-29. (In Persian).##Pezeshkirad, Gh., and Feali, S. 2010. Challenges and solutions for the processing, marketing and export of saffron: application of Delphi method. Agricultural Economics 4 (1): 137-157. (In Persian).##Pohekar, S.D., and Ramachandran, M. 2004. Application of multi-criteria decision making to sustainable energy planning-a review. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 8 (4): 365-381.##Saaty T.L. 2005. Theory and Applications of the Analytic Network Process: Decision Making with Benefits, Opportunities, Costs, and Risks. RWS publications.##Saaty, T.L. 1996. Decision making with dependence and feedback: The analytic network process. RWS Publications, Pittsburg, USA.##Saaty, T.L. 2008. Decision making with the analytic hierarchy process. International Journal of Services Sciences 1 (1): 83-98.##Saaty, T.L., and Vargas, L.G. 1987. Uncertainty and rank order in the analytic hierarchy process. European Journal of Operational Research 32 (1): 107-117.##Shahin, A., and Kalij, Y. 2009. Evaluation of distributors by analytical hierarchy process-The case of Paak dairy company. Iranian Journal of Engineering Education 10 (40): 151-171. (In Persian).##Silayoi, P., and Speece, M. 2004. Packaging and purchase decisions: An exploratory study on the impact of involvement level and time pressure. British food journal 106 (8): 607-628.##Silayoi, P., and Speece, M. 2007. The importance of packaging attributes: a conjoint analysis approach. European Journal of Marketing 41 (11/12): 1495-1517.##Wang, E. 2013. The influence of visual packaging design on perceived food product quality, value, and brand preference. International Journal of Retail and Distribution Management 41 (10): 805-816.##Westerman, S.J., Sutherland, E.J., Gardner, P.H., Baig, N., Critchley, C., Hickey, C., Mehigan, S., Solway, A., and Zervos, Z. 2013. The design of consumer packaging: Effects of manipulations of shape, orientation, and alignment of graphical forms on consumers’ assessments. Food Quality and Preference 27 (1): 8-17.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مطالعه امکان تولید آفلاتوکسین B1 در زعفران و محصولات حاصل از آن</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A study on the possibility of production of aflatoxin B1 in saffron</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران از با ارزش‌ترین محصولات دارویی استان‌های خراسان­رضوی و جنوبی است که در تمام مراحل برداشت، انتقال و انبارداری ممکن است به گونه‌های مختلف قارچ Aspergillus آلوده گردد. یکی از توکسین­های ناشی از این آلودگی، آفلاتوکسینB1 است. این پژوهش با هدف بررسی تولید این توکسین توسط قارچ Aspergillus flavus در مراحل مختلف برداشت، انتقال و انبارداری زعفران صورت گرفت. بافت‌های خشک و مرطوب زعفران و بافت‌های برنج آغشته شده به عصاره زعفران، با A. flavusتلقیح گردیده و تولید آفلاتوکسین در آن‌ها به روش کروماتوگرافی TLC بررسی گردید. قارچ آسپرژیلوس توانست در شرایط مختلف این پژوهش، تمام بافت‌های تلقیح شده را آلوده نماید. مقادیر مختلف آفلاتوکسینB1 در تیمارهای مختلف به‌ استثنای زعفران‌های نگه‌داری شده در شرایط خشک (شاهد)، تولید گردید. در بافت‌های برنج آغشته به عصاره زعفران نیز آفلاتوکسین  B1تولید گردید ولی میزان آن نسبت به تیمار برنج بدون زعفران، کمتر بود. بر اساس نتایج این پژوهش، بافت‌های زعفران به‌سرعت در شرایط گرم و مرطوب به گونه‌های مختلف آسپرژیلوس آلوده می‌گردند. زعفران خشک و مرطوب تلقیح شده با قارچ آسپرژیلوس، پس از مدتی حاوی مقدار زیادی آفلاتوکسین بود. میزان آفلاتوکسین تولیدی در بافت‌های زعفران، ارتباط مستقیم با رطوبت محیط و بافت داشت. با افزایش رطوبت، آلودگی بافت به قارچ بیشتر و تولید توکسین نیز افزایش یافت. آغشته کردن موادغذایی به زعفران هرچند میزان تولید آفلاتوکسین B1 را کاهش داد ولی تولید آن را متوقف نکرد. نتایج این پژوهش نشان داد که بسته‌بندی زعفران قبل از خشک شدن کامل بافت یا نگه‌داری آن‌ها در شرایط رطوبت بالا، خطر آلودگی به قارچ A. flavus و تولید آفلاتوکسین در آن‌ها را افزایش می‌دهد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron is the most important medicinal plants in the Khorasan Razavi and South Khorasan provinces, Iran. Aspergillus species can infect saffron tissues during harvesting, storage and transportation. Aflatoxin B1 is one of the important carcinogenic mycotoxin which is produced by Aspergillus species in saffron tissues. This study was carried out in order to investigate the production of aflatoxin B1 in saffron tissues from farm to food by TLC chromatography during the year 2015. Wet and dry saffron tissues and rice grains (with and without saffron extract) were inoculated with Aspergillus flavus spore suspensions. Production of Aflatoxin B1 in inoculated tissues was investigated by the TLC chromatography method. The results showed that the wet leaves and rice grains were infected with Aspergillus species very quickly. However, this process was very slow in dry tissues. Aflatoxin B1 was detected in all of the tested samples. The amounts of Aflatoxin B1 in the wet saffron tissues and rice grains were more than those found in dry tissues and saffron rice, respectively. The amount of Aflatoxin B1 had a direct correlation with moisture in the environment and the tissues. The contamination of the tissues and production of AflatoxinB1 were increased with increasing the amount of moisture. The results showed that the packaging of saffron before complete drying of its tissue or storing it in conditions with high humidity can increase the risk of infection with the Aspergillus species and production of Aflatoxin B1 in them. Based on our data, saffron can reduce Aspergillus infection and aflatoxin B1 production but not inhibit it. Saffron extract reduces Aspergillus infection and Aflatoxin B1 production in food and grains.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>185</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>194</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عباس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Abbas</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه گیاه پزشکی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه گیاه پزشکی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amohammadi@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سیمین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نجار</Family>
						<NameE>Simin</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Najjar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد بیماری شناسی گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد بیماری شناسی گیاهی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abbasmohammadi229@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فهیمه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سنگی کاظم آباد</Family>
						<NameE>Fahime</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sangi Kazem Abad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد بیماری شناسی گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد بیماری شناسی گیاهی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nasrin229@yahoo.co.in</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آلودگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آسپرژیلوس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>برنج</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توکسین‌های قارچی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کروماتوگرافی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Azzoune, N., Mokrane, S., Riba, A., Bouras, N., Verheecke, C., Sabaou, N., and Mathieu, F. 2016. Contamination of common spices by aflatoxigenic fungi and aflatoxin B1 in Algeria. Quality Assurance and Safety of Crops and Foods 8: 1-8.##Bayman, P., and Cotty, P.J. 1991. Vegetative compatibility and genetic diversity in the Aspergillus flavus population of a single field. Canadian Journal of Botany 69: 1707-1711.##Beheshti, H.R., Sadat Fakoor Janati, S., Feizy, J., and Asadi, M. 2014. Aflatoxin determination in saffron by high-performance liquid chromatography and immunoaffinity column clean-up. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 1: 102-111.##Davis, N.D., Diener, U.L., and Eldridge, D.W. 1966. Production of aflatoxins B1 and G1 by Aspergillus flavus in a semisynthetic medium. Applied Microbiology 14: 378-380.##Di Primo, P., Cappelli, C., and Katan, T. 2002. Vegetative compatibility grouping of Fusarium oxysporum f. sp. gladioli from saffron. European journal of plant pathology 108: 869-875.##Ellis, W., Smith, J., Simpson, B., Oldham, J., and Scott, P.M. 1991. Aflatoxins in food: occurrence, biosynthesis, effects on organisms, detection, and methods of control. Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition 30: 403-439.##Galvano, F., Galofaro, V., and Galvano, G. 1996. Occurrence and stability of aflatoxin M1 in milk and milk products: a worldwide review. Journal of Food Protection 59: 1079-1090.##Gock, M.A., Hocking, A.D., Pitt, J.I., and Poulos, P.G. 2003. Influence of temperature, water activity and pH on growth of somexerophilic fungi. International Journal of Food Microbiology 81: 11-19.##Hacibekiroglu, I., and Kolak, U. 2013. Aflatoxins in various food from Istanbul, Turkey. Food Addit Contam Part B Surveill 6: 260-264.##Hesseltine, C.W., Shotwell, O.L., Ellis, J.J., and Stubblefield, R.D. 1966. Aflatoxin formation by Aspergillus flavus. Bacteriological Reviews 30: 795-805.##Humans, I.W.G.o.t.E.o.C.R.t., Organization, W.H., and Cancer, I.A.f.R.o. 2002. Some traditional herbal medicines, some mycotoxins, naphthalene andstyrene. World Health Organization.##Júnior, D.P.L., Yamamoto, A.C.A., de Souza Amadio, J.V.R., Martins, E.R., do Santos, F.A.L., Simoes, S.d.A.A., and Hahn, R.C. 2012. Trichocomaceae: biodiversity of Aspergillus spp and Penicillium spp residing in libraries. The Journal of Infection in Developing Countries 6: 734-743.##Kafi, M., Koocheki, A., and Rashed, M.H. 2006. Saffron (Crocus sativus): Production and Processing. Science Publishers.##Martins, M.L., Martins, H.M., and Bernardo, F. 2001. Aflatoxins in spices marketed in Portugal. Food Addit Contam 18: 315-319.##Noorbakhsh, R., Bahrami, A.R., Mortazavi, S.A., Forghani, B., and Bahreini, M. 2009. PCR-based identification of aflatoxigenic fungi associated with Iranian saffron. Food Science and Biotechnology 18: 1038-1041.##Pawar, V., and Thaker, V. 2006. In vitro efficacy of 75 essential oils against Aspergillus niger. Mycoses 49: 316-323.##Richard, J.L. 2007. Some major mycotoxins and their mycotoxicoses—An overview. International Journal of Food Microbiology 119: 3-10.##Saeedizadeh, A. 2014. Identification of some saffron corm rot fungi and their control. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2: 205-213.##Scott, P.M., and Trucksess, M.W. 1996. Application of immunoaffinity columns to mycotoxin analysis. Journal of AOAC International 80: 941-949.##Shotwell, O.L., Hesseltine, C., Stubblefield, R., and Sorenson, W. 1966. Production of aflatoxin on rice. Applied Microbiology 14: 425-428.##Sinclair, J.B., and Dhingra, O.D. 1995. Basic plant pathology methods. CRC press.##Vahidi, H., Kamalinejad, M., and Sedaghati, N. 2002. Antimicrobial properties of Croccus sativus L. Iranian Journal of Pharmaceutical Research 1: 33-35.##Vinnere Pettersson, O., and Leong, S.l.L. 2011. Fungal Xerophiles (Osmophiles). eLS.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				