<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" "journalpublishing3.dtd">
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.90069.1240</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75264_8f86cb5cc947176a20de3243676da9da.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی تأثیر ورمی‌کمپوست و نیتروکسین بر ویژگی‏های بنه‏های دختری و عملکرد گل زعفران (Crocus sativus L.) سال دوم</article-title>
			        <subtitle>بررسی تأثیر ورمی‌کمپوست و نیتروکسین بر ویژگی‏های بنه‏های دختری و عملکرد گل زعفران (Crocus sativus L.) سال دوم</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>امینی فرد</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد حسین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیارگروه علوم باغبانی و مرکز پژوهشی گیاهان ویژه منطقه، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>افتاده فدافن</surname>
			            <given-names>علی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی سابق کارشناسی ارشد فیزیولوژی گیاهان دارویی، گروه باغبانی دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مرادی نژاد</surname>
			            <given-names>فرید</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیارگروه علوم باغبانی و مرکز پژوهشی گیاهان ویژه منطقه، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بهدانی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد علی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد گروه پژوهشی زعفران و مرکز پژوهشی گیاهان ویژه منطقه دانشگاه بیرجند، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2019</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>139</fpage>
			      <lpage>154</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>20</day>
			          <month>06</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>23</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75264.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75264.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>به منظور بررسی اثرات ورمی­کمپوست و نیتروکسین بر صفات بنه و عملکرد گل زعفران، آزمایشی در سال 95-1394 به صورت فاکتوریل بر پایه طرح پایه بلوک‏های کامل تصادفی، با سه تکرار در مزرعه دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند اجرا شد. تیمارهای آزمایش، شامل ورمی­کمپوست در چهار سطح (صفر، 5، 10 و 15 تن در هکتار) و نیتروکسین در سه سطح (0، 5 و 10 لیتر در هکتار)  به­صورت مصرف خاکی بودند. نتایج نشان داد، ورمی­کمپوست اثر معنی‏داری بر صفات بنه (وزن کل بنه، متوسط وزن ‏تر و خشک بنه دختری و قطر بنه دختری) داشت، به­طوری­که بیشترین وزن کل بنه در تیمار 15 تن در هکتار ورمی­کمپوست به­دست آمد. همچنین، نتایج سال دوم آزمایش، نشان­دهنده تأثیر معنی‏دار ورمی­کمپوست بر صفات گل (تعداد و عملکرد گل ، عملکرد تر و خشک کلاله) بود، به­طوری­که بیشترین عملکرد کلاله تر و خشک (63/1 و41/0 گرم در متر مربع به ترتیب) در سطح 10 تن در هکتار ورمی­کمپوست حاصل شد، و کمترین مقدار این صفات در تیمار شاهد (77/0 و21/0 گرم در متر مربع) مشاهده گردید. نیتروکسین نیز بر تعداد، عملکرد کل گل تر و عملکرد کلاله خشک تأثیرگذار بود. به­طوری­که، بیشترین میزان عملکرد کلاله خشک ( 36/0 گرم در متر مربع) در تیمار 10­ لیتر نیتروکسین در هکتار و کمترین مقدار این صفت در تیمار شاهد (24/0 گرم در متر مربع) حاصل گردید. اثرات متقابل نشان داد که، سطوح مختلف ورمی­کمپوست و نیتروکسین تأثیر معنی‏داری بر متوسط وزن کل بنه، عملکرد گل، عملکرد تر و خشک کلاله داشت. به­طورکلی، نتایج بیانگر تأثیر مثبت ورمی­کمپوست و نیتروکسین بر صفات بنه و عملکرد گل زعفران بود، به­طوری­که کاربرد 5 لیتر در هکتار نیتروکسین به همراه 10 تن در هکتار ورمی­کمپوست را می­توان برای این آزمایش توصیه نمود.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>عملکرد کلاله</kwd>
						<kwd>کود بیولوژیک</kwd>
						<kwd>کودآلی</kwd>
						<kwd>گیاه دارویی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Alavi Shari, J., Mohajeri, H., and Falaki, M.A. 1994. Effect of plant density on saffron yield. In: Proceedings of the Second Conference of Saffron and Medicinal Plants Cultivation, Gonabad, Iran, 8-9 Nov 1994, p.13-20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Abou-Hussein, S.D., El-Shoragy, T., and Abou-hadid, A.F. 2003. Effect of cattle and chicken manure with or without mineral fertilizers on tuber quality and yield of potato crop. Acta Horticulture 608: 95-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Alipur Miyandehi, Z., Mahmoudi, S., Behdani. A., and Sayyari, M.H. 2013. The study of animal manures, bio-chemical and corm size on yield and yield components of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) Saffron Research Journal 2: 73-84. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Amini, S., Maleki Farahani, S., and Shrgi, Y. 2014. Effect of organic fertilizers and biological (PGPR) on the quality of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) National Conference on Medicinal Plants, Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch Ayatollah Amoli, 11–14 March 2014, p. 91–96.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Amiri, M.E. 2008. Impact of animal manures and chemical fertilizers on yield components of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). American-Eurasian Journal of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences 4 (3): 274-279.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Arancon, N.Q., Edvards, C.A., Bierman, P., Metzeger, J.D, Lee, S., and Welc H.C. 2002. Effects of vermicomposts on growth and marketable fruits of field-grown tomatoes, pappers and strawberries. Pedobiologia 47 (5-6): 731-735.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Asadi Rahmani, H., and Samavat, S. 1999. Organic matter, its importance and its increase in soil. Technical Journal No. 425, Soil and Water Research Institute. Publishing of Karaj Agriculture Education. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Aytekin, A., and Acikgoz, A.O. 2008. Hormone and microorganism treatments in the cultivation of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) Molecular Plant 13 (5): 1135-1146.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Atiyeh, R.M., Arancon, N.Q., Edwards, C.A., and Metzger, J.D. 2000. Influence of earthworm-processed pig manure on the growth and yield of green house tomatoes. Bioresource Technology 75 (3): 175-180.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Bachman, G., and Metzger. 1998. The use of vermicomposting as a media amendment growth of tomatoes. Plant Nutrition 27 (1): 1107-1123.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A.R., Nassiri, M., and Rezvani Moghadam, P. 2005. Evaluation of quantitative relationships between saffron yield and nutrition (on farm trial). Iranian Journal of Field Crop Research 3 (1): 1-14. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Behdani, M.A. 2005. Ecological zoning and monitoring of yield fluctuations of saffron in Khorasan. Ph.D. in Agriculture (ecology of crops). Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Eldin, M.S., Elkholy, S., Fernandez, J.A., Junge, H., Cheetham, R., Guardiola, J.,  and Weathers, P. 2008. Bacillus subtilis FZB24 affects flower quantity and quality of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Planta Medica 13 (74): 16–20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Farokh Shahe, S. 2011. Effect of different levels of nitrogen and vermicompost organic fertilizer on onion yield. First National Conference on Environmental Conservation and Planning. 12–14 May 2011, p. 20–24.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Golzari, M. 2016. Effect of bio-fertilizer and mother corm weight on growth, flower and stigma yield and qualitative criteria of saffron. M.Sc dissertation, Faculty of Agriculture Birjand, University of Birjand, Iran. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Gutierrez-Manero, F.J., Ramos-Solano, B., Probanza, A., Mehouachi, J., Tadeo, F.R., and Talon, M. 2001. The plant-growth promoting rhizobacteria Bacillus pumilus and Bacillus licheniformis produce high amounts of physiologically active gibberellins. Physiologia Plantarum 111 (2): 206–211.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Hardtke, C. 2003. Gibberllin signaling: grass growing roots. Current Biology 13 (9): 366-367.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Haynes, R.J. 1996. Labile organic matter fraction as central components of the quality of agricultural soils. Advances in Agronomy 85 (1): 221- 261.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Shirani, H., Abolhasani Zeraatkar, M., Lakzian, A., and Akhgar, A. 2011. Decomposition rate of municipal wastes compost, vermicompost, manure and pistaco compost in different soil texture and salinity in laboratory condition. Journal Water Soil 25 (1): 84–93.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Jahan, M., and Jahani, M. 2007. The effects of chemical and organic fertilizers on saffron flowering. Acta Horticulture 739 (2): 81-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Jia, Y., Gray, V.M., and Straker, C.J.  2004. The influence of rhizobium and Arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi on nitrogen and phosphorus accumulation by Vicia  faba. Annals of Botany 94 (2): 251-258.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Kakhki Daneshvar, M., and Farahmand Gelyan, K. 2012. Review of interactions between ecommerce, brand and packaging on value added of saffron: A structural equation modeling approach. African Journal of Business Management 6 (26): 7924-7930.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Kolahkaj, Z. 2014. Effect of bacterria stimulus growth on the growth properties of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in the perennial fields. M.Sc, Faculty of agriculture, University of Birjand, Iran. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Jahani, M., Tabrizi, L., and Mohammadabadi, A.A. 2011. Investigation on the effect of biofertilizer, chemical fertilizer and plant density on yield and corm criteria of saffron (Crocus sativus L). Soil and Water 25 (1): 196-206. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Liuc, J., and Pank, B. 2005. Effect of vermicompost and fertility levels on growth and oil yield of Roman chamomile. Sciatica Pharmaceutical 46: 63-69.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Lucas Garcia, J., Agustin, P., Beatriz, R., Maria, P., and Francisco, J. 2004. Effect of inoculation of Bacillus licheniformis on tomato and pepper. Agronomie 24 (4): 169-176.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Martin, E.C., Slack, D.C., Tannksley, K.A., and Basso, B. 2006. Fresh and composted dairy manure applications on alfalfa yield and the environment in Arizona. Agronomy Journal 98 (1): 80-84.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Martin, J.P., Black, J.H., and Hawthorne, R.M. 1997. Influence of earthworm-processed pig manure on the growth and yield of greenhouse tomatoes. Bioresource Technology 75 (3): 175-180.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Mohamadzadeh, A.R., and Pasban, M. 2007. Effect of sources and levels of organic fertilizers on crop yield of saffron flowers. Tenth Congress of Soil Science, College of Agriculture and Natural Resources, Tehran University, 6-4 September 2007, p. 151–156.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Mrkovacki, N., and Milic, V. 2001. Use of Azotobacter chroococcum as potential useful in agricultural application. Annals of Microbiology 51 (2): 145-158.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Myers, B.J., Theiveyanathan, S., Obrien, N.D., and Bond, W.J. 1996. Growth and water use of Eucalyptus grandis and Pinus radiata plantations irrigated with effluent. Tree Physiology 16 (1-2): 211-219.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Nehvi, F.A., Khan, M.A., and Lone, A.A. 2010. Impact of microbial inoculation on growth and yield of saffron in Kashmir. Acta Horticulture 850 (31): 171-174.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Nieto, K.F., and Frankenberger, W.T. 1989. Biosynthesis of cytokinins by Azotobacter chroococcum. Soil Biology and Biochemistry 21 (7): 967-972.‏</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Omidi, H., Naghdibadi, H.A., Golzad, A., Torabi, H., and. Fotoukian, M.H. 2009. The effect of chemical and bio-fertilizer source of nitrogen on qualitative and quantitative yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal Medicinal Plant 8: 98–109. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Pandey, R. 2005. Management of meloidogyne incognita in Artemisia pallens with bio organics. Phytoparasitica 33 (3): 304-308.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Pierre Anoshi, E., Imam, E., and Jamali, R. 2010. Comparison of the effects of bio-fertilizers with chemical fertilizers on growth, yield and oil content of sunflower (Helianthus annuss L.) at different levels of drought stress. Journal of Agriculture Ecology 2 (3): 492-501. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Rezaian, S., and Paseban, M. 2007. The effect of micronutrients and manure fertilizers on the quantity and quality of Khorasan saffron. Second International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Technology, Iran, 8-9 April 2007, p.113-117.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani Moghaddam, B., Bkhshayy, S., Ghafouri, A., and Khrmdl, S. 2009. Quantitative characterization of biological fertilizers and vermicomposting on Savory herb, medicinal plants of Iran Industry Development Conference, Tehran, Iran, 8-9 March 2009, p. 223-225.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Rios, J.L., Recio, M.C., Giner, R.M., and Manez, S. 1996. An update review of saffron and its active constituents. Phototherapy Research 10 (3): 189-193.‏</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Sabti, M., Movahedi Naeini, S.A.R., Ghorbani Nasr Abadi, R., Roshani, Gh.A., Shahreyari, Gh., and Movahedi, M. 2009. Determination of the appropriate potassium extract in a clay soils with dominant clay and the effect of azotobacter and vermicompost on the concentration and amount of absorbed potassium and yield of wheat. Plant Production Research (Agricultural Sciences and Natural Resources) 16 (4): 59-76. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Salehi, A., Ghalavand, A., Sefidkon, F., and Asgharzadih, A. 2011. Effect of zeolite, Bacterial inoculum of vermicomposting concentration NPK elements essential oil content and essential oil yield in organic farming chamomile (Matricaria chamomilla L.). Journal of Medicinal and Aromatic Plants of Iran research 27 (2): 188-201. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Sepaskhah, A.R., and Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A. 2009. Saffron irrigation regime. International Journal of Plant Production 3 (1): 1-16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Sharma, S, Pradhan, K, Satya, S., and Vasudevan, P. 2005. Potentiality of earthworms for waste management and in other uses: a review. The Journal of American Science 1 (1): 4–16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Sundara, B., Natarajan, V., and Hari, K. 2002.Influence of phosphorus solubilizing bacteria on the changes in soil available phosphorus and sugarcane and sugar yields. Field Crops Research77 (1): 43-49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Teimori, S., Behdani, M.A., Ghaderi, M.G., and Sadeghi, B. 2013. Investigation on the effect of organic and chemical fertilizers on morphological and agronomic of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm criteria. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (1): 36–47. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Temperini, O., Rea, R., Temperini, A., Colla, G., and Rouphael, Y. 2009. Evaluation of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) production in Italy: Effects of the age of saffron fields and plant density. Food Agriculture and Environment 7 (1): 19-23.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Wu, S.C., Cao, Z.H., Li, Z.G., Cheung, K.C., and Wong, M.H. 2004. Effect of bio fertilizer containing N-fixer, P and K solubilizers and AM fungi on maize growth. Geoderma 125 (1-2): 155-166.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Zaller, J.G. 2007. Vermicompost as a substitute for peat in potting media: Effects on germination, biomass allocation, yields and fruit quality of three tomato varieties. Scientia Horticulturae 112 (2): 191-199._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.93391.1250</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_62311_ac22b8e4e37eabd6add0f00de15cb6ed.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>ارزیابی عملکرد گل و بنه زعفران تحت تأثیر وزن و عمق های مختلف کاشت بنه</article-title>
			        <subtitle>ارزیابی عملکرد گل و بنه زعفران تحت تأثیر وزن و عمق های مختلف کاشت بنه</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رضویان</surname>
			            <given-names>محسن</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد اگرواکولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رضوانی مقدم</surname>
			            <given-names>پرویز</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>اسدی</surname>
			            <given-names>قربانعلی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار گروه اگروتکنولوژی دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2019</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>155</fpage>
			      <lpage>170</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>25</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>16</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_62311.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_62311.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>به‌منظور مطالعه‌ اثر وزن‌های مختلف بنه‌ مادری و عمق کاشت بر عملکرد گل و بنه‌ زعفران (Crocus sativus L.)، آزمایشی در دو سال زراعی 95-94 و 96-95 در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، به‌صورت فاکتوریل بر پایه طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی اجرا شد. تیمارهای آزمایش شامل وزن‌های مختلف بنه مادری در چهار سطح 6-4، 8-1/6، 10-1/8 و 12-1/10 گرم و عمق کاشت بنه در سه سطح 10، 15 و 20 سانتی‌متر از سطح خاک بود. در سال اول عملکرد گل و بنه زعفران مورد بررسی قرار گرفت و در سال دوم فقط عملکرد گل زعفران ثبت شد. نتایج آزمایش در هر دو سال نشان داد که اثر متقابل وزن بنه مادری و عمق کاشت بر اکثر صفات گل معنی‌دار بود. با توجه به نتایج، افزایش وزن بنه مادری و عمق کاشت باعث افزایش عملکرد گل، خامه وکلاله زعفران شد. بیش‌ترین عملکرد کلاله‌ خشک در سال اول و دوم )به ترتیب با میانگین 10/0 و 53/0 گرم در مترمربع( در تیمار وزن بنه 12-1/10 گرم و عمق کاشت 20 سانتی‌متر به دست آمد که نسبت به شاهد (وزن بنه 8-1/6 گرم و عمق کاشت 20 سانتی‌متر) به­ترتیب 86 و 35 درصد افزایش نشان داد. اثر متقابل تیمارها بر عملکرد بنه‌های دختری معنی‌دار نبود اما اثر ساده‌ی هر یک از این تیمارها تأثیر معنی‌داری بر این صفت داشتند. بیش‌ترین عملکرد بنه با میانگین 60/1181 گرم در مترمربع مربوط به تیمار وزن بنه 12-1/10 گرم بود و در بین تیمارهای عمق کاشت این مقدار با میانگین 96/938 گرم متعلق به عمق کاشت 20 سانتی‌متر بود. در نهایت با توجه به برتری محسوس عملکرد در تیمارهای وزن بنه و عمق کاشت بالاتر در این طرح، جهت زراعت زعفران بنه­هایی با گروه وزنی بالاتر و عمق کاشت عمیق تر توصیه گردید.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>بنه‌های دختری</kwd>
						<kwd>بنه های مادری</kwd>
						<kwd>کلاله خشک</kwd>
						<kwd>خامه خشک</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Abrishamchi, P. 2003. Investigation about some biochemical changes related to breaking of dormancy and flower formation in Crocus sativus L. 3rd National Symposium on Saffron. 2-3 December 2003, Mashhad, Iran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Abrishami, M.H. 1997. Iranian Saffron: Historic, Cultural and Agronomic Prospects. Astan Ghods Razavi Publishing Co. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Ajaz, A.S., and Raj, B. 2008. Improved technology of saffron cultivation in Kashmir. Asian Journal of Horticulture 3 (2): 446-448.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>All, G., Igbal, A.M., Nehvi, F.A., Samad, S.S., Nagoo, Sh., Naseer, S., and Dar, N.A. 2013. Prospects of clonal selection for enhancing productivity in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). African Journal of Agricultural Research 8: 460-467.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Alipoor Miandehi, Z., Mahmodi, S., Behdani, M.A., and Sayyari, M.H. 2014. Effect of manure, bio- and chemical- fertilizers and corm size on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) yield and yield components. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (2): 73-84.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Alvarezorti, M., Gomez Gomez, L., Rubio, A., Escriban pardo, J., Jimenez, F., and Fernandez, J.A. 2004. Development and gene expression in saffron corms. Acta Horticulturae 650: 141-148.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Azizi, A., Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A., and Sepaskhah, A.R. 2008. Crop and pan coefficients for saffron in a semi- arid region of Iran. Journal of Arid Environments 72: 270- 278.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Benabaji, M.H., Mokhtarian, A., and Tavakoli Kakhki, H.R. 2012. The effects of plant density and corms size on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm production in nursery. In 4th International saffron symposium. 22-25 October 2012, Kashmir, India.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>De Iuan, J.A., Crcoles, H., Muoz, R.M., and Picornell, M.R. 2009. Yield and yield components o saffron under different cropping systems. Industrial Crops Production (30) 2: 212-219.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Fernandez, J.A. 2011. The world saffron and crocus collection: strategies for establishment, management, characterization and utilization. Genetic Resources and Crop Evolution 58: 125-137.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Galavi, M., Soloki, M., Mousavi, S.R., and Ziyaie, M. 2008. Effects of planting depth and soil summer temperature control on growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Asian Journal of Plant Science 7: 747-751.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Ghobadi, F., Ghorbani Javid, M., and Sorooshzadeh, A. 2014. Effects of planting date and corm size on flower yield and physiological traits of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) under Varamin plain climatic conditions. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (4): 265-276. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Gowhar, A., Nehvi, F.A., Ameeque, A., Naseeri, S., Iqbal, A., and Mand Sameer, S. 2012. Effect of corm size and weight on daughter corm formation in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). 4th International saffron symposium. 22-25 October 2012, Kashmir, India.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Hassanzadeh Aval, F., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Bannayan aval, M., and Khorasani, R. 2013. Effects of maternal corm weight and different levels of cow manure on corm and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Saffron Agronomy and Technology 1 (1): 22-39. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Kafi, M. 2002. Saffron, Production and Processing. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Press. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Khorramdel, S., Eskandari Nasrabadi, S., and Mahmoodi, G. 2015. Evaluation of mother corm weights and foliar fertilizer levels on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) growth and yield components. Journal of Applied Research on Medicinal and Aromatic Plants 2: 9-14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2015. Relationship between nitrogen and phosphorususe efficiency in saffron (Crocus sativus L.) as affected by mother corm size and fertilization. Industrial Crops and Production 71: 128–137.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Ebrahimian, E., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2016. How irrigation rounds and mother corm size control saffron yield, quality, daughter corms behavior and phosphorus uptake. Scientia Horticulturae 213: 132-143.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Seyyedi,, S.M., Azizi, H., and Shahriyari, R. 2014. The effect of mother corm size, organic fertilizers and micronutrient foliar application on corm yield and phosphorus uptake of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (1): 3-17. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A.R., Siyahmarguii, A., Azizi, K., and Jahani, M. 2011. The effect of high density and depth of planting on agronomic characteristic of saffron (Crucus sativus L.) and corms behavior. Journal of Agroecology 3 (1): 36-49. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Molina, R.V., Valero, M., Navarro, Y., Garcia-Luis, A., and Guardiola, J.L. 2004. The effect of time of corm lifting and duration of incubation at inductive temperature on flowering in the saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Science Horticulturae 103: 79-91.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Molina, R.V., Valero, M., Navarro, Y., Guardiola, J.L., and Garcia-Luis, A. 2005. Temperature effects on flower formation in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Science Horticulturae 103: 361-379.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Mollafilabi, A., Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Nassiri Mahallati, M. 2013. Effect of plant density and corm weight on yield and yield components of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) under soil, hydroponic and plastic tunnel cultivation. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 1 (2): 14-28. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Naderi- Darbaghshahi, M.R., Khajeh-Bashi, S.M., Bani- Ateba, S.A.R., and Deh-Dashti, S.M. 2008. The effects of planting method, density and depth on yield and exploitation period of saffron field (Crocus sativus L.) in Isfahan. Seed and Plant Journal 24: 643-657. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Nair, S.C., Kurumboor, S.K., and Hasegawa, J.H. 1995. Saffron chemoprevention in biology and medicine. A review. Cancer Biotherapy and Radiopharmaceuticals Journal 10 (4): 57-64.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Nassiri Mahallati, M., Koocheki, A., Boroumand Rezazadeh, Z., and Tabrizi, L. 2007. Effects of corm size and storage period on allocation of assimilates in different parts of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Field Crops Research 5 (1): 155-166. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Nasr Abadi, M. 2011. Effect of temperature in dormancy period, corm size and plant density on yield of flower and corm doughter in saffron. MSc Thesis, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Negbi, M. 1999. Saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Harwood Academic Publishers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Rahimi, H., Mokhtarian, A., Bazoobandi, M., Rahimi, H., Kiani, M., and Behdad, M. 2008. Effects of sowing depth and summer irrigation on Rhizoglyphus robini (Acari: Acaridae) population in Gonabad. Journal of Entomology and Phytopathology 76 (1): 1-14. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Huda, A.K.S., Parvez, Q., and Koocheki, A.R. 2007. Indigenous knowledge in agriculture with particular reference to medicinal crop production in Khorasan, Iran. Managing Knowledge, Technology and Development in the Era of Information Revolution. Edited by A. Ahmed, p. 105-115.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B. 1993. Effect of Corm Weight on Flowering of Saffron. Research and industrial Institutes of Khorasan Publication, Iran. 73 p. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, S.M., Dehnadi-Moghaddam, G., and Dooroodian, H. 2014. Evaluation of effects of date, depth and corm sowing distance on corms growth and stigma yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Langarood, Guilan province. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 3 (2): 137-144. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Sampatha, S.R., Shivashankar, S., Lewis, Y.S, and Wood, A.B. 1984. Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) cultivation, processing, chemistry and standardization. Journal of Food Science and Nutrition 20 (2): 123-157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Vafabakhsh, J., Ahmadiyan, J., and Mokhtariyan, A.A. 2009. Investigation of correlation between saffron flowering pattern and climatological parameters under planting depth and summer irrigation treatments. 3rd International Symposium on Saffron. Forthcoming Challenges in Cultivation, Research and Economics. 20-23 May 2009, Korokos, Kozani, Greece._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.98710.1257</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66475_5e5f1346a9d33a3d908937a82ac44e81.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تأثیر کود گاوی بر عملکرد و خصوصیات مورفولوژیک و فیزیولوژیک زعفران تحت تنش شوری (Crocus sativus L.)</article-title>
			        <subtitle>تأثیر کود گاوی بر عملکرد و خصوصیات مورفولوژیک و فیزیولوژیک زعفران تحت تنش شوری (.Crocus sativus L)</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>اصغری</surname>
			            <given-names>رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری گروه زراعت، واحد گرگان، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی گرگان، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>داداشی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیارگروه زراعت، واحد گرگان، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی گرگان، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رضوی</surname>
			            <given-names>سید علیرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار، بخش تحقیقات علوم زراعی و باغی، مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی خراسان رضوی، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، مشهد، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فیضی</surname>
			            <given-names>حسن</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی و پژوهشگر پژوهشکده زعفران، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه، خراسان رضوی، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c5">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بختیاری</surname>
			            <given-names>سعید</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد نیشابور، خراسان رضوی، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2019</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>171</fpage>
			      <lpage>184</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>26</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>27</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66475.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66475.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>به منظور مطالعه اثرات تنش شوری آب آبیاری و مقادیر مختلف کود گاوی بر خصوصیات مورفولوژیک و فیزیولوژیک زعفران (Crocus sativus L.)، آزمایشی در منطقه جلگه رخ تربت حیدریه (در مزرعه­ای که دومین سال کشت آن بود) در سال 1394 انجام شد. تیمارهای آزمایش شامل چهار سطح شوری آب آبیاری به عنوان عامل اصلی (1 (تیمار شاهد)، 4، 7 و 10 دسی زیمنس بر متر) و مقادیر کود گاوی (عامل فرعی) در چهار سطح شامل شاهد (بدون کود)،20، 40 و 60 تن در هکتار بودند که به صورت کرت­های خرد شده در قالب طرح بلوک­های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار اجرا شد. صفات مورد بررسی شامل تعداد و وزن تر گل، وزن خشک کلاله، میزان کلروفیل برگ، محتوی پرولین برگ، قطر، وزن تر و خشک بنه بود. نتایج تجزیه واریانس نشان داد که اثرات مقادیر مختلف کود گاوی و سطوح تنش شوری بر کلیه صفات مورد مطالعه در سطح یک درصد معنی­دار بود. بیشترین تعداد گل، عملکرد گل و وزن خشک کلاله در تیمار شوری شاهد (یک دسی زیمنس بر متر) و مصرف 60 تن در هکتار کود گاوی بدست آمد. با افزایش سطوح شوری تا 7 دسی زیمنس بر متر، میزان کلروفیل a، b و کل افزایش و پس از آن به شدت کاهش یافت به طوری­که این میزان کاهش در تیمار شوری 10 دسی زیمنس بر متر نسبت به شاهد به ترتیب 6/6، 9/16 و 12 درصد بود. نتایج حاکی از افزایش معنی­دار پرولین (2/14 درصد) در سطوح شوری 10 دسی زیمنس بر متر نسبت به شاهد بود. علاوه بر این قطر، وزن تر و خشک بنه نیز با افزایش سطوح شوری کاهش یافت به طوریکه میزان کاهش در تیمار شوری 10 دسی زیمنس بر متر نسبت به شاهد به ترتیب 5/13، 5/32 و 6/32 درصد بود. به طور کلی نتایج نشان داد که استفاده از کود گاوی باعث کاهش اثرات مخرب تنش شوری بر عملکرد گل و بنه زعفران می­شود.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>عملکرد گل</kwd>
						<kwd>عملکرد بنه</kwd>
						<kwd>محتوی پرولین</kwd>
						<kwd>کلروفیل</kwd>
						<kwd>کلاله</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Amirghasemi, T. 2001. Saffron, Red Gold of Iran. Nashr- Ayandegan Publication. 112 p. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Amiri, M.E. 2008. Impact of animal manures and chemical fertilizers on yield components of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). American-Eurasian Journal of Agriculture and Environmental Science 4: 274-279.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Arnon, D.I. 1949. Copper enzymes in isolated chloroplasts. Polyphennol oxidase in Beta vulgaris. Plant Physiology 24: 150-151.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Azizi-Zohan, A.A., Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A., and Sepaskhah, A.R. 2008. Crop and pan coefficients for saffron in a semi-arid region of Iran. Journal of Arid Environments 72: 270-278. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Bajji, M., Lutts, S., and Kinet, J.M. 2001. Water deficit effects on solute contribution to osmotic adjustment as a function of leaf ageing in three durum wheat (Triticum durum Desf.) cultivars performing differently in arid conditions. Plant Science 160: 669-681.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Bates, L.S., Waldern, R.P., and Tear, I.D. 1973. Rapid determination of free proline for water stress studies. Plant and Soil 39: 207-207.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A., Nassiri, M., and Rezvani Moghaddam, P. 2006. Evaluatio of quantitative relationships between saffron yield and nutrition (on farm trial). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 3: 1-14. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Chaji, N., Khorassani, R., Astaraei, A., and Lakzian, A. 2013. Effect of phosphorous and nitrogen on vegetative growth and production of daughter corms of saffron. Journal of Saffron Research 1: 1–12. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Foroughifar, H., and Poor-Kasmani, M.E. 2002. Soil science and management. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Press. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Gholami Touran Poshti, M., Maghsoudi moud, A.R., and Manoochehri Kalantari, Kh. 2005. Salt stress effect on the photosynthetic capacity of three Iranian saffron (Crocus sativus L.) clones. The 4th National Biotechnology Congress Islamic Republic of Iran. Kerman.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Ghorbani, R., and Koocheki, A. 2006. Organic saffron in Iran: prospects and challenges. Acta Horticulture 739: 369-374.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Gresta, F., Lombardo, G.M., Siracusa, L., and Ruberto, G. 2008. Effect of mother corm dimension and sowing time on stigma yield, daughter corms and qualitative aspects of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in a Mediterranean environment. Journal of the Science of Food and Agriculture 88: 1144–1150.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Hassani, A., and Omid beigi, R. 2001. Effects of water stress on some morphological, physiological and metabolic basil. Journal of Agricultural Knowledge 12 (3): 47-59. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Hassanzadeh Aval, F., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Bannayan aval, M., and Khorasani, R. 2013. Effects of maternal corm weight and different levels of cow manure on corm and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Saffron Agronomy and Technology 1 (1): 22-39. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Jahan, M., and Jahani, M. 2007. The effects of chemical and organic fertilizers on saffron flowering. Acta Horticulturae 739: 81-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Jami-alahmadi, M., Behdani, M.A., and Akbarpour, A. 2009. Analysis of agronomic effective factors on yield of saffron agroecosystems in southern khorasan. 3nd International Symposium on Saffron, 20-23 may 2009.  Greece. p. 14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Javadipour, Z., Movahhedi-Dehnavi, M., and Balouchi, H.R. 2013. Evaluation of photosynthesis parameters, chlorophyll content and fluorescence of safflower cultivars under saline condition. Electronic Journal of Crop Production 6 (2): 35-56.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Johari Pireivatlou, M. 2010. Effect of soil water stress on yield and proline content of four wheat lines. African. Journal of Biotechnology 9: 36-40. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Kafi, M., Rashed, M., Koocheki, A., and Mollafilabi, A. 2002. Saffron: Production and Processing. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Press. 276 p. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Khazaei, M., Monfared, M., Kamgar Haghighi, A.A., and Sepaskhah, A.R. 2013. The trend of change for weight and number of saffron corms as affected by irrigation frequency and method in different years. Journal of Saffron Research 1: 48–56. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Khodadadi, M., and Omid Beigi, R. 2004. Effect of sodium chloride salinity on somephysiological characteristics of two onion cultivars. Journal of Agricultural Science 14 (3): 11-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Najibnia S., and Lalehgani B. 2009. Evaluation of saffron yield (Crocus sativus L.) in intercropping with cereals, pulses and medicinal plants. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 7: 173–182. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Siahmarguee, A., Azizi, G., and Jahani, M. 2011. The effect of high density and depth ofplanting on agronomic characteristic of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) and corms behavior. Journal of Agroecology 3: 36–49. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Tabrizi, L., Jahani, M., and Mohammad Abadi, A.A. 2012. An evaluation of the effect of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm planting rate and pattern on the crop's performance. Iranian Journal of Horticultural Science 42: 379-391. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Kumar, R., Singh, V., Devi, K., Sharma, M., Singh, M.K., and Ahuja, P.S. 2009. State of art of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) agronomy: A comprehensive review. Food Reviews International 25: 44–85.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Leopold, A.C., and Willing, R.P. 1984. Evidence for toxicity effects of salts on membranes. In: Staples. R.C, and G.H. Toenniessen (Eds). Salinity Tolerance in Plants. Wiley. New York. 67–76.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Maas, E.V., and Hoffman, G.J. 1977. Crop salt tolerance – current assessment. Journal Irrigation and .Drainage Div. ASCE. 103: 115-134.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Miller, G., Suzuki, N., Ciftci-Yilma, S., and Mittler, R. 2010. Reactive oxygen species homeostasis and signaling during drought and salinity stresses. .Plant Cell Environment 33: 453–467.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammdi Aria, M., Lakzian, A., Haghnia, Gh., Besharati, H., and Fotovat, A. 2010. The effect of Thiobacillus and Aspergillus on phosphorus availability of enriched rock phosphate with sulfur and vermicompost. Journal of Water and Soil 24: 1-9. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Naghizadeh, M., Gholami Shabestari, M., and Mohadeseh Shamsaddin Saied, M. 2014. The study of some physiological responses of three Iranian saffron (Crocus sativus L.) landraces to salinity stress. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (2): 31-44. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Nicolas, M.E., Munns, R., Samarakoon, A.B., and Gifford, R.M. 1993. Elevated carbon dioxide improves the growth of wheat under salinity. Australian Journal of Plant Physiology 20 (3): 349- 360.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Omidi, H., Naghdibadi, H.A., Golzad, A., Torabi, H., and Fotoukian, M.H. 2009. The effect of chemical and bio-fertilizer source of nitrogen on qualitative and quantitative yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Medicinal Plant 8: 98-109. (In Persianwith English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Orabi, S.A., Salman, S.R., and Shalaby, A.F. 2010. Increasing resistance to oxidative damage in cucumber (Cucumis sativus L.) plants by exogenous application of salicylic acid and paclobutrazol. World Journal of Agriculture Science 6: 252-259.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Parida, A.K., and Das, A.B. 2005. Salt tolerance and salinity effects on plants: a review. Ecotoxicology and Environmental Safety 60: 324-349.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Porra, R.J. 2002. The chequered history of the development and use of simultaneous equations for the accurate determination of chlorophylls a and b. Photosynthesis Research 73: 149-156.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Rajaei, S.M., Niknam, V., Seyedi, S.M., Ebrahimzadeh, H., and Razavi, K. 2009. Contractile roots are the most sensitive organ in Crocus sativus to salt stress. Biology Plantarum 53 (3): 523-529.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani-Moghaddam, P., Mohammad-Abadi, A.A., and Sabori, A. 2006. Effect of different animal manure on flower yield and qualitative and quantitative characteristics of forage production of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Mashhad conditions. Acta Horticulture 739: 159-163.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Mohammad Abadi, A.A., Fallahi, J., and Aghhavani Shajari, M. 2010. Effects of chemical and organic fertilizers on number of corm and stigma yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). 59th International Congress and Annual Meeting of the Society for Medicinal Plant and Natural Product Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Koocheki, A., Molafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, M. 2014. Effect of biological and chemical fertilizers on replacement corm and flower yields of saffron (Crocus sativus L.).Iranian Journal of Crop Sciences. (In press). (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Rostami, M., Mohmmad Parast, B., and Golfam, R. 2015. The effect of different levels of salinity stress on some physiological characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.).Saffron Agronomy and Technology 3 (3): 179-193. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Sameni, A.M., and Kasraian, A. 2004. Effect of agricultural sulfur on characteristics of different calcareous soils from dry regions of Iran. II. Reclaiming effects on structure and hydraulic conductivity of the soils under saline-sodic conditions. Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis 35: 1235–1246.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Sepaskhah, A.R., and Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A. 2009.Saffron irrigation regime. International Journal of Plant Production 3: 1–16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Tahmasbi, L. 2003. Effects of salinity and some growth inhibitors on morphological characteristics, biochemical and chemical Pistachio almond cultivars, master's thesis, Shahid Bahonar University of Kerman. (In Persian)._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.129172.1296</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75281_2fecda66df5d8ced60885a16c70ef100.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی اثرات زیست‌محیطی نظام‌های تولید زعفران (Crocus sativus L.) تحت تأثیر اندازه زمین با استفاده از ارزیابی چرخه حیات</article-title>
			        <subtitle>بررسی اثرات زیست‌محیطی نظام‌های تولید زعفران تحت تأثیر اندازه زمین با استفاده از ارزیابی چرخه حیات</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>خرم دل</surname>
			            <given-names>سرور</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نصیری محلاتی</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>معلم بنهنگی</surname>
			            <given-names>فاطمه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>ملافیلابی</surname>
			            <given-names>عبداله</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه زیست فناوری موادغذایی، پژوهشکده فناوری های پیشرفته مواد غذایی، مؤسسه پژوهشی علوم و صنایع غذایی، مشهد، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2019</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>207</fpage>
			      <lpage>225</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>30</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>24</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75281.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75281.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>ارزیابی چرخه حیات (LCA) راهکاری شناخته شده و دقیق برای مقایسه اثرات زیست­محیطی فعالیت­های مختلف شامل مدیریت نظام­های کشاورزی است. از آنجا که نوع نهاده­هادر کشاورزی نقش مهمی در بروز آلودگی­های زیست­محیطی و انتشار گازهای گلخانه­ای دارد، LCA به طور گسترده­ای برای ارزیابی این اثرات در محصولات زراعی مورد استفاده قرار می­گیرد. هدف این مطالعه، بررسی اثرات زیست محیطی نظام­های تولید زعفران در استان خراسان رضوی تحت تأثیر اندازه زمین (کمتر از 5/0، 1-5/0 و بیشتر از 1 هکتار) با استفاده از LCA بود. نهاده­های مصرفی طی سال­های اول تا ششم با استفاده از پرسشنامه (13 مزرعه از هر اندازه زمین) جمع­آوری شد. LCA بر اساس روش ISO14044، در چهار گام شامل مشخص­سازی اهداف و حوزه عمل، ممیزی چرخه حیات، ارزیابی تأثیر چرخه حیات و تلفیق، نتیجه­گیری و تفسیر نتایج محاسبه گردید.واحد کارکردی معادل یک کیلوگرم گل در نظر گرفته شد. گروه­های تأثیرمورد مطالعه شامل گرمایش جهانی، اسیدی شدن و اوتریفیکاسیون (در محیط­های خشکی و آبی) بود. در آخرین مرحله، شاخص بوم­شناخت (Ecox) محاسبه شد. برای سنجش قابلیت روایی پرسشنامه، ضریب آلفای کرونباخ محاسبه گردید. نتایج نشان داد که ضریب آلفای کرونباخ برابر با 84%=α محاسبه گردید. میانگین پتانسیل گروه­های تأثیر گرمایش جهانی، اسیدی شدن، اوتریفیکاسیون در محیط­های آبی و خشکی به ترتیب 41/53±41/115 کیلوگرم معادل CO2، 16/0±35/0 کیلوگرم معادل SO2، 27/0±58/0 کیلوگرم معادل NOx و 09/0±20/0 کیلوگرم معادل PO4 به ازای یک کیلوگرم گل محاسبه شد. بیشترین سهم انتشار گازهای گلخانه­ای در گروه تأثیر گرمایش جهانی مربوط به CH4 بود. بالاترین سهم انتشار آلاینده­ها در گروه­های تأثیر اوتریفیکاسیون آبی و خشکی و اسیدی شدن به NH3 اختصاص داشت. به­طور کلی، نتایج نشان داد که اندازه زمین، میزان مصرف نهاده­ها و اثرات ­زیست محیطی را در واحد عملکرد گل تحت تأثیر قرارداد و گروه­های اوتریفیکاسیون و گرمایش جهانی حساسیت بیشتری نسبت به شدت فشرده­سازی تحت تأثیر اندازه زمین دارند، بنابراین افزایش کارایی مصرف منابع، یکی از رویکردهای مناسب برای کاهش اثرات زیست محیطی همگام با بهبود عملکرد اقتصادی در واحد سطح است.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>انتشار گازهای گلخانه‌ای</kwd>
						<kwd>فشرده‌سازی</kwd>
						<kwd>کارایی مصرف منابع</kwd>
						<kwd>گرمایش جهانی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Al-Kaisi, M.M., and Yin, X. 2005. Tillage and crop residue effects on soil carbon and carbon dioxide emission in corn–soybean rotations. Journal of Environmental Quality 34: 437–445.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Bacenetti, J., Fusi, A., Negri, M., Guidetti, R., and Fiala M. 2014. Environmental assessment of two different crop systems in terms of biomethane potential production. Science of the Total Environment 466–467: 1066-1077.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Bachmaier, J., Effenberger, M., and Gronauer, A. 2010. Greenhouse gas balance and resource demand of biogas plants in agriculture. Engineering in Life Sciences 10: 560–569.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Banaeian, N., Omid, M., and Ahmadi, H. 2011. Energy and economic analysis of greenhouse strawberry production in Tehran province of Iran. Energy Conversion and Management 52: 1020-1025.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Barker-Reid, F., Gates, W.P., Wilson, K., Baigent, R., Galbally, I.E., Meyer, C.P., Weeks, I.A., and Eckard, R.J., 2005. Soil nitrous oxide emission from rainfed wheat in SE Australia. In: A. van Amsted (Ed.). Non-CO2greenhouse gases (NCGG-4). Utrecht, the Netherlands: Mill Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Biswas, W.K., Barton, L., and Carter, D. 2008. Global warming potential of wheat production in Western Australia: A life cycle assessment. Water and Environment Journal 22: 206–216.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Bojacá, C.R., Wyckhuys, K.A.G., and Schrevens, E. 2014. Life cycle assessment of Colombian greenhouse tomato production based on farmer-level survey data. Journal of Cleaner Production 69: 26-33.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Brentrup, F., Küsters, J., Kuhlmann, H., and Lammel, J. 2001. Application of the life cycle assessment methodology toagricultural production: an example of sugar beet productionwith different forms of nitrogen fertilisers. European Journal of Agronomy 14: 221–233.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Brentrup, F., Küsters, J., Kuhlmann, H., and Lammel, J. 2004a. Environmental impact assessment of agricultural production systems using the life cycle assessment methodology: I. Theoretical concept of a LCA method tailored to crop production. European Journal of Agronomy 20 (3): 247–264.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Brentrup, F., Küsters, J., Lammel, J., Barraclough, P., and Kuhlmann, H. 2004b. Environmental impact assessment of agricultural production systems using the life cycle assessment (LCA) methodology: II. The application to N fertilizer use in winter wheat production systems. European Journal of Agronomy 20 (3): 265–279.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Carozzi, M., Ferrara, R.M., Rana, G., and Acutis, M. 2013. Evaluation of mitigation strategies to reduce ammonia losses from slurry fertilisation on arable lands. Science of the Total Environment 449: 126–133.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>CDIAC. 2013. Global Fossil-fuel CO2 Emissions. Carbon Dioxide Information Analysis Center.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Charles, R., Jolliet, O., Gillard, G., and Pellet, D. 2006. Environmental analysis of intensity level in wheat production using life cycle assessment. Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment 113: 216-225.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Cronbach, L.J. 1951. Coefficient alpha and the internal structure of tests. Psychometrika 16 (3): 297-334.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Crutzen, P.J. 1981. Atmospheric chemical processes of the oxides of nitrogen, including nitrous oxide. In: C.C. Delwiche (Ed.), Denitrification, Nitrification, and Atmospheric Nitrous Oxide (p. 17–44). New York: Wiley.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Dale, V.H., and Polasky, S. 2007. Measures of the effects of agricultural practices on ecosystem services. Ecological Economics 64: 286-296.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Dyer, J.A., and Desjardins, R.L. 2003. The impact of farm machinery management on greenhouse gas emissions from Canadian agriculture. Journal of Sustainable Agriculture 20: 59–74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>ECETOC. 1994. European Chemical Industry Ecology and Toxicology Centre (ECETOC). 1994. Ammonia Emissions to Air in Western Europe. Technical Report No. 62. ECETOC, Brussels.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Eckert, H., Breitschuh, G., and Sauerbeck, D. 1999. Kriterien einer umweltverträglichen Landbewirtschaftung (KUL)-ein Verfahren zur ökologischen Bewertung von Landwirtschaftsbetrieben (Criteria of Environmentally friendly land use (KUL)-a method for the environmental evaluation of farms). Agriculture Biotechnology Research 52: 57-76. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Esmaeilpour, B., Khorramdel, S., and Amin Ghafouri, A. 2015. Study of environmental impacts for potato agroecosystems of Iran by using life cycle assessment (LCA) methodology. Electronic Journal of Crop Production 8 (3): 199-224. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Fageria, N.K. 2009. The Use of Nutrients in Plants. Taylor and Francis Group, CRC Press, 430 p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Fallahpour, F., Aminghafouri, A., Ghalegolab Behbahani, A., and Bannayan, M. 2012. The environmental impact assessment of wheat and barley production by using life cycle assessment (LCA) methodology. Environment, Development and Sustainability 14: 979-992.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Finnveden, G., Hauschild, M.Z., Ekvall, T., and Suh, S. 2009. Recent developments in life cycle assessment. Journal of Environmental Management 91 (1): 1-21.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Garrigues, E., Corsona, M.S., Angers, D.A., van der Werfa, H.M.G., and Walter, C.  2011. Soil quality in Life Cycle Assessment: Towards development of an indicator. Ecological Indicators 18: 434–442.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Gasol, C.M., Gabarrell, X., Anton, A., Rigola, M., Carrasco, J., Ciria, M.J., and Rieradevall, J. 2007. Life cycle assessment of a Brassicacarinata bioenergy cropping system in southern Europe. Biomass and Bioenergy 31: 543-555.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Giampietro, M., Cerretelli, G., and Pimentel, D. 1992. Energy analysis of agricultural ecosystem management: human return and sustainability. Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment 38: 219–244.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Guinée, J. 1996. Data for the Normalization Step within LifeCycle Assessment of Products. CML Paper no. 14 (revisedversion). CML (Centre of Environmental Science), Leiden University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Guinée, J.B. 2001. Life Cycle Assessment: An Operational Guide to the ISO Standards. Centre of Environmental Science, Leiden University, Leiden.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Haas, G., Wetterich, F., and Köpke, U. 2001. Comparing intensive, extensified and organic grassland farming in southern Germany by process life cycle assessment. Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment 83V (1–2): 43-53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Hanley, N., Whitby, M., and Simpson, I. 1999. Assessing the success of agri-environmental policy in the UK. Land Use Policy 16: 67-80.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>IEA. 2013. CO2 Emissions from Fuel Combustion Highlights. International Energy Agency.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Iriarte, A., Rieradevall, J., and Gabarrell, X. 2010. Life cycle assessment of sunflower and rapeseed as energy crops under Chilean conditions. Journal of Cleaner Production 18V (4): 336-345.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>ISO (International Organization for Standardization). 2006. ISO 14040: 2006 (E) Environmental Management– Life Cycle Assessment– Principles and Framework.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Kafi, M., Rashed Mohasel, M.H., Koocheki, A., and Mollafilabi, A. 2002. Saffron, Production and Processing. Zaban va Adab Publications, Iran 276 p. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Kamkar, B., and Mahdavi Damghani, A.M. 2008. Principle of Sustainable Agriculture. Jihad Daneshgahi of Mashhad Press, Mashhad, Iran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Khorramdel, S., Abolhassani, L., and Azam Rahmati, E. 2016. Environmental impacts assessment of saffron agroecosystems using life cycle assessment methodology: (Case study: Torbat-e Heydarieh and Ghaen counties). Journal of Saffron Research 4 (2): 229-248. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Khorramdel, S., Ghorbani, R., and Amin Ghafori, A. 2015. Comparison of environmental impacts for dryland and irrigated barley agroecosystems by using Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) methodology. Journal of Plant Production Research 22 (1): 243-264. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Khorramdel, S., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Amin Ghafori, A. 2014. Evaluation of environmental impacts for wheat Agroecosystems of Iran by using Life Cycle Assessment methodology. Cereal Research 4 (1): 27-44. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Khorramdel, S., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Amin Ghafori, A. 2018. Economic evaluation of agroecosystem services of saffron in Khorasan Razavi province. Journal of Saffron Agronomy and Technology 6 (1): 73-89. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Khorramdel, S., Shabahang, J., and Amin Ghafouri, A. 2017. Evaluation of environmental impacts for rice agroecosystems using life cycle assessment (LCA). Iranian Journal of Applied Ecology 5 (18): 1-14. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Khoshnevisan, B., Rafiei, S., Omid, M., Keyhani, A., and Movahedi, M. 2013. Assessing of energy indices and environmental impacts of potato production (Case study: Fereydoonshahr region, Isfahan province). Iranian Journal of Biosystems Engineering 44 (1): 57-66. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Khoshnevisan, B., Rajaeifar, M.A., Clark, S., Shamahirband, S., Anuar, N.B., Mohd Shuib, N.L., and Gani, A. 2014. Evaluation of traditional and consolidated rice farms in Guilan Province, Iran, using life cycle assessment and fuzzy modeling. Science of the Total Environment 481: 242–251.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A. 2004. Indigenous knowledge in agriculture with particular reference production in Iran. Acta Horticulture p. 175-182. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Kopiñski, J. 2012. Realization of environmental and economic objectives by the farms of various specialization directions (in Polish). Problems Agricultural engineering 2: 37-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Kowalski, Z., Kulczycka, J., and Góralczyk, M. 2007. Environ- mental Life Cycle Assessment of the Manufacturing Processes (LCA) (in Polish). PWN Press, Warsaw, Poland.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Kronvang, B., Rubak, G.H., and Heckrath, G. 2009. International phosphorus workshop: Diffuse phosphorus loss to surface water bodies- risk assessment, mitigation options, and ecological effects in river basins. Journal of Environmental Quality 38: 1924–1929.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Lal, R. 2004. Carbon emission from and farm operations. Environment International 30: 981-990.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Meisterling, K., Samaras, C., and Schweizer, V. 2009. Decisions to reduce greenhouse gases from agriculture and product transport: LCA case study of organic and conventional wheat. Journal of Cleaner Production 17: 222–230.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Mirbagheri, E., Abbaspour, A., Rohani, A.,  and Ghorbani, H. 2012. Evaluation of phosphorus status in some potato fields of Mojen region in Semnan Province. Iranian Journal of Soil Research 26V (3): 235-243. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Mollafilabi, A., and Shoorideh, H. 2009. The new methods of saffron production. 4th National Festival of Saffron, Khorasan- Razavi, Iran, 27-28 October 2009. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Monti, A., Fazio, S., and Venturi, G. 2009. Cradle-to-farm gate life cycle assessment in perennial energy crops. European Journal of Agronomy 31: 77-84.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Moudrý, J., Jelínková, Z., Plch, R., Moudrý, J., Konvalina, P., and Hyšpler, R. 2013. The emissions of greenhouse gases produced during growing and processing of wheat products in the Czech Republic. Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment 11 (1): 1133-1136.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Nassiri Mahallati, M., and Koocheki, A. 2017. Trend analysis of nitrogen use and productivity in cereal production systems of Iran. Journal of Agroecology 9 (2): 360-378. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Nassiri, S.M., and Singh, S. 2009. Study on energy use efficiency for paddy crop using Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA) technique. Applied Energy 86: 1320-1325.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Nemecek, T., Dubois, D., Huguenin-Elie, O., and Gaillard, G. 2010. Life cycle assessment of Swiss farming systems: I. Integrated and organic farming. Agriculture Systems 104: 217-232.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Nikkhah, A., Emadi, B., and Firouzi, S. 2015. Greenhouse gas emissions footprint of agricultural production in Guilan province of Iran. Sustainable Energy Technologies and Assessments 12: 10–14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Oberndorfer, U., and Rennings, K. 2006. The impacts of the European Union emissions trading scheme on competitiveness in Europe. Center for European Economic Research (ZEW), Mannheim. Available at: ftp://ftp.zew.de/pub/zew-docs/dp/dp06051.pdf</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Oglethorpe, D., Edgerton, N., and Hanley, N. 2000. Modeling the demand and supply of environmental goods for ancient public good provision. Paper presented at Annual Meeting of the Agricultural Economics Society 14-17 April 2000, Manchester.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Pishgar-Komleh, S.H., Ghahderijani, M., and Sefeedpari, P. 2012. Energy consumption and CO2 emissions analysis of potato production based on different farm size levels in Iran. Journal of Cleaner Production 33: 183–191.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Pishgar-Komleh, S.H., Keyhani, A., Rafiee, S., and Sefeedpari, P. 2011a. Energy use and economic analysis of corn silage production under three cultivated area levels in Tehran province of Iran. Energy 36: 3335–3341.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Pishgar-Komleh, S.H., Sefeedpari, P., and Rafiee, S. 2011b. Energy and economic analysis of rice production under different farm levels in Guilan province of Iran. Energy 36: 5824-5831.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Rahimizadeh, M., Madani, H., Rezadoust, S., Mehraban, A., and Marjani, A. 2007. Analysis of energy in agroecosystems and methods of increasing energy efficiency. In: The 6th National Energy Congress. 12-13 June, 2007. Available at: http://Iranenergy.org.ir/sixth/new3/final_schedule.pdf</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Rao, P.S.R.S. 2000. Sampling methodologies with applications, Florida: Chapman and all/CRC Press. ISBN: 1- 58488214-X.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Rathke, G.W., and Diepenbrock, W. 2006. Energy balance of winter oilseed rape (Brassica napus L.) cropping as related to nitrogen supply and preceding crop. European Journal of Agronomy 24: 35-44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Reicosky, D.C., Kemper, W.D., Langdale, G.W., Douglas, Jr. C.L., and Rasmussen, P.E. 1995. Soil organic matter changes resulting fromtillage and biomass production. Journal of Soil and Water Conservation 50: 253-261</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Riemersma, S., Little, J., Ontkean, G., and Moskal-Hébert, T. 2006. Phosphorus Sources and Sinks in Watersheds: A Review. Alberta Soil Phosphorus Limits Project.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Romero-Gámez, M., Audsley, E., and Suárez-Rey, E.M. 2014. Life cycle assessment of cultivating lettuce and escarole in Spain. Journal of Cleaner Production 73: 193-203.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Romero-Gomez, M., Suarez-Rey, E.M., Anton, A., Castilla, N., and Soriano, T. 2012. Environmental impact of greenhouse and open-field cultivation using a life cycle analysis: the case study of green bean production. Journal of Cleaner Production 28: 63-69.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Roy, P., Nei, D., Orikasa, T., Xu, Q., Okadome, H., Nakamura, N., and Shiina, T. 2009. A review of life cycle assessment (LCA) on some food products. Journal of Food Engineering 90 (1): 1-10.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Roy, P., Shimizu, N., and Kimura, T. 2005. Life cycle inventory analysis of rice produced by local processes. Journal of the Japanese Society of Agricultural Machinery 67 (1): 61–67.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Russo, G., and De Lucia, B. 2008. Environmental evaluation by means of LCA regarding the ornamental nursery production in rose and sowbread greenhouse cultivation. Acta Horticulturae 801: 1597-1604.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Saborbilandi, A., Vadiei, A.R. 2007. The economic analysis of saffron and its impact on farmers income, The 6th National Conference on Agricultural Economic, Iran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Seyyedan, S.M. 2004. Investigation of factors affecting on technical inefficiency of garlic producers: A case study in Hamedan province. Pajouhesh and Sazandegi (64): 74-79. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Signor, D., Eduardo, C., and Cerri, P. 2013. Nitrous oxide emissions in agricultural soils: a review. Pesquisa Agropecuária Tropical (Agricultural Research in the Tropics), Goiânia 43 (3): 322-338. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Skowroñska, M., and Filipek, T. 2014. Life cycle assessment of fertilizers: a review. International Agrophysics 28: 101-110.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Syswerda, S.P. 2009. Ecosystem services from agriculture across a management intensity gradient in Southwest Michigan. PhD Thesis, Michigan State University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Teimouri, I., Salarvandian, F., and Ziari, K. 2014. The ecological footprint of carbon dioxide from fossil fuels in Shiraz. Journal of Geographical Research 59 (1): 193-204.  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Tzilivakis, J., Warner, D.J., May, M., Lewis, K.A., and Jaggard, K. 2005. An assessment of the energy inputs and greenhouse gas emissions in sugar beet (Beta vulgaris) production in the UK. Agricultural Systems 85 (2): 101-119.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Van der Hoek, K.W., and Van Schijndel, M.W. 2006. Methane and nitrous oxide emissions from animal manure management 1990–2003. Background document on the calculation method for the Dutch National Inventory Report. RIVM and MNP (Netherlands Environmental Assessment Agency), Bilthoven, The Netherlands, p. 1–50.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Wackernagel, M., Monfreda, C., Moran, D., Wermer, P., Goldfinger, S., Deumling, D., and Murray, M. 2005. National Footprint and Biocapacity Accounts 2005: The Underlying Calculation Method. Global Footprint Network, Oakland.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Whalen, J.K., and Chang, C. 2002. Phosphorus sorption capacities of calcareous soils receiving cattle manure applications for 25 years. Communications in Soil Science and Plant Analysis 33: 1011-1026.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Zohary, D., and Hopf, M. 1994. Domestication of Plants in the Old World. Second Ed. Clarendon Press, Oxford, p. 189-190.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Zolfi Bavariani, M., and Nouruzi, M. 2010. Effect of organic matter on residual phosphorus recovering in a calcareous soil. JWSS- Isfahan University of Technology 14 (52): 87-98. (In Persian with English Summary)._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.106340.1272</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75221_d049fcaa314ac4612d0e49c13ae0789c.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی برخی روش های مدیریت تغذیه و آبیاری به منظور سازگاری و توسعه کشت زعفران در مناطق خشک</article-title>
			        <subtitle>بررسی برخی روش های مدیریت تغذیه و آبیاری به منظور سازگاری و توسعه کشت زعفران در مناطق خشک</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>غلامی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمود</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی،  دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>کافی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>خزایی</surname>
			            <given-names>حمید رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>ابرقوئی</surname>
			            <given-names>حسین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه پیام نور استان یزد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2019</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>207</fpage>
			      <lpage>225</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>20</day>
			          <month>11</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>23</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75221.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75221.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>به منظور بهبود عملکرد زعفران و تغییر الگوی کاشت در مناطق خشک، آزمایشی بصورت کرت‌های خردشده در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی در سه تکرار طی سال‌های زراعی 1395-1392 در یک مزرعه تحقیقاتی واقع در روستای چرخاب از توابع استان یزد به اجرا درآمد. سطوح فاکتور اصلی شامل سه سطح آبیاری (آبیاری تا 100، 75 و 50 درصد نیاز آبی) به عنوان کرت‌های اصلی و 7 تیمار مختلف مدیریت کودی شامل شاهد، 10 تن در هکتار کود دامی یا ورمی‌کمپوست به صورت توزیع روی سطح خاک، 5 و 10 تن در هکتار ورمی‌کمپوست به صورت ردیفی در زیر ردیف‌های کاشت، 10 لیتر در هکتار هیومستر سفرون در یک نوبت و در دو نوبت پس از گلدهی، به عنوان کرت‌های فرعی بود. نتایج نشان داد که کاهش آبیاری از 75% به 50% نیاز آبی موجب کاهش معنی‌دار وزن خشک برگ، وزن بزرگترین بنه، وزن کل بنه و تعداد بنه مؤثر در بوته شد. اختلاف عملکرد بین تیمارهای آبیاری هر ساله بیشتر شد. به­طوریکه در سال اول آزمایش، تیمارها از نظر تعداد گل اختلاف معنی‌داری نداشتند اما در سال سوم آزمایش تعداد گل در تیمار 100% نیاز آبی با میانگین 76/100 گل در هر کرت بصورت معنی‌داری بیش از دو تیمار دیگر بود. همچنین با کاهش آبیاری از 100% به 75% نیاز آبی، تعداد کل بنه بیش‌از 40% کاهش یافت، اما وزن کل بنه کمتر از 30% کاهش یافت. بین تیمارهای مدیریت کودی، مصرف ورمی‌کمپوست به مقدار 10 تن در هکتار به­صورت ردیفی در زیر ردیف‌های کاشت (10RV) و مصرف کود هیومستر سفرون به مقدار 10 لیتر در هکتار طی دو نوبت‌ در طول فصل رشد (CH) به صورت معنی‌داری مطلوبتر بود. بطوریکه بیشترین تعداد گل در سال‌های دوم و سوم آزمایش در تیمار 10RV به ترتیب 78/71 و 22/98 عدد در هر کرت بدست آمد اما سود خالص حاصل از تیمار CH حدود 5/13 برابر بیش از بهترین تیمار این آزمایش (10RV) بود. درمجموع، روند تغییرات صفات طی سه سال آزمایش نشان داد که مزیت مصرف هیومستر سفرون نسبت به سایر تیمارها بیشتر است. لکن توصیه می‌شود در تحقیقات آتی مقادیر بیشتر این کود مورد بررسی قرار گیرد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کود دامی</kwd>
						<kwd>ورمی‌کمپوست</kwd>
						<kwd>وزن بنه</kwd>
						<kwd>هیومستر سفرون</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Arancon, N.Q., Edwards, C.A., Bierman, P., Welch, C., and Metzger, J.D. 2004. Influences of vermin composts on field strawberries: 1. Effects on growth and yields. Bioresource Technology 93: 145–153.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Asadi, G.A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Hassanzadeh Aval, F. 2014. Effects of soil and foliar applications of nutrients on corm growth and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in six year- old farm. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (1): 31-44. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Behdani, M. 2005. The ecological distribution and protection of function fluctuations of saffron in Khorasan. Ph.D. Thesis, Department of agronomy, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A.R., Nassiri, M. and Rezvani Moghadam, P. 2005. Evaluation of quantitative relationships between saffron yield and nutrition (on farm trial). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 3: 1-14. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Chaji, N., Khorassani, R., Astaraei, A.R. and Lakzian, A. 2013. Effect of phosphorous and nitrogen on vegetative growth and production of daughter corms of saffron. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (1): 1-12. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Golzari Jahan Abadi, M., Behdani, M.A., Khorram Del, S., and Sayyari Zohhan, M.H. 2005. The effect of soil conditioners and mother corm weight on growth characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Proceedings of 4th national symposium of saffron, Qaenat, Iran, 4-5 November 2005.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Hassanzadeh Aval, F., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Bannayan Aval, M., and Khorasani, R. 2013. Effects of maternal corm weight and different levels of cow manure on corm and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Saffron Agronomy and Technology 1 (1): 22-39. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Islamic Republic of Iran Meteorological Organization. Available at Web site http://www.irimo.ir/far/services/climate/820.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Juana, J.A.D., Corcolesb, H.L., Munozb, R.M., and Picornella, M.R. 2009. Yield and yield components of saffron under different cropping systems. Industrial Crop Production 30 (2): 212-219.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Kafi, M., Rashed Mohasel, M.H., Koocheki, A., and Mollafilabi, A. 2002. Saffron Production and Processing. Zaban va Adab Press, Mashhad. 280 p. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Kaya, C., Higgs, D., and Kirnak, H. 2001. The effects of high salinity (NaCl) and supplementary phosphorus and potassium on physiology and nutrition development of spinach. Bulgarian Journal of Plant Physiology 27 (3-4): 47-59.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Khademi, K., Sepahvand, A., Siahmansour, R., Mohammadian, A., and Ahmadi, S. 2014. Study of saffron yield in dry land farming and irrigated conditions in a period of six years in the city of Khorramabad province. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (2): 110-119. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Khazaei, M., Monfared, M., Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A., and Sepaskhah, A.R. 2013. The trend of change for weight and number of saffron corms as affected by irrigation frequency and method in different years. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (1): 48-56. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Fallahi, J., Amiri, M.B., and Ehyaei, H.R. 2012. Effect of humic acid application and mother corm weight on some quantitative characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) with emphasized on ecological operations. Proceedings of the 12th Iranian Crop Science Congress. Islamic Azad University, Karaj. Iran. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Jahani, M. Tabrizi, L., and Mohammadi, A.A. 2011a. Investigation on the effect of biofertilizer, chemical fertilizer and plant density on yield and corm criteria of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Water and Soil 25 (1): 196-206. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Karbasi, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2017. Some reasons for saffron yield loss over the last 30 years period (Review Article). Saffron Agronomy and Technology 5 (2): 107-122. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Mollafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2014a. The effects of high corm density and manure on agronomic characteristics and corms behavior of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in the second year. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (2): 144-155. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Seyyedi, M., Azizi, H., and Shahriyari, R. 2014b. The effects of mother corm size, organic fertilizer and micronutrient foliar application on corm yield and phosphorus uptake of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (1): 3-16. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Siahmargouii, A., Azizi, G., and Jahani, M. 2011b. The effect of intensive cropping and depth of corm planting on agronomical properties of saffron and corm gesture. Journal of Agroecology 3 (1): 36-49. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Mittler, R. 2002. Oxidative stress, antioxidants and stress tolerance. Trends Plant Science 7: 405-410.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammad Abadi, A.A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Fallahi, J. 2011. The effects of planting pattern and first irrigation time on growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Agroecology 3 (1): 84-93. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammadzadeh, A.R. 2007. Influence of organic matter from various sources on the yield of saffron. Proceedings of the 10th Congress of Soil Science. Karaj, Iran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Moussa, H.R. 2006. Influence of exogenous application of silicon on physiological response of salt-stressed maize (Zea mays L.). International Journal of Agriculture and Biology 8 (3): 293-297.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Nassiri Mahallati, M., Koocheki, A., Boroumand Rezazadeh, Z., and Tabrizi, L. 2007. Effects of corm size and storage period on allocation of assimilates in different parts of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 5 (1): 155-165. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Osmani Roudi, H., Masoumi, A., Hamidi, H., and Razavi, S.A.R. 2015. Effects of first irrigation data and organic fertilizer treatments on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) yield under Khaf climatic conditions. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 3 (1): 25-33. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Rasouli, Z., Maleki Farahani, S., and Besharati, H. 2013. Some vegetative characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) by various fertilizers. Iranian Journal of Soil Research 27 (1): 35-46. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Sabet Teimouri, M., Kafi, M., Avarseji, Z., and Orooji, K. 2010. Effect of drought stress, corm size and corm tunic on morphoecophysiological characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in greenhouse conditions. Journal of Agroecology 2 (2): 323-334. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Sabzevari, S., Khazaie, H.R., and Kafi, M. 2010. Study on the effects of humic acid on germination of four wheat cultivars (Triticum aestivum L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 8: 473-480. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B. 1993. Effect of Corm Weight on Saffron Flowering. Press of Iranian Research Organization for Scinece and T echnology- Center of Khorasan, p. 52-53. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Salarpour, F., and Farahbakhsh, H. 2016. The effect of salicylic acid on some physiological traits, Yield and yield components of fennel (Foenicum vulgare Mill.) under drought stress. Iranian Journal of Medicinal and Aromatic Plants 32 (2): 216-230. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Shamsi, K. 2010. The effects of drought stress on yield, relative water content, proline, soluble carbohydrates and chlorophyll of bread wheat cultivars. Journal of Animal and Plant Sciences 8 (3): 1051-1060.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Wang M., Zheng, Q., Shen, Q., and Guo, S. 2013. The critical role of potassium in plant stress response. International Journal of Molecular Science 14: 7370-7390._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.109405.1274</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_73904_1df7076806b2318e7d4baad968aa2f92.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی تأثیر کودهای آلی و بیولوژیک بر صفات کمی و کیفی زعفران (Crocus sativus L) در شرایط اقلیمی اردبیل</article-title>
			        <subtitle>بررسی تأثیر کودهای آلی و بیولوژیک بر صفات کمی و کیفی زعفران (Crocus sativus L.) در شرایط اقلیمی اردبیل</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>عالیزاده</surname>
			            <given-names>محمدباقر</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکترای اگروکولوژی گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مکاریان</surname>
			            <given-names>حسن</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>عبادی خزینه قدیم</surname>
			            <given-names>علی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشگاه محقق اردبیلی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>ایزدی دربندی</surname>
			            <given-names>ابراهیم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c5">
			          <name>
			            <surname>غلامی</surname>
			            <given-names>احمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2019</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>227</fpage>
			      <lpage>244</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>04</day>
			          <month>12</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>15</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_73904.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_73904.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>در سال­های اخیر جهت تولید محصولات سالم و کاهش مشکلات زیست­محیطی، از کودهای آلی و زیستی برای افزایش حاصلخیزی خاک، رفع نیاز  تغذیه­ای و افزایش رشد گیاهان استفاده می­شود. به­منظور بررسی تأثیر کودهای آلی و زیستی  بر صفات کمی و کیفی زعفران آزمایشی در دو سال زراعی 95- 1394 و 96- 1395 به­صورت کرت­های خرد شده در قالب طرح بلوک­های کامل تصادفی در سه تکرار در ایستگاه تحقیقات کشاورزی اردبیل اجرا شد. کرت­های اصلی شامل کودهای آلی در سه سطح شاهد، ورمی­کمپوست (10 تن در هکتار) و کود دامی (25 تن در هکتار) و کرت­های فرعی شامل کودهای زیستی در تلقیح با بنه و مخلوط با آب آبیاری در پنج سطح شاهد، ازتوباکتر (Azotobacter sp.PTCC 1658)، سودوموناس آیروژینوس (Pseudomonaaeroginosa)و باسیلوس سوبتیلیس (Bacillus subtilis) و تلفیق آن­ها (Azotobacter sp.PTCC 1658 + Bacillus subtilis +Pseudomonaaeroginosa  ) بودند. نتایج نشان داد که برهمکنش کودهای آلی و زیستی سبب افزایش معنی دار صفات وزن تر گل، عملکرد خشک و تر کلاله و خامه و ترکیبات کیفی شامل کروسین (عامل ایجاد رنگ)، پیکروکروسین (عامل ایجاد طعم) و سافرانال (عامل ایجاد عطر) نسبت به تیمار شاهد گردید. کاربرد کود دامی و ورمی­کمپوست همراه با کاربرد تلفیقی کودهای زیستی (ازتوباکتر، سودوموناس آیروژینوسو باسیلوس سوبتیلیس) عملکرد خشک کلاله را از 86/0 کیلوگرم در هکتار در تیمار شاهد، بترتیب به 93/2 و 70/2کیلوگرم در هکتار در تیمارهای مذکور افزایش داد. همچنین کود دامی همراه با کاربرد توأم کودهای زیستی، میزان پیکروکروسین، سافرانال و کروسین را به­ترتیب 73، 77 و 83 درصد نسبت به تیمار شاهد افزایش داد. با توجه به نتایج این آزمایش، کاربرد توأم کودهای آلی و زیستی ضمن کاهش آلودگی­های زیست محیطی، می تواند از طریق اثرات هم­افزایی باعث افزایش معنی­دار عملکرد کمی و کیفی زعفران شود.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>ازتوباکتر</kwd>
						<kwd>باسیلوس سوبتلیس</kwd>
						<kwd>سافرانال</kwd>
						<kwd>سودوموناس آیروژینوس</kwd>
						<kwd>کود دامی</kwd>
						<kwd>ورمی‌کمپوست</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.101427.1264</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66473_4d09e265ba3f534874eda96b4f7d6411.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>اقتصاد و بازاریابی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>برآورد هزینه‌های زیست‌محیطی انتشار گازهای گلخانه‌ای در مزارع زعفران (مطالعه موردی شهرستان تربت‌حیدریه)</article-title>
			        <subtitle>برآورد هزینه‌های زیست‌محیطی انتشار گازهای گلخانه‌ای در مزارع زعفران (مطالعه موردی شهرستان تربت‌حیدریه)</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نظام الاسلامی</surname>
			            <given-names>امین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجو کارشناسی ارشد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>ابوالحسنی</surname>
			            <given-names>لیلی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>شاهنوشی</surname>
			            <given-names>ناصر</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>کرباسی</surname>
			            <given-names>علیرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c5">
			          <name>
			            <surname>خضری</surname>
			            <given-names>داریوش</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه آمار، دانشگاه میامی، ایالات متحده آمریکا</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2019</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>275</fpage>
			      <lpage>283</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>18</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>27</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66473.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66473.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>تولید زعفران به‌عنوان یکی از گران‌قیمت‌ترین محصول کشاورزی و دارویی جهان، دارای مزیت نسبی بالایی می‌باشد. با توجه به اهمیت تولید این محصول در ایران به‌عنوان یک کالای مهم صادراتی غیرنفتی و راهبردی، برآورد هزینه‌های غیرمستقیم زیست‌محیطی مربوط به انتشار گازهای آلاینده آن ضروری است. هدف از این مطالعه محاسبه برآورد هزینه‌های زیست‌محیطی انتشار گازهای گلخانه‌ای در مزارع زعفران در شهرستان تربت‌حیدریه بود. در این پژوهش برای جمع‌آوری داده‌ها (همچون کودهای شیمایی، آبیاری، نیروی کار، کود حیوانی و سوخت فسیلی) از پرسشنامه و مصاحبه حضوری در سال زراعی 1397-1396 استفاده شد. برای بررسی رابطه بین ستانده خوب و بد از تابع فاصله که به‌صورت فرم ترانسلوگ که پارامتریک می‌باشد استفاده گردید. نتایج نشان داد که مقدار پتانسیل گرمایش جهانی (GWP) 24/369 کیلوگرم معادل  به ازای یک کیلو‌گرم کلاله زعفران محاسبه شد. هزینه زیست‌محیطی گازهای گلخانه‌ای متان، اکسید نیتروژن و دی‌اکسید کربن در یک هکتار با توجه به یک دوره هفت‌ساله به ترتیب 700/888/77، 820/742/212 و 200/289/76 ریال برآورد شد. درمجموع تولید زعفران هزینه‌ای معادل 720/920/366 میلیون ریال بابت انتشار گازهای گلخانه‌ای در یک دوره هفت‌ساله خسارت به محیط‌زیست وارد می‌کند. این میزان برای یک سال زراعی برای یک هکتار معادل با 240/417/52 میلیون ریال است. حدود 21% از درآمد به‌دست‌آمده در هکتار است. در پایان پیشنهاد می‌گردد برای کاهش اثرات زیست‌محیطی نظام تولید زعفران سیاست‌های مالیات بر کاهش مصرف کودهای شیمایی و نظام‌های خاک‌ورزی کاهش‌یافته موردبررسی و تحلیل قرار گیرد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>تابع فاصله</kwd>
						<kwd>پتانسیل گرمایش جهانی</kwd>
						<kwd>ترانسلوگ</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Aghaei, M., and Rezagholizadeh, M. 2011. Iran's comparative advantage in production of saffron. Journal of Agricultural Economics and Development (Science and Technology) 25 (1): 121-132. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Aigner, D.J., and Chu, S.F. 1968. On estimating the industry production function. The American Economic Review 58 (4): 826-839.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Akbari, H., Akbari, Z., and Alireza Loo, A. 2013. A discussion study of comparative advantage of Iranian saffron export. First National Conference on Management and Accounting in the New World of Business, Economics and Culture Ali Abad, Iran, 29 August 2013. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Bakhtiari, A.A., Hematian, A., and Sharifi, A. 2015. Energy analyses and greenhouse gas emissions assessment for saffron production cycle. Environmental Science and Pollution Research 22 (20): 16184-16201.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Brentrup, F., Kusters, J., Kuhlmann, H., and Lammel, J. 2004. Environmental impact assessment of agricultural production systems using the life cycle assessment methodology: I. Theoretical concept of a LCA method tailored to crop production. European Journal of Agronomy 20 (3): 247-264.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Christenson, L.R., Jorgenson, D.W., and Lau, L.J. 1971. Conjugate duality and the transcendental logarithmic function. Econometrica 39 (4): 255-256.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Coelli, T., and Perelman, S. 1999. A comparison of parametric and non-parametric distance functions: With application to European railways. European Journal of Operational Research 117 (2): 326-339.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Coelli, T., Perelman, S., and Romano, E. 1999. Accounting for environmental influences in stochastic frontier models: with application to international airlines. Journal of Productivity Analysis 11 (3): 251-273.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Ebrahimi, A., Bouzarjamhari, P., and Razavani Moghaddam, P. 2009. The role of crop cultivation of saffron in rural economy. M.Sc. Thesis, Faculty of Literature and Humanities, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Eslami, I., Mehrabi, A., Zehtabian, GH., and GHorbani, M. 2012. Estimation of agricultural water demand function in pomegranate gardens in Charkhob Village of Yazd. Journal of Rangeland and Watershed Management. Iranian Journal of Natural Resources 66 (1): 17-26. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Fare, R., Grosskopf, S., Lovell, C.K., and Yaisawarng, S. 1993. Derivation of shadow prices for undesirable outputs: a distance function approach. The Review of Economics and Statistics 374-380.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Fare, R., and Primont, D. 1995. Multi-output Production and Duality: Theory and Applications. Kluwer Academic Publishers, Massachusetts.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Ghorbani, M., Darijani, A.S., Koocheki, A.S., and Motallbi, M. 2008. Estimated environmental costs of greenhouse gas emissions in dairy cattle of Mashhad. Agricultural Economics and Development 17 (66): 43-68. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Griffin, R.C., Montgomery, J.M., and Rister, M.E. 1987. Selecting functional form in production function analysis. Western Journal of Agricultural Economics 216-227.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Grosskopf, S. 1996. Statistical inference and nonparametric efficiency: A selective survey. Journal of Productivity Analysis 7 (2): 161-176.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Halter, A.N., Carter, H.O., and Hocking, J.G. 1957. A Note on the Transcendental Production Function cx 1 a 1 e b 1 x 1 x 2 a 2 e b 2 x 2. Journal of Farm Economics 39 (4): 966-974.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Huang, H., and Leung, P. 2007. Modeling protected species as an undesirable output: The case of sea turtle interactions in Hawaii's longline fishery. Journal of Environmental Management 84 (4): 523-533.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>ISO, I. 2006. 14040: Environmental management–life cycle assessment–principles and framework. London: British Standards Institution.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Kafi, M., Hemmati Kakhki, A., and Karbasi, A. 2002. History, Economic Significance and Area under Cultivation, Production and Applications of saffron Iran, Technology of Production and Processing. Ferdowsi University Press, Mashhad. p. 21-38. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Karbasi, A., and Rategaripour, F. 2014. Evaluation of comparative advantage on production and export of saffron. Saffron Agriculture and Technology Journal 2 (1): 59-74. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Khanali, M., Elhami, A., and Movahedi, M. 2015. Evaluation of energy and environmental indicators of saffron production in Southern Khorasan Province by Life Cycle Assessment Method (Case Study: Birjand). International Conference on Science, Engineering and Environmental Technologies, Tehran, Iran, 15-16 May 2015. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Khanali, M., Farahani, S.S., Shojaei, H., and Elhami, B. 2017. Life cycle environmental impacts of saffron production in Iran. Environmental Science and Pollution Research 24: 4812–4821.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Khanali, M., Movahedi, M., Yousefi, M., Jahangiri, S., and Khoshnevisan, B., 2016. Investigating energy balance and carbon footprint in saffron cultivation–a case study in Iran. Journal of Cleaner Production 115: 162-171.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Khorramdel, S., Abolhassani, L., and Azam Rahmati, A. 2016. The investigating environmental impact of saffron production system using life cycle assessment method (Case Study: Torbat-e Heydarieh and Qaen). Saffron Research Journal (Two Quarterly) 4 (2): 248-292. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Khorramdel, S., and Gholizadegan, E. 2016. Study of greenhouse gas emissions and global warming potential of potato production systems. The first international conference and the 4th National Conference on Environmental Research and Agriculture in Iran, 5 November 2016. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Khorramdel, S., Rezvani Moghadam, P., Amin Ghafouri, A., and Golizadegan Ehsan Abad, AS. 2014. Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) of wheat production systems in the country. First National Congress on Food Health: Production, Conversion, Consumption, Karaj, Iran, 24 October 2014. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Khorramdel, S., Rezvani Moghadam, P., and Amin Ghafouri, A. 2017. Economic evaluation of services and functions of saffron production systems in Khorasan Razavi province. Scientific Journal of Saffron Agriculture and Technology. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Kozehgaran, S., Mousavi Baygi, M., Sanaee Nejad, H., and Behdani M. 2011. Survey the minimum, Average and maximum temperature in South Khorasan to identify areas susceptible to cultivating saffron using GIS. Water and Soil Journal (Science and Technology) 25 (4): 895-907. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Mola Filabi, A., Khoramdel, S., Aminghafori, A., and Hosseini, M., 2015. Evaluation of environmental impacts for saffron agroecosystems of Khorasan based on nitrogen fertilizer by using Life Cycle Assessment (LCA). Journal of Saffron Research 2 (2): 152-166. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Molaei, M., Hesari, N., and Javanbakht, A. 2017. Estimation of environmental efficiency of input-oriented agricultural products (Case Study: environmental efficiency of rice production). Journal of Agricultural Economics 11 (2): 157-172. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Muthu, S.S. 2014. Assessment of carbon footprint in different industrial sectors (2). Springer Science and Business.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Najarzadeh, R., Reed, M.R., Saghaian, S.H., Aghaei, M., and Rezagholizadeh, M. 2010. A Study of Iran’s Comparative Advantage in Saffron, the Red Gold. Agricultural and Applied Economics Association, In 2010 Annual Meeting, Denver, Colorado (No. 61583), USA, 25-27 July 2010.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Nalabandi, L., Dashti, GH., and Ajali, J. 2014. Comparative assessment of factors using economy of wheat production in small and large farms of Ahar County. Journal of Agricultural Science and Sustainable Production 23 (2): 85-96. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Nikkhah, A., Emadi, B., and Firouzi, S. 2015. Greenhouse gas emissions footprint of agricultural production in Guilan province of Iran. Sustainable Energy Technologies and Assessments 12: 10-14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>O’Brien, D., Shalloo, L., Crosson, P., Donnellan, T., Farrelly, N., Finnan, J., Hanrahan, K., Lalor, S., Lanigan, G., Thorne, F., and Schulte, R. 2014. An evaluation of the effect of greenhouse gas accounting methods on a marginal abatement cost curve for Irish agricultural greenhouse gas emissions. Environmental Science and Policy 39: 107-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Saffron Institute. 2013. Article. Available at website http://si.torbath.ac.ir/article</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Sardashi Hatami, Z., Bakhshi, M., and Jami Al ahmadi, M. 2014. Economic analysis of saffron production in Southern Khorasan Province. Ecological Agriculture Magazine 4 (1): 33-42. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, S.M. 2013. Determining Sample Size. Retrieved February, 23.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Soltani, A., Bazrgar, A., Koocheki, A., Zeinali, A., Ghaemi, A.S., and Hajjarpour, A. 2015. Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) in different systems in Khorasan. Journal of Crops Production 8 (1): 43-62. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Tohidi, Z. 2014. Study of how to plant and harvest saffron in Iran. Third National Conference Scientific and Research Achievements on saffron, Torbat-e Heydarieh, Iran, 5-6 December 2014. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Tosan, M., Alizadeh, A., Ansari, H., and Rezvani Moghaddam, P. 2015. Performance evaluation identification of susceptible areas of saffron cultivation in Khorasan Razavi province based on temperature indices. Saffron Agriculture and Technology Journal 3 (1): 1-12. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>International Energy Agency (IEA). 2016. Statistics. Available at Website www.iea.org _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.100615.1261</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66474_c7d566c90c1acea7b76a7d8ad6e6eb05.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی عوامل اجتماعی-اقتصادی اثرگذار بر سیستم ناپایدار کشت پر تراکم زعفران (مطالعه موردی: شهرستان گناباد)</article-title>
			        <subtitle>بررسی عوامل اجتماعی-اقتصادی اثرگذار بر سیستم ناپایدار کشت پر تراکم زعفران (مطالعه موردی: شهرستان گناباد)</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رمضانی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمدرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی مقطع کارشناسی ارشد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی دانشکده اقتصاد و توسعه‌ی دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رفیعی</surname>
			            <given-names>حامد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی دانشکده اقتصاد و توسعه دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نوروزی</surname>
			            <given-names>حسین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی مقطع دکتری تخصصی گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی دانشکده اقتصاد و توسعه‌ی دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2019</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>275</fpage>
			      <lpage>283</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>27</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66474.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66474.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>شهرستان گناباد در استان خراسان رضوی یکی از مناطق عمده کشت زعفران در کشور به شمار می‌رود که متأسفانه عملکرد مزارع زعفران این شهرستان طی سالیان اخیر کاهش چشم­گیری داشته است. بررسی‌های میدانی و نظرات مهندسین کشاورزی حاکی از آن است که کشت متراکم زعفران می‌تواند به عنوان یکی از دلایل کاهش عملکرد مطرح باشد. زیرا کشت متراکم این محصول اگرچه که باعث شروع زودتر دوره بهره‌برداری می‌شود، اما به دلیل ایجاد رقابت بین بنه‌ها، بر عملکرد گیاه در سال‌های بعد اثر منفی دارد و طول دوره بهره برداری را کاهش می‌دهد. ضمن این­که امکان کشت مجدد زعفران در آن مزرعه تا مدتی طولانی وجود نخواهد داشت. از این رو پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی تأثیر تراکم کشت بر عملکرد مزارع زعفران و تعیین عوامل اجتماعی- اقتصادی اثرگذار بر سیستم ناپایدار کشت پرتراکم زعفران صورت پذیرفت. به منظور  تحلیل داده‌ها از مدل هکمن دو مرحله‌ای که شامل یک الگوی پروبیت و یک الگوی رگرسیون خطی می‌باشد، در یک دوره 6 ساله طی سال‌های 1390 تا 1395 استفاده گردید. در نهایت متغیرهای سن، آگاهی کشاورزان نسبت به عوامل کاهش عملکرد، و شرکت در کلاس‌های آموزشی و ترویجی به عنوان عواملی شناخته شدند که تأثیر منفی و معنی‌داری بر تراکم کشت داشته و از این جهت می‌توانند موجب جلوگیری از کشت پرتراکم این محصول شوند.  متغیرهای درآمد و سطح تحصیلات اثر مثبت و معنی‌داری بر تراکم کشت دارند و اثر متغیر بیمه محصولات کشاورزی در هیچ‌کدام از دو مدل معنی‌دار نیست. لذا آگاهی ‌بخشی به کشاورزان از طریق کلاس‌های آموزشی و ترویجی و همچنین استفاده از تجارب کشاورزان مسن و باتجربه به منظور جلوگیری از کشت پرتراکم این محصول توصیه می‌شود.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>الگوی هکمن دو مرحله‌ای</kwd>
						<kwd>سیستم ناپایدار</kwd>
						<kwd>شهرستان گناباد</kwd>
						<kwd>زعفران</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Aghazadeh, R., and Hemmatzadeh, A. 2012. The effect of date, depth and spacing cultivation on vegetative and reproductive traits in Maku city. Quarterly Journal of New Science of Sustainable Agriculture 8 (1): 2-10. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Agricultural Jihad Organization of Gonabad. 2017. Available at http://www.koaj.ir.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Azizi-Zohan, A.A., and Pasandideh, M. 2013. The role of soil  in unsustainable production of saffron after a period of cultivation. Journal of Land Management 1 (1): 92-98. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Bouzarjmehri, KH., Shikh Ahmadi F., and Javani kh. 2016. Investigating financial impacts of cultivating saffron on rural families with an emphasis on sustainable agriculture (Case study: Balavelayat rural district, city of Bakharz). Saffron Agronomy and Technology 4 (1): 63-73. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Cheng, H.T., and Capps, O. 1988. Demand analysis of fresh and frozen finfish and shellfish in the United States. American Journal of Agricultural Economics 70 (3): 533-542.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Dadashian, M., Dashti, Gh., Hayati, B., and Ghahremanzade, M. 2015. The combined use of AHP and TOPSIS technique for determining the weighted criteria and evaluation of agricultural sustainability (Case study: Selected counties of east Azarbaijan province). Journal of Agricultural Knowledge and Sustainable Production 25 (1): 146-157. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Eskandari-Damaneh, H., Noroozi, H., Khosravi, H., Rafiee, H., and Taheri Rykande, E. 2015. Feasibility of implementing “low-crop planting” in order to restore Jazmoryan wetland (Case study: Jiroft county). Rural Development Strategies 2 (3): 287-297. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Fallahi, H.R., Alami, S., Behdani, M.A., and Aghhavani Shajari, M. 2015. Evaluation of local and scietific knowledge in saffron agronomy (Case study: Sarayan). Journal of Saffron Research 3 (1): 31-50. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>FAO. 2016. Food and Agriculture Organiation of the United Nations. Available at www.fao.org.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>FAO. 2017. The state of food security and nutrition in the world. Available at www.fao.org/ag.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Farahani, H., Javani, Kh., and Karami, E. 2012. Assessment of socio-economic sustainability of saffron production and its effect on rural development (Case study: Bala-Velayat village of Torbat Heydariyeh county). Quarterly Journal of Space Economics and Rural Development 1 (2): 95-112. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Geresta, F., Avola, G., Lombardoa, G.M., Siracusa, L., and Ruberto, G. 2009. Analysis of flowering, stigmas yield and qualitative traits of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) as affected by environmental conditions. Scientia Horticulturae 119 (1): 320-324.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Golmohammadi, F. 2014. Saffron and its farming, economic importance, export, medicinal characteristics and various uses in South Khorasan province- East of Iran. International Journal of Farming and Allied Sciences 3 (5): 566-596.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Haji Rahimi, M., and Torkamani, J. 2003. Assessment of the role of agriculture sector in the economic growth of Iran: Application of path analysis method. Agricultural Economics and Development 11 (41): 71-84. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Hatami-Sardashti, Z., Jami-Alahadi, M., Mahdavi-Damghani, A., and Behdani, M. 2011. Assessment Sustainability in Saffron Farms of Birjand and Qayen townships. Journal of Agroecology 3 (3): 396-405. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Heckman, J. 1976. The common structure of statistical models of truncation, sample selection and limited dependent variablesand a simple estimator for such models. Journal of Economic and Social Measurement 5 (4): 475-492.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Judge, G., Hill, C., Griffiths, W., Lee, T., and Lutkepol, H. 1982. Introduction to the Theory and</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Practice of Econometrics. New York.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A. 2006. Effect of corm size with and without storage on allocation of assimilate in different parts of saffron plant. 2nd International Symposium of Saffron Biology and Technology, Mashhad, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Siahmargouyi, A., Azizi, G., and Jahani, M. 2011. The effect of high-density planting and cultivation death of bulk on saffron crop charasterictics and bulks behaviour. Journal of Agroecology 3 (1): 36-49. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Lichtfouse, E., Navarrete, M., Debaeke, P., Souchère, V., Alberola, C., and Ménassieu, J. 2009. Agronomy for sustainable agriculture: a review. Sustainable Agriculture 29 (1): 1-6.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Mehta, S., Rupela, O., Bisht, S., Nayak, A.K., and Hegde, N.G. 2010. Improving the livelihoods of the resource-poor smallholder farmers and producers in developing countries: An urgent appeal for action by GCARD. Global Conference on Agricultural Research for Development, Montpellier, France, 28‐31 March 2010. p. 1-29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Ministry of Agriculture Jihad. 2015. The MAJ database. Available at Web site http://www.maj.ir. (verified 5 December 2015).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammad-Abadi, A., Rezvani-Moghaddam, P., and Fallahi, H.R. 2011. Effects of planting pattern and the first irrigation date on growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Medicinal Plants National Congress, Mazandaran, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Naderi-Darbaghshahi, M.R., and Khajeh-Bashi, A. 2008. The effect of planting method, density and depth on yield and exploition period of saffron. Seed Plant Journal 24 (1): 643-657. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation> Nemati, A., Iravani, H., and Asadi, A. 2014. Analysis of sustainability condition of potato cultivation in Bahar plain of Hamedan province. Economics and Iran Agricultural Development Researches 45 (3): 451-465. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Parent, D., Bélanger, V., Vanasse, A., Allard, G., and Pellerin, D. 2013. Method for the Evaluation of Farm Sustainability in Quebec, Canada: The Social Aspect. In: Marta-Costa A., Soares da Silva E. (eds) Methods and Procedures for Building Sustainable Farming Systems. Springer, Dordrecht.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Salami, H., and Ahmad Abadi, M.E. 2001. Application of Tobit econometric model and Two-stage Heckman method in determining factors affecting suger beet production in Khorasan province. Iranian Journal of Agricultural Sciences 32 (2): 433-445. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Sharifzadeh, M.Sh. 2014. Entrepreneurial sustainable agriculture: in search of a facilitating approach for developing entrepreneurial agro-enterprises. Journal of Entrepreneurship in Agriculture 1 (1): 103-112. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Tatlidil, F.F., Boz, I., and Tatlidil, H. 2009. Farmers’ perception of sustainable agriculture</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>and its determinants: a case study in Kahramanmaras province of Turkey. Environment, Development and Sustainability 11 (1): 1091-1106.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Tavakoli, J. 2014. Urbanization of agriculture and its social consequences in village (Case study: Southern Mirang village, Delfan county). Village Researches 5 (4): 875-892. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Temperini, O., Rea, R. 2009. Evaluation of saffron production in Italy: Effects of the age of saffron field and plant density. Journal of Food Agriculture and Environment 7 (1): 19-23.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Tobin, J. 1958. Estimation of relationships for limited dependent variables. Econometrica  26 (1): 24-36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Torkamani, J. 2000. Analysis of economic, technical efficiency and marketing of Iranian saffron, Science and Technology of Agriculture and Natural Resources 4 (3): 29-44. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Tosan, M., Alizadeh, A., Ansari, H., and Rezvani Moghadam, P. 2015. Evaluation of yield and identifying potential regions for saffron (Crocus sativus L.) cultivation in Khorasan Razavi province according to temprature parameters. Saffron and Agronomy Technology 3 (1): 1-12. (In Persian with English Summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Zulfiqar, F., and Thapa, G.B. 2017. Agricultural sustainability assessment at provincial level in Pakistan. Land Use Policy 68 (1): 492–502._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی کوتاه" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.95424.1253</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66476_60ba87740c2bd52c6b5df2b72dd3811e.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>سایر موضوعات مرتبط با زعفران</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تحلیل اثرات روانشناختی اجتماعی (امنیت شغلی و کیفیت زندگی کاری) بر افزایش رضایت شغلی زعفران‌کاران شهرستان بافق</article-title>
			        <subtitle>تحلیل اثرات روانشناختی اجتماعی(امنیت شغلی و کیفیت زندگی کاری) بر افزایش رضایت شغلی زعفران‌کاران شهرستان بافق</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>جماعتی اردکانی</surname>
			            <given-names>راضیه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>مربی گروه روانشناسی، دانشکده علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی، دانشگاه اردکان.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>06</month>
			        <year>2019</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>275</fpage>
			      <lpage>283</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>04</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>27</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2019, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2019</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66476.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66476.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>احساس امنیت شغلی و بهبود کیفیت زندگی کاری از جمله عواملی هستند که ممکن است رضایت شغلی زعفران­کاران را تأثیر قرار دهد و باعث افزایش کارایی آنان شود. هدف از پژوهش حاضر تحلیل اثرات روانشناختی اجتماعی (امنیت شغلی و کیفیت زندگی کاری) در افزایش رضایت شغلی زعفران­کاران شهرستان بافق بود که با استفاده از تحلیل همبستگی انجام گرفته است. جامعه آماری شامل تمامی زعفران­کاران شهرستان بافق بودند که با استفاده از جدول مورگان نمونه­ای به حجم 205 نفر به روش نمونه­گیری تصادفی ساده انتخاب شدند و با پرسشنامه­های امنیت شغلی، کیفیت زندگی کاری و رضایت شغلی مورد آزمون قرار گرفتند. داده­ها با استفاده از روش­های آماری ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و رگرسیون خطی تجزیه و تحلیل شدند. نتایج نشان داد که امنیت شغلی و کیفیت زندگی کاری رابطه معنی­داری با رضایت شغلی داشتند (01/0&gt;p). همچنین امنیت شغلی و کیفیت زندگی کاری به طور معنی­داری رضایت شغلی را پیش­بینی کردند (001/0&gt;p). نتایج تحقیق حاکی از آن است که این دو متغیر (امنیت شغلی و کیفیت زندگی کاری)، متغیرهای مهمی در جهت رضایت شغلی مطلوب در زعفران­کاران بودند، بنابراین پیشنهاد می­شود سازمان­های کشاورزی مربوطه سعی کنند محیط کاری امن، جالب و برانگیزاننده به وجود آورند تا تعهد، خلاقیت و سختکوشی افزایش یابد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>امنیت شغلی</kwd>
						<kwd>رضایت شغلی</kwd>
						<kwd>زعفران‌کاران</kwd>
						<kwd>کیفیت زندگی کاری</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Dales, B. 1997. Personnel, the mamagement of people at work. Max Well Macmillian International Edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Dunnette, M.D. 1996. Handbook of industrial and organizational psychology. 1: 1297-1343.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Fourie, A.S. 2004. Predicting satisfaction with quality of work life. Master thesis, University of South Africa.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Ghorbani, F., Khosravani, V., Jamaati, R., Alvani, A., and Akbari, H. 2016. The mediating effects of cognitive emotion regulation strategies on the relationship between alexithymia and physical symptoms: Evidence from Iranian asthmatic patients. Psychiatry Research 247: 144-151.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Hadizadeh Talasaz, Z., Nourani Saadoldin, S., and Shakeri, M.T. 2015. Relationship between components of quality of work life with job satisfaction among midwives in Mashhad. Hayat21 (1): 56-67.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Harrington, B., and Ladge, J.J. 2009. Corporate social accounting in Australasia. Research in Corporate Social Performance and Policy 7 (1): 251-277.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Jahani, Z. 2004. The relationship between Teacher's Job satisfaction with advancement motivation and teaching skills. Master's Thesis, Allameh Tabataba'i University. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Khaleghi Sorosh, F. 1988. Systematic review of employees' job security. M.Sc. Thesis, Tehran University, School of Management. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Khosravani, V.,  Alvani, A.,  Sharifi Bastan, F., Jamaati, R.,  and Akbari, H. 2016. The alexithymia, cognitive emotion regulation, physical symptoms in Iranian asthmatic patients. Journal of Personality and Individual Differences 101: 214-219.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Kloep, M., and Tarifa, F. 1994. Working conditions, work style, and job satisfaction among Albanian teachers. International Review of Education 40 (2): 159-172.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Koustelios, A., Kouli, O., and Theodorakis, N. 2003. Job security and job satisfaction among Greek fitness instructors. Perceptual and Motor Skills 97 (1): 192-194.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Krueger, P., Brazil, K., Lohfeld, L., Edward, H. G., Lewis, D., and Tjam, E. 2002. Organization specific predictors of job satisfaction: findings from a Canadian multi-site quality of work life cross-sectional survey. BMC Health Services Research 2 (1): 6.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Li, J., and Yeo, R.K. 2011. Quality of work life and career development: perceptions of part-time MBA students. Employee Relations 33 (3): 201-220.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Lillydahl, J.H., and Singell, L.D. 1993. Job satisfaction, salaries and unions: The determination of university faculty compensation. Economics of Education Review 12 (3): 233-243.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Loo Sees, B. 2005. Quality of work life and job performance among Malaysian executives in the electrical and electronics industry in Selangor. Ph.D. Desertation. University Putra Malaysia.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Mirkamali, S.M. 2004. Behavior and Relation in Organization and Management. (3nd Ed). Yastoroon Publication, Tehran. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Mosadeghrad, A.M., Ferlie, E., and Rosenberg, D. 2008. A study of the relationship between job satisfaction, organizational commitment and turnover intention among hospital employees. Health Services Management Research 21 (4): 211-227.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Mouhr, A.T., and Puck, J.F. 2007. Role conflict, general manager job satisfaction and stress and the performance of IJVs. European Management Journal 25 (1): 25-35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Nekouei, M.H., Othman, M., Masud, J., and Ahmad, A. 2014. Quality of work life and job satisfaction among employee in government organizations in IRAN. Journal of Basic and Applied Scientific Research 4 (1): 217-229.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Özer, G., and Günlük, M. 2010. The effects of discrimination perception and job satisfaction on Turkish public accountants’ turnover intention. African Journal of Business Management 4 (8): 1500-1509.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Saghaeian, R. 2011. Relationship between job security and organizational justice with job performance of employees of National Iranian Drilling Company in Ahvaz city, Master's thesis, Islamic Azad University, Marvdasht Branch. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>San Park, J., and Hyun Kim, T. 2009. Do types of organizational culture matter in nurse job satisfaction and turnover intention?. Leadership in Health Services 22 (1): 20-38.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Saraji, G.N., and Dargahi, H. 2006. Study of quality of work life (QWL). Iranian Journal of Public Health 35 (4): 8-14. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Sarmad, GH. 1993. Organizational Behavior. Tehran: Iran Banking Institute. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Sirgay, M.J., Efraty, D., Siegel, P., and Lee, D.J. 2001. A new measure of quality of work life (QWL) based on need satisfaction and spillover theories. Social Indicators Research 55 (3): 241-302.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Spector, P. E. 1997. Job Satisfaction. London: Sage Publications Thousand Oaks.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Sy, T., Tram, S., and O’Hara, L.A. 2006. Relation of employee and manager emotional intelligence to job satisfaction and performance. Journal of Vocational Behavior 68 (3): 461-473.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Tavakoli, A., Lagzian, M., Davodniya, A., and Alizade Zavarm., A. 2014. Investigating the relationship between quality of working life based on Walton's model and job satisfaction (Case Study: Razavi Khorasan Gas Company). Journal of Change Management 9 (3): 89-103. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Tsai, P.C.F., Yen, Y.F., Huang, L.C., and Huang, C. 2007. A study on motivating employees’ learning commitment in the post-downsizing era: Job satisfaction perspective. Journal of World Business 42 (2): 157-169.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Walton, R.F. 1973. Quality of work life: what is it?. Sloan Management Review, Fall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Zeinali Pour H., Noor Rahmani M., and Qureshi A. 2014. The study of relationship between quality of work life and job satisfaction of high school teachers in Bandar Abbas. American Journal of Life Science Research 2 (1): 118-124._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>