<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1397</YEAR>
<VOL>6</VOL>
<NO>1</NO>
<MOSALSAL>19</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>121</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر پرایمینگ هورمونی و وزن بنه بر عملکرد گل و خصوصیات بنه‌های دختری زعفران در سال اول</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Effect of hormone priming and corm weight on the yield of flowers and characteristics of daughter corms of saffron in the first year</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران یکی از مهم‌ترین محصولات کشاورزی و دارویی ایران است که نقش مهمی در صادرات غیرنفتی دارد. با وجود این‌که ایران بیش‌ترین سطح زیر کشت را دارا می‌باشد ولی میزان عملکرد آن در مقایسه با تولید جهانی اندک است. این پژوهش به‌منظور بررسی عملکرد گل و خصوصیات کمّی بنه­های دختری زعفران تحت تأثیر پرایمینگ تنظیم‌کننده‌های رشد گیاهی و دو اندازه مختلف بنه به صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح بلوک کامل تصادفی در چهار تکرار، تحت شرایط گلدانی در مزرعه تحقیقاتی پردیس ابوریحان- دانشگاه تهران اجرا شد. بنه‌های بزرگ (10-8 گرم) و کوچک (5-3 گرم) مادری زعفران با اسیدجیبرلیک‌ (GA3)، سایتوکینین (BA) و اکسین (IBA) با غلظت ppm250 به صورت مجزا و قبل از کاشت پرایمینگ هورمونی شدند. صفاتی از قبیل زمان شروع گلدهی، تعداد و عملکرد گل، وزن‌تر گل، وزن‌تر و خشک کلاله، تعداد و وزن بنه‌های دختری حاصل از بنه­های مادری اندازه‌گیری شدند. نتایج این تحقیق نشان داد که کاربرد بنه بزرگ با وزن 8 الی 10 گرم در مقایسه با بنه کوچک در تمام صفات به‌جز شروع گلدهی در سطح احتمال 1% تفاوت معنی‌دار دارد. کاربرد هورمون سایتوکینین در مقایسه با شاهد برای تمام صفات به‌جز آغاز گلدهی و وزن بنه‌های دختری در سطح احتمال 1% تفاوت معنی‌دار نشان داد. کاربرد هورمون جیبرلین نیز گلدهی را تسریع نمود و در کورم مادری بزرگ وزن بنه‌های دختری را 56% نسبت به شاهد افزایش داد و با شاهد در سطح احتمال 1% اختلاف معنی‌دار داشت. اکسین (IBA) در صفت تعداد گل با شاهد اختلاف معنی­دار نداشت و برای سایر صفات نیز باوجود اینکه از شاهد بهتر بود، با دو تیمار BA و GA3 دارای اختلاف معنی­دار بود. بطورکلی نتایج نشان داد که کاربرد بنه مادری بزرگ به‌همراه پرایمینگ هورمونی آنها با استفاده از BA و GA3 عملکرد گل و بنه زعفران را در سال اول بهبود خواهد بخشید.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron is one of the most important crops and medicinal plants in Iran and plays an important role in non-oil exports of the country. Although Iran has the largest area under cultivation of saffron, its yield is low compared with global production. The main objective of this study is to investigate the yield of flowers and quantitative characteristics of daughter corms under the effects of application of plant growth regulators priming and two different corm sizes. A factorial experiment arrangement in RCBD with four replications was conducted, under the terms of pot at the College of Aburaihan-University of Tehran, Iran during 2015. Small (3-5g) and large (8-10g) mother corm sizes were hormonal priming by gibberelic acid (GA3), cytokinin (BA), auxin (IBA) with 250 ppm concentration and before cultivation. The start of flowering, number and flowers yield, fresh weight of flower, fresh and dry weight of stigma, number and weight of daughter corms per mother corms were measured. The results showed that in all traits except the start of flowering large corms weighing of 8 to 10 g were cultivated in comparison with small corms and this was significant at the 1% level. Application of cytokinins hormone in comparison with control for all traits except the start of flowering and weight of daughter corms showed a significant difference at 1%. Application of gibberellic acid hormone treatment also accelerated flowering. In addition, it increased the weight of daughter corms by 56% in large mother corms compared to control and this had a significant difference from control at 1%. Auxin (IBA) in the number of flowers had no significant difference with control and also in other traits, although IBA was better than control, with both BA and GA3 treatments had a significant difference. The results indicated that the use of large mother corms with hormonal priming with BA and GA3 will improve flower and corm yield in the first year.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>3</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>15</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مرجان سادات</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسینی فرد</Family>
						<NameE>Marjan Sadat</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hoseinifard</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، گروه علوم زراعی و اصلاح نباتات، پردیس ابوریحان، دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، گروه علوم زراعی و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.hoseinifard@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قربانی جاوید</Family>
						<NameE>Majid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghorbani Javid</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه علوم زراعی و اصلاح نباتات، پردیس ابوریحان، دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه علوم زراعی و اصلاح نباتات،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mjavid@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ایرج</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اله دادی</Family>
						<NameE>Iraj</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Allahdadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه علوم زراعی و اصلاح نباتات، پردیس ابوریحان، دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه علوم زراعی و اصلاح نباتات، پردیس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>alahdadi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>الیاس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سلطانی</Family>
						<NameE>Elias</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Soltani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه علوم زراعی و اصلاح نباتات، پردیس ابوریحان، دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه علوم زراعی و اصلاح نباتات،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>elias.soltani@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اسید جیبرلیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سایتوکینین</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلاله</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>وزن بنه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Amirghasemi, T. 2004. Saffron, Red Gold of Iran. Nashr- Ayandegan Publication. 112 pp. (In Persian).##Amirshekari, H., Soroushzadeh, A., Modares Sanavi, A., and Jalali Joran, M. 2006. Study of effects of root temperature, corm size, and gibberellin on underground organs of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Biology 19 (1): 5-18. (In Persian with English Summary).##Arteca, R.N. 2000. Plant Growth Sustances Principles and Application. Translated by: Fathi, G. and Esmaielpour, B. Publications University of Mashhad. 72: 161-162.##Asthir, B., Kaur, A., and Basra, A.S. 1998. Do phytohormones influence the uptake and metabolism of sucrose in spikelets of wheat? Phyton Horn 38: 293–299.##Azizbikova, N.S.H., and Milaeva, E.L. 1978. Saffron Cultivation in Azerbaijan. In: Negbi. M.(ed). Crocus Sativus L. Harwood Academic Publishers. Australia. p. 63-71.##Azizi-Zehan, A.A., Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A., and Sepaskhah, A.R. 2008. Crop and pan coefficients for saffron in a Semi-arid region of Iran. Journal of Arid Environments 72: 270-278.##Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Jami Al-Ahmadi, M. 2008. Agroecological zoning and potential yield of saffron in Khorasan-Iran. Journal of Biological Sciences 8 (2): 298-305. (In Persian with English Summary).##Chrungoo, N.K., and Farooq, S. 1984. Influence of GA and NAA on the yield and growth of saffron. Indian Journal of Plant Physiology 27: 201-205.##Davis, P.J. 1988. Plant Hormones and their Role in Plant Growth and Development. Kluwer Academic Publishers. 432 pp.##De Juan, A., Moya, A., L˴pez, S., Botella, O., L˴pez, H., and Munoz, R. 2003. Influence of the corm size and the density of plantation in the yield and the quality of the production of corms of Crocus sativus L. ITEA 99: 169-180.##Dhua, R.S., Ghosh, S.K., Mitra, S.K., Yadav, L.P., and Bose, T.K. 2005. Effect of bulb size, temperature treatment of bulbs and chemicals on growth and flower production in tuberose. Acta Horticulture 205: 121-128.##Greenberg-Kaslasi, D. 1991. Vegetative and reproductive development in the saffron corms (Crocus Sativus L.). M.Sc Thesis, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem.##Gresta, F., Lombardo, G.M., Siracusa, L., and Ruberto, G., 2008. Effect of mother corm dimension and sowing time on stigma yield, daughter corms and qualitative aspects of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in a Mediterranean environment. Journal Science Food Agriculture 88: 1144–1150.##Hanks, G.R. 1984. Factors affecting the response of tulips to gibberllin. Scientia Horticulturae 23: 3-390.##Koocheki, A. 2013. Research on production of Saffron in Iran: Past trend and future prospects. Saffron Agronomy &amp; Technology 1 (1): 3-21. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Ganjeali, A., and Abbassi, F. 2007. The effect of duration and condition of incubation, weight of mother corms and photoperiod on corm and shoot characteristics of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal Field Crops Research 4: 315–331. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Nassiri, M., and Behdani, M.A. 2006. Agronomic attributes of saffron yield at agroecosystems scale in Iran. Proceedings of the 2nd International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Technology. Mashhad, Iran, 28-30 October 2006, p. 33-40.##Leite, V.M., Rosolem, C.A., and Rodrigues, J.D. 2003. Gibberlin and Cytokinin effects on soybean growth. Scientia Agricola 60: 537-541.##Letham, D.S. 1994. Cytokinins as phytohormones-sites of biosynthesis, translocation, and function of translocated cytokinin. In: Mok, D.W.S., Mok, M.C. (eds) Cytokinins: Chemistry, Activity, and Function. CRC Press, Boca Raton, FL, p. 57–80.##Long, R.L., Williams, K., Griffiths, E.M., Flematti, G.R., Merritt, D.J., Stevens, J.C., Turner, S.R.,  Powles, S.B., and Dixon, K.W. 2010. Prior hydration of Brassica tournefortii seeds reduces the stimulatory effect of karrikinolide on germination and increases seed sensitivity to abscisic acid. Annals of Botany 105: 1063-1070.##Mashayekhi, K., Soltani, A., and Kamkar, B. 2006. The relationship between corm weight and total flower and leaf numbers in saffron. In proceedings 2nd International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Technology, 28-30th October 2006, Mashhad, Iran, p. 93-96.##Matthew, G., Blanchard, M., Erik, and Runkle, S. 2008. Benzyladenine Promotes Flowering in Doritaenopsis and Phalaenopsis orchids. Journal of Plant Growth Regulation 27:141–150.##Molina, R.V., Valero, M., Navarro, Y., Guardiola J.L., and Garcia-Luice, A. 2005. Temperature effects on flower formation in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Scientia Horticulturae 103: 361-379##Mortezainejzhad, F., and Etemadi, N. 2010. Effect of gibberellic acid on the quality of flowers and flowering Salvia (Polianthes tuberosa L.). Journal of New Agricultural Science 6 (18): 89- 96.  (In Persian).##Nassiri Mahallati, M., Koocheki, A., Boroumand Rezazadeh, Z., and Tabrizi, L. 2007. Effects of corm size and storage period on allocation of assimilates in different parts of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 5: 155-166. (In Persian with English Summary).##Omidbaigi, R. 2005. Effect of corms weight on quality of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) Indian Journal of Natural Products and Resources 4 (3): 193-194.##Perme, Z., Mohebi, R., Nabizade, A., and Hosseini, M.A. 2010. Export capacity and target bazaars of Iranian saffron. Journal of Stound Research of Economics 51: 59-95.##Renau-Morata, B., Nebauer, S.G., Sánchez, M., and Molina, R.V. 2012. Effect of corm size, water stress and cultivation conditions on photosynthesis and biomass partitioning during the vegetative growth of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Indian Crop Product 39: 40-46.##Sadeghi, B. 1996. effect of warehousing and planting dates on flowering corms of saffron. Iranian Research Organization for Science and Technology, Khorasan Institute.##Setia, N., Sangeetha, R., Setia, R.C., and Malik, C.P. 1993. Alterations in growth and yield componse to foliar application of naphthyl acetic acid (NAA). Indian Journal Plant physiology 1: 47-52.##Sheibani, M., Nemati, S., Davarinejad, G., Azghandi, A., and Habashi, A. 2007. Induction of somatic embryogenesis in saffron using thidiazuron (TDZ). Acta Horticulturae 10 (20): 3564-3570.##Taiz, L., and Zeiger, E. 2010. Plant Physiology, Fifth edition. Translated by: Kafii, M., Zand, E., Kamkar, B., Abasi, F., Mahdavi, M. Publications University of Mashhad. p: 337, 347, 368, 381, 383.##Teixcia, D.S., and Jaime, A. 2003. The cut flower, postharvest condition. Biological Science Journal 3: 406-442.##Zaferanchi, S., Safari, M., Safari, V., and Mohamadinejad, G. 2011. The effect of plant growth regulators, naphthalene acetic acid and benzyl amino purine and performance characteristics of four genotypes of sesame. Journal of Crop Production in Environmental stress (2): 49-62.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اثر کاربرد کمپوست و ترکیب کمپوست و بیوچار بر جرم مخصوص ظاهری خاک بستر کاشت و میزان ظهور و رشد اولیه گیاهچه اکوتیپ‌های زعفران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The effect of compost and combination of compost and biochar application in soil bulk density of planting bed, seedling emergence rate and early growth of saffron ecotypes</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>ظهور جوانه زعفران به فشردگی و ساختمان خاک حساس است. جرم مخصوص ظاهری خاک به عنوان مهم­ترین شاخص کیفیت فیزیکی خاک معرفی می­شود. بر این اساس این آزمایش با هدف بررسی اثر کاربرد کمپوست و کمپوست-بیوچار در بستر کاشت بر میزان ظهور و رشد اولیه گیاهچه اکوتیپ­های زعفران و ارتباط آن با جرم مخصوص ظاهری خاک انجام شد. تیمارهای آزمایش شامل بسترهای کاشت (بدون افزودن ماده آلی (شاهد)، اختلاط 20 تن کمپوست در هکتار و اختلاط 10 تن کمپوست+ 8 تن بیوچار (مواد سلولزی درختان جنگلی) در هکتار) و اکوتیپ­های مختلف زعفران (بجستان، استهبان، فردوس، گناباد، نطنز، قائن، سرایان، تربت حیدریه و زرند) بودند. داده­های حاصل از آزمایش در قالب طرح بلوک­های کامل تصادفی بین بسترهای کشت مورد تجزیه مرکب قرار گرفت. نتایج نشان داد کاربرد کمپوست و کمپوست-بیوچار، پارامترهای ظهور جوانه اصلی و جوانه­های فرعی و همچنین پارامترهای رشد برگ را نسبت به شاهد بهبود داد. در بین اکوتیپ­ها زرند، تربت حیدریه و استهبان نسبت به سایر اکوتیپ­ها پاسخ متفاوتی از نظر درصد و سرعت ظهور جوانه اصلی به نوع بستر کاشت نشان دادند. تنوع قابل توجهی در بین اکوتیپ­ها از نظر تمام پارامترهای مورد مطالعه مشاهده شد که بیانگر سازگاری اکوتیپ­ها به شرایط اقلیمی منشأ بنه بود. به­طور کلی اکوتیپ­های بجستان، فردوس و قائن از نظر سطح و وزن خشک برگ برتری نشان دادند. کمپوست و کمپوست-بیوچار به­طور معنی­داری (12 درصد) موجب کاهش جرم مخصوص ظاهری خاک نسبت به شاهد شدند. تجزیه رگرسیون خطی نشان داد بین جرم مخصوص ظاهری و پارامترهای مورد بررسی ارتباط منفی وجود داشت و کاهش معنی­داری در تمام پارامترهای مورد بررسی با افزایش جرم مخصوص ظاهری مشاهده شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Emergence of saffron buds is sensitive to soil compaction and structure. Soil bulk density is introduced as the most important index of soil physical quality. Accordingly, this study was done to evaluate the effect of compost and compost-biochar in planting bed on the emergence and early seedling growth of saffron ecotypes and its relationship to soil bulk density. Experimental treatments consisted of planting beds (without any organic amendment (control), incorporation of 20 t.ha-1 compost and 10 t.ha-1 compost+ 8 t.ha-1 biochar (cellulosic material of hardwood)) and different ecotypes of saffron (Bajestan, Estahban, Ferdows, Gonabad, Natanz, Qaen, Sarayan, Torbate-Heydarieh and Zarand). Data obtained from experiment were subjected to combined analysis of variance among planting beds based on randomized complete block design. The results showed that application of compost and compost+biochar, improved emergence of the main and lateral buds as well as leaf growth parameters compared to the control. Zarand, Torbate-Heydarieh and Estahban ecotypes responded differently to the planting bed types in terms of emergence percent and rate of main bud compared to other ecotypes. Considerable variation was observed among the ecotypes in terms of all studied parameters, which indicated the adaptability of ecotypes to climatic conditions of corm provenance. Generally, the Bajestan, Ferdows and Qaen ecotypes showed superiority in terms of leaf area and dry weight. Compost and compost-biochar significantly (12%) reduced the soil bulk density compared to the control. Linear regression analysis indicated that there was a negative relationship between soil bulk density and the studied parameters, and significant decrease in all parameters was observed with increasing of soil bulk density.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>17</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>33</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جلال</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قنبری</Family>
						<NameE>Jalal</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghanbari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری زراعت، انجمن پژوهشگران جوان، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری زراعت، انجمن پژوهشگران جوان،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>jghanbari_62@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خواجویی نژاد</Family>
						<NameE>Gholamreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khajoei-Nejad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه شهید باهنر کرمان.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه شهید</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khajoei@uk.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بستر کاشت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرعت ظهور</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ظهور گیاهچه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فشردگی خاک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کودهای آلی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Agegnehu, G., Bass, A.M., Nelson, P.N., Muirhead, B., Wright, G., and Bird, M.I. 2015. Biochar and biochar-compost as soil amendments: Effects on peanut yield, soil properties and greenhouse gas emissions in tropical North Queensland, Australia. Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment 213: 72-85.##Amlinger, F., Peyr, S., Geszti, J., Dreher, P., Karlheinz, W., and Nortcliff, S. 2007. Beneficial effects of compost application on fertility and productivity of soils. Literature Study, Federal Ministry for Agriculture and Forestry. Environment and Water Management, Austria, Retrieved from: www.umweltnet.at/filemanager/download/20558/.##Behdani, M.A., and Fallahi, H.R. 2015. Saffron: Technical knowledge based on research approaches, University of Birjand Press. 411 p. (In Persian).##Bushman, B.S., Johnson, D.A., Connors, K.J., and Jones, T.A. 2015. Germination and seedling emergence of three semiarid Western North American legumes. Rangeland Ecology and Management 68 (6): 501-506.##Case, S.D.C., McNamara, N.P., Reay, D.S., and Whitaker, J. 2012.The effect of biochar addition on N2O and CO2 emissions from a sandy loam soil the role of soil aeration. Soil Biology and Biochemistry 51: 125-134.##Celik, I., Gunal, H., Budak, M., and Akpinar, C. 2010. Effects of long-term organic and mineral fertilizers on bulk density and penetration resistance in semi-arid Mediterranean soil conditions. Geoderma 160: 236-243.##Czyz, E.A. 2004. Effects of traffic on soil aeration, bulk density and growth of spring barley. Soil and Tillage Research 79: 153-166.##Dam, R.F., Mehdi, B.B., Burgess, M.S.E., Madramootoo, C.A., Mehuys, G.R., and Callum, I.R. 2005. Soil bulk density and crop yield under eleven consecutive years of corn with different tillage and residue practices in a sandy loam soil in central Canada. Soil and Tillage Research 84: 41-53.##daSilva, A.P., and Kay, B.D. 1996. The sensitivity of shoot growth of corn to the least limiting water range of soils. Plant and Soil 184: 323-329.##deJuan, J.A., Corcoles, H.L., Muñoz, R.M., and Picornell, M.R. 2009. Yield and yield components of saffron under different cropping systems. Industrial Crops and Products 30: 212-219.##Estefan, G., Sommer, R., and Ryan, J. 2013. Methods of Soil, Plant, and Water Analysis: A manual for the West Asia and North Africa region. 3rdeds. Copyright © ICARDA (International Center for Agricultural Research in the Dry Areas) Box 114/5055, Beirut, Lebanon. 244 pp.   ##Fischer, D., and Glaser, B. 2012. Synergisms between compost and biochar for sustainable soil amelioration. In S.E. Kumar (eds). Management of Organic Waste. In Tech., Shanghai, China. p. 167-198.##Ghafourian, H. 2016. Nano-Biochar, Biochar, Charcoal and Coal Based Biochar, Design of Pyrolysis Reactors Production Methods and Application. Amazon Kindle, 1st Edition, 116 pp.##Gresta, F., Lombardo, G.M., Siracusa, L., and Ruberto, G. 2008. Saffron, an alternative crop for sustainable agricultural systems. A review. Agronomy for Sustainable Development 28: 95-112.##Guo, L., Wu, G., Li, Y., Li, C., Liu, W., Meng, J., Liu, H., Yu, X., and Jiang, G. 2016. Effects of cattle manure compost combined with chemical fertilizer on topsoil organic matter, bulk density and earthworm activity in a wheat-maize rotation system in Eastern China. Soil and Tillage Research 156: 140-147.##Khorramdel, S., Eskandari Nasrabadi, S., and Mahmoodi, G. 2015. Evaluation of mother corm weights and foliar fertilizer levels on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) growth and yield components. Journal of Applied Research on Medicinal and Aromatic Plants 2: 9-14.##Koocheki, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2015. Relationship between nitrogen and phosphorus use efficiency in saffron (Crocus sativus L.) as affected by mother corm size and fertilization. Industrial Crops and Products 71: 128-137.##Kucera, B., Cohn, M.A., and Leubner-Metzger, G. 2005. Plant hormone interactions during seed dormancy release and germination. Seed Science Research 15: 281-307.##Latif, N., Khan, M.A., and Ali, T. 2008. Effects of soil compaction caused by tillage and seed covering techniques on soil physical properties and performance of wheat crop. Soil and Environment 27: 185-192.##Lazcano,  C., Sampedro, L., Zas, R., and Domínguez, J. 2010. Vermicompost enhances germination of the maritime pine (Pinus pinaster Ait.). New Forests 39: 387-400.##Lehmann, J., and Joseph, S. 2009. Biochar for environmental management: an introduction. In J. Lehmann and S. Joseph (eds). Biochar for Environmental Management: Science and Technology. Earthscan, London, p. 1-12.##Maguire, J.D. 1962. Speed of germination—aid in selection and evaluation for seedling 458 emergence and vigor. Crop Science 2: 176-177.##Melnyk, J.P., Wang, S., and Marcone, M.F. 2010. Chemical and biological properties of the world&#039;s most expensive spice: Saffron. Food Research International 43: 1981-1989.##Mukherjee, A., Lal, R., and Zimmerman, A.R. 2014. Effects of biochar and other amendments on the physical properties and greenhouse gas emissions of an artificially degraded soil. Science of the Total Environment 487: 26-36.##Nash, H.M., and Selles, F. 1995. Seedling emergence as influenced by aggregate size, bulk density, and penetration resistance of the seedbed. Soil and Tillage Research 34: 61-76##Orchard, T.J. 1977. Estimating the parameters of plant seedling emergence. Seed Science and Technology 5: 61-69.##Renau-Morata, B., Nebauer, S.G., Sanchez, M., and Molina, R.V. 2012. Effect of corm size: water stress and cultivation conditions on photosynthesis and biomass partitioning during the vegetative growth of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Industrial Crops and Products 39: 40-46.##Sadras, V.C., O&#039;Leary, G.J., and Roget, D.K. 2005. Crop responses to compacted soil: capture and efficiency in the use of water and radiation. Field Crops Research 91: 131-148.##Soane, B.D., and Van Ouweerkerk, C. 1995. Implications of soil compaction in crop production for quality of the environment. Soil and Tillage Research 35: 5-22.##Sohi, S., Krull, E., Lopez-Capel, E., and Bol, R. 2010. A review of biochar and its use and function in soil. Advances in Agronomy 105: 47-82.##Solaiman, Z.M., Murphy, D.V., and Abbott, L.K. 2012. Biochars influence seed germination and early growth of seedlings. Plant and Soil 353: 273-287.##Tammeorg, P., Simojoki, A., Makela, P., Stoddard, F.L., Alakukku, L., and Helenius, J. 2014. Short-term effects of biochar on soil properties and wheat yield formation with meat bone meal and inorganic fertiliser on a boreal loamy sand. Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment 191: 108-116.##Van Zwieten, L., Kimber, S., Morris, S., Chan, K.Y., Downie, A., Rust, J., Joseph, S., and Cowie, A. 2010. Effects of biochar from slow pyrolysis of papermill waste on agronomic performance and soil fertility. Plant and Soil 27: 235-246.##Wilson, M.G., Sasal, M.C., and Caviglia, O.P. 2013. Critical bulk density for a Mollisol and a Vertisol using least limiting water range: Effect on early wheat growth. Geoderma 192: 354-361.##Zhang, A.F., Cui, L.Q., Pan, G.X., Li, L.Q., Hussain, Q., Zhang, X.H., Zheng, J.F., and Rowley, D. 2010. Effect of biochar amendment on yield and methane and nitrous oxideemissions from a rice paddy from Tai Lake plain China. Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment 139: 469-475.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تاثیر دگرآسیبی گیاه زعفران (.Crocus sativus L) برخصوصیات جوانه زنی و رشدگیاهچه جو وحشی (Hordeum spontaneum)و مرغ (Agropayron repense)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Allelopathic effects of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) on germination and seedling growth characteristics of wild barley (Hordeum spontaneum) and couch grass (Agropayron repense)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>به‌منظور بررسی خصوصیات جوانه‌زنی و رشد اولیه گیاهچه دو علف هرز جو وحشی (Hordeum spontaeum)  و مرغ (Agropayron repense) تحت تأثیر غلظت­های عصاره آبی بنه و برگ زعفران (.Crocus sativus L) دو آزمایش مجزا برای هریک از گونه‌ها به‌صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح کاملاً تصادفی با سه تکرار در آزمایشگاه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی بیرجند در سال 1394 انجام شد. تیمارهای آزمایش شامل دو نوع اندام زعفران در دو سطح (برگ و بنه) و غلظت عصاره در پنج سطح (0، 0.5 ،1، 1.5 و 2 درصد وزنی- حجمی عصاره آبی) بود. نتایج نشان داد که غلظت­های مختلف عصاره برگ و بنه زعفران درصد جوانه­زنی هر دو گونه علف هرز را کاهش داد. کمترین درصد و سرعت جوانه­زنی جو وحشی و مرغ به­ترتیب از تیمارهای دو درصد عصاره‌ی برگ و دو درصد عصاره بنه حاصل شد. همچنین غلظت­های متفاوت عصاره برگ و بنه، شاخص­های طول ریشه‌چه، وزن­تر گیاهچه و وزن خشک گیاهچه را به‌طور معنی­داری کاهش داد. برازش مدل لجستیک سه پارامتری، رابطه بین سطوح مختلف عصاره آبی و درصد جوانه‌زنی بذور جو وحشی  و مرغ را به‌خوبی توجیه نمود. همچنین مقایسات گروهی بین عصاره برگ و بنه زعفران نشان داد که اثر بازدارندگی عصاره برگ و بنه برای هر دو علف هرز یکسان بوده و تفاوت معنی­داری با یکدیگر نداشتند. به‌طورکلی نتایج نشان داد که عصاره برگ زعفران بیشترین تأثیر را بر جو وحشی و عصاره بنه بیشترین تأثیر را بر علف هرز مرغ داشتند. لذا نتایج این تحقیق­، تأییدکننده این مطلب است که می­توان از اثرات دگرآسیبی زعفران، جهت کاهش این دو علف هرز در مزرعه بهره جست.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In order to evaluate the allelopathic effects of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm and leaf aqueous solution on germination characteristics and preliminary growth of weed species including wild barley (Hordeum spontaneum) and couch grass (Agropayron repense) two separate experiments for each species were conducted at the research laboratory of the School of Agriculture of the University of Birjand in 2016. A factorial experiment in a completely randomized design with three replications was conducted for each species. The factors included saffron organs at two levels (leaves and corms) and water extract concentrations at 5 levels (0, 0.5, 1, 1.5 and 2 percent). The results indicated that the lowest seed germination percentage of wild barley and couch grass were observed at a concentration of 2% of leaf and concentration of 2% of corm, respectively. The results indicated that the lowest rate of germination of wild barley and couch grass were observed at a concentration of 2% of leaf and corm extract, respectively. Different concentrations of leaf and corm extracts significantly decreased the length of radicle, seedling fresh weight and seedling dry weight of two weeds. The logistic model provided a successful estimation of the relationship between leaf water extract and germination percentage of two weeds. Based on orthogonal comparison tests, the allelopathic inhibitory effects of saffron leaves and corms were the same for two weeds. The results showed that leaf extract of saffron the most influence on wild barley and corm extract of saffron the best effect on couch grass. Therefore, results of this study, confirm that can be used the allelopathic effects of saffron to reduce these two weeds in the field.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>35</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>48</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قسمتی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghesmati</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد علوم باغبانی، گرایش فیزیولوژی گیاهان دارویی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد علوم باغبانی، گرایش</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.gh0781@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امینی فرد</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammed Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aminifard</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیارگروه باغبانی و مرکز پژوهشی گیاهان ویژه منطقه، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیارگروه باغبانی و مرکز پژوهشی گیاهان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mh.aminifard@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>معصومه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عبدالهی</Family>
						<NameE>Masume</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Abdollahi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد علوم باغبانی، گرایش فیزیولوژی گیاهان دارویی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد علوم باغبانی، گرایش</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>masumeabdollahi71@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>معصومه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شاکری</Family>
						<NameE>Masume</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shakeri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد علوم باغبانی، گرایش فیزیولوژی گیاهان دارویی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد علوم باغبانی، گرایش</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.shakeri@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>علف هرز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عصاره آبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>طول ریشه چه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>وزن خشک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abbasi, F., and Jahani, M. 2007. Allelopathic effects of saffron corms on seed germination of several important crops. International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Technology, Mashhad, Iran, pp. 250-256.##Alimoradi, L., Azizi, G., Jahani, M., Siah-Marguee, A., and Keshavarzi, A. 2008. Allelopathy as an alternative method for weed control in saffron fields: A suitable approach to sustainable agriculture. Competition for resources in a changing world: New drive for rural development, Stuttgart, p.127-145. (In Persian).##Alipoor, Z., and Mahmoodi, S. 2015. Allelopathic effects of leaf and corm water extract of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) on germination and seedling growth of flixweed (Descurainia sophia L.) and downy brome (Bromus tectorum L.). Saffron Agronomy and Technology 3:13-24. (In Persian with English Summary).##Amirghasemi, T. 2001. Saffron, Iranian Red gold. Cultural Institution Publication Posterity Press. p.70-110.##Asgarpour, R., Khajeh-Hosseini, M., and Khorramdel, S. 2015. Effect of aqueous extract concentrations of saffron organs on germination characteristics and preliminary growth of three weed species. Journal of Saffron Research 3 (1): 81-96.##Asgharipour, M.R., Rashed-Mohassel, M.H., Rostami, M., and Eizadi, E. 2006. The allelopathic potential of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) on following crop in rotation. International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Technology, Mashhad, Iran, 28-30 October p. 48p.##Azizi, M., Alimoradee, L., and Rashed-Mohassel, M.H. 2006. Allelopathic effects of Bunium persicum and Cuminum cyminum essential oils on seed germination of some weeds species. Iranian Journal of Medicinal and Aromatic Plants 22: 198-208. (In Persian).##Bohm, P.A.F., Zanardo, F.M.L., and Ferrarese, O. 2006. Peroxidase activity and lignification in soybean root growth-inhibition by juglone. Biologia Plantarum 50 (2): 315-317##Brown, P.D., and Morra, M.J. 1996. Hydrolysis products of glucosinolates in Brassica napus tissues as inhibitors of seed germination. Plant and Soil 181:307-316.##Chauhan, B.S., Gill, G., and Preston, C. 2006. Factors affecting seed germination of annual             sowthistle (Sonchus oleraceus) in southern Australia. Weed Science 54: 854-860.##Drost, D.C., and Doll, J.D. 1980. The allelopathic effect of yellow nutsedge (Cyperus esculentus) on corn (Zea mays L.) and soybean (Glycine max). Weed Science  28: 229-233.##Eghbali, S., Rashed-Mohassel, M.H., Nassiri-Mahallati, M., and Kazerooni-Monfared, E. 2007. Allelopathic potential of shoot and corm of saffron residues on wheat, rye, vetch and bean. Iranian Journal of Agricultural Research 6: 227-234. (In Persian).##Fernandez, J.A., Escribano, J., Piqueras, A., and Medina, J. 2000. A glycoconjugate from corms of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.) inhibits root growth and affects in vitro cell viability. Journal of Experimental Botany 51: 731-742.##Ghiazdowsk, A., Oracz, K., and Bogatek, R. 2007. Phytotoxic effect of sunflower leaf extracts on##germinating mustard (Sinapis alba L.) seeds. Allelopathy Journal 19: 215-226.##Hartman, H., Kester, D., and Davis, F. 1990. Plant propagation, principle and practices. Prentice Hall Imitational Editions. 647 p.##Hasani, M.R., and Khalajzadeh, S. 2011. Allelopathic effects of aerial plant water extract of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) on germination and seedling growth of Cichorum (Cichorium sativa L.). Seventh Congress Iranian Horticultural Science, Isfahan University of Technology. (In Persian with English Summary).##Hashemi Nia, S.M., Nassiri Mahallati, M., and Keshavarzi, A. 2009. Determining the threshold salinity and appropriate temperature and their combined effects on germination of Cuminum cyminum. Iranian Journal of Agricultural Research 7 (1): 303-310.##Hejazi, A. 2000. Allelopathy. Tehran University Press. p. 324-325. (In Persian).##Hojatian Far, M., Bagherzadeh, A., Asaadi, M.R., and Rahnama, O. 2011. Allelopathic effects of agricultural waste products on germination and seedling growth characteristics of maize single cross 704. First National Conference on New Issues in Agriculture. Islamic Azad University of Saveh. ( In Persian with English Summary).##Kohli, R.K., Singh, H.P., and Batish, D.R. 2001.Allelopathy in Agroecosystems. Food Products Press, USA, 447 p.##Kruse, M., Strandberg, M., and Strandberg, B. 2000. Ecological effects of allelopathic Plants. A review National Environment Research Institute, Sikleborg, Denmark. 66 p.##Lydon, J.R., Rele, T., and Chen, P.K. 1997.Allelopathic activity of annual ormwood (Artemisia annua) and the role artemisinin. Weed Science 45: 807-811.##Makkizadeh, M., Salimi, M., and Farhoudi, R. 2009. Allelopathic effect of rue (Ruta graveolens L.) on seed germination of three weeds. Iranian Journal Medicinal Aromatic Plants 24: 463-471. (In Persian).##Meyghani, F. 2003. Allelopathy from Concept to Application. Incident Beam Press. p. 41-107.##Mojab, M., and Mahmodi, M. 2008. Allelopathic effects of shoot and root water extracts of Hoary cress (Cardaria draba) on germination characteristic and seedling growth of Sorghum (Sorghum bicolor L.). Crop Production 1 (4): 65-78. (In Persian with English Summary).##Narwal, S.S., and Tauro, P. 1996. Allelopathy in pests management for sustainable agriculture. Proceding of the International Conference on Allelopathy. New Delhi, India. 1: 67-76.##Qasem, J.R. 1992. Pigweed (Amaranthus spp.) interference in transplanted tomato (Lycopersicom esculentum). Horticultural Science 67: 421-427.##Qomi, S., and Tavili, A. 2012. Inhibitory effect growth of salvia (Salvia sclarea L) on some seed germination characteristics downy brome (Bromus tomentellus Boiss). Iranian Journal of Seed Science and Technologhy 1: 201-211. (In Persian).##Ramezani, S., Saharkhiz, M.J., Ramezani, F., and Fotokian, M.H.  2008. Use of essential oils as bioherbicides. Journal of Essential Oil Bearing Plant 11: 319-327.##Rashed Mohassel, M. 1990. Weeds Identifies of South Khorasan Saffron. Industrial and Scientific Publications Research Organization of Iran –Central Khorasan.##Shaykra,  A., and Bukhtiar, B. 1990. Drought  tolerance in lentil. Differential genotypic response to drought. Journal of Agricultural Research 28:117 -126.##Soltanipor, M., Hajebi, A., Dastjerdi, A., and Ebrahimi, S. 2007. Allelopathic effects of aqueous extract of Zhumeria majdae on seed germination of seven species of vegetables. Iranian Journal of Medicinal and Aromatic Plants 23 (1): 51-58. (In Persian with English Summary).##Steinsiek, J.W., Oliver, L.R., and Collins, F.C. 1982. Allelopathic potential of wheat (Triticum aestivum) straw on selected weed species. Weed Science 30: 495-497.##Taheri, K., Saboora, A., and Kiarostami, K. 2011. Allelopathic effect of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) on germination and seedling growth of four sorghum (Sorghum bicolor L.) cultivars. Iranian Journal of Biology 24: 89-103. (In Persian).##Ture, M.A., and Tawaha, A.M. 2002. Inhibitory effects of aqueous extracts of black mustard on germination and growth of lentil. Pakistan Journal of Agronomy 1: 28-30.##Younesi, O., Sharifzadeh, F., Fatahi, F., and Pirozi, B. 2008. Study of allelopathic effects of rye and wheat on germination and early growth of lambsquarter (Solanum nigrum L.) and black nightshade (Chenopodium album). Journal of Resarch in Agriculturral Science 4: 41 -49. (In Persian with English Summary).##Zand, A., Rahimian, M., Ashhadi, H., Koocheki, A., Khalghani, J., Mosavi, K., and Ramzani, K. 2004. Weed Ecology (Application Management). Mashhad University Press. 558 p. (Translated in Persian).##Zeinali, E., and Ehteshami, M.R. 2003. Biology and Control of Important Weed Species. Gorgan University Press. p. 4-8. (In Persian).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تعیین قابلیت تصاویر ماهواره ای لندست 8 در تخمین سطح زیر کشت زعفران (نمونه موردی: شهرستان تربت حیدریه)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Capability of Landsat 8 satellite images to estimate the area under cultivation of saffron (case study: city of Torbat Heydarieh)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران محصولی استراتژیک است و برآورد سطح زیرکشت و در نهایت برآورد میزان تولید آن در محدوده­های جغرافیایی خاص، لازمه برنامه‌ریزی و تصمیم‌گیری‌های مقتضی جهت انجام مبادلات اقتصادی و تجاری می‌باشد. بنابراین، سرعت و دقت در این قبیل ارزیابی‌ها از اهمیت بالایی برخوردار است. استفاده تکنیک‌های سنجش از دور، به دلیل فراهم آوردن داده‌های به هنگام و قابلیت بالای آنالیز تصاویر و همچنین امکان مطالعه در یک محدوده وسیع و با دقت قابل قبول، می‌تواند کمک شایانی در این ارزیابی‌ها ایفا نماید. در این مطالعه به‌منظور تعیین قابلیت تصاویر ماهواره‌ای لندست 8 در برآورد و ارزیابی سطح زیرکشت محصول زعفران در شهرستان تربت‌حیدریه، پس از اعمال پیش ‌پردازش‌های اولیه بر روی تصاویر ماهواره‌ای با استفاده از روش‌های معمول پردازش تصاویر ماهواره‌ای، از جمله ترکیب باندی رنگ کاذب، آنالیز مؤلفه‌های اصلی، شاخص‌های گیاهی (NDVI، SAVI، EVI، DVI، RVI و TSAVI) و طبقه‌بندی نظارت‌شده اراضی تحت کشت زعفران شناسایی شدند. جهت ارزیابی صحت نتایج طبقه‌بندی، نقشه تولیدی با نقاط واقعیت زمینی مشخص‌شده از طریق GPS مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. ضـریب کاپـا و صـحت کلـی به ترتیب 88 و 98 درصد محاسبه شد. مساحت سطح زیر کشت زعفران در این مطالعه 4572/19503 هکتار برآورد گردید که با توجه به آمار سازمان جهاد کشاورزی مبنی بر 22000 هکتار سطح زیر کشت زعفران این شهرستان در سال 1393، می‌توان بیان داشت که تصاویر ماهواره‌ای لندست 8 از قابلیت بالایی برای تفکیک سریع اراضی زعفران در منطقه و تعیین سطح زیر کشت با دقت نسبتاً مناسب در مقیاس منطقه‌ای برخوردار است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron is a strategic product. It is necessary to manage the programming principles in order to estimate acreage and production. Therefore, the speed and accuracy of such assessments is very important. Using remote sensing techniques for providing updated data and high functionality as well as the possibility of studying a wide range of image analyses with an acceptable precision can help in the assessment.  In the present research, the area under cultivation of saffron in the city of Torbat Heydarieh was evaluated using Landsat 8 sensor data. After applying the primary processing on satellite images with using conventional techniques, satellite imagery processing including false color band combination, principal component analysis, vegetation index (NDVI, SAVI, EVI, DVI, RVI and TSAVI) and supervised classification of land under saffron cultivation were identified. Map production was done due to the fact that the earth was assessed via GPS in order to assess the classification. Kappa coefficient and overall accuracy were %88 and %98, respectively. The area under cultivation of saffron in this study was estimated to be 19503.4572 hectares. The results indicated that Landsat 8 satellite images have a high potential for rapid separation and identification of the area under cultivation of saffron in the region with relatively good accuracy and are appropriate tools to be used on a regional scale.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>49</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>60</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جلیل</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فرزادمهر</Family>
						<NameE>Jalil</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Farzadmehr</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>farzadm102000@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>کاظم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>تباکی بجستانی</Family>
						<NameE>Kazem</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tabaki Bajestani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد، بیابان زدایی، دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد، بیابان زدایی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>k.tabaki@na.iut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سنجش از دور</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سطح زیر کشت زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>LDCM</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Alavi-Panah, S.K. 2013. The application of remote sensing in earth science (soil science). Tehran University Publications, Tehran. (In Persian).##Alavi-Panah, S.K. 2015. Fundamentals of Modern Remote Sensing and Interpretation of Satellite Images and Aerial Photos. Tehran University Publications, Tehran. (In Persian).##Alipour, F., Agh Khani, M.H., Abaspour Fard, M.H., and Sepehr, A. 2014. Separation and estimate the area under cultivation of crops with the help of satellite images ETM+ (case study: farm Astan Quds Razavi). Journal of Agricultural Machinery 4 (2): 244-254. (In Persian).##Alizadeh Rabie, H. 2013. Remote Sensing (principles and application), Samt Publications, Tehran. (In Persian).##Farzadmehr, J., Arzani, H., and Nazari Samani, A.A. 2005. An investingation of the capability of multi-temporal data of Landsat 7 satellite in estimating vegetation cover and production (Case study: arid region, Saveh, Bakhshali-Nemati). Iranian Journal Natural Resource 58 (3): 719-729. (In Persian with English Summary).##Farzadmehr, J., Arzani, H., Darvishsefat, A.A., and Jafari, A. 2005. Investigation in estimating vegetation cover and phytomass production, using enhanced Ladsat data in a semi arid region. Iranian Journal Natural Resource 57 (2): 339-351. (In Persian with English Summary).##Jensen, J.R. 1996. Textbook: Introductory Digital Image Processing: Radiometric and Geometric Correction. Prentice and Hall Inc, New York.##Khajeddin, S.J., and Pourmanafi, S. 2007. Determination of rice paddies areas, using digital data IRS sensors around Zayandeh Rud in Isfahan region. Journal of Science and Technology of Agriculture and Natural Resources, Water and Soil Sciences 11 (1): 513-527. (In Persian).##Korhonen, L., Korhonen, K.T., Rautiainen, M., and Stenberg, P. 2006. Estimation of forest canopy cover: a comparison of field measurement techniques. Silva Fennica 40: 577-588.##Lillesand, T.M., and Kife, R.W. 2000. Remote Sensing and Image Interpretation. John Willey and Sons, New York.##Masoud, A.A., and Koike, K. 2005. Arid land salinization detected by remotely-sensed land cover changes: A case study in the Siwa region, NW Egypt. Journal of Arid Environments 66: 151-167.##Schmidt, H., and Karnicli, A. 2000. Remote sensing in the Seasonal variability of vegetation in a semi – arid envrionment. Journal of Arid Environments 45: 43-59.##Silleos, N.G., Alexandridis, T.K., Gitas, J.Z., and Perakis, K. 2006. Vegetation indices: advances made in biomass estimation and vegetation monitoring in the last 30 years. Geocarto International 21 (4): 21-28.##Tabaki Bajestani, K., Khajeddin, S.J., Mokhtari, A.R., and Jafari, R. 2014. Identifying geothermal resources using remotely sensed data (Case study: South Khorasan province, Ferdows). Iranian Remote Sensing and GIS 6 (2): 31-49. (In Persian).##Tong, P.H.S., Auda, Y., Populus, J., Aizpuru, M., Al Habshi, A., and Blasco, F. 2004. Assessment from space of mangroves evolution in the Mekong Delta, in relation to extensive shrimp farming. International Journal Remote Sensing 25 (21): 4795-4812.##Wardlow, D.B., Eghbert, L.E., and Castens, j.H. 2007. Analysis of time-series MODIS 250 m vegetation index data for crop classification in the U.S. central great plains. Journal of Remote Sensing of Environment 108: 290-310##Ziaeian-Firoozabadi, P., Sayad-Bydhndy, L., and Eskandari-Nodeh, M. 2009. Mapping and estimating the area under rice cultivation in Sari city using satellite images Radarst. Geography Research Natural 68: 45-58. (In Persian).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی بیماری‌زایی گونه Alternaria alternata روی برگ و کورم زعفران در آزمایشگاه و گلخانه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigation of Alternaria alternata pathogenicity on corm and leaves of saffron in vitro and greenhouse conditions</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تولید زعفران، با ارزش‌ترین گیاه دارویی و ادویه‌ای شرق ایران، تحت تأثیر بیمارگرهای مختلفی قرار می‌گیرد. این تحقیق با هدف جداسازی، شناسایی و بررسی بیماری‌زایی جدایه‌های Alternaria alternata به‌عنوان عامل پوسیدگی کورم و برگ گیاه زعفران، در سال‌های 94-1393 با نمونه‌برداری از خاک و بافت‌های گیاهی نواحی مختلف دشت بیرجند صورت گرفت. جدایه‌های قارچی به کمک محیط کشت عصاره سیب­زمینی دکستروز آگار جداسازی و خصوصیات ریخت‌شناسی آن‌ها بر روی محیط کشت سیب­زمینی هویج آگار بررسی شد. دی­ان­آی ژنومی جدایه‌های قارچی به روش CTAB استخراج و زیر واحدهای ریبوزومی به کمک آغازگرهای ITS1 و ITS4 تکثیر گردیدند. آزمون بیماری‌زایی جدایه‌ها بر روی گیاه زعفران به سه روش تلقیح برگ‌های بریده‌شده، تلقیح کورم زعفران در شرایط آزمایشگاهی و تلقیح گیاه زعفران درون گلخانه انجام شد. بر اساس خصوصیات ریخت‌شناسی، 80 جدایه A. alternata در این تحقیق از دشت بیرجند شامل شهرستان­های بیرجند، خوسف و سربیشه جداسازی گردیدند. در آزمون‌های بیماری‌زایی، پس از 3 تا 5 روز، برگ‌های بریده‌شده در محل تلقیح ابتدا کلروز و سپس نکروز بافت­ها مشاهده گردید. کورم‌ها در محل تلقیح پوسیده‌شده و برگ‌های گیاهان تلقیح­شده در گلخانه نیز دچار زردی و خشکیدگی شدند. شدت پوسیدگی و توسعه آن در جدایه‌های مختلف تقریباً یکسان و پس 5 از روز غده‌های آلوده، پوسیده­شده و بافت برگ­ها نکروزه گردیدند. توالی ناحیه ITS جدایه‌­ها 100 درصد با توالی جدایه‌های A. alternata بانک ژن شباهت داشتند و در شجره فیلوژنتیکی با آن‌ها در یک گروه قرار گرفتند. نتایج این تحقیق نشان داد که A. alternata پتانسیل ایجاد پوسیدگی کورم، لکه­برگی، کلروز و نکروز برگ‌های زعفران را در صورت وجود شرایط بیماری‌زایی، دارا است. این تحقیق اولین گزارش از بیماری‌زایی این قارچ روی بافت‌های مختلف زعفران در شرایط آزمایشگاهی و گلخانه است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron is one of the most important herbs and spices in the East of Iran and its production is affected by various pathogens. This study is aimed at isolation, identification and pathogenicity detection of Alternaria alternata isolates as leave spot and corm rot of saffron agents. Soil samples and infected plant tissues were collected from different areas of the Birjand plain (Birjand, Khusf and Sarbishe) during the years 2014-15. Alternaria species were isolated by potato dextrose agar medium and their morphological characteristics were studied on the potato carrot agar medium. For molecular studies, genomic DNA was extracted by the CTAB method and ribosomal subunits of fungal isolates were amplified using ITS1 and ITS4 primers. Based on morphological characteristics, 80 isolates of A. alternata were isolated. The ITS regions sequences of selected isolates had 100 similarities with A. alternata spices sequences in NCBI and MycoBank. These isolates caused chlorosis and necrosis on detached leaves, the inoculated corm was rotten and inoculated plants showed chlorosis and necrosis on leaves after 3-5 days. The results showed that A. alternata in the Birjand plain can cause corm rot and leaf chlorosis and necrosis is saffron. This study is the first report of the virulence of this fungus on saffron tissue in the East of Iran.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>61</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>72</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسین نیا</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hossainnia</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، گروه گیاه پزشکی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، گروه گیاه پزشکی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abbasmohammadi229@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عباس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Abbas</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه گیاه پزشکی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه گیاه پزشکی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amohammadi@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بیرجند</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بیماری‌زایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پوسیدگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تلقیح</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>لکه برگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF> Ahrazem, O., Rubio-Moraga, A., Castillo-López, R., Trapero-Mozos, A., and Gómez-Gómez, L. 2010. Crocus sativus pathogens and defence responses. Functional Plant Science and Biotechnology. Global Science Book Isleworth, UK, p. 81-90.##Akimitsu, K., Peever, T.L., and Timmer, L. 2003. Molecular, ecological and evolutionary approaches to understanding Alternaria diseases of citrus. Molecular Plant Pathology 4: 435-446.##Anonymus. 2014. Iran Agriculture Statistics (Vol. 2). Ministry of Jihad-Keshavrzi, Iran, 421 pp.##Atlas, R.M. 2010. Handbook of Microbiological Media. CRC press.##Di Primo, P., and Cappelli, C. 2000. Preliminary characterization of Fusarium oxysporum f. sp. gladioli causing Fusarium corm rot of saffron in Italy. Plant Disease 84: 806-806.##Droby , S., Dinoor, A., Prusky, D., and Barkai-Golan, R. 1984. Pathogenicity of Alternaria alternata on potato in Israel. Phytopathology 74: 537-542.##Foolad, M., Ntahimpera, N., Christ, B., and Lin, G. 2000. Comparison of field, greenhouse, and detached-leaflet evaluations of tomato germ plasm for early blight resistance. Plant Disease 84: 967-972.##Griffiths, L.J., Anyim, M., Doffman, S.R., Wilks, M., Millar, M.R., and Agrawal, S.G. 2006. Comparison of DNA extraction methods for Aspergillus fumigatus using real-time PCR. Journal of medical microbiology 55: 1187-1191.##Hassan, M., and Devi, L.S. 2003. Corm rot diseases of saffron in Kashmir valley. Indian Phytopathology 56: 122.##Hong, S.G., and Pryor, B.M. 2004. Development of selective media for the isolation and enumeration of Alternaria species from soil and plant debris. Canadian journal of microbiology 50: 461-468.##Houbraken, J., Due, M., Varga, J., Meijer, M., Frisvad, J.C., and Samson, R.A. 2007. Polyphasic taxonomy of Aspergillus section Usti. Studies in Mycology 59: 107-128.##Kalha, C.S., Gupta, V., Gupta, D., and Priya, S. 2007. First report of sclerotial rot of saffron caused by Sclerotium rolfsii in India. Plant Disease 91: 1203-1203.##Mohammadi, A., and Amini, Y. 2015. Molecular characterization and identification of Acrostalagmus luteoalbus from saffron in Iran. Agriculture Science Developments 4: 16-18.##Najjar, S. 2016. Taxonomic study of Aspergillus species associated with soil, crops and horticultural plants in Birjand plain. Department of plant protection,University of Birjand, Birjand, Iran. (In Persian with English Summary).##Negbi, M. 2003. Saffron: Crocus sativus L. CRC Press.##Noorbakhsh, R., Bahrami, A.R., Mortazavi, S.A., and Bahreini, M. 2009. PCR-based identification of aflatoxigenic fungi associated with Iranian saffron. Food Science and Biotechnology 18: 1018-1031.##Palmero, D., Rubio-Moraga, A., Galvez-Patón, L., Nogueras, J., Abato, C., Gómez-Gómez, L., and Ahrazem, O. 2014. Pathogenicity and genetic diversity of Fusarium oxysporum isolates from corms of Crocus sativus. Industrial Crops and Products 61: 186-192.##Raeder, U., and Broda, P. 1985. Rapid preparation of DNA from filamentous fungi. Letters in Applied Microbiology 1: 17-20.##Raj, P., Khan, S.S., Modak, M., Lone, Z.A., Rather, S.A., and Yaqoob, M. 2013. Biodiversity of endophytic fungi in saffron (Crocus sativus) and antimicrobial activity of their crude extract. IAJPR 3: 3702-3713.##Samson, R.A., Hoekstra, E.S., and Frisvad, J.C. 2004. Introduction to food-and airborne fungi. Centraalbureau voor Schimmelcultures (CBS).##Sharma, P., Sharma, S., and Sindhu, M. 2004. A detached leaf technique for evaluation of resistance in cabbage and cauliflower against three major pathogens. Indian Phytopathology 57: 315-318.##Simmons, E.G. 2007. Alternaria: An Identification Manual. CBS fungal biodiversity centre, Netherlands.##Tamura, K., Stecher, G., Peterson, D., Filipski, A., and Kumar, S. 2013. MEGA6: molecular evolutionary genetics analysis version 6.0. Molecular biology and evolution 30: 2725-2729.##Templeton, G. 2013. Alternaria toxins related to pathogenesis in plants. Microbial toxins 8: 169-192.##Thakur, R., Singh, C., and Kaul, B. 1992. First report of corm rot in Crocus sativus. Indian Phytopathology 45: 278.##Wani, M.A.S., and Dar, G. 2004.  Studies on Corm Rot of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.). University of Kashmir.##Woudenberg, J. 2015. Restyling Alternaria. Phytopathology,Wageningen University.##Zadoks, J.C. 1981. Mr. DuHamel&#039;s 1728 treatise on the violet root rot of saffron crocus: physical explanation of a disease that perishes several plants in the Gastinois, and saffron in particular. Landbouwhoge school, Wageningen.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی اقتصادی خدمات و کارکردهای بوم‌نظام‌های تولید زعفران در استان خراسان رضوی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Economic evaluation of agroecosystem services of saffron in Khorasan Razavi province</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>ارزش­گذاری خدمات بوم­­نظام­ها، مطلوب­ترین راهکار برای جلب توجه جامعه و سیاست­گزاران و تلاش در جهت حفظ و ارتقاء آن­ها می­باشد. این مطالعه با هدف برآورد ارزش اقتصادی خدمات و تبعات زیست­محیطی روش­های مدیریت در مزارع زعفران استان خراسان­رضوی در سال 1394 انجام شد. اطلاعات لازم از طریق پرسشنامه­ها در 75 مزرعه زعفران استخراج گردید. ارزش شش نوع از خدمات اکوسیستمی این مزارع (همچون تولید اکسیژن، تولید غذا، تنوع زیستی و خدمات فرهنگی) و دو مورد از تبعات منفی (شامل تولید گازهای گلخانه­ای و جریان نیتروژن و فسفر) بر اساس بهای دلار (معادل ریالی ارزش دلار در سال 2014 میلادی) برآورد گردید. نتایج نشان داد که میانگین این خدمات به ترتیب برابر با 106×21/54، 106×84/266، 106×24/60، 106×6/29 و 106×58/10 ریال در هکتار در سال محاسبه شد که سهم انواع خدمات شامل تولید غذا، اکسیژن، تنوع زیستی و خدمات فرهنگی از کل به ترتیب 39، 35، 19 و 7 درصد بود. دامنه تبعات منفی مزارع زعفران شامل انتشار گازهای گلخانه­ای و جریان نیتروژن و فسفر به ترتیب 106×54/18- تا 106×18/8-، 106×18/5- تا 106×07/4- ریال در هکتار در سال برآورد گردید. میانگین ارزش خدمات مزارع زعفران در استان خراسان­رضوی با کسر تبعات منفی 106×57/136 ریال در هکتار در سال محاسبه شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Monetary valuation of agroecoystem services makes them attractive for the society and policy makers should pay more attention to conservation of these services. In this study, the economic value of services as well as negative environmental externalities of saffron fields were estimated in the Khorasan Razavi province during 2015. Information was extracted from questionnaires collected from 75 fields. Using these data, economic values (such as O2 production, food, biodiversity and tourism) together with environmental externalities (including greenhouse gas emission and N and P leakage) were computed based on international value of dollar. Based on the results of the study, the mean values of the agroecosystem services of saffron field such as O2 production, food, biodiversity and cultural services were estimated to be 54.21×106, 266.84×106, 60.24×106, 29.6×106 and 10.58×106 Rls ha-1.y-1, respectively. The shares of these services were up to 39, 35, 19 and 7 percent of total value, respectively. The ranges of environmental externalities such as greenhouse gas emission and N and P leakage were estimated to be -18.54×106 to -8.18×106 and -5.18×106 to -4.07×106 Rls ha-1.y-1. The mean value of the total agroecosystem services of saffron fields excluding externalities, were estimated to be 136.57×106 Rls ha-1 y-1.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>73</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>89</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سرور</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خرم دل</Family>
						<NameE>Surur</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khorramdel</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>khorramdel@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پرویز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رضوانی مقدم</Family>
						<NameE>Parviz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rezvani Moghaddam</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rezvani@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>افسانه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امین غفوری</Family>
						<NameE>Afsaneh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Amin Ghafori</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مدرس دانشگاه پیام نور، خراسان رضوی و دکتری بوم شناسی زراعی گروه زراعت دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مدرس دانشگاه پیام نور، خراسان رضوی و دکتری</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.aminghafori@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تبعات زیست محیطی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تنوع زیستی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جریان نیتروژن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خدمات اکوسیستم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خدمات فرهنگی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Afshar, H. 1998. Women and Empowerment: Illustrations from the Third World, Macmillan Publication, London, UK.##Alene, A.D., Manyong, V.M., Omanya, G.O., Mignouna, H.D., Bokanga, M., and Odhiambo, G.D. 2008. Economic efficiency and supply response of women as farm managers: Comparative evidence from western Kenya. World Development 36 (7): 1247-1260.##Ashley, C. 2000. The impacts of tourism on Rural Livelihoods: Namibia’s Experience (No. ODI Working Paper 128), London: ODI.##Bakhtiari, A.A., Hematian, A., and Sharifi, A. 2015. Energy analyses and greenhouse gas emissions assessment for saffron production cycle. Environmental Science and Pollution Research 22 (20): 16184-16201.##Barani, H., Behmanesh, B., and Shahraki, M.R. 2013. Indigenous knowledge of medicinal plants of Chaharbagh pastures in Golestan province. Journal of Indigenous Knowledge 2: 61-86. (In Persian with English Summary).##Battese, G.E., Malik, S.J., and Gill, M.A. 1996. An investigation of technical inefficiency of production of wheat farmers in four districts of Pakistan. Journal of Agricultural Economics 47 (1): 37-49.##Birah, A., Srivastava, R., Chand, S., and Ahmed, S.Z. 2011. Role of women in pest management in and a man. Water management 35: 79-82.##Boozarjamhori, K. 2004. The role of indigenous knowledge in sustainable rural development. Iranian Journal of Geography Development 2: 5-20. (In Persian with English Summary).##Boozarjamhori, K., and Eftekhari, A. 2006. Analysis of the place of indigenous knowledge in sustainable rural development. Human Science of Modarres 9 (1): 17-47. (In Persian with English Summary).##Butler, R.W., Hall, C.M., and Jenkins, J.M. 1998. Tourism and Recreation in Rural Areas, New York.##Byrd, E., Bosley, H., and Dronberger, M. 2009. Comparisons of stakeholder perceptions of tourism impacts in rural eastern North Carolina. Tourism Management 30 (1): 693–703.##Costanza, R., d’Arge, R., DeGroot, R.S., Farber, S., Grasso, M., Hannon, B., Limburg, K., Naeem, S., O’Neill, R.V., Paruel, J., Raskin, R.G., Sutton, P., and VandenBelt, M. 1997. The value of the world’s ecosystem service and natural capital. Nature 387: 253-260.##Dale, V.H., and Polasky, S. 2007. Measures of the effects of agricultural practices on ecosystem services. Ecological Economics 64: 286-296.##De Groot, R., Brander, L., Ploeg, S., Costanza, R., Bernard, F., Braat, L., Christie, M., Crossman, N., Ghermand, A., Hein, L., Hussain, S., Kumar, P., McVittie, A., Portela, R., Rodriguez, L.C., Brink, P., and van Beukering, P. 2012. Global estimates of the value of ecosystems and their services in monetary units. Ecosystem Services 1: 50-61.##De Groot, R.S., Wilson, M.A., and Boumans, R.M.J. 2002. A typology for the classification, description and valuation of ecosystem function, goods and services. Ecological Economics 41: 393-408.##Del Grasso, S.J. 2002. Refinement, testing and application of the DEYCENY model to investigate ecological impacts of agriculture. PhD thesis, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, USA.##Doss, C.R., and Morris, M.L. 2000. How does gender affect the adoption of agricultural innovations? Agricultural Economics 25 (1): 27-39.##Emadi, M.H., and Amiri-Ardakani, M. 2003. Integration of indigenous knowledge and modern science, necessary toward sustainable development. Journal of Economics and Agricultural Development 10 (37): 11-36. (In Persian with English Summary).##Fallahi, H.R., Alami, S., Behdani, M.A., and Aghhavani Shajari, M. 2015. Evaluation of local and scientific knowledge in saffron agronomy (Case study: Sarayan). Journal of Saffron Research 3 (1): 31-50. (In Persian with English Summary).##FAO. 2007. Women farmers’ productivity in Sub-Saharan Africa. Available at http://www.fao.org/documents/show_cdr.asp?url_file=/DOCREP/004/y6000e/y6000e00.html.##Fitter, A., Elmqvist, T., Haines-Young, R., Potschin, M., Rinaldo, A., Setalä, H., Stoll-Kleemann, S., Zobel, M., and Murlis, J. 2010. An assessment of ecosystem services and biodiversity in Europe. In: Hester, R.E. and R.M. Harrison. 2010 (Eds.). Ecosystem Services. Issues in Environmental Science and Technology. Royal Society of Chemistry Publishing, UK, pp, 1-28.##Grandy, A.S., and Robertson, G.P. 2007. Land-use intensity effects on soil organic carbon accumulation rates and mechanisms. Ecosystems 10: 58-73.##Grandy, A.S., Loecke, T.D., Parr, S., and Robertson. G.P. 2006. Long-term trends in nitrous oxide emissions, soil nitrogen, and crop yields of till and no-till cropping systems. Journal of Environmental Quality 35: 1487-1495.##Hanley, N., Whitby, M., and Simpson, I. 1999. Assessing the success of agri-environmental policy in the UK. Land Use Policy 16: 67-80.##Holland, J., Dixey, L., and Burian, M. 2003. Tourism in Poor Rural Areas: Diversifying the Product and Expanding the Benefits in Rural Uganda and the Czech Republic, London, UK: ODI, IIED and ICRT.##Kafi, M., Rashed Mohasel, M.H., Koocheki, A.., and Mollafilabi, A. 2002. Saffron, Production and Processing. Zaban va Adab Publications, Iran, 276 pp. (In Persian).##Kamkar, B., and Mahdavi Damghani, A.M. 2008. Principle of Sustainable Agriculture. Jihad Daneshgahi of Mashhad Press, Mashhad, Iran. (In Persian).##Karami, A., and Zibayee, M. 2000. Investigation of technical inefficiency of Iranian rice producers: A case study in Fars, Guilan and Mazandaran province. Proceedings of the 3rd Conference of Agricultural Economics in Iran. Mashhad, Iran, p. 716-741. (In Persian)##Kerr, R.B., Snapp, S., Chirwa, M., Shumba, L., and Msachi, R. 2007. Participatory research on legume diversification with malawian smallholder farmers for improved human nutrition and soil fertility. Experimental Agriculture 43 (4): 437-454.##Kheshgi, H., Coninck, H., and Kessels, J. 2012. Carbon dioxide capture and storage: Seven years after the IPCC special report. Mitigation and Adaptation Strategies for Global Change 17 (6): 563-567.##Khorramdel, S., Abolhassani, L., and Rahmati E.A. 2016. Environmental impact assessment of saffron agroecosystems using life cycle assessment methodology: (Case study: Torbat-e Heydarieh and Ghaen counties). Journal of Saffron Research (In Press). (In Persian with English Summary).##Khorramdel, S., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Mollafilabi, A., and Valizadeh, S. 2016. Investigation of weed species diversity and community structure in saffron fields of Khorasan. Journal of Saffron Agronomy and Technology (In Press). (In Persian with English Summary).##Khozeymehnezhad H., Farhangfar, H., Behdani, M.A., and Hassanpour, M. 2016. Assessment of Saffron Farmers Knowledge on the Issues Associated with Irrigation (Case Study: Southern Khorasan). Saffron Agronomy and Technology 4 (1): 40-51. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A. 2004. Indigenous knowledge in agriculture with particular reference production in Iran. Acta Horticulture p. 175-182. (In Persian).##Koocheki, A., Khorramdel, S., and Jafari, L. 2014a. Evaluation of environmental consequences for sgroecosystems under conventional management in Khorasan Province. Journal of Agroecology (In Press). (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Nassiri Mahallati, M., Amin Ghafori, A., and Mahloji Rad, M. 2014b. Monetary value of agroecosystem services of wheat fields in Khorasan Razavi province. Journal of Agroecology (In Press). (In Persian with English Summary).##Kremen, C. 2005. Managing ecosystem services: what do we need to know about their ecology? Ecological Letters 8: 468-79.##Lahsaiizadeh, A., Jahangiri, J., and Khajenoori, B. 2006. Investigating of rural women economic participation (Case Study: Fars province). Iranian Journal of Sociology (6) 3: 124-145. (In Persian with English Summary).##Lv, Y., Gu, S., and Guo, D. 2010. Valuing environmental externalities from rice–wheat farming in the lower reaches of the Yangtze River. Ecological Economics 69: 1436–1442.##Madeley, J. 2002. Food for All: The Need for a New Agriculture: Zed books.##Madureira, L., Rambonilaza, T., and Karpinski, I. 2007. Review of methods and evidence for economic valuation of agricultural non-commodity outputs and suggestions to facilitate its application to broader decisional contexts. Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment 120: 5–20.##Mahdavi Damghani, A., Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Nassiri Mahallati, M. 2005. Ecological sustainability of a wheat-cotton agroecosystem in Khorassan. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 3 (1): 129-142. (In Persian with English Summary).##MEA, Millennium Ecosystem Assessment. 2005. Ecosystems and Human Well-Being: Synthesis. Island Press, Washington DC.##Mollafilabi, A., and Shoorideh, H. 2009. The new methods of saffron production. 4th National Festival of Saffron, Khorasan- Razavi, Iran, 27-28 October 2009. (In Persian).##Nassiri S.M., and Singh S. 2009. Study on energy use efficiency for paddy crop using Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA) technique. Applied Energy 86: 1320-1325.##Nassiri, M., and Koocheki, A. 2014. Trend analysis of nitrogen use and productivity in wheat production systems of Iran. Journal of Agroecology (In Press). (In Persian with English Summary).##Norris, K., Potts, S.G., and Mortimer, S.R. 2010. Ecosystem services and food production. In: Hester, R.E. and R.M. Harrison. 2010 (Eds.) Ecosystem Services. Issues in Environmental Science and Technology. Royal Society of Chemistry Publishing, UK. 52-69.##Oglethorpe, D., Edgerton, N., and Hanley, N. 2000. Modeling the demand and supply of environmental goods for ancient public good provision. Paper presented at Annual Meeting of the Agricultural Economics Society, Manchester, 14-17 April 2000,##Ostovar, S., and Ranjbar, Z. 2011. The role of indigenous Knowledge in sustainable agriculture. National Conference on Conservation of Biodiversity and Indigenous Knowledge, Kerman, Iran. 1-2 March 2011. (In Persian with English Summary).##Pishgar-Komleh, S.H., Sefeedpari, P., and Rafiee, S. 2011. Energy and economic analysis of rice production under different farm levels in Guilan province of Iran. Energy 36: 5824-5831.##Pretty, J., Hine, R., Gee, D., and Vaz, S. 1999. The Externalities of European Agriculture: Towards Fair and Ancient Pricing. European Environment Agency, Copenhagen.##Pretty, J.N., Brett, C., Gee, D., Hine, R.E., Mason, C.F., Morison, J.I.L., Raven, H., Rayment, M.D., and van der Bijl, G. 2000. An assessment of the total external costs of UK agriculture. Agricultural Systems 65: 113-136.##Quisumbing, A.R. 1996. Male-female differences in agricultural productivity: Methodological issues and empirical evidence. World Development 24 (10): 1579-1595.##Rezvani Moghaddam P., Khorramdel, S., and Mollafilabi, A. 2016. Evaluation of soil physical and chemical characteristics impacts on morphological criteria and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Saffron Research. (In Persian with English Summary).##Seyyedan, S.M. 2004. Investigation of factors affecting on technical inefficiency of garlic producers: A case study in Hamedan province. Pajouhesh and Sazandegi (64): 74-79. (In Persian with English Summary).##Syswerda, S.P. 2009. Ecosystem services from agriculture across a management intensity gradient in Southwest Michigan. PhD Thesis, Michigan State University.##TEEB Foundations. 2010. In: Kumar, P. (Ed.). The Economics of Ecosystems and Biodiversity: Ecological and Economic Foundations. Earth Scan, London, Washington.##Thornes, J. 2010. Atmospheric services. In: Hester, R.E. and R.M. Harrison. 2010 (Eds.) Ecosystem Services. Issues in Environmental Science and Technology. Royal Society of Chemistry Publishing, UK. 70-104.##Tilman, D., Cassman, K., Matson, P., Naylor, R., and Polasky, S. 2002. Agricultural sustainability and the costs and benefits of intensive production practices. Nature 418: 671–677.##Yousefian, J. 1996. Gender and Development. First edition, Banoo Press, Tehran. 128 pp. (In Press)##Zohary, D., and Hopf, M. 1994. Domestication of Plants in the Old World, second ed. Clarendon Press, Oxford, p. 189–190.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر قیمت زعفران (کاربرد الگوی قیمت‌گذاری هدانیک و شبکه عصبی مصنوعی)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Factors affecting the price of saffron )using the Hedonic pricing and artificial neural network model)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران به عنوان محصولی کشاورزی ارزشمند در سطح ملی و بین­المللی، به شیوه­های مختلفی توسط مصرف­کنندگان ارزش‌گذاری می­شود و قیمتی که برای آن پرداخت می­شود به عوامل متعددی بستگی دارد. با شناسایی این عوامل می­توان زعفران را با قیمتی در بازار عرضه نمود که مطابق با ترجیحات مصرف­کننده باشد. لذا، هدف اصلی این مطالعه ارزیابی عوامل مؤثر بر قیمت زعفران در شهر مشهد با استفاده از مدل قیمت­گذاری هدانیک است. وجه تمایز این مطالعه نسبت به مطالعات پیشین استفاده از رهیافت تحلیل حساسیت در چارچوب شبکه عصبی مصنوعی است. اطلاعات مورد نیاز تحقیق از طریق روش نمونه­گیری تصادفی ساده از 120 خریدار زعفران در سطح شهر مشهد جمع­آوری گردیده است. با در نظر گرفتن 14 متغیر توضیحی، نتایج مطالعه نشان داد که متغیرهای سن و نام تجاری کمترین اثر را بر قیمت زعفران دارند، در حالی که متغیر اهداف مصرفی اثر قابل توجهی بر قیمت این محصول دارد. در میان اهداف مصرفی، مصرف تغذیه­ای دارای اثر مثبت و مصارف دارویی و صنعتی اثر منفی بر قیمت زعفران دارند. با توجه به یافته­های پژوهش، به تولیدکنندگان و عرضه­کنندگان زعفران توصیه می­گردد که در استراتژی قیمت­گذاری این محصول به ترتیب به نوع مصرف، شیوه فروش و نوع زعفران توجه نمایند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron, a valuable agricultural product in the national and international level is valued by consumers in different ways and the price paid for it depends on different factors. Identifying these factors can be helpful to marketing saffron with the price that is consistent with consumer preferences. The major aim of this study is to evaluate the factors that affect the price of saffron in Mashhad using the Hedonic pricing model. What distinguishes this study from previous studies is using the sensitivity analysis approach in the context of artificial neural networks. The information needed for this research was collected from 120 saffron buyers in the city of Mashhad with the random sampling approach. Considering the 14 explanatory variables, the results showed that age and brand have the least impact on the price of saffron, while the consumption goals variable has a significant effect on the price of this product. Among the goals, nutritional uses has a positive effect, and medical and industrial uses have a negative effect on the price of saffron. According to the research findings, manufacturers and suppliers of saffron are recommended to price the product according to the buyers’ consumption goals, sale style and the saffron type, respectively.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>91</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>103</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آرش</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>دوراندیش</Family>
						<NameE>Arash</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Dourandish</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>adourandish@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امیر حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>توحیدی</Family>
						<NameE>amirhossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>tohidi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amirhossein_tohidi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مونا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>موسوی</Family>
						<NameE>Mona</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mousavi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجو کارشناسی ارشد، گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجو کارشناسی ارشد، گروه اقتصادکشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mnnmousavi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اهداف مصرفی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ترجیحات مصرف کننده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبکه عصبی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قیمت گذاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Cantarella, G.E., and Luca, S.D. 2005. Multilayer feedforward networks for transportation mode choice analysis: An analysis and a comparison with random utility models. Transportation Research Part C: Emerging Technologies 13 (2): 121-155.##Carew, R. 2000. A hedonic analysis of apple prices and product quality characteristics in British Columbia. Canadian Journal of Agricultural Economics 48 (3): 241-257.##Carew, R., Florkowski, W.J., and Smith, E.G. 2012. Hedonic analysis of apple attributes in metropolitan markets of Western Canada. Agribusiness 28 (3): 293-309.##Co, H.C., and Boosarawongse, R. 2007. Forecasting Thailand’s rice export: statistical techniques vs. artificial neural networks. Computers and Industrial Engineering 53 (4): 610-627.##Coulibaly, P., and Baldwin, C.K. 2005. Nonstationary hydrological time series forecasting using nonlinear dynamic methods. Journal of Hydrology 307 (1): 164-174.##Curry, B., Morgan, P., and Silver, M. 2001. Hedonic regressions: misspecification and neural networks. Applied Economics 33 (5): 659-671.##Dewenter, R., Haucap, J., Luther, R., and Rotzel, P. 2007. Hedonic prices in the German market for mobile phones. Telecommunications Policy 31 (1): 4-13.##Dimopoulos, Y., Bourret, P., and Lek, S. 1995. Use of some sensitivity criteria for choosing networks with good generalization ability. Neural Processing Letters 2 (6): 1-4.##Ethridge, D. E., and Davis, B. 1982. Hedonic price estimation for commodities: an application to cotton. Western Journal of Agricultural Economics 7 (2): 293-300.##Gevrey, M., Dimopoulos, I., and Lek, S. 2003. Review and comparison of methods to study the contribution of variables in artificial neural network models. Ecological Modelling 160 (3): 249-264.##Gevrey, M., Dimopoulos, I., and Lek, S. 2006. Two-way interaction of input variables in the sensitivity analysis of neural network models. Ecological Modelling 195 (1): 43-50.##Goethals, P.L., Dedecker, A.P., Gabriels, W., Lek, S., and De Pauw, N. 2007. Applications of artificial neural networks predicting macroinvertebrates in freshwaters. Aquatic Ecology 41 (3): 491-508.##Huang, C.L., and Lin, B.H. 2007. A hedonic analysis of fresh tomato prices among regional markets. Applied Economic Perspectives and Policy 29 (4): 783-800.##Khashei, M., and Bijari, M. 2011. A novel hybridization of artificial neural networks and ARIMA models for time series forecasting. Applied Soft Computing 11 (2): 2664-2675.##Lancaster, K.J. 1966. A new approach to consumer theory. The Journal of Political Economy 74 (2): 132-157.##Maanen, B.V., Coco, G., Bryan, K.R., and Ruessink, B.G. 2010. The use of artificial neural networks to analyze and predict alongshore sediment transport. Nonlinear Processes in Geophysics 17 (5): 395-404.##Martinez Garmendia, J. 2010. Application of hedonic price modeling to consumer packaged goods using store scanner data. Journal of Business Research 63 (7): 690-696.##Muñoz, R., Lagos Moya, M., and Gil, J.M. 2015. Market values for olive oil attributes in Chile: a hedonic price function. British Food Journal 117 (1): 358-370.##Parcell, J.L., and Schroeder, T.C. 2007. Hedonic retail beef and pork product prices. Journal of Agricultural and Applied Economics 39 (01): 29-46.##Rosen, S. 1974. Hedonic prices and implicit markets: product differentiation in pure competition. Journal of Political Economy 82 (1): 34-55.##Schollenberg, L. 2012. Estimating the hedonic price for fair trade coffee in Sweden. British Food Journal 114 (3): 428-446.##Selim, H. 2009. Determinants of house prices in Turkey: Hedonic regression versus artificial neural network. Expert Systems with Applications 36 (2): 2843-2852.##Seppä, L., Latvala, T., Akaichi, F., Gil, J.M., and Tuorila, H. 2015. What are domestic apples worth? Hedonic responses and sensory information as drivers of willingness to pay. Food Quality and Preference 43: 97-105.##Vickner, S.S. 2015. Estimating the implicit price of convenience: a hedonic analysis of the US breakfast sausage market. Agribusiness 31 (2): 281-292.##Waugh, F.V. 1928. Quality factors influencing vegetable prices. Journal of Farm Economics 10 (2): 185-196.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>شناخت اداراک و سازگاری زعفران کاران دشت کاشمر با تغییرات اقلیمی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Understanding perceptual and adaptation to climate change by the saffron farmers Of the Kashmar plain</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تغییرات اقلیمی تأثیرات جدی بر جوامع و معیشت آنان در مناطق خشک دارد. بخش کشاورزی به دلیل تعاملات گسترده­ای که با محیط دارد، بیش­ترین تأثیر را از تغییرات آب و هوایی می‌پذیرد. تخریب محیط زیست و کاهش عملکرد محصول زعفران و تضعیف اقتصاد خانوار از جمله پیامدهای تغییرات آب و هوایی در دشت کاشمر می­باشد. این مطالعه به منظور سنجش ادراک زعفران­کاران دشت کاشمر از تغییرات اقلیمی و ظرفیت سازگاری آنان با این پدیده انجام گرفته است. مطالعه حاضر  به واکاوی ادراکات و سازگاری زعفران­کاران با تغییرات آب و هوا به منظور افزایش استراتژِی ها در قبال مقابله با چالش­های تغییر آب و هوا در دشت کاشمر انجام گرفته است. روش کار توصیفی – تحلیلی با رویکرد پیمایشی می­باشد، جامعة آماری پژوهش با استفاده از روش نمونه­گیری کوکران و حجم نمونه 390 خانوار محاسبه شد. برای واکاوی ادراک زعفران­کاران و استراتژی­های سازگاری از مدل­های آماری از جمله رگرسیون لجستیک استفاده گردید. تجزیه و تحلیل ادراک زعفران­کاران نسبت به تغییر آب و هوا نشان می­دهد که افزایش دما و کاهش بارندگی دهه اخیر  در دشت کاشمر شدت گرفته است. نتایج مدل آماری لجستیک نشان می­دهد که تنوع محصول، تغییر در محصولات زراعی، پیدا  کردن شغل در خارج از مزرعه ، تغییر مساحت زمین، تغییر تاریخ کاشت روش­های سازگاری زعفران کاران در منطقه می­باشد. با توجه به اینکه تعداد زیادی از زعفران­کاران به درک تغییرات اقلیمی رسیده­اند و فعالیت­های کشاورزی خود را بر مبنای این تغییرات تنظیم می­کنند، لازم است دولت نیز شرایط سازگاری زعفران­کاران را با تغییرات اقلیمی تسهیل نماید.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Climate change has serious impacts on communities and livelihoods in dry areas. The agricultural sector accepts the greatest impact from climate change due to its extensive interactions with the environment. Environmental degradation and reduced yield of saffron and weakening of the household economy are among the consequences of climate change in the Kashmar plain. This study was carried out in order to evaluate the perception of saffron in the Kashmar plain from climate change and its capacity to adapt to this phenomenon. The present study was conducted to examine the perceptions and adaptation of saffron to climate change in order to expand the strategies for confronting the climate change challenges in the Kashmar plain. The method of this study is descriptive-analytic. The population of the study was calculated using Cochran&#039;s sampling method and a sample size of 390 households was chosen. Statistical models such as logistic regression were used to examine saffron perception and compatibility strategies. The analysis of saffron perceptions of climate change shows that the increase in temperature and the decrease in rainfall during the last decade in the Kashmar plain has been ongoing. The results of the logistic statistical model indicated that product diversity, change in crops, finding a job outside the farm, changing the amount of land, changing the planting date of saffron were adaptation methods used in the region. Given that many saffron growers have come to understand climate change and adjust their farming activities based on these changes, the government should facilitate the adaptation of saffron to climate change.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>105</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>117</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مرتضی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اسمعیل نژاد</Family>
						<NameE>morteza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>esmailnejad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه جغرافیا، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه جغرافیا، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>esmaelnejad.m@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انطباق</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تغییرات آب و هوا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رگرسیون لجستیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران‌کاران کاشمر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aggarwal, P., and Singh, A.K. 2010. Implications of global climatic change on water and food security. In: C. Ringler, A.K. Biswas, and A.C. Sarah (Eds.), Global change: Impacts on water and food security. New York: Springer (5): 49-63.##Barret, W.J. 1963. Manual for the Geography of Natural Resources. Burgess Publishing Company, Minnesota.##Caritas, B. 2008. Towards self reliance: 2008– 2012 strategic plan. Caritas Nyeri, Archdiocese of Nyeri, Kenya. African Crop Science Journal (20): 287-296##Connolly-Boutin, L., and Smit, B. 2016. Climate change, food security, and livelihoods in sub-Saharan Africa. Regional Environmental Change Journal (16): 385–399.##Deressa, T., Hassan, C., Ringler, T., Tekie Alemu, D., and yesuf, M. 2009. Determinants of farmers’choice of adaptation methods to climate change in the Nile Basin of Ethiopia. Global Environmental Change (19): 248–255.##Ericksen, S., Aldunce, P., Bahinipati, C.S., Martins, R.D., Molefe, J.I., Nhemachena, C., O&#039;brien, K., Olorunfem, F., Park, J., Sygna, L., and Ulsrud, K. 2011. When not every response to climate change is a good one: Identifying principles for sustainable adaptation. Climate and Development (3): 7-20.##Gbetibouo, A.G. 2009. Understanding farmers&#039; perceptions and adaptations to climate and variability. The Case of the Limpopo Basin, South Africa. IFPRI discussion paper 7: 1-36.##Gbetibouo, A. 2016. Understanding farmers’ perceptions and adaptations to climate change and variability the case of the Limpopo Basin, South Africa, Center for Environmental Economics and Policy in Africa (1): 8-15.##GOK. 2010. National Climate Change Response Strategy. Ministry of Environment and Mineral Resources. Government of Kenya, Nairobi.##Hosmer, D.W., and Lemeshow, S. 2000. Applied Logistic Regression, 2nd Ed. John Wiley and Sons, New York.##Ifeanyi-Obi, C.C., Etuk, U.R., and Jike-Wai, O. 2012. Climate change, effects and adaptation strategies; implication for agricultural extension system in Nigeria. Greener Journal of Agricultural Sciences (2): 53-60.## Campbell, D., Barker, D., and McGregor, D. 2011. Dealing with drought: small farmers and environmental hazards in Southern St. Elizabeth, Jamaica. Applied Geography (1): 146-158.##Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). 2007. Climate Change 2007. Impacts Adaptation and Vulnerability. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge.##Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). 2014. Impacts, adaptation and vulnerability, Part A: Global and sectoral aspects, contribution of working group II to the fifth assessment report of the intergovernmental panel on climate change Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, Cambridge.##Kates, R.W., Travis, W.R., and Wilbanks, T.J. 2012. Transformational adaptation when incremental adaptations to climate change are insufficient. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (109): 7156–7161.##Kifle, S., Teferi, B., Kebedom, A., and Abiyot, L. 2016. Factors influencing farmers decision on the use of introduced soil and water conservation practices in the Lowland’s of Wenago Woreda, Gedeo Zone, Ethiopia. American Journal of Rural (1): 24-30.##Koocheki, A. 2015. Workshop on climate change and low-carbon technologies (Proceedings). Ministry of Agriculture, Ministry of Research, Education and Extension, Tehran. (In Persian).##Koocheki, A., Nassiri, M., Soltani, A., Sharifi, H., and Ghorbani, R. 2006. Effects of climate change on growth criteria and yield of sunflower and chickpea crops in Iran. Climate Research (30): 247-253.##Koocheki, A., Nassiri, M., Alizadeh, A., and Ganjeali, A. 2009. Modelling the impact of climate change on flowering behaviour of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Crop Research (7): 583-593. (In Persian).##McCarthy, J.J., Canziani, O.F., Leary, N.A., Dokken, D.J., and White, K.S. 2001. Impacts, Adaptation and Vulnerability. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge (15): 877–912.##Maddison, D. 2006. The perception of and adaptation to climate change in Africa. CEEPA Discussion Paper No. 10. Centre for Environmental Economics and Policy in Africa, University of Pretoria, South Africa.##Pouliotte, J., Smit, B., and Westerhoff, L. 2009. Adaptation and development: Livelihoods and climate change in Subarnabad, Bangladesh. Climate Change and Development (1): 31-46.##Moradi, A., Koocheki, A., and Nassiri Mahallati, M. 2013. Effect of climate change on Maize production and shifting of planting date as adaptation strategy in Mashhad. Journal of Agricultural Science and Sustainable Production (4): 111-128. (In Persian with English Summary).##Rice, J.C. 1994. Logistic Regression: An Introduction. Advances in social science methodology, Greenwich, CT: JAI Press. Popular Introduction (3): 191-245.##Shisany. S., and Mafongoy, P. 2016. Adaptation to climate change and the impacts on household food security among rural farmers in uMzinyathi District of Kwazulu-Natal. South Africa, Food Security 1: 1- 12.##Smithers, J., and Smit, B. 2009. Human Adaptation to Climatic Variability and Change. In L. E. Schipper and I. Burton (Eds.), Adaptation to Climate Change. London: arthscan (17) 15-33.##UNFCC, 2006. Ph.D. This Definition is not from the Convention and can be regarded as a Working Definition, available in http://unfccc.int/essential_background/feeling the_ heat/items/2911.##Wheeler, S., Zuo, A., and Bjornlund, H. 2013. Farmers’ climate change beliefs and adaptation strategies for a water scarce future in Australia. Global Environmental Change 23 (2): 537–547.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اولین گزارش بیماری پوسیدگی بنه زعفران وحشی ناشی از  Fusarium oxysporum  در ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The first report of  Fusarium oxysporum   causal agent of wild saffron corm rot disease in Iran</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران (Crocus sativus L.) مهم­ترین گیاه در جهان است که از کلاله آن به دلیل داشتن مواد رنگی و مواد معطر در طباخی، قنادی و تولید داروها استفاده می­شود. بیماری پوسیدگی بنه زعفران یکی از بیماری‌های مهم زعفران در ایران می‌باشد. به‌منظور شناسایی عوامل پژمردگی و پوسیدگی بنه زعفران وحشی، به‌صورت تصادفی از گیاهان دارای علائم زردی و پژمردگی در مناطق ایوان و صالح‌آباد در استان ایلام نمونه‌برداری انجام گرفت. نمونه­ها با محلول سفیدکننده (5% هیپوکلریت سدیم) به­مدت دو تا سه دقیقه ضدعفونی سطحی شدند سه بار با آب مقطر استریل شستشو داده شدند و سپس این قطعات را با کاغذ صافی سترون خشک کرده و بر روی محیط کشت سیب‌زمینی دکستروز آگار (PDA) کشت داده شدند. تشتک‌ها به­مدت سه روز در انکوباتور با دمای ˚C 20 نگهداری شدند. قارچ به روش تک اسپور جداسازی و خالص گردید. تعداد 8 جدایه Fusarium oxysporium به‌عنوان عامل ایجاد پوسیدگی ریشه، بر اساس مشخصات ریخت­شناسی و میکروسکوپی با استفاده از کلیدهای معتبر شناسایی گزارش شد و بیماری­زایی این جدایه­ها به‌صورت مصنوعی در گلخانه مطابق اصول کخ بر روی رقم زعفران وحشی به اثبات رسید.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) is the most important plant in the world that has been used in cooking, confectionery and drug productions because of the color and aromatic substances in its sigma. Corm rot disease is one of the most important diseases in Iran. For identification of causal agents, wild saffron plants with wilt symptoms and rot lesions on corm were randomly collected in different regions of Ivan and Mehran in the Ilam province. Diseased samples were surface sterilized by dipping into domestic bleach solution (5% NaOCl). Then they were washed three times with sterile distilled water, dried with sterile filter paper and plated on potato dextrose agar (PDA). Samples were incubated for three days in an incubator at 20°C. A total of eight Fusarium isolates were obtained and purified using the single spore method. Fusarium oxysporium isolates were identified according to their morphological and microscopic characteristics as described by the identification key. The pathogenicity of Fusarium oxysporium isolates were artificially tested in the greenhouse on a wild susceptible cultivar according to Koch’s principles.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>119</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>123</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>قاسم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نجاری</Family>
						<NameE>Ghasem</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Najari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>فارغ التحصیل کارشناسی ارشد رشته بیماری‌شناسی گیاهی، دانشگاه ایلام</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>فارغ التحصیل کارشناسی ارشد رشته بیماری‌شناسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>najari70@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>خشنود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نوراللهی</Family>
						<NameE>Khoshnood</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nourollahi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه گیاهپزشکی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه ایلام</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه گیاهپزشکی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nourollahi52@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مریم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پیری</Family>
						<NameE>Maryam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Piri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>فارغ التحصیل کارشناسی ارشد رشته بیماری شناسی گیاهی، دانشگاه ایلام</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>فارغ التحصیل کارشناسی ارشد رشته بیماری شناسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>maryampiri67@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پوسیدگی بنه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قارچ</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Alexander, L.J., and Hoover, M.M. 1955. Disease resistance in wild species of tomato. Report of the National Screening Committee.## Amin, B., Feriz, H.M., Hariri, A.T., Meybodi, N.T., and Hosseinzadeh, H. 2015. Protective effects of the aqueous extract of (Crocus sativus L.) against ethylene glycol induced nephrolithiasis in rats. EXCLI Journal 14: 4-11.## Behnia, M.R. 1991. Saffron Cultivation. The University Publishing House of Tehran. (In Persian).## Brayford, D. 1996. (Fusarium oxysporum f. sp. gladioli). Mycopathologia 133: 47-48.## Bosland, M.C., Jones, T.C., Mohr, U., and Hunt, R.D. 1987. ed Monographs on Pathology of Laboratory Animals Genital System. Springer-Verlag, Berlin, p. 252-275.## Cappelli, C. 1994. Occurrence of (Fusarium oxysporum f. sp. gladioli) on saffron in Italy. Phytopathologia Mediterranea 33: 93-94.## Cappelli, C., and Di-Minco, G. 1999. Results of a triennial study on saffron diseases in Abruzzi. Informatore Fitopatologico 49: 27-32.## Garcia-Jimenez, J., and Alfaro-Garcia, A. 1987. (Fusarium oxisporum) Schlecht as casual agent of a seedborne disease of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Proceedings of the 7th Congress of the Mediterranean Phytopathological Union, 156 p.## Gullino, M., Romano, M., and Armato, B. 1983. Introduction to Italy of iris bulbs infected with(Fusarium oxysporum f. sp. gladioli)and (Penicillium corymbiferum) resistant to benzimidazoles. Informatore Fitopatologico (Italy).## Mathew, B. 1999. Botany, taxonomy and cytology of Crocus sativus L. and its allies. Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) Amsterdam, Netherlands. Harwood Academic, 19-30.## Nelson, P.M., and Wfo-Toussoun, T. 1983. Fusarium Species: An Illustrated Manual for Identification. The Pennsylvania State University.## Shah, A., and Srivastava, K. 1984. Control of corm rot of saffron. Progressive Horticulture 16: 141-143.## Yamamoto, W., Omatsu, T., and Takami, K. 1954. Studies on the corm rots of (Crocus sativus L.) On the saprophytic propagation of (Sclerotinia gladioli) and (Fusarium oxysporum f. sp. gladioli) on various plants and soil. Science Reports of the Hyogo University of Agriculture 1: 64–70.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				