<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Climate and Agriculture Tourism in the City of Ghaen</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی ارتباط بین اقلیم و اگروتوریسم زعفران در منطقه قاینات</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>145</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>155</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">10388</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2015.10388</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسمعیل نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه جغرافیا، دانشگاه بیرجند.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Climate is an important factor in the development of industrial tourism. The group travels to heal with climate. Elevation, moderate temperature and suitability of landscape are factors that are required to consider as conditions for tourism. There are some benefit such as center of cultivating barberry and saffron, a moderate climate and being located in transportation axis of east of Iran in the city of Ghaen that make it have a in high potential to absorb tourists. A review of climate convenience with bioclimatic indices such as W-strain and W_Sens shows that the first month of the spring and autumn in Ghaen, the climate is suitable for travelling, especially for the beautiful landscapes of barberry and saffron. Therefore, combining the moderate climatic and the beautiful landscapes of barberry and saffron can provide good conditions for agriculture tourism. Saffron tourism master span is the accurate and reasonable title in areas where the crop is grown, and studied. It is also a tourist profile. In this study, using the ecological indicators of climate such as severe weather, heat stress, cooling power of wind during the 22 years in Ghaen station. Bioklima software was used to investigate the climate comfort. This city provides such a situation that in the first months of spring and autumn, weather conditions are fit for tourists and for recreation and travel. Especially, the early autumn harvest of saffron in the city plus the beautiful scenery can attract travelers. So, combining the two factors of moderate climate and harvest of Saffron work hand in hand to attract tourism. Therefore, these two factors combined (a moderate climate and harvesting saffron) create beautiful scenes and can provide conditions for the development of agricultural tourism.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اقلیم مهم‌ترین عامل در توسعه صنعت توریسم محسوب می‌شود. مسافرت‌های گروهی و دسته‌جمعی با شرایط آب و هوایی پیوند می‌خورد. عامل ارتفاع و اعتدال درجه حرارت به همراه مناسب بودن شکل ظاهری زمین و قابلیت دسترسی آن، از عواملی محسوب می‌شوند که شرایط توریسم را فراهم می‌آورند. شهرستان قاینات با توجه به داشتن زمین‌های زراعی مناسب برای کشت محصول استراتژیک زعفران، واقع شدن در محور ترانزیتی شرق کشور و داشتن آب و هوای نسبتاً معتدل از قابلیت بالایی در جذب گردشگر برخوردار می‌باشد. طرح جامع توریسم زعفران، عنوانی است که به‌صورت جزئی اما دقیق و منطقی در مناطقی که این محصول کشت می‌شود، مورد بررسی قرار می‌گیرد و برای آن شناسنامه توریستی تهیه می‌شود. در این پژوهش با استفاده از شاخص‌های زیست اقلیم مانند سختی هوا، تنش گرمایی، قدرت خنک‌کنندگی باد در دوره آماری 22 ساله هواشناسی ایستگاه قاین و در محیط نرم‌افزار Bioklima به بررسی آسایش اقلیمی شهرستان قاینات پرداخته شد. نتایج نشان داد که این شهرستان در ماه‌های اول بهار و پاییز دارای قابلیت مناسبی ازلحاظ شرایط آب و هوایی برای تفریح و سفر به این شهر را دارد، به‌ویژه که اوایل پاییز فصل برداشت زعفران در این شهرستان بوده و می‌تواند مناظر زیبایی را برای جذب مسافران به وجود بیاورد؛ بنابراین تلفیق دو عامل اعتدال آب و هوا و برداشت محصول (زعفران) با توجه به ایجاد مناظر زیبا و منحصر به ‌فرد می‌تواند شرایط را جهت توسعه توریسم کشاورزی در قاینات فراهم نماید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آسایش اقلیمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توریسم کشاورزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص‌های بیوکلیماتیک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_10388_8c0db1e30bfba9115c5ffea2855bd15a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
