<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effects of of fulvic acid and cow manure on stigma active components and petal Antiradical Activity of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی اثر اسید فولویک و کود دامی بر مواد موثره و فعالیت ضد رادیکالی گلبرگ زعفران (.&lt;i&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/i&gt; L)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>415</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>428</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55269</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2017.99009.1260</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>امینی فرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه آموزشی علوم باغبانی و مرکز پژوهشی گیاهان ویژه منطقه دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فریده</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، رشته علوم باغبانی، گرایش فیزیولوژی گیاهان دارویی، ادویه‏ای و عطری. دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>components of saffron were evaluated under field conditions. Treatments were four levels cow manure (0, 10, 20 and 30 t.ha-1) and three fulvic acid (0, 5 and 10 kg.ha-1). This experiment was carried out as factorial based on randomized completely block design with three replications in research farm of Birjand University, Iran, during cropping year 2015-2016. Results showed that cow manure improved the active ingredients of stigma (picrocrocin, safranal and crocin) in first year of study. Also, results showed that petal antioxidant compounds (total phenol and anthocyanin) and active ingredients of stigma were influenced by cow manure in second year of study. The highest safranal was obtained in plants treated with 10 t.ha-1 cow manure in first year of experiment. Results also showed that fulvic acid has a positive effect active ingredients of stigma (picrocrocin and crocin), anthocyanin and total phenol in two years of experiment and the highest rate of anthocyanin and total phenol were obtained with 5 kg.ha-1 fulvic acid while the lowest values were recorded in control. Application of different levels of cow manure and fulvic acid had a positive effect on the active ingredients of stigma in two years of experiment and anthocyanin and phenol in second year of study. Thus, results showed that cow manure and fulvic acid have significant impact on antioxidant compounds and active ingredients of saffron under field conditions.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به منظور بررسی اثرات کود گاوی و اسید فولویک بر فعالیت آنتی‏اکسیدانی و مواد مؤثره زعفران (Crocus sativus L.)، آزمایشی به صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح پایه بلوک‏های کامل تصادفی در سه تکرار، در مزرعه دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند در سال زراعی 1395- 1394 اجرا شد. فاکتورها شامل کود گاوی در چهار سطح (صفر، 10، 20 و 30 تن در هکتار) و اسید فولویک در سه سطح (صفر، 5 و 10 کیلوگرم در هکتار) با سه تکرار بودند. نتایج دوساله نشان داد که در سال اول اجرای آزمایش کود گاوی بر مواد مؤثره کلاله ( پیکروکروسین، کروسین و سافرانال) و در سال دوم بر فعالیت آنتی‏اکسیدانی گلبرگ (آنتوسیانین و فنول) و مواد مؤثره کلاله معنی‏دار شد. بیشترین مقدار سافرانال در سال اول در سطح 10 تن در هکتار کود گاوی به دست آمد. اسید فولویک نیز در دو سال آزمایش بر مواد مؤثره (کروسین و پیکروکروسین)، آنتوسیانین و فنول اثر معنی‏داری داشت. به طوریکه بیشترین میزان آنتوسیانین و فنول در هر دو سال در تیمار 5 کیلوگرم در هکتار اسید فولویک و کمترین مقدار آنها در سطح شاهد مشاهده گردید. اثر متقابل کود گاوی و اسید فولویک نیز در دو سال بر مواد مؤثره کلاله و در سال دوم بر آنتوسیانین و فنول اثر معنی‏داری گذاشت. به طور کلی نتایج نشان داد،کود گاوی و اسید فولویک تاثیر مثبتی بر فعالیت آنتی‏اکسیدانی و مواد مؤثره زعفران در این آزمایش داشت.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد کلاله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کروسین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آنتوسیانین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کود آلی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_55269_df423e71f248887ac8fb9d5ab6789e03.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
