<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" "journalpublishing3.dtd">
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2013.4808</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4808_49228290cce92368676638ddc340783c.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>سایر موضوعات مرتبط با زعفران</subject>
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>پژوهش‌های زراعی زعفران در ایران: روند گذشته و نگاهی به آینده</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>کوچکی</surname>
			            <given-names>علیرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد گروه زراعت دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>12</month>
			        <year>2013</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>1</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>3</fpage>
			      <lpage>21</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>17</day>
			          <month>08</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2013, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2013</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4808.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4808.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p> زعفران از جنبه‌های مختلف اقتصادی، اجتماعی، زیست محیطی و سیاسی جایگاه ویژه‌ای در کشاورزی ایران و بخصوص مناطق زعفران‌کاری دارا می‌باشد. نقش کشاورزان ایران در اهلی‌سازی و تکامل زراعی این گیاه در منابع متعدد علمی بین‌المللی به‌صورت بارزی آورده شده است. گرچه نام این محصول مینیاتوری و به‌ اصطلاح دست‌ساز همیشه با نام ایران همراه بوده است ولی به‌نظر نمی‌رسد تلاش‌های علمی پژوهشگران ما در گذشته در خور این گیاه پرآوازه بوده باشد و مسلماً انتظار جهانیان از پژوهشگران ایرانی در زمینه زعفران خیلی بیش از آن است که امروزه برآورده شده است. در این نوشتار سعی شده است با نگاهی به پژوهش‌های زراعی زعفران در گذشته در سطح کشور، وضع موجود و دورنمای آینده آن نیز ترسیم شود. اگرچه پژوهش‌های زراعی اولیه در مورد زعفران در کشور از سابقه‌ای 70 ساله برخوردار است ولی طی یک دوره 40 ساله فعالیت علمی خاصی در این زمینه صورت نگرفت و فعالیت‌های پژوهشی منسجم عملاً از دهه 50 توسط برخی پژوهشگران پیشگام در خراسان آغاز شد. در دهه‌های 50 و 60 با پیدایش سازمان‌هایی همچون سازمان پژوهش‌های علمی و صنعتی (واحد خراسان) و شروع گسترش دوره‌های تحصیلات تکمیلی در دانشکده‌های کشاورزی پژوهش‌های زراعی زعفران در دهه‌های 50 و 60 نسبتاً گسترش یافت و این موضوع بخصوص در دهه‌های 70 و 80 سرعت بیشتری به‌ خود گرفت. در اوایل دهه 80 با تاسیس قطب علمی گیاهان زراعی ویژه در دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد و در اواخر دهه 80 با تاسیس گروه پژوهشی زعفران در دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند و همچنین تأسیس کانون ارتباط با دانش زعفران در همان دانشگاه، فعالیت‌های پژوهشی تداوم یافت. در اوایل دهه 90 تاسیس پژوهشکده زعفران در دانشگاه تربت حیدریه و تلاش در جهت انتشار دو نشریه تخصصی زعفران توسط دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند و پژوهشکده زعفران و گسترش قابل ملاحظه دوره‌های تحصیلات تکمیلی در دانشگاه‌ها و نیز توجه بیشتر به این محصول سرعت پژوهش‌های مربوط بیشتر شد. تأسیس دبیرخانه دائمی جشنواره زعفران در قائن، تشکیل شورای ملی زعفران در اتاق بازرگانی صنایع و معادن مشهد، تدوین طرح جامع بهبود و فرآوری زعفران، برگزاری کنگره و همایش‌های ملی، برگزاری دومین سمپوزیوم بین‌المللی زعفران در دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد نمونه‌هایی از توجه بیشتر به زعفران در سطح ملّی است که بدون تردید می‌تواند عامل مهمی در گسترش پژوهش‌های علمی روی این محصول باشد. امید است چنین رویه‌هایی زمینه‌های لازم را برای نوعی جنبش علمی در مورد زعفران فراهم ساخته باشد و انتظار می‌رود این جنبش علمی به‌صورتی منسجم و جامع، مبانی پژوهش‌های رایج را مورد تجدید نظر قرار داده و به‌علاوه جنبه‌های نوینی از تولید زعفران از جمله تولید در محیط‌های تحت کنترل، ارزیابی خلأ عملکرد، مدلسازی رشد و نمو، جنبه‌های فیزیولوژی و اکولوژی زراعی، نقش تغییرات اقلیم و گرمایش جهانی در گسترش سطح کشت و جابجایی عرصه‌های تولید آن در قالب پروژه‌های کلان بررسی نماید. بدون تردید انتقال یافته‌های علمی به عرصه‌های تولید و عرضه نتایج پژوهش‌ها درقالب نوشتارهای استاندارد بین‌المللی به جامعه علمی جهانی می‌تواند دستاورد عملی چنین جنبشی باشد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>ایران</kwd>
						<kwd>زراعی</kwd>
						<kwd>پژوهش‌های زعفران</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Abrishami, M.H. 2004. Saffron: from the past to the present. Encyclopedia of production, trade and use. Amirkabir Publishing Co. (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Alberini, M. 1990. Saffron: sap ore colors Lo zafferani Proceeds of the International Conference on Saffron (Crocus sativus L.). L`quila, Italy. P. 39-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Askari, M. 1963. Iranian saffron. Thesis. University of Tehran. (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Bagheri, A., and Hematti Kakhki, A. 1989. A review on saffron research. Research in Science and Industry. 10 (20 &amp; 21): 31-58. (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Bahrami, T. 1934. Crop production. Tehran 1: 234-241.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Basker, D., and Negibi, M. 1983. Uses of saffron. Economic botany. 37: 228-236.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A., Nassiri Mahallati, M., and Rezvani Moghaddam, P.  2005. The Evaluation of quantitative relationships between saffron yield and nutrition (On farm trial). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 3(1): 1-14. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P. and Jami Al-Ahmadi, M. 2008a. Agro-ecologicla zoning and potential yield of saffron in Khorasan-Iran. Journal of Biological Sciences 8(2): 298-305.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A., Nassiri, M., and Rezvani Moghaddam, P. 2008b. Models to predict flowering time in the main saffron production regions of Khorasan province. Journal of Applied Sciences 8(5): 907-909.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Caiola, M. G., and Canin, A. 2010. Looking for saffron (Crocus sativus L.) parent's. Functional Plant Science and Biotechnology. Global Science Books.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Ebrahimzade, H., Rajabian, T., Karimian, R., and Abrishami, P. 2006. Iranian saffron: with a research look. Etelaat publisher. (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Fernandez, J. A. 2004. Biology, biotechnology and biomedicine of saffron. Recent Research Development in Plant Science 2: 159-167.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Fernandez, J. A. 2007. Genetic resources of saffron and allies (Crocus spp.) Acta Horticulture 739: 167-189.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Filabi, A., Koocheki, A., and Sadeghi, B. 2011. Sustainable saffron production in Iran (unpublished).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Filabi, A. 2012. New Technology in Saffron production, challenges and approaches. Sixth National Saffron Festival, Ghaen.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Filabi, A. 2013. Personal communication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Ghodoosi, H. 2003. Iranian saffron documentary. Center for Saffron Scientific Information and Research. Mashhad. Iran. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Ghodoosi, H., Koocheki, A., Varidi, M., and Bolandi, M. 2003. Saffron. Seventy years of research on saffron in Iran: a review Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 1(2): 217-247. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Ghorbani, R., and Koocheki, A. 2013. Saffron: Biology and Agronomy (under publication)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Hssanzadeh, F., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Banayan aval, M., and Khorasani, R. 2013. Effects of maternal corm weight and different levels of cow manure on corm and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Saffron Agronomy and Technology (Accepted for publication). (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Hemati, A., and Hosseini, M. 2003. A review on 15 years of saffron research in Khorasan. Institute of Research for Technology Development.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Hosseini, M and Sadeghi, B. 1997. Effect of foliar fertilizer application on yield of saffron. Khorasan Scientific and Industrial Research Organization (research project).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Hosseini, A. 2013. Newsletter of Scientific Network for medicinal plants.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Jafari Shahri, S.H. 1965. Saffron cultivation: planting, stand management and harvesting, Thesis. Tabriz University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Jehade Kashavarzi Khorasan Razavi, 2012. Report on agronomic research for saffron (on published).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Kafi, M., Rashed Mohasel, H., Koocheki, A., and Filabi, A. 2002. Saffron: production and processing technology. Ferdowsi University Press p. 276. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Khosravi, M. 2005. Agroecological and economic prospects for intercropping cumin with saffron and annual crops. MSc. Thesis, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Nassiri Mahallati, M., Alizade, A., and Ganjali, A. 2000. Effect of temperature rise on flowering behavior of saffron. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 8(2): 1-13. (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A. 2003a. Iranian saffron in worldwide, challenges and opportunities. Proceedings of the Third National Saffron Conference. Mashhad. Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A. 2003b. Agriculture research. Past issue and future prospects. Name- ye- Farhangestan-e Olum. 22: 185-203. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Najibnia, S., and Lalehgani, B. 2005. Intercropping saffron with cereals, pulses and medicinal plants. Iranian Journal of Agronomic Researches 1: 175-184. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Ganjali, A., and Abbasi, F. 2006a. Effects of waiting period, corm size and region on corm criteria and above ground organs of saffron. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 4(2): 331-315. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Behdani, M.A., and Nassiri, M. 2006b. Agronomic attributes of saffron yield at agroecosystems scale in Iran. Journal of Applied Horticulture 8(2): 121-124.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Nassiri Mahalati, M., Alizadeh, A., and Ganjali, A. 2009a. Modeling the effects of climate change on flowering behavior of saffron. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 7(2): 583-590. (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A. 2009b. Good practice in saffron production in Iran. 3rd International Saffron Symposium. Greek.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Shabahang, J., and Khoramdel, S. 2010. The effect of irrigation intervals and intercropped marjoram (Origanum vulgare L.) with saffron on possible cooling effect for climate change adaption. Iranian Journal of Agronomic Researches. (Unpublished)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Siahgmargoie, A., Azizi, G., and Jahani, M. 2011. Effect of high corm density and depth of planting on agronomic criteria and corm behavior of saffron. Agroecology 3(1): 36-49. (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Fallahi, J. 2013a. Effects of spring, summer and autumn planting dates, irrigation management and companion crops on saffron yield. Agroecology. (Accepted for publication) (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Molafilabi, A., and Seyedi, M. 2013b. Effect of high corm density and animal manure on flower and corm yield of saffron. (under publication)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Madani. J. 1938. Saffron cultivation in Estahbanat. Farmer's letter. 4(2): 24-24.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammad Abadi, A.A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P. and Fallahi, J. 2011. Effects of planting pattern and the first irrigation date on growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Agroecology 3(1): 84-93. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Mokhtari, M. 2013. Saffron documentation. (Personal communication)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Molina, R.V., Valeron, M., and Nuaro, Y. 2005. Temperature effects on flower formation in saffron. Scientia Horticulture 103: 361-379.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Nassiri Mahalati, M., Koocheki, A., Broomand, Z., and Tabrizi, L. 2005. Effects of corm size and storing period on allocation of photosynthesis material in saffron. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 15(1): 155-166. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Negbi, M. 1999. Saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Medicinal and aromatic plants: industrial profile: Hayward Academic Publisher.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Amiri, M.B., Ehyaee, H.R. 2013a. Effect of different levels of biological fertilizers and mushroom compost on flower yield and characteristics of corms of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in an organic farming system. Journal of Horticultural Science. (Accepted for publication) (In Persian with English summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Huda, A.K.S., Parvez, Q. and Koocheki A. 2007.  Indigenous Knowledge in Agriculture with Particular Reference to Medicinal Crop Production in Khorasan, Iran. World Association for Sustainable Development (WASD) Conference. Fifth International Conference Griffith University, Brisbane, Australia. Pp: 105-115.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Khorramdel, S., Amin Ghafori, A., and Shabahang, S. 2013b. Evaluation of growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) affected by spent mushroom compost and corm density. Journal of Saffron Research (Accepted for publication). (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Khorramdel, S., Shabahang, S., and Amin Ghafori, A. 2013c. Evaluation of planting method, corm weight and density on growth characteristics and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Agroecology (Accepted for publication). (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Koocheki, A., Molafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, M. 2013d. Evaluation of the effect of biological and chemical fertilizers on some aspects of replacement corm and flower yields of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Crop Sciences (Accepted for publication). (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Koocheki, A., Molafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, M. 2013e. Flower and corm characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) as affected by levels of wheat mulch on different dates. Journal of Agroecology (Accepted for publication). (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Mohamad Abadi, A.A., Fallahi, F., and Aghhavani-Shajari, M. 2013f. Effects of nutrient management on flower yield and corm characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Horticultural Science. (Accepted for publication). (In Persian with English summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Sabeti, M. 1936. Saffron and its cultivation. Journal of Higher College of Crop Production (2): 11-14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B. 1988. Effect of chemical fertilizer and animal manure on leaf crop production and saffron yield. Khorasan, Scientific and Industrial Research Organization (research project).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B. 1993. Effect of corm weight on flower production of saffron. Khorasan scientific and Industrial Research Organization (research project).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Sadesghi, B. 1996. Effect of corm storage and date of planting on flower production of saffron. Khorasan Scientific and Industrial Research Organization (Research Project).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, b., 1997.  Effects of summer irrigation on yield of saffron. Khorasan Scientific and Industrial Research Organization. (Research Project)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B., Aghamiri, A., and Negari, A. 2003a. Saffron summer irrigation. Proceedings of the 3rd National Saffron Symposium. Mashhad. Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B., Negari, A., and Hattami, M. 2003b. Effects of time of planting on saffron flower production. Proceeding of the 3rd National Conference on Saffron, Mashhad. Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B. 2008. Strengthening the bases of sustainable saffron cultivation in Iran. Khorasan Razavi. Agricultural organization 26 pp. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B. 2012. Effect of corm weight on Saffron flowering. Proceedings of the 4th International Saffron Symposium. Keshmir. Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi. B. 2013. Round table scientific debate on saffron. Faculty of Agriculture. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B. and Filabi, A. 2013. Personal Communication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Shahalaei, S. M. 1941. Aromatic plants in medicine. Saffron and its useful benefits. Farmers' letter 8: 467.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Shaibani, R.  1931. A guide to saffron cultivation. Journal of Higher College of Crop Production. 4: 111-114.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Shargh Newspaper, 2013. Iran's Scientific Rank. No: 1769. Page: 6.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Soufizadeh, S., Zand, E., and Dihimfard, R. 2013. Evaluation of changes in yield trend and some morphological and physiological traits for wheat, corn and rice during the last 50 years in Iran. (Unpublished)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Willard, P. 2001. Secrets of saffron. The vagabond life of the world's most seductive spice, Beacon Press, Massachusetts. USA. </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Winterhalter, P., and Stranbinger, M. 2000. Saffron renewed interests in an ancient spice. Food Reviews International 16: 39-59.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Zand, E. 2013. Personal communication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Zare Feizabadi, A., Koocheki, A., and Nassiri Mahallati, M. 2006. Evaluation of the trend for average yield and total production of cereals in Iran and the future predictions. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 3(4): 49-69. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2013.4809</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4809_5bdf2836198fcc23f05c20c626a64694.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تأثیر وزن بنه مادری و سطوح مختلف کود گاوی بر عملکرد بنه و گل زعفران (.<i>Crocus sativus</i> L)</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حسن زاده اول</surname>
			            <given-names>فاطمه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکترای اکولوژی گیاهان زراعی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رضوانی مقدم</surname>
			            <given-names>پرویز</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد گروه زراعت دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بنایان اول</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار گروه زراعت دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>خراسانی</surname>
			            <given-names>رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه علوم خاک دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>12</month>
			        <year>2013</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>1</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>22</fpage>
			      <lpage>39</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>10</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2013, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2013</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4809.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4809.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p> به‌منظور مقایسه وزن‌های مختلف بنه مادری کشت شده و تعیین سطوح مناسب کود گاوی بر عملکرد گیاه زعفران (Crocus sativus L.)، آزمایشی طی 2 سال زراعی 1391-1390 و 1392-1391 در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد به‌صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با 4 سطح وزن بنه مادری (شامل گروه‌های وزنی 3 – 1/1، 5 – 1/3، 7 – 1/5 و 9- 1/7 گرم) و 4 سطح کود گاوی (0، 20، 40 و 60 تن در هکتار) و در 3 تکرار اجرا گردید. نتایج تجزیه واریانس شاخص‌های عملکرد بنه زعفران نشان داد که این شاخص‌ها به‌طور معنی‌داری تحت تاثیر وزن بنه مادری و کود گاوی قرار گرفت. همچنین اثر متقابل وزن بنه مادری در سطوح مختلف کود گاوی نیز بر شاخص‌های ذکر شده معنی⁭دار بود. در بین تیمارهای آزمایش، استفاده از بنه مادری با گروه وزنی 9-1/7 گرم با میزان مصرف 60 تن در هکتار کود گاوی، بیشترین تعداد کل بنه در واحد سطح (510 بنه در متر مربع) و بیشترین عملکرد بنه (1044 گرم در متر مربع) را نشان داد. به‌نظر می‌رسد بنه‌های با وزن بیشتر در سال اول کشت، تعداد بنه‌های بیشتری (در هر 4 گروه وزنی) تولید کرده اما بنه‌های با وزن کمتر توانایی تولید بنه‌های با وزن بیشتر از وزن بنه مادری، بیشتری دارند. شاخص‌های عملکرد گل زعفران در سال اول نشان داد که با افزایش وزن بنه‌های کشت شده، عملکرد گل در سال اول کشت افزایش ‌یافت. نتایج تجزیه واریانس تعداد گل و عملکرد تر و خشک گل و کلاله زعفران در سال دوم حاکی از پاسخ معنی‌دار این شاخص‌ها در واکنش به وزن بنه مادری، کود گاوی و اثر متقابل وزن بنه مادری در سطوح مختلف مصرف کود گاوی بود، به‌طوریکه با افزایش وزن بنه مادری و افزایش سطوح مصرف کود گاوی مقادیر این شاخص‌ها افزایش یافت. به نظر می‌رسد تولید بنه‌های با وزن بیشتر در سال اول کشت زعفران و به⁭دنبال آن افزایش عملکرد گل، نیازمند بنه‌های مادری درشت و مصرف کود گاوی در سطوح بیشتر باشد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>اندازه بنه</kwd>
						<kwd>بنه دختری</kwd>
						<kwd>کود دامی</kwd>
						<kwd>عملکرد کلاله</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Alizadeh, A., Sayari, N., Ahmadian, J., and Mohamadian, A. 2009. Study for zoning the most appropriate time of irrigation of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Razavi, northern and southern Khorasan provinces. Journal of Water and Soil 23(1): 109-118. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Amirghasemi, T. 2001. Saffron, Red Gold of Iran. Nashr- Ayandegan Publication 112 pp. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Amiri, M.E. 2008. Impact of animal manures and chemical fertilizers on yield components of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). American-Eurasian Journal of Agriculture and Environmental Science 4: 274-279.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Arslan, N., Ozer, A.S., and Akdemir, R. 2009. Cultivation of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) and effects of organic fertilizers to the flower yield. Acta Horticulturae 826: 237-240.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Azizi-Zohan, A.A., Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A., and Sepaskhah, A.R. 2006. Effect of irrigation method and frequency on corm and saffron production (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Science and Technology of Agriculture and Natural Resources 10(1): 45-54. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Azizi-Zohan, A.A., Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A., and Sepaskhah, A.R. 2008. Crop and pan coefficients for saffron in a semi-arid region of Iran. Journal of Arid Environments 72: 270-278. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A., Nassiri, M., and Rezvani Moghaddam, P. 2006. Evaluation of quantitative relationships between saffron yield and nutrition (on farm trial). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 3: 1-14. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Behnia, M.R. 2009. Effect of planting methods and corm density in saffron (Crocus sativus L.) yield in damavand region. Pajouhesh and Sazandegi 79: 101-08. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Ghorbani, R., and Koocheki, A. 2006. Organic saffron in Iran: prospects and challenges. Acta Horticulture 739: 369-374.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Hoseyni, M., Mollafilabi, A., and Nassiri Mahallati, M.2008. Spatial and temporal patterns in saffron (Crocus sativus L.) yield of Khorasan province and their relationship with long term weather variation. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 6(1): 79-88. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Jahan, M., and Jahani, M. 2007. The effects of chemical and organic fertilizers on saffron flowering. Acta Horticulturae 739: 81-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Jami-alahmadi, M., Behdani, M.A., and Akbarpour, A. 2009. Analysis of agronomic effective factors on yield of saffron agroecosystems in southern khorasan. 3nd International Symposium on Saffron, 20-23 may. Greece. pp 14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Kafi, M. 2002. Saffron, Production and Processing. Zaban va Adab Press (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A. 2004. Indigenous knowledge in agriculture with particular reference to saffron production in Iran. Acta Horticulturae 650: 175-182.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Alizadeh, A., and Ganjali, A. 2010. The effect of increased temperature on flowering behaviour of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 8(2): 324-335. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Mollafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2013. Effects of corm planting density and applying manure on flower and corm yields of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in the first year. Journal of Agroecology (in press). (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Koochaki, A., Tabrizi, L., Jahani, M., and Mohammad Abadi, A.A. 2012. An evaluation of the effect of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm planting rate and pattern on the crop's performance. Iranian Journal of Horticultural Science 42: 379-391. (In Persian with English Summary) </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammdi Aria, M., Lakzian, A., Haghnia, Gh., Besharati, H., and Fotovat, A. 2010. The effect of Thiobacillus and Aspergillus on phosphorus availability of enriched rock phosphate with sulfur and vermicompost. Journal of Water and Soil 24: 1-9. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Molina, R.V., Valero, M., Navarro, Y., Guardiola J.L., and Garcia-Luice, A. 2005. Temperature effects on flower formation in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Scientia Horticulture 103: 361-379.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Mosaferi, Z.H., 2001. Effects of different irrigation regimes on saffron yield. M.Sc. Thesis, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Naderi Darbaghshahi, M.R., Khajebashi, S.M., Banitaba, S.A., and Dehdashti, S.M. 2009. Effects of planting method, density and depth on yield and production period of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Isfahan region. Seed and Plant 24: 643-657. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Nassiri Mahallati, M., Koocheki, A., Boroumand Rezazadeh, Z., and Tabrizi, L. 2007. Effects of corm size and storage period on allocation of assimilates in different parts of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 5: 155-166. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Omidi, H., Naghdibadi, H.A., Golzad, A., Torabi, H., and Fotoukian, M.H. 2009. The effect of chemical and bio-fertilizer source of nitrogen on qualitative and quantitative yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Medicinal Plant 8: 98-109. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Pandey, D., Pandey, V.S., and Srivastava, R.P. 1979. A note on the effect of the size of corms on the sprouting and flowering of saffron. Progressive Horticulture 6: 89-92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani-Moghaddam, P., Mohammad-Abadi, A.A., and Sabori, A. 2006. Effect of different animal manure on flower yield and qualitative and quantitative characteristics of forage production of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Mashhad conditions. Acta Horticulture 739: 159-163.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Mohammad abadi, A.A., Fallahi, J., and Aghhavani Shajari, M. 2010. Effects of chemical and organic fertilizers on number of corm and stigma yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). 59th International Congress and Annual Meeting of the Society for Medicinal Plant and Natural Product Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B. 1993. Effect of corm weight on flowering of saffron. Research and industrial Institutes of Khorasan, Press. 73 pp. (In Persian) _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2013.4810</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4810_a57089c7ceacbc722b38950bd3434e7a.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>زیست فناوری، ژنتیک و اصلاح نباتات</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تجزیه و تحلیل بیوانفورماتیکی توالی‌های EST کلاله زعفران (.<i>Crocus sativus</i> L) به منظور تعیین جهت‌گیری کارکردی ژنوم و شبکه ژنی</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>علی اکبری</surname>
			            <given-names>معصومه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانش¬آموخته کارشناسی ارشد اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه شیراز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>شاملو دشت پاگردی</surname>
			            <given-names>روح اله</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری زراعت اصلاح تباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه شیراز.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>ابراهیمی</surname>
			            <given-names>اسماعیل</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه شیراز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>12</month>
			        <year>2013</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>1</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>40</fpage>
			      <lpage>54</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>09</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2013, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2013</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4810.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4810.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>روش‌های ژنومیکس کارکردی نظیر تجزیه و تحلیل توالی‌های EST، امکان شناسایی، بررسی بیان و مطالعه رونوشت‌های ژنی درگیر در شبکه‌های تنظیمی و متابولیکی را فرآهم آورده‌اند. در این پژوهش به منظور شناسایی جهت گیری کارکردی ژنوم و تعیین شبکه ژنی درگیر در تکامل کلاله زعفران، 6202 توالی EST مربوط به کتابخانه‌ی کلاله بالغ زعفران مورد بررسی و تحلیل قرار گرفتند. پس از پیرایش اولیه توالی‌ها، دسته بندی و هم گذاری آنها انجام شد که منتج به ایجاد 910 unigene (604 کانتیگ و 304 سینگلتون) گردید. جستجوی بلاست ایکس نشان داد که 570 unigene دارای hit مشخص در بین پروتئین‌های آرابیدوپسیس بودند و برای سایر توالی‌ها hit مشخصی شناسایی نشد. گروه‌بندی و Gene enrichment analysis توالی‌ها آنها را در 31 گروه کارکردی مختلف قرار داد که حضور 12 گروه در سطح آماری 1% معنی‌دار گردید. شبکه ژنی مربوط به توالی های با حضور بالا (بیش از 20 رونوشت)، نشان داد که ارتباطات ژنی پیچیده ای در کلاله بالغ زعفران وجود دارد. نتایج مشخص نمود که مسیر علامت‌دهی جاسمونیک اسید و عوامل رونویسی مربوط به آن همچون MYB21 و Zinc finger ها سهم بزرگی از شبکه تنظیمی را به خود اختصاص می‌دهند و نقش کلیدی ای در تنظیم متابولیسم اولیه و ثانویه کلاله و به خصوص متابولیسم کارتنوئیدها (به عنوان مهم ترین متابولیت های زعفران)، بر عهده دارند. ژن‌های شناسایی شده در این پژوهش می توانند نامزدهای مناسبی برای دست‌ورزی تکامل و متابولیسم کلاله زعفران باشند.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>ژنومیکس کارکردی</kwd>
						<kwd>کارتنوئید</kwd>
						<kwd>متابولیت ثانویه</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Ahrazem, O., Trapero, A., Gómez, M. D., Rubio-Moraga, A and Gómez-Gómez L. 2010. Genomic analysis and gene structure of the plant carotenoid dioxygenase 4 family: A deeper study in Crocus sativus L. and its allies. Genomics 96: 239-250.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Ajam, M. 2007. Red gold of Iran is still unrivalled. Available at Web site http://hamshahrionline.ir/details/38311.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Ali, Q., Ahsan. M., Tahir. M., Elahi. M., farooq. J. and Waseem, M. 2011. Gene expression and functional genomics approach for abiotic stress tolerance in different crop species. 2011. IJAVMS 5: 221-248.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Carlson, S., J. P., Chourey1, S., Helentjaris, T. and Datta, R. 2002. Gene expression studies on developing kernels of maize sucrose synthase (SuSy) mutants show evidence for a third SuSy gene. Plant Molecular Biology49: 15-29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, S.,  Li, X. Q., Zhao, A.,  Wang, L.,  Li, X., Shi, Q., Chen, M., Guo, J., Zhang, J., Qi, D. and Liu, G. 2009. Genes and Pathways Induced in Early Response to Defoliation in Rice Seedlings. Current Issues in Molecular Biology 11: 81-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Cushman, J. C. and Bohnert, H. J. 2000. Genomic approaches to plant stress tolerance. Current Opinion in Plant Biology 3: 117-124.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Dong, Q., Kroiss, L., Oakley, F. D., Wang, B. and V. Brendel. 2005. Comparative EST analysis in plant systems. Methods in enzymology 395: 400-416.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Fiore, A., Pizzichini. D., Diretto. G., Scossa. F. and Spano, L. 2010. Genomics and Transcriptomics of Saffron: new tools to unravel the mistery behind an attractive spice. Functional Plant Science and Biotechnology 4: 2-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Fleury, D., Jefferies. S., Kuchel, H. and Langridge, P. 2010. Genetic and genomic tools to improve drought tolerance in wheat. Journal of Experimental Botany 61: 3211-3222.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Gomez-Gomez, L., Rubio-Moraga, A. And Ahrazem, O. Anderstanding carotenoid metabolism in Saffron stigmas: Unravelling aroma and colour formation. 2010. Functional plant science and biotechnology 4(2): 56-63.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Hunter, W.N. 2007. The Non-mevalonate Pathway of Isoprenoid Precursor Biosynthesis. The Journal of Biological Chemistry 282 (30): 21573–21577.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Kladnik, A., Vilhar, B., Chourey. P.S. and Dermastia, M. 2004. Sucrose synthase isozyme SUS1 in the maize root cap is preferentially localized in the endopolyploid outer cells. Canadian Journal of Botany 82: 96-103.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Mandaokar, A., Thines1, B., Shin, B., Markus Lange1, B., Choi, G., Koo, Y.J., Yoo, Y. J., Choi, Y. D., Choi, G. and Browse J. 2006. Transcriptional regulators of stamen development in Arabidopsis identified by transcriptional profiling The Plant Journal 46: 984–1008.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Masoudi-Nejad, A., K. Tonomura, S. Kawashima, Y. Moriya, M. Suzuki, M. Itoh, M. Kanehisa, T. Endo and S. Goto. 2006. EGassembler: online bioinformatics service for large-scale processing, clustering and assembling ESTs and genomic DNA fragments. Nucleic Acids Research Vol. 34, Web Server Issue: 459-462.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Ogata, O and Suzukim H. 2011. Plant expressed sequence tags databases: practical uses and the improvement of their searches using network module analysis. Plant Biotechnology 28: 351-360.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Reeves, P. H., Ellis, C. M., Ploense, S. E., Wu, M-F., Yadav, V., Tholl, D., Che´ telat, A., Haupt, I., Kennerley, B. J., Hodgens, C., Farmer, E . E., Nagpal, P. and Reed, J. W. 2012. A Regulatory Network for Coordinated Flower Maturation. PLoS Genetics 8(2): e1002506</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Rubio, A., Rambla, JL., Ahrazem, O., Granell, A. and Gomez-Gomez, L. 2009. Metabolite and target transcript analysis during Crocus sativus L. stigma development. Phytochemestry 70: 1009-1016.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Srivastava, R., Ahmed, H., Dharamveer, D. R. K and Saraf, S. A. 2010. Crocus sativus L.: A comprehensive review. Pharmacogn Rev 4(8): 200-208.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Urano, K., Kurihara. Y., Seki, M. and Shinozaki, K. 2010. ‘Omics’ analyses of regulatory networks in plant abiotic stress responses. Current Opinion in Plant Biology 13: 132-138.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Usadel, B., Nagel. A., Steinhauser, D., Gibon, Y., O. Bläsing, E., Redestig. H., Sreenivasulu. N., Krall. L., Hannah, M. A., Poree, F., Fernie, A. R. and Stitt, M. 2006. PageMan: An interactive ontology tool to generate, display, and annotate overview graphs for profiling experiments. BMC Bioinformatics 7: 535.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Xoconostle-Cazares, B., Ramirez-Ortega, F., Flores-Elenes, L. and R. Ruiz-Medrano. 2010. Drought tolerance in crop plants. American journal of plant physiology 5: 241-256. _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2013.4811</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4811_1364d95726c5ffe883521030081e71a8.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>اثرات تاریخ و مقادیر کاربرد کاه و کلش گندم برخصوصیات بنه های دختری و گل‌انگیزی زعفران (.<i>Crocus sativus</i> L) در سال دوم</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رضوانی مقدم</surname>
			            <given-names>پرویز</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد قطب علمی گیاهان ویژه، گروه زراعت دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>کوچکی</surname>
			            <given-names>علیرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد قطب علمی گیاهان ویژه، گروه زراعت دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>ملافیلابی</surname>
			            <given-names>عبداله</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیئت علمی پژوهشکده علوم و صنایع غذایی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>سیدی</surname>
			            <given-names>سید محمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری اکولوژی گیاهان زراعی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>12</month>
			        <year>2013</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>1</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>55</fpage>
			      <lpage>70</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>26</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2013, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2013</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4811.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4811.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>به‌منظور بررسی تاثیر زمان پخش و مقادیر کاربرد کاه و کلش گندم بر شاخص‌های مربوط به عملکرد بنه‌های دختری زعفران در سال دوم، آزمایشی در دو سال زراعی 90-1389 و 1391-1390 بصورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با 15 تیمار و سه تکرار در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد اجرا شد. تیمارهای آزمایش بر اساس پنج سطح کاربرد مالچ کلش گندم (شاهد (عدم پخش مالچ)، 2، 4، 6 و 8 تن در هکتار) در سه زمان (خرداد، مرداد و مهرماه) به‌صورت پخش سطحی طراحی شدند. نتایج تجزیه واریانس در آزمایش حاکی از تاثیر معنی‌دار زمان پخش مالچ کلش گندم، مقادیر کاربرد مالچ و نیز اثر متقابل آن‌ها بر تمامی شاخص‌های کمی گل زعفران بود. بر اساس نتایج آزمایش، پخش مالچ کلش در مهرماه بیشترین تاثیر را در افزایش معنی‌دار تعداد گل در متر مربع و عملکرد گل‌تر و ‌خشک زعفران (به ترتیب تا 46، 61 و 65 درصد) داشت. هم‌چنین تمامی شاخص‌های مورد مطالعه بنه‌های دختری زعفران به‌طور معنی‌داری تحت تاثیر زمان پخش مالچ کلش گندم قرار گرفت. در بین تیمارهای مورد بررسی، بیشترین افزایش در عملکرد بنه‌های بیش از 12 گرم و عملکرد کل بنه‌های دختری زعفران در نتیجه کاربرد 8 تن مالچ کلش در مهرماه مشاهده شد. به‌طوری که کاربرد تیمار ذکر شده در مقایسه با شاهد، عملکرد بنه‌های با وزن بیش از 12 گرم و عملکرد کل بنه‌های زعفران را به‌ترتیب تا 104 و 103 درصد افزایش داد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>بنه‌های زعفران</kwd>
						<kwd>گل‌انگیزی</kwd>
						<kwd>مالچ گندم</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Aghaei, M., and Rezagholizadeh, M. 2011. Iran's comparative advantage in production of saffron. Journal of Agricultural Economics and Development 25: 121–132. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Azad shahraky, F., Taghavi, H., and Najafi, H. 2010. Effect of tillage and crop residue management on soil properties and yield of corn in Kerman. Knowledge of Modern Agriculture 6:1–9. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Bastian, F., Bouziri, L., Nicolardot, B., and Ranjard, L. 2009. Impact of wheat straw decomposition on successional patterns of soil microbial community structure. Soil Biology and Biochemistry 41:262–275.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Behboodi, B.S., and Samadi, L. 2004. The morphological study of amyloplast distribution in Crocus sativus L. fibrous roots. ISHS Acta Horticulturae 650 First International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Biotechnology: 49–54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A., Nassiri, M., and Rezvani Moghaddam, P. 2006. Evaluation of quantitative relationships between saffron yield and nutrition (on farm trial). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 3: 1–14. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, S., Zhang, X., Pei, D., and Sun, H. 2005. Effects of corn straw mulching on soil temperature and soil evaporation of winter wheat field. Transactions of the Chinese Society of Agricultural Engineering 21: 171–173.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, S.Y., Zhang, X.Y., Pei, D., Sun, H.Y., and Chen, S.L. 2007. Effects of straw mulching on soil temperature, evaporation and yield of winter wheat: Field experiments on the North China Plain. Annals of Applied Biology 150: 261–268.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Cheraghi, S., Rafiei, M., and Khorgami, A. 2011. The Effect of Foliar Application of Nitrogen at Different Dates, and Planting Method on Grain Yield, and Yield Components of Mung Bean in the Environmental Conditions of Khoramabad. Journal of Crop Physiology 3: 15-29. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Danga, B.O., and Wakindiki, I.I.C. 2009. Effect of placement of straw mulch on soil conservation, nutrient accumulation, and wheat yield in a humid Kenyan highland. Journal of Tropical Agriculture 47: 30–36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Du Prezz, C.C., Steyn, J.T., and Kotze, E. 2001. Long-term effects of wheat residue management on some fertility indicators of a semi-arid plinth sol. Soil and Tillage Research 63: 25–33.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Foroughifar, H., and Pour Kasmani, M.E. 2002. Soil Science and Management. (Translated) Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Press, Iran. 336 pp. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Ghorbani, R. 2006. The economics of saffron in Iran. Proceedings of the 2th International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Technology. Mashhad, Iran, 28–30 October 2006. 14 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Gresta, F., Avola, G., Lombardoa, G.M., Siracusa, L., and Ruberto, G. 2009. Analysis of flowering, stigma yield and qualitative traits of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) as affected by environmental conditions. Horticultural Sciences 119: 320–324.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Hatami Sardashti, Z., Jami Al-Ahmadi, M., Mahdavi Damghani, A.M., and Behdani M.A. 2011. Evaluation of sustainability in saffron agroecosystems in Birjand and Qaen counties. Journal of Agroecology 3: 396–405. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Jorabloo, A., ghoshchi, F., Morteza, A., and Silispoor, M. 2009. Effect of seedbed preparation and barley residue on corn forage yield and quality. Crop Ecophysiology 1: 44-53. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Kamkar, B., and Mahdavi Damghani, A. 2008. Principle of Sustainable Agriculture. JDM Press, 316 pp.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Khan, I.A. 2004. Induced mutagenic variability in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). ISHS Acta Horticulture 650. First International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Biotechnology: 281–284.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Koochaki, A., Tabrizi, L., Jahani, M., and Mohammad Abadi, A.A. 2012.  An evaluation of the effect of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm planting rate and pattern on the crop's performance. Iranian Journal of Horticultural Science 42: 379–391. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Gholami, A., Mahvadi Damghani, A., and Tabrizi, L. 2007. Organic Field Crop Handbook (Translated). Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Press, Iran. 385 pp. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Jahani, M., Tabrizi, L., and Mohammad Abadi, A.A. 2011. Investigation on the Effect of biofertilizer, chemical fertilizer and plant density on yield and corm criteria of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Water and Soil 25:196–206. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A., Nassiri, M., Alizadeh, A., and Ganjali, A. 2010. Modelling the impact of climate change on flowering behaviour of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 7: 583–594. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Limon-Ortega, A., Govaerts, B., and Sayre, K.D. 2008. Straw management, crop rotation, and nitrogen source effect on wheat grain yield and nitrogen use efficiency. European Journal of Agronomy 29: 21–28.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Molina, R.V., García-Luis, A., Coll, V., Ferrer, C., Valero, M., Navarro, Y., and Guardiola, J.L. 2004. Flower formation in the saffron (Crocus sativus L.). The role of temperature. Acta Horticulturae 650. First International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Biotechnology 39–48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Molina, R.V., Valero, M., Navarro, Y., Guardiola, J.L., and Garcia-Luis, A. 2005. Temperature effects on flower formation in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Sciatica Horticulture 103: 361–379.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Monzon, J.P., Sadras, V.O., and Andrade, F.H. 2006. Fallow soil evaporation and water storage as affected by stubble in sub-humid (Argentina) and semi-arid (Australia) environments. Field Crops Research 98: 83–90.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Naderi Darbaghshahi, M.R., Khajebashi, S.M., Banitaba, S.A., and Dehdashti, S.M. 2009. Effects of planting method, density and depth on yield and production period of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Isfahan region. Seed and Plant 24: 643–657. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Najafinezhad, H., Javaheri, M.A., Ravari, S.Z.A., and Azad Shahraki, F.A.D. 2009. Effect of crop rotation and wheat residue management on grain yield of maize cv. KSC704 and some soil properties. Seed and Plant Production Journal 25(2): 247–260. (In Persian with English Summary)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Nehvi, F.A., Lone, A.A., Khan, M.A., and Maghdoomi, M.I. 2010. Comparative study on effect of nutrient management on growth and yield of saffron under temperate conditions of Keshmir. Acta Horticulturae 850. Third International Symposium on Saffron: Forthcoming Challenges in Cultivation, Research and Economics: 165–170.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Pandey, D., Pandey, V.S., and Srivastava, R.P. 1979. A note on the effect of the size of corms on the sprouting and flowering of saffron. Progressive Horticulture 6:89–92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B. 1994. Effect of corm weight on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) flowering. Iranian Research Organization for Science &amp; Technology (I.R.O.S.T.).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B. 1996. Effects of corm size on flower production in saffron. Annual Report, Scientific and Industrial Research Organization of Khorasan, Mashhad, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B. 2008. Sustainable cropping of saffron in Iran. Research Report. Research Institute for Food Science and Technology, Razavi Korasan.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B., Aghamiri, S.A. and Negari, A.K. 1997. Effect of summer irrigation on increasing saffron (Crocus Sativus L.) yield. Iranian Research Organization for Science &amp; Technology (I.R.O.S.T.).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B., Razavi, M., and Mohajeri, M. 1987. Effect of chemical elements on saffron cultivation improvement. Khorasan Agricultural Research Center Pub.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Singh Sidhu, A., Sekhon, N.K., Thind, S.S., and Hira, G.S. 2007. Soil temperature, growth and yield of maize (Zea mays L.) as affected by wheat straw mulch. Archives of Agronomy and Soil Science 53: 95–102. _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2013.4812</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4812_035e1b027a6554719db8b1a9011a1b9b.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>امکان سنجی نواحی مستعد کشت زعفران در دشت کاشمر با استفاده از GIS</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>علـوی زاده</surname>
			            <given-names>سید امیر محمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار گروه جغرافیا و برنامه¬ریزی روستایی، دانشگاه پیام نور</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>منظم اسماعیل پور</surname>
			            <given-names>علی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری اقلیم شناسی، دانشگاه خوارزمی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حسین زاده کرمانی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمود</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>مدرس دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>12</month>
			        <year>2013</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>1</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>71</fpage>
			      <lpage>95</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>25</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>28</day>
			          <month>08</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2013, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2013</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4812.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4812.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>زعفران به‌عنوان گران‌بهاترین محصول کشاورزی و دارویی جهان از جمله گیاهانی است که با توجه به مقاومت خود در برابر خشکی نقش قابل توجهی در وضعیت اقتصادی و اجتماعی مناطق خشک و نیمه خشک خراسان جنوبی و رضوی پیدا کرده است. هدف اصلی این مطالعه، تعیین نواحی مستعد کشت زعفران با توجه به برخی متغیرهای اصلی مؤثر در آن می‌باشد. داده‌های اقلیمی مورد نیاز، از اداره کل هواشناسی خراسان رضوی برای دوره 1390-1368 اخذ شد. جهت تهیه نقشه سطوح ارتفاعی، شیب، جهت شیب، و TIN (شبکه نامنظم مثلثاتی) از نقشه‌های توپوگراف DEM(مدل رقومی ارتفاع) سازمان نقشه‌برداری با مقیاس 50000 :1استفاده گردید. نقشه پوشش گیاهی و کاربری اراضی از نقشه‌های قابلیت اراضی در مقیاس50000 :1 مربوط به موسسه تحقیقات آب و خاک کشور استخراج گردید. از سامانه اطلاعات جغرافیایی به‌منظور رقومی‌سازی و تهیه نقشه‌ها استفاده شد. پس از تشکیل پایگاه اطلاعات فضایی منطقه، با استفاده از نرم ‌افزار ArcGIS 9.3 اطلاعات توصیفی نقشه‌ها به آنها اضافه گردید. سپس براساس شرایط مورد نیاز در خصوص هر پارامتر و اهمیت هر یک از لایه‌ها، با استفاده از نرم‌افزار  AHP (فرایند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی) وزن‌دهی صورت گرفت و پس از عملیات هم‌پوشانی وزنی در محیط GIS پهنه‌بندی انجام گردید. نتایج حاصله قسمت‌های مرکزی و جنوبی دشت را به‌عنوان مستعدترین مناطق نشان داد که در حال حاضر کاربری این اراضی به کشت دیم، آبی، مراتع نیمه متراکم و متراکم اختصاص دارد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>پهنه‌بندی</kwd>
						<kwd>زعفران</kwd>
						<kwd>سیستم اطلاعات جغرافیایی</kwd>
						<kwd>شاخص‌های محیطی و اقلیمی</kwd>
						<kwd>کاشمر</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Abrishami, MH, 1987. Historical cognition of Iran's saffron, Toosi publishing house, Tehran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Adab, H. Esmaili,R., 2008, Evaluation of kriging and linear regression methods based on DEM Interpolation in the preparation of annual plan iso precipitation in Razavi Khorasan, Geographical Research Quarterly, No. 83, pp. 1-12. (In Persian with English summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Agricultural Organization annals of Razavi Khorasan Province, statistics unit, 2011. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Alijani, B &amp; Kaviani, M R. 1992. The Climatology Bases, Samt publishing house. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Alizadeh, A. 2002. Irrigation in saffron cultivation, articles collection of production technology, the publishing house of Mashhad Ferdosi University. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Alizadeh, A. Kamali.Gh, 2003. The pure need to irrigation of agricultural and garden products of Iran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Amir Ghasemi, T, 2004 .Saffron the red gold of Iran, Ayandegan publishing house, Tehran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Baily, H. P. 1979. Agriculture in Simi-Arid Environmental, Ecological Studies 34. Edited by: A.E.HALL, G.H. CANNELL and H.W. LOWTON.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Bazr Afshan, J &amp; ebrahim zadeh, I. 2006. An analysis on spatial diffusion of saffron in Iran and the effective factors on it, case study of khorasan province, Geography and Development Journal, fall &amp; winter. (In Persian with English summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Behdani. M, 2005. The ecological distribution and protection of function fluctuations of saffron in Khorasan, cultivation doctoral thesis, Agriculture &amp; Plants Improvement Department, The University of Mashhad Ferdosi. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Behnia, M R, 1991. Saffron Cultivation, The university publishing house of Tehran, Tehran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>BIaauw, A. H., 1935. DePeriodicke on Twling Van Een Boliris, Verhadel- ingder Koninklijke Academia Van Wetensch Append Afdeeling.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Buzanov, I.P 1968.Biologiya I selekticya sakharnio svekly. (Biology and sugar beet breeding). Kolos. Moskva.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Cropwat. 2010. Cropwat Version 8. Cropwat Software, London, FAO.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Drachovska, H, and sandera, 1959. Physiologic cukrovky. (Sugar beet physiology). Csav, praha.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Faraj Zadeh.M &amp; Teklobighash.A .2001. the agroclimatic distribution of Hamedan Province by using geographical information system, Geographical Research Journal, Geography school, No 14, pp 63-105. (In Persian with English summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Fekrat, H ,Ehtesham, M. Dadkhah,M, 2003. Iran's saffron, an unknown gem (planting, protection, harvesting and production), Shahr Ashoub publishing house, first edition, Tehran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Fiedler, 1975. J: Technology vyroby curvy. (Technology of sugar beet production). SZN, praha.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Geography Organization of Armed Forces, region topography maps with scale 125000.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Grik, D, 1996, an introduction on agricultural geography, translated by Koochaki Avaz Dehghanian, S. Ahari,A., the publishing house of Mashhad Ferdosi University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Halevy, A. H., 1990, Recent Advance in Control of Flowering Habit of Geophytes,Acta Horticulture, No. 266: 35-42.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Hashemlooyan B &amp; Ataie Azimi A, 2007. Saffron, scientific- specialized monthly of Olive, Islamic Azad University, Saveh unit, No 183, pp. 47-51. (In Persian with English summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Havlicek, 1985.J: vivo pocasi Na vysledky rostlinne vyroby (The effect of weather on cropproduction). Studding informs ace, Ovitz praha.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Holford.I.C.R, (1973), Phosphate adsorption by soils and its relationship to soil phosphates and plant availability, Ph.D. thesis London University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Houchang J, 1994. Agriculture and Climate, translated by Ali Zadeh A &amp; Koochaki A, The publishing house of Mashhad Ferdowsi University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Ismail-Zadeh, y, Jahanbakhsh., S., 2011, applicable requirements for saffron Agro climate with plain Magi, Journal - Geographical Space Research, Year 11, No. 35, pp. 18-1. (In Persian with English summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Kafi Mohammad, 2002. Saffron Eco physiology, saffron articles collection on production technology, the publishing house of Mashhad Ferdowsi University. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Kafi, M, and Kamkar,B.Mahdavi Damghani,A.B, Lahuti, M, 2003, the reactions of agricultural plants to the growth environment, the publishing house of Mashhad Ferdowsi University. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Kamali, G A, 1982. The bioclimatic plan of saffron in south of Khorasan , a review on 15 year researches of saffron in the research center of development and technology researches of Khorasan, pp. 10-14. (In Persian with English summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Kenny, G, and Warrick,R.A, Campbell,B.D, Sims, G.c, Camilleri,P.D Jamieson,N.d, 2000, Investigating climate change impacts and thresholds, climate change, no 46: 91-113.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A &amp; Khazaneh dari L, 1997. Agricultural continent and geography, quarterly journal of agricultural researches, No 45, pp. 56-71. (In Persian with English summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Koocheki, A, Dehghanian, S. Ahari,A. (translation), 1997. Written by David G., an introduction on agricultural geography, the publishing house of Mashhad Ferdowsi University. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Kudrna, k: zemedelske soutavy, 1979. (Agricultural systems).sis, praha.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Kurpelova, M; Trank,M. 1975. (Agro climatic condition of Czechoslovakia). Hydrometeor logic staves, period, Bratislava.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Makhdoom, majid, 1995. Infrastructure of land preparation, the publishing house of Tehran University. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Mirza bayati, R, 2005, the Estimation of saffron-growing areas in neyshabour plain by GIS, thesis submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirement for the degree master of science Geography, University of Tarbiat Modarres ,Tehran. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Mobaraki, Zahra, 2005. Mechanical planting of saffron in Qazvin Province, M.A thesis, Geography school, Tehran University. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammadi,H, and ranjbar F,soltani.M , 2011. Assess potential climate saffron in Marvdasht, Journal of Geography and Environmental Planning, Age 22, Serial No. 43, autumn 1390, pp. 154-143. (In Persian with English summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Molina R.V., Valero M., Navarro Y., Guardiola J.L., and García-Luis A. 2005. Temperature effects on flower formation in saffron (Crocus sativus). Sciatica Hort. Sci., 103:3.361-379.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Mosaferi, Z, 2001.the effects of various irrigation systems on the function of saffron, M.A thesis. Drainage Irrigation, Mashhad Ferdowsi University. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Nokandi A, 1999. Climate effects on saffron planting in south of Khorasan, M.A thesis, Isfahan University. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Jay.P,Weather and Yield, 2000. Translated by;Kafi,M,Ganjali,A,Nezami,A and F,Shariatmadar,Jihad Daneshgahi Mashhad publication, (in Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Plessner, O. and Ziv, M.1990, Corn Production in Saffron Crocus, Department of Agricultural Botany.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Rahmati, E, 2003.The function of environmental factors in production and function of saffron, Articles collection of the third national congress of saffron, The publishing house of Khorasan Research Organisation for Science &amp; Technology, pp. 146-151. (In Persian with English summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Rastin.N.J. 1985, Effective raining in irrigated farming, the university publishing center of Tehran. (In Persian).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Research-analytic news transmission monthly of Baghdar journal, 2009. NO35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Sadeghi, B. 1989. Botanic and Saffron, The publishing house of Khorasan Center Research Organization for Science &amp; Technology, Mashhad. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Sing Jasber &amp; S.S.Villon, 1995. Agricultural Geography .translation: Siavash Dehghanian et al., The publishing house of Mashhad Ferdowsi University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Statistics &amp; information of synoptic station of Khorasan Razavi Weather Organization.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Stehlk, V; 1982.Biologie druhu, variet a forem rep rodu beta L (Biologyof the species, varieties and forms of beets of the beta L genus with respect to large –scale production). Academia, praha.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Vafabakhsh, J, 2003. Potentiometric of saffron planting regions in Iran, The publishing house of Khorasan Center Research Organization for Science &amp; Technology, pp. 99-108. (In Persian with English summary).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Water &amp; soil research institute, land use map of region in scale of 125000.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>www.saharkhizsaffron.com. (Verified 15 December 2012).</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله علمی پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">زعفران</journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">University Of Torbat Heydarieh</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2383-1529</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">65</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.22048/jsat.2013.4813</article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4813_a4dcce887f7423ad6460ca126a27fa15.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>علوم و صنایع دارویی و پزشکی</subject>
					          		<subject>فرآوری، صنایع غذایی و بیوشیمی</subject>
					          		<subject>کشاورزی و علوم پایه</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تاثیر حلال در پیش تغلیظ و اندازه گیری کادمیوم در نمونه های زعفران به روش میکرواستخراج مایع-مایع پخشی بر پایه جامد شدن قطره آلی شناور- اسپکتروفتومتری UV- Vis</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حیدری</surname>
			            <given-names>سمیه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده کشاورزی، بخش گیاهان دارویی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه، تربت حیدریه</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>12</month>
			        <year>2013</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>1</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>96</fpage>
			      <lpage>115</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>31</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>03</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2013</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2013, University Of Torbat Heydarieh. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2013</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4813.html">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_4813.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>در این پژوهش از روش میکرواستخراج مایع- مایع پخشی بر پایه جامد شدن قطره آلی شناور – اسپکتروفتومتری UV- Vis به‌منظور استخراج و اندازه گیری آلاینده کادمیوم در نمونه‌های زعفران استفاده شد. اتانول به عنوان حلال پخشی، 1- آندکانول به عنوان حلال استخراج و استون به‌عنوان حلال رقیق کننده استفاده گردید. بررسی ها نشان داد که نوع و حجم حلال پخشی، حلال استخراج و حلال رقیق کننده در راندمان استخراج تاثیر به‌سزایی دارد. تحت شرایط بهینه، حد تشخیص 0005/0 میکروگرم بر میلی لیتر به‌دست آمد. نمونه‌های زعفران تربت حیدریه، قائنات و باخرز با روش پیشنهادی مورد تجزیه قرار گرفت و درصد بازیابی برای نمونه های زعفران آلوده شده با 1/0 میکروگرم بر میلی لیتر از کادمیوم به‌دست آمد. </p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>اندازه گیری اسپکتروفتومتری</kwd>
						<kwd>زعفران</kwd>
						<kwd>کادمیوم</kwd>
						<kwd>میکرواستخراج</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Dabiri, M. 1375. Environmental pollution (air, soil, water, noise). Tehran: Alliance Publishing 58-160.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Ballantyne, B., Marrs T.C., and Syverson T. 1994. General applied toxicology. Second edition. New York, Groves Dictionaries inc 210-212.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Shuklasr, p. 2005. Adsorption of Cu, Ni, and Zn on modified jute fibers. Bioresource Technology 6: 1430-38.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Lie, G.C., Lin, H.T., and Lai, C.S. 1990. Investigation of the heavy metal content in soil and rice at the fields irrigated by the waste water of cadmium stearate manufactory. Proceeding of the 2nd Workshop of Soil Pollution Prevention; National Taiwan University, Taipei, Taiwan.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Fu, J., Zhou, Q., Liu, J., Liu, W., Wang, T., and Zhang, Q. 2008. High levels of heavy metals in rice from a typical e-Waste recycling area in southeast China and its potential risk to human health. Chemosphere 71: 1269-75.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Zazouli, M.A., Bandpei, A.M., Maleki, A., Saberian, M., and Izanloo, H. 2010. Determination of cadmium and lead contents in black tea and tea liquor from Iran. Asia Journal of Chemistry 22(2): 1387-93.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Feriberg, L., Nordbery, G.F and Wouk, V.B. 1986. Hand book on toxicology of metal.  Amsterdam: Elsevier 2: 130- 184, 158- 210, 298- 354.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Gilman, A.G., Goodman, L.S., and Rall, TW. 1980. Heavy metal and heavy metal antagonist. In the pharmacology basic of theraputics. 7th edition.  Mamilan 2: 1605-1625.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Rios, JL., Recio, M.C., Giner, R.M., and Manez, S. 1996. An update review of saffron and its active constituents. Phytotherapy Research 10: 189- 93.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Karimi, G., Hosseinzadeh, H., and Khaleghpanah P. 2001. Study of antidepressant effect of aqueous and ethanolic extract of Crocus sativus in mice. Irn. J. Basic Medical Science 4: 11-15.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Hosseinzadeh, H., and Younesi, H. 2002. Petal and stigma extracts of Crocus sativus L. have antinociceptive and anti-inflammatory effects in mice. BMC Pharmacology 2-7.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Harak T., Kellner V., Ulk, J., Jurkova, M., and ejka, P. 2007. Determination of Some Beer Flavors by Stir Bar Sorptive Extraction and Solvent Back Extraction, Journal of the Institute of brewing 113 (2): 154-158.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Lord, H., and Pawliszyn, J. 2000. Evolution of Solid Phase Microextraction Thechnology, Journal of Chromatography 855: 153- 193.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Pawliszyn, J., 2003. Sample Preparation Quo Vadis, Analytical Chemistry 75: 2543.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Belord, R.G. and Pawliszyn, J.1989. The Application of Chemically Modified Fused Silica Fibers in the Extraction of Organics from Water Matrix Samples and Their Rapid Transfer to Capillary Columns, Water Pollutant Research Journal Canadian 24: 179- 189.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Arthur, L.C., and Pawliszyn, J. 1990. Solid Phase Microextraction with Thermal Desorption Using Fused Silica Optical Fibers, Analytical Chemistry 69: 2145.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Rezaei, M., Assadi, Y., Milani Hosseini, M.R., Aghaee, E., Ahmadi, F and Berijani, S. 2006. Determination of organic compounds in water using dispersive liquid-liquid microextraction, Journal of Chromatography 1116: 1-9.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Mirzaei, M., Behzadi, M., Mahmoud Abadi, N., and Beizaei, A. 2011. Simultaneous separation/preconcentration of ultra-trace heavy metals in industrial wastewaters by dispersive liquid–liquid microextraction based on solidification of floating organic drop prior to determination by graphite furnace atomic absorption spectrometry, Journal of Hazardous Materials 186: 1739-1743.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Dadfarnia, S., Haji Shabani A.M and E. Kamranzadeh. 2009. Separation/preconcentration and determination of cadmium ions by solidification of floating organic drop microextraction and FI-AAS,Talanta Journal 79: 1061-1065.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Dadfarnia, S., Salmanzadeh, A.M and Hajishabani A. M. 2008. A novel separation/preconcentration system based on solidification of floating organic drop microextraction for determination of lead by graphite furnace atomic absorption spectrometry, Analytica Chimica Acta 623: 163-167.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Metwanki, M.B., Hsu, W., and Huang, S. 2005. Determination of Clentuterol in Urine Using Headspace Solid Phase Microextraction or Liquid- Liquid- Liquid Microextraction, Analytica Chimica Acta 552: 67.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Zhao, H., Xia, S.Q., and Ma, P.S. 2005. Use of ionic liquids as green solvents for extractions. J. Chem. Technol. Biotechnology 80: 1089- 1996. </element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>