<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study of the relations of sink and source in saffron by means of correlation coefficients under different irrigation and fertilization levels</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی روابط منبع و مخزن در زعفران با استفاده از ضرایب همبستگی در سطوح مختلف آبیاری و تغذیه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>195</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>210</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">46083</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2017.51480.1156</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمود</FirstName>
					<LastName>غلامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>کافی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000000209331346</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>خزاعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron is the main medicinal plant of Iran. In order to study the relations of sink and source between saffron leaves and corms, a split plot experiment was conducted on the basis of complete randomized block design with three replications in a field in the Ashkezar city of Yazd province during 2013-2014. The main plots and sub plots were irrigated with three levels (100%, 75% and 50% of ETc) and the fertilization management methods including control (without any fertilizer or manure), applying 10 t/ha cow manure, 10 t/ha vermicompost by spreading, 10 t/ha vermicompost buried under planting corm rows, 5 t/ha vermicompost buried under planting corm rows, or spraying 10 l/ha Humaster Saffron fertilizer for 1 or 2 times after flowering. The Pearson correlation coefficients were calculated between leaf length in every measuring stage and the weight of biggest corm at the end of the first year (as daughter corm). The results showed that correlation coefficients were decreased until 40 days after emergence and then increased. The highest correlation coefficient reached around 80 days after emergence and followed until the end of the growth period. The best corm yield was reached for 10 t/ha vermicompost buried under planting corm rows. Also under different irrigation regimes, the best results were obtained through full irrigation treatment.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به‌منظور بررسی رابطه منبع و مخزن بین برگ و بنه زعفران، آزمایشی به‌صورت اسپلیت پلات در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی در سال‌های 1392و 1393 در یک مزرعه آزمایشی واقع در شهرستان اشکذر یزد به اجرا درآمد. در این آزمایش سطوح آبیاری شامل 100%، 75% و 50% نیاز آبی و تیمار مدیریت کودی شامل شاهد، 10 تن در هکتار کود دامی یا ورمی‌کمپوست به‌صورت توزیع روی سطح خاک، 5 و 10 تن در هکتار ورمی‌کمپوست به‌صورت ردیفی در زیر ردیف‌های کاشت، 10 لیتر در هکتار هیومستر سفرون در یک نوبت و در دو نوبت پس از گلدهی بودند. ضریب همبستگی پیرسون بین داده‌های حاصل از طول برگ با وزن بزرگ‌ترین بنه‌ به‌دست آمده در پایان سال اول محاسبه و منحنی تغییرات این ضرایب برحسب زمان رسم گردید. نتایج نشان داد که تا حدود 40 روز پس از سبز شدن، ضریب همبستگی کاهش و پس از آن افزایش می‌یابد. ضریب همبستگی از حدود 80 روز پس از سبز شدن، به حداکثر مقدار رسید و تا پایان دوره رشد تقریباً ثابت ماند. همچنین بیشترین عملکرد بنه با مصرف 10 تن در هکتار ورمی‌کمپوست به‌صورت ردیفی در زیر ردیف‌های کاشت به‌دست آمد. از بین تیمارهای آبیاری نیز بهترین نتایج در آبیاری کامل (عدم اعمال تنش آبی) حاصل شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اسید هیومیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تخصیص مواد فتوسنتزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طول برگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وزن بنه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ورمی‌کمپوست</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_46083_a1fe2d0ae375f8cc70d1076d6438e366.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
