<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1396</YEAR>
<VOL>5</VOL>
<NO>1</NO>
<MOSALSAL>15</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>105</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اثرات کاشت گیاهان پوششی بر جمعیت علف های هرز، خصوصیات زراعی و عملکرد گل و بنه زعفران(.Crocus sativus L)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Effects of cover crops on weeds density, agronomic characteristics, flower and corm yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>به منظور ارزیابی عملکرد گل و بنه زعفران و نیز جمعیت علف‌های هرز در مزرعه زعفران تحت تأثیر برخی گیاهان پوششی، آزمایشی در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد در سال زراعی 93-1392 در سه تکرار انجام شد. تیمارهای آزمایش شامل شش گونه گیاه پوششی جو، شبدر ایرانی، شنبلیله، خلر، کلزا و منداب و تیمار شاهد بود. نتایج تجزیه واریانس حاکی از اثر مثبت و معنی‌دار گیاهان پوششی بر تمامی شاخص‌های موردمطالعه بود. بیشترین تعداد گل در واحد سطح (23 عدد در متر مربع)، وزن تر گل (88/61 کیلوگرم در هکتار) و وزن خشک کلاله (990/0 کیلوگرم در هکتار) در شرایط کشت گیاه پوششی کلزا مشاهده شد و در ارتباط با وزن خشک کلاله زعفران، تیمار شاهد 41 درصد در مقایسه با کشت انواع گیاهان پوششی برتری داشت. علاوه بر این، حداکثر وزن کل بنه‌های دختری و وزن بنه‌های دختری بدون فلس در هر کلون در شرایط عدم کشت گیاه پوششی و پس از آن در شرایط کشت گیاه کلزا مشاهده شد. کشت گیاهان پوششی نیز به‌طور متوسط 17 درصد در مقایسه با تیمار شاهد در خصوص تعداد بنه‌های دختری در هر کلون برتری نشان داد. با این وجود کمترین مقدار تمامی خصوصیات کمی گل و بنه زعفران در شرایط کشت جو بدست آمد. نتایج بیانگر آن بود که اگرچه در بین تیمارهای گیاه پوششی، حداکثر مقدار تمامی ویژگی‌های مربوط به گل و بنه زعفران به ترتیب متعلق به خانواده شب بو، بقولات و گندمیان بود، اما کمترین تعداد علف‌های هرز به ترتیب به خانواده‌های گندمیان، شب بو، بقولات و در نهایت تیمار شاهد اختصاص یافت. بنابراین، نتایج حاکی از عدم برتری کشت گیاهان پوششی بجز گیاه پوششی کلزا در مقایسه با شاهد در خصوص بهبود شاخص‌های گل و بنه زعفران بود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>This experiment was conducted in order to study the effect of cover crops on weeds population, flower and corm yield of saffron. The experiment was carried out based on Randomized Complete Block Design with three replications at the Research Station, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran, in 2013-14. The treatments included six cover crops: barely (Hordeum vulgare), persian clover (Trifolium resupinatum), fenugreek (Trigonella Foenum – Graecum L.), grass pea (Lathyrus sativus), rapeseed (Brassica napus) and arugula (Eruca sativa) and control. The results of analysis of variance showed that the effect of cover crops was significant on all of the studied properties. The maximum flower number (23.m-2), flower fresh weight (61.88 kg.ha-1) and stigma dry weight (0.990 kg.ha-1) were observed in the planting of rapeseed. The stigma dry weight at the control treatment was 41% more than planting a different kind of cover crops. Furthermore, the highest total weight of replacement corms and replacement corms weight without tunic per clone were obtained at the control and then planting of rapeseed as a cover crop. The number of replacement corms per clone among cover crop treatments was about 17% more than that of control. However, the lowest amount of all parameters of flower and corm of saffron were obtained for arugula, Fabaceae species and barely cover crop treatments. Meanwhile, the minimum amount of weed density was observed for barely, arugula, Fabaceae species cover crops treatments and control. Therefore, the results indicated that control and rapeseed as a cover crop treatments had better effects on the flower and corm parameters of saffron.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>3</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>19</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهسا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اقحوانی شجری</Family>
						<NameE>mahsa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>aghhavani shajari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری اگرواکولوژی،دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی، مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری اگرواکولوژی،دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mahsashajari@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پرویز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رضوانی مقدم</Family>
						<NameE>Parviz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rezvani Moghaddam</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rezvani@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قربانی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghorbani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>reza-ghorbani@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کوچکی</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Koocheki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>akooch@umac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تعداد گل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلاله</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلزا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>وزن کل بنه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Amin Ghafori, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Nassiri Mahallati, M., and Khorramdel, S. 2014. Effect of cover crops on weeds, seed and oil yield of caster bean (Ricinus communis L.). Journal of Plant Production and Research 21 (4): 21-41.(In Persian with English Summary).##Barberi, P., and Mazzoncini, M. 2001. Changes in weed community compositionas influence by cover crop and management system in continuous corn. Weed Science 49: 491-499.##Behdani, M., and Fallahi, H.R. 2015. Saffron: Technical Knowledge-based on Research Approaches. Birjand University Press. 412 pp. (In Persian).##Campiglia, E., Caporali, F., Radicetti, E., and Mancinelli, R. 2010. Hairy vetch (Vicia villosa Roth.) cover crop residue management for improving weed control and yield in no-tillage tomato (Lycopersicon esculentum Mill.) production. European Journal of Agronomy 33: 94-102.##Fallahi, H.R., Paravar, A., Behdani, M.A., Aghhavani-Shajari, M., and Fallahi, M.J. 2014. Effects of saffron corm and leaf extracts on early growth of some plants to investigate the possibility of using them as associated crop. Notulae Scientia Biologica 6 (3): 282-287.##Fisk, J.W., Hesterman, O.B., Shrestha, A., Kells, J.J., Harwood, R.R., Squire,J.M., and Sheaffer, C.C. 2001. Weed suppression by annual legume cover cropsin no-tillage corn. Agronomy Journal 93: 319-325.##Ghorbani, R., Rashed Mohassel, M.H., Makarian, H., and Rastgoo, M. 2008. Effect of sheepgrazing on weed control in Saffron fields. Proceedings of the 2nd International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Technology. Mashhad, Iran, 28-30 October 2008, p. 389-394. (In Persian).##Gibson, K.D., McMillan, J., Hallett, S.G., Jordan, T., and Weller, S.C. 2011. Effect of living mulch on weed seed banks in tomato. Weed Technology 25 (2): 245-251.##Herrero, E.V., Mitchell, J.P., Lanimi, W.T., Temple, S.R., Miyao, E.M., Morse, R.D., and Campiglia, E. 2001. Use of cover crop mulches in a no-till furrow-irrigated processing tomato production. Journal of Horticultural Science and Technology 11: 43-48.##Isik, D., Kaya, E., Ngouajio, M., and Mennan, H. 2009. Weed suppression in organic pepper (Capsicum annum L.) with winter cover crops. Crop Protection 28: 356-363.##Jahan, M., Amiri, M. B., Dehghanipour, F., and Tahami, M.K. 2013. The effects of biofertilizers and winter cover crops on essential oil production and some agroecological characteristics of Basil (Ocimum basilicum L.) in an organic farming system. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 10 (4): 751-763. (In Persian).##Jihad Keshavarzi Khorasan Razavi. 2013. Iran Agriculture Statistics (Vol. 2). Ministry of Jihad-Keshavrzi, Iran. 421 pp.##Kafi, M. 2002. Saffron, Production and Processing. Zaban va Adab Publications. 276 pp. (In Persian).##Khoze Mary, A. 2000. Saffron in mixed cropping system. Journal of Saffron 8: 18-244.##Koocheki, A., Najibnia, S., and Lalehgani, B. 2009. Evaluation of saffron yield (Crocus sativus L.) in intercropping with cereals, pulses and medicinal plants. Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 7 (1): 163-172. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Fallahi, H.R. 2011. Final Report the Effects of Planting Date, Irrigation Management and Cover Crops on the Yield of Saffron and Diversity of Weed Species. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad.##Koocheki, A.R., Rezvani-Moghaddam, P., and Fallahi, H.R. 2015. Effects of planting dates, irrigation management and cover crops on growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Agroecology. (In Press). (In Persian with English Summary).##Kramberger, B., Gselman, A., Janzekovic, M., Kaligaric,M., and Bracko, B. 2009. Effects of cover crops on soil mineral nitrogen and on the yield and nitrogen content of maize. European Journal of Agronomy 31: 103-109.##Kuo, S., and Jellum, E.J. 2002. Influence of winter cover crop and residue management on soil nitrogen availability and corn. Agronomy Journal 94: 501-508.##Lal, R., Regnier, E., Eckert, D.J., Edwards, W.M., and Hammond, R. 1991. Expectation of cover crops for sustainable agriculture. Journal of Soil Water Conservation 23: 1-11.##Mahmood, A., 2001. Mix cropping system. Available at Web site: http://www.agri systems.org.##Naderi Darbaghshahi, M.R., Banitab, A.R., and Bahari, B. 2012. Evaluating the possibility of saffron and chamomile mixed culture. African Journal of Agricultural Research 7 (20): 3060-3065. (In Persian with English Summary).##Ngouajio, M., and Mennan, H. 2005. Weed populations and pickling cucumber (Cucumis sativus) yield under summer and winter cover crop systems. Crop Protection 24: 521-526.##Pullaro, T.C., Marino, P.C., Jackson, D.M., Harrinson, H.F., and Keinath, A.P. 2006. Effect of killed cover crop on weeds, weed seeds, and herbivores. Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment 115: 97-104.##Rahmati, A., 2003. Role of environmental factors on production, yield and quality of saffron. 3rd International Congress in Saffron. Mashhad. (In Persian)##Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Koocheki, A., Molafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, M. 2013. The effects of different levels of applied wheat straw in different dates on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) daughter corms and flower initiation criteria in the second year. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 1 (1): 55-70. (In Persian with English Summary).##Sabahi, H., Minoyi, S., and Liyaghati, H. 2006. A comparison between summer cover crop and inorganic nitrogen on garlic yield and the condition of weeds. Environmental Sciences 13: 23-32. (In Persian with English Summary).##Sainju, U.M., Singh, B.P., Whitehead, W.F., and Wang, S. 2006. Carbon supply and storage in tilled and non-tilled soils as influenced by cover crops and nitrogen fertilization. Journal of Environmental Quality 35: 1507-1517.##Shabahang, J., Khorramdel, S., Amin Ghafori, A., and Gheshm, R. 2013. Effects on management of crop residues and cover crop planting on density and population of weeds and agronomical characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Saffron Research 1 (1): 57-72. (In Persian with English Summary).##Soufizadeh, S., Zand, E., Baghestani, M.A., Kashani, F.B., and Nezamabadi, N. 2008. Integrated Weed Management in Saffron (Crocus sativus). Proceeding of the 2nd International Symposium Saffron Biology and Technology. 5-8 July 2008.##Tian, Y., Liu, J., Wang X., and Gao, L. 2010. Carbon mineralization in the soils under different cover crops and residue management in an intensive protected vegetable cultivation. Scientia Horticulturae. (In Press).##Totterdell, S., and Roberts, E.H. 1980. Characteristics of alternating temperatures which stimulate loss of dormancy in seeds of Rumex obtusifolius L. and R. crispus L. Plant Cell Environment 3: 3-12.##Valenzuela, H., and J. Smith. 2002. Sorghum-sudangrass Hybrids. Publication Number SA-GM-10, Sustainable Agriculture, Green Manure Crops. Cooperative Extension Service, College of Tropical Agriculture and Human Resources, University of Hawaii at Manoa. Honolulu, HI.##Wagger, M.G. 1989. Cover crops management and nitrogen rate in relation to growth and yield of no-till corn. Agronomy Journal 81: 533-538.##Zare Hosseini, H., Ghorbani, R., Rashed Mohassel, M.H., and Rahimi, H. 2014. Effects of weed management strategies on weed density and biomass and saffron (Crocus sativus) yield. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (1): 45-58. (In Persian with English Summary).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر پیش‌تیمار بنة مادری با سطوح مختلف اسید سالیسیلیک و نیترات پتاسیم بر عملکرد گل، بنه و شاخص‌های فلورسانس کلروفیل زعفران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Influence of saffron corm soaking in salicylic acid and potassium nitrate on vegetative and reproductive growth and its chlorophyll fluorescence indices</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران یکی از با ارزش­ترین گیاهان دارویی ایران است که در حوزة پراکنش خود تحت تأثیر برخی از تنش­های محیطی می­باشد. بنابراین، مصرف ترکیبات هورمونی و غذایی می­تواند ضمن کاهش آثار سوء تنش، موجبات افزایش رشد و عملکرد گیاه را فراهم سازد. به همین منظور آزمایشی در قالب طرح بلوک­های کامل تصادفی با چهار تکرار با هدف بررسی اثر غوطه­وریِ بنه­های مادری زعفران در سطوح مختلف اسید سالیسیلیک (5/0، 1 و 2 میلی مولار) و نیترات پتاسیم (250، 500، 1000 میلی­گرم بر لیتر) به همراه تیمار شاهد (آب مقطر به عنوان سطح صفر برای هر یک از ترکیبات مورد استفاده) روی برخی صفات مرتبط با رشد رویشی و زایشیِ زعفران در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی بیرجند در سال زراعی 1394 اجرا شد. صفات مورد بررسی شامل وزن­تر گل، وزن­تر گلبرگ، وزن­تر کلاله، طول کلاله، طول برگ، وزن و قطر بنة مادری و دختری، میزان کلروفیل کل و فلورسانس کلروفیل (با هدف بررسی تأثیر تیمارهای آزمایشی بر خسارت احتمالیِ ناشی از تنش گرمای تابستانه) بودند. نتایج نشان داد که بیشترین میزان Fv، Fv/Fm،F&#039;v/F&#039;m (به­ترتیب 117، 27/0 و 44/0)، کلروفیل کل (85/0 میکروگرم بر گرم وزن­تر)، وزن­ترگل، وزن­ترگلبرگ، وزن­ترکلاله (به ترتیب 9/36، 1/32 و 2/4 گرم در متر مربع)، طول کلاله و طول برگ (به­ترتیب 6/29 میلی­متر و 7/37 سانتی­متر) در تیمار غوطه­وریِ بنه در محلول 2 میلی­مولار اسید سالیسیلیک و بیشترین میزان F&#039;m به مقدار 434 در سطح 5/0 میلی­مولار اسید سالیسیلیک به دست آمد. تیمار مصرف 1000 میلی­گرم بر لیتر نیترات پتاسیم نیز به ترتیب موجب افزایش 19 و 30 درصدیِ مقادیر قطر و وزن بنه دختری گردید. در مجموع، نتایج این آزمایش نشان داد که غوطه­وری بنه­های مادری زعفران در محلول‌های اسید سالیسیلیک و نیترات پتاسیم موجب بهبود رشد و عملکرد زعفران می­شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron that is an important medicinal plant of Iran is influenced by several environmental stresses. Therefore, the consumption of appropriate hormonal and nutritional compounds can reduce the negative impacts of stresses on it and improve the growth and yield of the plant. For this purposes, an experiment was carried out based on a Randomized Complete Block Design with four replications to study the effect of Salicylic acid (0, 0.5, 1 and 2 mM) and Potassium Nitrate (0, 250,500 and 1000 ml.g-1), in the research field station of the College of Agriculture, the University of Birjand, Iran, in the growing season of 2015. The indices evaluated included flower and corolla fresh weight, stigma weight and length, leaf length, corm and cormel weights and diameter, chlorophyll florescence parameters and total chlorophyll content. The results showed that the highest amounts of Fv, Fv/Fm, F&#039;v/F&#039;m (117, 0.27 and 0.44, respectively), total chlorophyll (0.85 µg.g fresh weight), flower and corolla fresh weight (36.9 and 32.1 g.m-2, respectively), stigma weight (4.2 g.m-2) and length (29.6 mm) and leaf length (37.7 cm) were obtained at 2 mM level of salicylic acid, while the highest F&#039;m was recorded at 0.5 mM salicylic acid. In addition, pretreatment with 1000 mg.l-1 potassium nitrate increased the amounts of cormel weight and diameter by 30% and 19% compared with the control, respectively. Generally, the results of this experiment indicated an enhancement in saffron growth and yield, affected by corms soaking in salicylic acid and potassium nitrate.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>21</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>35</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مانی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جباری</Family>
						<NameE>Mani</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jabbari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد علوم باغبانی، گرایش فیزیولوژی گیاهان دارویی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد علوم باغبانی، گرایش</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mani.jabbari.mp@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خیاط</Family>
						<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khayyat</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه علوم باغبانی، پژوهشکدة گیاهان ویژه منطقه، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه علوم باغبانی، پژوهشکدة گیاهان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mhdkhayat@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمید رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فلاحی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamid-reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Fallahi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، پژوهشکدة گیاهان ویژه منطقه، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، پژوهشکدة</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hamidreza.fallahi@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صمدزاده</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>samadzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مربی گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مربی گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>arsamadzadeh@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>: بنه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پتانسیل عملکرد کوانتومی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد گل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فلورسانس متغیر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلاله</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلروفیل کل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Agarawal, S., Sairam, R.K., Srivasta, G.C., and Meena, R.C. 2005. Changes in antioxidant enzymes activity and oxidative stress by abscise acid and salicylic acid in wheat genotypes. Biologia Plantarum 49 (4): 541-550.##Amir, B.K. 2006. Response of Sword Lily, Gladiolus to increase dose of nitrogen and phosphorus. M.Sc Thesis. Sindh Agriculture. University Tando Jam.##Arnon, D.I. 1949. Copper enzymes in isolated chloroplasts. polyphenoloxidase in Beta Vulgaris. Plant Physiology 24: 1-15.##Azizbekova, N.Sh., Milyaeva, E.L., Lobova, N.V., and Chailakhyan, M.Kh., 1976. Effects of gibberellins and kinetin on formation of flower organs in saffron crocus. Plant physiology 25: 471-476.##Azizbekova, N.Sh., Milyaeva, E.L., and Chailakhyan, M.Kh. 1983. Effect of gibberellins on functional activity of dormant saffron buds. Soviet Plant physiology 29: 895-900.##Baker, N.R., and Rosenqvist, E. 2004. Applications of chlorophyll fluorescence can improve crop production strategies: an examination of future possibilities. Journal of Experimental Botany 55: 1607-1621.##Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Jami Al-Ahmadi, M. 2008. Agroecological zoning and potential yield of saffron in Khorasan-Iran. Journal of Biological Sciences 8 (2): 298-305.##Behdani, M.A., and Fallahi, H.R. 2015. Saffron: Technical Knowledge Based on Research Approaches. University of Birjand Publication. (In Persian).##Behnia, M.R., Estilai, A., and Ehdaie, B. 1999. Application of fertilizers for increased saffron yield. Journal of Agronomy and Crop Science 182: 9-15.##Chrungoo, N.K., and Farooq, S. 1984. Influence of gibberellic acid and naphthalene acetic acid on the yield of saffron and on growth in saffron crocus (C. sativus L.). Indian Journal of Plant physiology 28: 201-205.##El-Bassiony, A.M. 2006. Effect of potassium fertilization on growth and physiology of Gladiolus bulb. Journal of Applied Science and Research 2 (10): 780-785.##El-Tayeb, M.A. 2005. Response of barley grain to the interactive effect of salinity and salicylic acid. Plant Growth Regulation 42: 215-224.##Eraslan, F., Inal, A., Pilbeam, D.J., and Gunes, A. 2008. Interactive effects of salicylic acid and silicon on oxidative damage and antioxidant activity in spinach (Spinacia oleracea L. CV. Matador) grown under boron toxicity and salinity. Plant Growth Regulation 55: 207-219.##Gao, D., Cai, K., Chen, J., Luo, S., Zeng, R., Yang, J., and Zhu, X. 2011. Silicon enhances photochemical efficiency and adjusts mineral nutrient absorption in Magnaporthe oryzae infected rice plants. Acta Physiologiae Plantarum 33: 675-682.##Ghai, N., Setia, R.C., and Setia, N. 2002. Effect of paclobutrazol and salicylic acid on chlorophyll content, hill activity and yield components in Brassica napus L. (cv. GSL-1). Phytomorphology 52: 83-87.##Ghoname, A., Fawzy, Z.F., El-Bassiony, A.M., Riadand, G.S., and Abd El-Baky, M.M.H.. 2007. Reducing onion bulbs flaking and increasing bulb yield and quality by potassium and calcium application. Australian Journal of Basic and Applied Sciences 13 (2): 123-133.##Gutierrez-Corronado, M.A., Trejo-Lopez, C., and Larque-Saavedra, A. 1998. Effects of salicylic acid on the growth of roots and shoots in soybean. Plant Physiology and Biochemistry 38 (4): 563-565.##Horvath, E., Janda, T., Szalai, G., and Paldi, E. 2002. In vitro salicylic acid inhibition of catalase activity in maize: differences between the isozymes and a possible role in the induction of chilling tolerance. Plant Science 163 (6): 1129-1135.##Juan, J.A.D., Córcoles, H.L., M-Munoz, R., and Picornell, M. 2009. Yield and yield components of saffron under different cropping systems. Industrial Crops Production 30: 212–219.##Khan, W., Prithiviraj, B., and Smith, D. 2003. Photosynthetic responses of corn and soybean to foliar application of salicylates. Plant Physiology 160: 485-92.##Khodary, S.E.A. 2004. Effect of salicylic acid on the growth, photosynthesis and carbohydrate metabolism in salt stressed Maize plant. International Journal of Agriculture and Biology 6: 5-8.##Koocheki, A.R., and  Jahan, M. 2009. Effect of bio fertilizer and inorganic fertilizer on generative growth and yield of saffron under high corn density. 3rd International Symposium on Saffron Forthcoming Challenges in cultivation Research and Economics. 20-24 May. Krokos, Kozani, Greece.##Krishna, S., Surinder, K., Thind, S.K., and Gurpreet, K. 2004. Interactive effects of phenolics and light intensity on vegetative parameters and yield in soybean (Glycine max L. Merrill). Environment and Ecology 22: 390-394.##Leslie, C.A., and Romani, R.J., 1988. Inhibition of ethylene biosynthesis by salicylic acid. Plant Physiology 88: 833-837.##Lichtenthaler, H.K. 1992. The Kaustky effect: 60years of chlorophyll fluorescence induction kinetics.  Photosynthetica 27: 45-55.##Lu, C., Qiu, N., Lu, Q., Wang, B., and Kuango, T. 2002. Does salt stress lead to increased susceptibility of photosystem II to photoinhibition and changes in photosynthetic pigment composition in halophyte Sueda salsa grown outdoors? Plant Science 163: 1063-1068.##Majd, A., Maddah, S.M., Fallahian, F., Sabaghpour, S.H., and Chalabian, F. 2006. Comparative study of the effect of salicylic acid on yield, yield components and resistance of two susceptible and resistant chickpea cultivars to Ascochyta rabiei. Iranian Journal of Biology 19 (3): 314-324. (In Persian with English Summary).##Mansouri, M., Shoor, M., Tehranifar, A., and Selahvarzi, Y. 2015. Effect of foliar application of salicylic acid and thiamine on quantitative and qualitative characteristics of gerbera (Gerbera jamesonii L. cv. Pink Elegance). Journal of Science and Technology of Greenhouse Culture 6 (23): 15-24. (In Persian with English Summary).##Marschner, P. 2012. Mineral Nutrition of Higher Plants, 3rd ed.; Academic Press: London, UK. pp; 178–189.##Memon, S.A., Baloch, A.R., Baloch, M.A., and Keerio, M.I. 2013 Pre-soaking treatment and foliar application of KNO3 on growth and flower production of gladiolus (Gladiolus hortulanus). Journal of Agricultural Technology 9 (5): 1347-1366.##Moein, P., and Mortazaeinezhad, F. 2014. The survey of gibberellic acid, kinetin, salicylic acid, treatments on the reproductive traits of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.). The 1st International Conference on New Idea in Agriculher. Islamic Azad University Khorasgan Brangh. 26-27 Jan. 2014. Isfahan, Iran. (In Persian).##NadeAli, E., PakNejad, F., Moradi, F., Nasri, M., and Pazuki, A. 2010. Effects of methanol application on sugar beet (Beta vulgaris) relative water content, chlorophyll content and chlorophyll fluorescence parameters under drought stress conditions. Iranian Journal of Field Crop Science 41 (4): 731-740. (In Persian with English Summary).##Negbi, M. 1999. Saffron Cultivation: Past, Present and Future Prospects. Harwood Academic Publishers, Amsterdam .pp. 1-19.##Nelson, B.M.N., and Maria, A.B.D. 2006. Physiological and biochemical response of common bean varieties treated with salicylic acid under water stress. Crop Breeding and Applied Biotechnology 6: 269-277.##Padmalatha, T. G., Satyanarayana Reddy, R., Chandrasekhar, A., Shankar, S., and Chaturvedi, A. 2013. Effect of pre-planting soaking of corms with chemical and plant growth regulators on dormancy breaking and corm and cormel production in Gladiolus. International Journal of Plant, Animal and Environmental Sciences 3 (1): 28-33.##Paknejad, F., Nasri, M., Tohidi Moghadam, H.R., Zahedi, H., and Jami Alahmad, M., 2007. Effects of drought stress on chlorophyll fluorescence parameters chlorophyll content and grain yield of wheat cultivars. Journal of Biological Sciences 7 (6): 841-847 .##Pancheva, T.V., Popova, L.P., and Uzunova, A.N. 1996. Effects of salicylic acid on growth and photosynthesis in barley plants. Journal of Plant Physiology 149: 57-63.##Popova, L., Pancheva, T., and Uzonova, A. 1997. Salicylic acid: properties, biosynthesis and physiological role. Plant Physiology 23: 85-93.##Popova, L., Ananieva, V., Hristova, V., Christov, K., Geovgieva, K., Alexieva, V., and Stoinova, Z. 2003. Salicylic acid and methyl jasmonate induced protection on photosynthesis to paraquat oxidative stress. Bulgarian Journal of Plant Physiology (Special issue) 133- 152.##Popova, L.P., Maslenkova, L.T., Yordanova, R.Y., Ivanova, A.P., Krantev, A.P., Szalai, G., and Janda, T. 2009. Exogenous treatment with salicylic acid attenuates cadmium toxicity in pea seedlings. Plant Physiology and Biochemistry 47: 224-231.##Rai, V.K., Sharma, S.S., and Sharma, S. 1986. Reversal of ABA–induced stomatal closure by phenolic compounds. Journal of Experimental Botany 37: 129–34.##Ramazan. A., Hafiz, I.A., Ahmad, T., and Abbasi, N.A. 2010. Effect of priming with potassium nitrate and dehusking on seed germination of gladiolus (Gladiolus Alatus) Pakistan Journal of Botany 42 (1): 247-258.##Raskin, I. 1992. Role of salicylic acid in plants. Annual Review of Plant Physiology and Plant Molecular Biology 43: 439-463.##Rezvani-Moghaddam, P., Huda, A.K.S., Parvez, Q., and Koocheki, A. 2007. Indigenous knowledge in agriculture with particular reference to medicinal crop production in Khorasan, Iran. World Association for Sustainable Development Conference Proceedings 2007. Brisbane, Australia, pp. 105-115.##Roychowdhury, N., and Roychowdhury, P. 2006. The effect of field application of k on post-harvest behaviour of gladiolus. International Journal of Horticulture 3 (1): 33-35.##Shabala, S.I. 2002. Screening plants for environmental fitness: chlorophyll fluorescence as a ‘‘Holy Grail’’ for plant breeders. In: Hemantaranjan, A., (Ed.), Advances in Plant Physiology. Vol. 5. Scientific Publishers, Jodhpur, India, pp. 287–340.##Sarkar, R.K., and Malik, G.C. 2001. Effect of foliar spray of potassium nitrate and calcium nitrate on grasspea (Lathyrus sativus L.) grown in rice fallows. Lathyrus Lathyrism Newsletter 2: 47-48.##Sathiyamoorthy, P., and Vivekanandan, M. 2008. Cumulative effects of pre-sowing seed treatment and foliar application of salts in improving biomass and grain yield of soybean in moderate saline/alkaline soil. Journal of Agronomy and Crop Science 161 (2): 107-113.##Shakirova, F.M., Sakhabutdinova, A.R., Bozrutkova, M.V., Fatkhutdinova, R.A. and Fatkhutdinova, D.R. 2003. Changes in the hormonal status of wheat seedlings induced by salicylic acid and salinity. Plant Science 164: 317-322.##Shi, Q., Bao, Z., Zhu, Z., Ying, Q., and Qian, Q. 2006. Effects of different treatments of salicylic acid on heat tolerance, chlorophyll fluorescence and antioxidant enzyme activity in seedlings of Cucumis sativa. Plant Growth Regulation 48: 127-135.##Shi, G.R., Cai, Q.S., Liu, Q.Q., and Wu, L. 2009. Salicylic acid-mediated alleviation of cadmium toxicity in hemp plants in relation to cadmium uptake, photosynthesis, and antioxidant enzymes. Acta Physiologia Plantarum 31:  969-977.##Singh, K.P., Ramachandran, N., and Uma, S.1997. Growth, flowering, corm yield and corm-rot incidence as affected by level and frequency of potassium application in gladiolus (Gladiolus grandiflorus). Indian Journal of Agricultural Science 67 (9): 404-406.##Singh, B., and Usha, K. 2003. Salicilic acid induced physiological and biochemical changes in wheat seedling under water stress. Plant Growth Regulation 39: 137-141.##Tammam, A.A. 2003. Response of Vicia faba plants to the interactive effect of sodium chloride salinity and salicylic acid treatment. Acta Agronomica Hungarica 51 (3): 239-248.##Tari, I., Csiszar, J., Szalai, G., Horvath, F., Pecsvaradi, A., Kiss, G., Szepsi, A., Szabo, M., and Erdei, L. 2002. Acclimation of tomato plants to salinity stress after a salicylic acid pre-treatment. Acta Biologica Szegediensis 46 (3): 55-56.##Zhou, X., Mackeuzie, A., Madramootoo, C., and Smith, D. 1999. Effect of some injected plant growth regulators with or without sucrose on grain production, biomass and photosynthetic activity of field grown corn plants. Journal of Agronomy and Crop Science 183: 103-110.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تاثیر کودهای آلی و میکروارگانیسم‌های موثر((EM بر ویژگی‌های بنه‌های دختری زعفران (.Crocus sativus L)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Effect of Organic Fertilizers and Effective Microorganisms (EM) 
on Replacement Corm Criteria of Saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>به منظور بررسی تأثیر کود شیمایی و کودهای آلی به‌همراه مصرف میکروارگانیسم‌های مؤثر (EM) بر خصوصیات بنه‌ی زعفران، آزمایشی در سال زراعی 93-1392 در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار و 16 تیمار در شهر ریوش اجرا گردید. فاکتورهای آزمایشی شامل 1-کود شیمایی (حاوی 12 درصد ازت از منبع اوره و نیترات، 8 درصد فسفر، 4 درصد پتاسیم و کلات‌های آهن، روی، منگنز و مس) 2- کود دامی 40 تن در هکتار 3- کود دامی 40 تن در هکتار+ EM 4- کود دامی 80 تن در هکتار 5- کود دامی 80 تن در هکتار+EM 6- ورمی‌کمپوست 10 تن در هکتار 7- ورمی‌کمپوست 10 تن در هکتار+EM  8- ورمی‌کمپوست 15 تن در هکتار 9- ورمی‌کمپوست 15 تن در هکتار+EM  10- ورمی‌کمپوست 20 تن در هکتار 11- ورمی‌کمپوست 20 تن در هکتار+EM  12- ورمی‌واش 13- ورمی‌واش+‌EM 14- کود دامی 40 تن در هکتار+ورمی‌واش 15- کود دامی 40 تن در هکتار+ ورمی‌واش+EM  و 16- شاهد (عدم مصرف کود) بود.نتایج تجزیه واریانس حاکی از اثرات معنی‌دار تیمارهای کودی بر صفات مورد بررسی زعفران به استثنای تعداد کل بنه‌های دختری بود.بر اساس نتایج آزمایش، بیش‌ترین افزایش در عملکرد کل بنه‌های دختری (715 گرم در مترمربع)، تعداد بنه‌های دختری بیش‌تر از 8 گرم (57 بنه در مترمربع)، در نتیجه‌ی کاربرد کود شیمیایی حاصل شد که این تأثیر با اثر کود دامی 40 تن در هکتار+ورمی‌واش+EM برابری کرد. بر اساس نتایج مقایسات گروهی کاربرد EM همراه با ورمی‌کمپوست و کود دامی نسبت به مصرف ورمی‌کمپوست و کود دامی به تنهایی به‌طور معنی‌داری باعث کاهش صفات مورد بررسی زعفران شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>An experiment was conducted based on randomized complete block design with three replications at a field located in the Rivash town in the Khorasan Razavi province during the growing season 2013-2014 in order to compare and evaluate the effects of chemical fertilizer (Containing 12% N from Urea and nitrate sources, 8% P, 4%K and also Zn, Cu, Mg, Fe, Chelates), vermiwash and different levels of manure and vermicompost fertilizer with the use of biological EM (effective microorganisms) on the characteristics of corm in Saffron. Treatments included: 1.fertilizer chemical (containing 12% nitrogen from urea and nitrate, %8-P, 4% potassium and chelates together iron, zinc, manganese and copper) 2.Manure 40 t.ha-1, 3.manure 40 t.ha-1 + EM, 4.manure 80 t.ha-1, 5.manure 80 t.ha-1 + EM, 6.vermicompost 10 t.ha-1, 7.vermicompost 10 t.ha-1 + EM, 8.vermicompost 15 t.ha-1, 9.vermicompost 15 t.ha-1 + EM 10.vermicompost 20 t.ha-1 , 11.vermicompost 20 t.ha-1  + EM, 12.vermiwash, 13.vermiwash+ EM, 14.Manure 40 t.ha-1+ vermiwash, 15.Manure 40 t.ha-1 + vermiwash + EM, 16.Control (no fertilizer application). The results of analysis of variance showed a significant effect of treatments on all of the characteristics with the exception of the total number of saffron corms. The results indicated that the highest increase in total yield of corm (715 g.m-2), corm number more than 8 grams (57 corms.m-2), was obtained as a result of the use of chemical fertilizers and was equal to  the combined application of Manure 40 t.ha-1+ vermiwash + EM. The orthogonal comparisons showed that the use of EM with vermicompost and manure versus using vermicompost and manure alone significantly reduced the traits of saffron.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>37</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>49</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعیده</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مداحی</Family>
						<NameE>Saeideh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Madahi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، زراعت، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، زراعت، دانشگاه فردوسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>madahi.eng@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پارسا</Family>
						<NameE>mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Parsa</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>parsa@ferdowsi.um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مرتضی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گلدانی</Family>
						<NameE>Morteza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Goldani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>goldani@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کافی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kafi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.kafi@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کود بیولوژیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلاله‌ی زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ورمی‌کمپوست</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ورمی‌واش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ansari A.A. 2008. Effect of vermicompost and Vermiwash on the productivity of spinach (Spinacia oleracea), onion (Allium cepa) and potato (Solanum tuberosum). World Journal of Agricultural Sciences 4 (5): 554-557.##Ansari, A.A., Pereira, M., and Jaikishun, S. 2015. Effect of vermiwash obtained from different sources (neem, rice straw and bagasse) and standardized hydroponics solution on the growth of Colocasia esculenta (Australian Poi) in Guyana. American journal of experimental agriculture 7 (5): 275-283.##Arancon, N.Q., Edwards, C.A., Bierman, P., Metzger, J.D., and Lucht C. 2005. Effects of vermicomposts produced from cattle manure, food waste and paper waste on the growth and yield of peppers in the ﬁeld. Pedobiologia49: 297-306.##Bachman, G.R., and Metzger, J.D. 2008. Growth of bedding plants in commercial potting substrate amended with vermicompost. Bioresource Technology 99: 3155-3161.##Bajwa, R., Javaid, A., and Rabbani, N. 1999. EM and VAM technology in Pakistan. VII: Effect of organic amendments and effective microorganisms (EM) on VA mycorrhiza, nodulation and crop growth in Trifolium alexandrianum L. Pakistan Journal of Biological Sciences 2: 590-593.##Coleman, D.C., and Crossley, D.A.1995. Fundamentals of soil ecology. Academic Press, San Diego and London. Eghball, B. 2002. Soil properties as influence by phosphorus and nitrogen-based manure and compost application. Agronomy journal 94: 128-135.##Daiss, N., Lobo, M.G., Socorro, A.R., Brückner, U., Heller, J., and Gonzalez, M. 2008. The effect of three organic pre-harvest treatments on Swiss chard (Beta vulgaris L. var. cycla L.) quality. European Food Research and Technology 226: 345-353.##Daly, M.J., and Stewart, D.P.C. 1999. Influence of effective microorganisms (EM) on vegetative production and carbon mineralization- a preliminary investigation. Journal of Sustainable Agriculture 14: 15-25.##Gutierrez-Miceli, F.A., Oliva Llaven, M.A., Nazar, P.M., Sesma, B.R., Alvarez-Solis, J.D, and Dendooven, L. 2011. Optimization of  vermicompost and worm-bed leachate for the organic cultivation of radish. Journal of plant  nutrition 34: 1642-1653.##Higa, T. 2000. What is EM technology?. EM World Journal1: 1-6.##Higa,T., and Wididana, A.N. 1991. Changes in the soil micro flora induced by effective microorganisms. p, 153-162. In: Parr, J.F., Hornick, S.B., and Whitman, C.E. (ed.), Proceedings of the First International Conference on Kyusei Nature Farming. U.S. Department of Agriculture, Washington. D.C., USA.##Hussain, T., Anjum, A.D., and Tahir, J. 2002. Technology of beneﬁcial microorganisms. Nature Farming and Environment 3: 1-14.##Javaid, A., and Shah, M.B.M. 2010. Growth and yield response of wheat to EM (effective microorganisms) and parthenium green manure. African journal of biotechnology 9 (23): 3373-3381.##Khaliq, A., Abbasi, M.K., and Hussain, T. 2006. Effect of integrated use of organic and inorganic nutrient sources with effective microorganisms (EM) on seed cotton yield in Pakistan. Bioresource Technology 97: 967-972.##Koocheki, A., Jamshid Eyni, M., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2014a. The effects of mother corm size, manure and chemical fertilizers on replacement corm criteria and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Saffron Research 2 (1): 34-46. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Seyyedi, S.M., Azizi, H., and Shahriyari, R. 2014b. The effects of mother corm size, organic fertilizers and micronutrient foliar application on corm yield and phosphorus uptake of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (1): 3-16. (In Persian with English summary).##Krishnamoorthy, R.V., and Vajranabhiah, S.N. 1986. Biological activity of earthworm Casts an assessment of plant growth promoter levels in casts. Proceedings of Indian academy of Sciences (animal Science) 95: 341-351.##Kumar, R., Singh, V., Devi, K., Sharma, M., Singh, M.K., and Ahuja, P.S. 2009. State of art of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) agronomy: A comprehensive review. Food Reviews International 25: 44-85.##Melnyk, J.P., Wang, S., and Marcone, M.F. 2010. Chemical and biological properties of the world’s most expensive spice: Saffron. Food Research International 43: 1981-1989.##Mohammad poor, J., Ghodsi, M.R., Esmi, R., Shariatmadadi, Z., Adib, M.R., and Jahedi poor, S. 2013. Evaluate the effects of irrigation and fertilization on morphological traits and yield of saffron crops. Second National Conference on the latest scientific achievements of saffron. 8 December 2013. Torbat Heydarieh, Iran. (In Persian).##Ortega, R., and Fern´andez, M. 2007. Agronomic evaluation of liquid humus derived from earthworm humic substances. Journal of Plant Nutrition 30: 2091-2104.##Rashed Mohassel, M.H., Azizi, G., and Sabet Teimouri, M. 2006. Investigation on saffron reaction to mineral and organic fertilizers. Book of Abstracts. 2nd International Symposium on saffron biology and technology, 28-30 October 2006. Mashhad, Iran. (In Persian).##Rezaian, S., and Paseban, M. 2006. The effect of micronutrients and manure fertilizers on the quantity and quality of Khorasan saffron. In Proceedings 2nd International ymposium on Saffron Biology and Technology. 28-30 October 2006. Mashhad, Iran. (In Persian).##Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Koocheki, A. Molafilabi, A. and Seyyedi, M. 2013a. Effect of biological and chemical fertilizers on replacement corm and flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Iranian Journal of Crop Sciences 15 (3): 234-246. (In Persian with English Summary).##Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Khorramdel, S., Amin Ghafori, A., and Shabahang, J. 2013. Evaluation of growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) affected by spent mushroom compost and corm density. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (1): 13-26. (In Persian with English Summary).##Suthr, S. 2010. Evidence of plant hormone like substances in vermiwash: An ecologically safe option of synthetic chemicals for sustainable farming. Ecological Engineering 36: 1089-1092.##Teimori, M., Kafi, M., Orseji, Z., and Oreji, K. 2010. Effect of drought stress, the size and coverage of corms on morphoec physiological characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in greenhouse . Journal of Agroecology 2 (2): 323-334. (In Persian). ##Teimori, S., Behdani, M.A., Ghaderi, M.G., and Sadeghi B. 2013. Investigation on the effect of organic and chemical fertilizers on morphological and agronomic of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm criteria. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (1): 36-47. (In Persian with English summary).##Xu, H., Wang, R., and Mridha, M.A.U. 2000. Effects of organic fertilizers and a microbial inoculant on leaf photosynthesis and fruit yield and quality of tomato plants. Journal of  Crop Production 3 (1): 173-182.##Yan,  P.S., and Xu, H.L. 2002. Inﬂuence of EM Bokashi on nodulation, physiological characters and yield of peanut in nature farming ﬁelds. Journal of Sustainable Agriculture 19: 105-112.##Yasmin, S., and Nehvi, F.A. 2013. Saffron as a valuable spice: A comprehensive review. African Journal of Agricultural Research 8 (3): 234-242.##Zanzucchi, C. 1987. Research carried out by the consorzio comunalie paramensi on saffron (Crocus sativus L.). pp. 347-395.##Zarea Feizabadi, A., Jamali, S.M., Taheri, Gh., and Khazaei, H., 2012. Effect of manure and biological substrate on quantitative charactristics of bread wheat (Tritticum aestivum). Journal of Agroecology 2 (1): 63-74. (In Persian with English summary).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی و مقایسه خواص آنتی اکسیدانی، فنل های کل و فلاونوئیدهای گلبرگ زعفران (.Crocus sativus L) کاشته شده در مناطق مختلف استان لرستان</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Survey and comparison of the antioxidant activity, total phenolic, and flavonoid compounds of saffron petals sowing in different regions of the Lorestan province</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران یکی از ارزشمندترین محصولات غذایی و دارویی است که از نظر کشاورزی و اقتصادی در ایران و جهان از اهمیت بالایی برخوردار می‌باشد. امروزه عوامل مخرب محیطی باعث می‌شوند که بدن انسان نتواند با رادیکال‌های آزاد که طی عمل تنفس تولید می‌شوند مبارزه کند. در نتیجه سلول‌های بدن توسط رادیکال‌های آزاد تخریب شده و منجر به پیری زودرس و بیماری‌هایی مانند سرطان و تصلب شرائین می‌شوند. با توجه به محدود بودن کشت زعفران به چند کشور دنیا در زمینه تعیین خواص آنتی‌اکسیدانی گلبرگ زعفران تحقیقات زیادی صورت نگرفته است. این پژوهش جهت بررسی خاصیت آنتی‌اکسیدانی ترکیبات موجود در گلبرگ‌های زعفران و تعیین مقادیر فنل‌های کل و فلاونوئیدها از مزارع کاشت زعفران استان لرستان انجام گرفت. پس از تعیین مزارع کاشت زعفران بروش سیستماتیک تصادفی از گلبرگ‌های زعفران نمونه مرکب (2 کیلوگرم گلبرگ زعفران) تهیه شد. سپس به‌منظور اندازه‌گیری و تعیین میزان خواص آنتی‌اکسیدانی، مقادیر فنل و فلاونوئیدهای کل موجود در عصاره گلبرگ زعفران به‌ترتیب از روش‌های به دام اندازی رادیکال‌های آزاد (روش DPPH)، روش فولین سیوکا و روش رنگ سنجی کلرید آلمینیوم استفاده گردید. نتایج مقایسات میانگین مقادیر IC50 موجود در گلبرگ زعفران مزارع مختلف با آزمون چند دامنه‌ای دانکن نشان‌داد که مقدار IC50 مزارع نورآباد و ویسیان بترتیب با مقادیر 66/1 و 4/156میکروگرم بر میلی‌لیتر دارای بیشترین وکمترین خواص آنتی‌اکسیدانی در مقایسه با سایر مزارع دارا می‌باشند. نتایج مقایسه مقادیر فنل‌ها و فلاونوئیدهای کل موجود در گلبرگ زعفران مزارع با آزمون چند دامنه‌ای دانکن نشان‌داد که مقدار فنل کل با 8/1098میلی‌گرم گالیک اسید بر گرم عصاره هیدروالکلی مربوط به نورآباد و فلاونوئید با مقدار39/41 میلی گرم کوئرستین بر گرم عصاره هیدروالکلی مربوط به چغلوندی بیشترین مقادیر را در مقایسه با سایر مزارع به خود اختصاص دادند. نتایج مقایسه بین مقادیر IC50 به دست آمده از گلبرگ‌های زعفران مزارع مورد بررسی و BHT آنتی‌اکسیدان سنتزی و مصنوعی با آزمون حداقل اختلاف معنی‌داری (LSD) نشان‌داد که کمترین اختلاف به دست آمده متعلق به مزارع خرم آباد و چغلوندی بترتیب با مقادیر اختلاف 40/4 و 38/5 از بین سایر مزارع می‌باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron is one of the most valuable food and medicine products that has a high economic importance in Iran and other countries. Harmful environmental factors prohibit the human body from collating the free radicals that are produced during breathing resulting in problems such as premature aging, atherosclerosis and cancer. There has been only a few reported research studies on the antioxidant properties of Saffron petals in world. This research was carried out in order to survey the antioxidant compound that may be extracted from Saffron petals and indicate the total phenol content (TPC) and total flavonoid content (TFC) in the cultivated Saffron farms of the Lorestan province. After specifying the Saffron farms by the Random systematic method, the compound sampling was carried out (Saffron petals amount 2 kg). Then, the antioxidant activity, total amount of phenols and flavonoids in the extracts were measured by methods of DPPH, Folinciocalteau and Colorimetric assay, respectively. The results showed that the amount of IC50 was the lowest and highestin Noorabad and Vician farms with amounts of 1.66 and 156.4μg/ml, respectively by the Duncan test. The results of mean comparison showed that the total phenol content and total flavonoid content of 1098.8 mg Gallic acid/g extract and 41.39 mg cou/g extract, respectively that belonged to the Noorabad and the Chaghalvandi farms had the highest amounts among all of the saffron cultivation in the farms.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>51</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>60</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدیان</Family>
						<NameE>ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammadian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>محقق مرکز تحقیقات داروهای گیاهی رازی، دانشگاه علوم پزشکی استان لرستان، خرم آباد، ایران
محقق بخش تحقیقات منابع طبیعی، مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی استان لرستان، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، خرم آباد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>محقق مرکز تحقیقات داروهای گیاهی رازی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mohammadian53@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>احمدوند</Family>
						<NameE>Hassan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ahmadvand</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه شیمی،دانشکده پزشکی، دانشگاه علوم پزشکی لرستان، خرم آباد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه شیمی،دانشکده پزشکی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hassan_a46@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کرمیان</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Karamian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>محقق بخش تحقیقات منابع طبیعی، مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی استان لرستان، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، خرم آباد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>محقق بخش تحقیقات منابع طبیعی، مرکز تحقیقات</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>r_karamian2003@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سیاه منصور</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Siahmansour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار ، بخش تحقیقات منابع طبیعی، مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی استان لرستان، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، خرم آباد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار ، بخش تحقیقات منابع طبیعی، مرکز</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>siahmansour191@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سپهوند</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sepahvand</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>محقق، بخش تحقیقات منابع طبیعی، مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی استان لرستان، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، خرم آباد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>محقق، بخش تحقیقات منابع طبیعی، مرکز تحقیقات</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شهرام</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امیدواری</Family>
						<NameE>Shahram</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Omidvari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار ، بخش تحقیقات خاک و آب، مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی استان لرستان، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، خرم آباد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار ، بخش تحقیقات خاک و آب، مرکز تحقیقات</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>omidvari_s@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آنتی‌اکسیدان طبیعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رادیکال‌های آزاد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رنگ سنجی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کشت زعفرانن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Brand-Williams, W., Cuvelier, M.E., and Berset, C.1995. Use of free radical method to evaluate antioxidant activity. Lebensm Wiss Technology 28: 25-30.##Chang, C.C., Yang, M.H., Wenh. M., and Chern, J. C. 2002.Estimation of total flavonoid content in propolis by two complementary colorimetric methods. Journal of Food and Drug Analysis 10: 178-182.##Chen, Y., Zhang, H., Tian, X., Zhao, C., Cai, L., Liu, Y., Jia, L., Yin, H.X., and Chen, C. 2008. Antioxidant potential of crocins and ethanol extracts of Gardenia jasminoides ELLIS and Crocus sativus L. A relationship investigation between antioxidant activity and crocin contents. Food Chemistry 109: 484-492.##Chimi, H., Cillard, J., Cillar, P., and Rahmani, M. 1991. The peroxyl and hydroxyl radical scavenging activity of some natural phenolic antioxidant. Journal of the American Oil Chemists Society 68: 307-312.##Fernandez, J.A. 2004. Biology, biotechnology and biomedicine of saffron. Recent Research Development of Plant Science 2: 127-159.##Gil, M.I., and Kaber, A.A. 2002. Antioxidant capacities, phenolic compounds, Carotenoids and vitamin C contents of nectarine, peach, and plum cultivars from California. Journal of the Agricultural Food Chemistry 50: 4976-4982.##Hossein Goli, S.A., Mokhtari, F., and Rahimmalek, M. 2012. Phenolic Compounds and Antioxidant Activity from Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) Petal. Journal of Agricultural Science 4 (10): 175-181.##Hosseinzadeh, H., and Younesi, H. 2002. Petal and stigma extracts of Crocus sativus L. have antinociceptive and anti- inflammatory effects in mice. Bio Med Central Pharmacology and Toxicology 2: 1-8. (In Persian).##Karimi, E., Oskoueian, E., Hendra, R., and Jaafar, H. 2010. Evalution of Crocus sativus L. stigma phenolic and flavonoid compounds and its antioxidant activity. Journal Molecules 15: 6245-6249.##Khademi, K. 2011. Acquaintance about Crocus sativa agriculture. Propagation Publication Agriculture Jihad organization 1 (90): 1-19. (In Persian).##Konczak, I., Zabaras, D., Dunstan, M., and Aguas, P. 2010. Antioxidant capacity and phenolic compounds in commercially grown native Australian herbs and spices. Food Chemistry 122: 260-266.##Kosar, M., Goger, F., and Baser, K.H.C. 2011. In vitro antioxidant properties and phenolic composition of salvia halophila hedge from turkey. Food Chemistry 129: 374-379.##Kowalczyk, A., Biskup, I., and Fecka I. 2012. Total phenolic content and antioxidative properties of commercial tinctures obtained from some lamiaceae plants. Natural Product Communications 12: 1631-1634.##Milan, S. 2011. Total Phenolic content, Flavonoid Concentration and Antioxidant activity of Marrubium peregrinum L. extracts. Kargujevac Journal of the Sciences 33: 63-72.##Mirheidar, H. 1993. The Use the Plants in Prevention and Treatment of Diseases. Publication Islamic Cultural .535pp. (In Persian).##Mokhtari, F., Hossin goli, A., and rahim malek, M. 2012. Evaluation of the possibility in using saffron petals as a source of natural antioxidant. 7th National Congress on Horticultural Sciences  Iran. 2581-2584. (In Persian).##Murugaian, P., Srikumar, R., and Thangaraj, R. 2009. Isolation and estimation of phytochemical content in aqueous and ethanolic extract of Piper betel. Life Sciences and Bioinformatics 1: 29-31.##Norbaek, R., and Kondo, T. 2002. Flower Pigment Composition of Crocus species and cultivars used for a chemotaxonomic investigation. Biochemical Systematic and Ecology Journal 30 (8): 763-791.##Omidi, A., Riahinia, N., Montazer Torbati, M., and Behdani, M.A. 2014. Hepatoprotective Effect of Crocus sativus (saffron) petals extract against Acetaminophen toxicity in male wistar rats. Avicenna Journal of  Phytomedicine 4 (5): 330–336 .(In Persian).##Rafiei, Z., Jafari, M., Aalami, M., and Khamiri, M. 2012. Antioxidant properties of olive leaf extract and its application in sunflower oil. Journal of Food Research 21 (1): 11-21.##Schieber, A., stintzing , F.C., and Carle, R. 2001. By- product of plant food processing as a source of functional compounds recent developments. Journal Trends in Food Science and Technology 12 (11): 401-413.##Temerdashev, Z.A., Frolova, N.A., and Kolychev, I.A. 2011. Determination of phenolic compounds in medicinal herbs by reversed phase HPLC. Journal of Analytical Chemistry 66 (4): 407-414.##Thoo, Y.Y., Liang, J.Y., and Tan, C.P. 2010. Effects of binary solvent extraction system, extraction time and extraction temperature on phenolic antioxidants and antioxidant capacity from mengkudu (Morinda citrifolia). Food Chemistry 120: 290-295.##Wojdyło, A., Oszmianski, J., and Czemerys, R. 2007. Antioxidant activity and phenolic compounds in 32 selected herbs. Food Chemistry 105: 940-949.##Wong, C., Cheng, K., and Chen, F. 2006. A systematic survey of antioxidant activity of 30 Chinese medicinal plants using the ferric reducing antioxidant power assay. Food Chemistry 97: 705-711.##Zargari, A. 1990. Medicinal Plants 4th edition, Tehran University Publishing. 924pp. (In Persian).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تاثیر سطوح مختلف اسید هیومیک و تراکم بنه بر فعالیت آنتی اکسیدانی و مواد موثره زعفران (.Crocus sativus L)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Effects of different humic acid levels and planting density on antioxidant activities and active ingredients of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>به منظور بررسی تأثیر اسید هیومیک و تراکم کاشت بر فعالیت آنتی‏اکسیدانی و مواد مؤثره زعفران sativus L.) (Crocus آزمایشی در سال 1394 به‌صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح پایه بلوک‏های کامل تصادفی در دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند اجرا شد. تیمارهای آزمایش، شامل چهار سطح اسید هیومیک (صفر، 5، 10 و 15 کیلوگرم در هکتار) و سه سطح تراکم کاشت (50، 75 و 100 بنه در مترمربع) با سه تکرار بودند. نتایج نشان داد که تیمارهای مورد بررسی، اثر معنی‌داری بر فعالیت آنتی‌اکسیدانآنتی‌اکسیدانی گلبرگ (آنتی‌اکسیدان، فنول و آنتوسیانین) و مواد مؤثره زعفران (پیکروسین، سافرانال و کروسین) داشتند. بیشترین میزان آنتی‌اکسیدان (78/69 درصد) در تیمار 5 کیلوگرم در هکتار اسید هیومیک و تراکم 50 بنه در مترمربع مشاهده شد، اما محتوی فنول تحت تأثیر تیمارهای آزمایش قرار نگرفت. همچنین بالاترین میزان آنتوسیانین (40/46 میلی‌گرم در صد گرم وزن خشک) با کاربرد 10 کیلوگرم در هکتار اسید هیومیک و تراکم کاشت 75 بنه در مترمربع به دست آمد. نتایج مواد مؤثره زعفران نشان داد، که بیشترین عملکرد پیکروسین (60/40 درصد) در تیمار 15 کیلوگرم در هکتار اسید هیومیک و تراکم کاشت 75 بنه در مترمربع بدست آمد. همچنین بالاترین مقدار سافرانال (17/20 درصد) و کروسین (57/55 درصد) با کاربرد 10 کیلوگرم در هکتار اسید هیومیک و کمترین آن‌ها در تیمار شاهد (70/15 درصد) و (12/43 درصد) مشاهده شد. به‌طور کلی، نتایج بیانگر تأثیر مثبت اسید هیومیک و تراکم کاشت بر فعالیت آنتی‌اکسیدان و مواد مؤثره زعفران بود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The effects of applications of humic acid and planting density on antioxidant activities and components of saffron were evaluated under field conditions. Treatments were of four levels of humic acid (0, 5, 10 and 15 Kg.ha-1) and three densities of planting (50, 75 and 100 corms.m-2). The experiment was designed in randomized block design with three replications at the research station of the Faculty of Agriculture at the University of Birjand during the growing season of 2015. Petal antioxidant compounds (antioxidan, total phenol and Anthocyanins) and active ingredients of saffron (picrocin, safranal and crocin) were influenced by humic acid and planting density treatments. The highest antioxidant activity (69.7%) was obtained in plants treated with 5 kg.ha-1 humic acid with a planting density of 50 corms.m-2. However, no significant difference was found in phenol content under different treatments. The highest anthocyanin content (46.4 mg.100 g-1) was observed in 10 kg.ha-1 humic acid with a planting density of 75 corms.m-2. Picrocin content was influenced in response to humic acid planting density and the highest value (40.60%) was obtained from 15 kg.ha-1 humic acid with a planting density of 75 corms.m-2. The highest safranal (20.1%) and crocin (55.57%) were obtained in plants treated with10 kg.ha-1 acid humic, while the lowest values were recorded in the control (15.70%) and (43.12%) respectively. Thus, the results showed that humic acid and planting density have strong impacts on antioxidant compounds and active ingredients of saffron under field conditions.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>61</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>71</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فریده</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>احمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Farideh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ahmadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، علوم باغبانی، گرایش فیزیولوژی گیاهان دارویی، ادویه‏ای و عطری،دانشگاه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، علوم باغبانی، گرایش</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ahmadifaride17@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امینی فرد</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aminifard</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه علوم باغبانی و مرکز پژوهشی گیاهان ویژه منطقه، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه علوم باغبانی و مرکز پژوهشی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mh.aminifard@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خیاط</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khayat</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، گروه علوم باغبانی و مرکز پژوهشی گیاهان ویژه منطقه، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، گروه علوم باغبانی و مرکز پژوهشی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mhdkhayat@birjand.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صمدزاده</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Samadzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مربی، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مربی، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ars.1338@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کودهای آلی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد کیفی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فاصله کاشت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ahmadian, A., Ghanbary, A., Gluy, M., Siyahsar, B., and Arazmjoo, A. 2010. Different irrigation regimes and manure on the elements essential oil content and chemical composition cumin. Ecophysiology of Crop Plants and Weeds 16: 83-94.##Alavi-Shahri, H., Mohajeri, M., and Folaki, M.A. 1994. Evaluation of plant density (planting distanse) on saffron yield. Proceedings of 2nd Meeting of Saffron and Medicinal Plant Agronomy, Gonabad, Iran, 8-9 November 1994, p.13-20.##Behdani, M.A., Koocheki, A., Nassiri, M., and Rezvani Moghaddam, P. 2006. Evaluation of quantitative relationships between saffron yield and nutrition (on farm trial). Iranian Journal of Field Crops Research 3:1-14. (In Persian with English Summary).##Chuah, A.M., Lee, Y.C., Yamaguchi, T., Takamura, H., Yin, L.J., and Matoba, T. 2008. Effect of cooking on the antioxidant properties of colored peppers. Food Chemistry 111:20-28.##Daneshvar Kakhki, M., and Farahmand Gelyan, K. 2012. Review of interactions between           e-commerce, brand and packaging on value added of saffron: A structural equation modeling approach. African Journal of Business Management 6 (26): 7924-7930.##Edrisi, B. 2009. Post harvest physiology of cut flowers. Publications Payam Digar, Arak.##Fu Jiu, C., Dao Qi, Y., and Quing Sheng, W. 1995. Physiological effects of humic acid on drought resistance of wheat (in Chinese). Yingyong Shengtai Xuebao 6: 363–367.##Golzari, M. 2016. Effect of bio-fertilizer and mother corm weight on growth, flower and stigma yield and qualitative criteria of saffron. M.Sc dissertation, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Birjand, Iran. (In Persian with English Summary).##Heidari, Z., Besharati, H., and Maleki Farahani, S. 2014. Effect of some chemical fertilizer and bio fertilizer on quantitative and qualitative characteristics of saffron. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (3): 187-189. (In Persian with English Summary).##Haghirossadat, F., Bernard, F., Kalantar, M., Sheikhha, M., and Hokmollahi Azimzadeh, M. 2010. Bunium Persicum (Black Caraway) of Yazd province: Chemical assessment and    Evaluation of its antioxidant effects. Journal of Shaheed Sadoughi University of Medical Sciences 18 (3): 284-291.##INS (Iran National Standard). 2006. Research Institute of Standard and Iran. Saffron Bulletin, No. 259.##Ismaeili, V., moradi, P., and Ansari, Kh. 2015. Changes of crocin, picrocrocin and safranal in saffron (Crocus sativus L.) treated with compost and biological fertilizations. The first national conference on the use of medicinal plants and traditional medicine in life style, University of Torbat Heidariyeh, Iran, 6 December 2015, p. 46.49. (In Persian with English Summary).##Khan, A., Guramni, A.R., Khan, M.Z., Hussain, F., Akhtar, M.E., and Khan, S. 2012. Effect of humic acid on growth, yield, nutrient composition, photosynthetic pigment and total sugar contents of peas (Pisum sativum L). Journal of Chemical Society of Pakistan 6: 56-63.##Koocheki, A., Jahani, M., Tabrizi, L., Mohammad-Abadi, A.A., and Jahan, M. 2009. Effects of biofertilizer and inorganic fertilizer on generative growth and yield of saffron under high corm density. 3rd International Symposium on Saffron. Forthcoming Challenges in Cultivation, Research and Economics, Krokos, Kozani, Greece, 20-23 May 2009, p.14.##Kuntal, D., Raman, D., Thippenahalli, N.S., and  Sekeroglu, N. 2007. Influence of bio-fertilizers on the biomass yield and nutrient content in Stevia rebaudiana. Journal of Medicinal Plants Research 1 (1): 5-8.##Koocheki, A., Siahmarguee, A., Azizi, G., and Jahani, M. 2011. The effect of high density and depth of planting on agronomic characteristic of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) and corms behavior. Journal Agroecology 3: 36-49. (In Persian with English abstract).##Koocheki, A., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Mollafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2014. The effects of   high corm density and manure on agronomic characteristics and corms behavior of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in the second year. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (2): 144-155. (In Persian with English Summary).##Lozano, P., Castellar, M., Simancas, M., and Iborra, L. 1999. Quantitative high-performance liquid chromatographic method to analyze commercial saffron (Crocus sativus L.) products. Journal of Chromatography 830: 477-483.##Malakuti, M.G. 1996. Resistant  agriculture and yield increase with optimization use fertilizer in Iran. Instruction Agriculture Publication, Tehran. (In Persian).##Mohammad-Abadi, A.A., Rezvani-Moghaddam, P., and Sabori, A. 2007. Effect of plant distance on flower yield and qualitative and quantitative characteristics of forage production of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Mashhad conditions. Acta Horticulturae (ISHS) 739: 151-153.##Mohebi, N.K., and Klarestaghi, B. 2012. Effect of animal manure and crop density on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) flowering. 12th Iranian Crop Science Congress, Islamic Azad University, Karaj Branch, Iran, 6-9 September, p.34-37. (In Persian with English Summary).##Molina, R.V., Valero, M., Navarro, Y.J., Guardiola, L., and Garcia-Luice, A. 2005. Temperature effects on flower formation in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Sciatica Horticultural 103: 361-379.##Naghdi Buddy, H., Omidi, H., Golzad, A., Torabi, H., and Fotoukiyan, M. 2011. Changes of crocin, picrocrocin and safranal and agronomic characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)the impact of biological and chemical phosphate fertilizers. Journal of Medicinal Plants 4 (40): 58-68. (In Persian).##Nieto, K.F., and Frankenberger, W.T. 1991. Influence of adenine, isopentyl alcohol and Azotobacter chroococcum on vegetative growth of Zea mays. Plant Soil135: 213-219.##Omidi, H., Naghdi Badi, H., Golzad, A., Torabi, H., and Fotoukiyan, M. 2009. The effect of chemical and bio-fertilizer source of nitrogen on qualitive and quantitative of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Medicinal Plants 2 (30): 98-109. (In Persian). ##Patten, C.L., and Glick, B.R. 1996. Bacterial biosynthesis of indole-3-acetic acid. Canadian Journal of Microbiology 42: 207- 209.##Rasouli, Z., Maleki Farahani, S., and Besharati, H. 2015. Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) yield as affected by different fertilizing systems. Iranian Journal of Medicinal and Aromatic Plants 31 (2): 204-219. (In Persian with English Summary). ##Remon, S., Ferrer, A., Marquina, P., Burgos, J., and Oria, R. 2000. Use of modified atmospheres to prolong the postharvest life of burlat cherries at two different degrees of ripeness. Journal of the Science of Food and Agriculture 80 (10): 1552-1545.##Rouhani, R., Eyenafshar, S., and Ahmadzadeh , R. 2015. Study of anthocyanin and antioxidant compounds derived ethanol extract saffron flag with the help of ultrasound technology. Iranian Food Science and Technology 11 (2): 161-170.##Sabzevari, S., Khazaie, H.R., and Kafi, M. 2010. Study on the effects of humic acid on germination of four wheat cultivars (Triticun aestivum L.). Journal of Iranian Field Crop Research 8 (3): 473-480. (In Persian with English Summary).##Santiago, A., Lose, M., Carmona, E., and Delgado, A. 2009. Humic substances increase the effectiveness of iron sulfate and vivianite preventing iron chlorosis in white lupin. Bio- Fertilizer Soils 44: 875-883.##Sharif, M., Khattak, R.A., and Sarir, M.S. 2002. Effect of different levels of lignitic coal drived humic acid on growth of maize plants. Communication in Soil Science and Plant Analysis 33: 3567-3580.##Sidari, M., Atina, E., Francioso, O., Tugnoli, V., and Nardi, S. 2006. Biological activity of humic substances is related to their chemical structure. Soil Science Society of America Journal 71: 75-85.##Toor, R.K., Geoffrey, P., and Savagea, A.H. 2006. Influence of different types of fertilizers on the major antioxidant components of tomatoes. Journal of Food Composition and Analysis 19: 20-27.##Turkmen, N., Sari, F., and Veliglu, Y.S. 2005. The effect of cooking methods on total phenolic and antioxidant activity of selected green vegetables. Food Chemistry 93: 713-718.##Wrosotad, R.E. 1976. Color and pigment analysis in fruit products. Oregon State University Publications Limited, Cornwalis.##Zhang, X., and Schmidt. R.E. 1999. Antioxidant response to hormone containing product in Kentucky bluegrass subjected to drought. Crop Science 39: 545–551.##Zhang, X., and Schmidt, R.E. 2000. Hormone-containing products impact on antioxidant status of tall fescue and creeping bent grass subjected to drought. Crop Science 40: 1344–1349.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی الگوی بیانی ژن PIC2 مؤثر در گلدهی زعفران (.Crocus sativus L)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The structure of the protein and gene expression of PIC2, affecting flowering Flowers (Crocus sativus L.)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران (.Crocus sativus L) گیاهی است که به منظور استفاده از گل و کلاله قرمز رنگ گل، با اهداف زیادی ‌از جمله مصرف در صنایع غذایی، رنگ و پزشکی کشت می‌شود. به علت با ارزش بودن گل، شناخت ژن‌های شرکت‌کننده در مسیر گلدهی یکی از مهم‌ترین مسائل این گیاه است، که با روشن شدن این مسیر می‌توان ابتکار عمل در نظم گلدهی و تا حدودی زمان گلدهی و عوامل محیطی مؤثر بر آن را در دست گرفت. برای کشف و شناخت بهتر از مکانیزم مولکولی مؤثر در آغاز گلدهی گل، به‌طور اختصاصی ژن و میزان بیان ژنPistillata-like MADS box (PIC2) مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. توالی این ژن همسانی بالایی با اعضای خانواده جعبه MADS (از عوامل رونویسی در بیان پروتئین‌های کنترل اندام‌های گل) دارند. در این پژوهش، ژن PIC2 با استفاده از منابع بیوانفورماتیک، مورد مطالعه قرار گرفت و آغازگرها جهت تکثیر این ژن طراحی شدند. در ادامه، cDNA آن توسط آنزیم رونوشت بردار معکوس ساخته‌شد و به عنوان الگو برای تکثیر ژن PIC2 در واکنش PCR مورد استفاده قرارگرفت. میزان بیان‌ژن PIC2 در کلاله گل بیشترین و در بنه زعفران کمترین مقدار را نشان‌داد. طی واکنش PCR قطعه‌ایی به طول ۹۰۰ جفت باز از cDNA و قطعه‌ای به طول ۱۳۰۰ جفت باز از DNA ژنومی تکثیر یافت. این قطعه ژنی، یک پروتئین ۲۱۰ اسیدآمینه‌ای را رمز می‌کند که دارای منطقه با توالی جعبه MADS می‌باشد. با تجزیه و تحلیل ساختار مولکولی پروتئین رونوشت شده و بر اساس مدل‌سازی همولوژیکی، شکل فضایی آن نشان داد که این پروتئین ساختاری منظم دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron is grown for using its flower and red color stigma. This plant has many uses in the food industry, paints and medicine. Due to its high monetary worth, identification of genes involved in the flowering is very important. In order to better understand the molecular mechanisms involved in the onset of flowering, Gene and gene expression of Pistillata-Like MADS box (PIC2) were studied. The Gene sequences have high homology with other family members of the MADS-box family (one of the transcription factors control the expression of proteins flowers). In this research, the gene was studied using bioinformatics resources. Primers were designed for amplification of the gene and then the total DNA and RNA were extracted from the leaves of saffron. cDNA synthesis was performed by the reverse transcriptase enzyme and it was used as a template for amplification of PIC2 gene by PCR reaction. The reaction was amplified to a fragment with length 900 bp from cDNA and another fragment with length 2100 bp from genomic DNA. This gene encodes a protein that includes 210 amino acids. By analyzing the molecular structure of protein transcripts based on modeling of the gene homology, the spatial figure showed that they have a regular structure.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>73</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>90</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ایمان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یوسفی جوان</Family>
						<NameE>-</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>-</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه بیوتکنولوژی دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه بیوتکنولوژی دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>i.javan@torbath.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فائزه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قراری</Family>
						<NameE>faezeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>gharari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد ژنتیک و اصلاخ دام، کارشناس نشریات، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد ژنتیک و اصلاخ دام، کارشناس نشریات،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>qarari3@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بیان ژن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ژن Pistillata-like MADS box</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جعبه MADS</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدل‌سازی همولوژیکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ahrazem, O., Almudena Trapero, Gómez, M.D., Rubio-Moraga, A., and Gómez-Gómez, L. 2010. Genomic analysis and gene structure of the plant carotenoid dioxygenase 4 family: A deeper study in Crocus sativus and its allies. Genomics 96: 239-250.##Ahrazem, O., Rubio-Moraga, A., Trapero, A., and Gomez-Gomez, L. 2012. Developmental and stress regulation of gene expression for a 9-cis-epoxycarotenoid dioxygenase, CstNCED, isolated from Crocus sativus stigmas. Journal of Experimental Botany 63 (2): 681-694.##Alaey, M., Naderi, R., Khalighi, A., Vezvaeoi, A., and Salami, A.R. 2007. Study on effective components on the quantity and quality of genomic DNA extracted from Iran cyclamen, Pajouhesh and Sazandegi 73: 11-16.##Ashraf, N., Deepti, J., and Vishwakarma, R.A. 2015. Identification, cloning and characterization of an ultrapetala transcription factor CsULT1 from Crocus: a novel regulator of apocarotenoid. BMC Plant Biology 15 (25): 1-12.##Becker, A., and Theissen, G. 2003. The major clades of MADS-box genes and their role in the development and evolution of flowering plants, Molecular Phylogenetics and Evolution 29 (3): 464-489.##Castillo, R., Fernandez, J., and Gomez-Gomez, L. 2005. Implications of carotenoid biosynthetic genes in apocarotenoid formation during the stigma development of Crocus sativus and its closer relatives. Plant Physiology 139: 674-89.##D’Agostino, N., Pizzichini, D., Chiusano, M.L. and Giuliano, G. 2007. An EST database from saffron stigmas. BMC Plant Biology 7 (53): 1-8.##Davies, B., Rosa, A., Eneva, T., Saedler, H., and Sommer, H. 1996. Alteration of tobacco floral organ identity by expression of combinations of Antirrhinum MADS‐box genes. The Plant Journal 4: 663-677.##De Bodt, S., Raes, J., Florquin, K., Rombauts, S., Rouze, P., Theissen, G., and Van de Peer, Y. 2003. Genomewide structural annotation and evolutionary analysis of the type I MADS-box genes in plants. Journal of Molecular Evolution 56: 573–586.##Edstam, M.M., Viitanen, L., Salminen, T.A., and Edqvist, J. 2011. Evolutionary history of the non-specific lipid transfer proteins. Molecular Plant 4 (6): 947-964.##Emamzadeh, A.R., Hosseinkhani, S., Sadeghizadeh, M., Nikkhah, M., Chaichi, M.J., and Mortazavi, M. 2006. cDNA cloning, expression and homology modeling of a luciferase from the firefly Lampyroidea maculata. Journal of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology 39 (5): 578.##Fernandez, J.A. 2004. Biology, biotechnology and biomedicine of saffron. Recent Research Developments in Plant Science 2: 127-159.##Fernandez-Fuentes, N., Madrid-Aliste, C.J., Rai, B.K., Fajardo, J.E., and Fiser, A.S. 2007. M4T: A comparative protein structur modeling server. Nucleic Acids Research 35 (2): 363-368.##Goff S.A., Ricke, D., Lan, T.H., Presting, G., Wang, R., Dunn, M., Glazebrook, J., Sessions, A., Oeller, P., Varma, H., Hadley, D., Hutchison, D., Martin, C., Katagiri, F., Lange, B.M., Moughamer, T., Xia, Y., Budworth, P., Zhong, J., Miguel, T., Paszkowski, U., Zhang, S., Colbert, M., Sun, W.L., Chen, L., Cooper, B., Park, S., Wood, T.C., Mao, L., Quail, P., Wing, R., Dean, R., Yu, Y., Zharkikh, A., Shen, R., Sahasrabudhe, S., Thomas, A., Cannings, R., Gutin, A., Pruss, D., Reid, J., Tavtigian, S., Mitchell, J., Eldredge, G., Scholl, T., Miller, R.M., Bhatnagar, S., Adey, N., Rubano, T., Tusneem, N., Robinson, R., Feldhaus, J., Macalma, T., Oliphant, A., and Briggs, S. 2002.  A draft sequence of the rice genome (Oryza sativa L. ssp. japonica). Science 296 (5565): 92-100.##Hartz, C., Lauer, I., Del Mar San Miguel Moncin, M., Cistero-Bahima, A., Foetisch, K., Lidholm, J., and Scheurer, S. 2010. Comparison of IgE-binding capacity, cross-reactivity and biological potency of allergenic non-specific lipid transfer proteins from peach, cherry and hazelnut. International Archives of Allergy and Immunology 153 (4) :335-346.##Jodeir, S., and Dehghan Nayeri, F. 2016. Study of expression of the MADS-box transcription factors involved in flower formation in saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Cellular and Molecular Researches 4 (28): 488-499.##Johnson, M., Zaretskaya, I., Raytselis, Y., Merezhuk, Y., McGinnis, S., and Madden, T.L. 2008. NCBI BLAST: a better web interface. Nucleic Acids Research 36 (2): 5-9.##Josefina Poupin, M., Federici, F., Medina, C., Tomás Matus, J., Timmermann, T., and Arce-Johnson, p. 2007. Isolation of the three grape sub-lineages of B-class MADS-box TM6, PISTILLATA and APETALA3 genes which are differentially expressed during flower and fruit development. Gene 404 (1): 10-24##Kafi, M. 2004. Saffron (technology, production and processing). First Edition, Publication of Ferdowsi University of Mashhad. pp, 21-171.##Kafi, M., Zand, E., Mahdavi Damghani, B., and abbasi, F. 2010. Plant Physiology. Fourth Edition. Publication of Ferdowsi University of Mashhad 676.##Kalivas, A., Pasentsis, K., Polidoros, A.N., and Tsaftaris, A.S. 2007. Heterotopic expression of B-class floral homeotic genes PISTILLATA-GLOBOSA supports a modified model for crocus (Crocus sativus L.) flower formation. DNA  Sequence 18: 120-130.##Kolaskar A.S., and Tongaonkar P.C. 1990. A semi-empirical method for prediction of antigenic determinants on protein antigens. FEBS Letters 276 (1): 172-174.##Mandel, M.A., Gustafson-Brown, C., Savidge, B., and Yanofsky, M.F. 1992. Molecular characterisation of the Arabidopsis floral homeotic gene APETALA1. Nature 360: 273-277.##Masiero, S., Colombo, L., Grini, P.E, Schnittger, A., and Kater, M.M. 2011. The emerging iImportance of type I MADS-box transcription factors for plant reproduction. The Plant Cell Online 3: 865-872.##Messenguy, F., and Dubois, E. 2003. Role of MADS box proteins and their cofactors in combinatorial control of gene expression and cell development. Gene 316: 1–21.##Mihasan, M. 2010. Basic protein structure prediction for the biologist. Archives of Biological Sciences, Belgrade 62 (4): 857-871.##Mohammad Hashem, F., Nikpour, P., and Emadi-Baygi, M. 2011. Evaluation and optimization of various procedures of RNA extraction from human frozen tissues. Journal of Isfahan Medical School 29 (133): 327-335.##Moraga, A.R., Rambla, J.L., Ahrazem, O., Granell, A., and Gómez-Gómez, L. 2009. Metabolite and target transcript analyses during Crocus sativus stigma development. Phytochemistry 70: 1009-1016.##Murry, M., and Thompson, W.F. 1980. Rapid isolation of high molecular weight plant DNA. Nucleic Acid Research 8: 4321-4325.##Pelaz, S., Ditta, G.S., Baumann, E., Wisman, E., and Yanofsky, M.F. 2000. B and C floral organ identity functions require sepallata MADS-box genes. Nature 6783: 200-203.##Sambrook, J., and Russell, D.W. 2001. Molecular Cloning: A Laboratory Manual. New York. Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press. 628 pp.##Sarowar, S., Kim, Y.J., Kim, K.D., Hwang, B.K., Ok, S.H., and Shin, J.S. 2009. Overexpression of lipid transfer protein (LTP) gene enhances resistance to plant pathogens and LTP functions in long-distance systemic signaling in tobacco. Plant Cell Reports 28 (3): 419-427.##Shakib, A.M., and Ainsworth, C.C. 2009. Expression study of four gene clones belonging to MADS- box family in the dioecious plant sorrel (Rumex acetosa L.). journal of Agricultural biotechnology1 (1): 1-18.##Szczyglowski, K., and Amyot, L. 2003. Symbiosis, inventiveness by recruitment? Plant Physiology131: 935-940.##Theissen, G., Becker, A., Di Rosa, A., Kanno, A.,##Tsaftaris, A., Alexios, S., Polidoros, N., Pasentsis, K., and Kalivas, A. 2006. Tepal formation and expression pattern of B-class paleo Ap3- like MADS-box genes in crocus (Crocus sativus L.). Plant Science 2: 238-246.##Tsaftaris, A., Pasentsis, K., Makris, A., Darzentas, N., Polidoros, A., Kalivas, A., and Argiriou, A. 2011. The study of the E-class Sepallata3-like MADS-box genes in wild-type and mutant flowers of cultivated saffron crocus (Crocus sativus L.) and its putative progenitors. Journal of Plant Physiology 14: 1675-1684.##Tsaftaris, A.S., Pasentsis, K., and Polidoros, A.N. 2005. Isolation of a differentially spliced C-type flower specific Ag-Like MADS-box gene from Crocus sativus and characterization of its expression. Biologia Plantarum 4: 499-504.##Tsaftaris, A.S., Pasentsis, K., Iliopoulos, I., and Polidoros, A.N. 2004. Isolation of three homologous Ap1-like MADS-box genes in crocus (Crocus sativus L.) and characterization of their expression. Plant Science 5: 1235-1243.##Van Loon, L.C. and Van Strien, E.A. 1999. The families of pathogenesis-related proteins, their activities, and comparative analysis of PR-1 type proteins. Physiological and Molecular Plant Pathology 55 (2): 85-97.##Varjonen, E., Vainio, E., Kalimo, K., and Juntunen-Backman, K. 2002. Clinical importance of non-specific lipid transfer proteins as food allergens. Biochemical Society Transactions 30 (6): 910-913.##Kim, J.T., Munster, T., Winter, K.U., and Saedler, H. 2000. A short history of MADS-box genes in plants. Plant Molecular Biology 42: 115-149##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی عوامل مرتبط با شیوه فروش محصول تولید شده توسط زعفران‌کاران شهرستان قائن</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating factors related to selling behaviour of Saffron farmers in the Qaen Township</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران‌کاران به خاطر دلایل متعددی دارای رفتارهای بازاریابی متفاوتی در ارتباط با شیوه فروش زعفران تولیدی خودشان هستند، ازاین‌رو تحقیق توصیفی- همبستگی حاضر با هدف بررسی عوامل مرتبط با شیوه فروش محصول تولید شده توسط زعفران‌کاران شهرستان قائن صورت گرفت. جامعه آماری کلیه زعفران‌کاران شهرستان قائن در سال 1394 بودند (12860 نفر) که با استفاده از فرمول نمونه‌گیری کوکران 230 زعفران‏کار مشخص و از طریق روش نمونه‌گیری چندمرحله‌ای تصادفی مطالعه شدند. داده‏ها با استفاده از پرسشنامه ساختارمند و از طریق مصاحبه حضوری با زعفران‌کاران جمع‌آوری و با نرم‌افزار Spss20 تحلیل شدند. نتایج نشان داد که زعفران‌کاران دارای رفتارهای متفاوت فروش بوده و 23/38 درصد کل زعفران تولیدی به‌صورت پوشال، 55/31 درصد به‌صورت نگین و 21/30 درصد نیز به‌صورت دسته به فروش رفته است. تحلیل همبستگی نشان داد که بین متغیرهای تعداد افراد خانوار، مقدار زعفران خودمصرفی، درآمد حاصل از زعفران به کل درآمد، سطح زیر کشت، تعداد کلاس‌های آموزشی شرکت کرده، میزان رضایت از کمیت محصول و استفاده از برخی منابع اطلاعاتی بازاریابی با شیوه فروش زعفران‌کاران رابطه معنی‌داری وجود دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The marketing behavior of different Saffron farmers is different due to a few effective factors. The present descriptive/correlational study is aimed at investigating the selling behavior of Saffron farmers and the associated factors. The statistical population consisted of all Saffron farmers in the Qaen Township in 2015 (N= 12860) of which 230 were selected through a randomized multi-stage sampling method. The sample size was identified based on Cochran&#039;s sampling formula. Data was gathered through a valid and reliable questionnaire with face to face interviews done with farmers and analyzed by SPSS software package. The results indicated that Saffron farmers have distinct marketing behaviors, such that 30.7 percent of their Saffron products were sold in Dasteh type, 35.8 percent in Poshal type and 33.5 percent in Negin type. The results also showed that there were significant correlations between marketing behavior with variables such as the amount of self-consumption of saffron, acreage of cultivated area, their satisfaction from product quantity, the extent of use of some marketing information channels and the ratio of saffron income to total income.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>91</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>105</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خسروی</Family>
						<NameE>Majid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khosravi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد، توسعه روستایی، دانشگاه زنجان.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد، توسعه روستایی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mkhosravi788@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شمس</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shams</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی، گروه ترویج، ارتباطات و توسعه روستایی، دانشگاه زنجان.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی، گروه ترویج،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shams@znu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حیدر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قلی زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Higar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gholi Zadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، اقتصاد کشاورزی، گروه ترویج، ارتباطات و توسعه روستایی، دانشگاه زنجان.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، اقتصاد کشاورزی، گروه ترویج، ارتباطات</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hgholizadeh@znu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>زهرا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>هوشمندان مقدم فرد</Family>
						<NameE>Zahra</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hoshmandan moghadam</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی، دانشگاه زنجان.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hooshmand@znu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران‌کاران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شیوه فروش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شهرستان قائن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abdpoor Dalal, A. 2011. The study of potato marketing structure and its influencing factors in Ardabil. The first Conference of the Agricultural Development of North West provinces. University of Ardebil Payam Noor. (In Persian).##Abrishami, M.H. 2010. Iranian saffron, historical, cultural and agricultural understanding. Pub: Astane Ghodse Razavi. (In Persian).##Ashrafi, M., Sadr Alashrafi, S.M., and Karbasi, A. 2005.  Investigation on marketing margins of raisins and grape in Iran.  Evaluation of grapes and raisins marketing margin in Iran. Iranian Journal of Trade Studies (Ijts), 9 (23): 213-237. (In Persian with English Summary).##Bhajantri, Sh. 2011. Production, processing and marketing of potato in Karnataka (India): An Economic Analysis. MSc. Dissertation in Agribusiness Management. Department of Agricultural Marketing, Co-Operation and Business Management, Univesity of Agricultural Sciences.##Chalwe, S. 2011. Factors influencing bean producter’s choice of marketing channels in Zambia. Ph.D Thesis. University of Zambia. Available at website: http://crsps.net/wp-content/downloads/Dry%20Grain%20Pulses/Invenotired%206.11/Inventoried%206.8/4-2011-12-127.##Chokera, F., Ngwenya, T., and Njovo, M. 2014. The role of agricultural marketing on empowering rural farmers in masvingo province, Zimbabwe. European Journal of Business and Management 6 (3): 153-163.##Ghadiri Moghaddam, A., and Nemati, A. 2011. An investigation of effective factors on participation of farmers (hedge ratio) in tomato futures market. Journal of Economics and Agriculture Development 25 (3): 375-384. (In Persian with English Summary).##Islam, M.S., and Islam, M.N. 2009. Marketing of library and information products and services, A theoretical analysis. Business Information Review 26 (2): 123-132.##Jari, B., and Fraser, G.C.G. 2009. An analysis of institutional and technical factors influencing agricultural marketing amongst smallholder farmers in the Kat River Valley, Eastern Cape Province, South Africa. African Journal of Agricultural Research 4 (11): 1129-1137.##Javid A., Mohammadi, H., Farajzade, Z., and Haj-Bagheri, M.R. 2008. Economic analysis of saffron marketing and exporting issues in Iran with an emphasis on Fars province. 16 (45): 29-57. (In Persian).##Kafi, M., Rashed Mohassel, M.H., Koocheki, A.R., and Molafilabi, A.A. 2002. Saffron, Processing Technology. Publication of Ferdowsi University of Mashhad. (In Persian).##Khaledi, M., Shoukatfadaei, M., and Nekoofar, F. 2011. Marketing efficiency of poultry industry in Iran (case study: Karaj). Agricultural Economics and Development 24 (4): 445-448. (In Persian)##Khan, N., and Khan, M. 2012. Marketing of agricultural crops in rural Indian economy: A case Study. Journal of Economics and Sustainable Development 3 (2): 1-9.##Kutler, PH., and Armstrong, G. 2010. Marketing Principles. Translated by Bahman Foroozande. Tehran, Publication of Amookhte. (In Persian).##Makvandi, R., and Omani, A. 2013. The factors affecting the marketing of agricultural products. The first national congress on sustainable medicinal and agriculture plants. University of Shahid Mofatteh Hamadan. (In Persian).##Mehdipour, E., Sadr Alashrafi, S.M., and Kazem Nejad, M. 2006. Study of comparative advantage for potato production in Iran. Journal of Agricultural Sciences 12 (1): 15-25. (In Persian with English Summary)##Mojaverian, S., Rasouli, F., and Hosieni Yekani, S. 2013. The influential factors on the choice of sales channel by citrus producers in Mazandaran. Journal of Economics and Agriculture 27 (2): 123-133. (In Persian with English Summary).##Mzyece, A. 2011. Factors influencing cowpea producers’ choice of marketing channels in Zambia. MSc dissertation in agricultural sciences. Department of Agriculture Economics and Extension Education. Organisation of Agricultural Jihad of South Khorasan, 2013. Statistic of Agriculture.##Park, T.A. 2009. Assessing the returns from organic marketing channels. Journal of Agricultural and Resource Economics 34 (3): 483-497.##Patil, M.A. 2008. Study on Production and marketing management behavior of organic vegetable growers in Belgaum district. MSc. dissertation in agricultural extension and education. Department of Agricultural Extension Education College of Agriculture, Dharwad University of Agricultural Sciences.##Pikousova, K., and Prusa, P. 2011. Deterministic factors for choosing of distribution model. Pernerscontacts 4 (3): 91-97##Pleite, F.M.C. 2004. Selection of marketing channels by intensive horticultural crop growers in Almeria [Spain]. Spanish Journal of Agricultural Researc 2B (1): 27-33.##Prasanna, R., Bulankulama, S., and Kuruppuge, R.H. 2011. Factors Affecting Farmers Higher Gain from Paddy Marketing: A Case Study on Paddy Farmers in North Central Province, Sri Lanka. International Journal of Agricultural Management and Development (IJAMAD) 2 (1): 57-69.##Rezvani, M., Sadeghloo, T., Farajisabokbar, H., and Eftekhri, A. 2013. Analysis of factors affecting the milk marketing in space network of rural areas in Khodabandeh Township/ Zanjan province. Quaterly Journal of Space economy and rural development 2 (3): 1-28. (In Persian).##Sabouri, M.S., Faraj Elah Hosseini, S.J., Chizari, A.H., and Iranbakhsh, A.R. 2006. Analysis of farmers and expert’s point of view on the role of extention in Persian melon marketing in garmsar. Journal of New Agricultural Science 2 (3): 65-76. (In Persian with English Summary).##Sartwelle, J., O&#039;Brien, D., Tierney, W., and Eggers, T. 2000. The effects of personal and farm characteristics upon gain marketing practices. Journal of Agricultural and Applied Economics 32 (1): 95-111.##Sikawa, G.Y., and Mugisha, J. 2010. Factors influencing south-western Uganda dairy farmers’ choice of the milk marketing channel: a case study of Kirihura district south western Uganda (No. 0856-9681). Research report series. Available at web site: http://www.mocu.ac.tz/upload/researches/sikawa%20and%20mugisha.pdf##Trienekens, J.H. 2011. Agricultural value chains in developing countries a framework for analysis, International Food and Agribusiness Management Review 14 (2): 51-82.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				