<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effect of Zeolite Rates and Irrigation Management on Some Properties of Saffron Corms</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اثر مقدار زئولیت و مدیریت آبیاری بر برخی خصوصیات بنه زعفران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>201</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>213</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">38673</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2016.38673</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>خاشعی سیوکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مهندسی آب، دانشگاه بیرجند</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2863-8483</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری آبیاری و زهکشی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>هاشمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری آبیاری و زهکشی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امین</FirstName>
					<LastName>چالاک</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی مهندسی آب، دانشگاه بیرجند</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron (&lt;em&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/em&gt; L.) is a subtropical and valuable crop which is reproduced by corms. Due to the importance of corm weight in saffron yield, it is important to study the different factors that affect yield such as drought stress. For this purpose, this research was conducted as a factorial design based on completely randomized design (CRD) in the Agricultural Research Station of the University of Birjand during the period 2013-2015. The treatments consisted of Zeolite at four rates (0: Z0, 0.5: Z1, 1: Z2 and 2: Z3 as weight percentage) and irrigation management at three levels (traditional: I1, deficit irrigation as 70% moisture depletion: I2 and full irrigation: I3) with three replications. The results showed that zeolite rates has a significant effect on corm weight, number of corms less than 2gr, number of 6-8gr corms and number of replacement corms (P≤0.01). Irrigation management also has a significant effect on corm weight (P≤0.01), number of corms 6-8gr and number of replacement corms (P≤0.05). The treatments with no zeolite amended (Z0I1, Z0I2 and Z0I3) showed a reduction in corm weight compared to Z3I3 (P≤0.05). Z3I3, Z3I2 and Z3I3 showed an increase in the number of replacement corms while Z0I1 and Z0I2 had the least number of replacement corms. In conclusion, Z2I1 is recommended as the best treatment by considering the reduction in zeolite and water used, which increased corm weight by 26.64%, 23.88% and 17.81% compared to Z0I1, Z0I2 and Z0I3, respectively.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زعفران (&lt;em&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/em&gt; L.) گیاهی نیمه گرمسیری و گران‌بها است که توسط بنه تکثیر می‌شود. با توجه به اهمیت وزن بنه در عملکرد زعفران، بررسی اثر عوامل مختلف ازجمله تنش آبی بربنه اهمیت می‌یابد. بدین منظور تحقیقی به‌صورت فاکتوریل و در قالب طرح کاملاً تصادفی طی سال‌های‌ 1394-1392 در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند انجام شد. تیمار زئولیت در چهار سطح (Z0: صفر، Z1: 5/0، Z2: 1 و Z3: 2 درصد وزنی) و تیمار آبیاری در سه سطح (I1: آبیاری سنتی، I2: آبیاری با تخلیه 70 درصد رطوبتی و I3: آبیاری کامل) در سه تکرار در نظر گرفته‌شدند. نتایج نشان‌داد که سطح مصرف زئولیت اثر معنی‌داری بر متوسط وزن بنه، تعداد بنه با وزن کمتر از 2 گرم، تعداد بنه با وزن بین 6 تا 8 گرم و تعداد بنه خواهری داشت (P≤0.01). مدیریت آبیاری نیز اثر معنی‌داری بر متوسط وزن بنه (P≤0.01)، تعداد بنه با وزن بین 6 تا 8 گرم و تعداد بنه خواهری داشت (P≤0.05). وزن بنه در تیمارهای بدون کاربرد زئولیت (Z0I1، Z0I2 و Z0I3) نسبت به Z3I3 کاهش معنی‌داری داشتند (P≤0.05). همچنین تیمارهای Z3I3، Z3I2 و Z1I3 بیشترین و تیمارهای Z0I1 و Z0I2 کمترین تعداد بنه‌های خواهری را داشتند. با در نظر گرفتن کاهش مصرف زئولیت و آب آبیاری، تیمار Z2I1 را می‌توان به‌عنوان مناسب‌ترین تیمار پیشنهاد کرد به‌طوری‌که وزن بنه را نسبت به تیمارهای Z0I1، Z0I2 و Z0I3 به ترتیب 64/26، 88/23 و 81/17 درصد افزایش داد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برنامه‌ریزی آبیاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تنش آبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وزن بنه و تغذیه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_38673_a37897fbf7e8747eef588b4e062a61e4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
