<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1396</YEAR>
<VOL>5</VOL>
<NO>4</NO>
<MOSALSAL>18</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>102</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>فراتحلیل پژوهش‌های زراعی زعفران (.Crocus sativus L) با تاکید بر مصرف کود‌های آلی و عملیات زراعی در ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Meta-analysis of Saffron (.Crocus sativus L) Agronomical Researches, with an Emphasis on the Consumption of Organic Fertilizers and Agronomical Practices in Iran</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پژوهش‌های زراعی زعفران در رابطه با تأثیر کودهای آلی (دامی، زیستی و کمپوست) و عملیات زراعی (تراکم، روش، تاریخ و عمق کاشت) سابقه‌ای طولانی در ایران دارد. به دلیل پراکندگی و تفاوت‏های موجود در نتایج آزمایش‌های مختلف، در این بررسی از رهیافت فرا تحلیل استفاده شد. تعداد 47 مطالعه عملیات زراعی و 44 مطالعه کود‌های آلی از میان 202 مطالعه انتخاب و تجزیه فراتحلیلی شدند. در مطالعات کود‌های آلی، برتری کودهای دامی (گاوی) با تأثیر بر افزایش وزن خشک زعفران (493/1g=) با اطمینان 95% نسبت به سایر کودها مشاهده شد. مقادیر، 40 تا 50 تن در هکتار کودگاوی، 20 تا 30 تن در هکتار کمپوست که به­صورت ترکیب با کود‌های زیستی (نیتروکسین همراه با باکتری تثبیت‌کننده ازت) استفاده شده ­بودند، مؤثرتر از مقادیر بالاتر هر یک از این کود‌ها به تنهایی بوده است. مطالعات عملیات زراعی، برتری تراکم کاشت با تأثیر بر افزایش تعداد گل در هکتار را نشان داد. تراکم‌های مطلوب 50 تا 100 بنه در مترمربع، میانگین وزن مطلوب هر بنه 10 تا 20 گرم و متوسط وزن بنه مصرفی 9 تا 12 تن بنه در هکتار به‌دست آمد. روش کشت مناسب، روش ردیفی-کپه‌ای (فاصله بین ردیف 20 سانتی­متر و روی ردیف 10 سانتی­متر) و بهترین تاریخ‌های کاشت، اواخر اردیبهشت تا دهه اول خرداد و مناسب­ترین عمق کاشت، عمق 15 تا 20 سانتی‌متر بوده است. هدف از انجام این فرا تحلیل، درک بهتر مدیریت زراعی و کودی این محصول و ارائه بهترین مدیریت ممکن می‌باشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Studies that investigated the impact of organic fertilizers (manure, compost and biological fertilizers) and agronomical practices (density, method, date and depth of planting) on saffron yield have a long history in Iran. Due to the distribution and inconsistency in the results obtained from different studies, a meta-analytic approach was used in the current study. for this aim, 47 organic fertilizers studies and 44 agronomical practices studies were selected from 202 gathered studies and analyzed. The criteria for the selection of studies were the adequacy of data for the present meta-analysis. Among the individual fertilizer studies, manure fertilizer had the highest impact on saffron dry weight (g= 1.493) at 95% confidence interval. Average amount, 40 to 50ton/ha of cow manure, 20 to 30ton/ha of compost that is used as a combination with Biofertilizer (Nitroxin with Nitrogen-fixing bacteria) were more effective than higher amounts of these fertilizers will be alone. Among the agronomical practices studies, plant density had the highest and depth of planting had the lowest effect size on economical yield and number of flower. The optimal density for maximum yield was 50-100 corm per (m2), optimal consumed weight average 9-12 ton per hectare observed, optimal weight of any corm was 10-20 (g). Among planting methods, row-mass method was the best optimal (inter-planting was 20 cm and intra-planting 10 cm). The best planting dates was the end of May and the first decade of Jun. Optimal planting depth was 15-20cm. Homogeneity between organic fertilizers studies was accepted and the homogeneity between agronomical practices except depth of planting studies was accepted. This heterogeneity was caused by factors such as age of farms and different regions that had the most impact on heterogeneity and effect size. The present meta-analysis aims to provide a better understanding of agronomical and fertilizers management and offer the best possible management for this crop.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>311</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>327</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مختاری</Family>
						<NameE>mohamad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>mokhtari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، اکولوژی گیاهان زراعی، پردیس بین الملل، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، اکولوژی گیاهان زراعی، پردیس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mmelborn@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کوچکی</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Koocheki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>akooch@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نصیری محلاتی</Family>
						<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nassiri Mahallati</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mnassiri@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کود دامی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کود زیستی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کمپوست</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aghazadeh, R., and Hemmatzadeh, A. 2012. Effect of planting date, planting depth and distance on vegetative and reproductive variables of saffron in Maku climate. Quarterly of Knowledge of Modern Sustainable Agriculture 8 (1): 1-10. (In Persian with English Summary).##Begg, C.B., and Mazumdar., M. 1994. Operating characteristics of a rank correlation test for publication bias. Biometrics Journal 50: 1088-1101.##Behdad, M. 2005. Effects of corm density and methods of planting on yield of saffron. The Final Report of the Research Project of Ministry of Agriculture, Research Institute on Seeds and Seedling. (In Persian).##Behnia, M.R., Estilai, A., and Ehdaie, B. 1999. Application of fertilizer for increased saffron yield. Journal of Agronomy and Crop Science182: 9–15. (In Persian with English Summary).##Behnia, M.R., and Mokhtari., M. 2009. Effect of planting methods and corm density in saffron (Crocus sativus L.) Available at web site http //:www.sid.ir (verified Jun 2009). (In Persian with English Summary).##Bengtsson,G., Ahnstoom, J., and Weibull, A.H. 2005. The effects of agronomic agriculture on biodiversity and abundance: a meta-analysis. Journal of Applied Ecology 42: 261-269.##Borenstein, M., Hedges, L., Higgins, J.P.T., and Rothstein, H.R. 2009. Introduction to Meta-Analysis. A John Wiley and Sons, Ltd., Publication, Cornwall, UK.##Cooper, H.M., and Hedges., LV. 1994. The Hand Book of Research Synthesis. Russell Sage Foundation. New York.##Egger, M., Smith, G.D., and Altman, D.G. 2001. Systematic Reviews in Health Care Meta-analysis in context. BMJ Publishing Group.##Farahmandfar, B., Kelarestaghi, K., and Mohebbi, N. 2013. Effect of different levels of fertilizer, compost, vermicompost and cow on flowering and vegetative traits saffron (Crocus sativus L.).The second conference SeedScience and Technology, Islamic Azad University of Mashhad, Iran. Available at web site http://www.civilica.com/Paper-Seed techno 92-101.html. (In Persian with English Summary).##Ghalavnad, A., and Abdollahian-Noghabi, M. 2004. Effect of ecological adaptation and study of row spacing and planting method on land races yield of Iranian saffron. 2&quot;National Symposium of Saffron Gonabad. Iran. (In Persian).##Ghazi-Tabatabaei, M., and Vedadhir, A.A. 2010. Meta-Analysis in Social and Behavioral Research. Press Jameashnasan, Tehran. (In Persian)##Habibi, M., Fadaei, Z.N., Najafi, M., and Fadaei, Z. 2009. Confirmatory factorial structure, reliability and validity of the Achenbuch youth self-report scale (YSR): monozygotic and dyziygotic twins. Journal of Clinical Psychology 1: 1-18. (In Persian).##Kafi, M., and Showket, T. 2006. A comparative study of saffron agronomy and production systems of Khorasan (Iran) and Kashmir (India). On line in http// www.google scholar.##Kiaer, LP., Skovgaard, I.M., and Ostergard, H. 2009. Grain yield increase in cereal variety mixture: A meta-analysis of field trails. Field Crop Research 114: 361-373.##Koocheki, A., Jahani, M., Tabrizi, L., Mohammad-Abadi, A.A., and Jahan, M. 2011a. Evaluatethe effects of biological and chemical fertilizers and density on yield and characteristics of saffron corms (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Agroecology 3 (1): 36-49. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Nassiri-Mahlati, M., Moradi, R., and Alizadeh, R. 2011c. Meta-Anlysis of biodiversity in agriculture of Iran. Journal of Agroecology 1 (2): 1-15. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., RezvaniMoghaddam, P., Molafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, S.M. 2013. The effect of high corm density and  manure on agronomic characteristics and corm behavior of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in the second year. Journal of Saffron Research 1: 144-155. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Siahmargoie, A., Azizi, G., and Jahani, M. 2011b. Effect of high corm density and depth of planting on agronomic criteria and corm behavior of saffron. Agroecology Journal 3 (1): 36-49. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Nassiri- Mahallati. M., Bakhshaee, S., Davari, A., and Zare Zadeh, M. 2014. A meta analysis of nitrogen fertilizer experiments for cereal crops in Iran. Journal of Agrocology 2 (4): 1-21. (In Persian with English Summary).##Mehri, N. 2011. Poverty of meta-analysis in social science in Iran. Available at Web site http://www.SID.ir.(In Persian).##Migues, F.H., Perez, A.A., Frasco, J.A., and Zapiola, M.L. 2013. Meta-analysis of nitrogen fertilization effects on wheat grain protein in Argentina. Open Science Repository Agriculture, online. e70081981. DOI: 10.7392/open access.##Mohammadzadeh, A.R., and Ahmadpoor, A. 2004. The effect of organic matter from different sources on yield of flowers of Saffron. Research of Agricultural Extension and Education, Research Project, Institute of Soil and Water Research, Iran. (In Persian).##Naderi-Darbaghshahi, M.R., Khajeh-Bashi, S.M., Bani-Ateba, S.A.R., and Deh-Dashti, S.M. 2008. The effects of planting method, density and depth on yield and exploitation period of saffron field (Crocus sativus L.) in Isfahan. Seed and Plant Journal 24: 643-657. (In Persian with English Summary).##Omid-Baigi, R., Sadeghi, B., Zyaratnia, A., and Ramezani, S.M.  2010. Effect of corm weight on Saffron yield in climate Nishabur. Sonbole Research Monthly 4 (41): 16-17. (In Persian with English Summary).##Philibert, A., Loyceb, C., and Makowski, D. 2012. Assessment of the quality of meta-analysis in agronomy. Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment 148 (2012): 72– 82.##Rezvani-Moghaddam, P., Mohammad-abadi, A.A.,  Fallahi, J.,  Aghhavani, M., and Shajari, M. 2011. Effects of chemical and organic fertilizers on number of corm and stigma yield of saffron (Crocus sativus). 59th International Congress and Annual Meeting of the Society for Medicinal Plant and Natural Product Research, Antalya, Turky, 4-9 September, 2011.##Rezvani-Moghaddam, P., Khorramdel, S., Ghafori, A., and Shabahang, J. 2013a. Evaluation of growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) affected by spent mushroom compost and corm density. Journal of Saffron Researches 1 (1): 13-26. (In Persian with English Summary).##Rezvani-Moghaddam, P., Koocheki, A., Molafilabi, A., and Seyyedi, M. 2013b. Flower and corm characteristics of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) as affected by levels of wheat mulch on different dates. Journal of Agroecology 15 (3): 234-246. (In Persian with English Summary).##Rosenthal, R., and Dematteo, M.R. 2001. Meta-analysis: recent developments in quantitative methods for literature. Annual Review of Psychology 52: 59-82.##Rostami, M., and Mohammadi, H. 2013. The effect of planting date and plant density on the growth and yield of saffron corms in climate Malayer. Journal of Agroecology 5 (1): 27-38. (In Persian with English Summary).##Sabina, N., Nehvi, F.A., Iqbal, A.M., Daron, A., Gowhar, A., and Ngoo, S. 2012. Effect of organic and inorganic sources of fertilizers on growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) 4th international saffron symposium, Kashmir, India, 22-25 October, 2012.##Sadeghi, B. 1988. Effect of chemical fertilizer and animal manure on leaf crop production and saffron yield. Khorasan, Research Project, Scientific and Industrial Research Organization, Iran. (In Persian).##Sadeghi, B. 1993. Effect of corm weight on flower production of saffron. Research Project, Khorasan Scientific and Industrial Research Organization, Iran 73pp. (In Persian).##Sadeghi, B., Negari, A., and Hattami, M. 2003. Effects of time of planting on saffron flower production. Proceeding of the 3rd National Conference on Saffron, Mashhad. Iran p. 168-171.##Soltani, A., and Soltani, A. 2014. Meta-Analysis of Seed Priming effect on Germination: Case study in Iran.13thIranian Crop Science Congress, Karaj, Iran. 24-26 August, 2014. (In Persian).##Temperini, O., Rea, R., Temperini, A., Colla, G., and Rouphael, Y. 2009. Evaluation of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) production in Italy: Effects of the age of saffron fields and plant density. Food Agriculture Journal, Environment 7 (1): 19-23.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر منابع مختلف کودهای هیومیکی، زیستی و نانو در سطوح مصرف کود نیتروژن بر عملکرد گل زعفران (.Crocus sativus L)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Impact of use of different sources of humic, bio and nano fertilizers and nitrogen levels on saffron (.Crocus sativus L)   flower yield</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>این تحقیق به‌منظور بررسی تأثیر منابع مختلف کودهای هیومیکی، زیستی و نانو در سطوح مصرف کود نیتروژن بر عملکرد گل زعفران (Crocus sativus L.) در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشگاه تربت‌حیدریه واقع در زاوه در سال­زراعی 94-1393 به اجرا درآمد. تیمارهای آزمایش شامل سه سطح مصرف کود نیتروژن (صفر، ۲۵ و ۵۰ کیلوگرم در هکتار از منبع اوره) به‌عنوان عامل اصلی و مصرف منابع کودی مختلف شامل بیومیک (نانو)، سوپرهیومیک، ترکیب سوپرهیومیک و بیومیک، هیومی­فول (نوعی کود هیومیکی)، نیتروکارا (نوعی کود زیستی) و عدم مصرف کود به‌عنوان عامل فرعی به‌صورت اسپلیت پلات بر پایه طرح بلوک­ کامل تصادفی با 18 تیمار و سه تکرار بودند. صفات مورد ارزیابی شامل تعداد گل در هر کرت، وزن خشک گل، وزن خشک کلاله، وزن خشک خامه، وزن خشک گلبرگ با کاسبرگ بودند. آنالیز داده­های حاصل از آزمایش نشان داد که اثر سال و اثر منابع کودی بر تمامی صفات اندازه­گیری شده در سطح احتمال یک درصد معنی­دار بودند. اثر سطوح مصرف کود نیتروژن بر تمامی صفات اندازه­گیری شده به‌جز تعداد گل، وزن خشک خامه، میانگین وزن خشک خامه و میانگین وزن خشک کلاله، در سطح احتمال یک درصد معنی­دار بود. اثر منابع کودی بر تمامی صفات اندازه­گیری شده در سطح یک درصد معنی­دار بود، به­طوری­که وزن خشک گلبرگ و کاسبرگ در تیمار کودی بیومیک (7/34 گرم بر مترمربع) به میزان ۵/78 درصد نسبت به تیمار کود شاهد (۵/19 گرم بر مترمربع) بیشترین افزایش را داشت. تیمار کودی ترکیبی سوپرهیومیک + بیومیک در صفت وزن خشک کلاله (5/2 گرم بر مترمربع) بیشترین عملکرد را نسبت به تیمار شاهد (4/1 گرم بر مترمربع) داشت. تیمار کودی سوپرهیومیک وزن خشک کلاله را ۹/49 درصد نسبت به تیمار شاهد افزایش داد. به نظر می‌رسد استفاده از کودهای هیومیک، زیستی و نانو تأثیر خوبی بر عملکرد زعفران داشته است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>This study is aimed at investigating the effect of using humic, bio and nano fertilizers and levels of nitrogen fertilizers in flower yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) at the University of Torbat Heydarieh research farm located in Zaveh in 2014-2015. Treatments consisted of three levels of nitrogen application and use of fertilizer sources as the main factor, including Bioumik, Super Humic, combined Super Humic and Bioumik, Humi Ful, Nitrokara and no fertilizer as sub plots as split plot based on randomized complete block design with 18 treatments and three replications. Analysis of data showed that the effect of year and fertilizer sources on all traits measured was significant. The effect of nitrogen treatments was significant (at 1%) except on number of flowers, dry style, mean dry weight stigma, and mean dry weight. Fertilizer sources increased all measured traits significantly. Application of Biomic increased petals and sepals dry weight (736.34 g/m2) by 46.78% in comparison with the control (464.19 g/m2). The highest dry weight stigma (524.2 g/m2) was seen in Super Humic + Bioumik treatment compared to the control group (443.1 g/m2). Super Humic treatment increased dry weight stigma by 86.49% relative to control. It seems that the use of humic, bio and nano fertilizers has a good effect on saffron performance.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>329</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>344</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی اصغر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ارمک</Family>
						<NameE>Aliasghar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Armak</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، گروه تولیدات گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، گروه تولیدات گیاهی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aliasghararmak@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسن</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فیضی</Family>
						<NameE>Hassan</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Feizi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی و پژوهشگر پژوهشکده زعفران، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hasanfeizi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مسعود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>علی پناه</Family>
						<NameE>Masoud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Alipanah</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار دانشگاه تربت حیدریه، گروه تولیدات گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار دانشگاه تربت حیدریه، گروه تولیدات</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>alipanah.masoud@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تغذیه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلاله</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>منابع کودی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Alipoor, Z##. Mahmoodi, S., Behdani, M., and Sayari, M. 2013. The effect of corm weight and use of fertilizers on features and cream saffron stigmas (Crocus sativus L.). The second National Congress and conventional organic agriculture. (In Persian).##Amiri, M. 2008. Impact of animal manures and chemical fertilizers on yield components of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of American-Eurasian Science 4: 274-279.##Behdani, M. 2005. Ecological zoning and monitoring fluctuations in Khorasan saffron yield. Ph.D thesis of Agriculture (Crop Ecology), Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad. (In Persian).##Cui, H., Sun, C., Liu, Q., Jiang, J., and Gu, W. 2006. Applications of Nanotechnology in Agrochemical Formulation, Perspectives, Challenges and Strategies. Institute of Environment and Sustainable Development in Agriculture, Chinese Academy of agricultural sciences, Beijing, China, pp: 1-6.##Donyanavard, P., Kamgar Haghighi, A., Sepaskhah, A., Karimian, N., and Zand Parsa, SH. 2014. The different levels of irrigation water, manure and urea on the growth and yield of saffron. The third national conference on the latest achievements of scientific and research saffron, University of Torbat Heydarieh. (In Persian).##FAO, 2014. Food and agriculture organization of the United Nations. http://www.faostat.fao.org.##Ghavi, M., Sadr Abadi Haghighi, R., Bakhsh Kalarestaghi, K., and Naghibi, M. 2012.  The effects of biological and chemical fertilizers sprayed on performance and features corms flower (Crocus sativus L.). National Conference on Environment and Plant Production. (In Persian).##Gresta, F., Lombardo, G.M., Siracusa, L., and Ruberto, G. 2008. Effect of mother corm dimension and sowing time on stigma yield, daughter corms and qualitative aspects of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in a Mediterranean environment. Journal of Food Science and Agriculture 88: 1144-1150.##Hemati Kakhki, A., and Hosseini, M. 2003. A Review on 15 Years on Research on Saffron in Khorasan. Institute of Research and Development of Technology. Ferdowsi University of Mashhad Publications. 114p. (In Persian).##Hosseini, M. 1997. The Effect of Foliar Feeding on Increasing the Yield of Saffron. Publication Research Organization for Science and Technology, Institute of Khorasan. (In Persian).##Hun, H.S., Supanjani., Lee, K.D. 2006. Effect of co-inoculation with phosphate and potassium solubilizing bacteria on mineral uptake and growth of pepper and cucumber. Plant Soil Environment 52 (4): 332-338.##     Jahan M., and Jahani, M. 2007. The effects of chemical and organic fertilizers on saffron flowering. Second International Symposium on Saffron Biology and Technology, April 2007.##Khorramdel, S., Koocheki, A., Nassiri Mahallati, M., and Khorasani, R. 2010. Effect of different crop management systems on net primary productivity and relative carbon allocation coefficients for corn (Zea mays L.). Journal of Agroecology 2 (4): 667-680. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A. 2004. Indigenous knowledge in agriculture with particular reference to saffron production in Iran. Acta horticulturae 650: 175-182. (In Persian).##Koocheki, A., Jahani, M., Tabrizi, L., and Mohammad abadi, A. 2011. Evaluate the effectiveness of biological and chemical fertilizers and plant density on yield and characteristics of saffron corm flower (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of soil and water (Agricultural Science and Technology) 25 (1): 196-206. (In Persian).##Koocheki, A., Najib nia, S., and Lellah gani, B. 2009. Evaluating the performance of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) intercropping with cereals, pulses and medicinal herbs. Iran Agricultural Research 7: 175-184. (In Persian with English Summary).##Koocheki, A., Soltani, A., and Azizi, M. 1997. Plant Ecophysiology. The University of Mashhad. 272p.##Kumar, R., Singh, V., Devi, K., Sharma, M., Singh, M.K., and Ahuja, P.S. 2009. State of the art of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) agronomy: A comprehensive review. Food Review International 25: 44-85.##Lai, R. 2007. Soil Science in the Era of Hydrogen Economy and 10 Billion People. the Ohio State University, USA, pp: 1-9.##Ministry of Agriculture-Jahad. 2016. Agricultural Statistics, (Vol. 2). Islamic Republic of Iran, Ministry of Agriculture-Jahad, Press. (In Persian).##Mohammad Poor, J., Ghodsi, M., Esmi, R., Shariatmadari, Z., Adib, M., and Jahedi Poor, S. 2013. Effects of different irrigation and fertilizers on some morphological traits and yield of saffron. Second National Conference on the latest achievements of scientific and research saffron, University of Torbat Heydarieh. (In Persian).##Monreal, C.M. 2010. Nanofertilizers for increased N and P use efficiencies by crops. In summary of information currently provided to MRI concerning applications for round 5 of the Ontario research fund-research excellence program, p: 12-13.##Naderi Darbaghshahi, M.R., Khajebashi, S.M., Banitabar, S.A., and Dehdashti, S.M. 2009. Effects of planting method, density and depth on yield and production period of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Isfahan region. Seed Plant Journal 24: 643-657. (In Persian with English Summary).##Omidi, H., Naghdi abadi, H., Golzad, A., Torabi, H., and Fotokian, M. 2009. Chemical and biological nitrogen fertilizer effect on yield and quality of saffron (Crocus sativus L.). Journal of Medicinal Plants 8 (2): 99-109.  (In Persian with English Summary).##Rahimi daghi, S., mahmodi, S., bakhshi, M., and Sayari, M. 2013. Assessment shows consumption of fertilizer, pesticides and water and the impact of them on the performance of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in the city of Birjand and Kashmar. The first national congress on medicinal plants and sustainable agriculture, Faculty of Mofateh martyr. (In Persian).##Ramezani, A. 2000. Effect of corm weight on saffron yield in Neyshabur climate. Msc dissertation, faculty of agriculture, the University of Tarbiat modarres Tehran, Iran. (In Persian with English Summary).##Ranjith, N.K., Sasikala, C., and Ramana, C.V. 2007. Catabolism of l-phenylalanine and l-tyrosine by Rhodobacter sphaeroides OU5 occurs through 3,4-dihydroxyphenylalanine. Research Microbiology 158: 506-511.##Rezvani Moghaddam, P., Amiri, P., and Ehyayi, H. 2014. The effect of plant growth promoting rhizobacteria and different amounts of mushroom compost on flower yield and properties of saffron corms (Crocus sativus L.) in an organic farming system. Journal of Horticultural Science (Agricultural Science and Technology) 28 (2): 208-199. (In Persian with English Summary).##Sharif, M., Khattak, R.A., and Sarir, M.S. 2002. Effect of different levels of lignitic coal drived humic acid on growth of maize plants. Communication in Soil Science and Plant Analysis 33: 3567-3580.##Sidari, M., Atina, E., Francioso, O., Tugnoli, V., and Nardi, S. 2006. Biological activity of humic  substances     is related to their chemical structure. Soil Science Society of America Journal 71: 75-85.##Teimori, S., Behdani, M.A., Ghaderi, M.G., and Sadeghi, B. 2013. Investigation on the effect of organic and chemical fertilizers on morphological and agronomic of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) corm criteria. Journal of Saffron Research 1 (1): 36-47. (In Persian with English Summary).##Unal, M., and Cavusoglu, A. 2005. The effect of various nitrogen fertilizers on saffron (Crocus sativus L.) yield. Akdeniz Univ. Ziraaf Fak. Dergisi 18 (2): 257-260.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>اثر محلول‌پاشی نانو کودهای مختلف بر برخی صفات فیزیولوژیک زعفران (.Crocus sativus L)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Effect of Foliar Application of Chemical Nano-Fertilizers on Physiological Traits of Saffron (.Crocus sativus L)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>به منظور بررسی تأثیر نانو کودهای مختلف بر برخی صفات فیزیولوژیک زعفران، آزمایشی در قالب طرح بلوک­های کامل تصادفی با شش تیمار و سه تکرار در دانشگاه ملایر در سال زراعی 94-1393 انجام شد. تیمار­های آزمایشی شامل نانو کودهای تک عنصره­ی آهن، منگنز، بُر، پتاسیم، روی و شاهد بودند که با غلظت دو در هزار و به­صورت محلول­پاشی جهت بهبود وضعیت تغذیه گیاه مورد استفاده قرار گرفتند. نتایج به‌دست‌آمده نشان داد که اثر محلول­پاشی نانو کودها روی میزان محتوای نسبی آب، قند احیاکننده و قندهای غیر احیاکننده معنی­دار بود. نانو کودهای مختلف از نظر کلروفیل a و کلروفیل کل اختلاف معنی‌داری با تیمار شاهد نداشتند با این­وجود بیشترین میزان کلروفیل a (mg.g-1 Fw 53/1) در تیمار نانو کود آهن و کمترین میزان آن (mg.g-1 Fw 93/0) در تیمار نانو کود منگنز مشاهده شد. تیمارهای آزمایشی تأثیر معنی‌داری بر میزان کلروفیل b و آنزیم­های کاتالاز و پراکسیداز نداشتند. علاوه بر این تأثیر نانو کودهای مختلف بر میزان پروتئین و فنل معنی­دار بود. بیشترین میزان پروتئین (mg.g-1 Fw 56/1) در تیمارهای نانو کود پتاسیم و بُر با 12 درصد افزایش نسبت به شاهد مشاهده شد و کمترین میزان پروتئین برگ (mg.g-1 Fw 36/1) در تیمار نانو کود آهن به دست آمد که نسبت به تیمار شاهد سه درصد کاهش نشان داد. بیشترین میزان فنل (mg.g-1 Dw 27/0) با 5/10 درصد افزایش نسبت به شاهد در تیمار نانو کود منگنز مشاهده شد و فقط اختلاف این تیمار با شاهد معنی­دار بود. بر اساس نتایج این آزمایش به نظر می­رسد که کاربرد کلیه نانو کودهای مورد مطالعه با غلظت یکسان از لحاظ علمی قابل توصیه نیست.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In order to investigate the effects of different types of nano-fertilizers on some of the physiological characteristics of saffron (i.e. antioxidant enzymes, reducing and non-reducing sugars, photosynthetic pigments, total phenol content and relative water content of leaf) the current experiment was conducted at Malayer University during 2014-2015 growing season. The study was performed based on randomized complete block design (RCBD) with six treatments and three replications. The experimental treatments were control and five different types of nano-fertilizers (iron: Fe, boron: B, manganese: Mn, potassium: K and zinc: Zn). The effects of experimental treatments on relative water content, protein and total phenol content, reducing and non-reducing sugars were significant but there was no significant effect on chlorophyll b, leaf carotenoids, Catalase and Proxidase activity. Although the difference between nano-fertilizers and control treatment for chlorophyll a and also total chlorophyll was not significant but the highest amount of chlorophyll a (1.53 mg.g-1 Fw) measured in Fe treatment and the lowest amount (0.93 mg.g-1 Fw) observed in Mn treatment. Based on results, all of the experimental treatment increased the relative water content of leaf comparing to control. The highest amount of total phenol content (0.27 mg.g-1 FW) with 10.5% increase compared to control observed in Mn treatment and just the difference of this treatment with control treatment was significant. By application of Zn, Mn, K and B nano-fertilizer leaf protein content comparing to control treatment significantly increased whereas the difference between Fe and control wasn’t significant. The highest concentration of leaf protein (1.56 mg.g-1 Fw) with 12% increase compared to control treatment observed in K and B treatments whereas the lowest concentration (1.36 mg.g-1 Fw) with 3% decrease compared to control was related to Fe treatment. The different response of studied characteristic to application of various nano-fertilizer showed that different physiological traits hadn’t the similar sensitivity to all of mineral nutrients therefore application of entire nano-fertilizers with the same concentration isn’t scientifically recommendable</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>345</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>359</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مجید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رستمی</Family>
						<NameE>Majid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Rostami</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار فیزیولوژی گیاهان زراعی، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشگاه ملایر</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار فیزیولوژی گیاهان زراعی، گروه زراعت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>majidrostami7@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>معصومه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ملکی</Family>
						<NameE>Masoumeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Maleki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار فیزیولوژی گیاهی، گروه زیست شناسی، دانشگاه ملایر</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار فیزیولوژی گیاهی، گروه زیست شناسی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>masoumehmaleki@khayam.ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عفتی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Effati</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد، فیزیولوژی گیاهی، گروه زیست شناسی، دانشگاه ملایر</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد، فیزیولوژی گیاهی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>effati1990@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آنزیم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تغذیه گیاه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قند</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلروفیل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Akrami, M.R., Malakouti, M.J., and Keshavarz, P. 2014. Study of flower and stigma yield of saffron as affected by potassium and zinc fertilizers in Khorasan Razavi Province. Journal of Saffron Research 2 (1): 85-96. (In Persian with English Summary).##Al-Bishri, W., and Nabil Danial, E. 2013. Comparative study on the antioxidant, antimicrobial activities and total phenolic content of selected seeds from Saudi Arabia. Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment 11 (2): 202-207.##Alscher, R.G., Erturk, N., and Heath, L.S. 2002. Role of superoxide dismutases (SODs) in controlling oxidative stress in plants. Journal of Experimental Botany 53 (372): 1331-1341.##Amirghasemi, T. 2001. Saffron, Red Gold of Iran. Ayandegan Publication. Tehran. (In Persian).##Arif, M., Asifshehzad, M., Bashir, F., Tasneem, M., Yasin, G., and Iqbal, M. 2012. Boron, zinc and microtone effects on growth, chlorophyll contents and yield attributes in rice (Oryza sativa L.) cultivars. African Journal of Biotechnology 11 (48): 10851-10858.##Athar, H., and Ashraf, M. 2005. Photosynthesis under drought stress. In M. Pessarakli (eds). Handbook of Photosynthesis. CRC Press, New York. p. 795-810.##Babaeian, M., Haydari, M., and Ghanbari, A. 2009. Effects of foliar micronutrient application on osmotic adjustments, grain yield and yield components in sunflower (Alster cultivar) under water stress at three stages. Journal of Water and Soil Science 12 (46): 119-129. (In Persian with English Summary).##Bannister, J.V., Bannister, W.H., and Rotills, G. 1987. Aspects of the structure, function and application of superoxide dismutase. CRC Critical Reviews in Biochemistry 22: 110-180.##Benlloch-Gonzalez, M., Arquero, O., Fournier, J.M., Barranco, D., and Benlloch, M. 2008. K+ starvation inhibits water stress- induced stomatal closure. Journal of Plant Physiology 165: 623-630.##Bradford, M.M. 1976. A rapid and sensitive method for the quantitation of microgram quantities of protein utilizing the principles of protein-dye binding. Analytical Biochemistry 72: 248-254.##Bybordy, A., and Mamedov, G. 2010. Evaluation of application methods efficiency of zinc and iron for canola (Brassica napus L.). Notulae Scientia Biologicae 2 (1): 94-103.##Curie, C., and Briat, J.F. 2003. Iron transport and signaling in plants. Annual Review of Plant Biology 54: 183-206.##Dubois, M., Gilles, K., Hamilton, A., Rebers, J.K., and Smith, P.A.F. 1956. Colorimetric method for determination of sugars and related substances. Analytical Chemistry 28 (3): 350-356.##Fanaei, H.R., Galavi, M., Kafi, M., and Ghanbari Bonjar, A. 2009. Amelioration of water stress by potassium fertilizer in two oilseed species. International Journal of Plant Production 3 (2): 41-54.##Fathi Amirkhiz, K., Amini Dehaghi, M., Modares Sanavy, S.A.M., Rezazadeh, A.R., and Heshmati, S. 2011. Effect of iron application on enzymatic activity, grain yield and oil content of safflower under water deficit conditions. Iranian Journal of Crop Sciences 13 (3): 452-465. (In Persian with English Summary).## Fathi Amirkhiz, K., Amini Dehaghi, M., and Heshmati, S. 2015. Study the effect of iron chelate on chlorophyll content, photochemical efficiency and some biochemical traits in Safflower under deficit irrigation condition. Iranian Journal of Field Crop Science 46: 137-145. (In Persian with English Summary).##Gogorcena, Y., Iturbe-Ormaetxe, I., Escuredo, P., and Becana, M. 1995. Antioxidant defenses against activated oxygen in pea nodules subjected to water stress. Plant Physiology 108: 753-759.##Grotz, N., and Guerinot, M.L. 2006. Molecular aspects of Cu, Fe and Zn homestasis in plants. Biochemistry and Biophysica Acta 763 (7): 595-608.##Hajiboland, R., and Amirazad, H. 2010. Drought tolerance in Zn-deficient red cabbage (Brassica oleracea L. var. capitata f. rubra) plants. Horticultural Science 37: 88-98.##Khodary, S.E.A. 2004. Effect of salicylic acid on the growth, photosynthesis and carbohydrate metabolism in salt stressed maize plants. International Journal of Agriculture and Biology 6: 5-8.##Khorasani, R., Rezvani Moghaddam, P., and Hassanzadeh Aval, F. 2013. Effect of concentration, time and frequency of foliar applications on vegetative growth and production of replacement corms of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) by using a complete nutrient solution. In Second National Conference on the Newest Scientific and Research Findings on Saffron. Torbat-e- Heydarieh. Iran, 30 October 2013, p. 40. (In Persian).##Lichtenthaler, H., and Wellburm, A.R. 1983. Determination of total carotenoids and chlorophyll a and b of leaf extracts in different solvents. Biochemical Society Transactions 603: 591-593.##Marschner, H. 2011. Mineral nutrition of higher plants. 3rd ed. Academic Press.##McDonald, S., Prenzler, P.D., Autolovich, M., and Robards, K. 2001. Phenolic content and antioxidant activity of olive extracts. Food Chemistry 73:73-84.##Mittler, R., Vanderauwera, S., Gollery, M., and Breusegem, F.V. 2004. Reactive oxygen gene network of plants. Trends in Plant Science 9: 490-498.##Moeinian, M.R., Zargari, K., and Hasanpour, J. 2011. Effect of boron foliar application on quality characteristic and growth parameters of wheat grain under drought stress. American-Eurasian Journal of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences 10 (4): 593-599.##Morshedi, A., Malakouti, M.J., and Rezaei, H. 2001. Effect of iron foliar application on yield, quality and quantity characteristic and enrichment of canola grains in Bardisar, Kerman. Journal of soil and water 12: 56-68. (In Persian).##Mukhopadhyay, S.S. 2014. Nanotechnology in agriculture: prospects and constraints. Nanotechnology, Science and Applications 7: 63-71.##Nelson, N. 1944. A photometric adaptation of the somogyi method for the determination of glucose. The Journal of Biological Chemistry 153: 375-380.##Peivandi, M., Kamali Jamakani, Z., and Mirza, D. 2011. The Effect of Nano Fe Chelate and Fe Chelate on the Growth and Activity of some Antioxidant in summer savory (Satureja hortensis). New Cellular and Molecular Biotechnology Journal 5: 25-32. (In Persian with English Summary).##Peivandi, M., Parandeh, E., and Mirza, D. 2011. The effect of nano iron chelated with iron chelate on growth parameters and activity of antioxidant enzymes Basil (Ocimum basilicum). New Cellular and Molecular Biotechnology Journal 4: 89-98. (In Persian with English Summary).##Qasim, M., Ashraf, M.M., Jamil, A.M., Rehman, Y.S.U., and Rha, E.S. 2003. Water relations and gas exchange properties in some elite canola (Brassica napus L.) lines under salt stress. Annals of Applied Biology 142 (3): 307-316. ##Ranieri, A., Castagna, A., Baldan, B., and Soldatini, G.F. 2001. Iron deficiency differently affects peroxidase isoforms in sunflower. Journal of Experimental Botany 52 (354): 25-35.##Rostami, M., and Ahmadi, A.R. 2014. Investigation the effect of nitrogen forms and split fertilization on grain yield and nitrogen content of two corn hybrids. Agronomy Journal (Pajouhesh &amp; Sazandegi) 10: 40-46. (In Persian with English Summary).##Rostami, M., and Mohammadi, H. 2013. Effects of planting date and corm density on growth and yield of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) under Malayer climatic conditions. Journal of Agroecology 5: 27-38. (In Persian with English Summary).## Sepaskhah, A.R., and Kamgar-Haghighi, A.A. 2009. Saffron irrigation regime. International Journal of Plant Production 3 (1): 1-16.##Shafea, L. Saffari, M., Emam, Y., and Mohammad Nejad, Gh. 2011. Effect of nitrogen and zinc fertilizers on leaf zinc and chlorophyll contents, grain yield and chemical composition of two maize (Zea mays L.) hybrids. Seed and Plant Production Journal 27 (2): 235-246. (In Persian).##Shigeoka, S., Ishikawa, T., Tamoi, M., Miyagawa, Y., Takeda, T., Yabuta, Y., and Yoshimura, K. 2002. Regulation and function of ascorbate peroxidase isoenzymes. Journal of Experimental Botany 53 (372): 1305-1319.##Sun, B., Jing, Y., Chen, K., Song, L., Chen, F., and Zhang, L. 2007. Protective effect of nitric oxide on iron deficiency-induced oxidative stress in maize (Zea mays). Journal of Plant Physiology 164: 536-543.##Tavallali, V., Rahemi, M., Maftoun, M., Panahi, B., Karimi, S., Ramezanian, A., and Vaezpour, M. 2009. Zinc influence and salt stress on photosynthesis, water relations, and carbonic anhydrase activity in pistachio. Scientia horticulturae 123 (2): 272-279.##Welch, R.M.1995. Micronutrient Nutrition of Plants. Critical Reviews in Plant Sciences 14: 49-82.##Zabihi, H.R., and Feizi, H. 2014. Saffron response to the rate of two kinds of potassium fertilizers. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 2 (3): 191-198. (In Persian with English Summary).##Zare Dehabadi, S., Asrar, Z., and Mehrabani, M. 2008. Effect of zinc on growth and some physiological and biochemical parameters of spearmint (Mentha spicata L.). Iranian Journal of Plant Biology 20 (3): 230-241. (In Persian with English Summary).##Zhu, H., Han, J., Xiao, J.Q., and Jin, Y. 2008. Uptake, translocation and accumulation of manufactured iron oxide nanoparticles by pumpkin plants. Journal of Environmental Monitoring 10: 713-717.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ساخت و ارزیابی دستگاه تک‌ساز ردیفی گل زعفران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Design, construction and evaluation of a row singulator for saffron flowers</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>جداسازی کلاله از بقیه اجزای گل یکی از مهم‌ترین چالش‌ها در فرآیند تولید زعفران تجاری می‌باشد. مراحل جداسازی ماشینی کلاله از یک توده گل زعفران شامل: الف) تک سازی گل‌ها، ب) ردیف‌کردن گل‌ها، ج) برش دم (قسمت اضافی) گل‌ها و د) جداکردن گلبرگ و پرچم می‌باشد. درواقع بدون تک­سازی و جدا کردن تک‌تک گل‌ها از هم، جداسازی ماشینی کلاله نمی‌تواند انجام شود. به دلیل اهمیت این مرحله از جداسازی گل زعفران در این تحقیق یک دستگاه دست‌ساز آزمایشی برای تنک‌سازی و ردیف کردن گل زعفران ساخته شد، به‌طوری که قابلیت کار و نصب با دستگاه‌های برش و جداسازی کلاله از گل و تبدیل به مقیاس صنعتی را نیز داشته باشد. برای این منظور از یک استوانه بردارنده برای تک‌سازی گل‌ها و از یک سطح شیب‌دار و نوار نقاله برای ردیف کردن گل‌های زعفران استفاده شد. دستگاه ساخته شده ازنقطه‌نظر بازده تک سازی و تلفات مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفت. به این‌ منظور از سه نوع گل زعفران (غنچه، باز دم­کوتاه و دم­بلند)، سه سرعت دورانی استوانه بردارنده (6، 12 و 5/21 دور بر دقیقه)، سه میزان مکش (30، 70 و 100 میلی‌متر جیوه) و چهار قطر داخلی سوراخ انگشتی‌های مکشی (2 تا 5 میلی‌متر) با سه تکرار استفاده گردید. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد که به‌طورکلی، بیش‌ترین بازده تک‌سازی برای گل‌های زعفران باز دم­کوتاه برابر 75 درصد، در قطر سوراخ داخلی انگشتی‌های مکشی 5 میلی‌متر و میزان مکش 100 میلی‌متر جیوه در سرعت دورانی 6 دور بر دقیقه به‌دست می‌آید. برای ارزیابی عملکرد ردیف‌کردن گل زعفران، تعداد 100 عدد گل زعفران با طول 5 سانتی‌متر انتخاب شدند و در 5 تکرار آزمایش گردید که میانگین ردیف‌سازی با جهت صحیح گل‌ها برابر 84 درصد بدست آمد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Separation of stigma from petals is one of the required tasks in saffron production. The mechanical separation of saffron flowers may be performed through the following steps: I) singulation of the flowers ii) aligning the flowers iii) cutting the style (Konje) and iv) separating the stigma from the petals. Because of the importance of saffron flower separation, a prototype device was constructed in this project for singulating and aligning of saffron flowers, prior to the cutting operation. This device can also be installed to work with other cutting and separating equipment and produce on an industrial scale. A pickup vacuum cylinder was used for singulating the flowers and an inclined V-shaped surface was employed for aligning of saffron flowers. The constructed apparatus was evaluated from the standpoint of singling efficiency and losses. For this purpose, three types of saffron flowers (buds, open short tail and long tail), three rotational speeds of pickup cylinder (6, 12 and 21.5 rpm), three levels of suction (30, 70 and 100 mm Hg), and four different inner diameters of finger’s nozzle (2, 3, 4 and 5 mm) were used with three replications. The results of analysis on the constructed device showed that the highest efficiency (75%) is observed for short tailopen saffron flowers with 5 mm inner diameter of sucking nozzles, suction of 100 mm Hg and the rotational speed of 6 rpm. To evaluate the performance of flower aligning, 100 saffron flowers with an average length of 5 cm were selected and tested with 5 replications. The average aligning with the correct direction obtained was equal to 84%.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>361</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>377</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حامد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بخشی</Family>
						<NameE>hamed</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>bakhshi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد گروه مهندسی مکانیک بیوسیستم، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد گروه مهندسی مکانیک</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hamedbakhshy@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عباسپور فرد</Family>
						<NameE>Mohamad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Abaspour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مهندسی مکانیک بیوسیستم، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مهندسی مکانیک بیوسیستم، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abaspour@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سعیدی راد</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Saeidirad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار بخش تحقیقات فنی و مهندسی کشاورزی، مرکز تحقیقات و آموزش کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی خراسان رضوی، سازمان تحقیقات آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، مشهد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار بخش تحقیقات فنی و مهندسی کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>saiedirad@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آق خانی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Aghkhani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مهندسی مکانیک بیوسیستم، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مهندسی مکانیک بیوسیستم، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aghkhani@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رقیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پورباقر</Family>
						<NameE>Roghayeh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>pourbagher</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری گروه مهندسی مکانیک بیوسیستم، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری گروه مهندسی مکانیک بیوسیستم،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>paria_pourbagher@mail.um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تک سازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جداسازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ردیف کردن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گل زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Alishahi, A., and Shamsi, M. 2012. Saffron separation from other parts of the flowers in the wind tunnel and its assessment with fuzzy logic. Journal of Agricultural Machinery 2 (2): 120-126. (In Persian with English Summary).##Bakhshi, H. 2015. Design, construction and evaluation of a row singulator for saffron flowers. Msc. dissertation, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran. (In Persian with English Summary).##Emadi, B. 2008. Design of a wind tunnel for separating flower parts of saffron. In 9th Global Congress on Manufacturing and Management-GCMM, November 2008.‏##Esfandiari, M., Sharini, M., Gholipour, A., and Rahmati, A. 2011. Category and qualitative separation flower using a appearance of the image features. In Second National Conference on Computer Engineering and Information Technology, Hamedan, Iran, 17 february, 2011. (In Persian).##Graciaa, L., Perez-Vidalb, C., and Gracia-Lo´pezc, C. 2009. Automated cutting system to obtain the stigmas of the saffron flower. Biosystems Engineering 104 (4): 8-17.##Mohaimani, S.M., and Abbasi, M. 2007. Construction separation of stigma saffron the mechanical method. ISME, Amirkabir University of Technology, Tehran, Iran, 15-17 may, 2007.  (In Persian).##Paschino, F., and Gambella, F. 2008. First contribute to the mechanization string of saffron flowers (Croccus Sativus L.). International Conference, Italy, 15-17 September, 2008.##Saeidirad, M.H., Zaryfneshat, S., Nia, A.M., and Nazarzadeh, S. 2013. Investigation and research in the development of mechanization and to provide a best practice and the pattern of mechanized operations in the saffron harvest. Engineering Researches Center of Agriculture and Natural Resources of Khorasan Razavi. (In Persian).##Shamsi, M., Mazloomzadeh, M., Asghari, J., and Mohamadian, A. 2012. Review and assess the possibility of separating blow stigma from saffron flower. In Seventh National Congress of Agricultural Machinery Engineering and Mechanization, shiraz, Iran, 4-6 September, 2011. (In Persian).##Valeghozhdi, H., Hassan Beygi Bidgoli, H.B., Saeidirad, M.H., and Kianmehr, M.H. 2010. Shear strength of stem and picking force for saffron flowers. Agricultural Engineering Research, 11 (3): 41-54. (In Persian with English Summary).##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>طبقه‌بندی اقلیمی و تعیین مناطق مستعد کشت زعفران با استفاده از الگوریتم‌های داده‌کاوی در سطح استان خراسان رضوی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Climatic zonation and land suitability determination for saffron in Khorasan-Razavi province using data mining algorithms</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>پیش­بینی عملکرد محصولات کشاورزی، نقش مهمی در برنامه­ریزی صادرات، واردات، خرید تضمینی، قیمت­گذاری، سود مطمئن و افزایش بهره­وری کشاورزی دارد. عملکرد محصولات، تابع پارامترهای متعددی از جمله اقلیم است. در این تحقیق، عملکرد زعفران در استان خراسان رضوی توسط الگوریتم‌های طبقه­بندی شامل شبکه­های عصبی مصنوعی، مدل‌های رگرسیونی، درخت خطی محلی، درخت تصمیم، آنالیز تشخیص، جنگل تصادفی، ماشین بردار پشتیبان و آنالیز نزدیک‌ترین همسایه با استفاده از 11 پارامتر اقلیمی طی دوره 20 ساله زراعی (88-1368) ارزیابی شد. نتایج نشان داد که تعداد کمی از پارامترهای اقلیمی، بر عملکرد زعفران تأثیر دارند. پارامترهای دمای حداقل، میانگین و حداکثر و بارش به ترتیب بیشترین همبستگی مثبت و پارامترهای رطوبت مطلق حداکثر، رطوبت نسبی ساعت 6:30، ساعات آفتابی، رطوبت نسبی ساعت 18:30، تبخیر، رطوبت نسبی ساعت 12:30 و رطوبت مطلق حداقل نیز به­ترتیب بیشترین همبستگی منفی را با مناطق کشت زعفران داشتند. همچنین در طبقه­بندی مناطق کشت زعفران، آنالیز تشخیص و ماشین بردار پشتیبان، از دقت بالاتری برخوردار بودند. بین مناطق کشت زعفران و میزان عملکرد محصول همبستگی نسبتاً مناسبی با ضریب همبستگی 38/0 به‌دست آمد. بین مناطق کشت و پارامترهای اقلیمی همبستگی بالایی برخوردار است و آنالیز نزدیک‌ترین همسایه با ضرایب تعیین برابر ۱ و 94/0 در مراحل آموزش و آزمون، با دقت بالایی مناطق کشت را طبقه­بندی نماید، اما در پیش­بینی میزان عملکرد محصول بر اساس پارامترهای اقلیمی، دقت مدل­ها نسبتاً پایین بود (متوسط ضریب تعیین برابر 48/0 و 05/0 در مراحل آموزش و آزمون) و آنالیز نزدیک‌ترین همسایه، بالاترین دقت پیش­بینی را در مراحل آموزش و آزمون (به ترتیب ضریب تعیین برابر ۱ و 17/0) نشان داد. طبق یافته­های تحقیق، می­توان با استفاده از پارامترهای اقلیمی و الگوریتم­های داده­کاوی، به‌طور مناسب اقدام به تفکیک مناطق کشت نمود و با شناسایی مناطقی که اقلیم آن‌ها مشابه مناطق با میزان عملکرد بالا است، مناطق مستعد کشت زعفران را شناسایی نمود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Yield prediction for agricultural crops plays an important role in export-import planning, purchase guarantees, pricing, secure profits and increasing in agricultural productivity. Crop yield is affected by several parameters especially climate. In this study, the saffron yield in the Khorasan-Razavi province was evaluated by different classification algorithms including artificial neural networks, regression models, local linear trees, decision trees, discriminant analysis, random forest, support vector machine and nearest neighbor analysis. These algorithms analyzed data for 20 years (1989-2009) including 11 climatological parameters. The results showed that a few numbers of climatological parameters affect the saffron yield. The minimum, mean and maximum of temperature, had the highest positive correlations and the relative humidity of 6.5h, sunny hours, relative humidity of 18.5h, evaporation, relative humidity of 12.5h and absolute humidity had the highest negative correlations with saffron cultivation areas, respectively. In addition, in classification of saffron cultivation areas, the discriminant analysis and support vector machine had higher accuracies. The correlation between saffron cultivation area and saffron yield values was relatively high (r=0.38). The nearest neighbor analysis had the best prediction accuracy for classification of cultivation areas. For this algorithm the coefficients of determination were 1 and 0.944 for training and testing stages, respectively. However, the algorithms accuracy for prediction of crop yield from climatological parameters was low (the average coefficients of determination equal to 0.48 and 0.05 for training and testing stages). The best algorithm i.e. nearest neighbor analysis had coefficients of determination equal to 1 and 0.177 for saffron yield prediction. Results showed that, using climatological parameters and data mining algorithms can classify cultivation areas. By this way it is possible to identify areas that have similar climate to prone areas and recognize suitable areas for cultivation.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>379</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>392</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بشیری</Family>
						<NameE>mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bashiri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مرتع و آبخیزداری، دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه تربت‌حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مرتع و آبخیزداری، دانشکده کشاورزی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>me.bashiri@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ماروسی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Maroosi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه کامپیوتر و فناوری اطلاعات، دانشکده فنی و مهندسی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه کامپیوتر و فناوری اطلاعات،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ali_maroosi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امیر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سالاری</Family>
						<NameE>Amir</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Salari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>salari.1361@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قدوسی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghodoosi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مربی گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشکده فنی و مهندسی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مربی گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشکده فنی و مهندسی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.ghodoosi@torbath.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پارامترهای اقلیمی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توسعه کشت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>داده کاوی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شاخص آماری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد محصول</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abraham, A. 2005. Artificial neural networks, Presented in book: Handbook of Measuring System Design, Oklahoma State University, Stillwater, USA. pp. 902-908.##Alvarez, R. 2009. Predicting average regional yield and production of wheat in the argentine pampas by an artificial neural network approach. European Journal of Agronomy 30 (2): 70-77.##Ashrafi, S. 2010. Precipitation classification of northwest of Iran using cluster analysis and discriminate analysis. Journal of Climate Research 1 (3-4): 27-44. (In Persian).##Assaleh, K., Shanableh, T., and Kheil, Y.A. 2013. Group method of data handling for modeling magnetorheological dampers. Intelligent Control and Automation 4: 70-79.##Azadeh, A., Ghaderi, S.F., Anvari, M., and Saberi, M. 2006. Measuring performance electric power generations using artificial neural networks and fuzzy clustering. Proceedings of the 32nd Annual Conference of the IEEE Industrial Electronics Society (IECON’06), Conservatoire National des Arts and Metiers, Paris, France.##Bagheri, S., Gheysari, M., Ayoubi, Sh., and Lavaee, N. 2012. Silage maize yield prediction using artificial neural networks. Journal of Plant Production 19 (4): 77-96. (In Persian).##Bashiri, M., and Salari, A. 2016. Using geostatistics for zoning prone areas of saffron cultivation in Razavi-Khorasan province based on climatological parameters. Journal of Saffron Agronomy and Technology 4 (2): 155-167. (In Persian).##Bashiri, M., Seyedi, S.M., and Tosan, M. 2014. The effect of sunny hours numbers on saffron yield in Khorasan-Razavi province. 3rd National Congress on Saffron Scientific-Research Achievements, Torbat Heydarieh, 26-27 November 2014, 3pp. (In Persian).##Basu, J.K., Bhattacharyya, D., and Kim, T.H. 2010. Use of artificial neural network in pattern recognition. International Journal of Software Engineering and its Applications 4 (2): 23-34.##Breiman, L. 2001. Random forests. Machine Learning Journal 45 (1): 5-32.##Christopher, J., and Burges, C.A. 1998. Tutorial on support vector machines for pattern recognition. Journal of Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery 2: 121-167.##Coppersmith, D., Hong, S.J., and Hosking, J.R. 1999. Partitioning nominal attributes in decision trees. Journal of Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery 3 (2): 197–217.##Coulibaly, P., Anctil, F., Aravena, R., and Bobee, B. 2001. Artificial neural networks modelling of water table depth fluctuations. Water Resources Research 37 (4): 885-896.##Damangir, H. 2001. Training artificial neural network dynamics and its application in real time prediction of floods. M.Sc thesis, Shiraz University. (In Persian).##Ebrahimkhani, S., Afzali, M., and Shokoohi, A. 2012. Weather and road accidents factors using data mining algorithms. Zanjan Law Students Journal 1 (1): 112-125. (In Persian).## Golabi, M.R., Akhondali, A.M., and Radmanesh, F. 2013. Comparison of the performance of different neural networks algorithm functions in simulation of seasonal precipitation, Case study:  Selected stations of Khuzestan province. Journal of Geographical Sciences 13 (30): 151-169. (In Persian).##Hajian, A., Zomorrodian, H., Styles, P., Greco, F., and Lucas, C. 2012. Depth estimation of cavities from microgravity data using a new approach: the local linear model tree (LOLIMOT). Near Surface Geophysics Journal 10 (3): 221-234.##Hartmann, B., Ebert, T., Fischer, T., Belz, J., Kampmann, G., and Nelles, O. 2012a. LMNtool - Toolbox zum automatischen Trainieren lokaler Modellnetze. 22nd Workshop of Computational Intelligence, Dortmund, Germany, p. 341-355.##Hartmann, B., Ebert, T., Fischer, T., Belz, J., Kampmann, G., and Nelles, O. 2012b. LMN-Tool: Matlab-Toolbox for Local Model Networks. Siegen University, Deutschland.##Hosseini, M., Mollafilabi, A., and Nassiri, M. 2008. Spatial and temporal patterns in Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) yield of Khorasan province and their relationship with long term weather variation. Journal of Iranian Field Crop Research 6 (1): 79-88. (In Persian).##Imrie, C.E., Dean, S., and Korre, A. 2000. River flow using artificial neural network: generalization beyond the calibration range. Journal of Hydrology 233 (1-4): 138-153.##Islam, S., and Kothart, R. 2000. Artificial neural networks in remote sensing of hydrologic processes. Journal of Hydrologic Engineering 5 (2): 138-144.##Johnson, R.A., and Wichern, W.D. 2008. Applied multivariate statistical analysis (6th Edition), Upper Saddle River, NJ, USA, 800 p.##Kalantari, K.h. 2008. Processing and analysis of data on socio-economic research using SPSS software. Tehran, Saba Farhang, 388 p. (In Persian).##Kaul, M., Hill, R.L., and Walthall, C. 2005. Artificial neural networks for corn and soybean yield prediction. Journal of Agricultural System 85 (1): 1-18.##Khoshgoftaar, T.M., Golawala, M., and Van Hulse, J. 2007. An empirical study of learning from imbalanced data using random forest. Proceedings of the 19th IEEE Conference on Tools with Artificial Intelligence 2: 310-317.##Landeras, G., Ortiz-Barredo, A., and Lopez, J.J. 2009. Forecasting weekly evapotranspiration with ARIMA and artificial neural network models. Irrigation and Drainage Engineering, American Society of Civil Engineers 135 (3): 323-334.##Loh, W.Y. 2011. Classification and regression trees. Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews: Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery 1 (1):14-23.##Madala, H.R., and Ivakhnenko, A.G. 1974. Inductive learning algorithms for complex system modeling. Boca Raton: CRC, 373 pp.##Meng, X., Zhang, Z., and Xu, X. 2014. A novel K-Nearest neighbor algorithm based on I-Divergence with application to soil moisture estimation in maize field. Journal of Software 9 (4): 841-846.##Merdun, H., Çınar, O., Meral, R., and Apan, M. 2006. Comparison of artificial neural network and regression pedotransfer functions for prediction of soil water retention and saturated hydraulic conductivity. Soil and Tillage Research 90 (1-2): 108-116.##Moradkhani, H., Hsu, K.L., Gupta, H.V., and Sorooshian, S. 2004. Improved streamflow forecasting using self-organizing radial basis function artificial neural networks. Journal of Hydrology 295 (1-4): 246-262.##Mubiru, J. 2008. Predicting total solar irradiation values using artificial neural networks. Renewable Energy journal 33 (10): 2329-2332.##Mukerji, A., Chatterjee, C., and Raghuwanshi, N.S. 2009. Flood forecasting using ANN, Neuro-fuzzy and Neuro-GA models. Journal of Hydrologic Engineering. American Society of Civil Engineers 14 (6): 647-652.##Pardoe, I., Yin, X., and Cook, R.D. 2007. Graphical tools for quadratic discriminant analysis. Technometrics Journal 49 (2): 172-183.##Pinto, U., Maheshwar, B., Shrestha, S., and Morris, C. 2012. Modeling eutrophication and microbial risks in peri-urban river systems using discriminant function analysis. Water Research Journal 4 (6): 6476- 6488.##Piri, J., Amin, S., Moghaddamnia, A., Keshavarz, A., Han, D., and Remesan, R. 2009. Daily pan evaporation modeling in a hot and dry climate. Journal of Hydrologic Engineering, American Society of Civil Engineers 14 (8): 803-811.##Platt, J. 1998. Sequential minimal optimization: A fast algorithm for training support vector machines. Microsoft Research TechReport, Number MSR-TR-98-14: p. 21.##Rajagopalan, B., and Lall, U. 1999. A k-nearest neighbor simulator for daily precipitation and other variables. Water Resources Research 35 (10): 3089–3101.##Samsudin, R., Saad, P., and Shabri, A. 2008. The GMDH model and its application to forecasting of rice yields. Journal Teknologi Maklumat 20 (4): 113-124.##Shirdeli, A., and Tawassoli, A. 2015. Predicting yield and water use efficiency in saffron using models of artificial neural network based on climate factors and water. Saffron Agronomy and Technology 3 (2): 121-131. (In Persian).##Siemsen, E., Roth, A., and Oliveira, P. 2010. Common method bias in regression models with linear, quadratic, and interaction effects. Organizational Research Methods 13 (3): 456-476.##Smith, B.A., Hoogenboom, G., and McClendon, R.W. 2009. Artificial neural networks for automated year-round temperature prediction. Computers and Electronics in Agriculture 68 (1): 52-61.##Tamura, H., and Kondo, T. 1980. Heuristics free group method of data handling algorithm of generating optimal partial polynomials with application to air pollution prediction. International Journal of Systems Science 11 (9): 1095-1111.##Tauser, J., and Buryan, P. 2011. Exchange Rate Predictions in International Financial Management by Enhanced GMDH Algorithm. Prague Economic Papers 20 (3): 232-249.##Toloei Ashlaghi, A., Poorebrahimi, A., Ebrahimi, M., and Ghasemahmad, L. 2013. Using data mining techniques for prediction breast cancer recurrence. Iranian Journal of Breast Diseases 5 (4): 23-34. (In Persian).##Zealand, C.M., Bum, D.H., and Simonovic, S.P. 1999. Short term stream flow forecasting using Artificial Neural Networks. Journal of Hydrology 214 (1-4): 32-48.##Zhan, Y., Chen, H., and Zhang, G.C. 2006. An optimization algorithm of K-NN classification. IEEE International Conference on Machine Learning and Cybernetics, Dalian, China, pp. 2246-2251.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارزیابی عملکرد مدل هیبرید شبکه عصبی مصنوعی-ﺧﻮد ﺗﻮﺿﻴﺢ ﺟﻤﻌﻲ ﻣﻴﺎﻧﮕﻴﻦ ﻣﺘﺤﺮک (ARIMA-ANN) در پیش‌بینی صادرات زعفران ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Performance evaluation of artificial neural network-autoregressive integrated moving average (ARIMA) hybrid model in forecasting of Iranian saffron export</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>زعفران ایران از لحاظ کمی و کیفی از جایگاه نمایانی در سطح بین­المللی برخوردار است و با بهره­گیری از ظرفیت موجود می­توان درآمدهای صادراتی حاصل از آن را به­طور قابل ‌ملاحظه‌ای افزایش داد. از سوی دیگر، پیش­بینی فروش بر اساس تجزیه ‌وتحلیل سری زمانی یک عنصر بسیار مهم در طراحی و اجرای استراتژی­های بازاریابی در عرصه­ی بین­المللی است. اما رویکرد­های متداول پیش­بینی با نادیده گرفتن ساختار خطی یا غیرخطی داده­ها نتایج دقیقی را ارائه نمی­دهند. لذا، هدف اصلی این مطالعه طراحی یک مدل هیبرید متشکل از دو روش شبکه عصبی مصنوعی (ANN) و ﺧـﻮد ﺗﻮﺿـﻴﺢ ﺟﻤﻌـﻲ ﻣﻴـﺎﻧﮕﻴﻦ ﻣﺘﺤـﺮک (ARIMA) به‌منظور رفع نواقص و استفاده از ویژگی­های منحصر به‌فرد هر یک از این مدل­ها است. با استفاده از داده­های مربوط به صادرات زعفران ایران طی دوره­ی 1392-1283، نتایج مطالعه نشان داد که مدل هیبرید ARIMA-ANN در مقایسه با مدل­های ARIMA و ANN از عملکرد بهتری در پیش­بینی صادرات زعفران ایران برخوردار است. لذا، با توجه به کارایی شایان توجه مدل هیبرید ARIMA-ANN، استفاده از این مدل در تنظیم استراتژی­های مربوط به صادرات در بازارهای جهانی زعفران و همچنین در پیش­بینی متغیرهای سری ­زمانی توصیه می­گردد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In terms of quality and quantity, Iranian saffron has a considerable position at the international level and by taking advantage of the existing capacity; we can significantly increase the export earnings from it. On the other hand, sales forecasting based on time series analysis is s a very important element for the designing and implementing of marketing strategies in the international arena. However, the conventional approaches to forecasting, by ignoring the linear (or nonlinear) structure of data, do not provide accurate results. Therefore, the main objective of this study is to design a hybrid model consisting of two methods, artificial neural networks (ANN) and autoregressive integrated moving average (ARIMA), in order to overcome the deficiencies and the use of the unique features of the each of these methods. Using the data related to the export of Iranian saffron during the period 1904-2013, the results of the study showed that the ARIMA–ANN hybrid model is stronger and better performance than ARIMA and ANN individual models in order to forecasting of Iranian saffron export. Therefore, given the considerable performance ARIMA–ANN hybrid model, the use of this model is recommended in setting strategies related to the export and also in the forecasting of the forecasting of time series variables.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>393</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>405</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کهنسال</Family>
						<NameE>mohammad reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>kohansal</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>kohansal@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امیرحسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>توحیدی</Family>
						<NameE>Amirhossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tohidi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amirhossein_tohidi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بازاریابی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پیش‌بینی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سری زمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>صادرات</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ahmad, H.A., Dozier, G.V., and Roland, D.A. 2001. Egg price forecasting using neural networks. Journal of Applied Poultry Research 10 (2): 162-171.##Aydin, G. 2014. Modeling of energy consumption based on economic and demographic factors: The case of Turkey with projections. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews 35: 382-389.##Church, K.B., and Curram, S.P. 1996. Forecasting consumers&#039; expenditure: A comparison between econometric and neural network models. International Journal of Forecasting 12 (2): 255-267.##Co, H.C., and Boosarawongse, R. 2007. Forecasting Thailand’s rice export: Statistical techniques vs. artificial neural networks. Computers and Industrial Engineering 53 (4): 610-627.##Dalena, M., and Magazzino, C. 2012. Public expenditure and revenue in Italy, 1862–1993. Economic Notes 41 (3): 145-172.##Feng, L., and Zhang, J. 2014. Application of artificial neural networks in tendency forecasting of economic growth. Economic Modelling 40: 76-80.##Ghorbani, M. 2008. The efficiency of saffron’s marketing channel in Iran. World Applied Sciences Journal 4 (4): 523-527.##Jeong, K., Koo, C., and Hong, T. 2014. An estimation model for determining the annual energy cost budget in educational facilities using SARIMA (seasonal autoregressive integrated moving average) and ANN (artiﬁcial neural network). Energy 71: 71–79.##Jha, G.K., and Sinha, K. 2013. Agricultural price forecasting using neural network model: An innovative information delivery system. Agricultural Economics Research Review 26 (2): 229-239.##Kheirkhah, A., Azadeh, A., Saberi, M., Azaron, A., and Shakouri, H. 2013. Improved estimation of electricity demand function by using of artiﬁcial neural network, principal component analysis and data envelopment analysis. Computers and Industrial Engineering 64 (1): 425-441.##Lee, Y.S., and Liu, W.Y. 2014. Forecasting value of agricultural imports using a novel two-stage hybrid model. Computers and Electronics in Agriculture 104: 71-83.##Mishra, G.C., and Singh, A. 2013. A study on forecasting prices of groundnut oil in Delhi by ARIMA methodology and artificial neural networks. Agris on-line Papers in Economics and Informatics 5 (3): 25-34.##Najarzadeh, R., Reed, M., Saghaian, S., Aghaei, M., and Rezagholizadekh, M. 2011. A study of Iran’s comparative costs in saffron. Journal of International Agricultural Trade and Development 7 (1): 59-69.##Portugal, M.S. 1995. Neural networks versus time series methods: A forecasting exercise. Revista Brasileira de Economia 49 (4): 1-20.##Singhal, D., and Swarup, K.S. 2011. Electricity price forecasting using artiﬁcial neural networks. International Journal of Electrical Power and Energy Systems 33 (3): 550-555.##Tkacz, G. 2001. Neural network forecasting of Canadian GDP growth. International Journal of Forecasting 17 (1): 57-69.##Ullrich, C. 2009. Forecasting and hedging in the foreign exchange markets. Springer Science and Business Media.##Winklhofer, H., and Diamantopoulos, A. 2003. A model of export sales forecasting behavior and performance: development and testing. International Journal of Forecasting 19 (2): 271-285.##Yim, J., and Mitchell, H. 2005. Comparison of country risk models: hybrid neural networks, logit models, discriminant analysis and cluster techniques. Expert Systems with Applications 28 (1): 137-148.##Zhang, G.P. 2003. Time series forecasting using a hybrid ARIMA and neural network model. Neurocomputing 50: 159-175.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ویژگی‌های ضد میکروبی عصاره زعفران وحشی ( Crocus sativus  var.  haussknechtii  Boiss. and Reut. ex Maw)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Antimicrobial properties of extracts in ( Crocus sativus  var.  haussknechtii  Boiss. and Reut. ex Maw)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>   زعفران یکی از مهم­ترین گیاهان اقتصادی دنیا است که کاربرد دارویی فراوانی نیز دارد. سرده زعفران (Crocus L.) با حدود 90 گونه از تیره زنبقیان (Iridaceae) در نیمکره شمالی، به­ویژه غرب آسیا و ایران پراکندگی دارد. تحقیق حاضر به‌منظور بررسی فعالیت ضد میکروبی عصاره قسمت­های مختلف از زعفران مزروعی (C. sativus var. haussknechtii) از قبیل پوشش­بُنه، بُنه، گل­پوش و کلاله­ی واریته­ای بر روی برخی میکروارگانیسم­های بیماری‌زا (Bacillus cereus, Enterococcus faecalis, Escherichia coli, Pseudomonas fluorescens, Salmonella typhimurium, Staphylococcus aureus) می­باشد. نمونه­های گیاهی مورد نظر از چهار رویش­گاه مختلف استان کرمانشاه جمع‌آوری و در هرباریوم دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه شناسایی گردید. پس از آماده‌سازی مواد خام گیاهی، عصاره‌‌ الکلی 4 قسمت مختلف این گیاهان (گل­پوش، کلاله، غده و پوشش­غده) به روش خیساندن (ماسراسیون) استخراج شد. آزمایشات میکروبی با استفاده از روش حداقل غلظت مهارکنندگی (MIC) در دو غلظت (128/0) میکروگرم در میلی‌لیتر (μg.ml-1) و (512/0) میکروگرم در میلی‌لیتر (μg.ml-1) به شیوه‌ی میکرو براث دایلوشن تعیین گردید. نتایج حاصل به کمک آزمون­های آماری نشان داد که ارتباط معناداری (001/0&lt;p) بین افزایش غلظت عصاره­های الکلی گل­پوش این گیاه و قطر هاله عدم رشد وجود دارد. بدین ترتیب که عصاره متانولی گل­پوش نسبت به باکتری­های انترکوک ( 128/0) میکروگرم در میلی‌لیتر (μg.ml-1) و در سالمونلاواستاف ائورئوس (512/0) میکروگرم در میلی‌لیتر، اثر بازدارندگی دارد. بر اساس یافته­های این تحقیق عصاره الکلی قسمت­های مختلف واریته­ای زعفران مزروعی غیر از گل‌پوش (که خاصیت نسبتاً خوبی از خود نشان­داد)، خاصیت ضدمیکروبی از خود نشان ندادند. به این ترتیب گل‌پوش این نوع زعفران وحشی می­تواند کاندیدای مناسبی برای بررسی­های آزمایشگاهی باشد و جداسازی ترکیبات فعال موجود در آن برای دستیابی به داروهای ضد میکروبی، پیشنهاد می­شود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Saffron is one of the most important economic plants in the world that also has many pharmaceutical applications. Genus Crocus L. (Saffron) with about 90 species of the Iridaceae family in the northern hemisphere, especially in West Asia and Iran are scattered. The present study was to investigate the antimicrobial activity of extracts of various parts such as cover of corm, corm, perianth and stigma of the variety of saffron (C. sativus var. Haussknechtii) on some pathogenic microorganisms (Bacillus cereus, Enterococcus faecalis, Escherichia coli , Pseudomonas fluorescens, Salmonella typhimurium, Staphylococcus aureus) extrusion. Plant specimens were collected from four different habitats of Kermanshah province and then were identified in the herbarium of Razi University. After preparing raw plant extract four different parts of the plants (cover of corm, corm, perianth, stigma) by soaking (maceration) were extracted. Microbial tests using minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC) of the broth micro-dilution method were determined. The results of analysis by statistical tests showed a significant correlation (001/0 &lt;p) the increase in the concentration of alcoholic extracts there perianth saffron and inhibition zone diameter. Thus, Perianth methanol extract in Enterococcus (0/128) g ml, Salmonella and Staphylococcus (0/512) g ml has inhibitory effects against bacteria. Based on the findings of non-alcoholic extracts of different parts of a flower in this plant did not show antimicrobial properties. Thus perianth these wild saffron may be a good candidate for laboratory tests and isolation of active ingredients to achieve antimicrobial drugs, it is recommended.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>407</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>412</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید مقداد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>هاشمی</Family>
						<NameE>Seid Meghdad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hashemi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد علوم گیاهی، گروه زیست شناسی، دانشگاه رازی، باغ ابریشم، کرمانشاه، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد علوم گیاهی، گروه زیست شناسی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>meghdad.hashemi67@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>معصومی</Family>
						<NameE>Seid Mohamad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Maassoumi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گیاهشناسی، گروه زیست شناسی، دانشگاه رازی، باغ ابریشم، کرمانشاه، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گیاهشناسی، گروه زیست شناسی، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>smohammad@mail.ru</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حمید رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قاسم پور</Family>
						<NameE>Hamid Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gasempour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار فیزیولوژی گیاهی، گروه زیست شناسی، دانشگاه رازی، باغ ابریشم، کرمانشاه، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار فیزیولوژی گیاهی، گروه زیست شناسی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ghasempour2009@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عصاره</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زعفران</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فعالیت ضد باکتری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گل‌پوش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کلاله</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کرمانشاه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Azami, L., Babapour, A., and Garechahi, M., 2012. Antimicrobial Effect of aqueous extract of saffron petals on some of food-borne bacterial pathogen. Journal of Food Hygiene 2 (5): 63–74.##Escribano, J., Rios, I., and Fernandez, J.A., 1999. Isolation and cytotoxic properties of a novel glycoconjugate from corms of saffron plant (Crocus sativus L.).Biochimica et Biophysica Acta 1426: 217–222.##Fekrat, H. 2003. The application of crocin and saffron. Ethanol- extractable components in formulation of. Health care and beauty care products. Acta Horticulturae (ISHS) 650: 365–368.##Fernandez, J.A. 2006. Anticancer properties of saffron, Crocus sativus Linn. Advances in Phytomedicine  313–330.##Hammer, K.A., Carson C.F., and Riley T.V. 1999. Antimicrobial activity of essential oils and other plant extracts. Journal of Applied Microbiology 86 (6): 985–990.##Hashemi, S., Ghasempour H., and Masoumi S.M. 2012. Pollen morphology and evaluation of antimicrobial properties of wild saffron of Crocus, MSc. Dissertation, Razi University, Kermanshah, Iran. 98 p. (In Persian with English Summery).##Heatley, N.G. 1944. A Method for the assay of Penicillin. Biochemistry Journal 38: 61-65.##Kyanbakht S.A. 2008. A systematic review on pharmacology of saffron and its active constituents. Journal of Medicinal Plants 7 (28): 1–27.##Masoumi, S.M. 2001. Introduction of Edible Wild Plants of Kermanshah Province and Suggested Methods of Cooking and Eating.  Kowsar Publications, Kermanshah, Iran. 175 p.##Marla, S.R., Sreedevi, K., and Thomas, A. 2012. Antibacterial Property of Crocus sativus L. Research and Reviews : Journal of Herbal Science. New Delhi, India. 1 (1).##Mathew, B. 1999. Botany, Taxonomy and Cytology of Crocus sativus L. and its Allies; Amsterdam: Harwood Academic Publishers. pp. 19–30.##Mudasir, A.Mir., Rajesh, T.S., Rameashkannan, M.V., Riyaz, A.Pala., and Muthu Balaji, R. 2011. A Comparative study of phytochemical analysis and antimicrobial properties of stigmas and stamens of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) found in Kashmir. International Journal of Applied Biology and Pharmaceutical Technology 11 (6): 35–38.##Nassaro, F., Fratianni, F., De Martino, L., Coppola R., and De Feo, V. 2013. Effect of essentials pathogenic bacteria, pharmaceuticals 6 (2): 1451-1474.##Gandomi Nasrabadi, L., Azami Sarokelaei, A., Misaghi, A., Abbaszadeh, S., Shariatifar, N., and Tayyar Hashtjin, N. 2012. Study of antibacterial activity of aqueous and alcoholic extract of saffron petals of some bacteria in the food pathogens. Journal of Medicinal Plants 2 (42): 189-196.##Razavi, B.M., Imenshahidi, M., Abnous, K., and Hosseinzadeh, H. 2014. Cardiovascular effects of saffron and its active constituents: A Review Article Saffron Agronomy and Tecnology  1 (1): 313.##Saxena, R.B. 2010. Botany, taxonomy and cytology of Crocus sativus series. An International Quarterly Journal of Research in Ayurveda 31 (3): 374–381.##Vahidi, H., Kamalinejad, M., Sedaghati, N. 2002. Antimicrobial properties of Crocus sativus L. Iranian Journal of Pharmacology Research 1: 33–35.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				