<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of genetic variations in saffron with more than three stigmas using SSR and ISSR molecular markers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تنوع ژنتیکی در زعفران های با بیش از سه کلاله با استفاده از نشانگرمولکولی SSR و ISSR</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>347</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>358</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">66472</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.104167.1266</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهدانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>ایزانلو</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron is the most valuable spice in the world. It is genetically a monomorphic clone. However, differences in phenotype and quality have been reported. The most important agro-economically phenotypic variation is the appearance of flowers with more than three stigmas. The main objective of this study was to study the genetic variability of saffron clones with more than 3 stigmas using SSR and ISSR molecular markers. In this research, saffron clones with more than three stigmas were collected along with the corm and the root from Saffron fields of Qaen and Sarayan, South Khorassan province, then transferred as a whole to the Biotechnology Laboratory of the Faculty of Agriculture, the University of Birjand. The number of stigmas in each flower was counted. Genomic DNA was extracted according to the CTAB method from leaves of the flower with more than three stigmas. Flower with more than three stigmas was larger and had more petals than ordinary ones. The most frequent number of flowers with more than three stigmas was related to four and five stigmas with 38%. Six-spike samples with a frequency of 14% were observed. Among the collected samples, only one specimen with seven stigmas was observed. Of the 48 tested ISSR primers on the bulk of DNA, only 16 primers had amplified bands and selected. The results of agarose gel electrophoresis for ISSR primers amplified the bands ranged from 100 to 1000 bp. By examining the bands formed for ISSR primers, no significant polymorphism was observed between different clones of saffron. Therefore, based on this marker system, no sign of genetic diversity was observed between clones with different number of stigmas. Among the tested SSR markers, 10 primer pairs showed amplified band among the clones. The results of correlation analysis based on Spearman correlation coefficient showed that there was no statistically significant correlation between microsatellite marker alleles and number of stigmas.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زعفران زراعی به عنوان با ارزش­ترین ادویه جهان از نظر ژنتیکی کلون مونومورفی بوده، ولی تفاوت­هایی نیز در فنوتیپ و کیفیت گزارش شده است که مهم­ترین تنوع فنوتیپی از نظر زراعی و اقتصادی، وجود گل­های با بیش از سه کلاله است، بنابراین هدف از این تحقیق استفاده از نشانگرهای مولکولی مختلف جهت مطالعه مولکولی زعفران های با بیش از 3 کلاله در منطقه و اندازه­گیری تنوع ژنتیکی بین آن­ها بود. در این تحقیق، کلون­های زعفران با بیش از سه کلاله به­طور کامل همراه با خاک اطراف ریشه از مزارع کشاورزان جمع­آوری و بطور کامل در جعبه­های پلاستیکی، جهت حفظ شرایط زیستی، مستقر گردیدند. استخراج DNA به روش CTAB از برگ­های گل دارای بیش از سه کلاله انجام شد. زعفران­های با بیش از سه کلاله در مقایسه با حالت معمولی دارای گل­های بزرگتر و تعداد گلبرگ­های به نسبت بیشتری بودند. بیشترین فراوانی تعداد کلاله در بین نمونه­های بیش از سه کلاله مربوط به چهار و پنج کلاله با 38 درصد بود. نمونه­های دارای شش کلاله با فراوانی 14 درصد مشاهده شد. در بین نمونه­های جمع­آوری شده تنها یک نمونه با تعداد کلاله هفت نیز مشاهده گردید. از مجموع 48 آغازگر ISSR آزمون شده روی نمونه DNAی بالک، تنها 16 آغازگر تشکیل نوار دادند. نتایج حاصل از الکتروفورز ژل آگاروز برای آغازگرهای ISSR نشان داد که محدوده نوارهای تشکیل شده در فاصله 100 تا 1000 جفت باز بود. با بررسی نوارهای تشکیل شده برای آغازگرهای ISSR‌، چندشکلی قابل ملاحظه­ای بین کلون­های مختلف زعفران مورد بررسی مشاهده نشد. لذا، براساس این سیستم نشانگری تنوع ژنتیکی بین کلون­های با تعداد کلاله متفاوت ملاحظه نشد. از بین نشانگرهای SSR‌ آزمون شده، 10 نشانگر چند شکلی را بین کلون ها نشان دادند. نتایج تجزیه همبستگی براساس ضریب همبستگی اسپیرمن نشان داد که ارتباط معنی­دار آماری بین هیچ کدام از آلل­های نشانگر ریزماهواره و تعداد کلاله­ها مشاهده نشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اپی ژنتیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تنوع ژنتیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چندشکلی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66472_07e4864057498c8845c62a3119437be5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
