<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effect of intercropping patterns with mallow on replacement corms and flower yield and qualitative criteria of saffron in the third year</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر آرایش‌های کشت مخلوط با پنیرک بر عملکرد پیازهای دختری و گل و خصوصیات کیفی زعفران در سال سوم</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">110879</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2020.210799.1371</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سرور</FirstName>
					<LastName>خرم دل</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>معلم بنهنگی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری بوم شناسی زراعی گروه اگروتکنولوژی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید جلیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>داورپناه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری بوم شناسی زراعی گروه اگروتکنولوژی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron field from the onset of dormancy to flowering phase is free of vegetation and increased soil temperature and reduced land use efficiency are the clearest problems of sole saffron cultivation. In order to study the effect of intercropping patterns of mallow (Malva sylvetris L.) as a perennial medicinal plant with saffron (Crocus sativus L.) on replacement corm growth and flower yield affected as possible cooling of corms for climate change and global warming mitigation, an experiment was conducted at Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran during three growing seasons of 2015-2016, 2016-2017 and 2017-2018. Treatments were 15, 30, 45 and 60-cm row spacings for saffron from mallow planting rows and sole saffron and mallow cultivations. Based on results in the third year, the effect of intercropping patterns with mallow was significant on yield indicators of flower and corm of saffron. In comparison between sole cultivation and intercropped saffron revealed that the highest values for flower number, dried stigma yield and yield of replacement corms were recorded for sole saffron cultivation with 81 flowers.m-2, 0.2115 g.m-2 and 26.51 g.m-2, respectively.  In comparisons amongst intercropping patterns, the highest values for these criteria were related to 30-cm row spacings from mallow with 46 flowers.m-2, 0.155 g.m-2 and 13.39 g.m-2, respectively. However, corcin, picrocrocin and safranal contents were not significantly affected by intercropping patterns with mallow. Effect of intercropped saffron was significant on fresh weight of flower, dried weight of flower and branches number per plant of mallow. The maximum value for dried flower weight was observed for 60-cm row spacing with 28.89 g.m-2. The range for LER calculated with 1.01-1.77 and the maximum value was for 15-cm row spacing.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مزرعه زعفران، طی شروع دوره رکود تا گلدهی بدون رشد است و افزایش درجه حرارت خاک و کاهش کارایی استفاده از زمین از جمله مشکلات اصلی تک-کشتی این گیاه محسوب می‌شوند. به منظور بررسی تأثیر انواع آرایش‌های کشت مخلوط گیاه دارویی چندساله پنیرک (Malva sylvetris L.) با زعفران (Crocus sativus L.) بر رشد پیاز‌ و عملکرد گل به منظور تخفیف اثر تغییر اقلیم و گرمایش جهانی، آزمایشی در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، در سه سال زراعی 95-1394 و 96-1395 و 97-1396 به اجرا درآمد. تیمارها شامل فاصله ردیف 15، 30، 45 و 60 سانتی‌متر زعفران از پنیرک و کشت خالص پنیرک و زعفران بودند. نتایج سال سوم نشان داد که اثر آرایش‌های کشت مخلوط با پنیرک بر شاخص‌های عملکرد گل و پیاز زعفران معنی‌دار بود. مقایسه بین تیمارهای خالص با مخلوط نشان داد که بیشترین تعداد گل، عملکرد کلاله خشک و عملکرد پیازهای دختری در کشت خالص به ترتیب  برابر با 81 گل در متر مربع، 2115/0 گرم بر متر مربع و 51/26 گرم بر مترمربع مشاهده شد. در بین تیمارهای کشت مخلوط نیز بیشترین مقدار برای فاصله ردیف 30 سانتی‌متر به ترتیب با 46 گل در متر مربع، 155/0 گرم بر متر مربع و 39/13 گرم بر متر مربع بدست آمد. محتوی کروسین، پیکروکروسین و سافرانال تحت تأثیر معنی‌دار کشت مخلوط با پنیرک قرار نگرفت. اثر کشت مخلوط با زعفران بر وزن‌ گل تر، وزن خشک گل و تعداد شاخه جانبی پنیرک معنی‌دار بود. بیشترین وزن خشک گل پنیرک برای فاصله ردیف 60 سانتی‌متر با 89/28 گرم بر متر مربع مشاهده شد. دامنه نسبت برابری زمین 77/1-01/1 محاسبه شد که بالاترین میزان برای فاصله ردیف 15 سانتی‌متری پنیرک از زعفران بود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد کلاله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محتوی کروسین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نسبت برابری زمین</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
