<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effect of micronutrient foliar application on quantitative and qualitative traits of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اثر محلول پاشی با نیترات پتاسیم و روی بر صفات کمی و کیفی زعفران (Crocus sativus L.)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>147</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>163</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">94085</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2019.179188.1342</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>طباطبائیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه زراعت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحــد اصفهان (اردستان)، اصفهان، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسنیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان (اردستان)، اصفهان، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اعظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>کدخدایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه زراعت دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی اصفهان (واحد اردستان)، اصفهان، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This research was carried out with the aim of studying the effect of zinc and potassium levels as foliar application on quantitative and qualitative traits of saffron (&lt;em&gt;Crocus sativa&lt;/em&gt;) in Natanz city (village Badrude) in the second year of agriculture during 2019. The experiment was done as factorial layout based on a randomized complete block design with three replications. Elements such as KNO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; at the levels of control (K&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;), 5 in thousand (K&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) and 10 in thousand (K&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) and Zn-EDTA at the levels of control (Z&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;), 5 in thousand (Z&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) and 10 in thousand (Z&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) were the treatments. The studied traits included quantitative traits of fresh and dry weight of the girl&#039;s corm, fresh and dry weight of mother corm, fresh and dry yield of the flower, fresh dry yield of the stigma, qualitative traits of Crocin, picocrocin and safranal. The results showed that K&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and K&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; levels increased the quantitative traits, especially at K&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; level. While spraying zinc only at the Z&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; level quantitative traits increased and it had no significant effect on qualitative traits. The application of potassium fertilizer at the K&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; level along with the Z&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; had the greatest effect on increasing the quantitative traits of saffron. Perhaps one of the reasons for increasing flower yield can be attributed to the positive effects of potassium and zinc on the photosynthetic system of the plant. This increase in the amount of photosynthesis and metabolism, in turn, affects the amount of stigma production and increases  dry weight of the stigma. As a result of potassium spraying, amount of crocin and picrocrocin increased from K&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; to K&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; by 18 and 13 %, and safranal increased from K&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; to K&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and K&lt;sub&gt;3 &lt;/sub&gt;increased by 30% and 48%, respectively. In the present study, there was a positive and significant correlation between the amount of Crocin, Picrocrocin and Safranal contents with quantitative characteristics in saffron. It can be said that quality traits are influenced by quantitative traits and yield components of saffron. Therefore, flowering and flower yield of saffron is also effective in improving its quality.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این تحقیق با هدف مطالعه تأثیر محلول پاشی کود روی و پتاسیم بر صفات کمی و کیفی زعفران در شهرستان نطنز در روستای بادرود در سال دوم زراعی 1396 به صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح بلوک­های کامل تصادفی در سه تکرار اجرا گردید. تیمارها شامل سه سطح نیترات پتاسیم (شاهد (K&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;)، 5 در هزار (K&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) و 10 در هزار (K&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) و سه سطح روی (شاهد (Z&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;)، 5 در هزار (Z&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) و 10 در هزار (Z&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;)) بود. صفات مورد بررسی شامل صفات کمی وزن تر و خشک بنه دختری، وزن تر و خشک بنه مادری، عملکرد تر و خشک گل، عملکرد تر و خشک کلاله، صفات کیفی کروسین، پیکروکروسین و سافرانال بود. نتایج نشان داد سطوح کودی K&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; و K&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; موجب افزایش صفات کمی بویژه در سطح K&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; شد. در حالی که محلول­پاشی روی تنها در سطح Z&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; باعث افزایش صفات کمی شد و اثر معنی­داری بر صفات کیفی نداشت. کاربرد غلظت کود پتاسیم در سطح سوم (K&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) همراه با سطح دوم کود روی (Z&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;) بیشترین اثر را در افزایش صفات کمی زعفران داشت. شاید بتوان یکی از دلایل اﻓﺰاﯾﺶ ﻋﻤﻠﮑﺮد ﮔﻞ را ﺑﻪ اﺛﺮات ﻣﺜﺒﺖ پتاسیم و روی ﺑﺮ ﺳﯿﺴﺘﻢ ﻓﺘﻮﺳﻨﺘﺰی ﮔﯿﺎه ﻧﺴﺒﺖ داد. اﻳﻦ اﻓــﺰاﻳﺶ در ﻣﻴﺰان ﻓﺘﻮﺳﻨﺘﺰ و ﻣﺎده ﺳﺎزی ﻧﻴﺰ ﺑﻪ ﻧﻮﺑﻪ ﺧﻮد ﺑﺮ ﻣﻴﺰان ﺗﻮﻟﻴﺪ ﻛﻼﻟﻪ ﺗﺄﺛﻴﺮ داﺷﺘﻪ و ﺑﺎﻋﺚ اﻓﺰاﻳﺶ وزن ﺧﺸﻚ ﻛﻼﻟﻪ می­شود. در اثر محلول پاشی پتاسیم، میزان کروسین و پیکروکروسین از سطح K&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; به K&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; به ترتیب به میزان 18 و 13 درصد و سافرانال از سطح K&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; به K&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; و K&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; به میزان 30 و 48 درصد افزایش معنی­داری داشت. در مطالعه حاضر، همبستگی مثبت و معنی­داری بین میزان کروسین، پیکروکروسین و سافرانال با خصوصیات کمی در زعفران بود. شاید بتوان گفت که صفات کیفی زعفران تحت اثر صفات کمی و اجزای عملکرد زعفران می­باشد، بنابراین ﮔﻞاﻧﮕﯿﺰی و ﻋﻤﻠﮑﺮد ﮔﻞ زﻋﻔﺮان در ﺑﻬﺒﻮد ﮐﯿﻔﯿﺖ آن ﻧﯿﺰ ﻣﺆﺛﺮ ﻣﯽﺑﺎﺷﺪ.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیکروکروسین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تغذیه برگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران (Crocus sativus L)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سافرانال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد کلاله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کروسین</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Optimizing the effect of mother corm and urban waste compost levels on flower and corm yield of saffron using surface-response modeling in the first year</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بهینه‌سازی تأثیرمقدار بنه مادری و کمپوست زباله شهری بر عملکرد گل و بنه زعفران با استفاده از مدلسازی سطح-پاسخ در سال اول</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>165</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>184</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">95743</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2019.184094.1350</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>پارساپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد مهندسی کشاورزی اکولوژیک، گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پرویز</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضوانی مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سرور</FirstName>
					<LastName>خرم دل</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Response surface methodology (RSM) is defined as a set of mathematical and statistical techniques that are used to optimize yield of a product. In order to study the effects of urban waste compost and corm rates on flower yield of saffron using RSM, an experiment was conducted at the Research Field of the Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran during the growing season of 2017-2018. The treatments were determined based on low and high levels of urban waste compost (0 and 20 t.ha&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, respectively) and corm weight (5 and 15 t.ha&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, respectively). These were computed by using Minitab V. 17. Dry weight of stigma, dry weight of style, fresh weight of flower, flower number, corm number, dry weight of corm, and number of buds per corm were calculated as dependent variables and changes of these variables were evaluated by using a regression model. Lack-of-fit test was used to evaluate the quality of the fitted model. The adequacy of the model was tested by analysis of variance. In general, the full quadratic polynomial equation was tested to determine significance of the model and the components (such as linear, squared and first-order interaction terms). The quality of the fitted model was judged using the determination coefficient (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;). The results show that the effect of linear component on all traits studied except fresh weight of flower, dry weight of corm 0-4g, and number of buds per corm 0-4 and 8-4 grams were significant. The effect of total grade two had a significant effect on the traits of flower number, fresh weight of flower, dry weight of stigma, dry weight of style, number of daughter corms per 0-4, 4-8 and &gt;8 grams, dry weight of corm per 4-8 and &gt;8 grams and number of buds per &gt;8 grams was significant. Also, the interaction effect of two factors of urban waste compost and weight corm on the number of flowers, fresh weight of flower, dry weight of stigma, dry weight of style, number of daughter corms per 4-8 and &gt;8 grams, dry weight of corm 4-8 and &gt;8 grams, and number of buds per corm &gt;8 grams were significant. Lack of fit test had no significant effect on the studied traits. The full square model for the response variables gave insignificant lack-of-fit indicating that the data of experiment were satisfactorily explained. The highest flower number, fresh weight of flower, stigma dry weight and style dry weight were observed for 5 t.ha&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; corm+ 20 t.ha&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; compost. Optimum of corm weight and urban waste compost and desirability for the traits related to flower and corm with 5 t.ha&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, 20 t.ha&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;and d = 0.92 were urban waste compost with 12 t.ha&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;, 20 t.ha&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt;and d = 0.95, respectively. Based on the results, municipal waste compost and corm weight had a positive effect on most of the studied traits.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مدل سطح-پاسخ (RSM) مجموعه­ای از تکنیک­های آماری مورد استفاده برای بهینه­سازی نهاده­های تولید می­باشد. این آزمایش با هدف بررسی تأثیر سطوح کمپوست زباله شهری و بنه بر شاخص­های عملکرد گل زعفران با استفاده ازمدلسازی سطح-پاسخ در مزرعه پژوهشی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد در سال زراعی 97-1396 اجرا شد. تیمارها شامل کمپوست زباله شهری با سه سطح ( 0، 10 و 20 تن در هکتار) و وزن بنه مادری با سه سطح (5، 10 و 15 تن در هکتار) بودند، که با توجه به سطوح بالا و پایین هریک از فاکتورها توسط نرم افزار Minitab. V.17 تعیین شدند. وزن خشک کلاله، وزن خشک خامه، وزن تر گل، تعداد گل،تعداد بنه، وزن خشک بنه و تعداد جوانه در هر بنه به عنوان متغیرهای وابسته مورد اندازه­گیری قرار گرفتند و تغییرات این متغیرها با استفاده از مدل رگرسیونی ارزیابی شد. به منظور ارزیابی کیفیت و بسندگی مدل از آزمون عدم برازش و آنالیز واریانس استفاده شد. معادله چند جمله ای درجه دوم کامل  برای تعیین معنی­داری مدل و اجزای مدل و ضریب تبیین (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;)  برای ارزیابی کیفیت مدل برازش شده مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. نتایج نشان داد که اثر جزء خطی  بین کمپوست زباله شهری و مقدار بنه بر تمام صفات مورد مطالعه به جز وزن تر گل، وزن خشک بنه 4-0 گرم و تعداد جوانه در بنه­های موجود در گروه­های وزنیِ 4-0 و 8-4 گرم معنی­دار بود. اثر درجه دو متغیر مستقل کمپوست زباله شهری و مقدار بنه در صفات تعداد گل، وزن ترگل، وزن خشک کلاله، وزن خشک خامه، تعداد بنه در گروه­های وزنیِ 4-0، 8-4 و &gt;8 گرم، وزن خشک بنه 8-4 و &gt;8 گرم و تعداد جوانه در گروه وزنیِ&gt;8 گرم معنی­دار بود. هم­چنین برهمکنش معنی­داری بین کمپوست زباله شهری و مقدار بنه در متغیرهای  تعداد گل، وزن تر گل، وزن خشک کلاله، وزن خشک خامه، تعداد بنه در گروه­های وزنیِ 8-4  و &gt;8 گرم، وزن خشک بنه در گروه­های 8-4  و &gt;8 گرم و تعداد جوانه در گروه وزنیِ&gt;8 گرم مشاهده شد. آزمون عدم برازش در مورد هیچ­کدام از صفات معنی­دار نشدکه این امر نشان­دهنده برازش مطلوب مدل رگرسیون درجه دوکامل بود. بیش­ترین تعداد گل، وزن تر گل،  عملکرد کلاله خشک و هم­چنین وزن خشک خامه مربوط به تیمار 5  تن بنه در هکتار+20 تن در هکتار کمپوست زباله شهری بدست آمد. مقدار بهینه وزن بنه، مقدار کمپوست زباله شهری و درجه مطلوبیت برای صفات مرتبط با گل به ترتیب 5 تن در هکتار، 20 تن در هکتار و 92/0 d&lt;sub&gt;=&lt;/sub&gt;و برای صفات مرتبط با بنه،  12 تن در هکتار و 20 تن در هکتار و95/0 d&lt;sub&gt;=&lt;/sub&gt;محاسبه گردید. براساس نتایج حاصله، کمپوست زباله شهری و وزن بنه مادری بر اکثر صفات مربوط به بنه اثر مثبت گذاشتند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آزمون عدم برازش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بنه دختری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهینه‌سازی تولید</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تولید پایدار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد بنه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد کلاله</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Floristic study of weeds of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) fields in Cheshmesaran district in Azadshar</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مطالعه فلوریستیک علف‌های هرز مزارع زعفران (Crocus sativus L. ) بخش چشمه‌ساران شهرستان آزادشهر</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>185</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>209</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">101554</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2019.183023.1347</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کامبیز</FirstName>
					<LastName>خرمالی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش‌آموخته کارشناسی ارشد رشته شناسایی و مبارزه با علف‌های ‌هرز گروه تولیدات گیاهی دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی دانشگاه گنبدکاووس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>غلامعلی‌پور علمداری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی دانشگاه گنبدکاووس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی دانشگاه گنبدکاووس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زینب</FirstName>
					<LastName>اورسجی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استان گلستان، شهرستان گنبدکاووس، دانشگاه گنبدکاووس، دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، گروه تولیدات گیاهی. صندوق پستی 163.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>آهنگر</LastName>
<Affiliation>استان گلستان، شهرستان گنبدکاووس، دانشگاه گنبدکاووس، دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، گروه تولیدات گیاهی. صندوق پستی 163.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>A research was conducted to study floristic of weeds of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) fields located in Cheshmesaran district in Azadshar to report distribution and species diversity of weeds population. For this purpose, saffron fields under cultivation over 3 hectares was identified in three regions, including Narab, Vamenan and Tillabad village. Identification and sampling of weeds was done in vegetative growth stage of saffron (daughter corms) in 2017. 45 quadrates were used for each farm and then number and type of weed species each quadrat was counted separately. Weeds species based on Persian name, scientific name, genus, family, leaf shape, photosynthetic pathway, growth habit and life cycle were classified. Results of species composition of weeds in saffron fields of triple regions showed that Narab region with 54 species had the largest number of species. Veronica persica Poir weed and Stellaria midia in Narab and Veronica persica Poir in Vamenan were the dominant weed in these regions which had the highest relative density and frequency. In return, Hordeum murinum in the Tillabad region had the greatest density and frequency. This could be due to the differences in geographical coordinates, climatic conditions of sampling locations, competitive ability of weeds and management methods to control them in saffron fields. The results of species diversity of weeds showed that Narab and Tilabad included highest and lowest dominance index, which were about 0.13 and 0.08, respectively. In return, the highest Menhinick richness, Margalev and uniformiy of weeds were recorded in the Narab region about 0.67, 2.55 and 0.97, respectively. Narab and Vamenan regions also had maximum numerical value of Simpson (0.92) and Shannon- Wiener indices (2.64). Overall, the results showed that saffron fields of both regions of Narab and Vamenan were most similar in term of weed species number and population indices.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تحقیقی به‌منظور مطالعه فلوریستیک علف‌های هرز مزارع زعفران (&lt;em&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/em&gt; L.) واقع در بخش چشمه‌ساران شهرستان آزادشهر جهت گزارش پراکنش و تنوع گونه‌ای جمعیت علف‌های ‌هرز انجام شد. برای این منظور، مزارع زعفران با سطح زیر کشت بالغ بر 3 هکتار در سه منطقه شامل روستاهای نرآب، وامنان و تیل‌آباد مورد شناسایی قرار گرفت. شناسایی و نمونه‌برداری از علف‌های‌ هرز در مرحله رشد رویشی زعفران (بنه دختری) در سال 1396 انجام شد. تعداد 45 کوآدرات برای هر مزرعه مورد برررسی قرار گرفت و سپس تعداد و نوع گونه علف‌هرز در هر کوآدرات به‌تفکیک شمارش گردید. گونه‌های هرز بر اساس نام فارسی، نام علمی، جنس، تیره، شکل برگ، مسیر فتوسنتزی، شکل رویشی و چرخه زندگی طبقه‌بندی شدند. نتایج ترکیب گونه‌ای علف‌های هرز در مزارع زعفران مناطق سه گانه نشان داد که منطقه نرآب با 54 گونه از بیشترین تعداد برخوردار بود. علف‌هرز سیزاب ایرانی و گندمک در نرآب و سیزاب ایرانی در وامنان از علف‌های هرز غالب در این مناطق بوده که از بیشترین تراکم و فراوانی نسبی برخوردار بودند. در مقابل علف‌هرز جو موشی در منطقه تیل‌آباد از لحاظ تراکم و فراوانی بیشترین میزان را دارا بود. این امر می‌تواند به‌دلیل تفاوت در مختصات جغرافیایی، شرایط آب و هوایی محل‌‌های نمونه‌برداری، توان رقابتی علف‌های هرز و روش‌های مدیریتی کنترل آن‌ها در مزارع زعفران باشد. نتایج تنوع گونه‌ای علف‌های هرز نشان داد که مناطق تیل‌آباد و نرآب به‌ترتیب از بیشترین و کمترین شاخص غالبیت به‌میزان 13/0 و 08/0 برخوردار بودند. در مقابل، بیشترین غنای منهینگ، مارگالف و یکنواختی علف‌های هرز به منطقه نرآب به‌ترتیب معادل 67/0، 55/2 و 97/0 اختصاص داشت. هم‌چنین مناطق نرآب و وامنان به‌ترتیب از بیشترین مقدار عددی شاخص سیمپسون (92/0) و شانون- وینر (64/2) برخوردار بودند. در مجموع نتایج نشان داد که مزارع زعفران در دو منطقه نرآب و وامنان از لحاظ حضور تعداد گونه‌ای و شاخص‌های جمعیتی علف‌های هرز از بیشترین تشابه برخوردار بودند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بنه دختری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترکیب گونه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیزاب ایرانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص سمپسون</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص شانون- وینر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">یکنواختی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Cloning and Bioinformatics Investigation on CCD4a and CCD4b Genes from Iranian Saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>همسانه‌سازی و بررسی بیوانفورماتیکی ژن‌های CCD4a و CCD4b در زعفران (Crocus sativus L. ) ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>211</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>229</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">99689</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2019.182490.1343</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>حبیب زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری رشته بیوتکنولوژی کشاورزی، گروه به‌نژادی و بیوتکنولوژی گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه تبریز، تبریز، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>دورانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، گروه به‌نژادی و بیوتکنولوژی گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه تبریز،تبریز، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>زیارت نیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه زیست فناوری مواد غذایی، مؤسسه پژوهشی علوم و صنایع غذایی، مشهد، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>ولیزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، گروه به‌نژادی و بیوتکنولوژی گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه تبریز. تبریز، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron is one of the most expensive spices and natural colors used in various food, pharmaceutical and cosmetic industries. In recent years, a family of enzymes that digest carotenoid substrates into double bonds are identified and introduced in plants. This family is of enzymes Carotenoid Cleavage Dioxygenase (CCD) enzymes. In this study, two isoforms of this gene were cloned and sequenced due to the importance of &lt;em&gt;CCD&lt;/em&gt; genes in biosynthesis of apocarotenoids. Bioinformatics analyses including phylogenetic relationships and protein structures were evaluated. 3D modeling of these proteins was done by homologous modeling and using the Swiss Model database after selecting the appropriate pattern. The Ramachandran plot was drawn in order to validate the structure of the 3D model. The results show that the two CCD4a and CCD4b isoforms have both exons and one intron. &lt;em&gt;In silico&lt;/em&gt; analysis, the physicochemical properties of CsCCD4a and CsCCD4b proteins also show that the proteins derived from these two isoforms are similar in terms of molecular weight, amino acids, isoelectric points, aliphatic index, instability index and solubility. The results of study of 3D structures resulted in proposal of similar structures for two isoforms. The results of this study can provide valuable information on the behavior and response of CCD4 enzyme in the pathway for synthesis of apricotines in saffron, and these results can be useful in future protein engineering programs.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زعفران به عنوان یکی از گران­بهاترین ادویه­ها و رنگ­های طبیعی است که در صنایع مختلف از جمله غذایی، دارویی و آرایشی- بهداشتی مورد استفاده قرار می­گیرد. در سال‌های اخیر، خانواده‌‌ای از آنزیم‌ها که پیش ماده­های کاروتنوئیدی را در جایگاه پیوندهای دوگانه برش می‌دهند، در گیاهان شناسایی و معرفی شده‌اند. به این خانواده از آنزیم‌های برش­دهنده کارتنویید دی اکسیژناز CCD)) گفته می­شوند. در این تحقیق به دلیل اهمیت ژن‌های &lt;em&gt;CCD&lt;/em&gt; در بیوسنتز آپوکاروتنوئیدهای زعفران، دو ایزوفرم از این ژن با استفاده از روش نسخه­برداری معکوس همسانه­سازی، تعیین توالی و نتایج با موارد مشابه خارجی مورد مقایسه قرار گرفتند. بررسی­های بیوانفورماتیکی شامل بررسی ارتباطات خویشاوندی و نیز ساختار­های پروتتینی مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفت. مدل‌سازی سه ‌بعدی این پروتئین‌ها به روش همولوژی مدلینگ و با استفاده از پایگاه Swiss Model پس از انتخاب الگوی مناسب انجام گرفت. همچنین جهت اعتبار­سنجی ساختاری مدل ترسیم شده سه‌بعدی، پلات راماچاندران ترسیم گردید. نتایج حاصله نشان داد دو ایزوفرم &lt;em&gt;CCD4a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; و &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;CCD4b&lt;/em&gt; هر دو دارای دو اگزون (641 و 1099 جفت باز برای &lt;em&gt;CCD4a&lt;/em&gt;  و 614 و 1099 جفت باز برای &lt;em&gt;CCD4b&lt;/em&gt;) و یک اینترون (670 جفت باز در &lt;em&gt;CCD4a&lt;/em&gt; و 668 جفت باز در &lt;em&gt;CCD4b&lt;/em&gt;) هستند. بررسی &lt;em&gt;In silico &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;خصوصیات فیزیکوشیمیایی پروتئین‌های CsCCD4a و CsCCD4b بیانگر این حقیقت بود که پروتئین­های بدست آمده از این دو ایزوفرم از نظر وزن مولکولی، تعداد اسیدهای آمینه، نقطه ایزوالکتریک، شاخص آلیفاتیک، شاخص ناپایداری و حلالیت مشابه می­باشند. نتایج بررسی ساختارهای سه بعدی بدست آمده نشان داد این دو ایزوفرم دارای ساختارهای سه بعدی مشابهی می­باشند. یافته­های این تحقیق می­تواند اطلاعات با ارزشی در رابطه با رفتار و واکنش آنزیم CCD4 در مسیر سنتز آپوکاروتنوئیدهای زعفران فراهم کند و همچنین این نتایج می­تواند در  برنامه­های آتی اصلاح ژنتیکی زعفران ایران مفید واقع گردد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">CCD4</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بررسی فیلوژنتیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بیوانفورماتیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل‌سازی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of Secondary Metabolites, Total Phenol Content and Antioxidant Properties of Petal in Saffron Populations Under Conventional and once Irrigation Conditions</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی متابولیت‌های ثانویه، محتوای فنل کل و خواص آنتی‌اکسیدانی گلبرگ در جمعیت‎های زعفران تحت شرایط آبیاری مرسوم و یکبار آبیاری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>231</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>242</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">99688</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2019.187000.1352</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پریسا</FirstName>
					<LastName>شیخ الاسلامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، گروه تولید و ژنتیک گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه زنجان، زنجان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جلال</FirstName>
					<LastName>صبا</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه تولید و ژنتیک گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه زنجان، زنجان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرید</FirstName>
					<LastName>شکاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه تولید و ژنتیک گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه زنجان، زنجان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>عظیمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه تولید و ژنتیک گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه زنجان، زنجان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اعظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>ملکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگر پسا دکترای گروه تولید و ژنتیک گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه زنجان، زنجان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Each year a large amount of saffron petals which make up a significant proportion of saffron flowers are discarded as waste while this part of the flower also contains compounds such as phenol, anthocyanin, flavonoid and antioxidant properties. Two separate experiments were conducted using randomized complete block design with three replications in order to evaluate secondary metabolites, total phenol content and antioxidant capacity of petals in eight saffron populations under normal and once irrigation conditions  at the research farm of university of Zanjan on three year old saffron plants. In order to measure and determine secondary metabolites, total phenol content and antioxidant properties of saffron petal extract, UV-Visible  Metering Spectra, folin-Ciocalteu and DPPH were used, respectively. Combined analysis of variance under normal and once irrigation conditions showed that the difference between secondary metabolites and antioxidant properties was not significant in the two irrigation conditions. While, total phenol content was significantly higher under the once irrigation condition, the  Torbat-e-jam population had highest total phenol content (86.66 mg gallic acid per gram of methanolic extract) under this condition. In both irrigation conditions, the evaluated populations exhibited suitable amounts of picocrocin, safranal, phenol and antioxidant properties which can be considered to be of use for us in the food, pharmaceutical and chemical industries.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">گلبرگ زعفران که از لحاظ وزنی بخش قابل توجهی از گل زعفران را تشکیل می‌دهد سالانه در مقادیر زیاد به عنوان ضایعات دور ریخته می‌شود. در حالی­که این قسمت گل دارای ترکیباتی از جمله فنل، آنتوسیانین و فلاونوئید با خواص آنتی‌اکسیدانی هستند. به منظور ارزیابی متابولیت‌های ثانویه، محتوای فنل کل و ظرفیت آنتی‌اکسیدانی گلبرگ در 8 جمعیت زعفران، آزمایشی در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی در سه تکرار در دو شرایط آبیاری مرسوم و یکبار آبیاری در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشگاه زنجان بر روی بوته‌های سال سوم زعفران به اجرا درآمد. جهت اندازه‌گیری متابولیت‌های ثانویه، محتوای فنل کل گلبرگ و تعیین خواص آنتی‌اکسیدانی عصاره گلبرگ زعفران به ترتیب از روش‌های طیف نورسنجی فرابنفش- مرئی، فولین سیوکالتیو و  DPPHاستفاده گردید. نتایج تجزیه واریانس مرکب در دو شرایط آبیاری مرسوم و یکبار آبیاری نشان داد که متابولیت‌های ثانویه و خواص آنتی‌اکسیدانی در دو شرایط آبیاری تفاوت معنی‌داری نداشت. در حالی­که از نظر محتوای فنل کل در شرایط یکبار آبیاری افزایش معنی‎دار مشاهده شد. جمعیت تربت‌جام بیشترین مقدار فنل کل (56/86 میلی‌گرم گالیک اسید بر گرم عصاره متانولی) را در شرایط یکبار آبیاری داشت. در هر دو شرایط آبیاری، جمعیت‌های مورد ارزیابی مقادیر مناسبی از متابولیت‏های ثانویه، فنل و آنتی‌اکسیدان را داشتند، که می‌تواند برای استفاده در صنایع غذایی، دارویی و شیمیایی مورد استفاده قرار گیرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیکروکروسین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رادیکال آزاد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سافرانال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فولین سیوکالتیو</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کروسین و کم‌آبیاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of cell wall degrading enzymes of Fusarium species associated with root and corm of saffron in South Khorasan province</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی فعالیت آنزیم‌های مخرب دیواره سلولی گونه‌های Fusariumهمراه ریشه و بنه زعفران در استان خراسان جنوبی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>243</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>259</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">101557</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2020.184121.1349</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نیما</FirstName>
					<LastName>خالدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، موسسه تحقیقات ثبت و گواهی بذر و نهال، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، کرج، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3299-2131</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of this study is to identify  &lt;em&gt;Fusarium&lt;/em&gt; species associated with root and corm of saffron and evaluate extracellular enzyme activity secreted by them. In order to study the species of &lt;em&gt;Fusarium&lt;/em&gt;, a total of 53 root and corm samples were randomly collected from saffron fields of the South Khorasan province during 2017 growing season. After washing the samples with sterile water and disinfected the surface with 1% sodium hypochlorite, small pieces of root and corm were cultured on general and specific culture media. Purification of fungal colonies was performed using single spore and hyphal tip methods on 2% water agar medium. Identification of fungi based on the microscopic and morphological characteristics was performed with valid identification keys. The &lt;em&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; F. graminearum&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;F. culmorum&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;F. proliferatum species &lt;/em&gt;were identified based on morphological characters. The results obtained from molecular analysis using species-specific primers confirm morphological identification. The results reveal that 22.6% of saffron samples are contaminated by &lt;em&gt;Fusarium&lt;/em&gt; species. &lt;em&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/em&gt; is the predominant species with the highest isolation frequency in samples of 9.4% followed by &lt;em&gt;F. culmorum&lt;/em&gt; (5.7%), &lt;em&gt;F. proliferatum&lt;/em&gt; (3.8%) and &lt;em&gt;F. graminearum &lt;/em&gt;(3.8%) based on morphological and molecular observations,</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از این مطالعه شناسایی گونه‌های &lt;em&gt;Fusarium&lt;/em&gt; همراه با ریشه و بنه زعفران و ارزیابی فعالیت آنزیم‌های مخرب دیواره سلولی تولید شده توسط آن­ها می باشد. به منظور بررسی گونه‌های &lt;em&gt;Fusarium&lt;/em&gt;، طی فصل رشدی 1397 در مجموع 53 نمونه ریشه و بنه به طور تصادفی از مزارع زعفران استان خراسان جنوبی جمع­آوری شد. پس از شستشو نمونه­ها با آب مقطر استریل و ضدعفونی سطحی با هیپوکلریت سدیم یک درصد، قطعات کوچک ریشه و بنه روی محیط­های کشت‌ عمومی و اختصاصی کشت داده شدند. تهیه کشت خالص قارچ­ها به روش تک اسپور و نوک ریسه کردن روی محیط کشت‌ آب - آگار دو درصد انجام شد. شناسایی قارچ­ها بر اساس مشخصات میکروسکوپی و ریخت­شناختی با توجه به کلیدهای معتبر شناسایی انجام گرفت. با توجه به خصوصیات ریخت­شناختی، گونه های &lt;em&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/em&gt;، &lt;em&gt;F. culmorum&lt;/em&gt;،&lt;em&gt;F. proliferatum&lt;/em&gt; و &lt;em&gt;F. graminearum&lt;/em&gt; شناسایی شدند. نتایج به دست آمده از تجزیه و تحلیل مولکولی با استفاده از آغازگرهای اختصاصی گونه، شناسایی ریخت­شناختی را تأیید کرد. نتایج نشان داد که 6/22 درصد از نمونه­های زعفران توسط گونه­های &lt;em&gt;Fusarium&lt;/em&gt; آلوده بودند. بر اساس مشاهدات ریخت­شناختی و مولکولی، &lt;em&gt;F. oxysporum&lt;/em&gt;به­عنوان گونه‌ غالب با بیشترین درصد فراوانی در نمونه­ها به میزان 4/9 درصد پس از آن &lt;em&gt;F. culmorum&lt;/em&gt; (7/5 درصد)،&lt;em&gt;F. proliferatum&lt;/em&gt; (8/3 درصد) و &lt;em&gt;F. graminearum&lt;/em&gt; (8/3 درصد) بود. نتایج نشان داد که تمام جدایه‌های &lt;em&gt;Fusarium&lt;/em&gt; قادر به تولید آنزیم‌های مخرب دیواره سلولی و به طور عمده سلولاز و زایلاناز می‌باشند. سطوح فعالیت آنزیم­های سلولز، زایلاناز و پکتیناز در این مطالعه بالاتر از فعالیت لیپاز در همه جدایه­های مورد بررسی بود. تجزیه و تحلیل روند فعالیت آنزیم‌های مخرب دیواره سلولی نشان داد که برای بسیاری از جدایه‌های مورد بررسی حداکثر سطح فعالیت سلولاز، زایلاناز، پکتیناز و لیپاز به ترتیب در 72، 96، 144 و 192 ساعت پس از کشت در محیط مایع مشاهده شد. سپس فعالیت­های آنزیمی به تدریج با گذشت زمان کاهش یافت، تا اینکه در سطوح ثابتی باقی ماند. بر اساس منابع موجود &lt;em&gt;F. graminearum&lt;/em&gt;، &lt;em&gt;F. culmorum&lt;/em&gt; و &lt;em&gt;F. proliferatum&lt;/em&gt; برای اولین بار در ایران از روی زعفران گزارش می شوند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ریخت‌شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زایلاناز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سلولاز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شناسایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مولکولی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analysis of Competitiveness of Iran&#039;s Saffron Exporting Companies in Global Markets</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل رقابت پذیری بنگاه های صادرکننده زعفران ایران در بازارهای جهانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>261</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>276</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">90925</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2019.174203.1337</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>کرباسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>     Recent multi-year experiences in Iran show that reliance on income from the sale of crude oil leads to instability in export earnings.  In order to reduce the dependence of the Iranian economy on crude oil exports, export policies should be directed towards export of non-oil commodities, including exports of agricultural products. Saffron is one of the most important export items of the agricultural sector and medicinal plants. However, its production and export has not grown exponentially in recent years despite growing allocation of land and production. The results of various studies in  have shown that one of the main reasons for failure of Iranian companies in the world market for exporting medicinal herbs is decline in competitiveness in these markets in recent years. Therefore, this study seeks to examine factors affecting competitiveness of Iran&#039;s saffron exporting companies in global markets. Competitiveness measurements using symmetric revealed comparative advantage index and analysis of its influencing factors were analyzed using the Porter Diamond Competitive Model and Fractional Logit Panel regression model. The statistics and data were collected through collecting questionnaires from 35 saffron exporter companies for 2011-2016. The results showed that the six components of the Porter diamond model including demand conditions, factor conditions, supporting industries, firm strategy, state and unpredictable events affect the competitive situation of the companies under study. Accordingly, observance of quantitative and qualitative export standards, prevention of fluctuations in the price of saffron, reduction of exchange rate fluctuations in line with government policies, reduction of production fluctuations due to climate change by providing technical solutions and sufficient attention of companies to marketing strategies are proposed as new ways to improve the competitive situation of the companies being studied.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تجارب چندساله اخیر ایران نشان می­دهد که تکیه اقتصاد به درآمد حاصل از فروش نفت خام، بی­ثباتی درآمد صادراتی را به­دنبال دارد. به­منظور کاهش وابستگی اقتصاد ایران به صادرات نفت خام، جهت­گیری سیاست­های صادراتی باید به سود صدور کالاهای غیرنفتی از جمله صادرات محصولات کشاورزی تغییر یابد. زعفران یکی از اقلام مهم صادراتی ایران است که در سال­های اخیر علی رغم افزایش سطح زیرکشت و تولید ، میزان صادرات آن رشد چشمگیری نداشته است. نتایج پژوهش­های مختلف در ایران نشان می­دهد یکی از دلایل مهم عدم موفقیت شرکت های ایرانی در بازار جهانی صادراتی گیاهان دارویی، کاهش قدرت رقابت­پذیری در این بازارها در سال­های اخیر است. از این رو این مطالعه بر آن است تا به بررسی عامل­های مؤثر بر رقابت پذیری شرکت­های صادرکننده زعفران ایران در بازارهای جهانی بپردازد. اندازه گیری رقابت پذیری با استفاده از شاخص مزیت نسبی آشکار شده متقارن و تحلیل عوامل اثر گذار بر آن با استفاده از الگوی رقابتی الماس پورتر و مدل رگرسیونی پانل لاجیت کسری مورد تجزیه و تحلیل قرار گرفت. آمار و اطلاعات لازم از  طریق جمع آوری پرسشنامه از 35 شرکت صادرکننده زعفران برای سالهای 1395- 1390 به دست آمد. نتایج نشان داد عوامل شش­گانه الگوی الماس پورتر شامل شرایط تقاضا، شرایط عوامل، صنایع پشتیبان، استراتژی بنگاه، دولت و اتفاقات و حوادث غیر قابل پیش بینی، بر وضعیت رقابتی شرکت­های مورد مطالعه اثرگذار می­باشند. بر این اساس رعایت استاندادهای صادراتی به لحاظ کمی و کیفی، جلوگیری از نوسانات قیمتی زعفران، کاهش نوسانات نرخ ارز متناسب با سیاست­های دولت، کاهش نوسانات تولیدی به دلیل تغییرات اقلیمی با ارائه راهکارهای فنی و توجه کافی شرکت­هابه استراتژی­های بازاریابی در کوتاه­مدت و بلند­مدت به عنوان پیشنهاد جهت بهبود وضعیت رقابتی شرکت­های مورد مطالعه مطرح می شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رقابت پذیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صادرات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی الماس پورتر</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating Afghan farmers&#039; willingness to continue cultivation of Saffron (Case study: Herat Province)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر تمایل کشاورزان افغانستان به تداوم کشت زعفران (مطالعه موردی: استان هرات)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>277</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>293</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">93893</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2019.177614.1340</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شکراله</FirstName>
					<LastName>شعبان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آرش</FirstName>
					<LastName>دوراندیش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>قربانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron is one of the agricultural products considered for cultivation by Afghan farmers in recent years. Investigation of willingness of farmers in this region to continue cultivating this crop is especially important in developing this product and promoting it at the global level due to the exceptional position of Afghanistan’s saffron in the world. Therefore, the aim of this study is investigating willingness of farmers in Herat to continue production of Saffron. Data was collected using the random sampling method and completing questionnaires and performing personal interviews with saffron farmers in the Herat province in 2018 with 202 samples. The willingness to continue cultivating saffron farmers in the Herat Province was classified into four categories: very low, low, medium, and high. The results of using the ordered Logit model show that the variables yield, price, size of the farmer&#039;s household, saffron cultivation experience and capital have a positive influence on increasing willingness to continue cultivation of this product by saffron producers. On the other hand, non-agricultural income, age and availability of labor have an inverse effect on willingness to continue saffron production. At the end, suggestions are provided to achieve the research’s goal. These include provision of low-cost facilities for farmers to provide easier and cheaper access to utilization of new technologies such as use of laboratories, improvement of packaging quality and drying equipment.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زعفران یکی از محصولات کشاورزی است که در سال­های اخیر مورد توجه کشاورزان افغانستان قرار گرفته است. با توجه به موقعیت استثنایی زعفران افغانستان در دنیا، بررسی تمایل کشاورزان این منطقه به تداوم کشت این محصول از اهمیت ویژه­ای در توسعه این محصول و ارتقاء سطح جهانی آن برخوردار است. لذا هدف از انجام این پژوهش بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر تمایل به تداوم کشت زعفران در بین کشاورزان استان هرات افغانستان می­باشد. آمار و اطلاعات این پژوهش از طریق ابزار پرسشنامه و مصاحبه­ی حضوری با زعفران­کاران استان هرات، به روش نمونه­گیری تصادفی ساده با 202 نمونه در سال 1397 تهیه و میزان تمایل به تداوم کشت زعفران­کاران به 4 گروه خیلی کم، کم، متوسط و زیاد طبقه­بندی شد. نتایج به‌کارگیری الگوی لاجیت ترتیبی نشان داد متغیرهای عملکرد، قیمت، اندازه خانوار کشاورز، تجربه­ی زعفران­کاری و سرمایه در دسترس، اثر مثبتی بر افزایش تمایل به تداوم کشت این محصول توسط زعفران­کاران دارند؛ درحالی‌که متغیرهای درآمد غیرکشاورزی، سن و نیروی کار در جهت معکوس بر تمایل به تداوم زعفران­کاری اثرگذارند. در انتها پیشنهاداتی در جهت نیل به هدف پژوهش ارائه شده است. که ازجمله می­توان به اعطای تسهیلات کم ‌بهره به کشاورزان برای دسترسی آسان­تر و ارزان­تر به نهاده­های تولید و به‌کارگیری تکنولوژی­های نوین نظیر تجهیز آزمایشگاه­ها، بهبود کیفیت بسته­بندی­ها و تجهیزات خشک‌کردن محصول اشاره کرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تمایل به تداوم کشت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لاجیت ترتیبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هرات</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of the efficiency of Lazy Algorithm in Estimating Yield of Saffron Based on Climatic Parameters</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی کارایی الگوریتم تنبل در تخمین عملکرد محصول زعفران بر اساس پارامترهای اقلیمی (مطالعه موردی: بیرجند)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>295</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>304</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">102768</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2020.174803.1338</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فهیمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>خادم پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری گروه علوم و مهندسی آب، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>خاشعی سیوکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه علوم و مهندسی آب، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2863-8483</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهدانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron as the most precise agricultural and pharmaceutical product of the world has a specific place in industrial and export products of Iran. Nowadays, Iran is the largest producer and exporter of saffron in world and up to 93.7% of production of this valuable commodity belongs to Iran. Despite the antiquity of saffron cultivation and added value of this product compared to other current crops of Iran, fewer shares of new technologies are dedicated to saffron and its production is mainly based on indigenous knowledge.In thispaper, multiple models are employed to evaluate and develop the performance of KStar and LWL in order to get an estimate on production yield of saffron based on climate parameters. Thecalibration and evaluation of models are obtained from the statistics of crop yield and climate factors betweenyears 1988–2017. In order to evaluate the employed models, the following statistical criteria were used: Coefficient of Determination (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;), Mean Absolute Error (MAE), Root Mean Square Error (RMSE) and Nash- Sutcliffe (NSE). From among the proposed models, the KStar model is in the e-scenario with an R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; of 1.00, MAE and RMSE of 0.00 and NSE of 1.00, which has good accuracy in estimating production yield of the saffron plant. This precision of the KStar model has made it easy to estimate performance of saffron in different areas of the country based on the data available at different stations.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زعفران به عنوان با ارزش­ترین محصول کشاورزی و دارویی جهان جایگاه ویژه­ای در بین محصولات صنعتی و صادراتی ایران دارد. در حال حاضر، ایران بزرگترین تولید کننده و صادرکننده زعفران در جهان است، به طوری که بیش از 7/93 درصد تولید جهانی این محصول گران­بها به ایران اختصاص دارد. اما علیرغم قدمت کشت زعفران و ارزش افزوده این محصول در مقایسه با بسیاری از محصولات زراعی رایج در کشور سهم کمتری از فناوری­های نوین را به خود اختصاص داده و تولید آن عمدتاً بر دانش بومی متکی بوده است. پژوهش حاضر با هدف توسعه و ارزیابی کارایی مدل­های KStar و LWL در محاسبه عملکرد محصول گیاه زعفران بر اساس پارامترهای اقلیمی انجام گرفته است. کالیبراسیون و صحت­سنجی مدل­ها با استفاده از آمار عملکرد این محصول و عوامل اقلیمی طی سال­های 2017-1998 صورت پذیرفت. به منظور ارزیابی مدل­ها از شاخص­های آماری ضریب تبیین (R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;)، میانگین قدر مطلق خطا (MAE)، ریشه متوسط خطای مربعات (RMSE) و نش- ساتکلیف  (NSE) استفاده شد. از مدل­های پیشنهادی، مدل KStar در سناریوی e با 00/1 = R&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;، 00/0 =MAE ،  00/0 = RMSEو 00/1 = NSE می­باشند که از دقت مناسبی در تخمین عملکرد گیاه زعفران داشت. این دقت بالای مدل KStar، باعث شده که بتوان به راحتی عملکرد زعفران را در مناطق مختلف زعفران کاری کشور بر اساس داده­های موجود در ایستگاه­های مختلف تخمین زد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شاخص‌های آماری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گیاه زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">KStar</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">LWL</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
