<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analysis of social psychological effects (job security and quality of work life) on increasing job satisfaction of saffron farmers in Bafgh city</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل اثرات روانشناختی اجتماعی (امنیت شغلی و کیفیت زندگی کاری) بر افزایش رضایت شغلی زعفران‌کاران شهرستان بافق</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>275</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>283</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">66476</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.95424.1253</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>راضیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>جماعتی اردکانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی گروه روانشناسی، دانشکده علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی، دانشگاه اردکان.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Job security and improving the quality of work life are among the factors that can affect the job satisfaction of saffron workers and increase their productivity. The present study aims to analyze the social psychological effects (job security and quality of work life) on increasing job satisfaction of saffron Farmers in Bafgh city, which is done using correlation analysis. The statistical population consists of all saffron Farmers in Bafgh city. Using Morgan table, a sample of 205 individuals is selected through simple random sampling and tested by job security, work life quality and job satisfaction questionnaires. Data are analyzed by Pearson correlation coefficient and linear regression. The results show that job security and quality of work life have a significant relationship with job satisfaction (p &lt; .01). Also, job security and quality of work life significantly predict job satisfaction (p &lt; .001). The results of the research indicate that these two variables (job security and quality of work life) are important variables for optimal job satisfaction among saffron farmers. Therefore, it is suggested that the relevant agricultural organizations try to create a safe, interesting and stimulating working environment to increase commitment, creativity and hard work. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Keywords: job security, quality of work life, job satisfaction, saffron farmers.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">احساس امنیت شغلی و بهبود کیفیت زندگی کاری از جمله عواملی هستند که ممکن است رضایت شغلی زعفران­کاران را تأثیر قرار دهد و باعث افزایش کارایی آنان شود. هدف از پژوهش حاضر تحلیل اثرات روانشناختی اجتماعی (امنیت شغلی و کیفیت زندگی کاری) در افزایش رضایت شغلی زعفران­کاران شهرستان بافق بود که با استفاده از تحلیل همبستگی انجام گرفته است. جامعه آماری شامل تمامی زعفران­کاران شهرستان بافق بودند که با استفاده از جدول مورگان نمونه­ای به حجم 205 نفر به روش نمونه­گیری تصادفی ساده انتخاب شدند و با پرسشنامه­های امنیت شغلی، کیفیت زندگی کاری و رضایت شغلی مورد آزمون قرار گرفتند. داده­ها با استفاده از روش­های آماری ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و رگرسیون خطی تجزیه و تحلیل شدند. نتایج نشان داد که امنیت شغلی و کیفیت زندگی کاری رابطه معنی­داری با رضایت شغلی داشتند (01/0&gt;p). همچنین امنیت شغلی و کیفیت زندگی کاری به طور معنی­داری رضایت شغلی را پیش­بینی کردند (001/0&gt;p). نتایج تحقیق حاکی از آن است که این دو متغیر (امنیت شغلی و کیفیت زندگی کاری)، متغیرهای مهمی در جهت رضایت شغلی مطلوب در زعفران­کاران بودند، بنابراین پیشنهاد می­شود سازمان­های کشاورزی مربوطه سعی کنند محیط کاری امن، جالب و برانگیزاننده به وجود آورند تا تعهد، خلاقیت و سختکوشی افزایش یابد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">امنیت شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رضایت شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران‌کاران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کیفیت زندگی کاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_66476_60ba87740c2bd52c6b5df2b72dd3811e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
