<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Application of Multifunctional Ecological Footprint in Sustainability Analysis of Saffron Production in Southern Khorasan</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کاربرد ردپای اکولوژیک چند کارکردی در تحلیل پایداری تولید زعفران در خراسان جنوبی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>491</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>503</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">81650</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2019.119069.1290</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید محمد جعفر</FirstName>
					<LastName>اصفهانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار توسعه کشاورزی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران ، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>خزاعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی بخش مدیریت، اقتصاد و حسابداری، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The ecological footprint (EF) is a strong indicator of sustainability analysis that is used today in scientific communities. The footprint index determines the space required to support an activity by the average area needed to provide resources and absorb waste in term of global hectare (ghaGha). In this study, due to the significant increase in saffron production in recent years, the sustainability of saffron production in southern Khorasan province as one of the most important saffron production centers in the country was investigated. The data for this research was collected through questionnaires and interviews with the 396 farmers in 2017. According to the different yield and consumption of inputs in different years, sustainability investigation was carried out for the first to sixth years. For this purpose, the amount of bioproductve land directly required for the production of the saffron was considered as an indicator of the direct ecological footprint and the amount of bioproductve land needed to absorb the waste generated by the production process as indirect ecological footprint. The results of this study showed that the average indirect EF of saffron was 2.02 global hectare (ghaGha), which 0.07 was related to on farm and 0.13 gha Gha was related to off farm emission. The highest EF was allocated to the first year of production. &lt;br /&gt;The multi-functional ecological footprint showed that the EF land was 0.01 gha, EF revenue 0.63 gha Gha and EF yield was 0.003 ghaGha. Comparing the results of this study with the results of other agricultural sector studies conducted in Iran and elsewhere in the world showed thatGeneraly it seems that saffron production is relatively sustainable farming compared to other agricultural productscrops.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با توجه به اثرات سوء مصرف نهاده‌های خارجی در بخش کشاورزی و وابستگی این بخش به انرژی‌های مستقیم و غیرمستقیم، تحلیل پایداری تولیدات کشاورزی از اهمیت ویژه‌ای برخوردار شده است. شاخص ردپای اکولوژیک یک شاخص قوی در تحلیل پایداری است که امروزه در مجامع علمی از آن استفاده می‌شود. این شاخص فضای لازم برای حمایت از یک فعالیت را بوسیله میانگین مساحت لازم برای فراهم آوردن منابع مصرفی و جذب مواد زائد برحسب هکتار جهانی تعیین می‌کند. در این مطالعه با توجه به افزایش قابل ملاحظه تولید زعفران در سال‌های اخیر، پایداری تولید زعفران در استان خراسان جنوبی به عنوان یکی از مهمترین مراکز تولید زعفران کشور بررسی شد. اطلاعات لازم برای این پژوهش از طریق پرسشنامه و مصاحبه رودررو با 396 کشاورز در سال 1396 جمع آوری شد و با توجه به عملکرد و مصرف نهاده در سال‌های مختلف، محاسبات مربوط به پایداری برای سال‌های مختلف اول تا ششم انجام شد. برای این منظور میزان زمین بهره­ور زیستی که به طور مستقیم برای تولید محصول لازم است به عنوان شاخص ردپای اکولوژیک مستقیم و میزان زمین لازم برای جذب مواد زائد حاصل از فرآیند تولید به عنوان ردپای غیر مستقیم در نظر گرفته شد. نتایج مطالعه نشان داد که میانگین شاخص ردپای اکولوژیک غیرمستقیم زعفران 20/0 هکتار جهانی بود که 07/0 به انتشارات داخل مزرعه و 13/0 به انتشارات خارج مزرعه مربوط می‌شد. بیشترین شاخص ردپا به سال اول تولید اختصاص داشت. شاخص ردپای چند کارکردی نشان داد که شاخص ردپای اکولوژیک بر حسب زمین 01/0 هکتار جهانی، برحسب درآمد 63/0 هکتار جهانی و بر حسب عملکرد 003/0 هکتار جهانی است. مقایسه نتایج این مطالعه با نتایج مطالعات دیگر محصولات بخش کشاورزی که در ایران و سایر نقاط جهان انجام شده است نشان داد که تولید زعفران در حالت نسبتاً پایدارتری نسبت به سایر محصولات کشاورزی قرار دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ردپای اکولوژیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضریب تعادل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گازهای گلخانه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هکتار جهانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_81650_150650e032687b8d437e25cee84e1a2d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
