<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Effect of micronutrient foliar application on quantitative and qualitative traits of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tabatabaeian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Agronomy, Isfahan (Khorasgan) Branch, Islamic Azad University, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Saeed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hassanian</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc student., Ardestan Branch, Islamic Azad University, Ardestan, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Azam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kadkhodaie</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D., Department of Agronomy, Isfahan (Ardestan) Branch, Islamic Azad University, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This research was carried out with the aim of studying the effect of zinc and potassium levels as foliar application on quantitative and qualitative traits of saffron (Crocus sativa) in Natanz city (village Badrude) in the second year of agriculture during 2019. The experiment was done as factorial layout based on a randomized complete block design with three replications. Elements such as KNO3 at the levels of control (K1), 5 in thousand (K2) and 10 in thousand (K3) and Zn-EDTA at the levels of control (Z1), 5 in thousand (Z2) and 10 in thousand (Z3) were the treatments. The studied traits included quantitative traits of fresh and dry weight of the girl&#039;s corm, fresh and dry weight of mother corm, fresh and dry yield of the flower, fresh dry yield of the stigma, qualitative traits of Crocin, picocrocin and safranal. The results showed that K2 and K3 levels increased the quantitative traits, especially at K3 level. While spraying zinc only at the Z2 level quantitative traits increased and it had no significant effect on qualitative traits. The application of potassium fertilizer at the K3 level along with the Z2 had the greatest effect on increasing the quantitative traits of saffron. Perhaps one of the reasons for increasing flower yield can be attributed to the positive effects of potassium and zinc on the photosynthetic system of the plant. This increase in the amount of photosynthesis and metabolism, in turn, affects the amount of stigma production and increases  dry weight of the stigma. As a result of potassium spraying, amount of crocin and picrocrocin increased from K1 to K3 by 18 and 13 %, and safranal increased from K1 to K2 and K3 increased by 30% and 48%, respectively. In the present study, there was a positive and significant correlation between the amount of Crocin, Picrocrocin and Safranal contents with quantitative characteristics in saffron. It can be said that quality traits are influenced by quantitative traits and yield components of saffron. Therefore, flowering and flower yield of saffron is also effective in improving its quality.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2020</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>147</start>
					<end>163</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_94085_39579e9b566f7c5a62cd47e6cb85c5b8.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2019.179188.1342</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Optimizing the effect of mother corm and urban waste compost levels on flower and corm yield of saffron using surface-response modeling in the first year</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Parsapour</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc. student in Agroecology, Department of Agrotechnology, College of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parviz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rezvani Moghaddam</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Agrotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Surur</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khorramdel</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associated Professor, Department of Agrotechnology,Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Response surface methodology (RSM) is defined as a set of mathematical and statistical techniques that are used to optimize yield of a product. In order to study the effects of urban waste compost and corm rates on flower yield of saffron using RSM, an experiment was conducted at the Research Field of the Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran during the growing season of 2017-2018. The treatments were determined based on low and high levels of urban waste compost (0 and 20 t.ha-1, respectively) and corm weight (5 and 15 t.ha-1, respectively). These were computed by using Minitab V. 17. Dry weight of stigma, dry weight of style, fresh weight of flower, flower number, corm number, dry weight of corm, and number of buds per corm were calculated as dependent variables and changes of these variables were evaluated by using a regression model. Lack-of-fit test was used to evaluate the quality of the fitted model. The adequacy of the model was tested by analysis of variance. In general, the full quadratic polynomial equation was tested to determine significance of the model and the components (such as linear, squared and first-order interaction terms). The quality of the fitted model was judged using the determination coefficient (R2). The results show that the effect of linear component on all traits studied except fresh weight of flower, dry weight of corm 0-4g, and number of buds per corm 0-4 and 8-4 grams were significant. The effect of total grade two had a significant effect on the traits of flower number, fresh weight of flower, dry weight of stigma, dry weight of style, number of daughter corms per 0-4, 4-8 and &gt;8 grams, dry weight of corm per 4-8 and &gt;8 grams and number of buds per &gt;8 grams was significant. Also, the interaction effect of two factors of urban waste compost and weight corm on the number of flowers, fresh weight of flower, dry weight of stigma, dry weight of style, number of daughter corms per 4-8 and &gt;8 grams, dry weight of corm 4-8 and &gt;8 grams, and number of buds per corm &gt;8 grams were significant. Lack of fit test had no significant effect on the studied traits. The full square model for the response variables gave insignificant lack-of-fit indicating that the data of experiment were satisfactorily explained. The highest flower number, fresh weight of flower, stigma dry weight and style dry weight were observed for 5 t.ha-1 corm+ 20 t.ha-1 compost. Optimum of corm weight and urban waste compost and desirability for the traits related to flower and corm with 5 t.ha-1, 20 t.ha-1and d = 0.92 were urban waste compost with 12 t.ha-1, 20 t.ha-1and d = 0.95, respectively. Based on the results, municipal waste compost and corm weight had a positive effect on most of the studied traits.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2020</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>165</start>
					<end>184</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_95743_438152f3e714f44f102332a1d57e9851.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2019.184094.1350</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Floristic study of weeds of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) fields in Cheshmesaran district in Azadshar</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Kambiz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khormali</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc.  in Identification and Weeds Control, Plant Production Department, College of Agriculture and Natural Resources, Gonbad Kavous University.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ebrahim</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Gholamalipour Alamdari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department Plant Production, College of Agriculture and Natural Resources, Gonbad Kavous University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zaraie</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department Plant Production, College of Agriculture and Natural Resources, Gonbad Kavous University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Zeinab</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Avarseji</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department Plant Production, College of Agriculture and Natural Resources, Gonbad Kavous University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Leila</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ahangar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Golestan Province, Gonbad Kavous, Gonbad Kavous University, College of Agriculture and Natural Resources, Plant Production Department. BOX. 163.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>A research was conducted to study floristic of weeds of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) fields located in Cheshmesaran district in Azadshar to report distribution and species diversity of weeds population. For this purpose, saffron fields under cultivation over 3 hectares was identified in three regions, including Narab, Vamenan and Tillabad village. Identification and sampling of weeds was done in vegetative growth stage of saffron (daughter corms) in 2017. 45 quadrates were used for each farm and then number and type of weed species each quadrat was counted separately. Weeds species based on Persian name, scientific name, genus, family, leaf shape, photosynthetic pathway, growth habit and life cycle were classified. Results of species composition of weeds in saffron fields of triple regions showed that Narab region with 54 species had the largest number of species. Veronica persica Poir weed and Stellaria midia in Narab and Veronica persica Poir in Vamenan were the dominant weed in these regions which had the highest relative density and frequency. In return, Hordeum murinum in the Tillabad region had the greatest density and frequency. This could be due to the differences in geographical coordinates, climatic conditions of sampling locations, competitive ability of weeds and management methods to control them in saffron fields. The results of species diversity of weeds showed that Narab and Tilabad included highest and lowest dominance index, which were about 0.13 and 0.08, respectively. In return, the highest Menhinick richness, Margalev and uniformiy of weeds were recorded in the Narab region about 0.67, 2.55 and 0.97, respectively. Narab and Vamenan regions also had maximum numerical value of Simpson (0.92) and Shannon- Wiener indices (2.64). Overall, the results showed that saffron fields of both regions of Narab and Vamenan were most similar in term of weed species number and population indices.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2020</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>185</start>
					<end>209</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_101554_adc059a6c255b3e0383f4ccfd7bff98a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2019.183023.1347</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Cloning and Bioinformatics Investigation on CCD4a and CCD4b Genes from Iranian Saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Habibzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD. Student, Department of Plant Breeding and Biotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ebrahim</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Dorani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Department of Plant Breeding and Biotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Tabriz, Tabriz</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ziaratnia</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Food Biotechnology, Research Institute of Food Science and Technology (RIFST), Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mostafa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Valizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Department of Plant Breeding and Biotechnology, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Tabriz, Tabriz, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Saffron is one of the most expensive spices and natural colors used in various food, pharmaceutical and cosmetic industries. In recent years, a family of enzymes that digest carotenoid substrates into double bonds are identified and introduced in plants. This family is of enzymes Carotenoid Cleavage Dioxygenase (CCD) enzymes. In this study, two isoforms of this gene were cloned and sequenced due to the importance of CCD genes in biosynthesis of apocarotenoids. Bioinformatics analyses including phylogenetic relationships and protein structures were evaluated. 3D modeling of these proteins was done by homologous modeling and using the Swiss Model database after selecting the appropriate pattern. The Ramachandran plot was drawn in order to validate the structure of the 3D model. The results show that the two CCD4a and CCD4b isoforms have both exons and one intron. In silico analysis, the physicochemical properties of CsCCD4a and CsCCD4b proteins also show that the proteins derived from these two isoforms are similar in terms of molecular weight, amino acids, isoelectric points, aliphatic index, instability index and solubility. The results of study of 3D structures resulted in proposal of similar structures for two isoforms. The results of this study can provide valuable information on the behavior and response of CCD4 enzyme in the pathway for synthesis of apricotines in saffron, and these results can be useful in future protein engineering programs.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2020</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>211</start>
					<end>229</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_99689_1ad74437abf8d99a1d8d4b553c4e5980.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2019.182490.1343</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Evaluation of Secondary Metabolites, Total Phenol Content and Antioxidant Properties of Petal in Saffron Populations Under Conventional and once Irrigation Conditions</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">parisa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">sheykholeslami</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc. Student of Department of Plant Production and Genetics, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Zanjan, Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Jalal</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Saba</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor  of Department of Plant Production and Genetics, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Zanjan, Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Farid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shekari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Department of Plant Production and Genetics, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Zanjan, Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azimi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Department of Plant Production and Genetics, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Zanjan, Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Azam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Maleki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Postdoc. Researcher of Department of Plant Production and Genetics, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Zanjan, Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Each year a large amount of saffron petals which make up a significant proportion of saffron flowers are discarded as waste while this part of the flower also contains compounds such as phenol, anthocyanin, flavonoid and antioxidant properties. Two separate experiments were conducted using randomized complete block design with three replications in order to evaluate secondary metabolites, total phenol content and antioxidant capacity of petals in eight saffron populations under normal and once irrigation conditions  at the research farm of university of Zanjan on three year old saffron plants. In order to measure and determine secondary metabolites, total phenol content and antioxidant properties of saffron petal extract, UV-Visible  Metering Spectra, folin-Ciocalteu and DPPH were used, respectively. Combined analysis of variance under normal and once irrigation conditions showed that the difference between secondary metabolites and antioxidant properties was not significant in the two irrigation conditions. While, total phenol content was significantly higher under the once irrigation condition, the  Torbat-e-jam population had highest total phenol content (86.66 mg gallic acid per gram of methanolic extract) under this condition. In both irrigation conditions, the evaluated populations exhibited suitable amounts of picocrocin, safranal, phenol and antioxidant properties which can be considered to be of use for us in the food, pharmaceutical and chemical industries.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2020</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>231</start>
					<end>242</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_99688_fac029c020ed1423e205b33869f76850.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2019.187000.1352</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Evaluation of cell wall degrading enzymes of Fusarium species associated with root and corm of saffron in South Khorasan province</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Nima</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khaledi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Seed and Plant Certification and Registration Research Institute, Agricultural Research, Education and Extension Organization (AREEO), Karaj, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The aim of this study is to identify  Fusarium species associated with root and corm of saffron and evaluate extracellular enzyme activity secreted by them. In order to study the species of Fusarium, a total of 53 root and corm samples were randomly collected from saffron fields of the South Khorasan province during 2017 growing season. After washing the samples with sterile water and disinfected the surface with 1% sodium hypochlorite, small pieces of root and corm were cultured on general and specific culture media. Purification of fungal colonies was performed using single spore and hyphal tip methods on 2% water agar medium. Identification of fungi based on the microscopic and morphological characteristics was performed with valid identification keys. The F. oxysporum, F. graminearum, F. culmorum and F. proliferatum species were identified based on morphological characters. The results obtained from molecular analysis using species-specific primers confirm morphological identification. The results reveal that 22.6% of saffron samples are contaminated by Fusarium species. F. oxysporum is the predominant species with the highest isolation frequency in samples of 9.4% followed by F. culmorum (5.7%), F. proliferatum (3.8%) and F. graminearum (3.8%) based on morphological and molecular observations,</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2020</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>243</start>
					<end>259</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_101557_00cfc56c96b030a3b1a4ccf7ee6f6c91.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2020.184121.1349</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Analysis of Competitiveness of Iran's Saffron Exporting Companies in Global Markets</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">seyed hosein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D., Student of Agricultural Economic Department, Agricultural Faculty, Ferdowsi university of Mashhad, Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Karbasi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor of Agricultural Economic Department, Agricultural Faculty, Ferdowsi university of Mashhad, Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Agricultural Economic Department, Agricultural Faculty, Ferdowsi university of Mashhad, Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>     Recent multi-year experiences in Iran show that reliance on income from the sale of crude oil leads to instability in export earnings.  In order to reduce the dependence of the Iranian economy on crude oil exports, export policies should be directed towards export of non-oil commodities, including exports of agricultural products. Saffron is one of the most important export items of the agricultural sector and medicinal plants. However, its production and export has not grown exponentially in recent years despite growing allocation of land and production. The results of various studies in  have shown that one of the main reasons for failure of Iranian companies in the world market for exporting medicinal herbs is decline in competitiveness in these markets in recent years. Therefore, this study seeks to examine factors affecting competitiveness of Iran&#039;s saffron exporting companies in global markets. Competitiveness measurements using symmetric revealed comparative advantage index and analysis of its influencing factors were analyzed using the Porter Diamond Competitive Model and Fractional Logit Panel regression model. The statistics and data were collected through collecting questionnaires from 35 saffron exporter companies for 2011-2016. The results showed that the six components of the Porter diamond model including demand conditions, factor conditions, supporting industries, firm strategy, state and unpredictable events affect the competitive situation of the companies under study. Accordingly, observance of quantitative and qualitative export standards, prevention of fluctuations in the price of saffron, reduction of exchange rate fluctuations in line with government policies, reduction of production fluctuations due to climate change by providing technical solutions and sufficient attention of companies to marketing strategies are proposed as new ways to improve the competitive situation of the companies being studied.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2020</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>261</start>
					<end>276</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_90925_ddee6c3fe361e159f10d80d318ff7575.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2019.174203.1337</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating Afghan farmers' willingness to continue cultivation of Saffron (Case study: Herat Province)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shukrullah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shwoban</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc. Student of Agricultural Economic Department, Agricultural Faculty, Ferdowsi university of  Mashhad, Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Arash</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Dourandish</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Agricultural Economic Department, Agricultural Faculty, Ferdowsi university of  Mashhad, Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghorbani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor  of Agricultural Economic Department, Agricultural Faculty, Ferdowsi university of  Mashhad, Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Saffron is one of the agricultural products considered for cultivation by Afghan farmers in recent years. Investigation of willingness of farmers in this region to continue cultivating this crop is especially important in developing this product and promoting it at the global level due to the exceptional position of Afghanistan’s saffron in the world. Therefore, the aim of this study is investigating willingness of farmers in Herat to continue production of Saffron. Data was collected using the random sampling method and completing questionnaires and performing personal interviews with saffron farmers in the Herat province in 2018 with 202 samples. The willingness to continue cultivating saffron farmers in the Herat Province was classified into four categories: very low, low, medium, and high. The results of using the ordered Logit model show that the variables yield, price, size of the farmer&#039;s household, saffron cultivation experience and capital have a positive influence on increasing willingness to continue cultivation of this product by saffron producers. On the other hand, non-agricultural income, age and availability of labor have an inverse effect on willingness to continue saffron production. At the end, suggestions are provided to achieve the research’s goal. These include provision of low-cost facilities for farmers to provide easier and cheaper access to utilization of new technologies such as use of laboratories, improvement of packaging quality and drying equipment.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2020</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>277</start>
					<end>293</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_93893_fdd4eccb49ff788d3f7dd4fac3cbab96.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2019.177614.1340</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Evaluation of the efficiency of Lazy Algorithm in Estimating Yield of Saffron Based on Climatic Parameters</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fahime</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">KHadempour</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD. Student, Department of Science and Water Engineering, Faculty of Agriculture, Ph.D. Student of water Resource Engineering, University of Birjand, Birjand, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abbas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khashei Siuki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate professor, Department of Science and Water Engineering, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Birjand, Birjand, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Behdani</namePart>
				<affiliation>professor, Department of Agronomy and Plant Breeding, Faculty of Agriculture, University of Birjand, Birjand, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2020</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Saffron as the most precise agricultural and pharmaceutical product of the world has a specific place in industrial and export products of Iran. Nowadays, Iran is the largest producer and exporter of saffron in world and up to 93.7% of production of this valuable commodity belongs to Iran. Despite the antiquity of saffron cultivation and added value of this product compared to other current crops of Iran, fewer shares of new technologies are dedicated to saffron and its production is mainly based on indigenous knowledge.In thispaper, multiple models are employed to evaluate and develop the performance of KStar and LWL in order to get an estimate on production yield of saffron based on climate parameters. Thecalibration and evaluation of models are obtained from the statistics of crop yield and climate factors betweenyears 1988–2017. In order to evaluate the employed models, the following statistical criteria were used: Coefficient of Determination (R2), Mean Absolute Error (MAE), Root Mean Square Error (RMSE) and Nash- Sutcliffe (NSE). From among the proposed models, the KStar model is in the e-scenario with an R2 of 1.00, MAE and RMSE of 0.00 and NSE of 1.00, which has good accuracy in estimating production yield of the saffron plant. This precision of the KStar model has made it easy to estimate performance of saffron in different areas of the country based on the data available at different stations.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Saffron agronomy and technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University Of Torbat Heydarieh</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2383-1529</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>8</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2020</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>295</start>
					<end>304</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_102768_cbf9076334b08ff79650b1a661a33c16.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22048/jsat.2020.174803.1338</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>