<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Genetic Diversity of Alternaria alternata the Causal Agent of Saffron Rot in Southern and Razavi Khorasan Provinces Using Molecular Markers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تنوع ژنتیکی قارچ Alternaria alternata عامل پوسیدگی زعفران با استفاده از نشانگرهای ملکولی در استان‌های خراسان رضوی و جنوبی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>331</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>346</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">67009</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.113230.1277</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>قاسم</FirstName>
					<LastName>نجاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد بیماری شناسی گیاهی، گروه گیاهپزشکی، دانشگاه ایلام</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خشنود</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوراللهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه گیاهپزشکی، دانشگاه ایلام</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Alternaria leaf spot caused by Alternaria alternata is one of the most important plant diseases in world. In order to determine genetic diversity, 50 samples were collected from saffron farms of different regions in Razavi Khorasan province (Kashmar, Torbatjam, Torbathaidaryeh, Mahvellat, Bardeskan) and South Khorasan province (Qaen, Saraian, Brjand). A. alternata isolates were isolated with Potato Dextrose Agar media, Molecular test was carried out with a set of five pairs of SSR primers after purification and identification of isolates. A total of 22 alleles were produced by SSR primers with an average of 11.1 alleles in all populations. The highest amounts of alleles were related to locus Mavellat with 14 alleles and lowest of Saraian, Birjand and Qaen with 10 alleles. A Comparison of genetic diversity parameters in eight population showed that Torbatjam population has the highest genetic diversity but lower values were estimated for Qaenat. The highest and lowest genetic distance was detected between Qaen-Mahvellat (0.328) and Bardaskan-Mahvellat (0.054), respectively. Based on dendrogram of populations revealed two distinct groups, one group contained Qaen and the other Birjand, Mavellat, Saraian, Bardaskan, Kashmar, Torbatjam and Torbat hidaryeh. Analysis of molecular variance showed that 71 percent of the genetic diversity belongs to within populations and 29% is located among populations. There was the high genetic similarity between isolates from different regions. Results in this study will be useful in breeding for saffron resistant cultivars and developing necessary control measures.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">بیماری لکه موجی با عامل Alternaria alternata یکی از مهمترین بیماری‌های گیاهی در دنیا به شمار می‌رود. برای تعیین تنوع ژنتیکی در جمعیت‌های قارچAlternaria 50 نمونه در سطح مزارع زعفران در استان‌ خراسان رضوی (کاشمر، تربت‌جام، تربت حیدریه، مه ولات، بردسکن) و استان خراسان جنوبی (قائنات، سرایان، بیرجند) جمع آوری گردید. در نهایت 50 جدایه قارچ A. alternata از نمونه‌های آلوده با استفاده از محیط کشت سیب زمینی، دکستروز، آگار جداسازی گردید. آزمایش مولکولی جدایه‌ها بعد از خالص سازی و شناسائی با استفاده از پنج جفت آغازگر ریز ماهواره انجام گرفت. در مجموع 22 آلل با میانگین 11.1 آلل در تمام جمعیت ها توسط آغازگرهای ریزماهواره تولید شد. بیشترین مقدار آلل مربوط به جمعیت مه ولات با 14 آلل و و کمترین جمعیتهای سرایان، بیرجند و قائن با 10 آلل بود. مقایسه پارامترهای تنوع ژنتیکی در هشت جمعیت نشان داد که جمعیت تربت جام بیشترین تنوع ژنتیکی را دارند. اما مقادیر پایینی برای قائنات محاسبه شده است. بیشترین و کمترین فاصله ژنتیکی بین قائن- مه ولات (328/0) و بردسکن- مه ولات (054/0) دیده شد. بر اساس دندروگرام جمعیت ها، دو گروه از همدیگر متمایز شدند؛ یک گروه شامل قائنات و دیگری بیرجند، مه ولات، سرایان، بردسکن، کاشمر، تربت جام و تربت حیدریه بود. تجزیه واریانس ملکولی نشان داد که میزان تنوع ژنتیکی در درون جمعیت 71% و بین جمعیت‌ها 29% می‌باشد. شباهت ژنتیکی بالایی بین جدایه ها از مناطق مختلف وجود داشت. نتایج به دست آمده از این مطالعه می‌تواند در اصلاح ارقام مقاوم زعفران و گسترش اقدام قرنطینه‌ای بسیار مفید باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تنوع ژنتیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لکه موجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">SSR</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_67009_792fcb6ba5651745c62b5731b2a159c8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
