<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Ranking Factors Affecting Competitive Advantage in the domestic and international markets of Iranian saffron</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رتبه بندی عوامل مؤثر بر کسب مزیت رقابتی در بازارهای داخلی و بین المللی زعفران ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">107503</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2020.211678.1373</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیرحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>توحیدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>قربانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>کرباسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>اصغرپور ماسوله</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه جامعه شناسی، دانشکده ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهروز</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسنی-مهموئی</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگر گروه اقتصاد، دانشگاه موناش استرالیا</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3616-4715</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In terms of quantity and quality, Iranian saffron has a prominent position in international markets and by leveraging existing capacity, the its revenue can be significantly increased. However, the lack of a clear competitive strategy is one of the major problems of Iranian saffron companies in the domestic and international markets to gain a competitive advantage. Therefore, the main purpose of this study is to rank the factors affecting competitive advantage in the domestic and international markets of Iranian saffron. In this regard, considering the market position theory and the resource-based view, in this study, the importance of marketing resources and competitive strategies for one of the major producers and suppliers of saffron was investigated. In this study, a pairwise comparison-based questionnaire was used to collect the company&#039;s expert opinions. Using the analytic hierarchy process method, the results of the study showed that the differentiation strategy has the most effect on gaining competitive advantage. The results also indicated that in executing the differentiation strategy, particular attention must be paid to managerial and customer relationship capabilities. Accordingly, improving financial conditions and understanding customers&#039; needs and requirements are among the approaches that lead to the development of key company capabilities and gain a competitive advantage in saffron markets.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">فقدان استراتژی مشخص رقابتی یکی از مشکلات مهم شرکت های زعفران ایرانی در بازارهای داخلی و بین المللی برای کسب مزیت رقابتی است. لذا، رتبه بندی عوامل مؤثر بر کسب مزیت رقابتی در بازارهای داخلی و بین المللی زعفران ایران هدف اصلی این مطالعه می باشد. برای این منظور، با در نظر گرفتن نظریه‌ی موقعیت بازار و دیدگاه منبع-محور، در این مطالعه اهمیت منابع بازاریابی و استراتژی های رقابتی برای یکی از شرکت های مهم تولیدکننده و عرضه کننده‌ی زعفران مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. در این مطالعه، برای جمع آوری نظرات خبرگان شرکت از پرسشنامه مقایسه زوجی استفاده شد. با استفاده از روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی، نتایج مطالعه نشان داد که استراتژی تمایز بیشترین تأثیر را در کسب مزیت رقابتی دارد. همچنین، نتایج نمایانگر آن است که در اجرای استراتژی تمایز، باید به قابلیت های مدیریتی و قابلیت های ارتباط با مشتری توجه ویژه ای داشت. بر این اساس، بهبود شرایط مالی و درک صحیح نیازها و خواسته های مشتریان از جمله راهکارهایی است که منجر به توسعه‌ی قابلیت های کلیدی شرکت و کسب مزیت رقابتی در بازار زعفران می شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دیدگاه منبع-محور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قابلیت های سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت استراتژیک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
