<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Comprehensive Look at Nitrogen and Phosphorus Use Efficiency in Saffron (Crocus Sativus L.)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نگاهی جامع به کارآیی مصرف نیتروژن و فسفر در زعفران (.&lt;i&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/i&gt; L)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>75</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>91</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">17359</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2016.17359</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>کوچکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>سیدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری اکولوژی گیاهان زراعی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron (&lt;em&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/em&gt; L.) is an annual plant from a biological aspect, but it has a perennial cycle in the field conditions. Cytological impairments such as triploid and self-incompatibility mechanisms are considered as the most important reasons for male-sterility in saffron. Therefore, saffron reproduction is made by meristems tissues and establishment of new daughter corms which are produced by the mother corms. During the growing season, mother corms deteriorate gradually with increasing daughter corms growth. Each daughter corm is considered as a mother corm for replanting in the next growing season. Duo to the life cycle of saffron as a perennial plant in the field conditions, the gradual deterioration of mother corms during the growing season and also the remobilization of nitrogen and phosphorus from aerial part to daughter corms at the end of each growing season, the study of acquisition and use efficiency of nitrogen and phosphorus in saffron is more complicated than other annual or biannual plants. Firstly, the objective of this review article is to describe the nitrogen and phosphorus concentration in aerial parts and daughter corms in saffron. In addition, relevant literature related to the most important strategies for improving nitrogen and phosphorus use efficiency is reviewed. Secondly, the relationship between nitrogen and phosphorus use efficiency in saffron is discussed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زعفران (&lt;em&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/em&gt; L.) گیاهی است که از نظر بیولوژیکی یک ساله است، اما می‌تواند در شرایط زراعی به عنوان گیاهی چند ساله مورد کشت قرار گیرد. وجود اختلالات سیتولوژیکی به صورت ژنوم تریپلوئیدی و نیز خود ناسازگاری، عوامل ایجاد پدیده عقیمی در زعفران می‌باشند. از این رو، رشد زعفران هر ساله از طریق مناطق مریستمی که در سطح بنه‌ مادری قرار دارد، انجام می‌شود. با فعال شدن این مریستم‌ها رشد بنه‌های دختری در سطح بنه مادری آغاز می‌گردد. همزمان با رشد بنه‌های دختری در طی فصل رشد، بنه مادری به تدریج رو به تحلیل می‌رود. هر بنه دختری تشکیل شده نیز به نوبه خود در فصل بعد، یک بنه مادری تلقی می‌شود که می‌تواند جهت کشت مجدد استفاده شود. به دلیل ماهیت رشد چند ساله زعفران در شرایط زراعی، تحلیل بنه‌های مادری در طی فصل رشد و انتقال عناصر غذایی از اندام‌های هوایی به بنه‌های دختری در انتهای هر فصل رشد، مطالعه مکانیسم جذب و کارایی مصرف نیتروژن و فسفر در زعفران پیچیده‌تر از گیاهان یکساله و یا دو ساله می‌باشد. در این مقاله ابتدا به توصیف مکانیسم جذب نیتروژن و فسفر در اندام‌های هوایی و بنه‌های گیاه پرداخته شده است. در ادامه مهم‌ترین عوامل مؤثر در بهبود کارایی مصرف نیتروژن و فسفر در زعفران و ارتباط بین کارایی مصرف نیتروژن و فسفر مورد بررسی قرار گرفته اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بنه‌های دختری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بنه های مادری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گیاه چندساله</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_17359_d44c0f8240887f213b274dc6173ef6cf.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effects of Row Intercropping Ratios of Chickpea and Saffron on Their Quantitative Characteristics and Yield</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اثر نسبت های کشت مخلوط ردیفی نخود و زعفران بر عملکرد و برخی خصوصیات رشدی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>93</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>103</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">17360</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2016.17360</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>قربانعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سرور</FirstName>
					<LastName>خرم دل</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>هاتفی فرجیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد اگرواکولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In order to study the effect of additive intercropping series of chickpea (&lt;em&gt;Cicer arietinum&lt;/em&gt; L.) with saffron (&lt;em&gt;Crocus sativus &lt;/em&gt;L.) on their growth criteria and yield, a field experiment was done based on a randomized complete block design with three replications at the Agricultural Research Station, Faculty of Agriculture, the Ferdowsi University of Mashhad during two growing seasons of 2012-2013 and 2013-2014. The treatment included 100% saffron+20%chickpea, 100% saffron+40%chickpea, 100% saffron+60%chickpea, 100% saffron+80%chickpea, 100% saffron+100% chickpea and their monoculture. The trait studied were plant height, yield components, biological yield and seed yield of chickpea and the number of flowers, fresh weight of flowers, fresh weight of stigma and dry weight of stigma for saffron. The results showed that saffron intercropping series had a significant impact on plant height, number of branches, number of pods, number of seeds per pod, number of seeds per plant, biological yield and seed yield of chickpea (p≤0.01). The highest biological yield and seed yield of chickpea were observed in monoculture with 608.3 and 282.9 kg.m&lt;sup&gt;-2&lt;/sup&gt; and the minimum of these were obtained in 100%saffron+100% chickpea with 122.5 and 55.94 g.m&lt;sup&gt;-2&lt;/sup&gt;, respectively. The number of flowers, fresh weight of flower, fresh weight of stigma and dry weight of stigma for saffron were significantly affected by intercropping with chickpea (p≤0.01). The highest flower number and stigma dry weight of saffron were achieved in monoculture with 103.89 and 0.47 g.m&lt;sup&gt;-2&lt;/sup&gt; and the lowest of these were obtained in 100%saffron+20% chickpea with 28.94 flowers.m&lt;sup&gt;-2&lt;/sup&gt; and 0.14 g.m&lt;sup&gt;-2&lt;/sup&gt;, respectively. By increasing the chickpea ratio from 20 to 100% at additive intercropping series with saffron, the dry weight of stigma was increased by 142, 116, 41 and 5%, respectively. Therefore, we may conclude that intercropping of saffron with nitrogen fixation plants such as chickpea seems to be a rational ecological approach for sustainable management of saffron.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به منظور بررسی تأثیر نسبت‌های کشت مخلوط افزایشی نخود با گیاه نقدینه زعفران بر خصوصیات کمی و عملکرد، آزمایشی در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با هفت تیمار و سه تکرار در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد در دو سال زراعی 1391-1393 اجرا شد. تیمارها شامل 100% زعفران+20% نخود، 100% زعفران+40% نخود، 100% زعفران+60% نخود، 100% زعفران+80% نخود، 100% زعفران+ 100% نخود و کشت خالص دو گیاه بود. صفات مورد مطالعه شامل ارتفاع بوته، تعداد شاخه فرعی، تعداد غلاف در بوته، تعداد دانه در بوته، تعداد دانه در غلاف و وزن صد دانه و عملکرد بیولوژیکی و دانه نخود و تعداد گل، وزن تر گل، وزن تر کلاله و وزن خشک کلاله زعفران بودند. نتایج نشان داد که اثر نسبت‌های کشت مخلوط با زعفران بر ارتفاع بوته، تعداد شاخه فرعی، تعداد غلاف، تعداد دانه در غلاف، تعداد دانه در بوته، عملکرد بیولوژیکی و عملکرد دانه نخود معنی‌دار بود (05/0p≤). بالاترین عملکرد بیولوژیکی و دانه نخود برای کشت خالص به ترتیب با 3/608 و 9/282 کیلوگرم در هکتار و کمترین مقادیر برای تیمار 100% زعفران+ 100% نخود به ترتیب با 5/122 و 94/55 کیلوگرم در هکتار مشاهده گردید. اثر نسبت‌های کشت مخلوط ردیفی با نخود بر تعداد گل، وزن تر گل، وزن تر کلاله و وزن خشک کلاله زعفران در سطح احتمال یک درصد معنی‌دار بود (01/0p≤). بالاترین تعداد گل و وزن خشک کلاله زعفران برای کشت خالص به ترتیب برابر با 89/103 گل در متر مربع و 47/0 گرم کلاله در متر مربع و کمترین مقادیر برای 100% زعفران+ 20% نخود به ترتیب با 94/28 گل در بوته و 14/0 گرم کلاله در متر مربع مشاهده گردید. با افزایش درصد حضور نخود از 20 درصد به 100 درصد در کشت مخلوط افزایشی با زعفران، وزن خشک کلاله به ترتیب 142، 116، 41 و 5 درصد افزایش یافت. بدین ترتیب، با توجه کشت مخلوط زعفران با گیاهان تثبیت‌کننده نیتروژن نظیر نخود را بایستی جهت بهبود عملکرد این گیاه نقدینه به عنوان راهکار جایگزین اکولوژیکی در مدیریت پایدار آن مدنظر قرار داد. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تثبیت نیتروژن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کشت مخلوط افزایشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گیاه نقدینه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وزن کلاله</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_17360_be72744d9373a22a1583cba8b10faee6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Soil and Foliar Application of Effective Microorganisms on Growth Characteristics of Saffron in the Presence of Chemical and Organic Fertilizers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر مصرف خاکی و محلول‌پاشی ریز جانداران مؤثر بر ویژگی‌های رشدی زعفران در حضور کودهای شیمیایی و آلی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>105</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>117</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">17361</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2016.17361</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>ریوندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>1دانش‌آموخته کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد سبزوار، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، سبزوار، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>مروی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد سبزوار، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، سبزوار، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>متین</FirstName>
					<LastName>جامی معینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد سبزوار، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، سبزوار، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In order to investigate the effect of effective microorganism application method on saffron growth characteristics in the presence of chemical and organic fertilizers, a field experiment was conducted at Sheshtamad County during the growing season of 2013-2014. The experiment was carried out as split plot based on a randomized complete block design with three replications. The experimental factors included effective microorganisms (EM) application method as main plots (no application, soil application and foliar application of EM) and chemical and organic fertilizers application as subplots (no application, soil application of humic acid, soil application of 20, 20, 20+TE and soil application of humic acid + 20, 20, 20+TE). The results showed that soil and foliar application of EM had no significant effect on plant height, but it significantly increased corm number, corm yield, shoot dry weight and number of buds per corm. The average corm weight was reduced in response to soil and foliar application of EM. The highest corm number (220.33), corm yield (1023.33 g m&lt;sup&gt;-2&lt;/sup&gt;) and shoot dry weight (43.02 g m&lt;sup&gt;-2&lt;/sup&gt;) were obtained in soil application of EM treatment. The maximum number of buds per corm (8.68) and average corm weight (5.10 g) were observed in foliar application and no application of EM conditions, respectively. Application of 20, 20, 20+TE and combined application of humic acid and 20, 20, 20+TE increased corm number, corm yield, shoot dry weight and number of bud per corm compared to control and soil application of humic acid. Soil application of humic acid produced the highest average corm weight. Soil and foliar application of EM improved the response of saffron growth characteristics to organic and chemical fertilizers. According to the results, soil applications of EM and 20, 20, 20+TE are recommended to produce maximum corm yield in saffron.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به‌منظور بررسی اثر روش مصرف ریزجانداران مؤثر بر ویژگی‌های رشدی زعفران در حضور کودهای شیمیایی و آلی، آزمایشی در سال زراعی 93-1392 در شهرستان ششتمد خراسان رضوی انجام شد. آزمایش به‌صورت کرت‌های خردشده در قالب طرح پایه بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار اجرا گردید. فاکتور اصلی آزمایش شامل روش مصرف ریزجانداران مؤثر (EM) در سه سطح عدم مصرف، مصرف خاکی EM و محلول‌پاشی EM و فاکتور فرعی شامل مصرف کودهای آلی و شیمیایی در چهار سطح عدم مصرف، مصرف خاکی اسید هیومیک، مصرف خاکی کود 20, 20, 20+TE و مصرف خاکی اسید هیومیک + مصرف خاکی 20, 20, 20+TE بودند. نتایج نشان داد که مصرف خاکی و محلول‌پاشی EM ارتفاع بوته را تحت تأثیر قرار نداد، اما باعث افزایش معنی‌دار تعداد بنه، عملکرد بنه، وزن خشک اندام هوایی و تعداد جوانه در هر بنه در مقایسه با شرایط عدم مصرف EM گردید. متوسط وزن بنه در واکنش به مصرف خاکی و محلول‌پاشی EM کاهش یافت. بیشترین تعداد بنه (33/220 در مترمربع)، عملکرد بنه (33/1023 گرم در مترمربع) و وزن خشک اندام هوایی (02/43 گرم در مترمربع) در تیمار مصرف خاکی EM، بیشترین تعداد جوانه در بنه (68/8) در تیمار محلول‌پاشی EM و بیشترین متوسط وزن بنه (10/5 گرم) در شرایط عدم مصرف EM به دست آمد. استفاده از کود 20, 20, 20+TE و همچنین مصرف تلفیقی اسید هیومیک و کود 20, 20, 20+TE باعث افزایش تعداد بنه، عملکرد بنه، وزن خشک اندام‌ هوایی و تعداد جوانه در بنه در مقایسه با شرایط عدم مصرف کود و همچنین مصرف خاکی اسید هیومیک گردید. بیشترین متوسط وزن بنه در تیمار مصرف خاکی اسید هیومیک به‌دست آمد. مصرف خاکی و محلول‌پاشی EM باعث بهبود واکنش ویژگی‌های رشدی زعفران به مصرف کودهای آلی و شیمیایی گردید. با توجه به نتایج، مصرف خاکی EM و کود 20, 20, 20+TE جهت تولید حداکثر عملکرد بنه در زعفران قابل توصیه می‌باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اسید هیومیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کود زیستی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد بنه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محلول‌پاشی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_17361_eb786f0a8d6b12c455ba9c59b44ef201.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Economic Analysis and Comparison of Technical Efficiency in Small and Large Saffron Farms of Khorasan Razavi Province</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل اقتصادی تولید و مقایسه کارایی فنی مزارع کوچک و بزرگ زعفران در استان خراسان رضوی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>119</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>132</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">17362</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2016.17362</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>تکتم</FirstName>
					<LastName>محتشمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>کرباسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد، گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهاره</FirstName>
					<LastName>زندی دره غریبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، مهندسی اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of this study is to perform an economic investigation of the use of various inputs in saffron production and to measure the efficiency of its production in small and large farms of the Khorasan Razavi province. The required data was collected from 170 questionnaires completed by saffron producers in the Torbat-e Heydarieh and Zaveh counties in the year 2014. In order to ensure the accuracy of selected production function, the performance of Cobb Douglas, Transcendental and Translog functional forms were tested. The results suggest that Translog functional form is the most appropriate form for expression of production technology of this product.  The estimated elasticities based on this production function show that large land owners perform better in the input usage. Moreover, the comparison of technical efficiency between the two groups of farms indicates that 49 percent of small farms and 18 percent of large farms work at inefficient levels of production. The large difference between the lowest and highest technical efficiency in large farms group shows that there is an option to increase technical efficiency in these fields through the use of good management practices.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از این مطالعه بررسی اقتصادی مصرف نهاده‌های مختلف در تولید زعفران و نیز اندازه‌گیری کارایی تولید این محصول در مزارع کوچک و بزرگ استان خراسان رضوی می‌باشد. آمار و اطلاعات مورد نیاز از طریق تکمیل پرسشنامه از 170 زعفران‌کار شهرستان‌های تربت حیدریه و زاوه در سال 1393 جمع آوری شده است. به منظور اطمینان از صحت انتخاب الگوی تولید مورد استفاده سه فرم تابعی کاب داگلاس، ترانسندنتال و ترانسلوگ مورد آزمون قرار گرفته است. نتایج این پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که فرم تابعی ترانسلوگ مناسب‌ترین فرم برای بیان تکنولوژی تولید این محصول می‌باشد. کشش های تولیدی محاسبه شده بر پایه پارامترهای این تابع بیانگر آن است که بزرگ مالکان در استفاده از نهاده‌ها عملکرد بهتری از خود نشان می‌دهند. افزون بر این مقایسه کارایی دو گروه حاکی از آن است که 49 درصد از مزارع کوچک و 18 درصد از مزارع بزرگ تولید این محصول در سطح ناکارای تولید فعالیت می‌کنند. اختلاف زیاد کمترین و بیشترین کارایی فنی در بین زعفران‌کاران بزرگ مالک نشان می‌دهد امکان افزایش کارایی فنی در این گروه از مزارع نیز از طریق استفاده از شیوه‌های مدیریتی مناسب وجود دارد. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تابع تولید</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارایی فنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تابع مرزی تصادفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تخصیص بهینه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_17362_4f35373bb3cf8cdc426b74edcf0da552.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effects of Saffron Economic Stability of Rural Residents in the Darbeghazi District City of Nishabur</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اثرات کشت زعفران در پایداری اقتصادی روستاهای دهستان در بقاضی شهرستان نیشابور</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>133</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>142</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">17363</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2016.17363</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید امیر محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>علوی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار جغرافیا و برنامه ریزی روستایی، دانشگاه پیام نور، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمود رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرلطفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار جغرافیا و برنامه ریزی روستایی، دانشگاه زابل</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نازنین</FirstName>
					<LastName>نعیم آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی روستایی، دانشگاه خوارزمی تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Agricultural sustainability is undoubtedly one of the most important parts of sustainable development. The main source of income for the residents of villages of the Khorasan Razavi province is based on agricultural and horticultural products especially sale of saffron. In this regard the turquoise shades of the flowers of this plant encompass all of the fields in Nishabur and they have been much welcomed by farmers in this city. In this study, the cultivation of saffron in creating economic stability of the rural district Derbghazi in the central part of the city of Nishabur city will be examined. The research method in this paper is based on library, documentary, field and analytical – descriptive studies. In this context and in order to determine the economic stability of rural areas, the Morris Davis model has been used. This model contains three matrices that separately calculate and analyze the economic indicators. The statistical population under study consists of more than one hundred households from the rural villages in the Derbghazi rural district and the sample population studied consists of 308 households based on the Cochran formula. The results of the Morris Davis model indicate that among ten villages that were studied, Behroudi, Jilo, Khojan and Norouazabad have low economic stability, and Rouhabad, Haghiye, Shadmiyane, Karizak plus the villages of Jafarabad garden and Karizak Sabbah have average economic stability. In the end and based on the results of the research study some recommendations are presented in order to maintain employment in the region and support the farmers who are cultivating saffron to encourage the till of saffron and help the economic stability of the residents of the villages that were studied.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پایداری کشاورزی امروزه بی‌شک یکی از مهم‌ترین بخش‌های توسعه پایدار است. اتکای اصلی درآمد ساکنین روستا‌های استان خراسان رضوی به محصولات کشاورزی و باغی به‌ویژه زعفران می‌باشد. در این راستا گل‌های فیروزه فام این گیاه پهنه اراضی شهرستان نیشابور را نیز در برگرفته و در این شهرستان با استقبال زیاد کشاورزان مواجه شده است. در این مطالعه به بررسی کشت زعفران در ایجاد پایداری اقتصادی روستا‌های دهستان دربقاضی در بخش مرکزی شهرستان نیشابور پرداخته شده است. روش انجام این پژوهش، مبتنی بر مطالعات کتابخانه‌ای، اسنادی و میدانی و تحلیلی - توصیفی است. در همین چارچوب برای تعیین پایداری اقتصادی روستا‌ها، از مدل موریس دیویس استفاده شده است. این مدل شامل سه ماتریس می‌باشد که برای شاخص‌های اقتصادی به‌طور جداگانه محاسبه و تحلیل می‌شود. جامعه آماری روستا‌های بالای صد خانوار در دهستان دربقاضی می‌باشد، همچنین حجم نمونه مورد مطالعه براساس فرمول کوکران 308 خانوار است . نتایج حاصل از مدل موریس دیویس نشان داد، از بین ده روستای مورد مطالعه، روستا‌های بحرودی، جیلو، خوجان و نوروزآباد از پایداری کم، روستای روح‌آباد، حقیه، شادمیانه، کاریزک و همچنین روستا‌های باغ جعفرآباد و کاریز صباح از پایداری متوسطی برخوردار هستند.  در راستای نتایج این پژوهش پیشنهادی مبتنی  بر حفظ اشتغال در منطقه و حمایت از زعفرانکاران منطقه برای ترغیب کشت زعفران و پایداری روستا‌های مورد مطالعه ذکر شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توسعه پایدار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روستا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل موریس دیویس</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_17363_0c208d35e215077816d796718f7aa375.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Different Hormones on Callus Induction, Regeneration and Multiplication of Saffron (Crocus Sativus L.) Corms</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اثر هورمون‌های مختلف بر القای کالوس، باززایی و تکثیر بنه زعفران (.&lt;i&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/i&gt; L)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>143</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>154</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">17364</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2016.17364</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>صفرنژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی مرکز تحقیقات کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی خراسان رضوی و سرپرست مدیریت بیوتکنولوژی کشاورزی منطقه شرق و شمال شرق کشور، مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیده بی بی لیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>علمداری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد بیوتکنولوژی کشاورزی، بخش تحقیقات کشت بافت، شعبه مشهد، پژوهشکده بیوتکنولوژی کشاورزی ایران، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، مشهد،‌ ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هادی</FirstName>
					<LastName>درودی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترای جنگلداری، بخش تحقیقات کشت بافت، شعبه مشهد، پژوهشکده بیوتکنولوژی کشاورزی ایران، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، مشهد،‌ ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرضیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>دلیر</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد بیوتکنولوژی کشاورزی، بخش تحقیقات کشت بافت، شعبه مشهد، پژوهشکده بیوتکنولوژی کشاورزی ایران، سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی، مشهد،‌ ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron (&lt;em&gt;Crocus sativus; Iridaceae&lt;/em&gt;) is an important economic and medicinal crop in Iran. The saffron that is an herbaceous triploid geophyte is used mainly as a source of secondary metabolites having aromatic and medicinal value. The plant develops annually from buds on the mother corm – i.e. a thickened stem - which acts as a resting, perennating storage organ. In this research &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; propagation of &lt;em&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/em&gt; through direct and indirect methods has been studied. Corm slices as explants were sterilized and transferred to MS media with different concentrations of plant growth regulators. The results showed that use of HgCl&lt;sub&gt;2 &lt;/sub&gt;0.15% for 20 minutes is the best treatment for sterilization. The results of ANOVA of direct regeneration indicated that the most corm formation was observed in 2 mg/l BAP. Maximum callus induction was achieved on MS supplemented with 1 mg/l 2,4-D + 2 mg/l BAP. As results indicate the most number of embryos were obtained in MS medium containing 0.15 mg/ l NAA. Also this medium was suitable for germination of embryo. Corm formation was only observed in MS supplemented with1 mg/l 2, 4-D + 2 mg/l BAP in the indirect method. The corm was transferred to JF pot for adaptation and then it was transferred to the pot and soil for growing.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زعفران گیاهی تریپلوئید است که منبع متابولیت‌های ثانویه و یکی از مهمترین محصولات اقتصادی و دارویی ایران می‌باشد. در این مطالعه تکثیر درون شیشه‌ای زعفران با استفاده از دو روش مستقیم و غیرمستقیم مورد بررسی قرارگرفت. قطعات بنه که به‌عنوان ریزنمونه مورد استفاده قرار گرفتند، پس از ضدعفونی به محیط کشت MS با غلظت‌های مختلف هورمونی مربوط به باززایی مستقیم و غیر‌مستقیم منتقل شدند. تیمار کلرید جیوه 15/0 %  به‌مدت 20 دقیقه بهترین تیمار برای ضدعفونی زعفران بود. نتایج حاصل از تجزیه واریانس داده‌های باززایی مستقیم نشان‌داد که بیشترین بنه در محیط BAP  mg/l2 تشکیل می‌شود. مقایسه میانگین‌های درصد القای کالوس‌ بیانگر تفاوت معنی‌دار بین تیمارهای مورد استفاده در سطح 5% بود. کالوس‌زایی یک هفته بعد از کشت آغاز شد و  بهترین محیط برای القای کالوس محیط mg/ l 2,4-D 1 +  mg/ l BAP2 شناخته شد. بیشترین تعداد رویان در محیط MS با غلظت کم NAA (mg/ l  15/0) تولید شد. نتایج حاصل از بررسی جوانه‌زنی رویان‌ها نشان‌داد که دربین محیط‌های مورد استفاده محیط MS باmg/l NAA  15/0 بهترین تیمار برای جوانه‌زنی بود. تشکیل بنه تنها در محیط mg/ l 2,4-D 1 + mg/ l BAP 2 مشاهده‌شد. بنه‌ها برای سازگاری به جی فی منتقل و سپس به‌گلدان و خاک انتقال یافتند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تنظیم‌کننده‌های رشد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درون شیشه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_17364_79349158be7de6315d442aa9d6e3bcb2.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Using Geostatistics for Zoning Areas Suitable for Saffron Cultivation in the Khorasan Razavi Province Based on Climatological Parameters</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کاربرد زمین آمار در پهنه‌بندی مناطق مستعد کشت زعفران در سطح استان خراسان رضوی بر اساس پارامترهای اقلیمی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>155</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>167</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">17365</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2016.17365</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>بشیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه مرتع و آبخیزداری، دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیر</FirstName>
					<LastName>سالاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی، دانشکده کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron is one of the most economical and highly valuable plant species in Iran. About 80 percent of the total export of saffron in the world originates in the Khorasan Razavi province. The demand for higher production,&lt;em&gt; limitations&lt;/em&gt; of climatological&lt;em&gt;resources, soil and water&lt;/em&gt;have&lt;strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;caused the officials who are in charge of agriculture to seek for areas that &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;are potential candidates for the cultivation of saffron by means of precise, rapid and analytical methods. In the present study, geostatistical interpolation methods are used for climatological-ecological zoning of agricultural lands in the Khorasan Razavi province that are suitable candidates for saffron cultivation. To this aim, climatological and ecological requirements of saffron cultivation are first determined based on available scientific references. Then the necessary data are prepared. &lt;em&gt;In the present study&lt;/em&gt;, an &lt;em&gt;effort&lt;/em&gt; has been made in the spatial modeling and interpolation of the areas that are potential candidates for saffron cultivation based on the yield per unit area in 8 counties of the province during the 1989-1990 to 2008-2009 crop years and the 11 climatological parameters that affect saffron growth and blossom in the mentioned period of time. Based on the results, the maximum absolute humidity has been selected as the best covariate. The modeling of crop yield and the evaluation of the models were performed using geostatistical methods in GS&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt; software. Finally, the prepared zoning map showed that the geostatistical methods used are suitable choices for determination and zoning of areas that are suitable candidates for the development of saffron cultivation. The results for zoning have showed that a third of the southern areas in the Khorasan Razavi province (especially in the Gonabad county) have the maximum cultivation potential from the viewpoint of climatology, and in the northern direction of the province (especially in the Quchan and Binaloud counties)&lt;em&gt; the value of land decreases considering its potential suitability &lt;/em&gt;for saffron cultivation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از گونه‌های گیاهی ارزشمند اقتصادی ایران، زعفران می‌باشد. از کل &lt;em&gt;زعفران&lt;/em&gt; جهان، 80 درصد آن در &lt;em&gt;خراسان&lt;/em&gt; رضوی تولید می‌شود. تقاضای تولید بیشتر، محدودیت‌های اقلیمی و منابع آب و خاک سبب شده تا متولیان عرصه کشاورزی به دنبال پتانسیل‌یابی اراضی مستعد با استفاده از روش‌های دقیق، سریع و تحلیلی باشند. در پژوهش حاضر به منظور پهنه‌بندی اقلیمی اراضی کشاورزی استان خراسان رضوی برای کشت زعفران، از روش‌های درون‌یابی زمین‌آمار استفاده شد. بدین منظور ابتدا نیازهای اقلیمی زعفران با استفاده از منابع علمی موجود تعیین و با توجه به آمار عملکرد محصول در سطح 8 شهرستان استان خراسان رضوی طی دوره 20 ساله 88-1368 و با لحاظ کردن 11 پارامتر اقلیمی که در مراحل رشد و گلدهی زعفران موثر هستند، اقدام به مدل‌سازی مکانی و درون‌یابی مناطق مستعد کشت گردید. بر اساس نتایج، رطوبت مطلق حداکثر به‌عنوان بهترین متغیر کمکی جهت تخمین عملکرد زعفران به‌دست آمد. نتایج پهنه‌بندی نشان داد که ثلث جنوبی استان خراسان رضوی (مخصوصاً شهرستان گناباد) از نظر اقلیمی، دارای حداکثر پتانسیل کشت بوده و با حرکت به سمت شمال استان (مخصوصاً شهرستان قوچان و بینالود)، از میزان مستعد بودن کشت کاسته می‌گردد. نتیجه‌گیری‌ نهایی مدل‌سازی عملکرد زعفران با استفاده از روش‌های زمین‌آمار این است که این روش‌ها، گزینه‌ای مناسب جهت تعیین و پهنه‌بندی مناطق مستعد کشت این گیاه می‌باشند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زمین‌آمار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مناطق مستعد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خراسان رضوی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_17365_41f3bd6ec3ce9fff555107ed963e0c9d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
