<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analysis of Effects and Factors Influencing on Increasing the Cropping Pattern of Saffron in the City of Nishapur; Case study: Ishaq Abad district</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>واکاوی آثار و عوامل مؤثر بر گسترش الگوی کشت زعفران در شهرستان نیشابور مطالعه موردی: دهستان اسحق‌آباد</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>277</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>288</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">8621</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2015.8621</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>حمزه ئی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری جغرافیا و برنامه ریزی روستایی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خدیجه</FirstName>
					<LastName>بوزرجمهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه جغرافیا، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Selected appropriate cropping patterns, especially high-value crops such as saffron, shows that the pattern of cultivation of these crops can facilitate the achievement of the objectives of rural development programs. In recent years, saffron cultivation considerably has been increased in parts of the city of Nishapur like Isaac Abad district which altered the pattern of crop cultivation from onion to saffron cultivation. The purpose of this study was to identify factors that influence the development pattern of saffron, and the economic and social consequences of the mentioned districts. This study was conducted based on library information and field collected data. A random sampling method was used. The sample size was calculated using Cochran equation, the number of calculated samples were 220 Isaac Abad district saffron grower. Data was analyzed by Pierson Correlation methods. The results showed that geographical factor and attractions in the consumer market were the most important factors in the spread pattern of saffron cultivation in the region. In order to maintain the local potential is also planning to expand the crop pattern deserves more attention to geographical factors.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">انتخاب الگوی کشت مناسب به‌ویژه کشت محصولات دارای ارزش بالا نظیر زعفران، نشان می‌دهد که الگوی کشت این محصولات می‌تواند دستیابی به اهداف برنامه‌های توسعه روستایی را تسهیل کند. در سال‌های اخیر، کشت محصول زعفران در بخش‌هایی از شهرستان نیشابور همچون دهستان اسحق‌آباد، رشد قابل‌توجهی داشته، به‌نحوی‌که باعث تغییر الگوی کشت از پیاز به زعفران شده‌ است. هدف این تحقیق شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر گسترش الگوی کشت زعفران و آثار و نتایج اقتصادی و اجتماعی آن در دهستان مذکور است. روش تحقیق در این پژوهش توصیفی تحلیلی بوده و از منابع کتابخانه‌ای و میدانی نیز برای جمع‌آوری اطلاعات استفاده شده ‌است. حجم نمونه بر اساس فرمول کوکران مشتمل بر 220 زعفران کار دهستان اسحاق‌آباد در سال 1392 محاسبه و به روش تصادفی ساده انتخاب و نتایج نیز با ضریب همبستگی پیرسون تحلیل شد. نتایج این تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که عوامل جغرافیایی و جاذبه‌های بازار مصرف، مهم‌ترین فاکتورهای گسترش الگوی کشت زعفران در منطقه بوده است. به‌منظور حفظ این پتانسیل بومی و نیز برنامه‌ریزی برای گسترش الگوی کشت این محصول، شایسته است به عوامل جغرافیایی توجه بیشتری شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آثار اقتصادی و اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل جغرافیایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جاذبه‌های بازار</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_8621_5e60d9017e776b4cf4d506d939a9323c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
