<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Determining the Structure of Saffron Target Markets and Analyzing its Impact on Iranian Exports</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تعیین ساختار بازارهای هدف زعفران و تحلیل اثرگذاری آن بر صادرات ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">108510</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2020.217710.1379</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>آسیابانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مشهد، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، دانشکده کشاورزی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حامد</FirstName>
					<LastName>رفیعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>اقتصاد تولید و مدیریت- دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میلاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>امینی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهام</FirstName>
					<LastName>مهرپرور حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8663-8416</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Considering, increasing competition in global markets, it is important to have a comprehensive understanding of target markets for marketing planning. One of the influencing factors on the international marketing strategies selection is the assessment of the market structure in importing countries. Therefore, this study has pursued two main goals of determining the market structure of important saffron importing countries and investigating the effect of this variable on Iranian saffron to further the research literature on saffron export as one of the most important export products of Iranian agricultural sector. To achieve these objectives, the Herfindahl-Hirschman Index has been used to calculate the market structure and gravity model has been applied to determine this variable impact on Iran&#039;s exports over the period 2001-2017. Market structure results showed that out of the 16 main countries importing saffron, no country had a fully competitive structure and there was a degree of monopoly in all markets. Also, the results of changes in the market structure of saffron importing countries during the period 2001-2010 and 2011-2017 showed that the market structure of 7 countries Argentina, China, Germany, Japan, Spain, Sweden and the United Arab Emirates have become more monopolistic and 9 other countries have got more competitive structure. According to the results of the gravity model, the market structure of the importing countries has had a significant effect on Iranian saffron exports and the more competitive target markets have caused reduction of the Iranian saffron exports. Hence, as saffron target markets become more competitive, it is suggested that exporters pay more attention to improving their competitive components in the markets, especially packaging. In accordance with world standards, packaging should be based on the quality of the product and provide complete information to customers.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با توجه به رقابت روزافزون در بازارهای جهانی، نیاز به شناخت جامع بازارهای هدف جهت اتخاذ برنامه های بازاریابی اهمیت چشمگیری دارد. یکی از مولفه‌های اثرگذار در انتخاب استراتژی های بازاریابی در سطح بین المللی بررسی ساختار بازار کشورهای واردکننده است. لذا این مطالعه دو هدف اصلی تعیین ساختار بازار کشورهای مهم واردکننده زعفران و سپس بررسی اثر این متغیر بر صادرات زعفران ایران را جهت پیشبرد ادبیات پژوهش در حوزه صادرات زعفران به عنوان یکی از مهمترین محصولات صادراتی بخش کشاورزی ایران دنبال کرده است. جهت دستیابی به این اهداف از شاخص هرفیندال-هیرشمن برای محاسبه ساختار بازار و الگوی جاذبه برای تعیین نوع اثرگذاری متغیر بر صادرات ایران در دوره زمانی 2001-2017 استفاده شده است. نتایج ساختار بازار نشان داد که از میان 16 کشور اصلی واردکننده زعفران هیچ کشوری دارای ساختار رقابت کامل نبوده و در همه بازارها درجه ای از انحصار وجود دارد. همچنین نتایج تغییرات ساختار بازار کشورهای واردکننده زعفران در دو دوره زمانی 2001-2010 و 2011-2017 نشان داد که ساختار بازار 7 کشور آرژانتین، چین، آلمان، ژاپن، اسپانیا، سوئد و امارات متحده عربی انحصاری‌تر شده است و 9 کشور دیگر ساختار رقابتی تری پیدا کرده اند. براساس نتایج الگوی جاذبه، متغیر ساختار بازار کشورهای واردکننده اثر معنی داری بر صادرات زعفران ایران داشته است و رقابتی تر شدن بازارهای هدف موجب کاهش صادرات زعفران ایران شده است. از این رو، با توجه به رقابتی تر شدن بازارهای هدف زعفران، پیشنهاد می شود که صادرکنندگان بر بهبود مولفه های رقابتی خود در بازارها به ویژه بسته بندی توجه بیشتری نمایند. به طوری که مطابق با استانداردهای جهانی، باید بسته‌بندی براساس نوع کیفیت محصول انجام شود و اطلاعات کاملی به مشتریان ارائه کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی جاذبه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ساختار بازار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صادرات زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هرفیندال-هیرشمن</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
