<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study a possibility of saffron (&lt;i&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/i&gt; L.) production in vertical culture</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی امکان تولید زعفران (.&lt;i&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/i&gt; L) در سیستم کشت عمودی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>161</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>173</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">45140</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2017.21036.1063</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لورین</FirstName>
					<LastName>علی احمد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>سروش زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>مختصی بیدگلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه زراعت، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In recent years many research studies have been carried out to use a vertical planting system for production of some plants. Although saffron is one of the most expensive spices in the word, there is no investigation about saffron production in a vertical planting system. Therefore, the growth and production of saffron plant in two different systems (vertical and horizontal) were studied in the agricultural research field of the Tarbiat Modares University during the 2013-2014 growing seasons. In the vertical system, saffron corms were planted in fabric bags containing potting soil. The fabric bags were hanged on a cube of metal with an area of each side of the cube being equal to 2.25 square meters. In the horizontal system, the corms were planted in three plots with the area of each plots being 2.25 square meters. The results showed that in the vertical planting system, the number of flowers, flower dry weight and dry weight of stigma per unit area of land (10 flower, 347.34 and 0.56 mg respectively) were significantly higher than those obtained in the horizontal culture (They were almost three times higher) .In contrast, the numbers and dry weight of lateral corms (2.4 corm and 0.36 g respectively) and the dry weight of apical corm (0.88 g) in the horizontal system were significantly greater than those obtained in the vertical system. Dry weight of leaf and root were significantly greater in the vertical system. The total number of buds and leaves were more in the horizontal culture. However, the maximum leaf length of the vertical planting system was higher than those of the horizontal system.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با وجود این­که زعفران یکی از گران­ترین گیاهان دارویی در جهان است، اما تاکنون در مورد تولید آن در کشت عمودی مطالعه­ای انجام نشده است. بنابراین رشد و تولید زعفران در دو سیستم کشت متفاوت (عمودی و افقی) در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس در سال زراعی 1393-1392 مورد مقایسه قرار گرفت. بنه­های زعفران در سیستم کشت عمودی در کیسه­های پارچه­ای در یک مکعب که ابعاد هر وجه آن 5/1 در 5/1 متر بود کشت شدند. در کشت افقی در مزرعه بنه­ها در سه کرت که مساحت هر کرت 25/2 مترمربع بود کشت شدند. نتایج نشان داد که در سال اول رشد تعداد گل، وزن خشک گل و وزن خشک کلاله در واحد سطح در سیستم کشت عمودی به ترتیب 10 گل، 34/347 و 56 میلی­گرم در مترمربع بود که به­طور معنی­داری تقریباً سه برابر بیشتر از کشت افقی بود. در مقابل در سیستم کشت افقی تعداد و وزن خشک بنه­های دختری (به ترتیب 4/2 عدد و 36/0 گرم در بوته)، وزن خشک بنه­های مرکزی (88/0 گرم در بوته) و وزن خشک برگ و ریشه به‌طور معنی­داری بیشتر از کشت عمودی بود، ولی حداکثر طول برگ در کشت عمودی نسبت به کشت افقی بیشتر بود. لذا می‌توان نتیجه‌گیری کرد که از سیستم کشت عمودی برای افزایش محصول زعفران در سال اول استفاده کرد؛ اما باید در مورد بهبود وزن خشک بنه­های دختری جانبی و وزن خشک بنه­های مرکزی در این سیستم تحقیق بیشتر انجام داد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعداد بنه‌های دختری جانبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وزن خشک بنه‌های دختری جانبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وزن خشک بنه‌های مرکزی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_45140_78fc9e45baf9fc54e100749dfd205894.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
