<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effects of corm origin, corm weight and nutrient foliar application on yield and qualitative traits of saffron (.&lt;i&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/i&gt; L)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی تأثیر مبدأ بنه، وزن بنه و محلول‌پاشی برگی بر عملکرد کمی و کیفی زعفران (.&lt;i&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/i&gt; L)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>269</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>277</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">51720</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2017.93779.1251</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>صحابی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری اکولوژی گیاهان زراعی دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>جهان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>کوچکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>نصیری محلاتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In general, corm weight and nutrient management are considered as the most important factors in relation to quantitative and qualitative traits of saffron. In order to investigate the effects of mother corm origin, mother corm weight and nutrient foliar application on yield and qualitative traits of saffron, a field experiment was conducted as factorial layout based on a randomized complete block design with three replications at the Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Iran, during the years from 2012 to 2015. The mother corm origin (Iranian and Spanish corms), mother corm weight 8 g and lower (small), 8.1–15 g (medium) and 15.1-23 g (large) and nutrient foliar application (application and control) were considered as the first, second and third experimental factors, respectively. According to the results, the larger mother corms significantly resulted in a greater number of flowers per m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, increased fresh flower and dry stigma + style yields. However, the effect of nutrient foliar application was observed to be not significant on these traits. When Iranian mother corms were planted, the number of flowers per m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;, fresh flower and dry stigma + style yields were higher, compared with Spanish mother corms. For instance, flower number, fresh flower and dry stigma + style yields increased by 17, 13 and 14%, respectively, when planting Iranian mother corms. Nonetheless, picrocrocin concentration was higher (up to 3.8%) in the Spanish planted corm treatment. Based on the results, beside the optimal nutrient foliar application, the importance of adapting the corms origin with environmental conditions of the site designated for planting is emphasized.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">بنه مناسب و مدیریت عناصر غذایی، از مهم­ترین عوامل در بهبود تولید و کیفیت زعفران هستند. به‌منظور بررسی تأثیر وزن بنه و محلول­پاشی برگی بر عملکرد کمی و کیفی گل دو توده زعفران ایرانی و اسپانیایی، آزمایشی در سال­های 95-1392 به‌صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح بلوک­های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد به مرحله اجرا در آمد. مبدأ بنه مادری زعفران (شامل بنه ایرانی و اسپانیایی)، وزن بنه­ها در سه سطح شامل کمتر از 8 گرم (بنه ریز)، 1/8 تا 15 گرم (بنه متوسط) و1/15 تا 23 گرم (بنه درشت) و محلول­­­پاشی برگی کود کامل (فسفیت پتاسیم + بیومین) در دو سطح (محلول­­­پاشی و عدم محلول­­­پاشی) به ترتیب عوامل اول، دوم و سوم آزمایش در نظر گرفته شدند. بر اساس نتایج آزمایش، با افزایش وزن بنه جهت کاشت، تعداد گل، عملکرد گل­تر و عملکرد کلاله + خامه خشک زعفران به‌طور معنی­داری افزایش یافت، اما اثر محلول‌پاشی برگی بر شاخص­های ذکرشده معنی­دار نبود. تعداد گل و عملکرد گل‌تر زعفران درنتیجه کاشت بنه‌های ایرانی، به ترتیب17، 13 و 14 درصد بیشتر از بنه­های اسپانیایی بود. همچنین، عملکرد کلاله + خامه خشک حاصل از بنه­های ایرانی در مقایسه با بنه­های اسپانیایی تا 1/14 درصد افزایش یافت. با این وجود، غلظت پیکروکروسین در نتیجه کاشت بنه­های اسپانیایی تا 8/3 درصد بیشتر از بنه­های ایرانی بود. طبق نتایج این تحقیق، در کنار محلول­پاشی بهینه عناصر غذایی، اهمیت سازگاری منشأ بنه با شرایط محیطی محل کاشت مورد تأکید می­باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیکروکروسین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد کلاله خشک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت عناصر غذایی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_51720_66059426dec9cf2991430aad70b40c85.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
