<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Ranking factors affecting the packing of saffron from the perspective of consumers</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رتبه‌بندی عوامل مؤثر بر بسته‌بندی زعفران از دید مصرف‌کنندگان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>175</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>184</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">42371</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2016.54643.1165</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آرش</FirstName>
					<LastName>دوراندیش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیر حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>توحیدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پریسا</FirstName>
					<LastName>علیزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Packaging is a tool for recognition and differentiation of product and it plays a crucial role in consumers&#039; purchasing decisions, and it can be used to create competitive advantages. Saffron is one of the most important agricultural crops in Iran and its packaging in accordance with consumer demand increases sales and satisfaction of the consumers. Therefore, the main objective of this study is to rank the factors affecting the packaging from the perspective of consumers of saffron in Mashhad. Data was collected in the form of 99 questionnaires that have been answered by the consumers of saffron in Mashhad in 2015. Analytic hierarchy process (AHP) was used to rank these factors. The results showed that labeling information about internal and international standards and saffron nutrients on the package have the greatest impact on consumer preferences. Also, the results of the ranking alternatives indicated that attention to the brand labelled on the packing is the most important issue from the perspective of the consumers. Hence, labelling information elements on the package can be a good way for brand differentiation and increasing its value. According to the results, it is recommended that producers and suppliers of saffron pay more attention to features and information elements in package design.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">بسته­بندی به عنوان یک ابزار برای شناخت و تمایز محصول نقش بسیار مهمی در تصمیم خرید مصرف­کنندگان ایفا می­نماید و از آن می­توان برای ایجاد مزیت رقابتی استفاده نمود. زعفران یکی از محصولات مهم کشاورزی است که بسته­بندی مطابق با تقاضای مصرف­کنندگان موجب افزایش فروش و رضایت­مندی خریداران می­گردد. لذا هدف اصلی این مطالعه رتبه­بندی عوامل مؤثر بر بسته­بندی از دید مصرف­کنندگان زعفران در شهر مشهد می­باشد. اطلاعات این پژوهش، در قالب 99 پرسشنامه که در سال 1394 از سوی مصرف­کنندگان زعفران شهر مشهد پاسخ داده شده، جمع‌آوری شده است. برای رتبه­بندی عوامل مؤثر بر بسته­بندی این محصول، از روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی استفاده شده است. نتایج مطالعه نشان داد که ارائه اطلاعات مربوط به مواد مغذی زعفران و درج استانداردهای داخلی و بین­المللی، بر ترجیحات مصرف­کنندگان بیشترین تأثیر را دارند. همچنین، نتایج رتبه­بندی گزینه­ها نیز نشان داد که راهبرد توجه به نام تجاری درج شده روی بسته­بندی از نظر مصرف­کنندگان دارای بیشترین اهمیت است. لذا، درج عناصر اطلاعاتی روی بسته­بندی می­تواند شیوه مناسبی برای تمایز نام تجاری و افزایش ارزش آن باشد. با توجه به نتایج مطالعه، به تولیدکنندگان و عرضه­کنندگان زعفران پیشنهاد می­گردد که در طراحی بسته­بندی به ویژگی­ها و عناصر اطلاعاتی بیشترین توجه را داشته باشند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استانداردهای داخلی و بین‌المللی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل سلسله مراتبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترجیحات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نام تجاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_42371_7cc25faaeee3b47504c105aa66466b24.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
