<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effects of Mother Corm Weight and Cow Manure on Saffron Flower and Corm Yield</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اثر وزن بنه مادری و میزان کود گاوی بر عملکرد گل و بنه زعفران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>445</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>460</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55359</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2017.88165.1236</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رامین</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری بوم شناسی زراعی، پردیس بین الملل دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پرویز</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضوانی مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>کوچکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی و پژوهشگر پژوهشکده زعفران، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In order to investigate the effects of mother corm weight (including 4.1-7, 7.1-10 and 10.1-13 g) and different levels of cow manure (including 30 (control), 60 and 90 t/ha) on flower characteristics and daughter corms of saffron, a factorial experiment based on randomized complete block design with three replications was conducted during two cropping years (2012-13, 2013-14) in Zaweh county. The results of variance analysis in the first and second years showed that there were significant differences between the simple effects and the interaction effects in terms of most of the studied traits, and these differences were higher in the second year. The highest (56.8 m-2) and the lowest (41.3 m-2) flower numbers were obtained in 90 t/ha cow manure with bigger corm size ( 10.1-13 g) and 60 t/ha cow manure with smaller corm size (4.1-7 g) treatments, respectively. 60 t/ha cow manure with bigger corm size (10.1-13 g) and 60 t/ha cow manure with smaller corm size (4.1-7 g) treatments produced the highest (0.347 g.m-2) and the lowest (0.220 g.m-2) dry weight of stigma, respectively. The highest and the lowest of total number of daughter corms (504.2 and 264.7 m-2), total daughter corm yield (2677.3 and 1582.9 g.m-2) were shown in 90 t/ha cow manure with bigger corm size ( 10.1-13 g) and 30 (control) t/ha cow manure with smaller corm size (4.1-7 g) treatments, respectively. In addition, the mean comparison of interaction effect in the second year showed that there were significant differences between most of treatments. The interaction effects of studied traits in the second year showed that 90 t/ha cow manure with bigger corm size (10.1-13 g) and 30 (control) t/ha cow manure with smaller corm size (4.1-7 g) treatments produced the highest and the lowest flower number (231.0 and 156.5 m-2), stigma dry weight (2.062 and 1.053 g.m-2), total number of daughter corms (1024.5 and 505.5 m-2) and total daughter corms yield (4486.6 and 2133.1 g.m-2), respectively. Finally, it can be concluded that by increasing the use of cow manure (more than 60 t/ha) and the use of more than 7 grams mother corms, it is possible to improve the number and yield of daughter corms and these traits will increase the saffron stigma yield in the next coming years.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به‌منظور بررسی اثر وزن بنه مادری (شامل 7-1/4، 10- 1/7 و 13- 1/10 گرم) و سطوح مختلف کود گاوی (شامل30 (شاهد)، 60 و 90 تن در هکتار) بر خصوصیات گل و بنه‌های دختری زعفران، آزمایشی به‌صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح پایه بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار طی دو سال‌ زراعی (94-93 و 93-92) در شهرستان زاوه اجرا شد. نتایج تجزیه واریانس در سال اول و دوم نشان داد که بین اثرات ساده و اثرات متقابل اکثر صفات مورد مطالعه اختلاف معنی‌دار وجود داشت و این اختلافات در سال دوم بیشتر بود. بیشترین و کمترین تعداد گل بترتیب در تیمارهای 90 تن کود گاوی همراه با بنه درشت (13-1/10 گرم) و 60 تن کود گاوی همراه با بنه ریز (7-1/4 گرم) مشاهده گردید. تیمار های 60 تن کود گاوی همراه با بنه درشت و 60 تن کود گاوی همراه با بنه ریز بترتیب بیشترین و کمترین وزن خشک کلاله را تولید کردند. بیشترین و کمترین تعداد کل بنه دختری و عملکرد کل بنه دختری بترتیب متعلق به تیمارهای 90 تن کود گاوی همراه با بنه درشت و30 تن (شاهد) کود گاوی همراه با بنه ریز بود. همچنین مقایسات میانگین اثر متقابل در سال دوم نشان داد که تیمارهای 90 تن کود گاوی همراه با بنه درشت و30 تن (شاهد) کود گاوی همراه با بنه ریز بترتیب بیشترین و کمترین تعداد گل ، وزن خشک کلاله ، تعداد کل بنه دختری و عملکرد کل بنه دختری را دارا بودند. در نهایت می‌توان این‌گونه نتیجه‌گرفت که با افزایش مصرف کود گاوی (بیش از 60 تن) و استفاده از بنه‌های مادری با وزن بیش از 7 گرم می‌توان باعث بهبود صفات تعداد و عملکرد بنه دختری شده و این صفات بخصوص در سال‌های آتی باعث افزایش عملکرد کلاله زعفران می‌گردند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بنه دختری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعداد گل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد کلاله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کود آلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گلدهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وزن خشک بنه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_55359_a629162e0f480fecf0eae70025b82c95.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
