<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analysis of the role of strategic products in sustainable rural livelihoods (Case study: saffron production in the Roshtkhar rural district)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>واکاوی نقش محصولات استراتژیک در معیشت پایدار روستایی(مطالعه موردی: تولید زعفران در دهستان رشتخوار)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>273</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>293</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">46722</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2017.46917.1135</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>صادق</FirstName>
					<LastName>اصغری لفمجانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی روستایی، گروه جغرافیا، دانشگاه زابل، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>ایزدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی‌ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی روستایی، گروه جغرافیا، دانشگاه زابل، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron is the most expensive agricultural and pharmaceutical product in the world. It is significant for several reasons such as having high water productivity compared to other crops. It is providing rural employment and preventing their migration, having high medicinal and spice values, ease of maintenance and transportation. Most importantly, it is producing a high revenue compared to other agricultural products. On this basis, due to the suitability of some parts of Iran to saffron production and the role of this product in the livelihood of rural households, assessment of the sustenance impacts of saffron production in the active villages seems absolutely necessary. Therefore, the aim of the present study is to assess the status of saffron production and its role in the livelihood of rural households of the Roshtkhar Rural District. This research was done based on a descriptive-analytic approach. In this regard, the role of saffron cultivation in 355 households living in 13 villages with over 100 households in the study rural district was investigated. To this goal, after conducting documentary studies and initial field visits, a wide range of measures proportional to the circumstances of the study villages were adopted. Then, data collection was performed based on the selected indices and questionnaires were distributed to be filled by villagers and households... To analyze the data, the relevant statistical and spatial analyses were done through the application of Expert choice, SPSS, and ArcGIS software packages. The research findings indicated that the annual revenues derived from saffron production in 43.9% of the households under study were more than they obtained from other sources of income. Through the analysis of the study data, it can be concluded that saffron production has a significant effect on the improvement of the residents’ livelihood in the Roshtkhar Rural District and this fact has reinforced the households’ motivation to stay in the rural district.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">محصول زعفران به‌عنوان گران‌ترین محصول کشاورزی و دارویی جهان، به دلایلی چون بهره‌وری بالای آب در مقایسه با سایر محصولات کشاورزی، اشتغال روستاییان و جلوگیری از مهاجرت آن‌ها، ارزش والای دارویی و ادویه­ای، سهولت نگهداری و حمل‌‌و‌نقل و از همه مهم‌تر درآمدزایی بالای آن نسبت به سایر محصولات کشاورزی، یک محصول کشاورزی قابل‌توجه محسوب می‌گردد. بر این اساس، با توجه به مستعد بودن برخی از نقاط ایران در تولید زعفران، بررسی اثرات معیشتی آن در سطح روستاهای فعال در تولید زعفران، امری کاملاً ضروری به نظر می‌رسد. لذا هدف تحقیق حاضر، ارزیابی وضعیت تولید زعفران و نقش آن در معیشت خانوارهای روستایی دهستان رشتخوار است. این پژوهش به روش توصیفی‌– تحلیلی انجام گردیده­است. در این راستا، نقش زعفران در 355 خانوار زعفران‌کار ساکن در 13 روستای بالای 100 خانوار این دهستان مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. بدین منظور، ابتدا ضمن مطالعات اسنادی و بازدید­های اولیه میدانی، طیف گسترده­ای از شاخص‌ها تعیین گردید. سپس جمع­آوری داده­ها بر اساس شاخص­های انتخابی و با استفاده از پرسشنامه‌های روستا و خانوار انجام‌شده­است. برای تجزیه‌ و تحلیل داده­ها نیز از تحلیل‌های آماری و فضایی و نرم‌افزارهای Expert choice، SPSS و ArcGIS استفاده گردید. یافته‌های تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که درآمدهای سالانه حاصل از تولید زعفران در 9/43 درصد از خانوارهای مورد مطالعه، بیش از سایر درآمدها است. همچنین از تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌های مورد مطالعه می‌توان استنباط نمود که تولید زعفران بر بهبود وضعیت معیشت ساکنان روستاهای دهستان رشتخوار تأثیر چشم­گیری دارد و این امر باعث تقویت انگیزه ماندگاری خانوارهای ساکن در این دهستان شده­است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خانوارهای روستایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سطح مطلوبیت معیشت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محدودیت‌ تولید</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_46722_e213e33989a6395a0de60af1ff0b11ce.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
