<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Pricing strategies of saffron: strategic factors analytical</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی راهبردهای قیمت گذاری زعفران با رویکرد تحلیل عوامل استراتژیک</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>355</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>366</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55295</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2017.92171.1245</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>پیرملک</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>کرباسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>قربانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>رستگاری پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی و پژوهشگر پژوهشکده زعفران دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron is considered as an important crop for farmers of the Khorasan Razavi province due to the ability to create high employment and generate appropriate income. Problems of saffron producers in marketing and export has caused this product not to be in a good position in the world market despite its high quality. Therefore, the study of marketing mix as one of the most important factors affecting marketing of saffron in the region seems to be necessary. In order to identify the strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats of marketing mix of saffron, a strategic factor analysis approach was used in this study. The required information was collected through face-to-face interviews and completing a questionnaire with managers and experts of saffron producing and exporting companies in Mashhad and Torbat Heydarieh cities in 2015. To investigate the validity of the questionnaire, the questionnaires were reviewed by supervisors and consultants and several experts. At first, some initial questions were completed and using the Cronbach&#039;s alpha method, the reliability coefficient was 0.79. The results of the internal factor matrix showed that the weaknesses overcome the strength and, according to the results of external factors matrix, the points of opportunity are superior to the threat. The results of the study showed that the increase in the value added due to saffron processing with a score of 0.57 and export value with a score of 0.54 are the most important strength and low purchase price of farmers with a score of 0.13 and a lack of knowledge of the price of competitors with a score of 0.11 are the most important weaknesses in marketing mix price. Also, the export of the product with different qualities based on the financial ability of target customers with a score of 0.32 and price determination based on the competitive and economic environment with 0.23 are most significant opportunities, and the volatility of the exchange rate with a score of 0.4 and a price fluctuation in the export market with a score of 0.36 are the most important current threats of saffron marketing. The general results obtained from the status analysis matrix indicate that the saffron processing factor strategies are defensive. Therefore, according to the results, the strategies of establishing a regional exchange market for saffron and long-term control of prices in export markets with the aim of paying attention to pricing and fair purchase are suggested.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زعفران با توجه به قدرت ایجاد اشتغال بالا و ایجاد درآمد مناسب به عنوان یک محصول مهم برای کشاورزان استان­ خراسان رضوی به حساب می‏آید. وجود مسائل و مشکلات پیش­روی زعفران­کاران در زمینه بازاریابی و صادرات باعث گردیده این محصول به‌رغم کیفیت مرغوب، از وضعیت مناسبی در بازار جهانی برخوردار نباشد. لذا بررسی آمیخته بازاریابی قیمت به عنوان یکی از مهم­ترین عوامل مؤثر بر بازاریابی زعفران در منطقه ضروری به نظر می­رسد. به‌منظور شناسایی نقاط قوت، ضعف، فرصت‌ها و تهدیدهای آمیخته بازاریابی قیمت زعفران، در این مطالعه از رویکرد تحلیل عوامل استراتژیک استفاده شد. اطلاعات موردنیاز از طریق مصاحبه حضوری و تکمیل پرسشنامه تخصصی با مدیران و کارشناسان شرکت‌های تولیدکننده و صادرکننده زعفران در شهرهای مشهد و تربت‌حیدریه در سال 1394 جمع­آوری گردید. جهت بررسی روایی منطقی پرسش نامه‏ها و صحت و سقم سؤالات، پرسش نامه‏ها توسط اساتید راهنما و مشاور و چند تن از کارشناسان مورد بررسی و اصلاح قرار گرفت. در ابتدا تعدادی پرسش­نامه اولیه تکمیل شد و با کاربرد روش آلفای کرونباخ ضریب پایایی 79/0 حاصل گردید. نتایج ماتریس عوامل داخلی نشان داد که نقاط ضعف بر قوت غلبه دارند و بر طبق نتایج ماتریس عوامل خارجی نیز نقاط فرصت بر تهدید برتری دارند. نتایج مطالعه همچنین نشان داد ظرفیت‌ افزایش ارزش‌افزوده ناشی از فرآوری زعفران با امتیاز 57/0 و ارزش صادراتی با امتیاز 54/0 مهم‌ترین نقطه قوت و قیمت پایین خرید از کشاورزان با امتیاز 13/0 و عدم آگاهی از قیمت رقبا با امتیاز 11/0 مهم‌ترین نقاط ضعف آمیخته بازاریابی قیمت است. همچنین صادرات محصول، باکیفیت‌های مختلف بر اساس توانایی مالی مشتریان بازارهای هدف با امتیاز 32/0 و تعیین قیمت بر اساس محیط رقابتی و اقتصادی با امتیاز 32/0 با اهمیت‌ترین فرصت­ها و عدم ثبات نرخ ارز با امتیاز 40/0 و نوسان قیمت در بازار صادراتی با امتیاز 36/0 بااهمیت‌ترین تهدیدهای کنونی آمیخته بازاریابی قیمت زعفران است. نتایج کلی حاصل از ماتریس تحلیل وضعیت نشانگر تدافعی بودن راهبردهای فاکتور فرآوری زعفران است. لذا طبق نتایج به­دست آمده راهبردهای ایجاد نظام بورس منطقه‌ای داخلی زعفران و کنترل مدت‌دار قیمت در بازارهای صادراتی با هدف توجه به‌نظام قیمت‌گذاری و خرید عادلانه پیشنهاد می‏گردد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">راهبرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قیمت‌گذاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">SWOT</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_55295_6aebc07772ea1a24c5e33932d37d8813.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
