<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Proposed program for standardization of saffron corms production: obstacles and solutions</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>برنامه پیشنهادی برای استاندارد سازی تولید بنه‌های زعفران: موانع و ارائه راهکارها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>457</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>479</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">75218</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.119700.1287</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>سیدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>فارغ التحصیل دکتری، گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پرویز</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضوانی مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron (Crocus sativus L.) is a sterile triploid geophyte plant that is propagated by corms. Considering the crucial role of the mother corms quality in saffron production, a program for &quot;STANDARDIZATION OF SAFFRON CORMS&quot; should be developed in Iran, a measure that has not been taken up yet. There are several obstacles that stop us from having this comprehensive program, for example the lack of standard fields to produce high quality corms, the lack of a clear and precise criteria for sorting produced mother corms, the lack of supervision or poor supervision provided by authorized organizations on production and presentation of high quality corms and unbalanced supply and demand ratio in saffron corms markets, are considered as the most important reasons. Moreover, mixing the healthy and infected corms as well as the storage of corms, regardless of optimal temperature conditions or environmental hygiene, are considered as other challenges in the production and processing cycle of saffron. In this review, some obstacles and prerequisites for implementation of a comprehensive program for STANDARDIZATION OF SAFFRON CORMS are discussed. Further, useful approches and techniques for producing standard corms such as the establishment of managed fields, quality criteria for sorting harvested corms, and the principle storage of corms are outlined. In addition, some effective strategies for the implementation of this program, including the provision of training courses, comperhensive monitoring on the services and functioning in the supply and demand market of saffron corms, helping to meet the needs and demands of consumers, editing incentive plans and supportive programs to saffron producers are specifically provided.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زعفران (&lt;em&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/em&gt; L.) گیاهی ژئوفیت-تریپلوئید بوده و بر پایه رشد بنه‌ها یا اندام‌های زیرزمینی خود، تکثیر می‌یابد. با وجود اهمیت اندازه و کیفیت بنه‌های مادری در تولید زعفران، تاکنون برنامه‌ای جامع پیرامون استانداردسازی بنه‌های آن تدوین نشده است. در این ارتباط، عدم وجود مزارع استاندارد جهت تولید بنه‌های با کیفیت، نبود معیار مشخصی جهت درجه‌بندی بنه‌ها بر اساس اندازه یا ویژگی­های کیفی، نظارت ضعیف از سوی نهادهای ذیربط بر روند تولید و عرضه بنه‌های مادری مرغوب و همچنین نابسامانی در بازار عرضه و تقاضای بنه‌های زعفران، از مهم‌ترین موانع در محقق نشدن چنین برنامه‌ای به شمار می‌روند. همچنین اختلاط بنه‌های سالم و آلوده و نیز انبارداری بنه‌های زعفران بدون توجه به شرایط بهینه دمایی یا بهداشت محیطی از دیگر چالش‌های چرخه تولید و فراوری این محصول می­باشد. در این مقاله، ابتدا برخی موانع پیش روی برنامه استانداردسازی بنه‌های زعفران بررسی شده است و در ادامه، راهکارهای مؤثر جهت تولید بنه­های استاندارد نظیر احداث مزارع تحت مدیریت، کنترل کیفیت ودرجه‌بندی بنه‌های برداشت شده و نیز انبارسازی اصولی بنه‌های زعفران ارائه شده است. همچنین تدوین برنامه ذکر شده بر پایه مواردی نظیر برگزاری دوره‌های آموزشی، نظارت فراگیر بر فعالیت بازار عرضه و تقاضای بنه‌های زعفران، حمایت از حقوق مصرف‌کنندگان و ارائه برنامه‌های تشویقی و بسته‌های حمایتی به تولیدکنندگان به تفصیل مورد بحث قرار گرفته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازاریابی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازار عرضه و تقاضا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تولید زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درجه‌بندی بنه‌های مادری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_75218_e687e46649e6131c815326eac9fb0fdc.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
