<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analysis of Competitiveness of Iran&#039;s Saffron Exporting Companies in Global Markets</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل رقابت پذیری بنگاه های صادرکننده زعفران ایران در بازارهای جهانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>261</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>276</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">90925</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2019.174203.1337</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>کرباسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه اقتصادکشاورزی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>     Recent multi-year experiences in Iran show that reliance on income from the sale of crude oil leads to instability in export earnings.  In order to reduce the dependence of the Iranian economy on crude oil exports, export policies should be directed towards export of non-oil commodities, including exports of agricultural products. Saffron is one of the most important export items of the agricultural sector and medicinal plants. However, its production and export has not grown exponentially in recent years despite growing allocation of land and production. The results of various studies in  have shown that one of the main reasons for failure of Iranian companies in the world market for exporting medicinal herbs is decline in competitiveness in these markets in recent years. Therefore, this study seeks to examine factors affecting competitiveness of Iran&#039;s saffron exporting companies in global markets. Competitiveness measurements using symmetric revealed comparative advantage index and analysis of its influencing factors were analyzed using the Porter Diamond Competitive Model and Fractional Logit Panel regression model. The statistics and data were collected through collecting questionnaires from 35 saffron exporter companies for 2011-2016. The results showed that the six components of the Porter diamond model including demand conditions, factor conditions, supporting industries, firm strategy, state and unpredictable events affect the competitive situation of the companies under study. Accordingly, observance of quantitative and qualitative export standards, prevention of fluctuations in the price of saffron, reduction of exchange rate fluctuations in line with government policies, reduction of production fluctuations due to climate change by providing technical solutions and sufficient attention of companies to marketing strategies are proposed as new ways to improve the competitive situation of the companies being studied.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تجارب چندساله اخیر ایران نشان می­دهد که تکیه اقتصاد به درآمد حاصل از فروش نفت خام، بی­ثباتی درآمد صادراتی را به­دنبال دارد. به­منظور کاهش وابستگی اقتصاد ایران به صادرات نفت خام، جهت­گیری سیاست­های صادراتی باید به سود صدور کالاهای غیرنفتی از جمله صادرات محصولات کشاورزی تغییر یابد. زعفران یکی از اقلام مهم صادراتی ایران است که در سال­های اخیر علی رغم افزایش سطح زیرکشت و تولید ، میزان صادرات آن رشد چشمگیری نداشته است. نتایج پژوهش­های مختلف در ایران نشان می­دهد یکی از دلایل مهم عدم موفقیت شرکت های ایرانی در بازار جهانی صادراتی گیاهان دارویی، کاهش قدرت رقابت­پذیری در این بازارها در سال­های اخیر است. از این رو این مطالعه بر آن است تا به بررسی عامل­های مؤثر بر رقابت پذیری شرکت­های صادرکننده زعفران ایران در بازارهای جهانی بپردازد. اندازه گیری رقابت پذیری با استفاده از شاخص مزیت نسبی آشکار شده متقارن و تحلیل عوامل اثر گذار بر آن با استفاده از الگوی رقابتی الماس پورتر و مدل رگرسیونی پانل لاجیت کسری مورد تجزیه و تحلیل قرار گرفت. آمار و اطلاعات لازم از  طریق جمع آوری پرسشنامه از 35 شرکت صادرکننده زعفران برای سالهای 1395- 1390 به دست آمد. نتایج نشان داد عوامل شش­گانه الگوی الماس پورتر شامل شرایط تقاضا، شرایط عوامل، صنایع پشتیبان، استراتژی بنگاه، دولت و اتفاقات و حوادث غیر قابل پیش بینی، بر وضعیت رقابتی شرکت­های مورد مطالعه اثرگذار می­باشند. بر این اساس رعایت استاندادهای صادراتی به لحاظ کمی و کیفی، جلوگیری از نوسانات قیمتی زعفران، کاهش نوسانات نرخ ارز متناسب با سیاست­های دولت، کاهش نوسانات تولیدی به دلیل تغییرات اقلیمی با ارائه راهکارهای فنی و توجه کافی شرکت­هابه استراتژی­های بازاریابی در کوتاه­مدت و بلند­مدت به عنوان پیشنهاد جهت بهبود وضعیت رقابتی شرکت­های مورد مطالعه مطرح می شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رقابت پذیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صادرات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی الماس پورتر</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_90925_ddee6c3fe361e159f10d80d318ff7575.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
