<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume></Volume>
				<Issue>مقالات آماده انتشار</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identification and Prioritization  of  Development  Strategies for Entrepreneurial  and Commercialization of saffron in Rural Areas Of South Khorasan</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی راهبردهای توسعه کارآفرینی و تجاری‌سازی زعفران مناطق روستایی استان خراسان جنوبی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">110785</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2020.212516.1375</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>علیزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حبیب الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>سالارزهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>گل بهار</FirstName>
					<LastName>پورانجنار</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده اقتصاد و مدیریت، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to use entrepreneurial thinking to identify and prioritize the development strategies of entrepreneurship and commercialization of saffron in rural areas of South Khorasan province in order to rotate traditional agricultural activities in southern Khorasan Province toward innovative activities. In this paper, the integrated approach of the dynamics analysis process SWOT-AHP. First, SWOT analysis has identified and categorized the strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats of saffron activities in rural areas of South Khorasan Province. Since the issue of decision making of the present research is of a multi-index type and its structure has a hierarchical component of decision-making elements, including goal, criteria and sub-criteria, the hierarchical analysis process (AHP) to calculate the weight and importance of each of the criteria and The following criteria have been used through SWOT analysis. In order to collect the research data, the matrix of paired comparison of each of the components and groups was completed using 15 experts and agricultural industry activists, whose internal strengths with the relative weight of 372/0 were in the first rank and also external opportunities with a relative weight of 344/0 And external threats with a relative weight of 148 and, finally, internal weaknesses with a relative weight of 136/0 were ranked next. The results show that the most important strategy for the development of entrepreneurship and commercialization of saffron in rural areas of South Khorasan province is SO strategy with a utility index of 26.2. The most suitable strategies of this kind are the creation of a suitable platform for private sector investment in the development and commercialization of agricultural products, the use of specialized and experienced personnel to establish community-based associations and promote and educate in the field of commercialization, with emphasis on practical aspects through meetings. And various meetings with the people of the region, marketing and advertising to introduce strategic products in South Khorasan province, the strengthening and support of purchasing cooperatives in the cultivation areas were selected for direct purchase from farmers as the most important strategies.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف مطالعه حاضر بهره‌گیری از تفکر کارآفرینانه برای شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی راهبردهای توسعه کارآفرینی و تجاری‌سازی زعفران مناطق روستایی استان خراسان جنوبی در راستای سوق‌دهی فعالیت‌های سنتی کشاورزی در استان خراسان جنوبی به سمت فعالیت‌های نوآورانه بوده است؛ و در آن، از رویکرد تلفیقی فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی و سوات (SWOT-AHP) بهره‌گیری شده است. نخست، با استفاده از تجزیه و تحلیل سوات (SWOT)، شناسایی و طبقه‌بندی نقاط قوت، ضعف، فرصت‌ها و تهدیدات فعالیت‌های کشاورزی در مناطق روستایی استان خراسان جنوبی صورت گرفته است. از آن‌جا که مسئله تصمیم‌گیری تحقیق حاضر از نوع چند شاخصه و ساختار آن دارای سلسله مراتبی از عناصر تصمیم وابسته به هم شامل هدف، معیارها و زیرمعیارها بوده است، از فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی(AHP) برای محاسبه وزن و اهمیت هر کدام از معیارها و زیر معیارهای شناسایی شده از طریق تجزیه و تحلیل سوات استفاده شده است. برای گردآوری داده‌های پژوهش، ماتریس مقایسات زوجی هر کدام از مولفه‌ها و گروه‌ها با بهره‌گیری از نظر 15 نفر از متخصصان و فعالان صنعت کشاورزی تکمیل شده است، که قوت‌های داخلی با وزن نسبی372/0 در رتبه نخست و نیز فرصت‌های بیرونی با وزن نسبی344/0 و تهدیدهای بیرونی با وزن نسبی 148/0و در نهایت، ضعف‌های داخلی با وزن نسبی136/0 در رتبه‌های بعدی قرار گرفتند. نتایج بدست آمده نشان داده است که مهم‌ترین راهبرد‌‌ برای‌توسعه کارآفرینی و تجاری‌سازی زعفران  مناطق روستایی استان خراسان جنوبی  راهبرد SO با شاخص مطلوبیت2/26 است. کاربردی‌ترین راهبرد‌های مناسب از این نوع، ایجاد بستر مناسب جهت سرمایه‌گذاری بخش خصوصی  در زمینه توسعه  و تجاری‌سازی زعفران ، استفاده از نیروهای متخصص و با تجربه به منظور ایجاد تشکل‌های تعاونی مردمی و  ترویج و آموزش در زمینه تجاری‌سازی  با تاکید بر جنبه‌های عملی از طریق نشست‌ها  و جلسات مختلف با مردم منطقه، بازاریابی و تبلیغات برای معرفی محصول زعفران استان خراسان جنوبی، تقویت و حمایت از تعاونی‌های خرید محصول در مناطق کشت در راستای خرید مستقیم از کشاورزان  به عنوان مهم‌ترین استراتژی‌ها انتخاب شدند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"راهبردهای کارآفرینی"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"توسعه کارآفرینی"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"تجاری‌سازی"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">" محصولات کشاورزی"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"زعفران"</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">"سوات"</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
