<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of integrated management of soil fertilizers and summer irrigation on agronomic criteria and flower and stigma yield of saffron</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی مدیریت تلفیقی حاصلخیزکننده‌های خاک و آبیاری تابستانه بر خصوصیات زراعی و عملکرد گل و کلاله زعفران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>393</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>414</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">58033</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.70724.1205</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>قربانعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سرور</FirstName>
					<LastName>خرم دل</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>قربانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهاره</FirstName>
					<LastName>بیچرانلو</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری بوم شناسی زراعی، گروه اگروتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In order to evaluate the effects of organic, chemical and biological fertilizers and summer irrigation on growth characteristics, corm yield, flower yield and stigma yield of saffron, field experiment was conducted as factorial based on a randomized complete block design with three replications at Agricultural Research station, Faculty of Agriculture, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad during three growing season of 2013-2014, 2014-2015 and 2015-2016. The first factor included of animal cow manure (a1), chemical fertilizer (such as Nitrogen, P and K) (a2), Thiobacillus (a3), sulfur (a4), a3+a4 and control (a5) and the second factor was summer irrigation in three levels such as conventional irrigation (A: without summer irrigation), A+ once summer irrigation (23 July), A+ twice summer irrigation (22 June+23 July). Studied characteristics were number and fresh weight of flower, dry weight of stigma, corm diameter, corm weight in four groups (16 g), corms with contractile roots, number of flowering buds per corm, leaf length, dry weight of leaf and dry weight of tunic of saffron. The results in the third of experiment revealed that the interaction effect between fertilizers and summer irrigation were significant (P≤0.01) on all studied traits of saffron except stigma dry weight, corms with weight more than 16 g and dry weight of daughter corms. The highest flower number (282.7 per m2), flower fresh weight (103.2 g/m2), stigma dry weight (1.73 g/m2), leaf dry weight (13.33 g/m2), buds dry weight (4.61 g/m2), flowering buds number per corm (2.627), corm percentage with cractile roots (58.41%), corm diameter (2.97 cm) and corms in different weight were obtained in animal manure and A+once summer irrigation. About simple effects, the highest stigma dry weight and dry weight of daughter corms were observed in animal manure and the highest amount of this traits were obtained in treatment A+once summer irrigation. It seems that summer irrigation increased the flower and stigma yield of saffron due to decreasing soil temperature.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به منظور بررسی تأثیر کودهای آلی، شیمیایی و بیولوژیکی و آبیاری تابستانه بر خصوصیات رشد، بنه، گل و کلاله زعفران، آزمایشی به صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح پایه بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد طیسه سال زراعی 93-1392، 94-1393 و 95-1394 انجام شد. فاکتور اولشامل کود دامی (a1)، کود شیمیایی (NPK) (a2)، تیوباسیلوس (a3)، گوگرد (a4)، a4+a3و شاهد (a5) و فاکتور دوم، آبیاریتابستانه در سه سطح شامل عرف منطقه (A: بدون آبیاری تابستانه)،A+ یک نوبت آبیاری تابستانه (اول مرداد) و A+ دو نوبت آبیاری تابستانه (اول تیر+اول مرداد) بود.صفات مورد مطالعه شامل تعداد و وزن تر گل، وزن خشک کلاله، وزن خشک برگ،قطر بنه، وزن بنه در چهار گروه وزنی (4-2، 8-1/4، 16-1/8و بیش از 1/16 گرم)، وزن خشک بنه‌های دختری، درصد بنه‌های دارای ریشه انقباضی، تعداد و وزن خشک جوانه‌های گل دهنده بود. تجزیه و تحلیل نتایج سال سوم نشان داد کهاثر متقابل کود و آبیاری تابستانه، بر تمام صفات مورد بررسی به جز وزن خشک کلاله، بنه‌های با وزن بیش از 16 گرم و وزن خشک بنه‌های دختری معنی‌دار بود (01/0p≤). بیشترین تعداد گل در متر مربع (7/282)، وزن تر گل (g/m22/103) و وزن خشک کلاله (g/m273/1)، وزن خشک برگ (g/m233/13)، وزن خشک جوانه‌ها (g/m261/4)، تعداد جوانه‌های گل دهنده در بنه (627/2)، درصد بنه‌های دارای ریشه انقباضی (41/58)، قطر بنه ( cm61/3) و گروه‌های مختلف وزنی بنه در تیمار کود دامی و A+یک نوبت آبیاری تابستانه مشاهده شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ریشه انقباضی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعداد گل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جوانه گل دهنده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد کلاله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بنه دختری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کود دامی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_58033_f400a811f856c267a7320bba51ef4219.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effects of of fulvic acid and cow manure on stigma active components and petal Antiradical Activity of saffron (Crocus sativus L.)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی اثر اسید فولویک و کود دامی بر مواد موثره و فعالیت ضد رادیکالی گلبرگ زعفران (.&lt;i&gt;Crocus sativus&lt;/i&gt; L)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>415</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>428</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55269</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2017.99009.1260</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>امینی فرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه آموزشی علوم باغبانی و مرکز پژوهشی گیاهان ویژه منطقه دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فریده</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد، رشته علوم باغبانی، گرایش فیزیولوژی گیاهان دارویی، ادویه‏ای و عطری. دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>components of saffron were evaluated under field conditions. Treatments were four levels cow manure (0, 10, 20 and 30 t.ha-1) and three fulvic acid (0, 5 and 10 kg.ha-1). This experiment was carried out as factorial based on randomized completely block design with three replications in research farm of Birjand University, Iran, during cropping year 2015-2016. Results showed that cow manure improved the active ingredients of stigma (picrocrocin, safranal and crocin) in first year of study. Also, results showed that petal antioxidant compounds (total phenol and anthocyanin) and active ingredients of stigma were influenced by cow manure in second year of study. The highest safranal was obtained in plants treated with 10 t.ha-1 cow manure in first year of experiment. Results also showed that fulvic acid has a positive effect active ingredients of stigma (picrocrocin and crocin), anthocyanin and total phenol in two years of experiment and the highest rate of anthocyanin and total phenol were obtained with 5 kg.ha-1 fulvic acid while the lowest values were recorded in control. Application of different levels of cow manure and fulvic acid had a positive effect on the active ingredients of stigma in two years of experiment and anthocyanin and phenol in second year of study. Thus, results showed that cow manure and fulvic acid have significant impact on antioxidant compounds and active ingredients of saffron under field conditions.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به منظور بررسی اثرات کود گاوی و اسید فولویک بر فعالیت آنتی‏اکسیدانی و مواد مؤثره زعفران (Crocus sativus L.)، آزمایشی به صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح پایه بلوک‏های کامل تصادفی در سه تکرار، در مزرعه دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه بیرجند در سال زراعی 1395- 1394 اجرا شد. فاکتورها شامل کود گاوی در چهار سطح (صفر، 10، 20 و 30 تن در هکتار) و اسید فولویک در سه سطح (صفر، 5 و 10 کیلوگرم در هکتار) با سه تکرار بودند. نتایج دوساله نشان داد که در سال اول اجرای آزمایش کود گاوی بر مواد مؤثره کلاله ( پیکروکروسین، کروسین و سافرانال) و در سال دوم بر فعالیت آنتی‏اکسیدانی گلبرگ (آنتوسیانین و فنول) و مواد مؤثره کلاله معنی‏دار شد. بیشترین مقدار سافرانال در سال اول در سطح 10 تن در هکتار کود گاوی به دست آمد. اسید فولویک نیز در دو سال آزمایش بر مواد مؤثره (کروسین و پیکروکروسین)، آنتوسیانین و فنول اثر معنی‏داری داشت. به طوریکه بیشترین میزان آنتوسیانین و فنول در هر دو سال در تیمار 5 کیلوگرم در هکتار اسید فولویک و کمترین مقدار آنها در سطح شاهد مشاهده گردید. اثر متقابل کود گاوی و اسید فولویک نیز در دو سال بر مواد مؤثره کلاله و در سال دوم بر آنتوسیانین و فنول اثر معنی‏داری گذاشت. به طور کلی نتایج نشان داد،کود گاوی و اسید فولویک تاثیر مثبتی بر فعالیت آنتی‏اکسیدانی و مواد مؤثره زعفران در این آزمایش داشت.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد کلاله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کروسین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آنتوسیانین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کود آلی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_55269_df423e71f248887ac8fb9d5ab6789e03.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation the effect of manure and planting pattern on some flower and corm quantitative traits of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in Gonabad climatic conditions</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی اثر کود دامی و الگوی کشت بر برخی از خصوصیات کمی گل و بنه زعفران زراعی (Crocus sativus L.) در شرایط اقلیمی گناباد</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>429</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>444</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">62312</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.101708.1265</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یاسر</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسماعیلیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه کشاورزی مجتمع آموزش عالی گناباد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد بهزاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه کشاورزی مجتمع آموزش عالی گناباد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In order to study the response of saffron medicinal plant to planting density and different levels of manure, a two year experiment was conducted in split-plot as complete block design with three replications in 2015-16 and 2016-2017 in Gonabad area. Main factor consisted of 5, 10, and 15 cm plant spacing on row and sub factor was control (no manure application), and application of 0, 20, 40, and 60 t/ha cow manure. Experiment results showed that maximum value of fresh flower yield in first year (127.4 kg/ha) achieved in 60 t/ha and in second year (72.3 kg/ha) obtained from 40 t/ha manure application under 5 cm plant spacing in row. The highest fresh stigma yield in both years (10.300 and 5.383 kg/ha, respectively) was obtained due to high planting density (5 cm plant spacing in row) and 40 t/ha manure application. Also, dry stigma yield under this treatment with 2.300 and 1.770 kg/ha, respectively had more increase in both years than other treatments. The highest daughter corm number in both years (614 and 591 corm/m2, respectively) obtained from highest corm planting density. In first year, 40 t/ha manure treatment had the highest value (592 corm/m2) and in second year, 60 t/ha manure application showed the highest value (572 corm/m2). In first year, the highest corm yield with 22724 kg/ha achieved from 5 cm plant spacing in row and 40 t/ha manure. But, in second year the highest mean value (12429 kg/ha) obtained from the same planting density and use of 60 t/ha manure. Therefore, to achieve suitable economic yield in saffron cultivation, application of 40 t/ha cow manure in 20×5 cm planting density under climatic and edaphic conditions similar to this experiment location is suggested.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به منظور بررسی واکنش گیاه دارویی زعفران به تراکم کاشت و سطوح مختلف کود دامی آزمایشی دو ساله به صورت اسپلیت پلات و در قالب طرح بلوک های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار در سال های زراعی 95-1394 و 96-1395 در منطقه گناباد اجرا شد. عامل اصلی شامل فواصل روی ردیف 5، 10، و 15 سانتی متر و عامل فرعی بصورت شاهد (عدم مصرف کود)، و کاربرد 20، 40، و 60 تن در هکتار کود گاوی بود. نتایج آزمایش نشان داد حداکثر عملکرد گل تر در سال اول (4/127 کیلوگرم در هکتار) از کاربرد 60 تن در هکتار و در سال دوم (3/72 کیلوگرم در هکتار) از مصرف 40 تن در هکتار کود گاوی تحت تراکم کاشت 5 سانتی متر روی ردیف بدست آمد. بیشترین عملکرد کلاله تر در هر دو سال آزمایش (به ترتیب با مقادیر 300/10 و 383/5 کیلوگرم در هکتار) در اثر کاشت پرتراکم (فاصله روی ردیف 5 سانتی متر) و اعمال 40 تن در هکتار کود گاوی حاصل شد. عملکرد کلاله خشک نیز در نتیجه تأثیر همین تیمار به ترتیب با مقادیر 300/2 و 770/1 کیلوگرم در هکتار در دو سال آزمایش افزایش بیشتری در مقایسه با سایر تیمارها نشان داد. بالاترین تعداد بنه خواهری در هر دو سال آزمایش (به ترتیب 614 و 591 بنه در متر مربع) از کشت با بیشترین تراکم بنه حاصل شد. در سال اول، تیمار 40 تن در هکتار کود دامی بیشترین مقادیر (592 بنه در متر مربع) را داشته و در سال دوم، تیمار 60 تن در هکتار بالاترین مقادیر (572 بنه در متر مربع) را نشان داد. بیشترین عملکرد بنه در سال اول با میانگین 22724 کیلوگرم در هکتار از فاصله روی ردیف 5 سانتی متر و اعمال 40 تن در هکتار کود دامی حاصل شد. اما در سال دوم بیشترین میانگین (12429 کیلوگرم در هکتار) از همین تراکم کاشت و مصرف 60 تن در هکتار کود دامی بدست آمد. بنابراین، برای دستیابی به عملکرد اقتصادی مناسب در زراعت زعفران، کاربرد 40 تن در هکتار کود گاوی در تراکم کاشت 5×20 سانتی متر در شرایط اقلیمی و خاکی مشابه با محل این آزمایش پیشنهاد می گردد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تراکم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل محیطی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کلاله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کود گاوی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_62312_a80ad347c15cfe876f8f96d08373e5f4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effects of Mother Corm Weight and Cow Manure on Saffron Flower and Corm Yield</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اثر وزن بنه مادری و میزان کود گاوی بر عملکرد گل و بنه زعفران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>445</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>460</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55359</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2017.88165.1236</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رامین</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری بوم شناسی زراعی، پردیس بین الملل دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پرویز</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضوانی مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>کوچکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه اگروتکنولوژی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی و پژوهشگر پژوهشکده زعفران، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In order to investigate the effects of mother corm weight (including 4.1-7, 7.1-10 and 10.1-13 g) and different levels of cow manure (including 30 (control), 60 and 90 t/ha) on flower characteristics and daughter corms of saffron, a factorial experiment based on randomized complete block design with three replications was conducted during two cropping years (2012-13, 2013-14) in Zaweh county. The results of variance analysis in the first and second years showed that there were significant differences between the simple effects and the interaction effects in terms of most of the studied traits, and these differences were higher in the second year. The highest (56.8 m-2) and the lowest (41.3 m-2) flower numbers were obtained in 90 t/ha cow manure with bigger corm size ( 10.1-13 g) and 60 t/ha cow manure with smaller corm size (4.1-7 g) treatments, respectively. 60 t/ha cow manure with bigger corm size (10.1-13 g) and 60 t/ha cow manure with smaller corm size (4.1-7 g) treatments produced the highest (0.347 g.m-2) and the lowest (0.220 g.m-2) dry weight of stigma, respectively. The highest and the lowest of total number of daughter corms (504.2 and 264.7 m-2), total daughter corm yield (2677.3 and 1582.9 g.m-2) were shown in 90 t/ha cow manure with bigger corm size ( 10.1-13 g) and 30 (control) t/ha cow manure with smaller corm size (4.1-7 g) treatments, respectively. In addition, the mean comparison of interaction effect in the second year showed that there were significant differences between most of treatments. The interaction effects of studied traits in the second year showed that 90 t/ha cow manure with bigger corm size (10.1-13 g) and 30 (control) t/ha cow manure with smaller corm size (4.1-7 g) treatments produced the highest and the lowest flower number (231.0 and 156.5 m-2), stigma dry weight (2.062 and 1.053 g.m-2), total number of daughter corms (1024.5 and 505.5 m-2) and total daughter corms yield (4486.6 and 2133.1 g.m-2), respectively. Finally, it can be concluded that by increasing the use of cow manure (more than 60 t/ha) and the use of more than 7 grams mother corms, it is possible to improve the number and yield of daughter corms and these traits will increase the saffron stigma yield in the next coming years.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به‌منظور بررسی اثر وزن بنه مادری (شامل 7-1/4، 10- 1/7 و 13- 1/10 گرم) و سطوح مختلف کود گاوی (شامل30 (شاهد)، 60 و 90 تن در هکتار) بر خصوصیات گل و بنه‌های دختری زعفران، آزمایشی به‌صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح پایه بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار طی دو سال‌ زراعی (94-93 و 93-92) در شهرستان زاوه اجرا شد. نتایج تجزیه واریانس در سال اول و دوم نشان داد که بین اثرات ساده و اثرات متقابل اکثر صفات مورد مطالعه اختلاف معنی‌دار وجود داشت و این اختلافات در سال دوم بیشتر بود. بیشترین و کمترین تعداد گل بترتیب در تیمارهای 90 تن کود گاوی همراه با بنه درشت (13-1/10 گرم) و 60 تن کود گاوی همراه با بنه ریز (7-1/4 گرم) مشاهده گردید. تیمار های 60 تن کود گاوی همراه با بنه درشت و 60 تن کود گاوی همراه با بنه ریز بترتیب بیشترین و کمترین وزن خشک کلاله را تولید کردند. بیشترین و کمترین تعداد کل بنه دختری و عملکرد کل بنه دختری بترتیب متعلق به تیمارهای 90 تن کود گاوی همراه با بنه درشت و30 تن (شاهد) کود گاوی همراه با بنه ریز بود. همچنین مقایسات میانگین اثر متقابل در سال دوم نشان داد که تیمارهای 90 تن کود گاوی همراه با بنه درشت و30 تن (شاهد) کود گاوی همراه با بنه ریز بترتیب بیشترین و کمترین تعداد گل ، وزن خشک کلاله ، تعداد کل بنه دختری و عملکرد کل بنه دختری را دارا بودند. در نهایت می‌توان این‌گونه نتیجه‌گرفت که با افزایش مصرف کود گاوی (بیش از 60 تن) و استفاده از بنه‌های مادری با وزن بیش از 7 گرم می‌توان باعث بهبود صفات تعداد و عملکرد بنه دختری شده و این صفات بخصوص در سال‌های آتی باعث افزایش عملکرد کلاله زعفران می‌گردند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بنه دختری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعداد گل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد کلاله</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کود آلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گلدهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وزن خشک بنه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_55359_a629162e0f480fecf0eae70025b82c95.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effects of Nitroxin bio-fertilizer, superabsorbent polymer and planting method on yield of flower and corm of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) in rainfed-farming condition of Khorramabad, Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر کود زیستی نیتروکسین، پلیمر سوپرجاذب و روش کاشت بر عملکرد گل و بنه زعفران در شرایط دیم خرم آباد</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>461</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>472</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55682</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2017.81060.1221</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>حیدری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری، گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه لرستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خسرو</FirstName>
					<LastName>عزیزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه لرستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسماعیلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه زراعت و اصلاح نباتات دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه لرستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In order to study the effect of bio-fertilizers, planting method and superabsorbent polymer on quantitative yield of saffron under rainfed condition, a factorial experiment based on randomized complete block design with three replications was conducted at the Agricultural Research Station of Khorramabad, Iran during 2015-2016 growing seasons. In this study, Nitroxin bio-fertilizer (consumption 5 Lit/ha and non-consumption), Stockosorb superabsorbent polymer (consumption 240 kg/ha and non-consumption) and planting method (streaking and cluster) was tested. Results showed that triple interactions was significant for number of corm/m2 in first and second year and combined treatment including non-Nitroxin in cluster culture method using superabsorbent with 80.67 corm/m2 for first year and with 183.67 corm/m2 for second year was the superior treatment. Results showed significant differences for number of produced flowers and for fresh and dry weight of stigma in both years; and in the first year, treatment included cluster method cultivation, consumption of superabsorbent and no consumption of Nitroxin was superior; while in the second year, superior treatment was use of superabsorbent, Nitroxin and cluster method. For stigma dry weight of saffron, triple interactions was significant and in the first year, cluster method and consumption of superabsorbent and no usage of Nitroxin was superior (with 0.6 kg/ha), and in the second year, use of Nitroxin and superabsorbent and cluster method was superior (with 0.719 kg/ha). In general, results of the present study in dry-farming conditions over the two years, cluster method cultivation with usage of superabsorbent and Nitroxin could be recommended. Reasons of this recommendation and introduction of the mentioned method are dry climate conditions in area of study and reduction in consumption of chemical fertilizers for development of sustainable agriculture.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به منظور بررسی نقش کودهای زیستی، مواد سوپرجاذب و روش کاشت بر عملکرد گل و بنة زعفران در شرایط دیم، آزمایشی در سال‌های زراعی 94-1393 و 95-1394 به صورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی با سه تکرار در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه لرستان به اجرا در آمد. در این مطالعه‌ عامل‌های کود زیستی نیتروکسین (مصرف 5 لیتر در هکتار و عدم مصرف)، پلیمر سوپرجاذب استاکوزورب (مصرف 240 کیلوگرم در هکتار و عدم مصرف) و روش کشت (خطی و کپه‌ای) مورد آزمون قرار گرفت. نتایج نشان داد از نظر تعداد بنه در واحد سطح اثرات متقابل سه گانه در سال اول و دوم معنی‌دار بود و تیمار ترکیبیِ عدم مصرف نیتروکسین در کشت کپه‌ای همراه با مصرف سوپرجاذب درسال اول با 67/80 و در سال دوم با 67/183 بنه در متر مربع تیمار برتر بود. صفات تعداد گل و وزن کلاله تر و خشک در واحد سطح در هر دو سال اختلاف معنی‌دار آماری داشتند و در سال اول کشت کپه‌ای و مصرف سوپر جاذب و عدم مصرف نیتروکسین تیمار برتر بود؛ در حالیکه در سال دوم تیمار برتر کشت کپه‌ای با مصرف سوپرجاذب و نیتروکسین بود. از نظر عملکرد کلاله خشک زعفران در سال اول کشت کپه‌ای با مصرف سوپرجاذب و بدون کاربرد نیتروکسین با عملکرد حدود 6/0 کیلوگرم در هکتار و در سال دوم کشت کپه‌ای با مصرف نیتروکسین و سوپرجاذب با عملکرد 719/0 کیلوگرم در هکتار تیمارهای برتر بودند. بطورکلی نتایج این تحقیق نشان داد که در دو سال اجرای آزمایش در شرایط دیم، کشت کپه‌ای با مصرف سوپرجاذب و مصرف نیتروکسین قابل توصیه است. دلایل توصیه و معرفی این روش کاشت، شرایط خشک و کمبود آب در منطقه و کاهش مصرف کودهای شیمیایی در جهت حرکت به سوی کشاورزی پایدار است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استاکوزورب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نیتروکسین</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش کاشت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_55682_a532deab5dae5854f349fb69fa31ec21.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Water Deficit and the Effect of Silver Nanoparticles on Morphological Traits onSome Saffron Ecotypes (Crocus sativus L.) in South Khorasan</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تنش کم‌آبی و اثر نانو ذرات نقره بر صفات مورفولوژیک برخی اکوتیپ‌های زعفران (Crocus sativus L.) خراسان جنوبی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>473</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>485</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">57305</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.82080.1223</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سارا</FirstName>
					<LastName>صابرتنها</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد، گروه اصلاح نباتات و بیوتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه زابل</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>براتعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فاخری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد اصلاح نباتات، گروه اصلاح نباتات و بیوتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه زابل</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نفیسه</FirstName>
					<LastName>مهدی نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار اصلاح نباتات، گروه اصلاح نباتات و بیوتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه زابل</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>علیزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار اصلاح نباتات، گروه اصلاح نباتات و بیوتکنولوژی، دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه بیرجند</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present research was conducted to investigate the effect of water stress and silver nanoparticles on morphological traits of some saffron ecotypes. The experiment was done in form of split plot factorial in a randomized complete block design format in three replications at research farm of Birjand University with two levels including full and low water irrigation on 10 ecotypes of saffron and at three levels of silver nanoparticles including control treatment (distille water), 55 and 110 ppm. The traits such as germination date (germination), the number of germinated corm, the number of tillers, the number of leaves, leaf length, the pods length and leaf width were measured. The best date of emergence and the largest number of paws in complete irrigation treatment was observed under distilled water treatment (control). The highest number of corm germinated was observed in irrigated conditions at 55 ppm of silver nanoparticles in the Qaeen ecotype. The highest leaf length was observed under drought stress in the treatment with distilled water (control). The largest number of leaves and leaf width were observed under drought stress at 55 ppm of silver nanoparticles. According to the obtained results of this study, some of the traits at the conditions of drought stress under the silver nanoparticles with a concentration of 55 ppm and some of the traits in the full irrigation and lack of use of silver nanoparticles had the best performance, which it could be said that probably, in stress dryness, the amount of ethylene increases. Some of the obtained results of this study can be related to the effect of silver in preventing ethylene activity.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این پژوهش به‌منظور بررسی تأثیر تنش کم‌آبی و نانو ذرات نقره بر صفات مورفولوژیکی برخی اکوتیپهای زعفران انجام شد. آزمایش به‌صورت اسپیلت پلات فاکتوریل در قالب طرح بلوک‌های کامل تصادفی در سه تکرار در مزرعه تحقیقاتی دانشگاه بیرجند با دو سطح آبیاری کامل و کم‌آبی بر روی 10 اکوتیپ زعفران و در سه سطح نانو ذرات نقره شامل تیمار شاهد (آب مقطر)، 55 و 110 پی‌پی‌ام اجرا شد. صفاتی مانند تاریخ جوانه‌زنی (سبز شدن)، تعداد بنه جوانه‌زده، تعداد پنجه، تعداد برگ، طول برگ، طول غلاف و عرض برگ اندازه‌گیری شد. بهترین تاریخ خروج جوانه (سبز شدن) و بیشترین تعداد پنجه در تیمار آبیاری کامل، تحت تیمار آب مقطر (شاهد) مشاهده شد. بیشترین تعداد بنه جوانه‌زده در شرایط آبیاری در غلظت 55 پی‌پی‌ام نانو ذرات نقره در اکوتیپ قاین مشاهده شد. بیشترین طول برگ تحت تنش خشکی در تیمار با آب مقطر (شاهد) مشاهده شد. بیشترین تعداد برگ و عرض برگ تحت تنش خشکی در غلظت 55 پی‌پی‌ام نانوذره نقره مشاهده شد. بر اساس نتایج چنین استدلال شد برخی از صفات در شرایط تنش خشکی تحت نانو ذرات نقره با غلظت 55 پی-پی‌ام و برخی از صفات در آبیاری کامل و عدم استفاده از نانو ذرات نقره بهترین عملکرد داشتند که احتمالا می‌توان گفت در تنش خشکی میزان اتیلن افزایش می‌یابد، برخی از نتایج در این تحقیق می‌تواند به اثر نقره در جلوگیری از فعالیت اتیلن مرتبط باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تنش خشکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعداد بنه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعداد پنجه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیاز</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_57305_170e854011d39f836525d5335b1f1de3.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation acaricide of vegetative material and acaricide on control saffron mite Rhizoglyphus robini in the laboratory condition</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی کنه کشی ترکیبات گیاهی و شیمیایی بر کنه زعفران Rhizoglyphu robini در شرایط آزمایشگاهی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>487</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>497</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">61866</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.26623.1080</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرشته</FirstName>
					<LastName>یوسف زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه علم و فرهنگ شعبه کاشمر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عیسی</FirstName>
					<LastName>جبله</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه گیاهپزشکی، جهاد دانشگاهی خراسان رضوی، موسسه آموزش عالی جهاد دانشگاهی کاشمر، کاشمر، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>اولیایی ترشیز</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی گروه گیاه پزشکی سازمان جهاددانشگاهی خراسان رضوی،کاشمر، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه تولیدات گیاهی و پژوهشگر پژوهشکده زعفران دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>According to the export of saffron (Crocus sativus.L) and superiority of organic products in the market, this study performed in order to assessment natural methods in control of saffron mite which is a major pest of saffron, was conducted in the saffron institute of Torbat university in 2014. In this research has been studied effect of Bromopropylate and Propargite acaricides and Rosemary essential oil and Stinking assa resin on development steps of Rhizoglyphus robbini in four doases and six different times the peresence of acaricide (3, 6, 12,24,48,72 hours) in the factorial on complete randomized design and four replications. The laboratory condition was determined at photoperiod 16:8, humidity 65 ± 5 percentage and temperature 27 ± 2°C. Analysis results of data variance showed that the effects of treatments on mortality of egg ،larvae and mature mites were significant at the 1 percentage probability level. Also that Bromopropylate has maximum mortality percent among larvae and mature saffron mite. Also in this experiment time increasing and concentration increase mortality of larvae’s significantly. As well as the maximum percent of eggs failed to hatch related to Rosemary essential oil .Also larvae mortality percent was more than mature mite that had significant differences at 5% probability level .In this study was found Stinking assa resin has the greatest impact on the egg also Propargite and Bromopropilate have created the highest mortality on the larvae and adults respectively.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با توجه به صادراتی بودن گیاه زعفران (Crocus sativus L.) و برتری محصولات ارگانیک در بازار پسندی آن‌ها، این مطالعه به منظور بررسی روش‌های غیر‌شیمیایی و مقایسه با کنه کش های شیمیایی در کنترل کنه زعفران که از آفات مهم زعفران محسوب می‌شود، در پژوهشکده زعفران دانشگاه تربت حیدریه در سال 1393 انجام شد. در این تحقیق اثر کنه‌کش‌های بروموپروپیلات و پروپارژیت، اسانس های رزماری و صمغ آنغوزه بر مراحل زیستی کنه زعفران در 4 دز و 6 زمان مختلف مجاورت با کنه‌کش (3 و 6 و 12 و 24 و 48 و 72 ساعت) بصورت فاکتوریل در قالب طرح کاملا تصادفی در چهار تکرار بررسی شد. شرایط آزمایشگاهی با دوره نوری 16:8 ساعت، رطوبت 5±65 درصد و دمای 2±27 درجه سانتیگراد تعیین گردید. نتایج آنالیز واریانس داده ها نشان داد اثرات تیمارهای آزمایش بر میزان مرگ و میر تخم، لارو و کنه بالغ در سطح احتمال یک درصد معنی‌دار بود. هم چنین کنه کش بروموپروپیلات بیشترین تلفات را داشته که با افزایش زمان و غلظت میزان تلفات به طور معنی‌داری افزایش یافت. هم‌چنین بیشترین درصد تخم تفریخ نشده مربوط به اسانس رزماری بود و درصد مرگ و میر لاروها نیز بیشتر از کنه‌های بالغ بود که با یکدیگر اختلاف معنی‌داری در سطح احتمال 5 درصد داشتند. در این تحقیق مشخص شد که صمغ آنغوزه بیشترین تاثیر را روی تخم این آفت داشته است و کنه کش پروپارژیت و بروموپروپیلات به ترتیب بیشترین مرگ و میر را روی لارو و کنه بالغ ایجاد کرده اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اسانس رزماری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بروموپروپیلات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پروپارژیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صمغ آنغوزه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_61866_9b2ae14084a835abd70a714d9877084c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Assessing the Role of Trade Sanctions and Global Economic Crisis on Iran’s Saffron Exports</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی نقش تحریم‌های تجاری و بحران اقتصادی جهانی بر صادرات زعفران ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>499</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>511</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54312</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2017.85769.1231</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آرش</FirstName>
					<LastName>دوراندیش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار اقتصاد کشاورزی، گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میلاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>امینی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری اقتصاد کشاورزی، گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اندیشه</FirstName>
					<LastName>ریاحی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد اقتصاد کشاورزی، گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهام</FirstName>
					<LastName>مهرپرور حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری اقتصاد کشاورزی ، گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8663-8416</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>13</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Saffron is one of Iran’s exports of agricultural products that it could not keep and strengthen its position in the world market at recent years. Two events such as European Union trade sanctions against Iran (2006-2014) and global economic crisis (2007-2009) have directly and indirectly impacts on Iran’s economy and trade flows, respectively. According to process uncertainty about the abolition or continuation of the European Union trade sanctions and the possibility of a new global economic crisis, the aim of this paper is assessing the role of these two factors on Iran’s saffron exports. For this purpose, saffron exports to trading partners were analyzed by using gravity model and poisson pseudo maximum likelihood estimator in 2001-2014 periods. Based on the results, economic size, importer’s income and regional trade agreement have positive effect and distance and difference in GDP per capita have negative and significant impacts on saffron exports. The Results indicated that EU trade sanctions and global economic crisis have significantly negative effects on Iran’s saffron exports. In other words, due to Iran’s trading partners, global economic crisis have important role in saffron exports. Therefore, it is suggested that role of trade sanctions and economic crisis and their importance be considered to adopt long run strategic plan in order to strengthen Iran’s position in saffron world market and optimal basket of trading partners to be selected.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زعفران یکی از مهم‌ترین محصولات صادراتی کشاورزی ایران است که در سال‌های اخیر نتوانسته جایگاه خود را در بازار جهانی حفظ و تقویت کند. دو پدیدة تحریم‌های تجاری اتحادیة اروپا علیه ایران (2014-2006) و بحران اقتصادی جهانی (2009-2007) به ترتیب به صورت مستقیم و غیرمستقیم بر اقتصاد و جریان تجاری ایران اثرگذار بوده‌اند. با توجه به روند نامعلوم تحریم‌های اتحادیة اروپا در خصوص لغو یا استمرار آن و احتمال بروز بحران اقتصادی جهانی جدید، هدف پژوهش پیش رو، افزون بر شناسایی مؤلفه‌های اثرگذار، ارزیابی نقش و میزان اثرگذاری این دو مؤلفه بر صادرات زعفران ایران است. بدین منظور، صادرات زعفران به شرکای تجاری در دورة 2014-2001 با استفاده از الگوی جاذبه و برآوردگر درستنمایی شبه بیشینه پوآسن مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. بر اساس نتایج، متغیرهای اندازة اقتصاد، درآمد کشورهای واردکننده و موافقت‌نامه‌های تجاری اثری فزاینده و معنی‌دار و متغیرهای فاصله و تفاوت‌ اقتصادی اثری کاهنده و معنی‌دار بر صادرات زعفران داشته‌اند. نتایج گویای اثر منفی و معنی‌دار تحریم‌های تجاری اتحادیه اروپا و بحران اقتصادی جهانی بر صادرات زعفران ایران است. به عبارتی سبد شرکای تجاری ایران به گونه‌ای است که بحران اقتصادی نقشی تعیین‌کننده بر صادرات زعفران دارد. از این رو، پیشنهاد می‌شود در تدوین برنامة راهبردی بلندمدت به منظور تقویت جایگاه ایران در بازار جهانی زعفران، نقش تحریم‌های تجاری و بحران اقتصادی و اهمیت آن دیده شود و متناسب با آن سبد بهینه‌ای از شرکای تجاری انتخاب شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی جاذبه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برآوردگر درستنمایی شبه بیشینه پوآسن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بحران اقتصادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحریم اتحادیه اروپا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_54312_6373f23a97bd4a88db6c1c85f3352516.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>علمی پژوهشی زراعت و فناوری زعفران</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2383-1529</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>.Application of Risk Profile in Saffron Risk Management</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>کاربرد پروفیل ریسک در مدیریت ریسک محصول زعفران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>513</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>529</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">57181</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22048/jsat.2018.92906.1249</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الناز</FirstName>
					<LastName>نجاتیان پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده زعفران و مدرس مدعو گروه اقتصاد کشاورزی، دانشگاه تربت حیدریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>قدوسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مربی گروه صنایع، دانشکده فنی و مهندسی، دانشگاه تربت‌حیدریه</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسن پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه صنعتی قوچان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Agriculture is a unique sector because of its dependence on the climate and biological variables. Therefore, in agriculture it is vital to identify and evaluate risks to be sure that decisions made on the farm will bring positive results. Torbat-e-Heydarieh is the most important center in saffron cultivation and production in Khorasan Razavi province and Iran. This city is famous for its Saffron lands. It has the first rank in the world for producing Saffron . So, in this paper, we employed risk profile analysis to saffron risk management. By using previous literatures, all of the risks of agricultural sector are identified and classified in nine categories. The information was collected from the university elite and Saffron union members. To design the risk profile, we used data from 67 saffron producers of Torbat Heydariyeh in 1395. For evaluating of losses related to each risk component, two indexes of frequency and severity of risk were calculated and based on that risk matrix were created. Results showed that the greatest area of risk is included all of the risk of pests, diseases and weeds (Different types of weeds, Micro pests (Fungi and bacteria), Macro pests( Mice, ant, insect, Grazing livestock)), economic risk (Brokers, market fluctuations, lack of liquidity of farmers), Climate risk (drought, frost and freeze) and damage risk (Reduce yield due to farm life).</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کشاورزی بدلیل وابستگی به متغیرهای بیولوژیکی و شرایط اقلیمی دارای شرایط ویژه ایی است. رفتار این متغیرها تاثیر چشمگیری بر روی عملکرد محصولات کشاورزی و درآمد کشاورز دارد. بنابراین در این بخش تشخیص و ارزیابی ریسک ها برای تصمیم گیری صحیح و دستیابی به نتایج درست بسیار حائز اهمیت است. تربت حیدریه مهمترین مرکز کشت و تولید زعفران در خراسان و ایران و رتبه اول تولید زعفران در دنیا است. در این مطالعه کاربرد پروفیل ریسک برای مدیریت ریسک محصول زعفران مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. برای دست-یابی به پروفیل ریسک از داده‌های مربوط به 67 زعفران‌کار شهرستان تربت حیدریه در سال 1395 بهره گرفته شد. برای ارزیابی خسارت‌ هریک از ریسک‌ها از دو معیار فراوانی وقوع ریسک و میزان اثر ریسک و سرانجام ماتریس ریسک استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان داد که بزرگترین ناحیه ‌ی ریسک که دارای بیشترین احتمال وقوع و شدت اثر می‌باشد شامل تمام ابعاد گروه ریسک آفات، بیماریها و علف های هرز ( انواع علف های هرز، آفات میکرو( قارچ و باکتری) و آفات ماکرو( موش، مورچه، کنه و چرای دام))، سه مورد از گروه ریسک اقتصادی (واسطه و دلال، نوسانات بازار و عدم نقدینگی کشاورزان) دو مورد از ریسک اقلیمی (خشکسالی و سرمازدگی و یخبندان) و یک مورد از ریسک خسارت (افت عملکرد به دلیل عمر بالای مزرعه) است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زعفران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ماتریس ریسک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ریسک‌های کشاورزی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://saffron.torbath.ac.ir/article_57181_afbb544b8cfe1a58670f11b607c2c0e3.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
