<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>8</volume>
<number>30</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>شناسایی عوامل موثر بر انتقال آموزش به محیط کار در بین کارکنان شرکت پژوهش و فناوری پتروشیمی</title_fa>
	<title>Identification of the factors related to transfer of training to work environment amongst the employees of National Petrochemical Company</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;سازمان ها از دیرباز منابع مالی قابل توجهی را برای برگزاری آموزشهایسازمانی اختصاص می دهند. اما توسعه و پیشرفت منابع انسانی تنها با برگزاری آموزشهای عمومی و تخصصی حاصل نمی شود. امروزه از آموزش انتظار میرود که بتواند تغییرات رفتاری مطلوب را در کارکنان ایجاد کند. بررسیها نشان میدهد که بسیاری&lt;br&gt;
از برنامههای آموزشی تغییرات رفتاری مطلوب را در کارکنان ایجاد نمیکند. این بدان معنی است که کارکنان قادر به انتقال آموختههای خود به محیط کارشان نیستند. اثربخشی آموزش به شدت متکی بر فرضیاتی است که در انتقال آن به محیط کار رخ میدهد. بنابراین، یکی از بهترین راههای رسیدن به اثربخشی آموزشی افزایش نرخ انتقال آموزش است. از این رو در این پژوهش به شناسایی عوامل تاثیرگذار بر انتقال آموزش پرداخته و عوامل اساسی مورد بررسی قرار گرفتهاند.روش پژوهش از نوع پیمایشی بوده و جامعه آماری نیز شامل 500 نفر از افراد شرکت کننده در دورههای آموزشی شرکت پژوهش و فناوری پتروشیمی در سه شهر تهران، اراک و ماهشهر میباشد که تعداد ٢17 نفر از آنها از طریق روش نمونهگیری تصادفی طبقه ای انتخاب شده اند. در فرایند پژوهش با مطالعه پیشینه ٢7 عامل موثر بر انتقال آموزش شناسایی گردید و با اجرای سه مرحله تکنیک دلفی این عوامل به 18 عامل کاهش یافت. سپس برای شناسایی عوامل تسهیل کننده و مانع انتقال آموزش پرسشنامهای با 6٢ گویه ساخته شد. نتایج نشان میدهد که از 18 عامل، 7عامل به عنوان تسهیلگر ضعیف، 9عامل به عنوان مانع ضعیف، 1عامل به عنوان مانع قوی و 1عامل نیز به عنوان تسهیلگر قوی در این سازمان شناسایی شدند. همچنین نتایج تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی نشان داد که عوامل مرتبط با انتقال آموزش در 5&amp;nbsp; طبقه)فردی، حمایتی، آموزشی، سیستم پاداش و پیشرفت( گروه بندی شدند که منتج به ارائه یک سنخ شناسی جدید از عوامل موثر بر انتقال آموزش گردید.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Organizations have long been devoting significant financial resources to organizing organizational training. But the development of human resources is not achieved by conducting general and specialized training. Today, training is expected to provide the desired behavioral changes in the staff. Studies show that many educational programs do not create desirable behavioral changes in the staff. This means that employees are not able to transfer their learning to their work environment. The effectiveness of training is heavily reliant on the assumptions that occur in its transmission to the workplace. Therefore, one of the best ways to achieve educational effectiveness is to increase the transfer rate of education. Therefore, in this research, we have identified factors affecting the transfer of education. The research method was a survey and the statistical population included500 people who participated in the courses of Petrochemical Research and Technology Company in three cities of Tehran, Arak and Mahshahr. Among them, 217&amp;nbsp; persons were selected through stratified random sampling method.&amp;nbsp; In the research process, 27&amp;nbsp; factors influencing the transfer of education were identified by reviewing the related literature. By implementing three stages of Delphi technique, these factors decreased to 18&amp;nbsp; factors. Then, for identifying facilitating and preventing factors of transfer of training, a questionnaire was developed with 62&amp;nbsp; items. The results showed that of among the 18&amp;nbsp; identified factors, 7 factors were weak as facilitators, 9&amp;nbsp; factors were considered as weak barriers, one factor as a strong barrier and one factor as a strong facilitator in this organization. Also, the results of exploratory factor analysis showed that the factors related to the transfer of training were grouped in five levels: individual, supportive, educational, reward system and progression, which resulted in the presentation of a new typology of factors influencing the transfer of training.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>انتقال آموزش , عوامل تسهیل گر و مانع , سازمان پژوهش و فناوری پتروشیمی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Transfer of training, facilitation and barrier factors, Petrochemical Research and Technology Organization.</keyword>
	<start_page>99</start_page>
	<end_page>122</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-25-38&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید محمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>میرکمالی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002106</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002106</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>متاجی نیمور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>aliye1366@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002107</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002107</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مصطفی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حسن زاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002108</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002108</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
