<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>35</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی تأثیر مدیریت شادمان سازی (نشاط) بر عملکرد کارکنان شرکت گاز منطقه دو اصفهان بر مبنای مدل استیرز</title_fa>
	<title>Studying the Effects of Employees Happiness Management System on Employees' Performance Based On Steers' Model (Case: Isfahan Branch Gas Company)</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;شادمان سازی پرسنل به عنوان یک حوزه مطالعاتی در روانشناسی و مدیریت منابع انسانی،&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;اهمیت زیادی برای مدیران و کارکنان پیدا کرده است. شادی در محیط کار زمانی حاصل می&#8204;شود که فرد جهت دستیابی به اهداف کاری ، از توانایی ها و استعدادهای خود استفاده نماید. هدف این تحقیق پاسخگویی به&amp;nbsp; این سوال است که آیا شادمان سازی (نشاط) پرسنل بر عملکرد شغلی آنها تاثیر دارد. در این پژوهش از مدل ریچارد ام. استیرز استفاده شده است. روش انجام این تحقیق از نوع توصیفی همبستگی از شاخه میدانی، از لحاظ ماهیت، کاربردی و از لحاظ زمان، مقطعی می&#8204;باشد. جامعه آماری تحقیق شامل کارکنان شرکت گاز منطقه دو اصفهان با 800 نفر کارمند و انتخاب نمونه ای 256 نفره بر اساس فرمول تعیین حجم نمونه و به روش نمونه گیری طبقه ای تصادفی بود. شیوه گرد&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;آ&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;وری اطلاعات شامل مطالعات کتابخانه ای و ابزار پرسشنامه محقق ساخته بود. روایی محتوائی و صوری توسط صاحب نظران&amp;nbsp; و پایایی ابزار تحقیق با ضریب آلفای کرونباخ (082/) محاسبه گردید. در نهایت، هر ده فرضیه مربوط به تاثیر مولفه های شادمان سازی بر عملکرد مورد تائید قرارگرفته و در رتبه بندی متغیرها عامل یادگیری و علاقه به کار به ترتیب با 6/38 و 6/09 رتبه ، بیشترین میانگین را داشته اند.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;According to the increasing changes and developments in organizations, the managers are seeking to improve the staff performance to a large degree. In this way, they want to increase the functionality of organization production. Rise of happiness among staff which is a field of study in psychology and human resource management, has recently become important for managers and employees. Happiness in workplace comes when a person uses his abilities and talents to achieve his goals. The purpose of this research is to answer the question of whether employees' happiness affects their job performance. In this research, Richard M. Steers' model has been used. The research method is descriptive-correlation, practical in terms of nature, and sectional in terms of time period. The statistical population of the study consisted of employees of Isfahan's gas company with 800 employees and a sample selection of 256 people based on the sample size formula and random stratified sampling method. The information gathering method included library studies and a researcher-made questionnaire. The validity of questionnaire was determined by the experts and the reliability of the research tool was calculated using Cronbach's alpha coefficient (0.82). Finally, all ten hypotheses related to the effect of happiness components on performance have been confirmed. In rating of variables, learning factor and job interest had the highest mean with 6.38 and 6.9, respectively.&lt;/div&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شادمان سازی (نشاط) , یادگیری , علاقه به کار , عملکرد سازمانی , عدالت سازمانی , شرکت گاز</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>happiness, learning, job desire, organizational performance, organizational justice, Gas Company</keyword>
	<start_page>33</start_page>
	<end_page>58</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-25-27&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Seyed Rasool</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Aghadavood</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید رسول</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>آقاداوود</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>aghadavood@dehaghan.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846002215</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002215</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد دهاقان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
