<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <records>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>6</volume>
	<issue>24</issue>
	<startPage>3</startPage>
	<endPage>30</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Prioritization of Factors Affecting the Development of  Knowledge Management System Knowledge Management Cycle</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Jahaniar Bamdad Soufi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Ali Khatami Firoozabadi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mona Zakaria Sani</name>
	<email>m.zakaria68@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">In this research, factors affecting the development of knowledge management (KM) system are identified in different phases of KM cycle at Petrochemical technology and research center of Iranian Petrochemical Company. Then these factors are prioritized. In this research, first all activities of knowledge management cycle phases in mentioned company are identified locally by using a distributed questionnaire among elites. Then identified activities in before phase are prioritized with considering criteria of knowledge management in each phase from its cycle by second questionnaire. For data analyze and activities prioritization, are used from Fizzy Topsis and Analytical network process (ANP), then results of this methods compare each other. Results indicated which activities have the most priority at each phase of KM cycle, and the company must to attend this activities and investment on them for developing of knowledge management</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-21-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Knowledge management cycleActivities prioritization Fuzzy Topsis Analytical network process Petrochemical Technology and Research Center</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>eng</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>6</volume>
	<issue>24</issue>
	<startPage>31</startPage>
	<endPage>54</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Priorities and factors affecting on Managers Participation of National Iranian Oil Company (NIOC) in Trainings</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Amin Habibi Rad</name>
	<email>ahabibirad@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Kamran Feizi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Rezaeian</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>– Seyed Hasan Fakourian</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Askar Azizi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>5</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="5">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The research purpose is to explore the reasons why the managers do not participate in training programs actively? After that, it is necessary to remove these factors in next trainings to provide the needful knowledge and skills consistent with business condition for managers. Needed data gathered through the content analysis of manager`s ideas about the training programs of national Iranian oil company (NIOC) and then a questionnaire developed based on them. In this research 380 managers of NIOC participated. Findings show that the demands of managers depend on their work, education and work experience. However, training programs in the first half of the day, outside of work site, as a workshop or with mixed method have a higher priority from the managers perspective. In this research, also, the needed training subject as well as the solutions for improvement in organizational trainings from the managers point of view were investigated.
&#160;</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-22-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Training needs Managers Training BarriersTraining Priorities National Iranian Oil Company (NIOC</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>eng</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>6</volume>
	<issue>24</issue>
	<startPage>55</startPage>
	<endPage>103</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Providing an Integrated Model of the Perceived Justice, Job Satisfaction, Organizational Commitment and Variables of Planned Behavior Model Affecting the Willingness of Employees to Movement
(Case study: Pars Oil and Gas Company)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Hasan M. Joshaghani M. Joshaghani</name>
	<email>joshaghaniha@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mansoure Hadavi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of this paper is providing a model to determine the factors affecting the willingness of employees to job relocation. In the transition from the industrial age to the post-industrial age, post-industrial society, Be organized around knowledge creation and use of information On one hand, heavy reliance of this competitive environment on knowledge capitals and staff expertise and the other hand, fluidity of these capitals, has caused the issue of maintenance and keep them in organization is of great importance. Inability to properly manage the maintenance staff (Particularly worthy and capable), as the main organizational capital, in addition to the direct and indirect costs imposed, if employees leave the organization, makes transmission capabilities to competing companies and finally, the loss of competitive advantage. In this study, we considered the factors affecting the willingness of employees to job relocation by combining model of planned behavior and variables of organizational justice, organizational commitment, and job satisfaction. The sample consisted of 210 employees of pars oil and gas company (POGC). In this study, of a questionnaire to collect data&#160; and statistical software (SPSS and LISREL) for data analysis, was used. After analyzing data, results showed that Variables of organizational commitment, job satisfaction and organizational justice with variables of planned behavior, Are effective on willingness to job relocation</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-23-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>The theory of  planned behavior Organizational justice Job satisfaction organizational commitment Willingness to movement</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>eng</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>6</volume>
	<issue>24</issue>
	<startPage>105</startPage>
	<endPage>136</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Investigating the Relationship of Servant Leadership with the Organizational Trust and People Empowerment in Mazandaran Gas Co.</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Fattah Sharifzadeh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Vajhollah Ghorbanizadeh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hamed Mohammadi</name>
	<email>Mohammadi.16@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Farhad Rokni Lamouki</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">This study sets out to explore the relationship of servant leadership with the organizational trust and people empowerment in Mazandaran Gas Company. The statistical population was consisted of 459 employees of the company with a sample of 329 of them. A surveyor- built questionnaire with 80 items was used to collect data. Its reliability has been proven as 0.97 through Crombach`s coefficient alpha. In an inference analysis, the study used Pearson correlation test to investigate the hypotheses, t test to consider the difference between the Managers and employees perception and lizrel software to examine data for a path analysis and presenting a structural model. Correlation analysis indicated that in Mazandaran Gas Company, servant leadership is positively correlated to the organizational trust and people empowerment and also, there is no significant difference between the managers` and employees` perception of&#160; servant leadership</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-24-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Servant leadership Organizational trust People empowerment Mazandaran Gas Company</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>eng</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>6</volume>
	<issue>24</issue>
	<startPage>137</startPage>
	<endPage>160</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Diagnosis for Implementing and Applying Research Results of Human Resources Management in Oil Industry</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mahmoud Jafarpoor</name>
	<email>Mahmoudjafarpoor@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Nasrin Rezayi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Soudabeh Soori</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Organizational diagnosis is a systematic process for gathering data in order to interact effectively to tackle some organizational problems, challenges, pressures and restrictions. Thus, the purpose of present research is a diagnosis for implementing and applying the research results of human resources management in oil industry. In terms of purpose, its methodology was descriptive; in terms of results, it was applicable; in terms of data, it was quantitative and in terms of data gathering time, it was periodic. Questionnaire was used as a data gathering tool. The statistical society consisted of two groups: (1) professors and experts for the field of human resources management in reliable universities and (2) human resources managers in Tehran organizations and companies of oil industry field, including 335 people. The sample volume was specified with 180 people. Survey results showed that at the %99 confidence level, 35 indices are effective on the research results of human resources management and cause them not to be implemented and applied in oil industry. Among them, three indices of &#171;users' weakness in studying culture&#187;, &#171;not to apply suitable scientific and practical supervisors (consultants)&#187; and &#171;instability for major organizational decision-makings&#187; are the most important indices mentioned by the respondents. The identified indices were also classified in three groups of structural, behavioral (conceptual) and environmental damages.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-25-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Diagnosing Organizations Human Resource Management Structure Behavior Context.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>eng</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>6</volume>
	<issue>24</issue>
	<startPage>163</startPage>
	<endPage>180</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Considering the Relationship Structural, Relative and Cognitive Dimensions of Social Capital with Job Satisfaction and Job Stress
(Case study: Ghaed Basir Petrochemical Company)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Saeid Abdolmanafi</name>
	<email>saeid_manafi@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mansour Moazami</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mahmoud Gholami Karin</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Noruzy</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The present research aims to study the relationship of social capital with job satisfaction and job stress of the personels in Ghaed Basir Petrochemical Company. As for sampling 206 employees were selected using stratified sampling method and questionnaires of social capital, job satisfaction and stress scale were distributed between them. Pearson correlation test and stepwise regression analysis were used to analyze data. The results of Pearson correlation test indicate that there is a positive and meaningful relation between social capital and its tree dimension i.e. structural, relational and cognitive with job satisfaction. Moreover, the results show that there is a negative and meaningful relation between social capital and its structural and relational dimensions with job stress. Result of the stepwise regression analysis determined the share of relational and cognitive dimensions in the prediction of job satisfaction as 0.75 and 0.26 respectively. The shares of relational and structural dimensions in forecasting the job stress were also determined as -0.56, and -0.25 respectively. So we can, improve job satisfaction and reduce job stress with facilitate of social capital in organizations</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-26-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Social Capital Job Satisfaction Job StressGhaed Basir Petrochemical Company Diagnosis</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>eng</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>6</volume>
	<issue>24</issue>
	<startPage>181</startPage>
	<endPage>201</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Necessary Conditions for the Implementation of Green Management of HR in the Petroleum Industry</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Marjan Faiiazi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Saeed Shahbaz Moradi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Zahra Afshar</name>
	<email>Zahra.afshar@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">&#160;
Today's green human resource management is very important in organizations and in oil industry it is more important also. the aim of the present research is finding the necessary Prerequisite of doing the green human resource management in oil industry. how to do this research is mix method. in this way of research, first some interviews had done, then the results were paid attention in the point of content analysis. finally a questionnaire was designed and was given to the managers and experts of HR in national oil industry. the Cronbach's alpha coefficient of these questionnaire was. 973, and it is shown the high level of reliability of this questionnaire. The results of the present research indicates that among total category, supporting top managers is very important. As a result&#160; if the managers support green program, the introduction of the stages will be done. Among the strategic factors, present of green vision, Among the organizational factors, Budget, Among related factors with employees,&#160; staffing and development of environmental experts, also the employee's&#160;&#160; knowledge and skills are very important. Furthermore the results of&#160; Friedman test shows that financial factors and supporting from managers are very effective on green human resource processes</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-27-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Green human resources Management Green management Environmental Oil industry &#38; Green workers</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>eng</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>6</volume>
	<issue>24</issue>
	<startPage>203</startPage>
	<endPage>229</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Impact of the Intellectual Capital Efficiency on Financial Performance in the Petroleum Products Industry</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Roohola Ghabezi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Seyed Mahmoud Mousavi Shiri</name>
	<email>mousavi.shiri@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Soodabeh Jalili Anooshirvani</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Abdollah Habibi Moheb Seraj</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">&#160;
In this research, the relationship between the intellectual capital Efficiency and its components (structural, physical and human capital) with three components of financial performance including the profit per share, return on owner&#8217;s equity and return on assets in the Iranian petroleum products industry, along with two controlling variables; the size of the company and the financial leverage, have been tested. In order to test the hypothesis of the research, the information of eleven companies of the petroleum products industry listed&#160; in Tehran Stock Exchange during the years 2007 to 2012 (includes 55 years-company) has been collected and by using the multiple regression and Data Panel method has been analyzed and studied. The results show that there is a significant (or meaningful) relationship between intellectual capital and structural capital with profit per share, return on owner&#8217;s equity and return on assets. Finally the results show a significant relation between the coefficient value of intellectual capital and profit per share, but there is no significant relationship between the coefficient value of intellectual capital, return on owner&#8217;s equity and return on assets</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-28-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Intellectual Capital Human Capital Physical Capital Structural CapitalFinancial PerformancePetroleum Product</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
 </records>
 
  
  
  
  
 