<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <ArticleSet>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>21</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The effect of person-job fit and person-organization fit on employees’ organizational commitment: The mediating role of psychological contract (Case study: Iran’s national gas Co)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>9</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>28</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Yousef</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mohammadi Mogaddam</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>You_mohammad @yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hosein</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Gholamhoseini</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>), ho.gh20@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Abouzar</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Yazdanshenas</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>) a.yazdanshenas1986@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>MohammadReza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mazloomi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>mazloomi-mo@mashhad.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Organizational commitment has been one of the most popular work attitudes studied by practitioners and researchers. This article seeks to investigate the mediating role of psychological contract (PC) in the relationship between person-job (PJ) fit, person-organization (PO) fit and organizational commitment (OC). The target population for this study consists of support staff of Iran&#8217;s national gas company. The instrument for gathering data was questionnaire. The results of research showed that psychological contract fulfillment (PCF) has a positive and significant effect on OC. The results also showed a significant, positive and relatively weak effect of PO on PCF and OC. Despite of this, PCF could not mediate the relationship between PO and OC. This article adds new findings to the PC literature and emphasizes the importance of interactive role of PO, PJ in affecting on OC.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>organizational commitment- psychological contract- person-job fit person-organizationfit</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-347-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-347-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>21</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The Study of Affecting Factors on the E-Learning Readiness in National Petrochemical Company Employees</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>29</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>58</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>amouzad</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Mohamadamouzad@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ghahramani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>M-ghahramani@sbu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Elham</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Golinezhad</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Elhamgolinezhad@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The aim of this study is investing of the affecting factors on organizational learning readiness on national petrochemical co. staff. The results of this research is using implement in training processes. E-learning is a special type of distance learning that relies on network-based technologies and using transmission media such as the Internet or intranet and also multimedia tools, in an interactive virtual environment to provide training or retraining. This study examine Electronic Readiness which is the ability of an organization to successful adoption of information to use and gain profit from it .this research is descriptive and correlation. A total of 400 samples selected randomly and proportionally among subsidiaries petrochemical industries Staff and 376 questionnaires were completed and returned. the results were analyzed with statistical methods of structural equation modeling and using LISREL software. The results show environmental readiness and facilities with the strongest direct and positive relationship, has most effect on e-learning readiness .The learning styles and organizational culture readiness variables have the most direct effect and in general with mediation of environmental readiness and facilities variables have the greatest ensemble on the readiness of e-learning staff. the results of analyzes based on structural equation models and comparison with the previous studies indicate that the conceptual model supported by the data favorably</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Structural Equation- Modeling- E-learning- E-learning readiness- Learning Styles- Organizational Culture</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-348-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-348-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>21</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Conceptual Model of knowledge documentation of Human Resource in Executive Projects of oil industry</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>59</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>79</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mansour</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Moazami</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Nazly</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mahdiyoon</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>It is obvious that in our country, a large part of capital and budget of projects is spent for training and experience of managers who is responsible for managing and guiding the projects, while the experience may be archived in chest or shelves of managers and other executives. In most of projects, there are using trial and error methods in using of experiences and knowledge, as a result large sums of national wealth will be wasting. Application weakness of knowledge management and project implementation is one of the main problems raised by the implementation of all the projects. Knowledge and experiences of projects remain more in minds of those involved in implementing the project in other words , the main challenge of Projects is lack of attention to the concept of organizational memory as a maintenance and development status of the most valuable assets available and usable in next organization projects.</Abstract>
	<Keywords> knowledge documentation -conseptual Model-  executive projects-oil industry</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-349-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-349-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>21</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Strategic Human Resource Development Model Designing in National Iranian Oil Company</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>81</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>107</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mani</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Arman</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Maniarman59@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>SeyedMohammad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Arabi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mahboubeh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Khosravi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Today human resource Strategies are very important for human resource systems. While talking about strategies, integration and coordination is something is much more importance than strategies formulation and implementations. This study presents a model for the strategic development of human resource based on competencies model. In fact, the main question of this research is: What are the affecting factors in strategic human resource development? For answering to this question, After theoretical model exploration, we examine model in National Iranian Oil Company. In present study, we used NIOC data in human resource information system to examine strategic integration and coordination in HRD subsystems. Descriptive statistics and T test were used to answer the research questions. Study findings revealed that all of the competencies were perceived to be important to the success of Employee in NIOC. Based on the study findings, Strategic coordination and integration between SHRD activities create more performance and lead to good employee performance</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Human Resource Development- Strategic Human Resource Development Model- Training- Career-National Iranian Oil Company</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-350-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-350-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>21</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The influence of social capital on knowledge Pars Oil and Gas Company</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>109</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>132</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ehsan</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mehrabanfar</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Asal</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Aghaz</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>a.aghaz@aut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>While Traditional knowledge management emphasis is more on the technology and designing information systems, modern approaches focus more on human resources and their behaviors in knowledge sharing. So this research aims to investigate the influence of social capital on knowledge sharing between human resources of Pars Oil and Gas Company (POGC) by focusing on human features of knowledge sharing. Data was gathered using questionnaire. Results show that social capital affects on inter and intra departments knowledge sharing; high educated employees have more social capital, however people with higher managerial experiences, show less social capital than less experienced employees. It seems that managers don&#8217;t prefer to share their knowledge and experiences with their subordinates especially the more competent or new employed ones. Finally it is suggested that corporations working in petroleum industry, as the corporations which are successful in knowledge management, should share their experiences and knowledge with other corporations.&#160; It is assumed that it might lead to Iran development in long run.&#160;</Abstract>
	<Keywords>knowledge sharing- social capital- human resources- Pars Oil and Gas Company</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-351-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-351-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>21</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Strategic Model of Talent Management: A Case Study of Pars Oil and Gas Company</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>133</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>172</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Fatemeh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Khalvandi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Abbas</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Abbaspour</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>abbaspour@atu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>This study aimed to design a strategic model of talent management at Pars Oil and Gas Company (POGC) based on international best practice experience. Research method is a mixed method (qualitative-quantitative) and sampling is done in two phases.&#160;In qualitative phase, sample included 24 top managers and senior executives (experts) who were selected by purposive sampling and in quantitative phase, by random sampling method and using Cochran formula, sample size of 267 people were selected among all employees. Based on the related literature and accessible documents on this subject in POGC, the primary dimensions and components of strategic talent management were determined.&#160;Then, in order to fit the dimensions and components with the characteristics and expectations of company, the opinions of experts participating in interviews were analyzed by using content analysis method. In this way, the initial model of strategic talent management in POGC was designed. After evaluating and modifying the initial model by a second-order factor analysis, the final model was designed.&#160;In comparison with current domestic and international models, some distinct features of this model are its systematic basis, comprehensiveness and also its strategic approach that leads to consider the external environment and its adaptation with the internal environment and more importantly, the use of this strategic model of talent management helps POGC officials to have a&#160;unified framework for the identisication, development, maintenance and keeping ahead of valuable human capital rather than repeating what is done in human resource management department, and thereby meet the emerging challenges and needs of the company.

&#160;</Abstract>
	<Keywords>strategic model- talent management- strategic  Pars Oil and Gas Company-mixed method</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-352-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-352-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>21</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The influence of technology Acceptance on Increase the productivity of Human resource management
(Case Study: Lorestan Gas Co.)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>173</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>199</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Saeed</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Khodamoradi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Moslem</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Haghi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>&#160;&#160;Organizations For promoting the quality and quantity of services, increasing competition, efficiency and reducing the Costs and changes lead the organizations to modern challenges must be developed and increased productivity human resource management factor, and information technology important in the increasing productivity human resource management factor, the present study was conducted to survey The effect of information technology acceptance on increase the productivity human resource management factor. This descriptive analytical study was carried out during autumn 2011-2012 on all members of&#160;&#160; Province of Lorestan Gas Company, Private Joint Stock (218 participants). Data were collected using a standard questionnaire. Questionnaire rating was in the form of five-point Likert scale. Its validity was confirmed through content validity and professional comments and its reliability was established through the pretest-posttest done with 20 participants and with the Correlation coefficient of 0.9127 the data were analyzed using SPSS, software.Based on findings from multiple-variable regression 4 hypothesizes of research are accepted, Inclusive e) education with scantling +0.290, partnership with scantling +0.483, commitment with scantling +0.145, satisfaction with scantling +0.121) influenced on human resource productivity and and 3 others hypothesizes (salary and wage, Job Creativity, turnover Evaluation) in this article are not supported
&#160;</Abstract>
	<Keywords> information technology- acceptance- human resource productivity- Gas Company</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-353-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-353-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>21</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Identifying Human and Managerial factors affecting Organizational innovation in Gas refineries</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>201</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>232</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Abdolmajid</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mosleh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Khodakaram</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Salimifard</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohamadreza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Sadeghikia</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Increased competition, changes, and uncertainty have forced organizations to embrace innovation as an important function. Paying attention to the innovation is necessary to reply to Rapid technological changes rate. So many researches have been done about innovation, but there are a few studies about innovation in refineries. Due to this fact, the present study aimed to identify human and managerial factors that affect innovation in gas refineries. therefore, a sample consists of 287 persons of the 6 refineries include 5 refineries in South Pars Complex and Fajre Jam Gas Refinery in Bushehr Province were selected and surveyed.According to Research findings three categories factors have been recognized: 1. Cultural factors 2. Managerial factors and, 3. Human resource management factors.</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Innovation- Organization- Gas refineries- Cultural factors- Managerial factors- Human Resource Management factors</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-354-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-354-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>6</Volume>
			<Issue>21</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2014</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>comparing the methods of staff training in the Esfahan refined Oil Company</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>233</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>267</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad Ali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Nadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mansoorehsadat</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Hosesini</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>M_hosseini43@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>BibiEshrat</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>zamani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Today, organizations are paying particular attention to the ways and methods of teaching. If that is often not the result of poor training objectives training process, ways, methods and training techniques. Therefore, methods that can be used in training while working problems, to prepare them for activities and responsibilities, and the overall is over effectiveness of the training.
The present study was carried out to survey the methods of training with the carried periods on in the Esfahan refined Oil Company in 2012.The statistical population of the study included all the employees working at Isfahan oil Refinery Company from whom 285 were selected to take part in the study through Cohen, Manion &#38; Morrison (2000( Stratified random sampling. 285 questionnaires were distributed and 211 were returned. The research instrument of the current study was the researcher-made questionnaire and the construct validity of the questionnaires was confirmed through exploratory factor analysis and so did its reliability via Spearman Brown and Gattman's Cronbach Alpha coefficient (0.96). The data from research questions were analyzed at two descriptive and inferential statistics. The results of Mono-variable t-test indicated that each four lecturing, seminar, on the job training and out of organization teaching methods have affected on the degree of learning more than the average level and the results of Friedman test stated that on the job training method has had the highest fitness and lecturing method has had the lowest fitness according to the employees' viewpoint. Further, based on the results of this test, in lecturing, seminar, on the job training, out of organization institutions methods, the constituents of teacher, content and the place of sessions implementation, sequentially, have had the highest effectiveness on the employees' learning. The results Ki-2 test showed that there is a significant difference between teaching methods rank According to the demographic features (p&#8804;0.05).
&#160;</Abstract>
	<Keywords>lecturing-seminar- on the job training-out of organization training </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-356-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-356-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
 </ArticleSet>
 
  
  
  
  
 