<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>35</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی رابطه هوش هیجانی، تعهد سازمانی و رضایت شغلی با ویژگی های جمعیت شناختی کارکنان ( مورد مطالعه: شرکت نفت مناطق مرکزی ایران)</title_fa>
	<title>Investigating the relationship between emotional intelligence, organizational commitment and job satisfaction of employees with the demographic factors (case: Iranian Central Oil Fields Company (ICOFC)) </title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی مقایسه ای تفاوت هوش هیجانی، تعهد سازمانی و رضایت شغلی کارکنان شرکت نفت مناطق مرکزی ایران به تفکیک متغیرهای جمعیت شناختی (سن، سابقه خدمت، تحصیلات، پست سازمانی و جنسیت) می باشد. نوع تحقیق کاربردی بوده و از بعد روش، توصیفی - پیمایشی است. جامعه آماری پژوهش، کارکنان این شرکت نفتی بوده است که تعداد 359 نفر حجم نمونه به طور تصادفی ساده و با استفاده از جدول مورگان انتخاب شده و پرسشنامه&#8204;های استاندارد بین آنان توزیع شده است. بررسی نتایج نشان داد که دو متغیر هوش هیجانی و رضایت شغلی ضمن قرار گرفتن در وضعیت مطلوب ، در بین گروه های مختلف سنی، سابقه خدمت، پست سازمانی و جنسیت دارای تفاوت معناداری بوده اند. لیکن، متغیر تعهد سازمانی از وضعیت مطلوب کمی فاصله داشته ولی میزان آن بین گروه های مختلف سنی، سابقه خدمت، تحصیلات و پست سازمانی دارای تفاوت معناداری می&#8204;باشد. نتایج تحقیق حاکی از آن است که هر چه سن، پست سازمانی و سابقه شغلی فرد بیشتر می شود، هوش هیجانی وی نیز ارتقا پیدا کرده است. همچنین با ارتقاء پست سازمانی افراد، رضایت شغلی و تعهد سازمانی آن&#8204;ها افزایش یافته است. از طرف دیگر با افزایش سن و سابقه کاری، رضایت شغلی نیز افزایش داشته است. یافته ها همچنین نشان از آن داشت که میزان هوش هیجانی و رضایت شغلی کارکنان مرد بیشتر از کارکنان زن بوده و افراد دارای تحصیلات فوق دیپلم و دیپلم دارای تعهد سازمانی بالاتری نسبت به کارکنان با سطح تحصیلات بالاتر می باشند.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;The research is going to compare the levels of emotional intelligence, organizational commitment and job satisfaction of employees of Iranian Central Oil Fields Company (I. C. O. F. C) according to different demographic factors such as age, job experience, education, organizational position, and gender. Research type is applied-developing and on the other hand, is consumed as a descriptive-survey. The population of the research was Iranian Central Oil Fields Company employees and acording to the Morgan table, 359 employees randomly have been selected and standardized questionnaires were distributed among them. The results indicated that emotional intelligence and job satisfaction have significant differences while it comes to age, job experience, organization position and gender. In addition, organizational commitment did'nt reach desired score, but it showed magnificent differences considering age, job experience, education and position. Based on findings, by increasing age, organizational position and job experience the emotional intelligence of the employees have improved. Also, by promoting their positions, job satisfaction and organizational commitment has increased. On the other hand, while age and experience have increased an increase in job satisfaction was detected. Emotional intelligence and Job satisfaction of the male employees have been more than those of female employees. Results show comparing to those with higher education, people who have diploma or associate's degree show more commitment to the organization.&lt;/div&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>هوش هیجانی , تعهد سازمانی کارکنان , رضایت شغلی , ویژگی های جمعیت شناختی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>emotional intelligence, organizational commitment, job satisfaction, demographic factors.</keyword>
	<start_page>105</start_page>
	<end_page>134</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-25-30&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Sirous </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Amirghodsi </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سیروس</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>امیرقدسی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>sirous_a@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002221</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002221</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Bonyadi Naeini </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بنیادی نائینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Bonyadi@iust.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846002222</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002222</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
