<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>36</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارایه چارچوب بومی معماری فرهنگ بهره وری در شرکت ملی مناطق نفت خیز جنوب</title_fa>
	<title> 
Providing a Native Framework for the Culture of Productivity in the National Company Southern oil fields 
</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;بهره وری شاخص کلیدی عملکرد سازمان ها در هر سطح می باشد که یک مفهوم ذهنی تلقی می شود. با تغییر الگوهای فکری می توان به بهبود بهره وری و تغییر عملکرد فردی و سازمانی امیدوار بود. با نگاهی دقیق تر درمی یابیم که ارزش ها، نگرش ها، معیارها و اعتقادات مشترک در بین اعضای سازمان موجب می شود که همه همسو در جهت نیل به اهداف سازمان به شکل هوشمندانه تلاش کنند. این امر در صنعت نفت که تکیه اقتصادی کشور ما محسوب می شود از جایگاه ویژه ای برخوردار است. پژوهش حاضر با هدف ارایه چارچوبی برای معماری بومی فرهنگ بهره وری، با رویکرد پژوهش کیفی است. بدین منظور پس از بررسی پیشینه پژوهش و انجام مصاحبه های نیمه ساختاریافته به روش نمونه گیری هدفمند در بین خبرگان شرکت ملی مناطق نفت خیز جنوب و دانشگاه، ابعاد چارچوب بومی معماری فرهنگ بهره وری به روش تحلیل محتوای جهت دار و تلخیصی انجام شد. در نهایت چارچوبی منسجم بر پایه ارزش های سازمانی (شامل ارزش های ابزاری که خود مشتمل بر &amp;laquo;ارزش های اخلاقی یا بین فردی و ارزش های شایستگی یا کفایت اجتماعی&amp;raquo; و ارزش های غایی که مشتمل بر &amp;laquo;ارزش های فردی و ارزش های اجتماعی یا تعاملات بین فردی&amp;raquo;) ارائه شد. همچنین نگرش (شامل باورها، بعد عاطفی و بعد رفتاری)، هنجارها (شامل هنجارهای رسمی (قانون)، هنجارهای غیررسمی (عادات ها) و هنجارهای اجتماعی (آداب)) و نیز نمادها (شامل داستان ها، آداب و رسوم، نمادهای فیزیکی و زبان) ارایه شده است.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Productivity is the key indicator of the performance of organizations at each level, which is considered a mental concept. By changing the patterns of thought, one could hope to improve productivity and change individual and organizational performance. A closer look at what common values, attitudes, norms, and beliefs among members of the organization will make everyone consistently work towards the goals of the organization intelligently. This is of particular importance in the oil industry, which is the economic reliance of our country. This research aims to provide a framework for the native culture of productivity, with a qualitative research approach. For this purpose, after studying the history of research and performing semi-structured interviews through targeted sampling among the experts of the National Iranian South oilfields Company and University, the dimensions of the native framework of the culture of productivity were determined through content analysis of directional and tabular content. Finally, a coherent framework based on organizational values ​​(including the value of a tool that includes &amp;quot;ethical or interpersonal values ​​and merit values ​​or social adequacy&amp;quot; and ultimate values ​​that includes &amp;quot;individual values ​​and social values ​​or interactions Interpersonal &amp;quot;) has been constructed. Also, the attitude (including beliefs, emotional dimension and behavioral dimension), norms (including formal norms (law), informal norms (habits) and social norms (customs)) as well as symbols (including stories, customs, physical symbols and Language) were presented</abstract>
	<keyword_fa> معماری, فرهنگ, بهره وری, تحلیل محتوا, شرکت ملی مناطق نفت خیز جنوب</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Architecture- Culture- Productivity- Content Analysis- National Oil Company of Southern Oilfields </keyword>
	<start_page>103</start_page>
	<end_page>136</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-40-4&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mahta </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>joudzadeh </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهتا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>جودزاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003265</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003265</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Nour mohammad </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Yaghoubi </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>نورمحمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>یعقوبی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>yaghoobi@hamoon .usb.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846003266</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003266</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Seyed Aliqoli</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>  Roshan </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید علیقلی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>روشن</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003267</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003267</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mehdi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Nadaf</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نداف</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003268</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003268</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
