<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1398</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2019</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>41</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>شناسایی الگوی مدیریت استعداد به عنوان استراتژی برنده سازمان؛ مطالعه ای در شرکت ملی مناطق نفت خیز جنوب</title_fa>
	<title>Identifying the pattern of the talent management as the winning strategy of the organization; A study in the National Iranian South Oil Company

</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12.0pt;&quot;&gt;پژوهش حاضر با هدف شناسایی ابعاد، مولفه&amp;shy; ها و شاخص &amp;shy;های مدیریت استعداد در شرکت ملی مناطق نفت خیز جنوب انجام شد. این پژوهش از نظر هدف کاربردی، از نظر داده&amp;shy; ها کیفی و از نظر ماهیت مطالعه، داده بنیاد محسوب می شود. جامعه آماری متشکل از خبرگان حوزه نفت و اساتید دارای سوابق مرتبط با مدیریت استعداد بودند و نمونه گیری از آنها بصورت هدف مند و گلوله برفی انجام شد. جمع آوری اطلاعات از طریق مصاحبه صورت گرفت. برای تحلیل داده ها از روش تحلیل محتوا و کدگذاری داده ها با رویکرد نظریه داده بنیاد استفاده شد. برای تعیین اعتبار یافته&amp;shy; ها، مصاحبه با افراد کانونی انجام شد و از تکنیک&amp;shy; های اشباع نظری و رویه&amp;shy; های ویژه کدگذاری بهره گرفته شد. برای تعیین روایی از تکنیک &amp;shy;های جمع &amp;shy;آوری داده&amp;shy; ها از منابع متعدد، تحلیل موارد منفی و انعطاف روش استفاده شد. نتایج بدست آمده نشان داد الگوی مدیریت استعداد شرکت ملی مناطق نفت خیز جنوب دارای 5 بعد(جذب، آموزش و بهسازی، نگهداشت، ارزشیابی و تعالی استعداد)، 13 مولفه و 83 شاخص می&amp;shy;باشد. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;br&gt;
This study was conducted to identify the dimensions, components and indices of the talent management in the National Iranian South Oil Company. The study has been considered an applied research in terms of its purpose and in terms of data was qualitative and it has been done based on grounded theory in terms of the nature of the implementation. The statistical population of the study was experts of the oil field and university professors having academic and operational background related to the talent management, which was selected through the targeted sampling and by snowball method. Data collection was done through interview. &amp;nbsp;Content analysis and data encoding with Grounded theory approach has been used to analyze the data. In order to determine the internal validity of the findings, it was utilized interviews with the focal persons and techniques of obtaining theoretical saturation, using special coding procedures. In order to define the validity of the findings, it was utilized data collecting techniques from multiple sources, negative cases analysis, and flexibility of the method. The results showed that the talent management pattern of the NISOC has 5 dimensions (talent recruitment, training and development, retention, evaluation and excellence), 13 components and 83 indicators.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>الگوی مدیریت استعداد,  جذب, آموزش و بهسازی,  نگهداشت,  ارزشیابی و تعالی. </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Pattern of the talent management, Recruitment, Training and Development, Retention, Evaluation and Excellence</keyword>
	<start_page>173</start_page>
	<end_page>206</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-279-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Manoochehr </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Barani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>منوچهر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بارانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>barani499mis@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846004962</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004962</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، دبی، امارات متحده عربی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Abbas </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Khorshidi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>عباس</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خورشیدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Aba.khorshidi@iauctb.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846004963</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004963</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی،واحد اسلامشهر</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Asghar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Moshabaki Esfahani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>اصغر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مشبکی اصفهانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>moshabak@modares.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846004964</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004964</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hajiha</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حاجیها</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ahajiha@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846004965</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004965</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، دبی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
