<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1398</year>
	<month>11</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2020</year>
	<month>2</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>42</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>مدل‌سازی تفسیری – ساختاری برون‌سپاری منابع انسانی در شرکت پتروشیمی مارون</title_fa>
	<title>Interpretative-Structural Modeling of Outsourcing Human Resources in Maroon Petrochemical Company</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;هدف تحقیق مدل&#8204;سازی عوامل مؤثر در برون&#8204;سپاری منابع انسانی در شرکت پتروشیمی مارون بود. تحقیق از لحاظ هدف، کاربردی، از لحاظ نحوه گردآوری داده&amp;shy; ها، توصیفی &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman,serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt; اکتشافی و از نوع آمیخته بود. جامعه آماری تحقیق کارشناسان و خبرگان شرکت پتروشیمی مارون در حوزه منابع انسانی بودند که تعداد این افراد 15 نفر گزارش شد. تجزیه و تحلیل داده&#8204;ها با استفاده از مدل&#8204;سازی تفسیری ساختاری انجام گرفت. نتایج نشان داد که متغیرهای افزایش انعطاف&#8204;پذیری، کاهش هزینه&amp;shy; های درون&amp;shy; سازمانی و بهبود خلاقیت، دارای نقش مستقل در مدل بوده و بر متغیرهای میانجی و وابسته مدل تأثیر معناداری دارند. متغیرهای وابسته مدل عبارت بودند از: کاهش سرمایه&amp;shy; گذاری تکنولوژی&#8204;، کسب وجهه مناسب و افزایش امنیت که علاوه&#8204;بر متغیرهای مستقل ذکرشده، تحت تأثیر متغیرهای میانجی (شامل عوامل ارتقای کیفیت محصولات، افزایش تغییر&amp;shy;پذیری در نیازها، افزایش تغییرات در فناوری و استفاده از فناوری جدید، تمرکز بیشتر بر فعالیت&amp;shy; های محوری، دستیابی به توانمندی&#8204;های جدید، بهبود عملکرد عملیاتی، استفاده از خدمات آموزشی، دستیابی به تجربه&#8204;های جدید، ارائه خدمات جدید، بهبود مدیریت، مدیریت ریسک و چابک&#8204;سازی سازمان) نیز قرار گرفتند. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>The research purpose was to identifying a model of factors affecting human resource outsourcing (HRO) in Maroon Petrochemical Company. The research is considered practical in terms of purpose and descriptive-exploratory based on mixed method, in terms of data collection. The statistical population was experts and experts of Maroon petrochemical company in the field of human resources. The number of these people was reported 15. For data analysis, interpretive-structural modeling was used. The results showed that the variables of increasing flexibility, decreasing organizational costs and improving creativity have an independent role in the model and on the intermediary and dependent variables of the model have a significant effect. The dependent variables of the model were: decrease of technology investment, gaining the good image and increasing security, in addition to the independent variables mentioned, influenced by the intermediary variables including factors product quality development, increasing the change need, increasing technological changes and the use of new technology, focusing more on core activities, achieving new capabilities, improving operational performance, using educational services, acquiring new experiences, providing new services, improving management, risk management and Agility organization.&amp;nbsp;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>برون‌سپاری منابع انسانی, محرک‌های برون‌سپاری, مدل‌سازی تفسیری – ساختاری, پتروشیمی مارون.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Human resources outsourcing, outsourcing drivers, interpretive- Structural modeling, Maroon Petrochemical Company.</keyword>
	<start_page>179</start_page>
	<end_page>210</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-353-3&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name> Seyed Najmeddin </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mousavi </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید نجم‌الدین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>موسوی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mousavi.na@lu.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846005491</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846005491</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه لرستان، خرم آباد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Razieh </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Feli</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>راضیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فعلی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Feli.ra@fc.lu.ac.ir- raziehfeli@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846005492</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846005492</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه لرستان، خرم آباد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
