<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" 

"journalpublishing3.dtd">

<article 
article-type="research-article"
dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en" 
xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
>

<front>

<journal-meta>

  <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">1</journal-id>
  <issn>2251-8886</issn>

  <publisher>

	<publisher-name>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher-name>
  </publisher>

</journal-meta>



<article-meta>

  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">385</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Designing Competency Model for Project Managers in Petroleum Industry

</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Dianat</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Seyedjavadin</surname>
		<given-names>Seyed Reza </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> Shahhoseini</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Ali</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>9</volume>

  <issue>36</issue>

  <fpage>3</fpage>

  <lpage>40</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>13</day>
				  <month>04</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Due to rapid environmental changes and the large scope of project activities in the petroleum industry, project management is of particular importance. One of the essential and important factors for the success of projects is to focus on the behavioral characteristics, and in other words, the competencies of project managers. In this regard, designing a model of project managers' competencies in the petroleum industry of Iran has been considered in this research. The research methodology is an applied method, based on the goals, and is a mixed method (qualitative-quantitative), regarding to the collecting data method. In the qualitative part, the statistical population included all project managers, managers Senior, and Minister's deputy in the Petroleum industry, 14 of them were selected through purposeful sampling and using snowball technique as a statistical sample of the study. The data collection tool was a deep interviewing in qualitative part. Content analysis was used to analyze the interview data. The reliability of the qualitative part considerd by responder's review. In the quantitative part of the research, the statistical population of the study was composed of all poject managers working in the Iran Petroleum. of the oil industry project that had enough experience in the field. Among them 170 persons were selected randomly as a research sample. The data collection tool was a researcher-made questionnaire in the quantitative part. The results of quantitative analysis led to the production of 394 key concepts that were categorized 152 items in 15 main components. Finally, these main key categories were classified into six key items: 1. background factors, 2. environmental faualctors, 3. causal factors, 4. pivotal phenomenon 5.Strategies, and 6. achievements and outcomes. The quantitative results showed that the amount The fitness index for the whole model was calculated as 60percent, which indicates that the overall fitness of the model is acceptable.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">394</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>The Formulation of Retirement Management Model 
(Case:Refah Kargaran Bank)
</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Parsa Ziabari </surname>
		<given-names>Leila </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Etebarian</surname>
		<given-names>Akbar </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Hadi Peykani</surname>
		<given-names>Mehraban </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Zamani Moghadam</surname>
		<given-names>Afsaneh </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>9</volume>

  <issue>36</issue>

  <fpage>41</fpage>

  <lpage>74</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>04</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>02</day>
				  <month>07</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

&#160;The aim of this research was to develop a retirement management model in the Workers' Refah Bank. In terms of its purpose, the method is a combination of the phenomenological method in the quantitative part and descriptive-correlation method, in the quantitative part of research. The statistical population of the research in the qualitative section has been 39 people including: close-to-retirement (15 people), during retirement (8 people) and retirees (16 people). Snowball method has been used until reaching saturation of information. The population of research in the quantitative section for close to retirement stage was 115, for retirement stage, 30 persons and for after retirement stage was 1175 people. The sample size was 92, 28 and 285, respectively, based on random sampling for each of these three groups. The data collection tool was semi-structured interview in the qualitative part and the questionnaire, in the quantitative part of research. Validity of the questionnaires was reviewed by using content validity-contextual validity as well as structural validity. The reliability of the questionnaires was calculated through Cronbach's alpha, which was calculated for all three questionnaires above 0.8 which indicates their good reliability. &#160;In order to analyze the data in the qualitative section, the 7-step quantitative method of Colaizzi was used and in the quantitative part, statistical tests such as factor analysis, mean and variance test, cross-sectional test and model quality test were used. Finally, dimensions and components of our model were identified and confirmed for close-to-retirement (concerns, expectations, and expectations) during retirement (concerns, needs and motives, expectations) and for after-retirement (challenges, expectations, personal strategies). &#160;
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">386</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Investigating and Analysing Instructional Design and Workplace Learning Models and Selection of Adaptive Model to Optimize Organizational Training in Petrochemical Industry</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> Rahimian </surname>
		<given-names>Hamid</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> abspour </surname>
		<given-names>Abbas</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> Taheri </surname>
		<given-names>Mortaza</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> Najafi</surname>
		<given-names>Ali</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>9</volume>

  <issue>36</issue>

  <fpage>75</fpage>

  <lpage>102</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2017</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>02</day>
				  <month>09</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The present research aimed to analyze instructional design,workplace learning, and selecting the optimum model of learning for human resources training in petrochemical industry.The previous roles have become faint and new opportunities have appeared in petrochemical industry by starting the process of privatization and changing the nature of the company from holding to a governance and development organization. So, the main questions in this study were: what is the similarity among the world popular models about instructional design and workplace learning models? What is the most adaptive model about training and workplace learning in petrochemical industry? Therefore, a qualitative meta-synthesis approach has been used to reply these questions. This process was conducted in two steps. Its first step was conducted by Sandelowski and Barroso method in 2007. The second step was conducted by analysis of documents, observation, and experts' views using Maxqda software. Finally, the related adaptive model to the characteristics of petrochemical industry was offered including five dimentions of: performance analysis, performance design, performance development, performance implementation, and performance monitoring which were adopted from 70:20:10, Mager and human performance technology models. Regarding the dominant systematic approach in instructional design and workplace learning model, and considering of performance conception in all designing processes, it seems that the present study,as the first study in this field, can have an effective role in organizational training.t
&#160;
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">387</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title> 
Providing a Native Framework for the Culture of Productivity in the National Company Southern oil fields 
</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>joudzadeh </surname>
		<given-names>Mahta </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Yaghoubi </surname>
		<given-names>Nour mohammad </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>  Roshan </surname>
		<given-names>Seyed Aliqoli</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> Nadaf</surname>
		<given-names>Mehdi</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>9</volume>

  <issue>36</issue>

  <fpage>103</fpage>

  <lpage>136</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>30</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>16</day>
				  <month>05</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Productivity is the key indicator of the performance of organizations at each level, which is considered a mental concept. By changing the patterns of thought, one could hope to improve productivity and change individual and organizational performance. A closer look at what common values, attitudes, norms, and beliefs among members of the organization will make everyone consistently work towards the goals of the organization intelligently. This is of particular importance in the oil industry, which is the economic reliance of our country. This research aims to provide a framework for the native culture of productivity, with a qualitative research approach. For this purpose, after studying the history of research and performing semi-structured interviews through targeted sampling among the experts of the National Iranian South oilfields Company and University, the dimensions of the native framework of the culture of productivity were determined through content analysis of directional and tabular content. Finally, a coherent framework based on organizational values ​​(including the value of a tool that includes &#34;ethical or interpersonal values ​​and merit values ​​or social adequacy&#34; and ultimate values ​​that includes &#34;individual values ​​and social values ​​or interactions Interpersonal &#34;) has been constructed. Also, the attitude (including beliefs, emotional dimension and behavioral dimension), norms (including formal norms (law), informal norms (habits) and social norms (customs)) as well as symbols (including stories, customs, physical symbols and Language) were presented
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">395</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Effect of Toxic Leadership on Social Loafing with Mediating Role of Employee' Soldiering (Case: Ilam Petrochemical Company)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>  Khalili</surname>
		<given-names>Karam</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>9</volume>

  <issue>36</issue>

  <fpage>137</fpage>

  <lpage>158</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>18</day>
				  <month>09</month>
				  <year>2017</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>09</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The main purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of toxicity leadership style on social loafing the role of mediation in employees&#160;soldiering&#160;.&#160;This research is&#160;an applied research,&#160;based on the purpose of the research and is&#160;a&#160;field research,&#160;based on the nature of the method.&#160;The statistical population of this research includes employees of Ilam Petrochemical Company, which are 600 people. For example, using Morgan table, 234 people were selected based on simple random sampling.&#160;The data collection tool was a standard questionnaire whose validity was confirmed by experts and confirmed by Cronbach's alpha coefficient. For data analysis, Liserl software has been used.The results show that the&#160;toxicity&#160;leadership style has a positive and significant effect on social&#160;loafing&#160;and&#160;employees'&#160;soldiering. Also,&#160;employees'&#160;soldiering&#160;has a positive and significant impact on employees' social&#160;loafing.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">397</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Investigating the Relationship Between Organizational Trust and Employees’ Attitudes With Regard to the Mediating Role of the
Psychological Contract


</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> Habibi </surname>
		<given-names>Masoomeh</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Narimani</surname>
		<given-names>Mehdi </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>9</volume>

  <issue>36</issue>

  <fpage>159</fpage>

  <lpage>188</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>01</day>
				  <month>07</month>
				  <year>2017</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Awareness of employees’ attitudes has always been used as one of the important management tools in organizations. Because, employees’ attitudes can affect their behavior in the workplace. Therefore, it's important to understand what factors can affect it. In this regard, due to the increasing level of employees' maturity in many organizations and becoming knowledge-based, two factors of organizational trust and psychological contracts in this research have been considered and their relationship with employees’ attitudes has been studied. In this process, by analyzing the theoretical foundations and the relationship between the factors and components constituting each of the variables studied, the conceptual model of the research has been extracted and tested in one of the companies of the National Iranian Oil Company. The research method used in this research has been descriptive correlational. The results indicate a positive and significant relationship between the three variables of organizational trust, psychological contracts and occupational attitudes with each other. Also, the mediating role of psychological contract in the relationship between organizational trust and job attitudes was also confirmed
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">396</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Exanimating the relationship between organizational culture, organizational silence and Organizational citizenship behavior
(Case: Research Institute of Petroleum Industry)

</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mokhtari</surname>
		<given-names>Ebrahim </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>9</volume>

  <issue>36</issue>

  <fpage>189</fpage>

  <lpage>212</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>15</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2017</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>09</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

This study aimed to&#160;investigate the relationship&#160;between&#160;organizational culture&#160;and organizational&#160;silence&#160;organizational citizenship behavior.&#160;This research is applied in terms of the purpose and&#160;is a survey, based on&#160;data collection methods,&#160;using&#160;structural&#160;equation modeling.&#160;Statistical population included all&#160;the&#160;staff&#160;in Research Institute of Petroleum Industry.&#160;According to the Morgan's table samples were chosen by random sampling method and finally&#160;272&#160;questionnaires&#160;were distributed and analyzed.&#160;In order to collect data, it has been used Denison's organizational culture questionnaire ,&#160;Vandain's organizational Silence questionnaire and Organ's questionnaire for&#160;organizational citizenship behavior&#160;,&#160;based on five point scales (from very high to very little). ). Face and content validity have been used to evaluate questionnaires Validity. Also, Cronbach's alpha was used to establish the reliability of instruments،&#160;0.89،&#160;0.76 and 0.82 for each questionnaire, respectively. Data was analyzed by&#160;using the&#160;statistical softwares&#160;SPSS and LISREL.&#160;Results showed that there is direct and meaningful relationship between Organizational Culture with Organizational Silence and&#160;organizational citizenship behavior.&#160;Also,&#160;there is&#160;negative&#160;and meaningful&#160;relationship between&#160;organizational&#160;silence&#160;and organizational citizenship behavior.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">388</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Identifying and ranking of factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship with the aim of corporate performance improvement using Fuzzy AHP technique (Case: Coil manufacturing industry.)

</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Hosseini </surname>
		<given-names> Mirza Hassan </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Keshavarz</surname>
		<given-names>- Elham </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>9</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>9</volume>

  <issue>36</issue>

  <fpage>213</fpage>

  <lpage>242</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>20</day>
				  <month>11</month>
				  <year>2017</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>18</day>
				  <month>06</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Todays, under the competitive conditions, organizational entrepreneurship can play an important role in the success of organizations and make them differentiate from others. Therefore, gaining of knowledge about the factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship is of particular importance. Accordingly, the purpose of this research was to identify and rank the factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship and determine their importance and priority in order to improve the company's performance. For this purpose, after studying the theoretical foundations and research background in this area, the factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship that help improve company performance were identified in three groups: structural, background and behavioral factors. In the next step, the priority and importance of each of these factors was evaluated using the fuzzy hierarchical process analysis technique and by a survey of experts from active and top companies in the field of steel industry. The results indicated that the most important factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship with the aim of improving and enhancing the company's performance were: structural factors, underlying factors and then behavioral factors. Among the structural factors, the most important factors were: structure of entrepreneurial organization, decision making and control, reward system. On the other hand, political factors / government, infrastructures, communications, access to resources were identified as the most important underlying factors. Finally, the most important behavioral factors were organizational culture, management support, riskiness, managerial characteristics, employee characteristics
</body>

</article>

