<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" 

"journalpublishing3.dtd">

<article 
article-type="research-article"
dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en" 
xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
>

<front>

<journal-meta>

  <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">1</journal-id>
  <issn>2251-8886</issn>

  <publisher>

	<publisher-name>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher-name>
  </publisher>

</journal-meta>



<article-meta>

  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">365</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Talent Management in Iranian oil industry: effected factors and main orientation</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> bagheri</surname>
		<given-names>Moslem</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>alishiri</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Mahdi </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> tavallaee</surname>
		<given-names>Rohollah</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> tahmasebi</surname>
		<given-names>Siamak</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2014</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>5</volume>

  <issue>19</issue>

  <fpage>9</fpage>

  <lpage>37</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>13</day>
				  <month>08</month>
				  <year>2013</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>05</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Talent Management is one of the most recent development in HRM which many human resource specialists in the world are working on it. Successful implementation of TM has a great impact on strategic human resource management. Iranian oil industry, with its considerable economic and technological importance, has a great capability to use this system. &#160;In this paper, based on deep interview with oil industry experts, using snowball technique and qualitative methodology, we tried to study environmental and organizational factors which impacts on TM main orientation implementation in Iranian oil industry. We classified this factors in environmental factors in general environment of the industry, challenges in oil industry HRM and definition of talent in it. At last, we propose a competitive orientation for TM in Iranian oil industry
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">366</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Designing a method for feasibility study of teleworking system implementation
case study : Iranian oil pipeline & telecommunication company 

</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Hosseini</surname>
		<given-names>MirzaHasan</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Salajeghepour</surname>
		<given-names>Ahmad</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2014</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>5</volume>

  <issue>19</issue>

  <fpage>39</fpage>

  <lpage>71</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>13</day>
				  <month>08</month>
				  <year>2013</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>05</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

This paper is seeking to present a procedure to assessthe potential preparation of the employees of an enterprise for suggestion of remote working and consider the possibility of teleworking system execution. Therefore, at first, the international teleworking literature was studied and effective indices were extracted and localized. At the next stage, a hierarchic model with the capability of measuring the employees&#8217; preparation level for teleworking was designed and its elements and dimensions were defined and the coefficients of each elements was determined by the experts and organizational managers and academic personos&#8217; Ultimately, the designed model was implemented as a balanced questionnaire in July 2012 in Iranian Oil Pipeline &#38; Telecommunication Company and their potential preparation level was evaluated for success in teleworking schema and the most talented employees were graded respectively for suggesting the telework. In addition to this objective, the most important findings of this study indicated that a positive relationship exists between computer skills and employees&#8217; familial status and culture and their tendency to telework, and the experienced employees are more obliged to the enterprise and woman employees have tendency to the teleworking more than the men. Finally, the most important agents of non-tendency of the employees to the teleworking was identified and prioritized as their viewpoint
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">367</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>The survey of effective factors on Strategic human resource planning Implementation in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company (N.I.O.P.D.C)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Beikzad</surname>
		<given-names>Jafar  </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Seyed Mofid</surname>
		<given-names>Ali Reza </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2014</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>5</volume>

  <issue>19</issue>

  <fpage>73</fpage>

  <lpage>102</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>14</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2013</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>05</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The main pupose of this research is to survey of effective factors on Strategic human resource planning Implementation in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company (N.I.O.P.D.C). In order to this survey, lee&#160; &#38; Gough &#38; Moses &#38; Sinelane theories and for survey of effective factors on HR, Stainer and Christopher theories have been used with ten phrases as theorical framework.Statistical society of this research is the employees of NIOPDC whom are 301 persons. The volume of statistical sample calculated with Cockran&#8217;s equation of 173 ones and with categorized random sampling has been chosen. The instrument of data gathering is the questionnaire which arranged whith mentioned theories as operational definitions of of effective factors on Strategic human resource planning Implementation in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company (N.I.O.P.D.C) which delivered to statistical society after justifiability and reliability tests. Then questionnaires collected, summarized, categorized and analyzed with descriptional and deductive statistics.Results expresses that six factors such as CEO cooperation on strategic planning of HR in NIOPDC, team cooperation of HR strategic planning of employees, employees and management&#8217;s obligations in HR strategic planning, change management in HRM strategic planning and attention to cultural dimentions in HR strategic planning are effective in HR strategic planning at NIOPDC.
&#160;
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">368</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title> Evaluation of the effectiveness of the on-the- job training courses in NIGC based Kirkpatrick, Phillips and CIPP models</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Hamemoradi</surname>
		<given-names>Majid</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Khorasani</surname>
		<given-names>Abasalt</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>FathiAjargah</surname>
		<given-names>Kourosh</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2014</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>5</volume>

  <issue>19</issue>

  <fpage>103</fpage>

  <lpage>130</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>13</day>
				  <month>08</month>
				  <year>2013</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>05</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The objective of this research is &#34;effectiveness evaluation of on-the job- training courses of National Iranian Gas Co. based on 3 patterns of Kirkpatrick, Phillips and CIPP&#34;.The statistical society is the employees of the National Iranian Gas Co. who attended the short term training courses in the first 6 months of the year 1390With reference to the obtained data about 10350 people includes in this research in all the country, of whom based on the sampling, a number 1195 people from Tehran Province's Gas Co. were elected and the company elected 291 people based on Morgan's Table with the methods of random selection method as the research sample.Survey questions were used for the data collection of the mentioned sample.
The results of the research shows that the training courses of the National Iranian Gas Co. were not sufficiently effective in factors of reactions, learning, behavior, results, procedure and relevant our-put and has been effective only in two In-put and profitability factors.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">369</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>An investigation into factors influencing knowledge workers’ productivity
(Case study: national Iranian Oil Company)
</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Abili</surname>
		<given-names>Khodayar </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> Hayat</surname>
		<given-names>Aliasghar</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Yozbashi</surname>
		<given-names>Alireza </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2014</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>5</volume>

  <issue>19</issue>

  <fpage>131</fpage>

  <lpage>160</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>13</day>
				  <month>08</month>
				  <year>2013</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>05</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The present paper aims at studying factors affecting knowledge workers&#8217; productivity in national Iranian Oil Company, using descriptive survey method. 90 experts working at staff divisions were sampled, using census method and responded to a reliably confirmed questionnaire. One sample t test revealed at &#945;= 0.05 that individual level factors, such as competence, job satisfaction, proficiency have a highly significant effect on oil company knowledge workers&#8217; productivity. Also one sample t test revealed at &#945;= 0.05 revealed that organization level factors, such as involvement, motivation, organizational communication, and training have highly significant effect on oil company knowledge workers&#8217; productivity. one sample t test revealed at &#945;= 0.05 revealed that job factors, such as meaningful and challenging job, job autonomy, and job clarification have highly significant effect on oil company knowledge workers&#8217; productivity.
Indicating participants&#8217; responses&#8217; significance, Freedman&#8217;s test ranked factors influencing knowledge workers&#8217; productivity as follows: individual factors, jobrelated factors, and organizational factors
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">370</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>The Impact of Transformational Leadership on Organizational Innovation: A Study of the National Iranian Gas Company</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mobini dehkordi</surname>
		<given-names>Ali</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Dehghan najmabadi</surname>
		<given-names>Amer</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mohammadi</surname>
		<given-names>AliReza</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Piran</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2014</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>5</volume>

  <issue>19</issue>

  <fpage>161</fpage>

  <lpage>197</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>13</day>
				  <month>08</month>
				  <year>2013</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>05</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

This paper aims to investigate the effect of transformational leadership on organizational innovation among line and senior managers of national Iranian gas company. This study is practical in terms of the objective, descriptive survey in terms of gathering data procedure and finally quantitative with regards to the gathered data. Our research population contains all of the line and senior managers of national Iranian gas company who are about 400 people. The Cochran formula was employed to calculate 227 people as the statistical sample of our paper. Structural equation modeling (SEM) and partial least squares (PLS) was used for analyzing our data. Our findings indicate the significant impact of transformational leadership on organizational innovation. Moreover, theanalyseof four factors: idealized influence, inspirational motivation, intellectual stimulation and individual consideration exhibit the significant role of them on organizational innovation.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">371</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Social and institutional context of technological capabilities and knowledge creation in Iran oil industry (1979-1908)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>  Mehdizadeh</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammadreza</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Rezavi</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Reza </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2014</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>5</volume>

  <issue>19</issue>

  <fpage>199</fpage>

  <lpage>226</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>13</day>
				  <month>08</month>
				  <year>2013</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>05</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

In this essay the situation of petroleum knowledge creation and dissemination in Iran oil industry and its technological capabilities have been investigated. This configuration and trend has been studied by a documentary method and content analysis of the scientific articles that published in&#160; a distinguished&#160; journal of Iran oil industry&#160; and so the related structures during&#160; 1979-1908.the result is that ,however&#160; so many brilliant activities and technological&#160; outputs&#160; in this sector developed but the policy makers and research-oriented&#160; sections couldn't&#160; go ahead&#160; and the set the direction of industry to a knowledge and technology oriented trend and&#160; sector .so it&#160; couldn't reach to the innovation capabilities that are the foundation of technology development in oil industry.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">372</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>The Study of Spiritual Leadership Impact on Organizational Justice and Organizational Commitment of Employees of company Gas Ardabil Province</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>taghizadeh</surname>
		<given-names>Hooshang</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>shokri</surname>
		<given-names>abdolhossein </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2014</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>5</volume>

  <issue>19</issue>

  <fpage>227</fpage>

  <lpage>255</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>13</day>
				  <month>08</month>
				  <year>2013</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>05</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The present study aimed to assess the impact of spiritual leadership on organizational justice and organizational commitment of Gas Company employees of Ardabil province. The research method was descriptive and statistical population includes all official personnel of Gas Company. The research sample includes 70 people selected by the sampling formula in limited population. These numbers are selected using Simple Random Sampling. For collecting intransitive data, three questionnaires were used. To its validity if formal validity and reliability using Cronbach's alpha coefficient and the breakdown of the moral component leadership, organizational justice and organizational commitment has been calculated. For analysis of these data simple variable Regression and Kolmogorov-Smironov test has been used. Results indicate that spiritual leadership has an impact on organizational justice and organizational commitment.
</body>

</article>

