<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>34</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>مدل یابی مدیریت سکوت سازمانی در سازمان تامین اجتماعی</title_fa>
	<title>Introducing a Model Organizational Silence Management at the Social Security Organization</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>در سال&amp;shy;های اخیر با وجود تحولاتی که در بخش دولتی رخ داده، همچنان بهره &amp;shy;وری پایین سازمان&amp;shy;های دولتی دغدغه اصلی خط &amp;shy;مشی&amp;shy;گذاران کشور است. سکوت و دلسردی کارکنان نسبت به سرنوشت و برنامه&amp;shy;های سازمان و عدم درک و تفاهم مؤثر بین کارکنان و مدیریت، زنگ خطری برای کاهش عملکرد سازمانی است که در سطح کلان&amp;shy;تر به جامعه آسیب می&amp;shy;رساند&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; این تحقیق به دنبال مدل یابی برای پوشش ابعاد پدیده سکوت سازمانی است. مدیریت سکوت سازمانی بخشی مهم از مدیریت رفتار سازمانی است که براثربخشی تصمیم&amp;shy;گیری سازمانی تاثیر مستقیم دارد. در پژوهش حاضر با روش پیمایشی و با تکیه بر مدل سازی معادلات ساختاری، داده&amp;shy;ها با کمک پرسشنامه&amp;shy;ای محقق ساخته از نمونه&amp;shy;ای شامل354 نفر از مردان و زنان شاغل در ستاد مرکزی سازمان تامین اجتماعی گردآوری شد. پرسشنامه مزبور براساس نظریه&amp;shy;های موجود و با بررسی تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی در 174 گویه طراحی گردید. از طریق تحلیل عاملی تاییدی، مولفه&amp;shy;های پرسشنامه مورد تایید قرار گرفت و سپس مدل نهایی با تایید مولفه&amp;shy; ها و زیر مولفه &amp;shy;های آن&amp;shy;ها تعیین شد. مدل نهایی، راهی برای فهم سکوت سازمانی پیشنهاد داده و به مدیران و سیاست&amp;shy;گذاران کمک می&amp;shy;کند این پدیده را در سازمان کاهش داده و روح کار و تلاش را در کارکنان ایجاد نمایند. مدیران می&amp;shy;توانند برای برچیدن سکوت در سازمان&amp;shy;ها از این نظریه مدد جویند. این نظریه به نظریه&amp;shy;پردازان سازمان کمک می&amp;shy;کند تا به فرضیه&amp;shy;هایی قابل آزمون در تحقیقاتی جامع&amp;shy;تر دست یابند.&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Despite various developments in the public sector in recent years, low productivity of government agencies has been the main concern of Iranian policy makers. Employee silence and indifference towards the fate of an organization and its programs and lack of effective understanding between employees and management is an alarm of imminent reduction in organizational performance affecting the whole society at a macro level. This research attempts to provide a model to cover different dimensions of organizational silence. Organizational silence management is an important part of organizational behavior management which directly affects organizational decision-making. Survey research method and structural equation modeling were used and data were collected using a researcher-made questionnaire. The sample consisted of 354 male and female employees of the headquarters of the Iranian Social Security Organization. The questionnaire was designed on the basis of existing theories and using exploratory factor analysis method in 174 items. Using confirmatory factor analysis method, the components were confirmed and the final model was determined after confirmation of the components and sub-components. The final model offers a way to understand organizational silence and helps managers and policy makers reduce this phenomenon in their organization and create the spirit of work and effort among their staff. Managers can utilize this theory to eradicate organizational silence. This theory helps organization theorists achieve testable hypotheses in more comprehensive research.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>سکوت سازمانی , مدیریت سازمانی , مولفه های سازمانی , سازمان تامین اجتماعی , نظریه پردازی داده بنیاد</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Organizational silence, organizational management, organizational components, Iranian Social Security Organization, data-based theorizing.</keyword>
	<start_page>3</start_page>
	<end_page>30</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-191-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>naser</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Poursadegh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ناصر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>پورصادق</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>dr.naser.poursadegh@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846003032</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003032</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Supreme National Defense University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه عالی دفاع ملی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>naser</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Asghari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ناصر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عسگری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>naser.asgari60@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846003033</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003033</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Shahid Sattari University of Aeronautical Engineering</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علوم و فنون شهید ستاری</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>saeed</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>khodabandeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سعید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خدابنده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>skh_sso@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846003034</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003034</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Social Security Organization</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>سازمان تامین اجتماعی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
