<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>8</volume>
<number>29</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی و آزمون مدل چابکی سازمانی درصندوق بازنشستگی صنعت نفت</title_fa>
	<title>Investigate and Testing the Model of Organizational Agility for the 
Pension Fund of Oil Industry
</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;هدف اصلی این پژوهش بررسی و آزمون مدل چابکی سازمانی در صندوق بازنشستگی صنعت نفت می باشد. در واقع سوال اساسی پژوهش این است که چابکی سازمانی برای سازمان مورد مطالعه چه ابعاد و مولفه هایی را در بر می گیرد؟ به این منظور و برای پاسخ به این سوال، ابتدا با بررسی ادبیات موضوع و مطالعه پژوهش های مرتبط با چابکی چارچوبی تهیه شد. سپس رابطه بین متغیرها و مولفه های احصا شده، در سازمان مورد مطالعه با استفاده از روش تحلیل عاملی و از طریق نرم افزاراسمارت پی ال اس آزمون و مورد تائید قرار گرفت و مدل نهایی با ابعاد و مولفه های ذیل ارائه شد: چابکی رهبری )با پنج مولفه تنظیم زمینه چابکی، خلق همکاری، چابکی در خلاقیت، چابکی در خودرهبری، ایجاد هم افزایی)؛ چابکی در خدمت رسانی )با چهار مولفه سرعت، شایستگی و کیفیت، پاسخگویی، انعطاف پذیری و نوآوری؛ چابکی کارکنان (با چهار مولفه هوشمندی و آگاهی، انعطاف پذیری، تشریک مساعی، شایستگی)؛ فرهنگ چابکی (با پنج مولفه همکاری و پرورش، تنوع پذیری، شایستگی، نوآوری و خلاقیت، شفافیت)؛ چابکی در فرایندهای سازمانی (با سه مولفه ساختار مناسب و منعطف، مقررات و دستورالعمل های بروز و روان، روش ها و فرایندهای نوین)، چابکی در فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات (با دو مولفه زیرساخت ها و سخت افزار بروز و پرسرعت، نرم افزارها و برنامه های&lt;br&gt;
مناسب و بهنگام)&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
The purpose of this study has been evaluating and testing organizational agility model for the Iranian pension funds. In fact, the fundamental questions are: what are the dimensions and components of organizational agility for the studied organizations? How the retirement organization could be agile and what are its characteristics? In order to answer these questions, at first by reviewing the literature, studying the research relevant to agility, a framework was provided. Then, the relationship between variables and facts inferred, by using factor analysis and the application of smart PLS, was tested and approved. And finally the proposed model was presented with the following component dimensions: Leadership Agility (with five components of setting agility background, creating collaboration, creativity, self-leadership, creating synergy); agility in service delivery (with four components of speed, competence and quality, flexibility and innovation, accountability); workforce agility (with four components of intelligence and knowledge, flexibility, cooperation, competence); cultural agility (with five components of cooperation and training, flexibility, competence, innovation and creativity, transparency and trust); Agility of organizational factors (with three components of flexible structure, clear and smooth rules and instructions, modern methods and processes), agility in communication and information technology (with two components of high-speed and updated hardware and infrastructure, software and appropriate and timely programs).</abstract>
	<keyword_fa> مدل چابکی سازمانی , صندوق بازنشستگی صنعت نفت , تحلیل عاملی تائیدی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword> Model of Organizational Agility Pension Funds Oil Industry Factor Analysis</keyword>
	<start_page>117</start_page>
	<end_page>142</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-160-7&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Hoda</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Sanatigar </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>هدا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صنعتی گر</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>hodasanatgar@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002085</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002085</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان (خوراسگان)</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mehrban</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hadi Peykani </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهربان</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>هادی پیکانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002086</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002086</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه خوراسگان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Darioush</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Gholamzadeh </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>داریوش</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>غلامزاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002087</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002087</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد واحد تهران مرکزی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
