<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title> Human Resource Management in Oil Industry </title>
<link>http://www.iieshrm.ir</link>
<description>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry - Journal articles for year 2016, Volume 7, Number 28</description>
<generator>Yektaweb Collection - https://yektaweb.com</generator>
<language>en</language>
<pubDate>2016/9/11</pubDate>

					<item>
						<title>Investigating the Effect of Internal Resource    Re-configuration of Dynamic Capabilities on the Businesses Performance</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=53&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Achieving competitive advantage and optimal performance by the companies and industries because of high rates of changes in the operational and structural environment and technologies is the most important challenge facing managers, therefore different theories and approaches has been proposed to overcome the problem. The theory of dynamic capabilities has been presented over the past two decades as a supplemental resource-based view to help us understand how to develop resources of an organization over the time and how to maintain a competitive advantage. In this article we have tried to present a conceptual model of&amp;nbsp; the most impressive capabilities related to the resources re-configuration of dynamic capabilities that have significant impact on improving construction companies performance. Research models using data collected from 97 construction companies in the PLS software were analyzed. The results based on the structural equation modeling method reveals that learning capability as one dimension of internal resources re-configuration&amp;nbsp; has the most&amp;nbsp; impact on performance of construction companies.</description>
						<author>Ali  Mobini Dehkori</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Examining Effects of Personality on 
Knowledge Sharing and Innovative 
Work Behavior of Employees 
(Case study: The Research Institute of Petroleum Industry
</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=54&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>In the current business environment, knowledge is a key capability to generate competitive advantage in organizations. However, effective knowledge-sharing among employees is affected by different factors and consequently could have various useful implications. Therefore, this paper intends to investigate the effect of personality traits on knowledge sharing and innovative work behavior as an integrative model in Research Institute of Petroleum Industry. A descriptive-survey and correlation methodology was conducted and a questionnaire developed for data gathering. Partial Least Squares (PLS) method also used to test research hypotheses. Result of analyzing 84 collected questionnaires from the organization indicated that personality traits of extroversion, agreeable, and openness have significant positive effect on knowledge sharing. It is also supported the significant positive effect of knowledge sharing on innovative work behavior. Finally, based on research findings, some practical implications for knowledge management practitioners to foster knowledge sharing and innovative work behavior suggested and research opportunities for future researchers to fill this research&amp;rsquo;s gaps proposed.</description>
						<author>Meghdad  Haji Mohammad Ali JahroMeghdadmi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Defining Structural Model of Human Resource Management in Project-Based Organizations: New Trend Based on HR Quadriad</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=55&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Human resource management is a collective act carried out by several players within project based organization. Typically in a project based organization, four players play the major role in management of human resources: project worker, line manager, project manager and HR specialists, which dysfunction in the HR organization can be explained by the weak interplay between two or more of these players. On the other hand, HRM practices have been changed based on projecetification and types of project- based work setting. Therefore, since the project- based organization is the main focus of this paper, firstly a clear definition of these kind of organizations is given. Then, the HR structure and organization in project-based organization and different types of project-based work setting explained. Later on, with discerning the HR structure and the role of all players in HR quadriad, and by means of objective data analysis related to limit and participation of RIPI project workers, the roles of HR players in RIPI determined and based on that, the structural model of HRM at RIPI designed for the first time in Iran. This paper also concludes some strategic guidelines and suggestions for the establishment of HRM in project based organizations in Iran.</description>
						<author>Gholamreza  Asili </author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Training Transfer Model for Enhancement of Effectiveness and Development of Human Resources in Tehran oil Refinery Company</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=56&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
The current research was conducted to present a model for training transfer in Tehran oil Refinery Company. Descriptive research method was adopted. Whole employees take apart with 360 people and the sample size by using the chart Kerejesy- Morgan included 186 members. In order to collect the data, Holton standard questionnaires (2000) as well as Salorenzo training transfer questionnaire (2004) were distributed among personnel's of operation unit by using simple random sampling technique. Descriptive and deductive statistical methods were applied for the analysis of the collected data using SPSS and lisrel. The results of the research demonstrated that the transfer of training has been favorable and in the medium level. There was a meaningful relationship among personal factors, educational factors and organizational factor with training transfer. In this research there was no meaningful relationship between self-efficacy, negative personal results, and supervisor's prevention with educational transfer. The most important effecting factors on training transfer were the educational factors with 0/69 path coefficient and then the organizational factors with 0/45 path coefficient and personal factors with 0/24 path coefficient, in order. Among educational factors, the most effective factor in educational courses has been the feedback. Also among organizational factors, the most important factor was the expectations from the functional results, and among personal factors; the most important variable was the capacity for the transfer. Finally the structural model of the effective factors on educational transfer was designed</description>
						<author>Sanaz  Farhad </author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Examining the Effects of Human Resource Empowerment Components on Organizational Commitment 
(Case: National Iranian Gas Transmission Company)
</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=57&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of human resources empowerment components on the organizational commitment of the personnel of Iranian Gas Transmission Company using a descriptive and correlation method. The statistical population of the research has been the personnel of Iran Gas Transmission Company (Tehran Staff). In order to collect information, a questionnaire from Kuo &amp; et al. (2010) and in the 5-choice Likert scale has been used. Finally, 228 questionnaires were collected and analyzed. Applying SPSS software, the reliability of the questionnaire was estimated by Cronbach's alpha 0.919. This means that the questionnaire has a high reliability. The hypotheses of this study were tested using the structural equation model and using Lisrel software. The results of Laserl outputs show the positive and meaningful impact of human resources empowerment components (including sense of being competent, sense of being effectiveness, sense of trust, sense of independence, sense of being meaningful) on organizational commitment.</description>
						<author>Abbas   Saleh Ardestani</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Presenting a Framework for Human Resources Training and Development in Iranian Complex Projects
</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=58&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Competent project managers and competency-based training play a major role in project-based organizations and hence, ensure the success of projects. As oil projects are always subject to risks and hazards, developing human resources is an important function HR development programs must be based on real and immediate needs. This study aims at providing a model for developing staff in Iranian complex projects (case study of POGC). Hence, based on multi-methods approach, three strategies have been used to answer the research questions namely document analysis, Delphi technique, and benchmarking. To validate research findings, two techniques were used entitled member check and peer debriefing. Based on the findings, the overall HR development strategy at POGC owns a linear nature which comes in contrast with the company complex projects. Hence, the prescribed model is based on needs assessment from various perspectives (goal based and failure based), flexible and systematic instructional design, individual development plan, and goal based and performance based evaluation.</description>
						<author>Saeed   Safaee Movahed</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Examining the Role of Knowledge Sharing on the Organizational Learning Process, Regarding the Mediating Effect of Technology and Social Interaction in Pension Fund of Iranian Oil Industry</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=59&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>In today&amp;rsquo;s complex and ambiguous environments, organizations inevitably have to learn constantly and pay much attention to knowledge management in order to survive, provide better services to their customers, and make fundamental growth.&amp;nbsp; Therefore, one of the most important instruments that can help an organization continuously create knowledge is sharing knowledge across its units and among their members, while emphasizing the role of technology and social interaction. Furthermore, sharing knowledge plays an important role in organizational learning and creating an effective organization. Regarding the importance of the oil industry in Iran, the main and ultimate purpose of this research is to investigate the role and influence of knowledge sharing on organizational learning process concerning two mediator variables of the technology and social interaction in the oil Industry Pension Fund. To do this, a simple random sampling method has been chosen, and the sample size, which was about 118 people, was determined based on Cochran's formula. Data were collected by a questionnaire and then analyzed by the SPSS software. The results suggest that there is a significant relationship between knowledge sharing, and its dimensions, and organizational learning. Also, the technology and social interaction mediate this relationship.</description>
						<author>Yousof   Mohammadi Moghadam</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>The role of organizational commitment in formation of learning organization in IIES</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=60&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>The aim of this research is to study the effect of organizational commitment on forming learning organization in Institute for International Energy Studies (IIES). There have been considered three components of organizational commitment includes affective commitment, normative commitment and continuance commitment, and seven dimensions of learning organization includes continues learning, inquiry and dialogue, team learning, knowledge management system, shared vision, system connection and strategic leadership. The data gathering method is library study and surveying (a questionnaire includes 39 questions). The population includes specialists and researchers of IIES containing 90 employees and statistical sample contains 73 employees that have been chosen by accidental sampling method. To investigate normal distribution of data, the K-S Test has been used and following to its result, the Spearman Test and Structural Equations Model have been used to analysis the correlation between variables. Moreover, conceptual model of research has been verified through Structural Equations Model.The result of this research reflects that the organizational commitment effects positively on forming learning organization, and possibility of developing this organizational form requires the high level of affective and normative commitment.</description>
						<author>Seyed Sadegh   Zarghami</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
	</channel>
</rss>
