<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title> Human Resource Management in Oil Industry </title>
<link>http://www.iieshrm.ir</link>
<description>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry - Journal articles for year 2014, Volume 5, Number 20</description>
<generator>Yektaweb Collection - https://yektaweb.com</generator>
<language>en</language>
<pubDate>2014/9/10</pubDate>

					<item>
						<title>Organizational socialization and its role in newly recruited employees' intention to leave
Case study: pars oil and Gas Company
</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=357&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>The present paper intends to study socialization and its relationship with the newly recruited employees' intention to leave. The data have been collected out of 171 statistical samples from Pars oil and Gas Company located in Assaluye. This Company employed nearly 1200 university graduates in 2011-2012. Interviews as well as questionnaire have been used as data collection instruments. Thus two standard questionnaires of socialization and employees' intention to leave are used, the validity and reliability of which have been proven.&amp;nbsp;Spearman correlation test in SPSS has been selected to analyze the statistical data. The results indicate that there is a meaningful negative relationship between socialization and its fourfold classification including training, organizational perception, company's support and its future prospects with employees' intention to leave. Addition, the results demonstrate that there is no meaningful difference between regular and highly talented employees concerning intention to leave.</description>
						<author>Hosein- Hasanzadeh</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>predictive validity of IOOC Employment Test and its Relation to employees performance in IOOC</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=358&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Every test especially recruitment exams must have reliability and validity in order to be reliable and adequate guide for organization&amp;rsquo;s leaders in making decisions.The present study aims at examining the predictive validity of IOOC employment test and its relationship with employees' performance in IOOC. The study population includes recruited employees in IOOC in 1385. The data was gathered using document archive and scores of seasonal performance of employees. In addition ANOVA for analyzing date, titled Generalized Estimating Equation (GEE), multiple linear regression models with a Forward Stepwise Liner Regression, were used. Findings showed there is a significant positive and meaningful relationship between scores of employment test and IOOC employees&amp;rsquo; performance. However, the result of qualitative indicates there isasignificant positive and meaningful relationship between scores of &amp;ldquo; written test and oral&amp;rdquo; and their job performance, written test has more validity.</description>
						<author>Alireza AminiNazari</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Assessment of human resource management system of National Iranian Oil Company based on” 5P” MODEL of strategic human resource management (Schuler, 1992)</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=359&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
Despite the fact that human resource strategic management enjoys a worldwide maturity, it is an emergent realm of study in Iran. This novel management approach, similar to a many modern management concepts and practices, is only used in managers' diction, and as unconventional technical jargon. Aligned with the significance associated with this area and feel the need to Assess human resource management system of National Iranian Oil Company and analyze the gap between the present condition and the desirable one, the &amp;ldquo;5P&amp;rdquo; Model of strategic human resource management (Schuler, 1992) selected and according to parameters of the model the study has been designed and conducted. The sample to this study has been drawn by random selection of subjects from human resources departments' administrative staff in main and subsidiary companies of National Iranian Oil Company. While study's researcher-developed questionnaire's internal reliability was determined via experts' consensus, its structural reliability was confirmed through factor analysis. Besides, its internal consistency was measured through Cronbach's Alpha coefficient. The findings, in line with previous evaluations of the studied model, have revealed its being highly-welcomed and apposite to National Iranian Oil Company's structure. National Iranian's Oil Company's low average score for the five activities of the model, including philosophies; policies; programs; practices; and processes, indicates the significant existing gap between Company's current condition and the desirable one, it; thus, implies the fact that these five are not aligned with Company's strategic needs. Moreover, it verifies the effect of internal and external environmental factors over Company's main strategies aiming at creating strategic needs. The findings, in line with previous evaluations of the studied model, have revealed its being highly-welcomed and apposite to National Iranian Oil Company's structure. Ultimately and in accordance with study's findings, some implications have been offered seeking to improve and enhance the present human resource management system, besides approaching goals of human resource strategic management in National Iranian Oil Company.</description>
						<author>MohammadReza Bashiri</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>The examination of relationship between individual characteristics and Workforce productivity in Guilan Gas Corporation Abstract</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=360&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>The aim of this study is to examine the relationship between individual factors and workforce productivity in Guilan Gas Company. In order to examine the relationship between individual factors and productivity, the Pearson correlation test was used. Moreover, regression analysis used to examine the effects of individual factors on labor productivity. The results showed that among the individual factors , three factors such as skills, job satisfaction and job security have a significant relationship with labor productivity but motivation don't have a significant relationship with labor productivity. Relationship between personality and productivity is significant only in terms of level of education and in groups of Master's Degree and above. Regression analysis showed that approximately 36% of the variation in the dependent variable depends on the three correlated individual factors.</description>
						<author>sajede  kardanzirak</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Examining Effect of Emotional Intelligence on Managers Performance
Case Study: Parsian Gas Refining Co
</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=361&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>The main objective of the present study is to investigate the effect of emotional intelligence on managers performance in Parsian Gas Refining Company. Goleman competence model that include five Components of emotional intelligence that forms theoretical bases of this work. Statistical society of this work includes the managers of triple managers positions in PGRC includes 48 person and PGRC personnel includes 375 person. Here for evaluation of head in PGRC the EI questionnaire and for evaluation of their performance the self made Questionnaire are used. The research method is of frequency-survey type and society is equal to the sample and the spss software is used to analyze the data. statistical test that was done includes graphs in descriptive level and in inferential level the Parsian correlation. Coefficient and regression are used to test the assumptions. The analyze of data show that there is a Significant positive relationship between the EI and managers performance at PGRC .the social skills Component is the best way to predict the managers performance in this company. Moreover, the maximum correlation percent between the assumptions is related to the relationship between Self-regulation and the managers performance&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;</description>
						<author>Abes  shirpoor</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Intelligent scheduling for emergency room(ER) personnel
to improve productivity
</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=362&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Improving productivity in emergency services and managing limited resources of emergency room(ER) are key challenges for health managers of oil industry. One critical and costly resource is ER personnel&amp;nbsp; and its lack can lead to long queue of patients. Thus appropriate scheduling for nurses and physicians can help ER managers to&amp;nbsp; get maximum benefit of their current human resource and reduce their costs. In this schedule different criteria should be considered . Meeting all of them is difficult for the hospital expert person.Objective of this research is to design an intelligent schedule for ER personnel in order that waiting time is reduced and hospital management constraints are fully considered.First , patient flow in ER is simulated.Secondly, Gentic Algorithm(an Intelligent approach) is applied to solve the multi objective problem.Results show that average and standard deviation of patients waiting time for first visit is reduced by 74% and&amp;nbsp; 53% respectively.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;</description>
						<author>Masoume  Amidi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>The role of human resource management, organizational structure and culture in promoting corporate entrepreneurship (Case study: Petrochemical Research &amp; Technology Company)</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=363&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>The purpose of this research is to determine the manner of interaction and the prioritization among effective factors on corporate entrepreneurship by the Decision Making Trial and Evaluation Laboratory approach. Factors examined in this study include factors related to human resource management, organizational structure and culture. The statistical population of this study consists of twenty managers and experts of &lt;em&gt;Petrochemical Research and Technology Company&lt;/em&gt;. The data-gathering method is questionnaire whose validity has been evaluated by the content validity method and also the opinions of four experts and specialists. In order to determine the reliability of the survey, Test-Retest method is used whose results signify 84% correlation between answers. In this study, 12 factors have been analyzed as effective factors on corporate entrepreneurship. The findings of this research demonstrate that the effective factors on corporate entrepreneurship can be categorized into two groups; driver factors or causes which are generally related to human resource management and dependent factors or effects which are totally related to organizational culture and structure. Driver factors have a greater effect on the promotion of corporate entrepreneurship and can provide a proper background for the achievement of dependent factors.</description>
						<author>mostafa  safdary</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Designing a Model for development of Knowledge networks in Research and technology Hub of Oil Industry
&quot;Using soft-ThinkingApproach and cognitiveMapping model&quot;</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=364&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Knowledge network is one of the new strategies of knowledge management and it,s rationale of it is create synergy effects through a combination of effective human resources knowledge workers and knowledge bases of allied companies. Today, the face of complex structural issues and various stakeholders,s views to it, leading to increase use of software systems, particularly in managerial issues to resolve them. On the other hand limitations in the methodology and to enhance the quality of a qualitative research, the incentive to use cognitive mapping tool has been created. Among the different attitudes and the formation of a cognitive map is provided. The results have shown that the pattern of development of knowledge networks in the hub of the oil industry has a three dimensional network structure of knowledge, content knowledge network and knowledge network.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</description>
						<author>Rohollah Tavalaee</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
	</channel>
</rss>
