<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <records>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2019-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>41</issue>
	<startPage>3</startPage>
	<endPage>36</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Designing model of competencies of human resources managers of the Oil Ministry in the context of globalization</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Reza Vaezi</name>
	<email>Theory.management@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Davood Hosseinpour</name>
	<email>PA95Mgt@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mir Ali Sayed Naghavi</name>
	<email>asnagavi@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Fatemeh Taji</name>
	<email>taji_soheila@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The task and role of managers in the age of globalization has become difficult. To solve the complex problems of globalization, managers need to be equipped with the knowledge of complexity and acquire new capabilities, and organizations must redesign their structures and processes based on global relationships. The purpose of this research was to design a model of competencies of human resources managers of the Ministry of Oil's in the age of globalization. The study was conducted using a Delphi method of 21 experts. Data were collected using a questionnaire with 118 questions and distributed in a random sample of 278 managers and experts of the Ministry of Oil. Data analysis was performed using structural equation modeling method to investigate the research hypotheses. As a result, globalization changes affect the intelligence competence, managerial competence, human resource competence, value creation of human resource competence, cultural competence of managers.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-763-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Competencies of HR managers</keyword>
	<keyword>Context of Globalization</keyword>
	<keyword>Ministry of Oil</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2019-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>41</issue>
	<startPage>37</startPage>
	<endPage>70</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Determining the Specifications of Human Resource Management Processes in Matrix Organization: A Meta-Synthesis Oriented Study</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Jabbar Babashahi</name>
	<email>j.babashahi@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email>rtahmasebi@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Meysam Shahbazi</name>
	<email>meisamshahbazi@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hosein Hasanzadeh</name>
	<email>ho.hasanzadeh@ ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng"></abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-764-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Matrix Organization</keyword>
	<keyword>HRM Processes</keyword>
	<keyword>Functional and Project Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Meta-Synthesis Method.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2019-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>41</issue>
	<startPage>71</startPage>
	<endPage>94</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The impact of spirituality in the workplace on self-control of human resources</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Reza Sepahvand</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Heidar Seidzadeh</name>
	<email>Seidzadeh.he@fc.lu.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Current research accomplished with the aim of investigating the impact of workplace spirituality on self-control of human resources in Ilam gas refining company. This study in terms of goal and research type has been consumed an applied and descriptive-correlation research, respectively. Research population has been the mentioned company experts and the sample size determined 228 persons by using Cochran formula. The validity and reliability of questionnaire confirmed by using content validity and Cronbach's alpha, respectively. For data analyzing, it has been used the method of structural equation modeling by using AMOS software. The results showed that workplace spirituality with path coefficient of 0.43 has a positive and meaningful impact on self-control. Also, the dimensions of alignment values at the organizational level with factor loading of 0.84 and Sense of Community at the group level with factor loading of 0.76 have the most and the least factor loading in realization of workplace spirituality, respectively.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-765-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Spirituality in the workplace</keyword>
	<keyword>Self-control</keyword>
	<keyword>Human resources</keyword>
	<keyword>Structural Equation Modeling.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2019-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>41</issue>
	<startPage>95</startPage>
	<endPage>128</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Effect of Psychological Capital and Social Responsibility on Emotional Organizational Commitment and Creativity of Employees</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mahdi Dehghani Soltani</name>
	<email>ma.dehghani22@vru.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Maryam Mesbahi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohadeseh Hoseinkhani Naniz</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of psychological capital and social responsibility on emotional organizational commitment and creativity with clarifying role of work engagement. This research is consumed applied in terms of purpose and descriptive in terms of data gathering. The employees of Kerman Province Gas Company were consisted the research population. Cochran formula was used for estimating the 229 sample and to identify and select the sample from the community, convenience sampling method was used. To collect data, it has been used the standard questionnaires for measuring psychological capital, work engagement, emotional organizational commitment, social responsibility, and creativity. The validity and reliability of them were examined through the content validity and Cronbach's alpha, respectively. LISREL software and structural equation modeling was used for data analyzing. The findings show psychological capital has positive and meaningful effects on the social responsibility, work engagement and emotional organizational commitment. Also, social responsibility has positive and meaningful effects on work engagement and creativity and emotional organizational commitment has positive and meaningful effects on the creativity.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-766-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Psychological Capital</keyword>
	<keyword>Social Responsibility</keyword>
	<keyword>Emotional Organizational Commitment.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2019-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>41</issue>
	<startPage>129</startPage>
	<endPage>148</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Effect of Organizational Justice and Social Capital on the Mental Health in Isfahan Oil Refining Company</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email>masoodatayi@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Seyed Mohammadreza Davoodi</name>
	<email>smrdavoodi@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">This study was conducted to determine the relationship between organizational justice and social capital on mental health with the role of mediator of organizational virtue in Isfahan Oil Refining Company. This research based on its goals was an applied and descriptive-oriented research. The statistical population of the study consisted of 2812 people, using Morgan table 340 people has been selected by random sampling. Data were collected by using four standard questionnaires of organizational justice, organizational social capital, and organizational virtue and mental health.Validity of the questionnaires were confirmed by the experts and Cronbach's alpha method was used to assess the reliability of the questionnaires.Testing of research hypotheses was done using the path analysis method using AMOS software. The results of this research indicated a positive and direct impact of organizational justice on social capital.This effect in the standard state is equal to 0.23 and has the highest impact coefficient among other relationships. Also the results show the indirect relationship between organizational justice and social capital on mental health with the role of mediator of organizational virtue.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-767-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Organizational justice</keyword>
	<keyword>Social capital</keyword>
	<keyword>Organizational virtue</keyword>
	<keyword>mental health.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2019-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>41</issue>
	<startPage>149</startPage>
	<endPage>172</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Effect of Job Complexity on Creativity with the Mediating Role of Job Stress in South-East Oil Pipeline and Telecommunication 
	Company of Iran</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Montazeri</name>
	<email>montazer56@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Tahereh Razavi Karamouz</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Neda Pasandipour</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The present study was conducted to &#34;determine the effect of job complexity on employees' creativity with the mediating role of job stress in South-East Oil Pipeline and Telecommunication Company of Iran&#8221;. This research was applied study, and in terms of nature and method was correlation. The statistical population of this study consisted of all employees in Iran Oil Pipeline and Telecommunication Company South-East Zone, whose number was 1011. From this statistical population, based on Krejcie and Morgan (1970) table, a sample of 278 persons was selected by random stratified method. In order to data collection, three questionnaires were used including Hackman and Oldham&#8217;s job complexity (1976), Harris et al&#8217;s job stress (1994), Torrance&#8217;s creativity of staff (1980). For data analyzing, SEM were used. The results showed that with regard to the mediating role of job stress, job complexity have significant effect on creativity. Also, job complexity has significant effect on creativity.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-774-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>job complexity</keyword>
	<keyword>employees' creativity</keyword>
	<keyword>job stress</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2019-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>41</issue>
	<startPage>173</startPage>
	<endPage>206</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Identifying the pattern of the talent management as the winning strategy of the organization; A study in the National Iranian South Oil Company</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Manoochehr Barani</name>
	<email>barani499mis@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Abbas Khorshidi</name>
	<email>Aba.khorshidi@iauctb.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Asghar Moshabaki Esfahani</name>
	<email>moshabak@modares.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Hajiha</name>
	<email>ahajiha@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">This study was conducted to identify the dimensions, components and indices of the talent management in the National Iranian South Oil Company. The study has been considered an applied research in terms of its purpose and in terms of data was qualitative and it has been done based on grounded theory in terms of the nature of the implementation. The statistical population of the study was experts of the oil field and university professors having academic and operational background related to the talent management, which was selected through the targeted sampling and by snowball method. Data collection was done through interview. &#160;Content analysis and data encoding with Grounded theory approach has been used to analyze the data. In order to determine the internal validity of the findings, it was utilized interviews with the focal persons and techniques of obtaining theoretical saturation, using special coding procedures. In order to define the validity of the findings, it was utilized data collecting techniques from multiple sources, negative cases analysis, and flexibility of the method. The results showed that the talent management pattern of the NISOC has 5 dimensions (talent recruitment, training and development, retention, evaluation and excellence), 13 components and 83 indicators.
&#160;</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-769-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Pattern of the talent management</keyword>
	<keyword>Recruitment</keyword>
	<keyword>Training and Development</keyword>
	<keyword>Retention</keyword>
	<keyword>Evaluation and Excellence</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2019-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>41</issue>
	<startPage>207</startPage>
	<endPage>224</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Stress Management by Integrative Approach of Bow-Tie and Fuzzy Couple Comparison Matrix</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Meysam Azimian</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Shima Mirnezafat</name>
	<email>mirnezafat1392@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Jafar Gheidar Khalajani</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammadhossein Karimi Govareshki</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of this paper was to use the fuzzy couple comparison matrix and Bow-Tie to select the best scenario for stress management of nursing staff in Petroleum Industry Health Organization. This research is considered a developmental and applied research in terms of its objective in which the fuzzy data has been used. The research type has been correlational and based on data collection, it is consumed a cross-sectional research. The dependent variables were final value (weight) of stressors, the effects of stress, and barriers to occupational stress in nursing staff. Also, Independent variables were the relative value of options relative to each other. Using an integrated method of fuzzy Bow-Tie to select the best scenario to stress management of nursing staff was the invention of this research. The results which obtained by a survey of experts, showed that lack of physical and mental health, low salaries and benefits, lack of control over working conditions, inappropriate physical environment and lack of participation in decision making were identified as the most important factors of stress in nursing staff, respectively.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-770-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Stress management</keyword>
	<keyword>Bow-Tie</keyword>
	<keyword>Fuzzy couple comparison matrix</keyword>
	<keyword>Petroleum Industry Health Organization</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2019-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>41</issue>
	<startPage>225</startPage>
	<endPage>242</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Crisis Management Model in the Petroleum Firms System</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Reza Khalili</name>
	<email>Reza-Khalili2019 @ outlook.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Amir Mahmoodzadeh</name>
	<email>A.mahmoudzadeh@spri.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Iran Ghazi</name>
	<email>I.Ghazi@spri.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Mehdi Rashidi</name>
	<email>rashidimm@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">In recent decades, energy companies have been thinking about remediation and recruitment of new human resources. The new wave of hiring has had both positive and negative effects. Negative effects (such as over-recruitment and crowding in companies, rising costs of human resources, etc.) have caused a crisis in some energy companies. The purpose of this study was to present a model for crisis management in oil companies' human resources system. The research method was descriptive survey and the statistical sample consisted of 200 managers and experts of the National Iranian Oil Company. Statistical software was also used to analyze the results. The results showed that except for one index (identifying the probable events) all of the mentioned indicators of the model can be prescribed for human resource crisis management strategies in oil companies. The highest mean score is related to the index &#34;Developing Human Resources Management Policies and Measures to Promote Motivation, Job Satisfaction and Commitment of Employees&#34; and the next indicator is the priorities of implementing training courses for empowerment.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-771-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Crisis</keyword>
	<keyword>Crisis Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Human Resources</keyword>
	<keyword>Petroleum Firms System.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2019-12</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>41</issue>
	<startPage>243</startPage>
	<endPage>262</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Validation of the 360-degree Appraisal through Assessment Center in the National Iranian Gas Company</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Iman Shakeri</name>
	<email>imanshakeri70@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Zohreh Mousavi</name>
	<email>zohre.moosavi@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Abolghasem Nouri</name>
	<email>a.nouri@edu.ui.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hamidreza Oreizi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The aim of this study has been validation of 360-degree Appraisal through assessment center in the National Iranian Gas Company. For this purpose, 76 of &#160;key executives that participated in assessment center and 360-degree appraisal selected by available sampling.&#160;Data analyzed by SPSS software and Pearson correlation, linear regression, stepwise regression tests. The results showed 360-degree appraisal scores significantly can predict assessment center scores and dimensions of 360-degree appraisal (supervisors, colleagues, subordinates and individual evaluations) are different in predicting assessment center scores. Also, the construct validity demonstrated weak support for convergent validity of competences. The findings indicate in order to increase validity of competency-based tools such as 360-degree appraisal, design and use of those should as much as possible be accurate and based on scientific evidence.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-772-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>performance appraisal</keyword>
	<keyword>assessment center</keyword>
	<keyword>360degree appraisal</keyword>
	<keyword>validation</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
 </records>
 
  
  
  
  
 