<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <records>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>3</startPage>
	<endPage>32</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Analytical Comparison of Business Network and Business Ecosystem</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Mobini Dehkordi</name>
	<email>mobini@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Jabbar Torkaman</name>
	<email>J.Torkaman@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Emergence of the new concepts in business field of study beside of increasing environmental changes has made it more complex. The continuous changes, shows the importance of theoretical and practical readiness in relation to environmental issues. Two topics that have got attention of both academics and practitioners are &#8220;Business Network&#8221; and &#8220;Business Ecosystem&#8221;. This paper tries to scrutinize the concepts in order to delimitate them and considers outcomes of moving to and shaping business ecosystem. Therefore, Science direct, Emerald Insight and Google Scholar documents in period of 2000 to 2019 is extracted. 54 Documents are identified. In order to analyze, main concepts are extracted and verified by panel of experts. Coding is the method of analysis. Finally, findings are categorized in structural, mental and relative dimensions. Two concepts have many similarities in terms of structural and mental dimensions but from relative point of view there are significant differences. One of the most important outcomes of shaping business ecosystem is the change of innovation model from conservative and imitative to absorptive innovation.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-896-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Business Network</keyword>
	<keyword>Business Ecosystem</keyword>
	<keyword>Document Analysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Actors Interaction</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>33</startPage>
	<endPage>64</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Presenting a Regional Competitiveness Model based on the Knowledge-Based entrepreneurial ecosystem Structure</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Sasani</name>
	<email>ali_sasani@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammadali Shahhoseini</name>
	<email>shahhoseini@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mehran Rezvani</name>
	<email>m.rezvani@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">In today's age where knowledge is a driving force at regional and country level, the role of entrepreneurial ecosystems that foster the innovative and knowledge based entrepreneurial activities is very crucial in terms of competitiveness of resource attraction and wealth creation. Now the question arises: what is the model of regional competitiveness based on the knowledge entrepreneurship ecosystem structure? In order to answer this question, the present study was conducted with the purpose of application, qualitative approach and method of grounded theory. In this regard, in-depth interviews were conducted with 21 theoretical and practical informants in the field of regional policy and entrepreneurship who were selected based on snowball pattern. Among the categories cited, &#34;changing the mindset of stakeholders to the efficiency of knowledge-based entrepreneurship capabilities&#34; was identified as the focal category that would be expected if the strategies were implemented in the shadow of environmental and the mediator conditions.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-873-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Entrepreneurship Ecosystem</keyword>
	<keyword>Grounded Theory</keyword>
	<keyword>Knowledge Intensive Economy</keyword>
	<keyword>Regional Competitiveness</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>65</startPage>
	<endPage>94</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Designing model of competencies development for top and middle managers of the National Iranian Petrochemical Company</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Neda Ramezanpanah</name>
	<email>n.ramezanpanah@ase.ui.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Sayyed Mohsen Allameh</name>
	<email>sm.allameh@ase.ui.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hosein Samavatian</name>
	<email>h.samavatian@ase.ui.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>maryam ghanenia</name>
	<email>m.ghanenia@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of this research was to design a model for developing the competencies of top and middle managers of the National Iranian Petrochemical Company. This research carried out by using a mixed approach. Statistical population was top and middle managers of the National Iranian Petrochemical Company. In data collection stage, it was used a semi-structured interview method, study of high-level documents and literature review of research in the qualitative part and a researcher-designed questionnaire in quantitative part. The extracted data from the interviews analyzed by thematic method using the MAXQDA &#160;software. Based on the findings, the managers' competency model, including three dimensions of personal, interpersonal and administrative, ten components and forty six indices and managers' development model with two general methods, organizational development and self-development designed and the necessary development methods for every competency were presented.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-886-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>competency model</keyword>
	<keyword>competency development</keyword>
	<keyword>National Iranian Petrochemical Company</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>95</startPage>
	<endPage>122</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">An Integrated Human Resource Planning Framework for Project-based Organizations in Oil and Gas Industry</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Abbas Abbaspour</name>
	<email>Abbaspour1386@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hamed Dehghanan</name>
	<email>hghanan@atu.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Laya Olfat</name>
	<email>olfat@atu.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Seyed Mohhammadsadegh Seyedkhamoushi</name>
	<email>ssadegh@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The complexities of the oil industry, combined project-based organizations&#8217; complexities, have led the traditional planning of HR being failed. The success of these organizations is based on integrative human resource planning. To this end, the purpose of this study was to determine the factors and components of human resource planning in oil and gas project-based organizations and providing an integrative framework using a qualitative approach. According to the used exploratory approach, in this research, theoretical sampling method has been used. The data were collected through semi-structured interviews with 28 oil industry experts. Finally, based on the obtained components, an integrated human resource planning framework has been presented in oil and gas project-based organizations that includes simultaneous planning of the HR&#8217;s ten subsystems including: &#160;Organization Design, Recruitment and Selection, HR Development, Promotion and Succession, Retention, Total Reward, Performance Management, Communication, Knowledge Management and, Safety and Health.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-887-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Human Resource Planning</keyword>
	<keyword>Project-based Organization</keyword>
	<keyword>Oil and Gas Industry</keyword>
	<keyword>Complexity</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>123</startPage>
	<endPage>148</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Introducing the Analytics and Identifying Model of Human Resource Risks in National Iranian Gas Company</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Masoumeh Mahrad</name>
	<email>Mhtab.r1376@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Roohalla Samiee</name>
	<email>samiei@aliabadiau.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hossein Dideh Khani</name>
	<email>h.didekhani@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Parviz Saeedi</name>
	<email>Dr.parvizsaeedi@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The focus of this research, due to the importance of human resource risks issues, has been on providing an analytical qualitative model to optimize the human resource risk management.&#160; In order to carry out the project, twenty samples were selected among faculty members and top managers in related fields. Fuzzy Delphi and interpretive structural modeling were used to analyze the data. The findings were led to an integrated model of human resource risks with four levels. Contextual risks as the foundation level and the most influential one and the behavioral risks as the most influenced level of the proposed model were identified. Managers were expected, in order to minimize human resource risks, to be more responsive to the levels of the model.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-897-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Human Resource Risks</keyword>
	<keyword>Fuzzy Delphi</keyword>
	<keyword>Interpretive Structural Modeling</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>149</startPage>
	<endPage>182</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Job Burnout Effect on Non-executive Personnel Attention Cognitive Function and Psychosocial Wellbeing</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Sedigheh Javadpour</name>
	<email>sedigheh.javadpour@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Alireza Moradi</name>
	<email>moradi90@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Marieke van Vugh</name>
	<email>m.k.van.vugt@rug.nl</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Jamileh Zarei</name>
	<email>jamileh.zarei@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Amouzad Mehdirji</name>
	<email>mohamadamouzad@gmail.comj</email>
	<affiliationId>5</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>AmirPouya Tanhaeei</name>
	<email>amirpoya.tanhaei@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>6</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="5">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="6">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The present research concentrated on the cognitive function of the attention factors and the parameters of psychosocial wellbeing in the employees of non-executive personnel of the Oil Industry. This descriptive cross-sectional research was conducted on 68 candidates from three volunteer departments with the mean age of 37 and 14 years of work experience. The subjects registered in the research website and attended the relevant standard tests for the assessment of psychosocial wellbeing previously made available to them on-line. Also, the Attention Network Test was applied in the assessment of the Attention factors cognitive function. The data analysis was done by SPSS 25, with the results indicating that the burnout level has a meaningful correlation with parameters of Executive Control Network, and reaction time of Attention, along with those of social-health, stress, anxiety and depression.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-928-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Burnout</keyword>
	<keyword>Social Well-being</keyword>
	<keyword>Mental Health</keyword>
	<keyword>Nonexecutive Personnel</keyword>
	<keyword>Attention Cognitive Function</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>183</startPage>
	<endPage>210</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Phenomenology of the Experience of Experts and Novice Managers in the Oil Industry to Identify Their Cognitive Differences</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Maryam Sadat Akhbari Dorcheh</name>
	<email>m_akhbari@edu.ui.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hamid Reza Oreyzi Samani</name>
	<email>dr.oreyzi@edu.ui.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hosein Eskandari</name>
	<email>sknd@atu.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hamid Bidram</name>
	<email>h.bidram@sci.ui.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">This study aimed to identify the cognitive differences between expert and novice managers in the performance of their main tasks by examining their perspectives and experiences. To do so, two four-people groups of experts and novice managers, from two subsidiaries of National Iranian Oil Refining and Distribution Company were selected. A task analysis interview was conducted for every participant and the data was encoded by Crandall, Klein, and Hoffman&#8217;s (2006) guideline and the two groups were compared together. The results revealed various cognitive differences between the two groups. Most importantly, expert managers considered probabilities, obtained the approval of others for their decisions, and paid attention to the importance of workforce. These cognitive differences can help organizations hire qualified managers, identify weaknesses in the performance of managers, and train managers.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-926-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>cognitive task analysis</keyword>
	<keyword>naturalistic decision-making</keyword>
	<keyword>expert managers</keyword>
	<keyword>novice managers
 </keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>211</startPage>
	<endPage>238</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Designing an Indigenous Model of Intellectual Capital Measurement with Pathological Approach at the Ministry of Petroleum</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Fereydoon Qasemi</name>
	<email>fgh1393@hotmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Karma Allah Danesh Fard</name>
	<email>cdaneshfard@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Reza Najaf Beigi</name>
	<email>najafbeigi@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Ali Afshar Kazemi</name>
	<email>.  Dr.mafshar@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of this research was to design a native model of intellectual capital measurement with a pathological approach at the Ministry of Petroleum. By reviewing related literature as well as expert interviews and theme analysis, key dimensions and components of intellectual capital at the Ministry of Petroleum identified, and it has been proposed an initial model by rational communication between these dimensions and components. This model was shaped through opinions of 40 experts, collected by a questionnaire. Main factors identified through interviewing by 18 experts. Validation of proposed model was approved by experts. According to this model, the intellectual capital of the Ministry of Petroleum of Iran was consisted of three parts including: human, structural and social capital which consists of 8 dimensions and 22 components. The proposed model can be used as a basis for measuring intellectual capital in the Ministry of Petroleum.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-895-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Intellectual Capital</keyword>
	<keyword>Intellectual Capital Measurement</keyword>
	<keyword>Pathology</keyword>
	<keyword>Ministry of Petroleum</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>239</startPage>
	<endPage>264</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Designing Talent Management System Template via Mixed Method in Gas Company of Sistan &#38; Baluchestan Province</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Keyvan barzegar</name>
	<email>keyvanbarzegar72@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Seyed Aligholi Roshan</name>
	<email>salirowshan@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohsen Yaghoubi</name>
	<email>Mohsen.yaeghoubi@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of the present study was to design a talent management system model in Gas Company of Sistan and Baluchestan province. The mixed method (qualitative-quantitative) was selected as the research method. The statistical population in the qualitative section consisted of managers and supervisors and the research data was gathered through in-depth semi-structured interviews with 11 individuals. The data were analyzed using the grounded theory method and 185 primitive codes, 53 concepts and 18 categories were extracted. The statistical population in the quantitative section consisted of all employees and sampling method was stratification. According to the variance as the dispersion criterion, the sample size estimated 209. Data were collected using a researcher-made questionnaire and the validity and reliability of the questionnaire were confirmed by partial least squares method. The results showed that the final template has the necessary validity. This template provides an appropriate framework for moving to the ideal state of talent management.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-929-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Talent Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Talent Management System Template</keyword>
	<keyword>Attraction and Selection</keyword>
	<keyword>Training and Development</keyword>
	<keyword>Retaining</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>265</startPage>
	<endPage>294</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Role of Talent Management in the Indication of Innovative Capabilities of Pars Oil &#59;Gas Company</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Seyedeh Mona Hejazi</name>
	<email>mh_22066@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Masoumeh Oladian</name>
	<email>m.oladian@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Seyed Rasoul Hosseini</name>
	<email>hosseinirasual@csu.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of this study was to study the role of talent management in the emergence of innovative capabilities. The methodology of this study was fundamental in terms of purpose, and descriptive-survey in terms of data collection method and the nature of the research. Interviews, Delphi method and questionnaire were used for data collection. The statistical population of the study consisted of knowledgeable experts and experts in the field of talent management and professional competence of the staff with high backgrounds in decision-making and executive levels as well as academics background in this field. Sample size was determined based on Cochran formula and 103 individuals were selected using simple random sampling. The face validity of the questionnaire was confirmed by experts and its reliability was confirmed by Cronbach's alpha coefficient of 0.886. Structural equation modeling using PLS2 software was used to test and test the hypotheses and to investigate the causal relationships of the variables in the study. In this study, the executive mechanisms, barriers and facilitators of model implementation were also examined. The results showed that talent management with regard to moderating variables (individual, environmental, organizational, human, contextual, and cultural) was influential in updating innovative capabilities.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-912-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Talent management</keyword>
	<keyword>innovative capabilities</keyword>
	<keyword>Pars Oil &#38; Gas Co.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>295</startPage>
	<endPage>316</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Identification and ranking performance evaluation components of Talents National Iranian Oil Company</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad bashokouh ajirlo</name>
	<email>mohammadbashokouh@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Zahra pouramini</name>
	<email>z.pooramini@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Majid yahyavi ghasem gheshlaghi</name>
	<email>Majidyahyavi74@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Alireza Fardi Azar</name>
	<email>A_fardiazar@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">According to competitive environments; demand for talents is rising, but most organizations are struggling to maintain Talents. In this regard, the system of Competency-based performance assessment in maintaining talent is a requirement. The purpose of this paper was to identify and rank the components of the evaluation of the performance of talents. This research was carried out at the National Iranian Oil Company and the data collection tool was a questionnaire distributed among 223 managers, experts and employees. The results showed that the components of evaluation of talent performance include leadership competencies, problem solving, communication, and teamwork, technical and technical, planning and organizing, exposure to pressure, flexibility, innovation and customer orientation.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-885-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Talents</keyword>
	<keyword>Performance Evaluation</keyword>
	<keyword>National Iranian Oil Company</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>317</startPage>
	<endPage>342</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Relationship between Green Human Resource Management and Green Supply Chain Management</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Ebrahim Rajabpour</name>
	<email>E.Rajabpour@pgu.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mehdi Afkhami Ardakani</name>
	<email>Afkhami@nigc-yazd.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">There is a growing interest among researchers in Green developments; however, research on the most important organizational capital, namely green human resources management (GHRM), is scant. Therefore, the purpose of this study was to investigate the role of green HRM in the green supply chain management (GSCM). The methodology of this study is applied and survey strategy. The statistical population of the study consisted of managers, supervisors, supervisors and experts of Barzouieh Petrochemical Company, which is about 700 people. Its statistical sample size is estimated at 207 according to Morgan's formula. Data were collected using a researcher-made Green HRM questionnaire and Green Supply Chain, based on Ahmadi, Afshari and Shekari (2014) research, on a five-point Likert scale. Construct, content and face validity of the questionnaire were investigated. Cronbach's alpha reliability coefficient was 0.87. Collected data were analyzed using statistical software SPSS and LISREL. Finally, as a result, Organizational Green Human Resource Management has a positive, direct and significant effect on Green Supply Chain Management and subsystems of GHRM (Green recruitment and selection, Green Training &#38; Development, Green Pay and Reward System and Green Performance Assessment) have a positive, direct and significant effect on GSCM.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-902-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Sustainable Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Green Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Green Human Resource Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Environmental Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Green Supply Chain Management</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>343</startPage>
	<endPage>372</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Presenting a Model of Effective Training System for the Staff of the Iran Ministry of Petroleum</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Bahare Tahvildari</name>
	<email>btahvildari5@gmail.com.</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Abbas Khorshidi</name>
	<email>Ali.Khosravi¬_Babadi@iauctb.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Alireza Araghie</name>
	<email>araghieh@iiau.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Aliakbar Khosravi Babadi</name>
	<email>Ali.Khosravi¬_Babadi@iauctb.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Batool Faghih Aram</name>
	<email>Faghiharam1388@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>5</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="5">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of this study was to present a model of effective training system for staff of Iran Ministry of Petroleum. The research is consumed an applied research in terms of its goals, a qualitative one in terms of data and the data base is self-contained, in terms of the method of conducting the research. The study population consisted of experts in the field of education including university professors and senior managers of the Ministry of Petroleum who were selected by purposeful sampling method. After 30 interviews, the researcher's diagnosis was that the information had reached saturation point. The data gathering tool was a survey of relevant national and international documents as well as a semi-structured exploratory interview. Finally, the data base and coding method was used to classify the data. To insure the validity of the study, using the research method by the research members was applied in addition to studying the theoretical foundations. The findings indicated that the model of the effective training system of the staff of the Ministry of Petroleum of Iran comprises aspects such as learner, content, instructor, environment, executive requirements, results and organization and management</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-924-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Effective Education</keyword>
	<keyword>Education System</keyword>
	<keyword>Oil Ministry Staff.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>44</issue>
	<startPage>373</startPage>
	<endPage>402</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Pathology of Training staff of the National Oil products Distribution Company ; based on Grounded Theory approach</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mahdi Divdar</name>
	<email>mdivdar@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mahboubeh Soleimanpouromran</name>
	<email>m.pouromran@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Today, the pathology of employee training is one of the most important challenges for organizations to plan more accurately and benefit from training patterns and methods. Therefore, due to the importance of human resources improvement and effective management, a model tailored to the company's native features is needed. The main purpose of this study was to determine the pathology of training the staff of National oil Products Distribution Company using the Grounded Theory&#160; method. The information was gathered through a semi-structured interview with 24 of the company's experts and review of 40 new articles. By selective and axial coding, the components of the final model and how they relate to each other were obtained. The results of the study included extraction of 31 main components and 119 sub-categories in three dimensions of process, structure and context in the paradigm of causal, axial, confounding, actions and tendencies, contexts and outcomes.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-875-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>pathology</keyword>
	<keyword>human resources training</keyword>
	<keyword></keyword>
	<keyword>Grounded Theory approach</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
 </records>
 
  
  
  
  
 