<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title> Human Resource Management in Oil Industry </title>
<link>http://www.iieshrm.ir</link>
<description>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry - Journal articles for year 2019, Volume 10, Number 38</description>
<generator>Yektaweb Collection - https://yektaweb.com</generator>
<language>en</language>
<pubDate>2019/3/10</pubDate>

					<item>
						<title>Providing a Model for Shaping Horizontal Alignment among Human Resources Management Practices
</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=630&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
Two types of fitness and alignment are essential in human resource management. Vertical alignment that points to the consistent of HRM strategies and activities with corporate strategies and goals and, horizontal alignment that is related to the consistency among various practices of human resource management. With regard to effective results and synergies resulting from consistent and integrated HR practices, identifying the dimensions of horizontal fitness in human resource management practices, providing a desirable and comprehensive model is inevitable. The present study was carried out for this purpose by using qualitative meta-analysis method. So that the most important definitions of the concept of alignment and horizontal alignment, as well as the models and theories related to it, have been identified and investigated. Then their strengths and weaknesses compared with each other and, finally, the proposed model was designed in such a way that includes a comprehensive definition of horizontal alignment and its effective dimensions. The main advantage of the proposed model is that it combines all definitions of the concept of alignment and horizontal alignment, and investigates horizontal integrity dimensions among human resource management practices, including process integrity, architectural and configuration integrity, and executive integrity in a comprehensive manner.</description>
						<author>Jabbar  Babashahi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Designing a Model for Explaining Creative Deviance in the National Iranian Oil Company</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=623&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>In many companies, the path from initiating creative ideas from individuals to innovate is not fully implemented for many reasons. Such companies have been convinced to use employees' new ideas effectively and know that will not happen except with a creative deviance. So, the goal of this research was to design a model of creative deviance in the National Iranian Oil Company using the grounded theory method as one of the qualitative methods.In this study, deep interviews were conducted with 11experts in the National Iranian Oil Company and University Professors , using theoretical sampling method for determining research sample. Then, the components of creative deviation were identified in three stages of coding in grounded theory method, including: open, axial, and selective coding methods. According to the results, management and organizational component (causal conditions), creative deviance (action/reaction strategy) characteristics of actors and features of the idea (context), managerial, organizational and biographical conditions (intervening conditions), positive and negative consequences in the individual and organizational levels (consequences) were extracted and creative deviance model was designed.</description>
						<author>Hojjat  Vahdati</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Factors affecting the tendency to leave the organization using an intelligent model based on multi-objective neural network and genetic algorithms

</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=624&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Since the improvement of human resource efficiency can play an effective role in the efficiency of organizations, it has always been one of the main research topics.The tendency to leave the organization is one of the factors affecting the efficiency of human capital, which can be predicted using in-data models, conditions governing the organization and the factors affecting it. For this purpose, intelligent algorithms based on neural network and multi-objective genetic algorithm have been used in this research to predict the tendency to leave an organization. In this regard, a standard dataset was created based on a questionnaire of employees satisfaction and the desire to leave the job in the Karoon Oil and Gas Production Company. Then, using an artificial neural network as a classifier and a multi-objective genetic algorithm, the important factors or features were selected. In the next step, an expert system was proposed to select effective features. In order to test and evaluate the neural network algorithm developed with the standard data set, the necessary training was provided. The results showed that by using the proposed model, not only the willingness of employees to leave the organization can be predicted with more than 88% accuracy, but also, the key factors of leaving the organization can be determined.</description>
						<author>Mohsen  Sardari Zarchi </author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Improving the occupational health and work life quality of employees in the oil platforms with the analysis of workaholism effects </title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=625&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Variety of factors can affect the work-life quality of human resources which is the most fundamental resource of an organization. This study has addressed the effect of occupational health variable on the relationship between workaholism and the quality of work life. The study is considered an applied research in terms of purpose and descriptive survey in terms of methodology. The statistical population included 160 employees of Soroosh platform. According to Cochran formula 113 people were selected among them by the simple random sampling method. The standardized questionnaires of Spens and Robbins, Walton quality of work life as well as the occupational health questionnaire by Goldberg and Hiller were used as data gathering tools. The research hypotheses test was performed by Smart PLS software and research findings confirmed the role of health care mediating role in this regard. In addition, the results indicated that workaholism has a positive and significant effect on quality of work life, yet has a negative effect on occupational health.</description>
						<author>Elaheh  Ebrahimi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Explanation of Indicators and Operational Model of Crisis Management in Petrochemical Industry </title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=626&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Natural disasters and industrial accidents are among the serious threats of Industry sector. When an accident happens in the petrochemical industry, not only much of the economy will be in hurt, but environmental pollution is also caused by a high risk of petrochemical operations. Therefore, crisis management is very important in this industry. The aim of this study was to provide crisis management model using structural equation modeling with a study in petrochemical Central Province of Iran. This research is considered an applied research in terms of purpose and is a description and analytical survey in terms of gathering information. The statistical population included managers and experts of petrochemical industry from Central Province of Iran. The research sample was selected randomly by using the Cochran it is done. Data collection tool was researcher made questionnaire. The reliability and validity of research tools have been confirmed. After identifying the indicators of crisis management in the petrochemical industry, the effective indicators were extracted with techniques of exploratory factor analysis. A conceptual model introduced by using confirmatory factor analysis techniques. Analyze data was done by using SPSS and LISREL software. From the exploratory factor analysis for aspects of prevention, preparedness, reaction, and post-reaction , 2, 8, 4 and 11 factors extracted, respectively. Confirmatory factor analysis also revealed a significant relationship between the variables and latent structures has been confirmed that it shows the model has a good fit.</description>
						<author>Ebrahim   Rahimi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Knowledge Management Enablers and Measurement of Their Communication with Organization Performance </title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=627&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>The purpose of this study was to explain the relationship between knowledge management Enablers and organizational performance in Nouri Petrochemical Company. This research is considered an applied research which was done by a descriptive-survey method. The statistical population has been consisted of 340 official employees of Nouri Petrochemical Company. By using random sampling method, 181 people were selected. Data analysis was done using descriptive and inferential statistics by SPSS and LISREL software. The results showed that in the field of knowledge management Enablers in the Nouri Petrochemical Company including information technology, culture and staff with Beta Coefficient of 0.405, 0.373 and 0.135, had the highest amount of relevance and impact on the process of creating knowledge, respectively. But organizational structure was not effective. Also, among the dimensions of creating knowledge process in this company, internalization, externalization and socialization with Beta Coefficient of 0.325, 0.268 and 0.176 have shown the highest degree of relevance and impact on organizational creativity. But the composition dimension was not effective. Ultimately, the results also showed that organizational creativity has a meaningful effect on organizational performance (Beta=0.610), supporting the main hypothesis of this research.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</description>
						<author>Mohammad Hossein  Pourshojaei</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>The Relationship between Paternalistic Leadership and Employees' Silence Emphasizing On Moderating Role of Organizational Justice </title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=628&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>The aim of present research was to investigate the relationship between paternalistic leadership and organizational silence emphasizing on the moderating role of organizational justice. The research method has been descriptive-correlational and the statistical population of the research was the staff of Chaharmahal &amp; Bakhtiari Gas Company including 230 people. By using Kerjesi formula and Morgan table, a sample of 140 employees were selected through simple random sampling method. For collecting data, three standard questionnaires of patriarchal leadership, Chang et al. (2004), Vakola and Bouradas (2005), and organizational justice, Niehoff &amp; Moorman (1993) were used. The reliability of the questionnaires using Cronbach's alpha coefficients was 0.86, 0.73 and 0.79, respectively. SPSS and AMOS software were used to analyze the data. Findings of the research showed that there is a relationship between patriarchal leadership, authoritarian leadership, benevolent leadership and ethical leadership with organizational silence. Considering the moderating role of organizational justice, and given the fact that the level of meaningfulness is lower than the amount The error of 0.05 and the critical value exceeded the acceptable range of 1.96, all the hypothesis of the research were confirmed.</description>
						<author>Maryam  Ahmadi Zahrani </author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Mathematical Modeling of Contractors Selection at the Research Institute of Petroleum Industry</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=629&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;pre&gt;
One of the techniques used in management is the outsourcing of activities that are not necessarily associated with success due to the lack of proper selection of the contractor. Since this technique is implemented in a large part of the activities of the petroleum industry research center, this study addresses this issue. This research has been conducted with a applied-development approach, utilizing the expert group's view of mathematical modeling of selecting contractors at the oil industry research institute with the Bernardo model. The results showed that the research institute of petroleum industry in evaluating contractors should use a two-stage model. Also, from the viewpoint of the expert group in the first phase of selection, the number of selective criteria increases, the final utility rate is reduced in the expert group agreement, but this in the second phase of the selection reflects precisely the results of the photograph. Based on the results of this research, suggestions were managed to increase the satisfaction of contractors and stakeholders in this industry.&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
						<author>Abolfazl  Danaei </author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
	</channel>
</rss>
