<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>5</volume>
<number>20</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارزیابی نظام مدیریت منابع انسانی شرکت ملی نفت ایران برمبنای مولفه ها ی مدل مدیریت استراتژیک منابع انسانی &quot; P5&quot; شولر(1992)</title_fa>
	<title>Assessment of human resource management system of National Iranian Oil Company based on” 5P” MODEL of strategic human resource management (Schuler, 1992)</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;مدیریت استراتژیک منابع انسانی مقوله ایست که علی رغم بلوغ جهانی، در آغازین مراحل شکل گیری خود در ایران بوده و همچون سایر مفاهیم وروش های مدیریتی نوین، تنها در ادبیات مدیران و به عنوان واژگانی مدرن نمود می&amp;shy;یابد&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:system,sans-serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt; در راستای اهمیت این حوزه و همچنین احساس نیاز در ارزیابی نظام مدیریت منابع انسانی شرکت ملی نفت ایران وتحلیل شکاف وضعیت موجود با شرایط مطلوب، مدل مدیریت استراتژیک منابع انسانی&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:system,sans-serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;p5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;( شولر ،1992) انتخاب وبرمبنای مولفه های مدل مذکوراین مهم صورت پذیرفته است.جامعه آماری این پژوهش متولیان منابع انسانی ستاد، شرکت های اصلی و تابعه شرکت ملی نفت ایران بوده و نمونه آماری به صورت تصادفی انتخاب گردیده است. روایی محتوای پرسشنامه&amp;shy;ی طراحی شده ، از طریق توافق متخصصان، روایی سازه ازطریق تحلیل عاملی تأییدی و پایایی آن با محاسبه ضریب آلفای کرونباخ بررسی گردیده است. یافته های تحقیق در راستای ارزیابی نظام مدیریت منابع انسانی شرکت ملی نفت ایران ضمن تأیید تأثیر عوامل محیطی داخلی و خارجی براستراتژی های کلان سازمان به&#8204;منظور خلق نیاز های استراتژیک، میانگین نمره پایین سایرمؤلفه های پنج گانه مدل در قسمت &amp;quot;وضعیت موجود&amp;quot; نشان ازشکاف قابل ملاحظه وضع موجود نسبت به وضع مطلوب داشته وعدم همسویی حیطه های فلسفه، خط مشی ها، برنامه ها، عملکردها و فرآیند های منابع انسانی با نیاز های استراتژیک سازمان را نشان می دهد. در پایان و برمبنای سایر یافته های پژوهش، پیشنهادهایی به منظور بهبود وارتقای نظام موجود مدیریت منابع انسانی ونزدیک شدن به مدیریت استراتژیک منابع انسانی در شرکت ملی نفت ایران ارائه گردیده است.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
Despite the fact that human resource strategic management enjoys a worldwide maturity, it is an emergent realm of study in Iran. This novel management approach, similar to a many modern management concepts and practices, is only used in managers' diction, and as unconventional technical jargon. Aligned with the significance associated with this area and feel the need to Assess human resource management system of National Iranian Oil Company and analyze the gap between the present condition and the desirable one, the &amp;ldquo;5P&amp;rdquo; Model of strategic human resource management (Schuler, 1992) selected and according to parameters of the model the study has been designed and conducted. The sample to this study has been drawn by random selection of subjects from human resources departments' administrative staff in main and subsidiary companies of National Iranian Oil Company. While study's researcher-developed questionnaire's internal reliability was determined via experts' consensus, its structural reliability was confirmed through factor analysis. Besides, its internal consistency was measured through Cronbach's Alpha coefficient. The findings, in line with previous evaluations of the studied model, have revealed its being highly-welcomed and apposite to National Iranian Oil Company's structure. National Iranian's Oil Company's low average score for the five activities of the model, including philosophies; policies; programs; practices; and processes, indicates the significant existing gap between Company's current condition and the desirable one, it; thus, implies the fact that these five are not aligned with Company's strategic needs. Moreover, it verifies the effect of internal and external environmental factors over Company's main strategies aiming at creating strategic needs. The findings, in line with previous evaluations of the studied model, have revealed its being highly-welcomed and apposite to National Iranian Oil Company's structure. Ultimately and in accordance with study's findings, some implications have been offered seeking to improve and enhance the present human resource management system, besides approaching goals of human resource strategic management in National Iranian Oil Company.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی استراتژیک , مدل "p5" مدیریت استراتژیک منابع انسانی (شولر, 1992) , نیاز های استراتژیک کسب و کار , همسویی استراتژیک ,  شرکت ملی نفت ایران</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Schuler's “5P” Model of Strategic Human Resource Management (1992)- Strategic business needs, Strategic alignment- National Iranian Oil Company.</keyword>
	<start_page>53</start_page>
	<end_page>82</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-311-30&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>MohammadTaghi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Amini</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد تقی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>امینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001858</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001858</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه پیام نور تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Lotfeali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Bakhtiari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>لطفعلی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بختیاری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001859</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001859</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه امام حسین(ع)</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>MohammadReza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Bashiri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد رضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بشیری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>bashiri.mr@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001860</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001860</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
