<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <records>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2017-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>8</volume>
	<issue>31</issue>
	<startPage>3</startPage>
	<endPage>39</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Comparative Study between Abusive Supervision and Social Loafing</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Naser Pour Sadegh</name>
	<email>dr.naser.poursadegh@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The present article is based on a conducted comparative study between abusive supervision and social loafing among A Public sectore Company&#8217;s staff. This study is designed through the comparative-analysis approach based on survey method. The statistical population of this study is among 250 &#160;The Company&#8217;s staff. The measurement tool used in this study is a questionnaire including 3 personal information questions and 15 questions regarding testing the hypothesis. The reliability of the questionnaire, based on Cronbach's&#160;alpha, is 0.912. Kolmogorov&#8211;Smirnov&#160;Test is used to study the normal distribution of data, and the Pearson&#160;Correlation Coefficient Test is used to test the hypothesizes of the present study, in this regard,&#160; SEM analysis is used for its fitting. The result gained through the present study shows that there is a meaningful and direct relationship between abusive supervision and social loafing among The Company&#8217;s staff. In the same vein, the results gained through the fitting SEM show that for one unit change in abusive supervision variable, there is, then, 0.82 changes in social loafing variable.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-146-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>abusive supervision</keyword>
	<keyword>social loafing</keyword>
	<keyword>supervision style</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2017-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>8</volume>
	<issue>31</issue>
	<startPage>41</startPage>
	<endPage>71</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Driving factors’ pattern of the elites’ inclination towards turnover from the viewpoint of NIOPCS directors</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mehdi kheir Andish</name>
	<email>dr.me.kh@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mir Ali Seyed Naghavi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Sayareh Safari</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The importance of human resource has highlighted &#8220;turnover&#8221; issue in most organizations. Today the high rate of desertion is regarded as an organizational problem. Undoubtedly, the elites&#8217; turnover imposes huge costs on organizations. Therefore, it is essential to identify the causes of their turnover. The purpose of this study is to identify the causes of elite&#8217;s desertion, and its impact on the inclination of the staff of NIOPDC to desert. The present study is descriptive in terms of purpose, applied in terms of function, and survey research in terms of method. The questionnaire was formulated based upon survey literature and survey elites&#8217; opinions. The reliability value of 0.885 was calculated using Cronbach&#8217;s Alpha. The statistical population includes directors of NIOPDC (Tehran), 105 of which were chosen as sample using Cochran formula. The results obtained from data analysis using Confirmatory Factor Analysis and Path Analysis indicated that occupational and organizational factors have a meaningful impact on the staff desertion. Personal factors, on the other hand, had no meaningful impact.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-147-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>turnover</keyword>
	<keyword>elites</keyword>
	<keyword>organizational factors</keyword>
	<keyword>occupational factors</keyword>
	<keyword>personal factors</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2017-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>8</volume>
	<issue>31</issue>
	<startPage>73</startPage>
	<endPage>105</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Disclosure of the Context of Implicit Theories of Leadership from the Perspectives of the Employees of the National Iranian Oil Distribution Company of Kerman Region and Its Validation</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Sadegh Sharifi Rad</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Saeed Mortazavi</name>
	<email>mortazavi@um.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Fariborz Rahim Nia</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Mehdi Farahi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Implicit theories of leadership as a series of cognitive structures that differentiate leaders from non-leaders have significant implications for followers as well as human resource management. In this regard, the present research attempted to identify and present the characteristics and capabilities of ideal leaders from the viewpoint of followers. Data collection was done using semi-structured interviews with 15 heads of units and employees of Iran's Oil Distribution Company in Kerman area. Exploratory blended research strategy was selected and used as a contractual content analysis tool. The texts of the interviews were compiled, had been written and coded, and then categories and themes were extracted; the results of coding and data analysis were classified into two themes of positive prototypes and negative prototypes. In the lowest level, 28 units of thoughts were discovered. Categories for positive pre-models include &#34;charismatic&#34;, &#34;humanistic&#34;, &#34;committed to securing,&#34; &#34;emotional maturity,&#34; &#34;high decision-making power,&#34; and for negative patterns of titles, &#34;self-protecting&#34;, &#34;deceitful&#34; and &#34;narrow&#34;. After the discovery of the categories of implied leadership theories in the qualitative stage, a quantitative validation of the model was developed and a 28-item questionnaire was designed and distributed among 128 samples under the supervision of units' heads, and the validity of the model was confirmed.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-148-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Implicit Theories of Leadership</keyword>
	<keyword>Positive Prototypes</keyword>
	<keyword>Negative Prototypes</keyword>
	<keyword>National Iranian Oil Distribution Company of Kerman Province</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2017-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>8</volume>
	<issue>31</issue>
	<startPage>107</startPage>
	<endPage>127</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Investigating the Impact of Managers’ Reverse Behaviors on Employees’ Organizational Indifference
 (The Case of Study: Isfahan Province Gas Company)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Reza SalehZadeh</name>
	<email>r.salehzadeh99@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Arash Shahin</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Afshin Jahanbazi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Studies have shown that in the recent decades managers&#8217; behaviors and their impacts on employees&#8217; outcomes are important topics in the organizational behavior and applied psychology domains and are discussed in different leadership theories. The aim of this research was to investigate the impact of managers&#8217; reverse behaviors on employees&#8217; organizational indifference in Isfahan Province Gas Company. This study used a mixed method research (i.e. qualitative and quantitative methods). First, through the interviews with employees and using thematic analysis, the managers&#8217; behaviors were identified. Next, based on the identified behaviors and Kano model the type of each behavior was classified and according to this classification the managers&#8217; reverse behaviors were identified. Then the impact of managers&#8217; reverse behaviors on employees&#8217; organizational indifference was investigated by Structural Equation Modeling (SEM) using AMOS software. Based on the results of the interviews, 46 managers&#8217; behaviors were identified out of which ten behaviors were must-be; five behaviors were one-dimensional, eighteen behaviors were attractive and thirteen behaviors were reverse type. Also, the results showed that managers&#8217; reverse behaviors have a significant positive effect on organizational indifference (b=0.86).</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-149-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Reverse Behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>Organizational Indifference</keyword>
	<keyword>Kano Model</keyword>
	<keyword>Isfahan Province Gas Company</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2017-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>8</volume>
	<issue>31</issue>
	<startPage>129</startPage>
	<endPage>152</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Identifying and ranking  the factors influencing on interests of work and work engagement of employees of National Iranian Gas Company (case study: gas company employees of Ilam)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Reza Sepahvand</name>
	<email>mrezasep@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Zohreh Mohammadyari</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of this study is Identifying and ranking&#160; the factors influencing on interests of work and work engagement of employees of National Iranian Gas Company. The research method is mix method (qualitative - quantitative). The population in qualitative part includes human resources experts and managers of the National Gas Company and in quantitative section includes all staff of the National Gas Company. Grounded Theory was used for analyzing data in qualitative section and Identifying factors.
In quantitative section, for examining the effectiveness of identifying factors influencing on interests of work and work engagement of employees , structural equation modeling has been applied by using LISREL software and for ranking Identifying factors Fuzzy AHP was used. The results showed that four main factors influencing the interests of work and work engagement include; organizational Resources, personal resources, career resources and competencies and supervisors and colleagues support. Among these factors, the most effective factor has been organizational resources.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-150-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>interests of work</keyword>
	<keyword>work engagement of employees</keyword>
	<keyword>organizational Resources</keyword>
	<keyword>personal resources</keyword>
	<keyword>career resources</keyword>
	<keyword>support</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2017-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>8</volume>
	<issue>31</issue>
	<startPage>153</startPage>
	<endPage>175</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Explanation and prioritization of the factors affecting key employees’ turnover intention in privatized firms of National Oil Company (case study: Ahvaz pipe industrial Company)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mehrban Hadi Peykani</name>
	<email>paykanin2323@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Khanifar</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Regarding the importance of organizational turnover, the related physical and spiritual costs in long term, and necessity for prediction and control of turnover to retain key employees, the present study was conducted to investigate, explain and prioritize the factors affecting employees&#8217; turnover intention in Ahvaz pipe industrial Company in the context of a correlation type applied survey. Data were collected by submitting a questionnaire among 271 employees. The results of data analysis by SPSS and LISREL software confirmed construct validity of the research variables and revealed that feeling of working with organization has the highest priority with Friedman rank of 5.498; followed by supervisor&#8217;s characteristics (3.994), work-related shocks (3.902), and job properties (3.856). Job-related feelings and emotions had the lowest importance.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-151-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2017-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>8</volume>
	<issue>31</issue>
	<startPage>177</startPage>
	<endPage>205</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Typology of human resources performance evaluation indices (Case study: Fars Province Gas Company)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Alireza Pooya</name>
	<email>alirezapooya@um.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Marziyeh Norouzi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Each organization to determine the quality of your work had an urgent need to evaluate the system. A correct understanding of the needs and the proper management of human resources in organizations is key to success. The aim of this study is to identify and categorize the factors affecting employee performance evaluation is using factor analysis. After reviewing the literature, 62 factors affecting the performance, were identified and were reduced to 45. Using factor analysis These factors were divided into 8 main indicator Which include Personality factors, performance management, Teamwork, Commitment and ethical values of the organization, Communication skills, Information and knowledge management, Designing products and services based on customer needs and expectations. Finally, using SEM The research model was confirmed.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-152-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Performance evaluation</keyword>
	<keyword>human resources</keyword>
	<keyword>factor analysis</keyword>
	<keyword>Typology</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2017-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>8</volume>
	<issue>31</issue>
	<startPage>207</startPage>
	<endPage>230</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Studying and Prioritizing the Effective Organizational Factors on Human Resource Retention (Case Study: Pars Special Economic Energy Zone)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Abdolreza Beigi Nia</name>
	<email>beiginia@shahed.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mostafa Ghazi Zadeh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Shoeib Hayati</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The objective of this research has been identifying and prioritizing organizational factors affecting the retention of human resource in Pars Special Economic Energy Zone. The population was 1,000 at the time of study and the sample was estimated 283 using sampling from a finite population (Cochran method). For data&#160; collection, a 59-item researcher made questionnaire was used to identify factors affecting the human resource retention. SPSS software, Kolmogorov-Smirnov test, T-test and ANOVA were used to for data analysis and Friedman method was also utilized to prioritize factors. Results of this study indicated that organizational factors indicators affecting human resource retention in the study organization included payments, social support, job stress, independence, physical conditions of the workplace, management style and supervision, promotion opportunities and organizational justice, respectively.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-153-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Human Resource Retention</keyword>
	<keyword>Organizational Factors</keyword>
	<keyword>Pars Special Economic Energy Zone</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
 </records>
 
  
  
  
  
 