<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>8</volume>
<number>30</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی عوامل تأثیرگذار و تأثیرپذیر بر بدبینی سازمانی در کارکنان ستاد شرکت ملی پخش فرآورده های نفتی ایران</title_fa>
	<title>Investigating Affecting and Influential Factors on Organizational Cynicism Among Staff of National Iranian oil Products Distribution Company (NIOPDC)</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;هدف از تحقیق حاضر بررسی عوامل تأثیرگذار و تأثیرپذیر بر بدبینی سازمانی در کارکنان ستاد شرکت ملی پخش فرآورده های نفتی ایران بوده است. جامعه آماری در این تحقیق شامل کلیه کارکنان ستاد شرکت ملی پخش فرآورده های نفتی ایران است که تعداد آنها 1246 نفر، می باشد. حجم نمونه با استفاده از جدول کرجسی و مورگان 297 نفر تعیین شد. گردآوری اطلاعات به دو روش کتابخانه ای و میدانی انجام گرفت. ابزار گردآوری اطلاعات پرسشنامه بوده است. روایی پرسشنامه ها با استفاده از روایی صوری و روایی سازه، و پایایی پرسشنامه ها با استفاده از ضریب آلفای کرونباخ مورد تایید قرار گرفت.جهت آزمون فرضیه های تحقیق از مدل معادلات ساختاری استفاده شده است. نتایج بدست آمده از آزمون فرضیات این پژوهش نشان داد که عوامل روانشناختی )سیاست سازمانی درک شده و انحراف از قرارداد روانشناختی( بر بدبینی سازمانی کارکنان تأثیر می گذارند. همچنین، بدبینی سازمانی بر پیامدهای نگرشی و پیامدهای رفتاری )رضایت شغلی کارکنان، تعهد سازمانی و رفتار کاری مخرب کارکنان( تأثیرگذار است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>The aim of this study was to investigate the effecting factors and being affected factors on organizational cynicism in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company. The statistical population in this study was included all employee in the National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company including 1246 people. The sample size was determined by Morgan and Krejcie of 297 people. Data collection was conducted by literature review and fieldwork. Data collection tool has been the questionnaire. Questionnaire validity has been verified using formal validity and construct validity, and questionnaire reliability checked by using Cronbach's alpha coefficient .To test the research hypotheses, structural equation model was used. The results of the research showed that psychological factors (perceived organizational politics, deviation from the psychological contract) have an impact on organizational cynicism. Also, organizational cynicism attitudes outcomes, and behavioral outcomes (job satisfaction, organizational commitment, destructive behavior of employees) were impressive.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>بدبینی سازمانی , سیاست سازمانی درک شده , انحراف از قرارداد روانشناختی , استقلال شغلی , رضایت شغلی , تعهد سازمانی , رفتار کاری مخرب</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>organizational cynicism- perceived organizational politics- deviation from the psychological contract- job satisfaction.</keyword>
	<start_page>75</start_page>
	<end_page>98</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-25-37&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>یوسف</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>محمدی مقدم</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>you_mohammad@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002231</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002231</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علوم انتظامی امین</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سوگل</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>آزاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002232</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002232</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران شمال</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
