
	<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"	xmlns:cr_unixml="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2020-07-23T21:38:16+04:30</responseDate>
	<request metadataPrefix="cr_unixml" verb="ListRecords" set="10.1002">http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?mag_id=7&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</request>
	<ListRecords>
		
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>7-71</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</full_title>
									<abbrev_title></abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2251-8886</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-4409</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>8</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>30</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Development of a Personnel Appointment and Promotion structural Model for first line management level 
(case study: National Iranian Oil Company)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email>delavar@atu.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="5">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Promotion and appointment of appropriate human resources to accurately and objectively, one of the main factors leading to the success of organizations. Decide on the appointment and promotion of staff according to merit factor in organizations is a matter of days. This study aims to develop a model for the promotion and appointment of staff to first line management level based on individual and organizational components was performed. For the present study were all employees of National Iranian Oil Company that was established in the &#160;first line management career of those surveyed were in 1521. Among the different variables of literature, management experience, job rank, work experience and merit with dependent variable (position rank) showed significant relationship. After study of the variables, was developed scoring instructions. data obtained from scoring instructions using SPSS 22 and LISREL softwares were analyzed. Direct and indirect effects and overall effects of professional experience, job rank, work experience and competence on the dependent variable (position rank) were studied. Results show that independent variables and Mediator variable(job rank) had a significant effect on the dependent variable. The other obtained results, data were fit and proper indices with model.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Specialized experience</keyword>
	<keyword>job rank</keyword>
	<keyword>job experience</keyword>
	<keyword>competence and  position rank</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>3</first_page>
								  <last_page>25</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-71-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>7-72</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</full_title>
									<abbrev_title></abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2251-8886</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-4409</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>8</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>30</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Competency Model of Managers and Human Resource Professionals in
Gas Company in East Azerbaijan Province Using ISM Technique</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email>iranzadeh@iaut.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Undoubtedly, the most important competitive advantage of organizations in the world of today's rapid changes is having a competent human factor. This is the most important strategic factor that cannot be easily imitated and it could affect the success and sustainable development of organizations. Hence, the success of any organization is dependent on the development of human resources and the development of human resources in any organization and even in every country will not be possible without understanding and discovery capabilities, capabilities and competencies of this great and potential capital. In other wors, due to the special and strategic status of human resource managers and coping with the CEO, communicating with all employees and other managers , their competencies will be very importance. For this purpose, designing and development of competencies models for HR managers would be necessary to meet the needs of organizations in today's rapidly changing conditions. In the present study, after identifying the competencies required by managers and human resources specialists in the gas company of East Azarbaijan, they were ranked by HR managers and non-human resources managers using the ISM technique. The statistical population of this research was all managers and supervisors of the company in high, intermediate and operational levels of the organization including 60 persons.&#160; Due to the limited statistical community, the whole society was considered as the research sample. The results of data analysis showed that among the twenty factors extracted from the research literature in this research and based on a distributed questionnaire, ten factors have been identified as the most important competencies of the managers and human resources specialists of the gas company of East Azarbaijan Province of Iran. The ISM technique was then used to identify the relationship between the factors affecting employee empowerment implementation.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Competency Model</keyword>
	<keyword>Human Resource Managers</keyword>
	<keyword>HR Professionals</keyword>
	<keyword>ISM Technique.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>27</first_page>
								  <last_page>50</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-72-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>7-73</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</full_title>
									<abbrev_title></abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2251-8886</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-4409</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>8</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>30</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Survey the Effect of Talent Management on Organizational Citizenship Behavior
(Case study: Yazd Gas Company)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email>rezapezeshki@stu.yazd.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			In recent years, human is known as one of the most important of competitive factors, in order to increase efficiency and productivity in organizations. According to the importance of this subject in Gas Company, the aim of this research is survey the effect of talent management`s dimensions as the last wave in human resources on organizational citizenship behavior. Structural equation modeling was used for this purpose. The population of this survey are all staff of Yazd Gas Company, which among them, were selected 122 people as sample. Findings show, there is a significant relationship between all dimensions of talent management, except attract, on organizational citizenship behavior. Unlike talent management, organizational citizenship behavior is in good situation. According to the findings, managers of this organization, can increase their efficiency and productivity in attract and training of human resources by reduce their costs and only by alignment and retention through control and regular feedback, increase organizational citizenship behavior.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Human resource</keyword>
	<keyword>talent management</keyword>
	<keyword>organization customer behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>Structural equation modeling.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>51</first_page>
								  <last_page>74</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-73-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>7-74</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</full_title>
									<abbrev_title></abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2251-8886</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-4409</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>8</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>30</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Investigating Affecting and Influential Factors on Organizational Cynicism Among Staff of National Iranian oil Products Distribution Company (NIOPDC)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email>you_mohammad@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The aim of this study was to investigate the effecting factors and being affected factors on organizational cynicism in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company. The statistical population in this study was included all employee in the National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company including 1246 people. The sample size was determined by Morgan and Krejcie of 297 people. Data collection was conducted by literature review and fieldwork. Data collection tool has been the questionnaire. Questionnaire validity has been verified using formal validity and construct validity, and questionnaire reliability checked by using Cronbach's alpha coefficient .To test the research hypotheses, structural equation model was used. The results of the research showed that psychological factors (perceived organizational politics, deviation from the psychological contract) have an impact on organizational cynicism. Also, organizational cynicism attitudes outcomes, and behavioral outcomes (job satisfaction, organizational commitment, destructive behavior of employees) were impressive.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>organizational cynicism- perceived organizational politics- deviation from the psychological contract- job satisfaction.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>75</first_page>
								  <last_page>98</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-74-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>7-75</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</full_title>
									<abbrev_title></abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2251-8886</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-4409</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>8</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>30</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Identification of the factors related to transfer of training to work environment amongst the employees of National Petrochemical Company</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email>aliye1366@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Organizations have long been devoting significant financial resources to organizing organizational training. But the development of human resources is not achieved by conducting general and specialized training. Today, training is expected to provide the desired behavioral changes in the staff. Studies show that many educational programs do not create desirable behavioral changes in the staff. This means that employees are not able to transfer their learning to their work environment. The effectiveness of training is heavily reliant on the assumptions that occur in its transmission to the workplace. Therefore, one of the best ways to achieve educational effectiveness is to increase the transfer rate of education. Therefore, in this research, we have identified factors affecting the transfer of education. The research method was a survey and the statistical population included500 people who participated in the courses of Petrochemical Research and Technology Company in three cities of Tehran, Arak and Mahshahr. Among them, 217&#160; persons were selected through stratified random sampling method.&#160; In the research process, 27&#160; factors influencing the transfer of education were identified by reviewing the related literature. By implementing three stages of Delphi technique, these factors decreased to 18&#160; factors. Then, for identifying facilitating and preventing factors of transfer of training, a questionnaire was developed with 62&#160; items. The results showed that of among the 18&#160; identified factors, 7 factors were weak as facilitators, 9&#160; factors were considered as weak barriers, one factor as a strong barrier and one factor as a strong facilitator in this organization. Also, the results of exploratory factor analysis showed that the factors related to the transfer of training were grouped in five levels: individual, supportive, educational, reward system and progression, which resulted in the presentation of a new typology of factors influencing the transfer of training.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Transfer of training</keyword>
	<keyword>facilitation and barrier factors</keyword>
	<keyword>Petrochemical Research and Technology Organization.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>99</first_page>
								  <last_page>122</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-75-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>7-76</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</full_title>
									<abbrev_title></abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2251-8886</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-4409</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>8</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>30</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Presentation of a framework for reward payments based on the performance using BSC-ANP approach in the Iranian Oil Terminal Company</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email>rahimi2053@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The present study was carried out to Presentation of a framework for reward payments based on the performance in the Iranian Oil Terminal Company. This research is considered applicable in terms of purpose, in terms of data collection is Descriptive-survey. In this study, after reviewing literature and interviews with senior managers of company and identifying evaluation criteria's, map of network relationships in order to distributing reward in units and sections of organization has been introduced as a native framework. In addition, has been used BSC-ANP approach to ranking criteria and alternatives (organization units) in order to distribute the rewards. The results show that among the units of company &#34;loading and export operations&#34; and &#34;naval operation&#34; are more important than other units. Also section of &#34;main processes&#34; with an average ratio of 8% has first priority in reward payment. Represented framework makes reward payment in relation to performance evaluation of employee examined in various dimensions and come out of steady state.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Reward</keyword>
	<keyword>Analytic Network Process</keyword>
	<keyword>Balance Scorecard</keyword>
	<keyword>Iranian Oil Terminals Company</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>123</first_page>
								  <last_page>143</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-76-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>7-77</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</full_title>
									<abbrev_title></abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2251-8886</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-4409</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>8</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>30</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Investigating the Mediating Role of Leader-Member Exchange (LMX) in Direct and Indirect Relationship of Ethical Climate with Role Stress in Staff Employees of National Iranian Oil Company (NIOC)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email>m_myegane@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Nowadays, ethical and moral values observance is the major and effective factor on the attitudes and behaviors of employees in the workplace. The aim of this research is investigating the mediating role of leader-member exchange in the direct and indirect relationship between ethical climate with role stress. This research is a correlational study. The statistical population is all the staff employees of National Iranian Oil Company (NIOC). The participants of this study include 300 employees who were selected by stratified random sampling method. The instruments used in this study were Ethical Climate, Role Stress, and Leader-Member Exchange Questionnaires. Data were analyzed by Pearson correlation and Structural Equation Modeling (SEM). Structural equation modeling analyses indicated that the proposed model fits the data properly. The results supported the direct relationship of ethical climate and role stress and also this relationship was mediated through the leader-member exchange.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Ethical Climate</keyword>
	<keyword>Role Stress</keyword>
	<keyword>Leader-Member Exchange (LMX).</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>145</first_page>
								  <last_page>160</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-77-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>7-78</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</full_title>
									<abbrev_title></abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">2251-8886</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic">2588-4409</issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>8</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>30</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>The Factors Affecting the Organizational Belonging of Personnel in Kermanshah Province Gas Company and presenting a Conceptual Model for its Evaluation</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Hamidreza</given_name>
					<surname>Jalilian</surname>
					<email>h_jalalian@pnu.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Morteza</given_name>
					<surname>Morady</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Ali</given_name>
					<surname>Morady</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Jamal</given_name>
					<surname>Fatahi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			With regard to the chaos and competitive environment of organizations, managers do not have much time to control employees, hence, motivated, conscientious, committed and belongs employees to the organization are the most important competitive advantage in organizations . Several factors such as individual factors and organizational factors have been considered&#160; as the consequences for the organization belonging precedence and are listed in different sources; The present study sought to evaluate the impact of individual and organizational factors on the organization belonging and the consequences of it and eventually belonging enterprise operational model. This research is considered a descriptive- survey, and on basis of purpose is a developmental -applied research. The statistical population was 480 employees of Kermanshah Province Gas Company that 288 persons were selected as sample. Path analysis was used to analyze the data. Test results showed that organizational factors affect belonging and its consequences, but the impact of individual factors were not confirmed. It was also found that organizational belonging is most effective to organizational outcomes.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>organizational belonging organizational factorspersonal factors Gas Companies</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>161</first_page>
								  <last_page>185</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-78-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
			
		</ListRecords>
		</OAI-PMH>
		 
  
  
  
  
 