<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.0//EN" "http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov:80/entrez/query/static/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2251-8886</Issn>
<Volume>8</Volume>
<Issue>32</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>9</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Designing of Competency model for knowledge workers in RIPI</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>3</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>24</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Jabbar</FirstName>
	<LastName>Babashahi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hamidreza</FirstName>
	<LastName>Yazdani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Reza</FirstName>
	<LastName>Tahmasebi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ebrahim</FirstName>
	<LastName>Rajab Pour</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Human capital is the most important competitive advantage in the twenty-first century. In other words, organizations gain a competitive advantage in the marketplace, if they could attract the best knowledge workers, develop and retain them. Competencies paradigm is a new approach to integrate the system to achieve this goal. As well, Research Institute of Petroleum Industry (RIPI) as a knowledge-based organization needs to empower knowledge workers in order to fulfill the objectives of the research and development of the oil industry. This study aimed to identify and design the competency model of knowledge workers in the three categories of researchers, scientific boards and managers. Strategy of this study has been case study and the method of data analysis has been theme technique. The study population groups were included outstanding managers, experts&#8217; researchers, faculty members and consultants.
Interviews were conducted with them by using purposive sampling and snowball to the point of saturation. Based on the research findings, competency models were classified into different categories of knowledge workers in the two sets of basic competencies and core competencies. Also, core competencies was divided in three main categories including knowledge workers &#34;individual characteristics&#34;, &#34;knowledge&#34; and &#34;skill&#34;. Each of these main categories was made up of numerous competencies.</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2251-8886</Issn>
<Volume>8</Volume>
<Issue>32</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>9</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Selection of strategic alternatives for human resources development in oil industry by using MADM techniques</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>25</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>50</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Aliyeh</FirstName>
	<LastName>Kazemi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Fatemeh</FirstName>
	<LastName>Saadat Ahmadnia</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>The significance of human resources and their development in the progress of communities and organizations are of utmost importance. Managers should adopt the correct and optimized strategies for development of human resources as the most important factor in providing quality and efficiency in public and business organizations and eventually the major foundation of economical, social and cultural development. In the present study, the strategic alternatives of human resources development in oil industry of Iran have been investigated using several different multi-attribute decision making methods including AHP, SAW, TOPSIS and ELECTRE. For this purpose, eleven strategic alternatives have been specified by experts and prioritized based on the four following factors: time, cost, staff resistance and manager acceptance. Ultimately, Borda&#8217;s method has been used for final ranking and combination of the strategic alternatives. The results showed that stratic choices including right planning, job turnover, increasing salaris and compensates have the higher priority.</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2251-8886</Issn>
<Volume>8</Volume>
<Issue>32</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>9</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Designing a Talent Excellence Model Using Systematic Literature Review and Qualitative Meta Synthesis in Isfahan province Gas Company</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>51</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>84</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Farzaneh</FirstName>
	<LastName>Soltani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Arash</FirstName>
	<LastName>Shahin</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<LastName>Shaemi Barzoki</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>This study has been considered to design a talent excellence model. Despite the common sense of excellence in the field of human resources and various awards at national level and organizational studies, comprehensive studies in the field of talent excellence have not been carried out. A systematic review and meta-synthesis of qualitative research have been used as the corresponding approach in this study to analyze the results and findings of previous researchers; and with the seven steps of this method, talent excellence model has been examined and classified in the 8 criteria, 30 sub-criteria. For quality control in qualitative meta-synthesis in this study, the GASP and kappa method has been used. Based on a scale of 50 points of CASP, selected articles were evaluated in terms of quality. For assessing the reliability of designed model, the Kappa index was used. Kappa index value was calculated 0.7477 showing that it has been at the valid level of agreement. Finally, in order to confirm the model in the Gas Company of Isfahan Province, we interviewed with the managers and experts of the Gas Company and analyzed the finding by the method of thematic analysis. Also, using the relative coefficient of CVI and CVR, the validity of the logical content of the model was confirmed according to university professors.</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2251-8886</Issn>
<Volume>8</Volume>
<Issue>32</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>9</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Identfying and ranking the effective factors in knowledge sharing between the counterpart organizations (Case study: Petrochemical Industry)</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>85</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>116</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Navid</FirstName>
	<LastName>Nezafati</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Nasim</FirstName>
	<LastName>Ganbar Tehrani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Shifra</FirstName>
	<LastName>Davari</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>One of the main elements of the knowledge management, is sharing the knowledge inside the organization or with the other organizations which has some advantages such as: access to the competitive knowledge, achieving value and synergy, and not sharing the knowledge in the industries, especially petrochemical industry, in which the active companies require high amount of knowledge for the execution of different projects, will result in the waste of capital, impose of extra costs and the reduction of productivity. So, the goal of this research has been the identification and ranking the effective factors in knowledge sharing in the counterpart organizations. In order to achieve this goal, the library studies were conducted and the factors related to the owner and gainer of the knowledge, the content factors, the cooperation base factors and the technology infrastructures factors, were identified. For explaining the effectiveness of the factors, field studies were conducted in this research by a 25-questions questionnaire. After distributing and gathering the questionnaires, its factor validity and reliability was calculated by SPSS software. At the next step, for explaining the effectiveness of the factors, the single-sample t-test was used and determined that all factors were effective. Then, by using Friedman test, the effective factors were rated, and the cultural and suitable environment of the organization that gains the knowledge was ranked in the first, and the amount of the ambiguity in the knowledge was ranked in the last.</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2251-8886</Issn>
<Volume>8</Volume>
<Issue>32</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>9</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Investigating the influence of knowledge management practices on the psychological empowerment of human resources by moderating role of demographic variables in Iranian Central Oil Fields Company (I. C. O. F. C)</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>117</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>148</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Sirous</FirstName>
	<LastName>AmirGhodsi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<LastName>Maleki</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<LastName>Bonyadi Naeeni</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammas Javad</FirstName>
	<LastName>Esfandiari</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Psychological empowerment is one of the useful tools for improving the effectiveness of the organization's staff and their quality. Psychological empowerment is affected by numerous factors including knowledge management. The present research investigated the impact of knowledge management practices on the psychological empowerment of human resources by moderating role of demographic variables in Iranian Central Oil Fields Company (I. C. O. F. C). The method in this study insisted applied-developing research method and on the other hand, descriptive-survey. The goal population has been the Company&#8217;s staff of ICOFC including 5480 employees. By Cochran&#8217;s formula 359 employees have randomly been selected. Standardized questionnaires including: Knowledge management of Khaki and psychological empowerment of human resources of have been used. The reliability of questionnaires proved by Cronbach&#8217;s Alpha that for the variables of knowledge management and psychological empowerment were 0.903 and 0.884, respectively. The results showed that knowledge management has an effect on psychological empowerment and its components. The effect&#8217;s intensity of knowledge management on psychological empowerment's components has been 0.788, 0.772, 0.754, 0.742, and 0.703 respectively for sense of trust, sense of efficacy, sence of competency, sense of self-determination, and sense of meaning. The partial correlation test results showed that there is no moderating role for demographic variables in the relationship between knowledge management and the psychological empowerment.</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2251-8886</Issn>
<Volume>8</Volume>
<Issue>32</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>9</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Factors affecting retention of knowledge workers with the aim of developing work life quality plans at the Institute For International Energy Studies</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>149</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>176</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Vajhollah</FirstName>
	<LastName>Ghorbanizadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mehdi</FirstName>
	<LastName>Kheir Andish</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Azam</FirstName>
	<LastName>Adnan Rad</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Today, knowledge workers are the most important assets of organizations and managers should make efforts to maintain these employees. Considering the importance of this issue, this paper investigated the maintenance of knowledge workers, using an approach to develop the work life quality. In order to design the conceptual model, some previous studies have been exploited to select the variables. The main question has been whether the improvement of knowledge workers&#8217; work life quality affects their persistence. In order to answer this question, a questionnaire was distributed among a random sample of 66 knowledge workers of the Institute for International Energy Studies , and collected data were analyzed using structural equation modeling. Findings indicated that there is a significantly direct relationship between the development of job factors of work life quality and the persistence of knowledge workers.</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2251-8886</Issn>
<Volume>8</Volume>
<Issue>32</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>9</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Identification and evaluation of projects knowledge management infrastructures in project-based organizations of Iranian oil & gas industry in upstream</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>177</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>204</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad Javad</FirstName>
	<LastName>Salehi Taleshi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mojtaba</FirstName>
	<LastName>Hosseinali Pour</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hani</FirstName>
	<LastName>Arbabi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>The purpose of this research is identification, evaluation and comparing the reality of &#34;projects knowledge management infrastructures&#34; in some project-based organizations of iranian oil &#38; gas industry in upstream. Applying &#160;quantitative method and survey strategy, projects knowledge management infrastructures in project-based organizations of iranian oil &#38; gas industry in upstream were monitored. Khnowledg management infrastructure questionnaires were completed in 41 upstream organizations in oil &#38; gas industry of Iran. Results showed that among infrastructures, &#34;organizational culture&#34; and &#34;human resource&#34; had the highest score and &#34;structure&#34; had the lowest score. Consulting organizations, general contractor, construction management, design-build contractor, and employer ranked consequently, one to five in terms of suitability of knowledge management structures. From a public and private perspective, private organizations ranked first and then semi-private and public organizations in the next place in terms of knowledge management infrastructure. But none of these two rankings were statistically significant.</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
<Issn>2251-8886</Issn>
<Volume>8</Volume>
<Issue>32</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>9</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Investigating the mediating role of knowledge absorptive capacity on relationship between human resource management policies and organizational performance
(Case Study: Qom Province Gas Company)
</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>205</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>232</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad Taghi</FirstName>
	<LastName>Sadeghi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Farzad</FirstName>
	<LastName>Movahedi Sobhani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<LastName>Rajab Zadeh Ghatari</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hossein</FirstName>
	<LastName>Shirazi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Today, employees are the main capital of each organization that enables them to improve their competitive performance by utilizing their competent human resources. In this way, Training and development of competent human resources have been related to organizational performance in implementing human resource management policies, effectively, to be a base of creating creativity and innovation in organization. In other ways, in rapid changing markets, knowledge and knowledge absorption capability have a critical role in creating innovation opportunities and competitive advantage of companies. Given the importance of this issue in the gas company the purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of HRM policies on organizational performance and explain the mediating role of knowledge absorptive capacity in this regard. The statistical population of the research is all Official staff of Qom Gas Company that 85 of them participated in this survey based on Cochran's formula. Three questionnaires (HRM policies, organizational performance and knowledge absorptive capacity) were used to collect data. Validity of the questionnaire was verified formally and contently. Reliability was gained by calculating the Cronbach's value of 0.87. The analyzes were performed by using the LISREL software to evaluate the structural equation model. Findings indicate that there is a positive and significant relationship between research variables and knowledge absorption capability in the relationship between HRM and organizational performance has a mediating role.</Abstract>


</Article>
</ArticleSet>
