<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1396</YEAR>
<VOL>8</VOL>
<NO>32</NO>
<MOSALSAL>32</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>232</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>طراحی مدل شایستگی کارکنان دانشی در 
پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت
</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Designing of Competency model for knowledge workers in RIPI</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>مهمترین مزیت رقابتی سازمان&#8204;ها در قرن بیست و یکم، سرمایه&#8204;های انسانی است. به&#8204;عبارتی، مزیت رقابتی نصیب سازمان&#8204;هایی خواهد شد که بتوانند در بازار رقابتی، بهترین کارکنان دانشی را جذب نموده، پرورش داده و نگه دارند. متدولوژی شایستگی&#8204;ها، دیدگاه جدیدی برای یکپارچه&#8204;سازی این نظام می&#8204;باشد. پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت نیز به&#8204;عنوان سازمانی دانش&#8204;مدار در راستای تحقق اهداف تحقیق و توسعه&#8204;ای صنعت نفت، نیازمند مبرم به کارکنان دانشی و توانمند می&#8204;باشد. هدف پژوهش حاضر، شناسایی و طراحی مدل شایستگی کارکنان دانشی در سه رده پژوهشگری، هیأت علمی و مدیریتی می&#8204;باشد. روش تحقیق مطالعه موردی و شیوه تحلیل داده&#8204;ها تحلیل تم است. جامعه آماری پژوهش را گروه&#8204;های مختلف&#160; از قبیل مدیران برجسته، کارشناسان و پژوهشگران، اعضای هیأت علمی و مشاوران پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت تشکیل داده&#8204;اند که با استفاده از نمونه گیری هدفمند و گلوله برفی مصاحبه&#8204;ها تا حد اشباع با آنان انجام شد. بر اساس یافته&#8204;های پژوهش، مدل شایستگی رده&#8204;های مختلف کارکنان دانشی در دو دسته از شایستگی&#8204;های پایه&#8204;ای و شایستگی&#8204;های محوری دسته&#8204;بندی گردید. همچنین، شایستگی&#8204;های محوری هر رده از کارکنان دانشی در سه مقوله اصلی &#171;ویژگی&#8204;های فردی&#187;، &#171;دانش&#187; و &#171;مهارت&#187; تقسیم&#8204;بندی شد. هر کدام از این مقوله&#8204;های اصلی خود از شایستگی&#8204;های متعددی تشکیل شده&#8204;اند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Human capital is the most important competitive advantage in the twenty-first century. In other words, organizations gain a competitive advantage in the marketplace, if they could attract the best knowledge workers, develop and retain them. Competencies paradigm is a new approach to integrate the system to achieve this goal. As well, Research Institute of Petroleum Industry (RIPI) as a knowledge-based organization needs to empower knowledge workers in order to fulfill the objectives of the research and development of the oil industry. This study aimed to identify and design the competency model of knowledge workers in the three categories of researchers, scientific boards and managers. Strategy of this study has been case study and the method of data analysis has been theme technique. The study population groups were included outstanding managers, experts&#8217; researchers, faculty members and consultants.
Interviews were conducted with them by using purposive sampling and snowball to the point of saturation. Based on the research findings, competency models were classified into different categories of knowledge workers in the two sets of basic competencies and core competencies. Also, core competencies was divided in three main categories including knowledge workers &#34;individual characteristics&#34;, &#34;knowledge&#34; and &#34;skill&#34;. Each of these main categories was made up of numerous competencies.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>3</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>24</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>جبار</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>باباشاهی</Family>
				<NameE>Jabbar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Babashahi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حمیدرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>یزدانی</Family>
				<NameE>Hamidreza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Yazdani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>رضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>طهماسبی</Family>
				<NameE>Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Tahmasebi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>ابراهیم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رجب پور</Family>
				<NameE>Ebrahim</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rajab Pour</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>eirajabpour@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>knowledge worker</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>competency</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>competencies of knowledge workers</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>RIPI</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کارکنان دانشی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شایستگی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شایستگی های کارکنان دانشی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Agut, S., &amp; Grau, R. (2002). Managerial competency needs and training requests: The case of the Spanish tourist industry. Human Resource Development Quarterly, 13(1), 31.##Boyatzis, Richard E. (2008): Competencies in the 21st century. In  Journal of Mgmt Development 27 (1), pp. 5–12. ##Çizel, B., Anafarta, N., &amp; Sarvan, F. (2007). An analysis of managerial competency needs in the tourism sector: the case of Turkey. Tourism Review, 62(2), 14-22.##Claussen; J; Grohsjean, T; Luger, J; Probst, G. (2013). Talent management and career development: What it takes to get promoted. Journal of World Business, Volume 49, Issue 2, Pages 236-244.##Dubois,  David  D.;  Rothwell,  William  J.  (2004). The  competency  toolkit. Amherst, Mass.: HRD Press.##Drucker, P. F. (1999). Knowledge-worker productivity: The biggest challenge. California management review, 41(2), 79-94.##Ennis, M. R. (2008). Competency models: a review of the literature and the role of the employment and training administration (ETA) (pp. 1-25). Office of Policy Development and Research, Employment and Training Administration, US Department of Labor.## Hammer, M., Leonard, D., &amp; Davenport, T. (2004). Why don't we know more about knowledge? MIT Sloan Management Review, 17-18.##Heidary Dahooie, J., Afrazeh, A., &amp; Mohammad Moathar Hosseini, S. (2011). An activity-based framework for quantification of knowledge work.Journal of Knowledge Management, 15(3), 422-444. ##Horwitz, F. M., Heng, C. T., &amp; Quazi, H. A. (2003). Finders, keepers? Attracting, motivating and retaining knowledge workers. Human resource management journal, 13(4), 23-44.##Kelloway, E. K., &amp; Barling, J. (2000). Knowledge work as organizational behavior. International journal of management reviews, 2(3), 287-304.##Loufrani-Fedida, S., &amp; Missonier, S. (2015). The project manager cannot be a hero anymore! Understanding critical competencies in project-based organizations from a multilevel approach. International Journal of Project Management, 33(6), 1220-1235.## Ramírez, Y. W., &amp; Nembhard, D. A. (2004). Measuring knowledge worker productivity: A taxonomy. Journal of intellectual capital, 5(4), 602-628.##Reinhardt, W., Schmidt, B., Sloep, P., &amp; Drachsler, H. (2011). Knowledge worker roles and actions—results of two empirical studies. Knowledge and Process Management, 18(3), 150-174.##Torres, P., &amp; Augusto, M. (2016). The impact of experiential learning on managers’ strategic competencies and decision style. Journal of Innovation &amp; Knowledge.##افخمی اردکانی، مهدی؛ باباشاهی، جبار؛ یزدانی، حمیدرضا؛ طهماسبی، رضا. (1395). ارائه ابزاری جهت شناسایی و سنجش مشاغل دانشی؛ پژوهشی با رویکرد آمیخته. فصلنامه پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع سازمانی. در دست انتشار.##دانش فرد، کرم‌اله. (1385). اداره اثربخش سازمان‌های دانایی‌محور. ماهنامه تدبیر، شماره 174، ص. 18.##دهقانان، حامد. (1385). مدیریت بر مبنای شایستگی (ضرورت‌ها و راهکارها). فصلنامه مجلس و راهبرد، سال سیزدهم، شماره 53، ص. 117.##رضایت، غلامحسین؛ یمنی دوزی سرخابی، محمد؛ کیامنش، علیرضا؛ نوه ابراهیم، عبدالرضا. (1390). طراحی الگوی شایستگی‌های روسای دانشگاه‌های دولتی ایران. مجله آموطش عالی، سال چهارم، شماره 1 (پیاپی 13)، ص. 47.##نجفی، اسداله؛ افرازه، عباس؛ فاطمی قمی، سید محمدنقی. (1389). ارائه روشی تلفیقی برای اندازه‌گیری و پیش‌بینی بهره‌وری دانش‌کاران مبتنی بر تکنیک سری‌های زمانی؛ مورد کاوری شرکت پارس خودرو. پژوهشنامه پردازش و مدیریت اطلاعات،سال بیست و ششم، شماره 2 (پیاپی 64)، ص. 301.  ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>انتخاب گزینه‌های استراتژیک توسعه منابع انسانی با استفاده از روش‌های تصمیم‌گیری چندشاخصه  
(مورد مطالعه: صنعت نفت)
</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Selection of strategic alternatives for human resources development in oil industry by using MADM techniques</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>اهمیت منابع انسانی و توسعه آن در پیشرفت سازمان&#8204;ها و جوامع بر کسی پوشیده نیست. مدیران برای توسعه این منابع به عنوان مهم&#8204;ترین عامل تأمین کیفیت و بهره&#8204;وری در سازمان&#8204;های دولتی و بازرگانی و زیربنای اصلی توسعه اقتصادی، اجتماعی و فرهنگی باید استراتژی&#8204;های صحیح و بهینه را اتخاذ کنند. در این مقاله با استفاده از روش&#8204;های مختلف تصمیم&#8204;گیری چندشاخصه شامل روش&#8204;های AHP، SAW، TOPSIS و ELECTRE، گزینه&#8204;های استراتژیک توسعه منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت کشور بررسی شده است. به این منظور، یازده گزینه استراتژیک برای توسعه منابع انسانی توسط خبرگان تعیین شده و این گزینه&#8204;ها تحت تأثیر چهار شاخص زمان، هزینه، مقاومت کارکنان و مقبولیت مدیر اولویت&#8204;بندی شده&#8204;اند. از روش بردا برای تلفیق و رتبه&#8204;بندی نهایی گزینه&#8204;های استراتژیک استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان داد گزینه&#8204;های استراتژیک برنامه&#8204;ریزی درست و اصولی، گردش شغلی و جابجایی کارکنان، افزایش حقوق و تسهیلات کارکنان در یک بازه زمانی از اولویت بالاتری برخوردار هستند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The significance of human resources and their development in the progress of communities and organizations are of utmost importance. Managers should adopt the correct and optimized strategies for development of human resources as the most important factor in providing quality and efficiency in public and business organizations and eventually the major foundation of economical, social and cultural development. In the present study, the strategic alternatives of human resources development in oil industry of Iran have been investigated using several different multi-attribute decision making methods including AHP, SAW, TOPSIS and ELECTRE. For this purpose, eleven strategic alternatives have been specified by experts and prioritized based on the four following factors: time, cost, staff resistance and manager acceptance. Ultimately, Borda&#8217;s method has been used for final ranking and combination of the strategic alternatives. The results showed that stratic choices including right planning, job turnover, increasing salaris and compensates have the higher priority.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>25</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>50</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عالیه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کاظمی</Family>
				<NameE>Aliyeh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Kazemi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>aliyehkazemi@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فاطمه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سعادت احمدنیا</Family>
				<NameE>Fatemeh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Saadat Ahmadnia</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>development of human resources</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>multi attribute decision making</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>AHP</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>SAW</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>TOPSIS</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ELECTRE</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Borda’s Method.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>توسعه منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تصمیم‌گیری چندشاخصه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>AHP</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>SAW</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>TOPSIS</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ELECTRE</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>روش بردا</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Adhikari, D.R., (2010), Human resource development (HRD) for performance management, International Journal of Productivity and Performance Management, 59(4), 306 – 324.##    Hoque, Z., James, W., (2000). Linking the balanced scorecard measures to size and market factors: impact on organizational performance. Journal of Management Accounting Research.  12(1), 1-17.##    Kwak, N.K., McCarthy, K.J., Gerald E. Parker, G.E., (1997). A Human Resource Planning Model for Hospital/Medical Technologists: An Analytic Hierarchy Process Approach, Journal of Medical Systems, 21(3), 173-187. ##    Matsuo, M., (2015). Human resource development programs for knowledge transfer and creation: the case of the Toyota Technical Development Corporation, Journal of Knowledge Management, 19(6), 1186 – 1203.##    Otley, D., (1999). Performance Management: A framework for management control systems research. Management Accounting Research, 10(2) 363-382.##    Truss, C., Gratton, L., (1994). Strategic Human Resource Management, The International Journal of HRM, 43.##    Wright, P., Macmahon, G., (1992). Theoretical Perspective for SHRM; Journal of Management, 18.##آذر، عادل. رﺟﺐزاده، علی. (1389). ﺗﺼﻤﯿﻢﮔﯿﺮی ﮐﺎرﺑﺮدی رویﮑﺮد MADM‬، ﺗﻬﺮان: اﻧﺘﺸﺎرات ﻧﮕﺎه داﻧﺶ، چاپ چهارم، صفحات 59-79.##    ابطحی، سیدحسین. موسوی، سیدمحمد. (1388). تدوین استراتژی های منابع انسانی (مطالعه موردی: یکی از سازمان‌های معنوی کشور)، فصلنامه پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی دانشگاه جامع امام حسین(ع)، شماره 3، صفحات 1-23. ##    ابیلی، خدایار. ابوالعلایی، بهزاد. انصاری‌رنانی، قاسم. جزئی، نسرین. طباطبایی، سیداحمد. گودرزی، علی‌محمد. نظاری، محمود. (1382). توسعه منابع انسانی؛ چالش‌ها و راهکارها، مجله تدبیر، شماره133، صفحه ‌14. ##    اﺻﻐﺮﭘﻮر، ﻣﺤﻤﺪﺟﻮاد. (1390)، ﺗﺼﻤﻴﻢﮔﻴﺮیﻫﺎی ﭼﻨﺪﻣﻌﻴﺎره، تهران: اﻧﺘﺸﺎرات داﻧﺸﮕﺎه ﺗﻬﺮان، چاپ دهم، صفحه 260.##    اعرابی، سیدﻣﺤﻤﺪ. ایزدی، داود. (1381)، مدیریت استراتژیک منابع انسانی (راهنمای عمل)، خلاصه کتاب مایکل آرمسترانگ، دفتر پژوهش‌های فرهنگی، صفحه 10.##    تونکه‌نژاد، ماندنی. داوری، علی (1388)، توسعه منابع انسانی با رویکرد جامعه-شناختی سازمان، فصلنامه پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی دانشگاه جامع امام حسین(ع)، سال اول، شماره 3، صفحات 51-80.##    جزنی، نسرین. طاهری، نادر. ابیلی، خدایار (1389)، تدوین راهبردهای توسعه منابع انسانی با رویکرد توسعه دانش کارکنان، مطالعات مدیریت راهبردی، شماره 2، صفحات 15-29.##    حقیقت، فاطمه (1386)، استفاده از روش فرایند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی در برنامه‌ریزی استراتژیک توسعه منابع انسانی، دومین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت استراتژیک، صفحات 3 و 7 .##    حقیقت، فاطمه (1387)، استفاده از تکنیک‌های ELECTRE و TOPSIS جهت مطالعه موردی ارزیابی و اولویت‌بندی استراتژی‌های توسعه منابع انسانی شرکت نفت، ششمین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت، صفحه 3.##    سلطانی،ایرج. (1377)، نقش توسعه منابع انسانی در ارتقای بهره‌وری سازمان‌ها، مدیریت دولتی، شماره 39. صفحات 59-67.##    علیرضائی، ابوتراب. امینی، امین. (1388)، سروکوال و فرایند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی ابزارهایی مناسب برای سنجش و اولویت بندی کیفیت خدمات آموزشی در صنعت نفت، مدیریت و منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، شماره 9. صفحات 159-180.##    قلیچ‌لی، بهروز. توکلی، فهیمه. (1389)، تعالی منابع انسانی: ارزیابی، برنامه‌ریزی و بهبود، تهران، نشر سرامد، صفحه 27.##    کافی، بهروز. توکلی، فهیمه. (1385)، نگرشی بر مدیریت منابع انسانی، تهران ، انتشارات فرازاندیش سبز، صفحات 28-32.##    مبارک‌آبادی، هوشنگ. (1385)، نقش دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی در توسعه منابع انسانی، همایش عملکرد 25 ساله دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، همدان، صفحه 183.##    مشایخ، فریده. (1381)، دیدگاه‌های نو در برنامه‌ریزی آموزشی، تهران، انتشارات سمت. صفحه 76.##    مهرگان، محمدرضا. (1383)، پژوهش عملیاتی پیشرفته، نشر کتاب دانشگاهی، چاپ اول، صفحه 165.##    میرسپاسی، امیر. (1381)، مدیریت استراتژیک منابع انسانی و روابط کار، تهران ، انتشارات میر، صفحات 4-32.##    نصیری، محمدتقی. حیدری، محمد. شهبازی، سارا. انصاری، اسماعیل. (1392)، همبستگی استراتژی های منابع انسانی براساس الگوی آلن یلسی با عملکرد سازمانی کارکنان بیمارستان آیت‌اله کاشانی شهرکرد، مدیریت ارتقای سلامت، دوره 2، شماره 3، صفحات 36-44. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>طراحی الگوی تعالی استعداد با استفاده از رویکرد مرور سیستماتیک و فراترکیب کیفی در شرکت گاز استان اصفهان
 

</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Designing a Talent Excellence Model Using Systematic Literature Review and Qualitative Meta Synthesis in Isfahan province Gas Company</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در این پژوهش به طراحی مدل سرآمدی استعداد پرداخته شده است. علی رغم رایج بودن مفهوم تعالی و سرآمدی در حوزه منابع انسانی و وجود جوایز مختلف در سطح ملی و سازمانی، تاکنون مطالعات جامع و مانع در حوزه سرآمدی استعداد انجام نشده است. محقق با بکارگیری رویکرد مرور سیستماتیک و فراترکیب کیفی در این پژوهش به تحلیل نتایج و یافته های محققین قبلی پرداخته و با انجام گام های هفت گانه این روش مدل تعالی استعداد را در 8 معیار، 30 زیر معیار طبقه بندی کرده است. برای کنترل کیفیت روش فراترکیب کیفی در روند این پژوهش از دو روش GASP و کاپا استفاده شده است. بر اساس مقیاس 50 امتیازی CASP روبریک، مقالات انتخاب شده از لحاظ کیفیت مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفتند. همچنین به منظور سنجش پایایی مدل طراحی شده از شاخص کاپا استفاده شد. مقدار شاخص کاپا برابر با 0.7477 محاسبه شد که در سطح توافق معتبر قرار گرفته است. در نهایت برای تایید مدل در شرکت گاز استان اصفهان با مدیران و خبرگان شرکت گاز مصاحبه شد و با روش تحلیل تماتیک مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. روایی محتوای منطقی مدل نیز توسط اساتید دانشگاهی با استفاده از ضریب نسبی CVI و CVR تایید شد .
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>This study has been considered to design a talent excellence model. Despite the common sense of excellence in the field of human resources and various awards at national level and organizational studies, comprehensive studies in the field of talent excellence have not been carried out. A systematic review and meta-synthesis of qualitative research have been used as the corresponding approach in this study to analyze the results and findings of previous researchers; and with the seven steps of this method, talent excellence model has been examined and classified in the 8 criteria, 30 sub-criteria. For quality control in qualitative meta-synthesis in this study, the GASP and kappa method has been used. Based on a scale of 50 points of CASP, selected articles were evaluated in terms of quality. For assessing the reliability of designed model, the Kappa index was used. Kappa index value was calculated 0.7477 showing that it has been at the valid level of agreement. Finally, in order to confirm the model in the Gas Company of Isfahan Province, we interviewed with the managers and experts of the Gas Company and analyzed the finding by the method of thematic analysis. Also, using the relative coefficient of CVI and CVR, the validity of the logical content of the model was confirmed according to university professors.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>51</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>84</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فرزانه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سلطانی</Family>
				<NameE>Farzaneh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Soltani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه اصفهان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>اصفهان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>آرش</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شاهین</Family>
				<NameE>Arash</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shahin</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه اصفهان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>اصفهان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>shahin@ase.ui.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شائمی برزکی</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shaemi Barzoki</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه اصفهان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>اصفهان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Excellence</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>talent</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Systematic review</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Meta-synthesis</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سرآمدی (تعالی)</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>استعداد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مرور سیستماتیک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فراترکیب</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Bhatnagar, J. (2008), ‘Managing Capabilities for Talent Engagement and Pipeline Deveopment,’ Industrial and Commercial Training, 40, 19–28.##Bohmer, N., &amp; Scinnenburg, H. (2016). How gender and career concepts impact Global Talent Management. HR, Learning &amp; Organization Studies , 73-93.##Beck, C.(2002), “Mothering multiples: A meta–synthesis of the qualitative research”. The American Journal of Maternal /Child ,Nursing, 28(2):p93-99##Collings, D. G., &amp; Mellahi, K. (2009). Strategic talent management: A review and research agenda. Human Resource Management Review , 304–313##Finfgeld, D, L.,(2003). “Meta synthesis: The state of the art—so far”. Qualitative Health Research, 13(7): p893-904##Foster, C. (2015). Managing the flow of talent through organizations – a boundary-less model. Development and Learning in Organizations: An International Journal.##Gumus,S., Apak,S., Gumus,H., Kurban.,Z.(2013),An application in human resources management for meeting Differentiation and innovativeness requirements of business: talent Management. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences##Gallardo, E., Dries, N., &amp; Cruz, T. (2013). what is the meaning of talent in the word of work? Human Resource Management Review, 290-300.##Hall GM. How to write a paper. 3th ed. London: BMJ publishing group; 2003. p.92-98.##Jensen, L, A and Allen..(1996), “Meta-synthesis of qualitative findings”, Qualitative Health Research,6(4):p553–560##King, K. A. (2015). Global talent management: Introducing a strategic framework and multiple-actors model. Journal of Global Mobility: The Home of Expatriate Management Research.##Mensah, J. K. (2015). A “coalesced framework” of talent management and employee performance: For further research and practice. International Journal of Productivity and Performance Management.##Noblit, G, W and R, D, Hare.(1998), “Meta–Ethnography: Synthesizing qualitative studies”. Newbury Park, CA: Stage##Okoli, C., &amp; Schabram, K. (2010). A Guide to Conducting a Systematic Literature Review of Information Systems Research. Working Papers on Information Systems.##Phillips, 1. 1. (2005). Investing in Your Company's Human Capital. United States of America: AMACOM in Brandt##Phillips, R., and Roper, O.(2009). A framework for talent management in real estate: Emerald Group, Journal of Corporate Real Estate, Vol. 11 No. 1, 2009,  pp. 7-16##Schiemann, W. A., Seibert, J. H., &amp; Morgan, B. S. (2013). Hidden drivers of success:Leveraging employee insights for strategic advantage. Alexandria, VA: Society for Human Resource Management##Sandelowski, M and J, Barroso.(2007), “Handbook for synthesizing qualitative research”,New York, NY: Springer##Thunnissen, M., Boselie, P., &amp; Fruytier, B. (2016).Talent management and the relevance of context: Towards a pluralistic approach. Human Resource Management Review (in this issue)##ابزری, م., شاهین, آ و محمدشفیعی, م. (1390). حاکمیت مؤلفه های تعالی بر اساس مدل EFQM - مطالعه موردی یک گروه صنعتی . مدیریت تولید و عملیات.19-36##باباییان، علی. رضایی، نسرین. نظری، کامران.(1395). بررسی و تحلیل رابطۀ مدیریت استعداد با عملکرد کارکنان ناجا (مورد مطالعه؛ فرماندهی انتظامی شهرستان کرمانشاه).فصلنامه منابع انسانی ناجا##حاجی زاده، ابراهیم. اصغری ،محمد.(1390). روش ها وتحلیل آماری با نگاه به روش تحقیق در علوم زیستی و بهداشتی. انتشارات جهاد دانشگاهی . چاپ اول##عرب پور، علیرضا. نیک پور،امین. (1394) تاثیر ابعاد مدیریت استعداد بر بهره‌وری نیروی انسانی در سازمانهای دولتی شهر کرمان. پژوهش های مدیریت منابع انسانی سال هفتم بهار 1394 شماره 1 (پیاپی 19) ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>شناسایی و تبیین عوامل مؤثر در اشتراک دانش بین سازمان‌های همکار و رتبه‌بندی آنها
(مورد مطالعه: صنعت پتروشیمی)
</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Identfying and ranking the effective factors in knowledge sharing between the counterpart organizations (Case study: Petrochemical Industry)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>یکی از ارکان اصلی مدیریت دانش، به&#8204;اشتراک&#8204;گذاری دانش در سطوح داخلی سازمان و با سایر سازمان&#8204;ها به&#8204;ویژه سازمان-های همکار است که دارای مزایایی از جمله دسترسی به دانش رقابتی، افزایش مزیت رقابتی، کسب ارزش و هم&#8204;افزایی است و عدم بهره&#8204;گیری از آن در صنایع، به ویژه صنعت پتروشیمی که شرکت&#8204;های فعال در آن نیازمند حجم وسیعی از دانش برای اجرای پروژه&#8204;های مختلف هستند، منجر به هدررفت سرمایه&#8204;ها، تحمیل هزینه&#8204;های سربار و کاهش بهره&#8204;وری خواهد گشت. لذا هدف پژوهش، شناسایی و تبیین عوامل مؤثر در اشتراک دانش و رتبه&#8204;بندی آنها در صنعت پتروشیمی در نظر گرفته شد که از این منظر، پژوهش کاربردی محسوب می&#8204;شود. به منظور تحقق هدف پژوهش، مطالعات کتابخانه&#8204;ای انجام گرفت و عوامل مرتبط با دارنده و گیرنده دانش، محتوایی، بستر همکاری و زیرساخت&#8204;های فناوری شناسایی شد. برای تبیین مؤثر بودن و رتبه&#8204;بندی عوامل، مطالعات میدانی نیز صورت گرفت و گردآوری داده&#8204;ها از طریق پرسشنامه&#8204;ای 25 سؤالی که روایی محتوای آن توسط اساتید تأیید شده بود، انجام شد. پس از توزیع و گردآوری پرسشنامه&#8204;ها، روایی عاملی و پایایی آن هم با نرم&#8204;افزار SPSS محاسبه و با آلفا کرونباخ 1/88 تأیید گردید. نتایج آزمون t تک&#8204;نمونه&#8204;ای نشان داد که کلیه عوامل مذکور، مؤثر هستند؛ همچنین نتایج آزمون فریدمن حاکی از آن بود که فضای فرهنگی و جوّ مناسب سازمان گیرنده دانش در رتبه اول و میزان ابهام در دانش رتبه آخر عوامل مؤثر، قرار دارند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>One of the main elements of the knowledge management, is sharing the knowledge inside the organization or with the other organizations which has some advantages such as: access to the competitive knowledge, achieving value and synergy, and not sharing the knowledge in the industries, especially petrochemical industry, in which the active companies require high amount of knowledge for the execution of different projects, will result in the waste of capital, impose of extra costs and the reduction of productivity. So, the goal of this research has been the identification and ranking the effective factors in knowledge sharing in the counterpart organizations. In order to achieve this goal, the library studies were conducted and the factors related to the owner and gainer of the knowledge, the content factors, the cooperation base factors and the technology infrastructures factors, were identified. For explaining the effectiveness of the factors, field studies were conducted in this research by a 25-questions questionnaire. After distributing and gathering the questionnaires, its factor validity and reliability was calculated by SPSS software. At the next step, for explaining the effectiveness of the factors, the single-sample t-test was used and determined that all factors were effective. Then, by using Friedman test, the effective factors were rated, and the cultural and suitable environment of the organization that gains the knowledge was ranked in the first, and the amount of the ambiguity in the knowledge was ranked in the last.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>85</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>116</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>نوید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>نظافتی</Family>
				<NameE>Navid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Nezafati</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شهید بهشتی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>n_nezafati@sbu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>نسیم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>غنبر تهرانی</Family>
				<NameE>Nasim</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ganbar Tehrani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>شیفرا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>داوری</Family>
				<NameE>Shifra</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Davari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>knowledge sharing</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>effective factors on knowledge sharing</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>petrochemical industry</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اشتراک‌گذاری دانش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عوامل مؤثر در اشتراک دانش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>صنعت پتروشیمی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abili, K.; Thani, F. N.; Mokhtarian, F.; Rashidi, M. M. (2011), “The role of effective factors on organizational knowledge sharing”, Procedia-Social and Behavioral Science, No. 29, 1701-1706.##Alavi, M. &amp; Leidner, D. (2001), “Review: knowledge management and knowledge management systems: conceptual foundations and research issues”, MIS Quarterly, No. 1, 107-136.##Bennet, A.; Bennet, D. (2003), “The Partnership between Organizational Learning and Knowledge Management”, Springer-Verlag.##Cheng, M. Y.; Ho, J. S.; Lau, P. M. (2009), “Knowledge sharing in academic institutions:a study of Multimedia University Malaysia”, Electronic Journal of Knowledge Management, No. 3, 313–324.##Easterby-Smith, M.; Lyles, M. A.; Tsang, E. W. (2008), “Inter-Organizational Knowledge Transfer: Current Themes and Future Prospects”, Journal of Management Studies, No. 4, 677-690.##Grisham, T (2009), “The Delphi technique, a method for testing complex and multifaceted topics”, International Journal of Managing Projects in Business, No. 1, 112–130.##Hsiu-Fen, L. (2007), “Knowledge sharing and firm innovation capability: an empirical study”, International Journal of Manpower, No. 3/4, 315-332.##Huang, C.; Luther, R.; Tayles, M. (2007), “An evidencebased taxonomy of intellectual capital”, Journal of Intellectual Capital, No. 3, 386-403.##Hung, Y.‐C.; Huang, S.‐M.; Lin, Q.‐P.; Tsai, M.‐L. (2005), “Critical factors in adopting a KMS for the pharmaceatical industry”, Industrial M &amp; Data systems, No. 2, 164 –183.##Ilvonen, I.; Vuori, V. (2013), “Risks and benefits of knowledge sharing in co-opetitive knowledge networks”, International Journal of Networking and Virtual Organizations, No. 3, 209-223.##King, W. R. (2009), “Knowledge Management and Organizational Learning. W.R. King (ed.), Knowledge Management and Organizational Learning”, Annals of Information Systems, No. 4, 3-13.##Lee, H.; Choi, B. (2000), “Knowledge Management Enablers, Processes, and Organizational Performance: An Integration and Empirical Examination”, APDSI 2000 Full Paper.##Lin, H.; Lee, G. (2004), “Perceptions Of Senior Managers Toward Knowledge Sharing Behavior”, Management Decision, No. 1, 108-125.##Plessis, M. (2008), “What bars organizations from managing knowledge successfully”, International Journal of Information Management, No. 1, 285-292.##Tang, L. (2008), “Informal inter-organizational knowledge sharing: the case of the biotechnology industry”, Paper presented at the Annual Meeting of the NCA 94th Annual Convention. San Diego.##Van Vuuren, J. S. (2011), “Inter-organizational knowledge sharing in public sector: the role of social capital and information and communication technology”, Unpublished doctoral dissertation, Victoria University of Wellington.##Yang, J. T. (2010), “Antecedents and consequences of knowledge sharing in international tourist hotels”, International Journal of Hospitality Management, No. 29, 42–52.##ابوالقاسمی، محمود؛ رشید حاجی خواجه‌لو، صالح؛ احمدی، سید محمد (1390)، نقش مکانیزم‌های توانمندساز سازمانی در استقرار فرایندهای مدیریت دانش، راهبرد فرهنگ، شماره دوازدهم و سیزدهم، صص 200-183. ##پهلوانی، معصومه؛ پیرایش، رضا؛ علیپور، وحیده؛ باشکوه، محمد (1389)، بررسی و اولویت عوامل فرهنگی مؤثر در به اشتراک‌گذاری دانش در مراکز تحقیق و توسعه پتروشیمی، مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، شماره 5، صص 36-19.##تولایی، روح‌اله؛ بامداد صوفی، جهانیار؛ رضائیان، علی؛ صالحی صدقیانی، جمشید (1392)، ارائه الگوی توسعه شبکههای دانش در هابهای پژوهش و فناوری صنعت نفت با استفاده از الگوهای جهانی، فصلنامه مطالعات راهبردی جهانی شدن، شماره 13، صص 78-55.##رفوآ، شبنم؛ تاجداران، منصور؛ رضایی شریف‌آبادی، سعید (1392)، وضعیت‌یابی مؤلفه‌های زیرساختی پیاده‌سازی اشتراک دانش در صنعت بیمه، تحقیقات کتابداری و اطلاع‌رسانی دانشگاهی، شماره 3، صص 346-325.##عزیزی، مجتبی؛ صبحیه، محمدحسین؛ آراستی، محمدرضا؛ البدوی، امیر (1391)، انتقال بین‌سازمانی دانش مدیریت پروژه، کلید نوآوری در سازمان‌های پروژه‌محور (جستاری بر کنسرسیوم‌های بین‌المللی در صنعت نفت ایران)، فصلنامه نوآوری و ارزش‌آفرینی، شماره 1 و 2، صص 51-39.##علی ئی، مریم (1389). ارائه مدلی برای تسهیم دانش بر اساس فرآیند سلسله مراتبی، سومین کنفرانس مدیریت دانش، تهران.##فلفلانی، عطیه (1390). بررسی عوامل تأثیرگذار بر تسهیم دانش در میان دانشجویان، چهارمین کنفرانس مدیریت دانش، تهران.##کاظمی، مصطفی؛ ملک‌زاده، غلامرضا (1392)، تبیین عوامل مؤثر بر پیاده‌سازی سامانه‌ی مدیریت دانش در شرکت‌های فناور کوچک مستقر در مراکز رشد فناوری، مجله مدیریت فردا، شماره 32، صص 62-46.##میرغفوری، حبیب‌اله؛ صادقی آرانی، زهرا؛ صابری، حامد (1387)، بررسی تجزیه و تحلیل موانع تسهیم دانش در سازمان-های دولتی (مطالعه موردی: سازمان‌های دولتی استان یزد)، ششمین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت دانش.##واعظی، رضا و مسلمی، طیبه (1388)، شناسایی عوامل سازمانی موثر بر اجرای مطلوب سیستم مدیریت دانش (مطالعه موردی شرکت همکاران سیستم)، مجله مدیریت توسعه و تحول، شماره 1، صص 19-7. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر اقدامات مدیریت دانش بر توانمندسازی روانشناختی منابع انسانی با نقش تعدیل‌گر متغیرهای جمعیت‌شناختی در شرکت نفت مناطق مرکزی ایران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Investigating the influence of knowledge management practices on the psychological empowerment of human resources by moderating role of demographic variables in Iranian Central Oil Fields Company (I. C. O. F. C)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>توانمندسازی روانشناختی از ابزارهای سودمند ارتقای کیفی کارکنان و افزایش اثربخشی سازمان است. توانمندسازی روانشناختی متأثر از عوامل مختلفی از جمله اقدامات مدیریت دانش می&#8204;باشد. هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی تأثیر اقدامات مدیریت دانش بر توانمندسازی روانشناختی منابع انسانی با نقش تعدیل&#8204;گر متغیرهای جمعیت&#8204;شناختی در شرکت نفت مناطق مرکزی ایران می&#8204;باشد. تحقیق حاضر از نوع کاربردی-توسعه&#8204;ای بوده و از بعد روش توصیفی-پیمایشی است. جامعه آماری، کارکنان شرکت نفت مناطق مرکزی ایران به تعداد 5480 نفر بوده که با استفاده از فرمول کوکران 359 نفر به طور تصادفی ساده انتخاب شده&#8204;اند. ابزار پژوهش پرسشنامه&#8204;های استاندارد اقدامات مدیریت دانش خاکی(1390) و توانمندسازی روانشناختی منابع انسانی وتن و کمرون (1998) بوده است. ضریب آلفای کرونباخ برای متغیرهای مدیریت دانش و توانمندسازی روانشناختی در ابزار پژوهش، به ترتیب برابر با 903/0 و 884/0 بوده و لذا، پایایی آنها مورد تایید قرار گرفت. نتایج نشان داد که اقدامات مدیریت دانش بر توانمندسازی روانشناختی منابع انسانی و مؤلفه&#8204;های آن اثرگذار است. مدیریت دانش، به ترتیب با شدت 788/0، 772/0، 754/0، 742/0 و 703/0، دارای تأثیر بر مؤلفه های داشتن اعتماد، احساس مؤثر بودن، احساس شایستگی، احساس خودمختاری و احساس معنی&#8204;داری بوده است. نتایج آزمون همبستگی تفکیکی نشان&#8204;دهنده عدم وجود نقش تعدیل&#8204;کنندگی متغیرهای جمعیت&#8204;شناختی در رابطه بین مدیریت دانش و توانمندسازی روانشناختی منابع انسانی می&#8204;باشد</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Psychological empowerment is one of the useful tools for improving the effectiveness of the organization's staff and their quality. Psychological empowerment is affected by numerous factors including knowledge management. The present research investigated the impact of knowledge management practices on the psychological empowerment of human resources by moderating role of demographic variables in Iranian Central Oil Fields Company (I. C. O. F. C). The method in this study insisted applied-developing research method and on the other hand, descriptive-survey. The goal population has been the Company&#8217;s staff of ICOFC including 5480 employees. By Cochran&#8217;s formula 359 employees have randomly been selected. Standardized questionnaires including: Knowledge management of Khaki and psychological empowerment of human resources of have been used. The reliability of questionnaires proved by Cronbach&#8217;s Alpha that for the variables of knowledge management and psychological empowerment were 0.903 and 0.884, respectively. The results showed that knowledge management has an effect on psychological empowerment and its components. The effect&#8217;s intensity of knowledge management on psychological empowerment's components has been 0.788, 0.772, 0.754, 0.742, and 0.703 respectively for sense of trust, sense of efficacy, sence of competency, sense of self-determination, and sense of meaning. The partial correlation test results showed that there is no moderating role for demographic variables in the relationship between knowledge management and the psychological empowerment.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>117</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>148</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سیروس</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>امیرقدسی</Family>
				<NameE>Sirous</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>AmirGhodsi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>علم و صنعت</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>sirous_a@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ملکی</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Maleki</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>صنعتی شریف</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بنیادی نائینی</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Bonyadi Naeeni</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>علم و صنعت</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد جواد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>اسفندیاری</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammas Javad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Esfandiari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>knowledge management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>psychological empowerment</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>human resource</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>structural equation modeling</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت دانش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>توانمندسازی روانشناختی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Alavi, M., &amp; Leidner, D. E. (2001). Review: Knowledge management and knowledge management systems: Conceptual foundations and research issues. MIS quarterly, 107-136.##Amichai, Y.H., Katelyn, Y.A.M., &amp; Samuel, A. (2008). Assessment of organisational involvement in implementing empowerment. Journal of Computers In Human Behavior, 14, 34-49.##Amirkhani, A., Tajmirriahi, J., Mohammadi, M., &amp; Dalir, M. (2012). Assessing the effectiveness of knowledge management in empowering and development of human resources: A case study on Ati Luleh Sepahan Company. Interdisciplinary Journal of Contemporary Research in Business, 3(12), 131-147.##Appelbaum, S. H., &amp; Honeggar, K. (1998). Empowerment: a contrasting overview of organizations in general and nursing in particular-an examination of organizational factors, managerial behaviors, job design, and structural power. Empowerment in Organizations, 6(2), 29-50.##Badah, A. (2012). Relationship between the knowledge management processes and the administrative empowerment with the employees of the ministry of higher education and scientific research-jordan. European Scientific Journal, 8(28).##Bhatt, G. D. (2001). Knowledge management in organizations: examining the interaction between technologies, techniques, and people. Journal of knowledge management, 5(1), 68-75.##Birasnav, M. (2014). Knowledge management and organizational performance in the service industry: The role of transformational leadership beyond the effects of transactional leadership. Journal of Business Research, 67(8), 1622-1629.##Bose, R. (2004). Knowledge management metrics. Industrial management &amp; data systems, 104(6), 457-468.##Chidambaranathan, K., &amp; Swarooprani, B. S. (2015). Knowledge management as a predictor of organizational effectiveness: the role of demographic and employment factors. The Journal of Academic Librarianship, 41(6), 758-763.##Conger, J. A., &amp; Kanungo, R. N. (1988). The empowerment process: Integrating theory and practice. Academy of management review, 13(3), 471-482. ##Dubitzky, W. (2011). Toward a system-centric global knowledge management approach to discovering (organizing and sharing) scientific knowledge from large-scale data. Omics: a journal of integrative biology, 15(4), 243-246.##Gold, A. H., &amp; Arvind Malhotra, A. H. S. (2001). Knowledge management: An organizational capabilities perspective. Journal of management information systems, 18(1), 185-214.##Haghighi, M. A., Tabarsa, G. A., &amp; Kameli, B. (2014). Investigation the Relationship between Knowledge Management Processes and Empowerment of Human Resources. Global Journal of Management Studies and Researches, 1(2), 122-130.##Hsia, T. L., Lin, L. M., Wu, J. H., &amp; Tsai, H. T. (2006). A framework for designing nursing knowledge management systems. Interdisciplinary Journal of Information, Knowledge, and Management, 1(1), 13-22.##Kalajahi, M., &amp; Janani, H. (2015). Effect of the Knowledge Management on Empowering Physical Education Teachers in Universities of Northwestern of Iran. International Journal of Sport Studies, 5 (8), 921-924.##Khansharifan, A., Soleimanpour Omran, M., &amp; Askarzadeh, H. (2015). Investigating the Relationship between Knowledge Management and Employee Empowerment (Case study: Education Organization of Bojnourd City). MAGNT Research Report, 3 (2), 502-512.##King, W.R., Chung, T.R., &amp; Haney, M.H. (2008). Knowledge Management and Organizational Learning. Omega, 36 (2), 167-172.##Krenz, P., Basmer, S., Buxbaum-Conradi, S., Redlich, T., &amp; Wulfsberg, J. P. (2014). Knowledge management in value creation networks: establishing a new business model through the role of a knowledge-intermediary. Procedia CIRP, 16, 38-43.##Lin, H. F., &amp; Lee, G. G. (2005). Impact of organizational learning and knowledge management factors on e-business adoption. Management Decision, 43(2), 171-188. ##Liu, P. L. (2011). Empirical study on influence of critical success factors on ERP knowledge management on management performance in high-tech industries in Taiwan. Expert Systems with Applications, 38(8), 10696-10704.Mehrara, A., Razaghi, M. E., Moosavi, S. J., &amp; Hajizadeh, M. (2012). Study of Knowledge Management Efficiency on Employees Performance in Kerman Sport and Youth Offices. Journal of Basic and Applied Scientific Research, 2(10), 10656-10662.##Meng, L., Jin, Y., &amp; Guo, J. (2016). Mediating and/or moderating roles of psychological empowerment. Applied Nursing Research, 30, 104-110.##Mumford, M. D., &amp; Licuanan, B. (2004). Leading for innovation: Conclusions, issues, and directions. The leadership quarterly, 15(1), 163-171.##O'dell, C., &amp; Grayson, C. J. (1998). If only we knew what we know: Identification and transfer of internal best practices. California management review, 40(3), 154-174.##Ooi, K. B. (2014). TQM: A facilitator to enhance knowledge management? A structural analysis. Expert Systems with Applications, 41(11), 5167-5179.##Ozbebek, A., &amp; Kilicarslan, T. E. (2011). Empowered employees’ knowledge sharing behavior. International Journal of Business and Management Studies, 3(2), 69-75.##Sadeghi Boroujerdi, S., and Hasani, K. (2013). Relationship between Knowledge Management and Employee Empowerment in the Sport and Youth Organization of Iran. International Journal of Research in Organizational Behavior and Human Resource Management, 1(4), 195-209.##Salajeghe, S., Rashidi, R. P., &amp; Mousaei, M. (2013). Analysis of Psychological Empowerment and its Relationship with Knowledge Management (The Case of Jam Petrochemical Company Located in South Pars Area, Iran). International Journal of Academic Research in Accounting, Finance and Management Sciences, 3(4), 245-253.##Shahhosseini, S., &amp; Piri, M. (2015). Investigation the Role of Knowledge Management in Staff Empowerment (Case Study: General Department of Education, Western Azerbaijan Province). Int. J. Rev. Life. Sci., 5(4), 163-168.##Siachou, E., &amp; Gkorezis, P. (2014). Do empowered employees absorb knowledge? An empirical investigation of the effects of psychological empowerment dimensions on absorptive capacity. Management Research Review, 37(2), 130-151.##Spreitzer, G. M., &amp; Doneson, D. (2005). Musings on the past and future of employee empowerment. Handbook of Organizational Development. Thousand Oaks: Sage.##Spreitzer, G. M. (1995). Psychological empowerment in the workplace: Dimensions, measurement, and validation. Academy of management Journal, 38(5), 1442-1465.##Tseng, S. M. (2014). The impact of knowledge management capabilities and supplier relationship management on corporate performance. International Journal of Production Economics, 154, 39-47.##Thomas, K. W., &amp; Velthouse, B. A. (1990). Cognitive elements of empowerment: An “interpretive” model of intrinsic task motivation. Academy of management review, 15(4), 666-681.##Tohidi, H., &amp; Jabbari, M. M. (2012). The aspects of empowerment of human resources. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 31, 829-833.##Turban, E., Mclean, E., &amp; Wetherbe, J. C. (2002). Information technology for management: transforming business in the digital economy. 3rd ed, John Wiley&amp; Sons. Inc.##Whetten, D.A., and Cameron, K.S. (2011). Developing management skills. New York: (8 Edition), Prentice Hall.##Whetten, D.A., and Cameron, K.S. (1998(. Developing Management Skills. New York, Addison –Wesley, Wheelan.##اعرابی، سید محمد؛ موسوی، سعید (1389)، «استراتژی دانش»، چاپ اول، تهران، انتشارات مهکامه.##بروجرون، برایان (1386)، «مدیریت دانش»، چاپ اول، ترجمه غلامرضا ملک زاده، انتشارات نما.##خاکی، ندا (1390). بررسی رابطه بین مؤلفه های مدیریت دانش و بهره‌وری نیروی انسانی در مراکز آموزش عالی منتخب (پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد)، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران (پردیس قم)، ایران.##قربانی‌زاده، وج الله؛ خالقی‌نیا، شیرین (1388)، نقش انتقال دانش ضمنی در توانمندسازی کارکنان، فصلنامه پژوهش های مدیریت منابع انسانی دانشگاه جامع امام حسین، سال اول، شماره 2، صص 105-85.##نیاآذری،کیومرث؛ بریمانی، ابوالقاسم؛ حاجی قلیخانی، بی بی سعیده (1390)، بررسی نقش مدیریت دانش بر خلاقیت دبیران در مدارس متوسطه، فصلنامه مدیریت، سال هشتم، شماره 21، صص 87-79.##نیک بخت، اکرم؛ سیادت، سید علی؛ هویدا، رضا؛ مقدم، اعظم (1389)، رابطه ی بین مدیریت دانش با سبک های رهبری مدیران گروه های آموزشی از دیدگاه هیأت علمی دانشگاه علوم پزشکی اصفهان، مدیریت اطلاعات سلامت، دوره هفتم، شماره 2، صص 224-216. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>عوامل موثر بر حفظ کارکنان دانشی با هدف توسعه برنامه‌های کیفیت زندگی کاری در 
موسسه مطالعات بین‌المللی انرژی
</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Factors affecting retention of knowledge workers with the aim of developing work life quality plans at the Institute For International Energy Studies</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در عصر حاضر کارکنان دانشی از جمله مهمترین دارایی&#8204;های یک سازمان محسوب می-شوند و مدیران باید بیشترین تلاش خود را برای حفظ این کارکنان به کار گیرند. با توجه به اهمیت موضوع، این مقاله به بررسی مسئله حفظ کارکنان دانشی با استفاده از رویکرد توسعه کیفیت زندگی کاری می&#8204;پردازد. در تدوین مدل مفهومی پژوهش از نتایج برخی از مطالعات پیشین جهت انتخاب متغیر&#8204;ها، بهره&#8204;برداری شده است. پرسش اساسی این است که آیا بهبود کیفیت زندگی کاری کارکنان دانشی در ماندگاری آنان در سازمان تأثیری دارد. به منظور پاسخگویی به این پرسش، پرسشنامه&#8204;ای میان یک نمونه تصادفی 66 نفری از کارکنان دانشی موسسه مطالعات بین&#8204;&#8204;المللی انرژی شهر تهران توزیع و داده&#8204;های جمع&#8204;آوری شده، با استفاده از مدل&#8204;سازی معادلات ساختاری تجزیه و تحلیل شد. یافته&#8204;های پژوهش نشان می&#8204;دهد که میان توسعه عوامل شغلی کیفیت زندگی کاری و ماندگاری کارکنان دانشی رابطه معنادار و مستقیم وجود دارد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Today, knowledge workers are the most important assets of organizations and managers should make efforts to maintain these employees. Considering the importance of this issue, this paper investigated the maintenance of knowledge workers, using an approach to develop the work life quality. In order to design the conceptual model, some previous studies have been exploited to select the variables. The main question has been whether the improvement of knowledge workers&#8217; work life quality affects their persistence. In order to answer this question, a questionnaire was distributed among a random sample of 66 knowledge workers of the Institute for International Energy Studies , and collected data were analyzed using structural equation modeling. Findings indicated that there is a significantly direct relationship between the development of job factors of work life quality and the persistence of knowledge workers.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>149</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>176</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>وجه اله</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قربانی زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Vajhollah</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ghorbanizadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>علامه طباطبائی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>vghorbanizadeh@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>خیراندیش</Family>
				<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Kheir Andish</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه هوایی شهید ستاری</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>هوایی شهید ستاری</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>اعظم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عدنان راد</Family>
				<NameE>Azam</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Adnan Rad</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>علامه طباطبائی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Knowledge</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Knowledge Workers</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>quality of work life</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>persistence of Knowledge Workers.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دانش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کارکنان دانشی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کیفیت زندگی کاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ماندگاری کارکنان دانشی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abdul Aziz, R.; Nadzar, F.; Husaini, H., Maarof, A.; Radzi, S. &amp; Ismail, A. (), “Quality of work life of librarians in government academic libraries in the Klang Valley, Malaysia”, The International Information &amp; Library Review , No. , pp. .##Abu Taher, Md (), “Variations of quality of work life of academic professionals in Bangladesh: A discriminant analysis”, European Journal of Training and Development, Vol.  No. , pp. ##Adelstein, J. (), “Disconnecting knowledge from the knower,  The knowledge worker as Icarus”, Equal Opportunities International, Vol. , No. , pp. .##Adhikari, D.; Gautam, D. (), “Labor legislations for improving quality of work life in Nepal”, International Journal of Law and Management,Vol.  No. , pp. .##Auerbach, C.; McGowan, B.; Ausberger, A.; Strolin-Goltzman, J.; Schudrich, W. (), “Differential factors influencing public and voluntary child welfare workers' intention to leave”, Children and Youth Services Review, No.   pp. . ##Arthur, M. (), “On Being a Knowledge Worker”, Organizational Dynamics, Vol. , No. , pp. –, .##Benest, F. (), &quot;The Role of Benefits in Winning the War for Talent.&quot; Benefits &amp; Compensation Digest  (): -.##Casper, W.; Harris, C. (), “Work-life benefits and organizational attachment: Self-interest utility and signaling theory models”, Journal of Vocational Behavior,NO. , pp. ##Celik, D. A.; Oz, E. U. (), “The effects of emotional dissonance and quality of work life perceptions on absenteeism and turnover intentions”, Social and Behavioral Sciences ,  – .##Fenwick, T. (), “Knowledge workers in the in-between: network identities”, Journal of Organizational Change Management, Vol. , No. , pp. -.##Ganesh, S.; Ganesh, M. P. (), “Effects of masculinity-femininity on quality of work life Understanding the moderating roles of gender and social support Gender in Management”, An International Journal, Vol. , No. , pp. .##Guidice, R.; Heames, J. (), “The indirect relationship between organizational-level knowledge worker turnover and innovation”, The Learning Organization, Vol. , No. , pp. -.##Hannif, z.; Connell, J. (), “Call centres, quality of work life and HRM practices”, Employee Relations, Vol. No. , pp. -.##Hernaus, T.; Mikulic, J. (), “Work characteristics and work performance of knowledge workers’, EuroMed Journal of Business, Vol. , No. , pp. .##Holtshouse, D. (), “Knowledge work 2020: thinking ahead about knowledge work”, On the Horizon, Vol. , ss: ,  pp. .##Huang,Y.; Wu, Y. (), “Intellectual capital and knowledge productivity: theTaiwan biotech industry”, Management Decision, Vol. , No. , pp. -.##Hughes, J.; Rog, E. (), “Talent management A strategy for improving employee recruitment, retention and engagement within hospitality organizations”, International Journal of Contemporary Hospitality Management,Vol. , No. , pp. -.##Kandasamy, I.; Ancheri, S. (), “ Hotel employees’ expectations of QWL: A qualitative study”, International Journal of Hospitality Management , –.##Kelley, L.; Blackman, D.; Hurst, J.P. (), “An exploration of the relationship between learning organisations and the retention of knowledge workers”, The Learning Organization,Vol.  No. , pp. -.##Lam, T.; Zhang, H.; Baum, T. (), “An investigation of employee’s job satisfaction on turnover intent: a test of a structural measurement model using a national sample of workers”, Social Science Journal, Vol. ,  No. , pp. -.##Layer, J. (), “The effect of cognitive demands and perceived quality of work life on human performance in manufacturing environments. International”, Journal of Industrial Ergonomics  () –. ##Lee, T.; Maurer, s. (), “The retention of knowledge workers with the unfolding model fo voluntary turnover”, Human resource management review, Vol. , No. , pp. -.##Lei, H.; Lan, J. (), “Research into the influence factors of knowledge workers sharing residual claims rights”, Journal of Knowledge-based Innovation in China. Vol. , No. , pp. -.##Lewis, D. (), “ Extrinsinc and Intrinsinc Determinants of work life quality”, Journal of Leadership in Health Services, Vol. , No. , pp. -.##Li, J.; Yeo, R. (), “ Quality of work life and career development: perceptions of part-time MBA students”, Employee Relations, Vol.  No. , pp. .##Lu, J.; Lv, Y. (), “Research of Electric Power Enterprise Knowledge Workers' Incentive Based on Fuzzy Model”, Procedia Engineering ,pp.  – .##Mak, B.; Sockel, H. (), “A conirmatory factor analysis of IS employee motivation and retention”, Information &amp; Management, No. , pp. -.##Maruta, R. (), “Transforming knowledge workers into innovation workers to improve corporate productivity”, Knowl. Based Syst. (), doi:./ j.knosys....##Mitchell, R.; Meacheam, D. (), “Knowledge worker control: understanding via principal and agency theory”, The Learning Organization, Vol.  No. , , pp.-.##Nair, N.; Vohra, N. (), “predicting work alienation of knowledge workers”, Management Decision,  Vol. , No. , pp. -.##Nelson, K.; McCann, J. (), “Designing for knowledge worker retention &amp; organization performance”, Journal of Management and Marketing Research, pp. -.##Noor, S.; Abdullah, M. (), “Quality work life among factory workers in Malaysia”, Social and behavioral sciences, No.  , pp.  –##O’Donohue, W.; Sheehan, C.; Hecker, R; Holland, P. (), “The psychological contact ofknowledge workers”, Journal of Knowledge Management, Vol. , No. , pp. -.##Oldham, G.R.; Hackman, J.R. (), “Not what it was and not what it will be: the future of job design research”, Journal of Organizational Behavior, Vol. , No. , pp. .##Paton, S. (), “Cutting through the confusion of contemporary work”, Journal of Knowledge Management, Vol. , No. , pp. -.##Phillips, D.; Roper, K. (), “A framework for talent management in real estate”, Journal of Corporate Real Estate, Vol. , No. , pp. -.##Saraji, G.; Dargahi, H. (), “Study of Quality of Work Life”, Iranian J Publ Health, Vol. , No. , pp.-.##Switzer, C. (), “Time for change: empowering organizations to succeed in the knowledge economy”, JOURNAL OF KNOWLEDGE MANAGEMENT, VOL. ,  NO. , pp. -##Teo, S.; Lakhani, B.; Brown, D.; Malmi, T.(), “Strategic human resource management and knowlend dge workers”, Management Research News Vol. , No. , pp. .##Tho, N. D.; Nguyen, D. P.; Ha, M. Q. T. (), “Marketers’ psychological capital and performance”, Asia-Pacific Journal of Business Administration, Vol.  No. , pp. -.##Valcour, M. (), “Influences on employee perceptions of organizational work–life support: Signals and resources”, Journal of Vocational Behavior .##Von Glinow, M. A. (), “The New Professionals.Cambridge, MA: Ballinger”, Wall Street Journal.. (May ): A, .##Walker JW. Human resource strategy. New York: McGraw-Hill; .##Wickramasinghe, N.; Ginzberg, M. (), “Integrating knowledge workers and the organization: the role of IT”, International Journal of Health Care Quality Assurance, , pp. -.##Zboralski, K. (), “Antecedents of knowledge sharing in communities of practice”, Journal of Knowledge Management, Vol. , No. , pp. .##	ابطحی، حسین؛ خیراندیش، مهدی (1390)، &quot;مدیریت دانش: با رویکرد بستر سازمانی&quot;، چاپ اول، تهران، نشر مدیران فردا .##	اسماعیلی، ایوب (1387)، چالش های سازمان های ایرانی در مواجهه با نیروهای دانشگر، میثاق مدیران، شماره 37، 70 – 75.##	اسکندری، مجتبی؛ عابدی، علی نقی (1388)، بررسی عوامل مرتبط با حفظ و نگهداری کارکنان در نیروهای مسلح جمهوری اسلامی ایران، فصلنامه پژوهش های مدیریت منابع انسانی دانشگاه جامع امام حسین (ع)، سال اول، شماره 2، ص ص 107- 125.##	 دانایی فرد، حسن؛ الوانی، سید مهدی؛ آذر، عادل (1387)، روش شناسی پژوهش کمی در مدیریت: رویکردی جامع، تهران، انتشارات صفار ـ اشراقی.##	  داوری، علی؛ رضازاده، آرش (1392)، &quot;مدل سازی معادلات ساختار با نرم افزارPLS&quot;، چاپ اول، تهران، انتشارات جهاد دانشگاهی.##	 سلطانی، ایرج؛ داستانی، مهدی (1389)، کیفیت زندگی کاری و مؤلفه های اثرگذار بر آن، تدبیر، شماره 217 .##دولان، شیمون. ال؛ شولر، رندالاس (1380)،&quot; مدیریت امور کارکنان و منابع انسانی&quot;، چاپ پنجم، تهران، انتشارات مرکز آموزش مدیریت دولتی. ##میرباقری، سید علیرضا؛ طهماسبی، هامون؛ هاشمی، علی (1389)، استراتژی های اثربخش در نگهداری کارکنان دانش محور، ماهنامه تدبیر، شماره 219 . ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>شناسایی و سنجش زیرساخت‌های مدیریت دانش پروژه‌ها در سازمان‌های پروژه‌محور 
صنایع بالادستی نفت و گاز ایران
</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Identification and evaluation of projects knowledge management infrastructures in project-based organizations of Iranian oil & gas industry in upstream</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف این پژوهش، شناسایی و سنجش میزان وجود زیرساخت&#8204;های مدیریت دانش پروژه&#8204;ها در تعدادی از سازمان&#8204;های پروژه&#8204;محور صنایع بالادستی نفت و گاز ایران و مقایسه&#8204;ی آن&#8204;ها است. این پژوهش با بهره&#8204;گیری از رویکرد پژوهش کمّی و استراتژی پیمایشی به رصد زیرساخت&#8204;های مدیریت دانش پروژه&#8204;ها پرداخته است. پرسشنامه&#8204;های سنجش زیرساخت&#8204;های مدیریت دانش در 41 سازمان بالادستی صنعت نفت و گاز تکمیل گشت. براساس نتایج، از میان زیرساخت&#8204;های مدیریت دانش، مؤلفه&#8204;های &#171;فرهنگ سازمانی&#187; و &#171;نیروی انسانی&#187; بیشترین و مؤلفه&#8204;ی &#171;ساختار&#187; کمترین سطح را داشته&#8204;اند. سازمان&#8204;های مشاور، پیمانکار عمومی، مدیریت طرح، پیمانکار طرح و ساخت و کارفرما در رتبه&#8204;های یک تا پنج از حیث مناسب بودن ساختارهای مدیریت دانش قرار داشتند. از منظر دولتی و خصوصی بودن، سازمان&#8204;های خصوصی در رتبه&#8204;ی نخست و پس از آن سازمان&#8204;های نیمه&#8204;خصوصی و دولتی در جایگاه&#8204;های بعدی از لحاظ زیرساخت&#8204;های مدیریت دانش قرار داشتند؛ در عین حال، هیچ&#8204;یک از این دو رتبه&#8204;بندی از نظر آماری تفاوت معناداری را بین بخش های مورد بررسی نشان نداد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The purpose of this research is identification, evaluation and comparing the reality of &#34;projects knowledge management infrastructures&#34; in some project-based organizations of iranian oil &#38; gas industry in upstream. Applying &#160;quantitative method and survey strategy, projects knowledge management infrastructures in project-based organizations of iranian oil &#38; gas industry in upstream were monitored. Khnowledg management infrastructure questionnaires were completed in 41 upstream organizations in oil &#38; gas industry of Iran. Results showed that among infrastructures, &#34;organizational culture&#34; and &#34;human resource&#34; had the highest score and &#34;structure&#34; had the lowest score. Consulting organizations, general contractor, construction management, design-build contractor, and employer ranked consequently, one to five in terms of suitability of knowledge management structures. From a public and private perspective, private organizations ranked first and then semi-private and public organizations in the next place in terms of knowledge management infrastructure. But none of these two rankings were statistically significant.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>177</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>204</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدجواد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>صالحی طالشی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Javad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Salehi Taleshi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>موسسه آموزش عالی مهر البرز تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>jsalehi_68@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مجتبی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حسینعلی پور</Family>
				<NameE>Mojtaba</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Hosseinali Pour</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شهید بهشتی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hosseinalipour@sbu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>هانی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>اربابی</Family>
				<NameE>Hani</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Arbabi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تربیت مدرس</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>arbabi@modares.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Project Knowledge Management (PKM)</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Project-Based Organization (PBO)</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Oil & Gas Upstream Industries</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت دانش پروژه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سازمان پروژه‌محور</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>صنایع بالادستی نفت و گاز</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Acharya, A. &amp; Mishra, B. (2017). “Exploring the relationship between organizational structure and knowledge retention: A study of the Indian infrastructure consulting sector” , Journal of Knowledge Management, 21(4), pp.961-985, https://doi.org/10.1108/JKM-11-2016-0506.##Adenfelt, M. and Lagerstro, K. (2006). “Enabling knowledge creation and sharing in transnational projects” , International Journal of Project Management, 24(3), 191–198. ##Ajmal, M., Helo, P. and Kekale, T. (2010). “Critical factors for knowledge management in project business”, Journal of knowledge management, 14(1), 156-168.##Akhavan, P. and Zahedi, M. (2014). “Critical success factors in knowledge management among project-based organizations: A multi-case analysis” , The IUP Journal of Knowledge Management, 12(1), 20-38.##Bakker, R.M., Cambré, B., Korlaar, L. and Raab, J. (2011). “Managing the project learning paradox: A set-theoretic approach toward project knowledge transfer”, International Journal of Project Management, 29(5), 494-503.##Becerra-Fernandez, I. &amp; Sabherwal, R. (2014). “Knowledge management: Systems and processes”, New York, NY: Routledge.##Bresnen, M., Edelman, L., Newell, S., Scarbrough, H. and Swan, J. (2005). “A community perspective on managing knowledge in project environments”, in Love, P., Fong, P.S.W. and Irani, Z. (Eds.), Management of knowledge in project environments, Oxford: Elsevier Publications, 81-102.##Caldas, C., Elkington, R., O’Connor, J. and Kim, J. (2014). “Development of a method to retain experiential knowledge in capital projects organizations”, Journal of Management in Engineering, Publisher: American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE), pp. 04014083-1~11. doi:10.1061/(ASCE)ME.1943-5479.0000322.##Chong, S.C. and Choi, Y.S. (2005). “Critical factors in the successful implementation of knowledge management” , Journal of Knowledge Management Practice, 6(1).##Chourides, P., Longbottom, D. and Murphy, W. (2003). “Excellence in knowledge management: An empirical study to identify critical factors and performance measures” , Measuring Business Excellence, 7(2), pp. 29-45.##Davenport, T.H., De Long, D.W. and Beers, M.C. (1998). “Successful knowledge management projects”, Sloan Management Review, 39(2), 43-57.##Davenport, T.H. and Probst, G.J.B. (2002). “Knowledge management case book” , 2nd Ed, John Wiley &amp; Sons, Weinheim.##Desouza, K.C. and Evaristo, J.R. (2006). “Project management offices: A case of knowledge-based archetypes” , International Journal of Information Management, 26(5), 414-423.##Du Plessis, M. (2007). “Knowledge management: What makes complex implementations successful?”, Journal of knowledge management, 11(2), 91-101.##Dayan, R., Heisig, P. &amp; Matos, F. (2017). “Knowledge management as a factor for the formulation and implementation of organization strategy” , Journal of Knowledge Management, 21(2), 308-329.##Fong, P.S.W. (2005). “Managing knowledge in project-based professional services firms: An international comparison”, in Love, P., Fong, P.S.W. and Irani, Z. (Eds.), Management of knowledge in project environments, Elsevier, Amsterdam, pp. 103-131.##Frey, P., Lindner, F., Muller, A. and Wald, A. (2009). “Project knowledge management organizational design and success factors- An empirical study in Germany” , Proceedings of the 42nd Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences, pp. 1-14, doi: 10.1109/HICSS.2009.356.##Hacker, J., Bodendorf, F. and Lorenz, P. (2017). “A framework to identify knowledge actor roles in enterprise social networks”, Journal of Knowledge Management, 21(4) , pp.817-838, https://doi.org/10.1108/JKM-10-2016-0443. ##Hanisch, B., Lindner, F., Mueller, A. and Wald, A. (2009). “Knowledge management in project environments” , Journal of Knowledge Management, 13(4), 148-160.##Holsapple, C.W. and Joshi, K.D. (2000). “An investigation of factors that influence the management of knowledge in organizations”, Journal of Strategic Information Systems, 9(2), pp. 235-261.##Ho, C. F., Hsieh, P. H. &amp; Hung, W. H. (2014). “Enablers and processes for effective knowledge management”, Industrial Management &amp; Data Systems, 114(5), 734-754.##Holt, G.D., Love, P.E.D. &amp; Li, H. (2000). “The learning organization: Toward a paradigm for mutually beneficial strategic construction alliances”, International Journal of Project Management, 18(6), 415-421.##Hung, Y., Huang, S., Lin, Q. and Tsai, M. (2005). “Critical factors in adopting a knowledge management system for the pharmaceutical industry”, Industrial Management &amp; Data Systems, 105(2), pp. 164-183.##Ismail Al-Alawi, A., Yousif Al-Marzooqi, N. &amp; Fraidoon Mohammed, Y. (2007). “Organizational culture and knowledge sharing: Critical success factors” , Journal of knowledge management, 11(2), 22-42.##Kim, T. H., Lee, J. N., Chun, J. U. &amp; Benbasat, I. (2014). “Understanding the effect of knowledge management strategies on knowledge management performance: A contingency perspective” , Information &amp; management, 51(4), 398-416.##Lang, J.C. (2001). “Managerial concerns in knowledge management” , Journal of Knowledge Management, 5(1), pp. 43-57.##Lee , H. &amp; Choi, B. (2003). “Knowledge management enablers, processes, and organizational performance: An integrative view and empirical examination” , Journal of Management Information Systems, 20(1), 179-228.##Levin, G. (2010). “Knowledge management success equals project management success”, PMI Global Congress, Washington D.C., 11 Oct 2010.##Liebowitz, J. (1999). “Key ingredients to the success of an organization's knowledge management strategy” , Knowledge and Process Management, 6(1), 37-40.##Lindner, F. and Wald, A. (2011). “Success factors of knowledge management in temporary organizations”, International Journal of Project Management, 29(7), 877-888.##Mathi, K. (2004). “Key success factors for knowledge management”, Master Thesis, MBA: International Business Management &amp; Consulting, University of Applied Sciences, Germany.##Noruzy, A., Dalfard, V., Azhdari, B., Nazari-Shirkouhi, S. &amp; Rezazadeh, A. (2013). “Relations between transformational leadership, organizational learning, knowledge management, organizational innovation, and organizational performance: An empirical investigation of manufacturing firms” , The International Journal of Advanced Manufacturing Technology, 64(5-8), 1073–1085.##Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) (2001). OECD's Knowledge Management Project. Del-rapport om den Danske Pilotundersøgelse [OECD Knowledge Management Project — Report — Danish Pilot-Survey]. Aarhus: Center of Management.##Pemsel, S. and Wiewiora, A. (2013). “Project management office a knowledge broker in project-based organizations” , International Journal of Project Management, 31(1), 31-42.##Project Management Institute. (2013). “A Guide to the Project Management Body of Knowledge (PMBOK Guide- Fifth Edition)” , Newtown Square, PA: Project Management Institute.##Ryan, S. and Prybutok, V. (2001). “Factors affecting knowledge management technologies: A discriminative approach” , Journal of Computer Information Systems, 41(3), pp. 31-37.##Shankar, R., Singh, M.D., Gupta, A. and Narain, R. (2003). “Strategic planning for knowledge management implementation in engineering firms”, Work Study, 52(4), 190-200.##Skyrme, D. and Amidon, D. (1997). “The knowledge agenda” , Journal of Knowledge Management, 1(1), pp. 27-37.##Soliman, F. and Spooner, K. (2000). “Strategies for implementing knowledge management: Role of human resources management” , Journal of Knowledge Management, 4(4), pp. 337-345.##Taylor, W.A. and Wright, G.H. (2004). “Organizational readiness for successful knowledge sharing: Challenges for public sector managers” , Information Resources Management Journal, 17(2), 22-37.##Teerajetgul, W., Chareonngam, C. and Wethyavivorn, P. (2009). “Key knowledge factors in Thai construction practice” , International Journal of Project Management, 27(8), 833-839.##Todorović, M. L., Petrović, D. Č., Mihić, M. M., Obradović, V. L. &amp; Bushuyev, S. D. (2015). “Project success analysis framework: A knowledge-based approach in project management” , International Journal of Project Management, 33(4), 772-783.##Wong, K.Y. and Aspinwall, E. (2005). “An empirical study of the important factors for knowledge management adoption in the SME sector” , Journal of Knowledge Management, 9(3), pp. 64-82.##Yahya, S. and Goh, W.K. (2002). “Managing human resources toward achieving knowledge management”, Journal of Knowledge Management, 6(5), 457-468.##اربابی، هانی، دانایی‌فرد، حسن، و صبحیه، محمدحسین (1394). ”تبیین هم‌سویی کنترل راهبردی و عناصر مدیریت پروژه و تأثیر آن بر استراتژی پروژه“، چشم‌ انداز مدیریت بازرگانی، 14:1، 49-67.##تولایی، روح‌الله، و رشیدی، محمدمهدی (1390). ”مدیریت ارزش‌آفرین دانش و دستاوردهای نوین آن در صنعت نفت“ ، تهران: مؤسسه‌ی مطالعات بین‌المللی انرژی.##حسن‌زاده، محمد (1387). ”مدیریت دانش: مفاهیم و زیرساخت‌ها“ ، تهران: کتابدار.##طبرسا، غلامعلی، و اورمزدی، نوشین (1388). ”تبیین و سنجش عوامل زمینه‌ای برای استقرار مدیریت دانش؛ مطالعه‌ی موردی: شرکت ملی پخش فراورده‌های نفتی ایران، منطقه‌ی تهران“ ، پیام مدیریت، 26، 39-69.##علی‌پور یگانه، رضا، هندی، سیدصالح، و مطهری، سیدمهدیا (1393). ”اهمیت مدیریت داده در صنعت بالادستی نفت و گاز“ ، ماهنامه‌ی علمی-ترویجی اکتشاف و تولید نفت و گاز، 119، ۱۳-۲۰. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی نقش میانجی ظرفیت جذب دانش بر رابطه بین خط‌مشی‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی و عملکرد سازمانی (موردمطالعه: شرکت گاز استان قم)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Investigating the mediating role of knowledge absorptive capacity on relationship between human resource management policies and organizational performance
(Case Study: Qom Province Gas Company)
</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>امروزه، کارکنان سرمایه&#8204;های هر سازمان بشمار می&#8204;آیند که سازمان&#8204;ها را قادر می سازد با بهره&#8204;گیری از منابع انسانی توانمند عملکرد رقابتی خود را بهبود &#8204;بخشند. در همین زمینه،&#160; آموزش و توسعه منابع انسانی شایسته، به عملکرد سازمان&#8204;ها در خصوص اجرای مؤثر مجموعه خط&#8204;مشی&#8204;های مدیریت منابع انسانی وابسته است تا بتواند زمینه ساز ایجاد خلاقیت و نوآوری در سازمان باشد. از سوی دیگر، در بازارهای به&#8204;سرعت در حال تغییر امروز، دانش و ظرفیت جذب آن در ایجاد فرصت&#8204;های نوآوری و مزیت رقابتی شرکت&#8204;ها نقش محوری دارد. با توجه به اهمیت این موضوع در شرکت گاز، هدف مطالعه حاضر بررسی تأثیر خط&#8204;مشی&#8204;های مدیریت منابع انسانی بر عملکرد سازمانی و تبیین نقش میانجی ظرفیت جذب دانش در این رابطه بوده است. جامعه آماری تحقیق کلیه کارکنان رسمی شرکت گاز استان قم بوده است که 85 نفر بر اساس فرمول کوکران در این پیمایش شرکت داشتند. برای جمع&#8204;آوری داده&#8204;ها از سه پرسشنامه (خط&#8204;مشی&#8204;های مدیریت منابع انسانی، عملکرد سازمانی و ظرفیت جذب) استفاده&#8204; شده است. روایی پرسشنامه از طریق صوری و محتوایی و پایایی با محاسبه مقدار کرونباخ 87/0 تائید شد. تحلیل&#8204;ها با استفاده از نرم&#8204;افزار لیزرل به&#8204;منظور ارزیابی مدل معادلات ساختاری صورت گرفت. یافته&#8204;های به&#8204;دست&#8204;آمده حاکی از آن است که رابطه مثبت و معناداری بین متغیرهای تحقیق وجود داشته و ظرفیت جذب دانش در رابطه بین خط&#8204;مشی&#8204;های مدیریت منابع انسانی و عملکرد سازمانی، نقش میانجی دارد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Today, employees are the main capital of each organization that enables them to improve their competitive performance by utilizing their competent human resources. In this way, Training and development of competent human resources have been related to organizational performance in implementing human resource management policies, effectively, to be a base of creating creativity and innovation in organization. In other ways, in rapid changing markets, knowledge and knowledge absorption capability have a critical role in creating innovation opportunities and competitive advantage of companies. Given the importance of this issue in the gas company the purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of HRM policies on organizational performance and explain the mediating role of knowledge absorptive capacity in this regard. The statistical population of the research is all Official staff of Qom Gas Company that 85 of them participated in this survey based on Cochran's formula. Three questionnaires (HRM policies, organizational performance and knowledge absorptive capacity) were used to collect data. Validity of the questionnaire was verified formally and contently. Reliability was gained by calculating the Cronbach's value of 0.87. The analyzes were performed by using the LISREL software to evaluate the structural equation model. Findings indicate that there is a positive and significant relationship between research variables and knowledge absorption capability in the relationship between HRM and organizational performance has a mediating role.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>205</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>232</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد تقی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>صادقی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Taghi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sadeghi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>sadeghi22@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فرزاد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>موحدی سبحانی</Family>
				<NameE>Farzad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Movahedi Sobhani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رجب زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rajab Zadeh Ghatari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تربیت مدرس</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شیرازی</Family>
				<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shirazi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد قم</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد قم</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Human Resource Policies- Knowledge Absorption Capability- Organizational Performance</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>خط‌مشی‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ظرفیت جذب دانش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عملکرد سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abecassis-Moedas, C.; Mahmoud-Jouini, S.B. (2008), “Absorptive capacity and source-recipient complementarity in designing new products: an empirically derived framework”, Journal of Product Innovation Management, vol. 25, No. 5, pp. 473–490.##Ale Ebrahim, N. Ahmed, S., &amp; Taha, Z. (2010), &quot;SMEs; Virtual research and development (R&amp;D) teams and new product development: A literature review [Review]&quot;, International Journal of the Physical Sciences, 5(7), 916–930.##Alfes, K., Shantz, A. D., Truss, C., &amp; Soane, E. C. (2013), “The link between perceived human resource management practices, engagement and employee behavior: A moderated mediation model”, The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 24(2), 330–351.##Appelbaum, E., Bailey, T., Berg, P., Kallerberg, A.L. (2000), “Manufacturing Advantage: Why High performance Work Systems Pay Off”, Cornell University Press, Itacha, New York.##Argote, L., McEvily, B., &amp; Reagans, R. (2003), “Managing knowledge in organizations: An integrative framework and review of emerging themes”, Management Science, 49(4), p 575.##Arthur, J. B. (1994), “Effects of human resource systems on manufacturing performance and turnover”, Academy of Management Journal, 37, 670–687.##Barney, J. (1991), “Firm resources and sustained competitive advantage”, Journal of management, 17(1), 99-120.##Boxall, P., Purcell, J. (2003), “Strategy and Human Resource Management”, First ed. Palgrave Macmillan.##Cascio W., F., (1998), “Managing Human Resources”, Boston, McGraw Hill Publishing Company. ##Chang, S., Gong, Y., Way, S. a., &amp; Jia, L. (2013), “Flexibility-oriented HRM systems, absorptive capacity, and market responsiveness and firm innovativeness”, Journal of Management, 39(7), 1924–1951.##Chen, Y., Chang, C. &amp; Lin, Y. (2014), “The determinants of green radical and incremental innovation performance: green shared vision, green absorptive capacity, and green organizational ambidexterity”, Sustainability, 6, 7787–7806.##Chenhal, R. H., &amp; Longfield- Smith, K. (2007), “Multiple Perspective of Performance Measures European”, Management Journal, 25, 266-282.##Chiang, J.C.H. (2007), “Subsidiary performance in MNCs: the influences of absorptive capacity and social capital on knowledge transfer”, Nova Southern University, Fort Lauderdale, FL, doctoral dissertation.##Chuang, C.H., &amp; Liao, H. (2010), “Strategic human resource management in service context: Taking care of business by taking care of employees and customers”, Personnel Psychology, 63(1), 196-253.##Chuang, C.H., Jackson, S. E., &amp; Jiang, Y. (2016), “Can knowledge-intensive teamwork be managed? Examining the roles of HRM systems, leadership, and tacit knowledge”, Journal of Management, Vol 42, Issue 2, 524-554.##Chuang, C.-H., Jackson, S.E., Jiang, Y. (2010), “Using team-based HRM systems and empowering leadership to support knowledge acquisition and sharing”, Academy of Management Annual Meeting Proceedings, Best Paper Proceedings of the Academy of Management Annual Conference, pp. 1–6. ##Clark, I., Colling, T. (2005), “The management of human resources in project management-led organizations”, Pers. Rev. 34, 178–191.##Cohen, W. M., and Levinthal, D. A. (1990), “Absorptive Capacity:A New Perspective on Learning and Innovation”, Administrative Science Quarterly, 35(1):128-152.##Collins, C. J., &amp; Smith, K. G. (2006), “Knowledge exchange and combination: The role of human resource practices in the performance of high-technology firms”, Academy of Management Journal, 49(3), 544–560.##Cooper MJ, Upton N. &amp; Seaman S. (2005), “ Customer relationship management: A comparative analysis of family and nonfamily business practices”, Journal of Small Business Management 43(3): 242–256.##Delaney, J.T. &amp; Huselid, M.A. (1996), “The Impact of Human Resource Management Practices on Perception of Organizational Performance”, Academy of Management Journal, Vol. 39 No. 4, pp. 949-969.Denis, C. and Michel, T. (2011),##Delmas, M.A., Hoffmann, V.H. &amp; Kuss, M. (2011), “Under the tip of the iceberg: absorptive capacity, environmental strategy, and competitive advantage”, Business and Society, 50, 116–154.##DeNisi, S.A. and Griffin, W.R. (2001),”Human Resources Management”, Houghton Mifflin Company, New York, NY.##Dominguez, A.A. (2011), “The Impact of Human Resource Disclosure on Corporate Image”, Journal of Human Resource Costing &amp; Accounting, Vol. 15, No.4, pp.279 ± 298.##Dong, J.Q., McCarthy, K.J., Schoenmakers, W.W.M.E., (2017), “How central is too central? Organizing inter organizational collaboration networks for breakthrough innovation”, J. Prod. Innov. Manag, (in press).##Dong, J.Q., Yang, C.-H., (2016), “Being central is a double-edged sword: knowledge network centrality and new product development in U.S. pharmaceutical industry”, Technol. Forecast. Soc. Chang, 113 (1B), 379–385.##Edwards, J. R., &amp; Bagozzi, R. P. (2000), “On the nature and direction of relationships between constructs and measures”, Psychological Methods, 5(2), 155-174.##Ekaterini, G. (2010), “Impact of Leadership Styles on four variables of Executive Workforces”, International Journal of Business and Management, Vol. 5 No. 6, pp. 3-16.##G. Cepeda, D. Vera, (2007), “Dynamic capabilities and operational capabilities: a knowledge management perspective”, Journal of Business Research, Vol. 60, 426–437.##Garcia-Morales, V. J., Ruiz-Moreno, A., &amp; Liorens-Montes, F. J. (2007), “Effects of technology absorptive capacity and technology proactivity on organizational learning, innovation and performance: an empirical examination”, Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 19(4), 527-558.##George, G., Zahra, S. A., Wheatley, K. K., &amp; Khan, R. (2001), “The effects of alliance portfolio characteristics and absorptive capacity on performance: a study of biotechnology firms”, The Journal of High Technology Management Research, 12(2), 205-226. ##Gerhart, B. (2007), “Perspectives on Organizational Fit”, First ed. Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, London New York.##Gupta, A. K., &amp; Govindarajan, V. (2000), “Knowledge flows within multinational corporations”, Strategic Management Journal, 21, 473-406.##Haenlein, M., Kaplan, A.M., (2004), “A beginner’s guide to partial least squares analysis”, Understanding Statistics, 3 (4), 283-297.##Harvey, G., Skelcher, C., Spencer, E., Jas, P., &amp; Walshe, K. (2010), “Absorptive capacity in a non-market environment”, Public Management Review, 12(1), 77-97.##Huemann, M., Keegan, A., Turner, J.R. (2007), “Human resource management in the project-oriented company: a review”, Int. J. Proj. Manag, 25, 315–323.##Hult, G. T. M., Ketchen, D. J., &amp; Slater, S. F. (2005), “Market orientation and performance: An integration of disparate approaches”, Strategic Management Journal, 26(12), 1171–1181.##Huselid, M. A., &amp; Becker, B. E. (2011), “Bridging micro and macro domains: Workforce differentiation and strategic human resource”, Journal of Management, 37(2),421-428.##Huselid, M.A. (1995), “The Impact of Human Resources Management Practices on Turnover, Productivity and Corporate Finance Performance”, Academy of Management Journal, Vol.38 No. 3, pp. 635-672.##Jackson, S.E. and Schuler, R.S. (2000), “Managing Human Resource, A Partnership Perspective”, Southern-Western College Publishing, London.##Jansen, J.J.P., Bosch, F.A.J.V.D., Volberda, H.W. (2005), “Managing potential and realized absorptive capacity: how do organizational antecedents matter?”, Acad. Manag. J, 48, 999–1015.##Jiménez-Jiménez, D., &amp; Valle, R.S. (2011), “Innovation, organizational learning, and performance”, Journal of Business Research, 64(4), 408-417.##Kase, R., Paauwe, J., Zupan, N. (2009), “HR practices, interpersonal relations, and intrafirm knowledge transfer in knowledge-intensive firms: a social network perspective”, Hum. Resour. Manag, 48, 615–639.##Katou, A. (2008),”Measuring the impact of HRM on organizational performance”, Journal of Industrial Engineering and Management, Vol 1, No 2, pp. 119-142.##Katou, A. and Budhwar, P. (2006), “The Effect of Human Resources Management Systems on Organizational Performance: Test of a Mediating Model”, International Journal of Human Resources Management, Vol. 17 No. 7, pp. 1223-1253.##Keegan, A., Huemann, M., Turner, J.R., (2012), “Beyond the line: exploring the HRM responsibilities of line managers, project managers and the HRM department in four project-oriented companies in The Netherlands, Austria,the UK and the USA”, Int. J. Hum. Resour. Manag. 23, 3085–3104.##Khan, M.A. (2010), “Effects of Human Resource Management Practices on Organizational Performance ± an Empirical Study of oil and Gas Industry in Pakistan”, European Journal of Economics, Finance and Administrative Sciences, Vol. 24, pp. 157-175.##Kuokkanen L, Jouko K. (2003), “Promoting or Impeding Empowerment: Nurses Assessment of their Work Environment”, J Nurs Administration.; 33:209-15.##Lane PJ., Salk JE., Lyles, MA., (2001), “Absorptive capacity, learning, and performance in international joint ventures”, Strategic Management Journal, Vol. 22, No. 11, pp. 39–61.##Lane, P.J., Koka, B.R. and Pathak, S. (2006), “The reification of absorptive capacity: A critical review and rejuvenation of the construct”, Academy of Management Review, 31(4), 833–863.##Leal-Rodríguez, A.L., Leal-Millán, A., Roldán-Salgueiro, J.L., Ortega-Gutiérrez, J., (2013), “Knowledge management, relational learning and the effectiveness of innovation outcomes”, Serv. Ind. J. 33, 1294–1311.##Lee, F. H., Lee, F.-Z. And Wu, W.-Y. (2010), “The Relationship between Human Resource Management Practices, Business Strategy and Firm Performance: Evidence from Steel Industry in Taiwan”, The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 21(9):1351-1372.##Lepak, D.P., Liao, H., Chung, Y., Harden, E.E. (2006), “A conceptual review of human resource management systems in strategic human resource management research”, Res. Pers. Hum. Resour. Manag. 25, 217–271.##Lewin, A. Y., Massini, S., &amp; Peeters, C. (2011), “Microfoundations of internal and external absorptive capacity routines”, Organization Science, 22(1), 81–98.##Liao S.H &amp; Hu T.C. (2007), “Knowledge transfer and competitive advantage on environmental uncertainty: An empirical study of the Taiwan semiconductor industry”, Technovation, Vol. 27, pp. 402-411.##Lichtenthaler, U. &amp; Lichtenthaler, E. (2012), “Technology transfer across organizational boundaries: Absorptive capacity and desorptive capacity”, California Management Review, 53(1): 154-170.##Lichtenthaler, U. (2009), “Absorptive Capacity, Environmental Turbulence, and the Complementarity of Organizational Learning Processes”, Academy of Management Journal, Vol. 52, No. 4, pp.822-846.##Liu, Hefu, Ke, Weiling, Wei, Kwok Kee, Hua, Zhongsheng. (2012), “The Impact of IT Capabilities on Firm Performance: The Mediating Roles of Absorptive Capacity and Supply Chain Agility”, Decision Support Systems, 54(3):1452–1462.##Malik, M.E., Nawab, S., Naeem, B. and Danish, R.Q. (2010), “Job Satisfaction and Organization Commitment of University Teachers in Public Sectors of Pakistan”, International Journal of Business and Management, Vol. 5, No. 6, pp. 17-26.##Mayson, S. and Barret, R. (2006), “The Science and Practices of Human Resources Management in Small Firms”, Human Resources Management Review, Vol. 16 No. 4, pp.447-455.##Meng, X., Gallagher, B., (2012), “The impact of incentive mechanisms on project performance”, Int. J. Proj. Manag. 30, 352–362.##Meyer, M. and Kirsten, M. (2005), “Introduction to Human Resource Anagement”, New Africa Books (Pvt) Ltd, Claremont, CA.##Minbaeva, D., Pedersen, T., Björkman, I., Fey, C. F., &amp; Jeong, H. (2003), “MNC knowledge transfer, subsidiary absorptive capacity, and HRM”, Journal of International Business Studies, 34(6), 586-599.##Minbaeva, D.B., Mäkelä, K., Rabbiosi, L., (2012), “Linking HRM and knowledge transfer via individual-level mechanisms”, Hum. Resour.Manag. 51, 387–405.##Mohsin, M., Bashir, M. and Latif, A. (2013), “The effect of information technology support on innovation concepts: A study of textile sector in Pakistan”, International Journal of Academic Research and Social Sciences, 3(3), 105-112.##Morgan RE, Strong CA. (2003), “Business performance and dimensions of strategic orientation”, Journal of Business Research, 56: 163–176.##Morgan, R. and C. Turnell, (2003), “Market-based organizational learning and market performance gains”, British Journal of Management, 14: 255–274.##Murray, S. and J. Peyrefitte, (2007), “Knowledge type and communication media choice in the knowledge transferprocess”, Journal of Managerial Issues, 19: 111–133.##Neely, A. D.; Adams, C., &amp; Kennerley, M. (2002), &quot;The Performance Prism: The Scorecard for Measuring and Managing Stakeholder Relationships”, Financial Times/Prentice Hall, London.##Nonaka I., Toyama R., and Hirata T. (2008), “Managing Flow: A Process Theory of the Knowledge-based Firm”, New York: Palgrave Macmillan.##Park, B. I. (2011), “Knowledge transfer capacity of multinational enterprises and technology acquisition in international joint ventures”, International Business Review, 20(1), 75-87.##Patterson, W. &amp; Ambrosini, V. (2015), “Configuring absorptive capacity as a key process for research intensive firms”, Technovation, 36, 77-89.##Patton, D. (2014), “Realizing Potential: The Impact of Business Incubation upon the Absorptive Capacity of New Technology Based Firms”, International Small Business Journal, 32(8): 897–917.##Paul, L. (2009), “Action Theory and the Training and Performance Application: Performance Templates”, Industrial and Commercial Training, Vol. 41, No. 5, pp. 270-279.##Popaitoon, S., Siengthai, S. (2014), “The moderating effect of human resource management practices on the relationship between knowledge absorptive capacity and project performance in project-oriented companies”, International Journal of Project Management, 32, 908–920.##Qureshi, M.T., Ayisha, A., Mohammad, A.K., Rauf, A.S. and Syed, T.H. (2010), “Do Human Resource Management Practices have an Impact on Financial Performance of Banks? ”, African Journal of Business Management, Vol. 4, No. 7, pp. 1281-1288.##Rehman, S. (2012), “A Study of Public Sector Organizations with Respect to Recruitment, Job Satisfaction and Retention”, Global Business &amp; Management Research, Vol. 4, No. 1, pp.76-88.##Rizov, M. and Croucher, R. (2009), “Human Resource Management and Performance in European Firms”, Cambridge Journal of Economics, Vol. 33, No. 2, pp. 253-272.##Roberts N., Galluch, P. S., Dinger, M., Grover V. (2012), “Absorptive capacity and information systems research: review, synthesis, and directions for future research”, MIS Quarterly, 36(2):625-648.##Segares, A. (1997),  “Assessing the Unidimensionality of Measurement: Paradigm &amp; Illustration Within the Context of Information System”, International Journal of Management Science, 25(1), 8.##Seo, Y.W., Chae, S.W., Lee, K.C., (2011), “The impact of creative self-efficacy, IT support, and knowledge on individual creativity through absorptive capacity. In: U-and E-Service, Science and Technology”, Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, pp. 177–186.##Singh, K. (2004), “Impact of HR Practices on Perceived Firm Performance in India: Asia Pacific”, Journal of Human Resources, Vol. 42, No.3, pp.301-317.##Söderlund, J., Bredin, K., (2006), “HRM in project-intensive firms: changes and challenges”, Hum. Resour. Manag. 45, 249–265.##Song, J. (2014), “Subsidiary absorptive capacity and knowledge transfer within multinational corporations”, Journal of International Business Studies, 45(1), 73–84.##Subramony, M., (2009), “A meta-analytic investigation of the relationship between HRM bundles and firm performance”, Hum. Resour. Manag. 48, 745–768.##Tang, F, Mu, J, &amp; MacLachlan, D.L. (2010), “Disseminative capacity, organizational structure and knowledge transfer”, Expert Systems with Applications: An International Journal, Vol. 37, pp.1586-1593.##Teece, D.J., Pisano, G. &amp; Shuen, A. (1997), “Dynamic capabilities and strategic management”, Strategic Management Journal, 18: 509-534. ##Tessema, M. and Soeter, J. (2006), “Challenges and Prospects of HRM in Developing Countries: Testing the HRM-Performance Link in Eritrean Civil Service”, The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 17(1), 30-42.##Tran, Y., Mahnke, V. &amp; Ambos, B. (2010), “The Effect of Quantity, Quality and Timing of Headquarters-initiated Knowledge Flows on Subsidiary Performance”, Manag Int Rev, Vol. 50, pp. 493–511.##Turner, R.J., Huemann, M., Keegan, A. (2008), “Human Resource Management in the Project-oriented Organization”, Project Management Institute, USA.##Y. Wu, (2010), “Applicability of the resource-based and dynamic-capability views under environmental volatility”, Journal of Business Research, 63 (1), 27–31.##Zahra, S. A. and George, G. (2002), “Absorptive capacity: A review, reconceptualization and extension”, Academy of Management Review, 27(2): 185–203.##برومند، مجتبی؛ رنجبری، مریم (1388)، «اقدامات راهبردی مدیریت منابع انسانی و عملکرد نوآوری: با تأکید بر نقش مدیریت دانش»، نشریه توسعه انسانی پلیس، دوره 6، شماره 24، صص: 41 -54.##شوماخر، رندال ای؛ لومکس، ریچارد جی (1388)، «مقدمه‌ای بر مدل‌سازی معادله ساختاری». ترجمه قاسمی، وحید. چاپ اول، تهران: انتشارات جامعه شناسان.##میر سپاسی، ناصر (1394)، «مدیریت استراتژیک منابع انسانی و روابط کار با نگرشی به روند جهانی‌سازی»، چاپ پنجم، تهران، انتشارات کتاب‌سرا.##هومن، حیدر علی (1384)، «مدل یابی معادلات ساختاری با کاربرد نرم‌افزار لیزرل»، چاپ سوم، تهران، انتشارات سمت. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
