<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1398</YEAR>
<VOL>10</VOL>
<NO>40</NO>
<MOSALSAL>40</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>228</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>طراحی فرامدلی برای توسعه‌ استراتژیک منابع انسانی براساس الگوی سیپ با مرور هدف‌مند  مطالعه‌های پیشین</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Designing a Meta Model for Strategic Human Resource Development based on the CIIP Framework by Reviewing Previous Studies</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف پژوهش حاضر،بررسی و مرور هدف&#173;مند تعاریف، چارچوب&#173; ها و مدل &#173;های پیشین توسعه&#173; استراتژیک منابع انسانی به&#8204;منظور ارائه&#173; ی مدلی جامع و نظام&#173; مند برای توسعه&#173; استراتژیک منابع انسانی براساسِ الگوی سیپ می&#173; باشد. روشِ پژوهش حاضر از نوع کیفی است که براساس روش فراترکیب انجام شده است. برای جمع&#173; آوری داده&#173;ها از داده&#8204;های ثانویه به نام اسناد و مدارک گذشته استفاده&#173; شده است. شیوه&#173; تحلیل داده&#173; ها تلفیقی از تحلیل محتوای کمّی و کیفی می &#173;باشد. جامعه&#173; مورد بررسی این پژوهش، کلیه&#173; مقاله &#173;های منتشر شده در مجله&#173; های ISI، کتاب&#173; ها&#173; و پایان&#173;نامه&#8204;های خارجی مرتبط با موضوع پژوهش در بازه&#173; زمانی 2017-1989 بود. پژوهشگران مطابق با الگوی سیپ برای هر یک از چهار مقوله اصلی شامل &#34;بستر (زمینه)&#34;، &#34;درون&#173;داد (ورودی)&#34;، &#34;فرآیند&#34; و &#34;برون&#173;داد (خروجی)&#34;، مقوله&#8204;های فرعی متعددی که در پژوهش&#173;های مختلف خارجی به آن اشاره شده بود، را شناسایی کرده&#173;اند. براساسِ این مقوله&#160; &#173;ها، مدل یکپارچه نهایی ارائه و اعتبارسنجی شده است. فرامدل ارائه شده در پژوهش حاضر، می &#173;تواند به متخصصان و کارشناسان حوزه توسعه منابع انسانی کمک کند که قبل از شروع اجراء و پیاده&#173; سازی موفقیت &#173;آمیز توسعه استراتژیک منابع انسانی، چه بسترها (زمینه&#8204;ها) و درون دادهایی و در حین اجراء چه فرایند&#173;ها و مکانیزم&#173; هایی را لازم است در نظر بگیرند و در نهایت، برون&#173; دادهای آن، چه خواهد بود.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>This study tended to provide a comprehensive and systematic model for SHRD based on the CIIP model. To this mean, a targeted review of the definitions, frameworks and models of (SHRD) was carried out. The research method was qualitative meta-synthesis. For data collection, secondary data sources called previous documents were explored. The method of data analysis was a combination of quantitative and qualitative content analysis. The study population consisted of all the articles on the SURD topic, published in ISI journals, books and foreign dissertations between the years 1989-2017. Based on the CIIP framework, researchers recognized several subcategories for each of the four categories of &#34;context&#34;, &#34;input&#34;, &#34;process&#34;, and &#34;product&#34; mentioned in various foreign studies, repeatedly. As a result, a final integrated model was presented and validated on the basis of these categories and relevant subcategories. This metamodel is applicable to HRD professionals to help them determine which &#34;contexts&#34; and &#34;inputs&#34; are required to consider before a successful implementation of strategic human resource development, to help them determine the required &#8220;processes&#8221; and &#8220;mechanisms&#8221; during implementation, and to help them determine the final products.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>3</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>36</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدیه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>اسدی</Family>
				<NameE>Mahdieh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Asadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>asadi.mahdieh@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حمیدرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>یزدانی</Family>
				<NameE>Hamidreza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Yazdani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hryazdani@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مقدم زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Moghadamzadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>amoghadamzadeh@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>زارعی متین</Family>
				<NameE>Hasan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zarei Matin</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>matin@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Strategic human resource development (SHRD)</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>CIPP Framework</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Targeted review</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Meta-Synthesis</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Quantitative and qualitative Content analysis.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>توسعه استراتژیک منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>الگوی سیپ</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بررسی و مرور هدف‌مند</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فراترکیب</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تحلیل محتوای کمّی و کیفی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>AbuKhalifeh, A. N., Som, A. P. M., &amp; AlBattat, A. R. (2013). Strategic Human Resource Development in Hospitality Crisis Management: A Conceptual Framework for Food and Beverage Departments. International Journal of Business Administration, 4(1), 39.##Alagaraja, M. (2013). Mobilizing organizational alignment through strategic human resource development. Human Resource Development International, 16(1), 74-93.##Ansett, S. (2005, April). Boundary spanner: The gatekeeper of innovation in partnerships. In Accountability Forum, Vol. 6, No. 4, 36-44.##Anzaya, M. (2004). The Relationship between Business Strategy Types and Training Emphasis in Selected Companies in Kenya (Doctoral dissertation, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign).##Armstrong, G. (2005). Differentiation through people: How can HR move beyond business partner?. Human Resource Management: Published in Cooperation with the School of Business Administration, The University of Michigan and in alliance with the Society of Human Resources Management, 44(2), 195-199.##Ashton, D. &amp; Green, F. (1996). Education, training and the global economy. Cheltenham, UK: Edward Elgar.##Bae, J. &amp; Lawler, J. J. (2000). Organizational and HRM strategies in Korea: Impact on firm performance in an emerging economy. Academy of management journal, 43(3), 502-517.##Barney, J. (1991). Firm resources and sustained competitive advantage. Journal of management, 17(1), 99-120.##Barron, D., Phipps, V., &amp; Steinmeyer, P. (2005). After the disaster: 10 issues for employers. Workforce Management Online (Nov.), accessed Jan, 2, 2006.##Baruch, Y. &amp; Peiperl, M. (1997). High flyers: glorious past, gloomy present, any future? Career Development International, 2(7), 354-358.##Beck, C. T. (2002). A meta-synthesis of qualitative research. MCN: The American Journal of ##Maternal/Child Nursing, 27(4), 214-221.##Becker, G. (1964). Human capital national bureau of economic research. New York, 11.##Becker, B. E., Huselid, M. A., Huselid, M. A., &amp; Ulrich, D. (2001). The HR scorecard: Linking people, strategy, and performance. Harvard Business Press.##Beer, M. &amp; Spector, B. (1989), ``Corporate wide transformations in human resource management'', in Walton, R.E. and Lawrence, P.R. (Eds), Human Resource Management. Trends and Challenges, Harvard University School Press, Boston, MA.##Bench, S. &amp; Day, T. (2010). The user experience of critical care discharge: a meta-synthesis of qualitative research. International journal of nursing studies, 47(4), 487-499.##Berge, Z. L. (2008). Why it is so hard to evaluate training in the workplace. Industrial and Commercial Training, 40(7), 390-395.##Blackwell, R. &amp; Blackmore, P. (2003). Towards strategic staff development in higher education. McGraw-Hill Education (UK).##Blazey, M. L. (2013). Insights to Performance Excellence 2013-2014: Understanding the Integrated Management System and the Baldrige Criteria. ASQ Quality Press.##Bontis, N. &amp; Fitzenz, J. (2002). Intellectual Capital ROI: A causal map of human capital antecedents and consequents. Journal of Intellectual Capital, 3(3), 223-247.##Boudreau, J. W. &amp; Ramstad, P. M. (2004). Talentship”: A decision science for HR. Why HR measurement must focus on informing better talent decisions. Strategic HR Review, 3(2), 28-31.##Burgoyne, J. (1986). Management development for the individual and the organization. Personnel Management, 40–44.##Cascio, W. F. (2005). From business partner to driving business success: The next step in the evolution of HR management. Human Resource Management: Published in Cooperation with the School of Business Administration, The University of Michigan and in alliance with the Society Human Resources Management of, 44(2), 159-163.##Chenail, R. J. &amp; Weiss, A. D. (2007). Utilizing qualitative meta-synthesis to conduct systematic reviews of primary healthcare research.##Chermack, T. J. &amp; Swanson, R. A. (2008). Scenario planning: human resource development's strategic learning tool. Advances in Developing Human Resources, 10(2), 129-146.##CIPD (2010). Annual Survey Report( 2010): Learning and Talent Development, CIPD, UK.##Collins, C. J. &amp; Clark, K. D. (2003). Strategic human resource practices, top management team social networks, and firm performance: The role of human resource practices in creating organizational competitive advantage. Academy of management Journal, 46(6), 740-751.##Crutchfield, E. B. (2013). Developing Human Capital in American Manufacturing: A Case Study of Barriers to Training and Development (Studies on Industrial Productivity). New York: Routledge.##Davenport, T. H., Prusak, L., &amp; Wilson, H. J. (2003). What's the big idea?: Creating and capitalizing on the best management thinking. Harvard Business Press.##Davis, D. &amp; Daley, B. J. (2008). The learning organization and its dimensions as key factors in firms' performance. Human Resource Development International, 11(1), 51-66.##Deligny, A. (1998). Human resource development in France. Handout distributed at international HRD course, University of Minnesota, St. Paul.##Desimone, R. L., Werner, J. M., &amp; Harris, D. M. (2002). Human Resource Development. Orlando. Harcourt College Publishers Dulebohn, J.H. &amp; Ferris, G.R (1999). The role of influence tactics in perceptions of performance evaluations' fairness. Academy of Management Journal, 42(3), 288-303.##D'Netto, B., Bakas, F., &amp; Bordia, P. (2008). Predictors of management development effectiveness: an Australian perspective. International Journal of Training and Development, 12(1), 2-23.##Du Gay, P., Salaman, G., &amp; Rees, B. (1996). The conduct of management and the management of conduct: contemporary managerial discourse and the constitution of the  ‘competent’manager. Journal of Management Studies, 33(3), 263-282.##Dwyer, T. D. (2000). The elusive match: Building a strategic partnership between HR and business. International HR Journal, 9, 35-41.##Eisenhardt, K. M. &amp; Martin, J. A. (2000). Dynamic capabilities: what are they?. Strategic management journal, 21(10‐11), 1105-1121.##Espedal, B. (2005). Management development: Using internal or external resources in developing core competence. Human Resource Development Review, 4(2), 136-158.##Finfgeld, D. L. (2003). Metasynthesis: The state of the art—so far. Qualitative health research, 13(7), 893-904.##Fombrun, C., Tichy, N.M., &amp;  Deranna, M.A. (1984). Strategic Human Resource Management, Wiley, Chichester.##Fuller, J. &amp; Farrington, J. (1999). From training to performance improvement: Navigating the transition. Jossey-Bass/Pfeiffer.##Garavan, T. (1991). Strategic human resource development. Journal of European Industrial Training, 15(1), 17–30.##Garavan, T. N. (2007). A strategic perspective on human resource development. Advances in Developing Human Resources, 9(1), 11-30.##Garavan, T. N., Costine, P., &amp; Heraty, N. (1995). The emergence of strategic human resource development. Journal of European Industrial Training, 19(10), 4-10.##Garavan, T. N., Heraty, N., &amp; Morley, M. (1998). Actors in the HRD process: An exploratory study. International studies of management &amp; organization, 28(1), 114-135.##Garavan, T. N., McGuire, D., &amp; O’Donnell, D. (2004). Exploring human resource development: A levels of analysis approach. Human Resource Development Review, 3(4), 417-441.##Garavan, T. N. &amp; Carbery, R. (2012). Strategic human resource development. In J. P. Wilson (Ed.), International human resource development: Learning, education, and training for individuals and organizations (3rd ed.). London: Kogan Page Limited. ##Garavan, T., Shanahan, V., Carbery, R., &amp; Watson, S. (2016). Strategic human resource development: towards a conceptual framework to understand its contribution to dynamic capabilities. Human Resource Development International, 19(4), 289-306.##Gattiker, U. E. (1995). Firm and taxpayer returns from training of semiskilled employees. Academy of management Journal, 38(4), 1152-1173.##Gilley, J. W. &amp; Gilley, A. M. (1998). Strategically integrated HRD: Partnering to maximize organizational performance. Perseus Books.##Gilley, J. W. &amp; Maycunich, A. (2000). Organizational learning, performance and change. Da Capo Press.##Gilley, J. W. &amp; Maycunich Gilley, A. M. (2003). Strategically integrated HRD: A six-step approach to creating results-driven programs performance (2nd ed.). Cambridge, MA: Perseus Publishing.##Gist, M. E. &amp; Mitchell, T. R. (1992). Self-efficacy: A theoretical analysis of its determinants and malleability. Academy of Management Review, 17, 183–211.##Gold, J., Walton, J., Cureton, P., &amp; Anderson, L. (2011). Theorising and practitioners in HRD: the role of abductive reasoning. Journal of European Industrial Training, 35(3), 230-246.##Goldstein, I. L. &amp; Ford, J. K. (2002). Training in organizations: Needs assessment, development, and evaluation. Wadsworth/Thomson Learning.##Grieves, J. (2003). Strategic human resource development. Sage.##Grossman, R. J. (2007). New Competencies for HR: Researchers have identified six core competencies for top HR professionals. HR MAGAZINE, 52(6), 58.##Guest, D. E. (1991). Personnel management: the end of orthodoxy?. British Journal of Industrial Relations, 29(2), 149-175.##Hambrick, D. C. (2003). On the staying power of defenders, analyzers, and prospectors. Academy of Management Perspectives, 17(4), 115-118.##Harrison, R. (1992). Employee Development. Institute of Personnel Management, London. ##Harrison, R. (1997). Employee Development. London: Institute of Personnel Management.##Harrison, R. &amp; Kessels, J. W. (2004). Human resource development in a knowledge economy: An organisational view. New York, NY: Palgrave Macmillan.##Hillion, B. &amp; McLean, G. N. (1997). The status of human resource development in French companies. In R. J. Torraco (Ed.), Academy of Human Resource Development 1997 Conference Proceedings (pp. 694-701). Baton Rouge, LA: Academy of Human Resource Development.##Hu, P. (2007). Theorizing Strategic Human Resource Development: Linking Financial Performance and Sustainable Competitive Advantage. Online Submission.##Huselid, M. A. (1995). The impact of human resource management practices on turnover, productivity, and corporate financial performance. Academy of management journal, 38(3), 635-672.##Huselid, M. A., Jackson, S. E., &amp; Schuler, R. S. (1997). Technical and strategic human resources management effectiveness as determinants of firm performance. Academy of Management journal, 40(1), 171-188.##Jackson, S. E. &amp; Schuler, R. S. (2003). Managing Human Resources through Strategic Partnerships. 8th edn. South-Western, Cincinnati, OH.##Jankowicz, D. (1999). Editorial: Putting the “I” into HRD . . . Why do we do it? Human Resource Development International, 2(3), 171–174.##Jensen, L. A. &amp; Allen, M. N. (1996). Meta-synthesis of qualitative findings. Qualitative health research, 6(4), 553-560.##Kalamas, D. J. &amp; Kalamas, J. B. (2004). Developing employee capital: setting the stage for lifelong learning. Human Resource Development.##Kessels, J. W. M. &amp; Poell, R. F. (2004). Andragogy and social capital theory: The implications for human resource development. Advances in Developing Human Resources, 6(2), 146–157.##Kondrasuk, J. N. (2004). The effects of 9/11 and terrorism on human resource management: Recovery, reconsideration, and renewal. Employee Responsibilities and Rights Journal, 16(1), 25-35.##Lam, L. W. &amp; White, L. P. (1998). Human resource orientation and corporate performance. Human Resource Development Quarterly, 9(4), 351-364.##Lee, R. (1996). What makes training pay? Issues in People Management. London: Institute of Personnel and Development. ##Lee, M. (2003), HRD in a Complex World, Routledge, New York, NY.##Lee, M. &amp; Stead, V. (1998). Human resource development in the United Kingdom.Human Resource Development Quarterly, 9(3), 297–308.##Lepak, D. P., Bartol, K. M., &amp; Erhardt, N. L. (2005). A contingency framework for the delivery of HR practices. Human resource management review, 15(2), 139-159.##Lepak, D. P. &amp; Snell, S. A. (2003). Managing the human resource architecture for knowledge-based competition. In S. E. Jackson, H. A. Hitt and A. S. DeNisi (Eds. ). Managing knowledge for sustained competitive advantage. San Francisco; Jossey-Bass. 127-154.##Lockwood, N. R. &amp; SPHR, G. (2005). Crisis management in today’s business environment. SHRM Research Quarterly, 4, 1-9.##Luoma, M. (2000). Investigating the link between strategy and HRD. Personnel Review, 29(6), 769-790.##Lyons, R. (2016). Strategic Human Resource Development Impact on Organizational Performance: Does SHRD Matter? (Doctoral dissertation, North Dakota State University).##March, J. G. (1991). Exploration and exploitation in organizational learning. Organization science, 2(1), 71-87.##Maurice, M., Sellier, F., &amp; Silvestre, J. J. (1986). The social foundations of industrial power. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.##McCracken, M. &amp; Wallace, M. (2000a). Exploring strategic maturity in HRD–rhetoric, aspiration or reality?. Journal of European Industrial Training, 24(8), 425-426.##McCracken, M. &amp; Wallace, M. (2000b). Towards a redefinition of strategic HRD. Journal of European industrial training, 24(5), 281-290.##McLean, G. N. &amp; McLean, L. (2001). If we can't define HRD in one country, how can we define it in an international context?. Human Resource Development International, 4(3), 313-326. ##McWilliams, A., Van Fleet, D. D., &amp; Wright, P. M. (2001). Strategic management of human resources for global competitive advantage. Journal of Business Strategies, 18 (1), 1-24.##Millmore, M. &amp; Lewis, P. (2007). Strategic human resource management: contemporary issues. Pearson Education.##Morrow, J. L. &amp; Hitt, M. A. (2000). Rational and political models of strategic decision making: Understanding the role of firm performance and stakeholder political pressure. Public Administration And Public Policy, 79, 165-180.##Mueller, F. (1996). Human resources as strategic assets: An evolutionary resourcebased view. Journal of Management Studies, 33, 757-785.##Noe, R. A. (2002). Employee training and development. New York: McGraw-Hill.##O’Donnell, D., Garavan, T. N., &amp; McCarthy, A. (2001). Understanding the Irish VET system: Beyond neoclassicism. International Journal of Manpower, 22(5), 425-444.##Okongwu, S. O. (1995). Competency requirements for training and development instructors in the Nigerian petroleum industry for the 1990s. Unpublished doctoral dissertation, University of Minnesota, St. Paul.##Opperman, C. &amp; Meyer, M. (2008). Integrating training needs analysis, assessment and evaluation: aligning learning with business results. Knowres Publishing.##Ostroff, C. (2000). Human resource management and firm performance: Practices, systems, and contingencies. Unpublished manuscript. Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ.##Pasek, J. I. (2002). Crisis management for HR, HR Magazine, 47(8), 111–115.##Paterson, B. L., Thorne, S. E., Canam, C., &amp; Jillings, C. (2001). Meta-study of qualitative health research: A practical guide to meta-analysis and meta-synthesis (Vol. 3). Sage.##Peterson, S. L. (2008). Creating and sustaining a strategic partnership: A model for human resource development. Journal of Leadership Studies, 2(2), 83-97.##Pettigrew, A., Sparrow, P., &amp; Hendry, C. (1988). The forces that trigger training. Personnel Management, 20(12), 28-32.##Pfeffer, J. (1994). Competitive advantage through people: Unleashing the power of the work force (No. 04; e-book.).##Pfeffer, J. (1998). The real keys to high performance. Leader to leader, (8), 23-29.##Pfeffer, J. &amp; Veiger, J. F. (1999). Putting people first for organizational success. Academy of Management Perspectives, 13(2), 37-48.##Phillips, J. (2003). Return on investment in training and performance improvement programs. 2nd ed. Boston, MA: Butterworth-Heinemann.##Porter, M. E. (1980). Competitive strategy: techniques for analyzing industries and competitors.##Porter, M. E. (1985). Competitive advantage: creating and sustaining superior performance. 1985. New York: FreePress, 43, 214.##Prahalad, C. K. &amp; Hamel, G. (1990). The Core Competence of the Corporation, Harvard Business Review. ##Rainbird, H. (1994). The changing role of the training function: a test for the integration of human resource and business strategies? Human Resource Management Journal, 5(1), 72-90.##Robinson, D. G. &amp; Robinson, J. C. (1996). Performance Consulting: Moving beyond training. San Francisco: Berrett-Koehler.##Robinson, D. G. &amp; Robinson, J. (2005). Strategic business partner: Aligning people strategies with business goals. Berrett-Koehler Publishers.##Rothwell, W. J. &amp; Kazanas, H. C. (1994). Human resource development: A strategic approach. Amherst, MA: Human Resource Development Press.##Rummler, G. A. &amp; Brache, A. P. (1995). Improving performance: Managing the white space on the organization chart (2nd ed). San Francisco: Jossey-Bass.##Sahoo, Ajit Kumar, &amp; Sahoo, Chandan Kumar. (2012). Impact of Strategic HRD Initiatives on Individual Performance. Productivity, 53((2, 194-202.##Salisbury, M. &amp; Plass, J. (2001). A conceptual framework for a knowledge management system. Human Resource Development International, 4(4), 451–464.##Sandelowski, M. &amp; Barroso, J. (2007). Handbook for synthesizing qualitative research. New York, NY: Springer.##Schneider, B. &amp; White, S. S. (2004). Service quality: Research perspectives (Vol. 107). Sage.##Semler, S. W. (1997). Systematic agreement: A theory of organizational alignment. Human Resource Development Quarterly, 8(1), 23-40.##Snell, S. A. (1992). Control theory in strategic human resource management: The mediating effect of administrative information. Academy of management Journal, 35(2), 292-327.##Swanson, R. A. (1995). Human resource development: Performance is the key. Human Resource Development Quarterly, 6(2), 207-213.##Swanson, R. A. (2001). Human resource development and its underlying theory. Human Resource Development International, 4(3), 299-312.##Swanson, R. A. &amp; Holton, E. F. (2009). Foundations of Human Resource Development. 2nd edn. Berrett-Koehler, San Francisco.##Thackwray, B. (1997). Effective evaluation of training and development in higher education, London: Kogan Page.##Torraco, R. J. &amp; Swanson, R. A. (1995). The strategic roles of human resource development. Human Resource Planning, 18, 10-21.##Torraco, R. J. &amp; Swanson, R. A. (1996). The strategic roles of human resource development. Human Resource Planning, 18, 10-21.##Tseng, C. C. &amp; McLean, G. N. (2008). Strategic HRD practices as key factors in organizational learning. Journal of European Industrial Training, 32(6), 418-432.##Ulrich, D. (1996). Human Resource Champions. The next agenda for adding value and delivering results. Boston, Mass.: Harvard Business School Press. In World Economic Forum (2010a)‗ Stimulating Economies through Fostering Talent Mobility ‘World Economic Forum (2011), Global Talent Risk–Seven Responses ‘World Migration Report 2010b‗ An Overview of International Migration Trends.##Ulrich, D. (1998). A new mandate for human resources. Harvard Business Review, 76(1), 124–133.##Walton, J. (1999).Strategic human resource development,” Financial Times, Prentice Hall, London.##Wang, J., Hutchins, H. M., &amp; Garavan, T. N. (2009). Exploring the strategic role of human resource development in organizational crisis management. Human Resource Development Review, 8(1), 22-53.##Watkins, K. E. &amp; Marsick, V. J. (1995). The case for learning. In Proceedings of the 1995, Academy of Human Resource Development Annual Conference. Baton Rouge, LA: Academy of Human Resource.##Williamson, O. E. (1981). The economics of organization: The transaction cost approach. American journal of sociology, 87(3), 548-577.##Wognum, I., Bosker, R., &amp; Torraco, R. J. (1998). Strategic HRD aligning and HRD effectiveness.##Wognum, I. &amp; Fond Lam, J. (2000). Stakeholder involvement in strategic HRD aligning: the impact on HRD effectiveness. International Journal of Training and Development, 4(2), 98-110.##Wood, S. &amp; De Menezes, L. (1998). High commitment management in the UK: Evidence from the workplace industrial relations survey, and employers' manpower and skills practices survey. Human Relations, 51(4), 485-515.##Woolfe, R. (1993). The path to strategic alignment. Information Strategy-Pennsauken-, 9, 13-23.##Wright, P. M. &amp; Snell, S. A. (1991). Toward an integrative view of strategic human resource management. Human resource management review, 1(3), 203-225.##Yang, J. C. &amp; McLean, G. N. (1994). Perceived competencies needed by human resource development managers in Korea. In T. C. Head (Ed.), Proceedings of the 24th Annual Information Exchange of the Organisation Development Institute (PP: 90-99). Cleveland, OH: The Organisation Development Institute.##Zemke, R. (1985). In Search of a Training Philosophy. Training, 22(10), 93.##Zimmer, L. (2006). Qualitative meta‐synthesis: a question of dialoguing with texts. Journal of advanced nursing, 53(3), 311-318.##Zula, K. J. &amp; Chermack, T. J. (2007). Integrative literature review: Human capital planning: A review of literature and implications for human resource development. Human Resource Development Review, 6(3), 245-262.#### ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>مدل توسعه اخلاق حرفه‌ای از طریق شناسایی عوامل موثر بر آن </TitleF>
		<TitleE>Model of Professional Ethics Development by Identifying its Effective Factors</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف از پژوهش حاضر شناسایی عوامل موثر در توسعه اخلاق حرفه&#8204;ای و ارائه مدلی در این زمینه بود. این پژوهش بر اساس هدف، اکتشافی-توصیفی و بر اساس نتیجه، کاربردی- توسعه&#8204;ای بوده و از روش ترکیبی با ابزار پرسش&#8204;نامه&#8204; محقق ساخته و تحلیل محتوا به انجام رسیده است. در ابتدا، عوامل موثر در توسعه اخلاقِ حرفه&#8204;ای به روش تحلیل محتوا از دیدگاه صاحب نظران شناسایی گردید. جامعه آماری شامل 220 نفر از کارکنان امور بین&#8204;المللِ شرکت ملی نفت ایران بود که با استفاده از جدول مورگان، 136 نفر با روش نمونه&#8204;گیری هدفمند انتخاب شدند. روایی پرسش&#8204;نامه از طریق نظرسنجی از صاحب&#8204;نظران و متخصصان و پایایی آن با استفاده از ضریب آلفای کرونباخ (با ضریب 0.7) بررسی و تایید شد. نتایج نشان داد که عوامل فرهنگی، پایه&#8204;ای، ارزشی، سازمانی و مدیریتی در توسعه اخلاق حرفه&#8204;ای موثر است و عوامل مدیریتی بر اساس تعیین ضریب مسیر (0.85) به&#8204;عنوان متغیری قوی، در توسعه اخلاق حرفه&#8204;ای موثر می&#8204;باشد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The purpose of this study was to exploration the effective factors in the development of professional ethics and modeling this case. This research is considered exploratory-descriptive based on its goal and functional-developmental, based on the result. It has been done based on a combination method, by using a researcher-made questionnaire and content analysis. At first step, effective factors in the development of professional ethics were identified by content analysis of experts' perspectives. The statistical population consisted of 220people from international affairs staff of National Iranian Oil Company. According to Morgan's table and by using purposeful sampling 136 people was selected. Validity of the questionnaire has been checked by experts and the reliability was confirmed according to the amount of Cronbach's alpha coefficient (0.7). The results showed that cultural, basic, value, organizational and managerial factors are effective in the development of professional ethics and management factors are more effective in developing professional ethics based on path coefficient (0.85) and is consumed as a strong variable.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>37</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>64</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>ناصر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>پورصادق</Family>
				<NameE>Naser</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Poursadegh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه دفاع ملی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دفاع ملی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>dr.naser.poursadegh@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>وحیده</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بهاورنیا</Family>
				<NameE>Vahide</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Behvarnaia</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد رودهن</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>vahidehbahavarnia@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>رشید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ذذوالفقاری زعفرانی</Family>
				<NameE>Rashid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zolfaghari Zafarani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد رودهن</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Professional Ethics</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Oil Ministry</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>National Iranian Oil Company</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اخلاق حرفه‌ای</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>وزارت نفت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شرکت ملی نفت ایران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Hartog, M. &amp; Winstanley, D. (2007). Ethics and Human Resources Management: Professional Development and Practice. Journal of Business &amp; Professional Ethics. Vol. 21, No. 2, pp: 152-160##Hellriegell, D. &amp; Slocum, W. J. (2006). Management. South-western college. https://trove.nla.gov.au/work/7877375. Publisher description at http://www.loc.gov/catdir/enhancements/fy1411/95016618-d.html ##Kacetl, J. (2014). Business Ethics for Students of Management, Journal of Procedia- Social and Behavioral Sciences. No. 109, pp: 875–879.##Lau, H. C. (2005). Idris M.A. Soft foundations of the critical success factors on TQM implementation in Malaysia. TQM Magazine. No. 13(4), p: 533.##Shafritz, J. M., Russell, E.W., &amp; Borick, C.P. (2000). Introducing Public Administration. New York: Longman, Pearson Longman.##Svensson, G. &amp; Wood, G. (2004). Codes of ethics best practice in the swedish public sector, The international journal of public sector management. No. 17, Vol. 2 ,178-195.##William, F. &amp; Cruz. J. A. (2008). Professional Ethics in Engineering. Rice University, Houston. Texas.##Zionts, T. L. (2006). Professional Standards of Educational Managers: Their Importance and Ease of Implementation. Retrieved from Proquest.com.##ابزری، مهدی و دلوی، محمدرضا (1385). مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی (مفاهیم، الگوها، تغییر) با رویکرد تعالی گرا، چاپ اول، اصفهان: نشر قاصد سحر.##حاضر، منوچهر (1391). ابعاد اخلاقی رهبری در سازمان‌ها، مجله مدیریت دولتی، شماره 16، صص 48-45.##حرانی، ابن شعبه (1385). تحف العقول (سخنان چهارده معصوم)، ترجمه صادق حسن‌زاده ،  قم: نشر آل‌علی .##خیاط‌مقدم، سعید و طباطبائی‌نسب، سیده‌ مهدیه (1395). مؤلفه‌های اخلاق حرفه‌ای در مدیریت، فصلنامه اخلاق در علوم و فنّاوری، سال یازدهم، شماره 1، صص 192-188.##دفت، ریچارد ال (1384). تئوری سازمان و طراحی ساختار، ترجمه علی پارسائیان و سیدمحمد اعرابی، تهران: موسسه مطالعات و پژوهش های بازرگانی. ##سایت شرکت ملی نفت ایران (1397). همایش مدیران منابع انسانی، نهم تیر ماه، شماره خبر 16093، پایگاه اطلاع رسانی شرکت ملی نفت ایران.##سایت شرکت ملی نفت ایران (1397). سخنرانی مدیر توسعه منابع انسانی، گردهمایی مدیران منابع انسانی شرکت ملی نفت ایران، پایگاه اطلاع رسانی شرکت ملی نفت ایران.##سلطانی، مرتضی (1392). مدیریت اخلاق در سازمان، نشریه تدبیر، دوره 19، شماره 252، ص 96.##سلیمی، مهدی (1395). ارائه الگوی توسعه اخلاق حرفه‌ای در سازمان‌های ورزشی، فصلنامه اخلاق در علوم و فناوری، شماره 1، صص 13-1.##شاه‌علی، مهرزاد، رشید‌پور، علی، کاووسی، اسماعیل و اعتباریان، علی اکبر (1393). الگوی پیاده سازی اخلاق حرفه‌ای در سازمان‌های دولتی ایران، فصلنامه مدیریت شهری، شماره 39، صص 406-393.##شرمرهون، جان آر (1393). مدیریت رفتارسازمانی، ترجمه مهدی ایران نژاد پاریزی، محمدعلی بابایی زکلیلی و محمدعلی سبحان، چاپ سوم، تهران: نشر موسسه تحقیقات و آموزش مدیریت.##غررالحکم (سخنان قصار امام علی (ع)) (1378). ترجمه سیدهاشم رسولی محلاتی، تهران: دفتر نشر فرهنگ اسلامی.##قراملکی، فرامرز (1390). اخلاق حرفه‌ای در مدیریت علوی، مجله اندیشه حوزه، شماره 32و 33، پایگاه مقالات مدیریت.##قراملکی، فرامرز (1390).  اخلاق حرفه‌ای، قم: نشر مجنون.##قراملکی‌، فرامرز (1388). درآمدی بر اخلاق حرفه ای ، چاپ دوم، تهران: نشر سرآمد.##قلی پور، آرین (1387). جامعه ‌شناسی سازمانها: رویکرد جامعه شناختی به سازمان و مدیریت، چاپ سوم، تهران: سمت.##کالینز، جیم (1395). ساختن برای ماندن، ترجمه سپهرپور و حلمی، چاپ اول، تهران: نشر آوین.##لاوتون، آلن (1380). مدیریت اخلاق در خدمات عمومی، ترجمه ربیعی و گیوریان، چاپ اول، تهران: نشر دانشگاه آزاد.##لاوتون، آلن (1382). مدیریت اخلاق در خدمات دولتی، ترجمه ربیعی و گیوریان، چاپ اول، تهران: نشر یکان.##لینگ، داگ و کیل، فرد (1391). هوش اخلاقی، ترجمه علی محمد گودرزی، چاپ اول، تهران: نشر رسا.##مارتین، مایک و شینزینگر، رولاند (1387). ترجمه نادر محبتی، نشر سازمان سنجش کشور ##مصباحی، مریم و عباس‌زاده، عباس (1392). الگوی سیستمی اخلاق حرفه‌ای در آموزش عالی، فصلنامه اخلاق زیستی، سال سوم، شماره 10، صص 34-11.##مقیمی، سید محمد (1390). سازمان و مدیریت رویکردی پژوهشی، تهران: نشر ترمه.##مقیمی، سید محمد (1394). اخلاق سازمانی جوهره فرهنگ سازمانی کارآمد، فرهنگ مدیریت، دوره 6، شماره 17، صص 93-87.##مکسول، جیمز (1387). اخلاق حرفه ای در مدیریت، ترجمه یاوری، چاپ اول، تهران: نشر فردا.##منشور اخلاقی کارکنان شرکت ملی نفت ایران (1395). پایگاه اطلاع رسانی شرکت ملی نفت ایران، خردادماه.##نراقی، ملااحمد (1386). معراج السعاده، قم: دفتر انتشارات زینی.##هس‌مر، ال.تی (1388). اخلاق در مدیریت، ترجمه سیدمحمد اعرابی و داود ایزدی، تهران: دفتر پژوهش‌های فرهنگی.##هس‌مر، ال‌تی (1380). اخلاق در مدیریت، ترجمه سیدمحمد اعرابی و داود ایزدی، تهران: دفتر پژوهش‌های فرهنگی.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>طراحی الگوی فرهنگ سازمانی کارآفرینانه مبتنی بر نظریه‌پردازی داده بنیاد ؛ مطالعه ای در شرکت گاز استان سیستان و بلوچستان</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Designing Entrepreneurial organizational culture model based on Grounded Theory; A Case in Gas Company of Sistan and Baloochestan Province</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>فرهنگ کارآفرینانه با ایجاد نظامی از ارزش&#8204;های مشترک، باعث ارتقاء سطح بهره&#8204;وری سازمان&#8204;ها می&#8204;شود. از آن&#8204;جایی&#8204;که تاکنون مدلی جامع برای فرهنگ کارآفرینانه ارائه نشده و با توجه به اهمیت شرکت گاز استان سیستان و بلوچستان به&#8204;عنوان یک سازمان خدماتی، با استفاده از روش تحقیق کیفی با رویکرد کاربردی، مدل فرهنگ کارآفرینانه مناسب این شرکت ارائه شده است. این پژوهش از لحاظ هدف، کاربردی و از نظر ماهیت، توصیفی-پیمایشی است. به&#8204;منظور طراحی مدل پژوهش، مصاحبه نیمه&#8204;ساختاریافته&#8204;ای با 12 نفر از خبرگان سازمان انجام شد و اطلاعات به&#8204;دست آمده با تکیه بر نظریه&#8204;پردازی داده&#8204;بنیاد مورد تحلیل قرار گرفت. سپس نتایج در قالب 5 بُعد اشتیاق سازمانی، تعهد ذی&#8204;نفعان، ظرفیت توسعه و یادگیری، هماهنگی&#8204; و انسجام و تغییرات مبتنی بر شناخت فرصت و 14 مؤلفه، شناسایی و دسته&#8204;بندی گردید. روایی محتوایی مدل توسط اساتید دانشگاه و اعضای گروه پژوهش تأیید شد و پایایی مدل نیز از طریق شاخص کاپا مورد سنجش قرار گرفت.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The entrepreneurial culture enhances organizational productivity by creating systems of shared values. Since a comprehensive model for the entrepreneurial culture has not been presented yet, and due to the importance of the Gas Company of Sistan and Bluchestan as a service organization, using a qualitative research method with an applied approach an entrepreneurial culture model for this company has been presented. This research, regarding the purpose is applied and regarding the nature is a descriptive survey. In order to design the research model, a semi-structured interview method was executed with 12 experts and the obtained information was analyzed based on the grounded theory. Data was categorized in the five dimensions: organizational enthusiasm, stakeholder alignment, learning and development support, cooperation and cohesiveness, and opportunity driven changes, and 14 components. The content validity of the model was verified by university professors and research group of the organization and the stability model was also measured through the Kappa index.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>65</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>96</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید علیقلی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>روشن</Family>
				<NameE>Seyed Aligholi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rowshan</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>سیستان و بلوچستان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>salirowshan@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>ملیحه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شهریاری</Family>
				<NameE>Malihe</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shahriari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>سیستان و بلوچستان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>shahriary.malihe@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Entrepreneurial culture</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational enthusiasm</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Stakeholder alignment</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Learning & development support</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Cohesiveness and opportunity driven change</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Grounded theory</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فرهنگ کارآفرینانه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اشتیاق سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تعهد ذی‌نفعان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ظرفیت توسعه و یادگیری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>هماهنگی و انسجام</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تغییرات مبتنی بر شناخت فرصت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نظریه‌پردازی داده‌بنیاد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Bhardwaj, B.R. (2012). Internal environment for corporate entrepreneurship: Assessing CEAI model for emerging economies, Journal of Chinese Entrepreneurship, 4 (1), 70-87.##Burns, P. (2011). Entrepreneurship and Small Business (3rd ed.). Basingstoke, U.K.: Palgrave Macmillan Press.##Chakraborty, S., Thompson, J., &amp; Yehoue, E. (2016). The culture of entrepreneurship. Journal of Economic Theory. 163, 1-36. ( 10.1016/j.jet.2015.12.007.)##Chen, X.P., Yao, X., &amp; Kotha, S. (2010). Entrepreneur Passion and Preparedness in Business Plan Presentations: A Persuasion Analysis of Venture Capitalists' Funding Decisions. Academy of Management Journal, 52(1), 199-214.##Covin, J. O. &amp; Miles, M. P. (1999). Corporate entrepreneurship and the pursuit  of  competitive advantage Entrepremeurship. Theory &amp; practice, 23 (3), 47-63.##Cornwall, J.R. &amp;  Baron P. (1990). Organizational Entrepreneurship. Homewood, IL: Homwood.##Creswell, J. W. (2005). Educational Research: Planning, Conducting, and Evaluating Quantitative and Qualitative Research (2nd edition). Doctoral dissertation.  Department of Management Science.##Dimitratos, P., Voudouris, I., Plakoyiannaki, E., &amp; Nakos, G. (2012). International entrepreneurial culture‌__Toward a comprehensive opportunity-based operationalization of international entrepreneurship. International Business Review, 21(4), 708-721.##Ekvall L.K., Grundry, J.R.,Kichul, &amp; Prather C.W.(1994), Buliding The Creative Organization.Organizatinal Dynamics, 22(4), 22-37.##Engelen, A. (2010), Entrepreneurial orientation as a function of national cultural, variations in two countries, Journal of International Management ,16, 354-368##Engelen, A., Christina, F. T., Thalmann, J., &amp; Brettel, M. (2013). The Effect of  Entrepreneurial Orientation: A Comparison between Germany and Thailand. Journal of Small Business Management. 51(4), 1-21.##Fernández, W. D. (2004), Using the Glaserian Approach in Grounded Studies of Emerging Business Practices. Electronic Journal of Business Research Methods, 2(2). 83-93##Freeman, R.E. (2004) ,A Stakeholder Theory of Modern Corporations, Ethical Theory and Business, 7th Edition.##Hatch, M. J. &amp; Schultz, M. (2001). Are the Strategic Stars Aligned for Your Corporate Brand? Harvard Business Review, 79(2): 128-136.##Hisrich, R., Langan-Fox, J. &amp; Grant, S. (2007).Entrepreneurship research and practice: A call to action for psychology.Journal of American Psychlogist, 62(6), 575-589.##Hisrich, R. &amp; Michael, P. (2005). Entrepreneurship. NewYork: McGraw-Hill Irwin.##Ireland, R. D., Hitt, M. A., &amp; Sirmon, D. G.( 2003). A Model of Strategic Entrepreneurship: The Construct and Its Dimensions. Journal of Management, 29(6):963-989.##Johnson, J. M. (2002.) In-Depth Interviewing. In J. F. Gubrium, &amp; J. A. Holstein (Eds.), Handbook of Interview Research: Context &amp; Method: 103-119. Thousand Oaks, CA., USA: Sage Publications Inc.##Jones, T. M., Felps, W., &amp; Bigley, G. A. (2007). Ethical Theory and Stakeholder-RelatedDecisions: The Role of Stakeholder Culture. Academy of Management Review, 32(1):137-155.##Kaid, A. &amp; Rosli, M. (2011). How does organizational culture shape the relationship between entrepreneurial orientation and the organizational performance of banks? European Journal of Social Sciences, 20 (1), 28- 46.##Kearney, C., Hisrich, R. &amp; Roche, F.(2008). A conceptual model of public sector corporate entrepreneurship.International Entrepreneurship and Management Journal, 4(3), 295-31.##Kuratko, D. F., Hornsby, J.S., &amp; Bishop, J.W. (2005). An examination of managers’ entrepreneurial actions and job satisfaction. International Entrepreneurship and Management Journal, 1(3),. 275–291.##Lee, J. (2001). A Grounded Theory: Integration and Internalization in ERP Adoption and Use, Unpublished Doctoral Dissertation, University of Nebreska, In Proquest UMI Database.##Lee, S. M., Seong-bae, L., &amp; Raghuvar, D. P. (2011). Culture &amp; entrepreneurial orientation: a multicountry study. International Entrepreneurship &amp; Management Journal, 7, 1-15.##Lee, S. &amp; Lim, S. (2008). &quot;Entrepreneurial orientation &amp; performance of service business, International Journal of Service Business,3(1), pp: 1–13.##Lessen, A. H. (2007). Corporate entrepreneurship: an empirical study of the importance of strategic consideration in the creation of radical innovation Managing Global Transitions, 5 (2), 109-131.##Lumpkin, G. T. &amp; Dess, G. G. (1996). Clarifying the entrepreneurial orientation construct and linking it to perfonnance.  Academy of Management Review, 27(1), 135-172.##McGuire, S. (2004). Entrepreneurship Organizational culture. The George Washington University in Partial Fulfillment of the Requirement for the degree of doctor, Department of Management Science.##Maguire, S., Hardy, C., &amp; Lawrence, T. B. (2003). Institutional Entrepreneurship in Emerging Fields: HIV/AIDS Treatment advocacy in canada, Academy of management journal,47(5),657-80.##Mintzberg, H. (1979). The Structuring of Organizations. Englewood Cliffs, NJ, USA:Prentice-Hall.##Morrise, M. H.(1998).Entrepreneurial Intensity:Sustainable Advantages for Individuals Organizations , And societies. Westport, CT:Quorum.##Morris, M. H., Kuratko, D. F., &amp; Covin, J. C.(2011). Corporate entrepreneurship and Innovation.South-Western. Thomson Publishers.##Real, C., Roldán, L., &amp; Leal, A. (2014). From entrepreneurial orientation and learning Orientation to business performance. British Journal of Management, 25 (2), 186-208.##Richerson, P. J. &amp; Boyd, R.(1998).Complex Societies the Evolutionary Origins of a Crude Superorganism. Human Nature, 10(3): 253-289.##Salimath, M. &amp; Cullen, J. (2010). Formal &amp; informal institutional effects on entrepreneurship: a synthesis Journal of Organizational Analysis.18(3),358-385.##Sandelowski, M. &amp; Barroso, J. (2007). Handbook for Synthessizing Qualitative Research. New York: Springer.##Sathe, V.(1988). From Surface to Deep Corporate Entrepreneurship, Human Resource Management, 27(4), 384- 411.##Schaufeli, W. B. &amp; Salanova, M. (2007),Work engagement: an emerging psychological concept and its implications for organizations, in S.W. Gilliland, D.D. Steiner, and Skarlicki, D.P.(Eds), Research in Social Issues in Management,135-177, Information Age Publishers, Greenwich, CT.##Shepherd, D. A., Patzelt, H., &amp; Hayn J. M. (2012). Entrepreneurial Spirals: Deviation-Amplifying Loops of an Entrepreneurial Mindset and Organizational culture, Entrepreneurship: Theory and Practice, 1042-2587.##Shihab, M., Wismiarsi, T.,  &amp; Sine, K. (2011). Relationship between organizational culture and entrepreneurial orientation; Indonesian SMEs context. Proceeding of 2nd International Conference on Business, Economics and Tourism Management, IPEDR, IACSIT Press, Singapore,24, 93- 97.##Strauss, A. L. &amp; Corbin, J. M. (1998), Basics of qualitative research: techniques and procedures for developing grounded theory (2nd ed.). Thousand Oaks: Sage Publications.##Van de Ven, A. H. (1986).  Central Problems in the Management of Innovation. Management Science, 32(5): 590-607.##Winslow, E. K. (1990). The Issue of Motivating Entre (Intra) Preneurial Behavior, The Journal of Creative Behavior, 24, 256-262.##Wong, M. (2014). Entrepreneurial Culture: Developing a Theoretical Construct and its Measurement), Electronic Thesis and Dissertation Repository. Paper 2138.##Zheng, W., Yang, B., &amp; McLean, G. N. (2010). Linking organizational culture, structure, strategy, and organizational effectiveness: Mediating role of knowledge management, Journal of Business Research, 63, 763–771.##اکاتی، حمید، میر، فاطمه، سرگزی اول، مهدیه و نکویی، حسن(1396). مطالعه تاثیر مولفه‌های فرهنگ سازمانی کارآفرینانه بر خلاقیت و نوآوری کارکنان دانشگاه زابل، دومین کنفرانس ملی اقتصاد، مدیریت و حسابداری، اهواز.##پرهیزگار، محمد مهدی، آقاجانی افروزی، علی‌اکبر و نادعلیزاده طبری، محدثه (1389). ارائه الگویی اثربخش از نقش یادگیری سازمانی در فرآیند شناسایی فرصت‌های کارآفرینانه، مجموعه مقالات کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت، نوآوری و کارآفرینی، شیراز، 27 و 28 بهمن ماه، صص 16-1.##جفایی، منیر، رجایی، زهرا و توسلی، نیاز(1390).  بررسی نقش تعهد سازمانی در کارآفرینی سازمانی در دانشگاه آزاد، مجموعه مقالات اولین کنفرانس ملی کارآفرینی، تعاون، جهاد اقتصادی، نایین، 28و 29 آذر ، صص 16-1.##حسین زاده، طاهره، قهرمانی، محمد و پرداختچی، محمدحسن (1389). فرهنگ سازمانی و رابطه آن با کارآفرینی سازمانی، چشم انداز مدیریت دولتی، شماره 1، صص 39-25.##حیدری، حسین، پاپ زن، عبدالحمید و کرمی دارابخانی، رؤیا (1390). بررسی رابطه میان فرهنگ سازمانی و مولفه‌های کارآفرینی سازمانی (مطالعه موردی: سازمان جهادکشاورزی شهرستان)، فصلنامه ابتکار و خلاقیت در علوم انسانی، سال1، شماره3، صص166-145.##دانایی فرد، حسن و امامی، سید مجتبی(1386). استراتژی‌های پژوهش کیفی: تأملی بر نظریه داده بنیاد، اندیشه مدیریت، دوره 1، شماره2 ، صص 97- 69 .##داوری، رؤیا و آقاجانی، حمیدرضا (1395). بررسی وضعیت فرهنگ سازمانی کارآفرینانه در دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران، دومین کنفرانس بین‌المللی علوم انسانی با رویکرد بومی- اسلامی و تأکید بر پژوهش‌های نوین.##رضائیان، علی(1395). مبانی سازمان و مدیریت، چاپ نوزدهم، تهران: سمت.##زارعی متین،حسن، مقیمی، سید محمد و غفوریان یاورپناه، هادی(1392). تحلیل رابطه‌ی فرهنگ سازمانی کارآفرینانه و هوش‌عاطفی، فصلنامه مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی، دوره11، شماره 4، صص31-5.##سبحانی‌نژاد، مهدی، شهایی، بهنام و یوزباشی، علیرضا (1389) سازمان یادگیرنده( مبانی نظری، الگوهای تحقق و سنجش)، تهران: یسطرون.##شوقی، بهزاد و محمدداودی، امیرحسین(1390). بررسی تعاملات نظری میان یادگیری سازمانی، نوآوری و کارآفرینی. مجموعه مقالات کنفرانس ملی کارآفرینی، تعاون و جهاد اقتصادی، صص 17-1.##علیمردانی، محمد، فراهانی، ابوالفضل و قاسمی، سید حمید(1394). ارتباط بین فرهنگ سازمانی با کارآفرینی سازمانی در اداره کل ورزش و جوانان استان قم، پژوهش‌های کاربردی در مدیریت ورزشی، سال 4، شماره1، صص35-25. ##کریمی، آصف، رضایی، روح الله،احمدپور داریانی، محمود و انصاری، محسن(1392). تاثیر فرهنگ سازمانی بر گرایش کارآفرینانه (مورد مطالعه پردیس کشاورزی منابع طبیعی دانشگاه تهران)، فصلنامه توسعه کارآفرینی، دوره 6،  شماره 3، صص182-163.##مختاری نیا، طاهره، قدیری نژاد، سیدجعفر و جعفری پور، صاحبه (1396). بررسی عوامل اثرگذار تعهد سازمانی و رضایت شغلی بر عملکرد کارکنان در یک سازمان، دهمین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت و اقتصاد، اردیبهشت 1396.##مقیمی، سید محمد، کردنائیج، اسداله، قناتی، سوسن و یزدانی، حمیدرضا (1388). بررسی رابطه‌ی بین عناصر ساختار سازمانی و فرهنگ کارآفرینانه در دانشگاه تهران، فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، دوره اول، شماره3، صص 134-119.##منصوریان، یزدان (1386). گرانددتئوری (نظریۀ زمینه ای)، همایش چالش‌های علم اطلاعات در دانشگاه اصفهان، سایت جامع مدیریت مدیریار(www.modiryar.com).##میرزادارنی، حمیده (1392). دریچه ای به سوی نشاط اجتماعی، علوم اجتماعی، شماره62، صص 70-62.##میرزایی توکلی، سید منصور و شریعتمداری، مهدی(1394). بررسی تاثیر معنویت در محیط کار و تعهد سازمانی بر رضایت شغلی پرسنل ستادی نهاد نمایندگی مقام معظم رهبری در دانشگاه ها، مدیریت در دانشگاه اسلامی ، سال 4، شماره1، صص76-59.##نادری فر، علیرضا ، شهرکی، علیرضا و فنودی، مهدی (1395). مطالعه فرهنگ کارآفرینانه سازمانی و ارتباط آن با تعهد سازمانی کارکنان (مطالعه‌ای درسازمان تامین اجتماعی استان سیستان و بلوچستان)، دومین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت و فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات.##نیلی‌پور طباطبائی، سید اکبر و غفاری‌راد، حمید(1396). تأثیر فرهنگ سازمانی کارآفرینانه بر تسهیم دانش در شبکه سراسری ایران‌گیت، سومین کنفرانس بین المللی مهندسی صنایع و مدیریت.##هومن، حیدرعلی(1394)، راهنمای عملی پژوهش کیفی، تهران: سمت، مرکز تحقیق و توسعه علوم انسانی.##یزدانشناس، مهدی(1392). بررسی وضعیت فرهنگ سازمانی کارآفرینانه در بخش دولتی ایران و پیشنهاد راهکارهایی برای ارتقای آن، فصلنامه مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی، دوره 11، شماره 4، صص 158-137.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی و تمایل به ترک خدمت سازمان: بررسی نقش میانجیِ نقض قرارداد روان‌شناختی </TitleF>
		<TitleE>Human Resource Management Practices and organization Turnover Intentions; A review of the mediating role of Psychological Contract Breach </TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در این پژوهش، تأثیر اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی بر قصد ترک خدمت و نقض قرارداد روان&#8204;شناختی کارکنان شرکت گاز شهر رشت مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. این تحقیق از نظر هدف، کاربردی، از نظر گردآوری اطلاعات، توصیفی و از شاخه مطالعات پیمایشی و از حیث ارتباط بین متغیرهای پژوهش، از نوع همبستگی است. جامعه آماری در این پژوهش تمامی کارکنان اداری شرکت گاز شهر رشت (در مجموع 210 نفر) را در بر می&#8204;گیرد. روش نمونه&#8204;گیری در این پژوهش سیستماتیک بود و به&#8204;منظور گردآوری اطلاعات از پرسش&#8204;نامه&#8204;های استاندارد استفاده شد. نتایج تحلیل آماری با استفاده از نرم&#8204;افزار آموس نشان داد که اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی و ابعاد آن بر نقض قرارداد روان&#8204;شناختی تأثیر منفی دارد. همچنین تأثیر اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی و ابعاد آن بر تمایل به ترک خدمت نیز منفی بود. مقدار بحرانی اثر غیرمسـتقیم میـان اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی و تمایل به ترک خدمت از طریق متغیر میانجیِ نقض قرارداد روان&#8204;شناختی برابـر بـا 2.10 بدست آمد. به این معنا که نقض قرارداد روان&#8204;شناختی به&#8204;عنوان متغیر میانجی در تأثیر دو متغیر فوق ایفای نقش دارد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The main goal of this research has been investigating the impact of human resource management practices on the employee turnover intentions by considering psychological contract breach in the gas company of Rasht. So, it's considered an applied research, in terms of its goals, a descriptive survey, in terms of information gathering and correlational in terms of the interrelation between the research variables. The statistical population in this research included all the administrative staff of Gas Company in Rasht (totally 210 people). Systematic sampling has been used. In order to collect information, standard questionnaires were used. Using AMOS software, statistical analysis revealed that human resource management practices and its dimensions have a negative effect on psychological contract breach. Also, the impact of human resource management practices and its dimensions on employees' turnover intentions were also negative. The critical value of the indirect effect of human resource management practices and the employees' turnover intentions through the mediating variable of the psychological contract breach (2.10) showed that psychological contract breach plays a mediating role between mentioned two variables.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>97</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>120</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رنگریز</Family>
				<NameE>Hassan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rangriz</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>rangriz@khu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مهذبی</Family>
				<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mohazabi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mmg.mohazabi@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Human Resource Management Practices</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Psychological Contract Breach</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organization Turnover Intentions</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Gas Company of Rasht City</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نقض قرارداد روان‌شناختی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تمایل به ترک خدمت سازمان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شرکت گاز شهر رشت.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aggarwal, U. &amp; Bhargava, S. (2009). Reviewing the relationship between human resource practices and psychological contract and their impact on employee attitude and behaviours: A conceptual model, Journal of European Industrial Training, Vol. 33 No. 1, PP:4-31.##Allen, D. G., Shore, L.Y., &amp; Griffeth, R. W. (2003). The role of perceived organizational support and supportive human resource practices in the turnover process, Journal of Management, Vol. 29 No.1, PP:  99-118.##Andersson, L.M. (1996). Employee Cynicism: An Examination Using a Contract Violation Framework, Human Relations, Vol. 49, PP: 1395-1418.## Biron M., &amp; Boon, C. (2013). Performance and turnover intentions: a social exchange perspective. Journal of Managerial Psychology, 28 (5), PP: 511-531.##Blomme, R. J., Van Rheede, A., &amp; Tromp, D. M. (2010), The use of the psychological contract explain turnover intentions in the hospitality industry: a research study on the impact of gender on the turnover intentions of highly educated employees, The International Journal of Human Resource Management, Vol. 21, No. 1, PP:  144-162.##Cable, D.A.J (2008).The psychological contract: the development and validation of a managerial measure, unpublished dissertation, The University of Waikato.##Cantisano, G.T., Domínguez, J.F.M., &amp; Depolo, M. (2008). Psychological contract breach and outcomes: Combining meta-analysis and  structural equation models, Psicothema, Vol. 20, N. 3, PP:  487-496.##Cho, S., Woods, R. H., Jang, S., &amp; Erdem, M. (2006). Measuring the impact of human resource management practices on hospitality firms’ performances. International Journal of Hospitality Management, Vol. 25 No 2, PP:  262-277.##Chen, C. &amp; Huang, J. (2009). Strategic human resource practices and innovation performance — The mediating role of knowledge management capacity, Journal of Business Research , 62, PP:  104–114.##Christian, J.S. &amp; Ellis, A.P.J. (2014). The Crucial Role of Turnover Intentions in Transforming Moral Disengagement into Deviant Behavior at Work, Journal of Business Ethics, 119(2), PP:  193–208.##Coyle‐Shapiro, J. &amp; Kessler, I. (2000). Consequences of the psychological contract for the employment relationship: A large scale survey, Journal of management studies, Vol. 37 No. 7, PP:  903-930.##Cullinane, N. &amp; Dundon, T. (2006). The psychological contract: a critical review.International Journal of Management Reviews.Vol. 8, ISS. 2, PP:  113-129. Blackwell Publishing Ltd.##Deery, S. J., Iverson, R. D., &amp; Walsh, J.T. (2006). Towards a better understanding of psychological contract breech: A study of customer service employees, Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. 91 No.1, PP:  166 -175.##Flint, D., Haley, L. M., &amp; McNally, J. J. (2013). Individual and organizational determinants of turnover intent. Personnel Review, 42 (5), PP:  552-572.##Gary, D. (2006).Expanding into China? What Foreign Employers Should Know About Human Resource Management in China Today? S.A.M. Advanced Management Journal, 71(4), p. 11.##Guest, D. E. (2004).The psychology of the employment relationship: An analysis based on the psychological contract, Applied psychology, Vol 53(4), PP:  541-555.##Guchait, P., Cho, S., &amp; Meurs, J. A. (2015). Psychological contracts, perceived organizational and supervisor support: Investigating the impact on intent to leave among hospitality employees in India. Journal of Human Resources in Hospitality &amp; Tourism, 14(3),. pp 290-315.##Lv, Z. &amp; Xu, T. (2016). Psychological contract breach, high-performance work system and engagement: the mediated effect of person-organization fit. The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 29(7), PP:  1257-1284.##Manxhari, M. (2015). Employment Relationships and the Psychological Contract: The Case of Banking Sector in Albania. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 210, PP:  231-240.##Nahas, T., Abd-El-Salam, E.M., &amp; Shawky, A.Y. (2013). The impact of leadership behaviour and organisational culture on job satisfaction and its relationship among organisational commitment and turnover intentions: A case study on an Egyptian company. Journal of Business and Retail Management Research, 7(2), PP:  3-43.##Persson, S. &amp; Wasieleski, D. (2015). The Seasons of the Psychological Contract: Overcoming the Silent Transformations of the Employer– employee Relationship. Human Resource Management Review, 25(4), PP:  1-15.##Restubog, S. L. D., Zagenczyk, T. J., Bordia, P., Bordia, S., &amp; Chapman, G. J. (2015). If you wrong us, shall we not revenge? Moderating roles of self-control and perceived aggressive work culture in predicting responses to psychological contract breach. Journal of Management, 41(4), PP:  1132-1154.##Rousseau, D. M. &amp; Greller, M. M. (1994). Human resource practices: administrative contract makers”, Human Resource Management, Vol. 33 No 3, PP:  385-401.##Robinson, S. L. &amp; Morrison, E. W. (1995).Psychological contracts and OCB: The effect of unfulfilled obligations on civic virtue behavior, Journal of organizational behavior, Vol. 16 No. 3, PP:  289-298.##Santhanam, N., Kamalanabhan, T.J., Dyaram, L., &amp; Hans Z. (2017). Impact of Human Resource Management Practices on Employee Turnover Intentions: Moderating Role of  Psychological Contract Breach. Journal of Indian Business Research. 25(3), PP:  1-22.##Shen, J. (2010). University Academics’Psychological Contracts and Their Fulfilment, Journal of Management Development, Vol. 29, No. 6, PP:  575-591.##Suazo, M. M., Turnley, W. H., &amp; Mai, R. R. (2005).The role of perceived violation in determining employees' reactions to psychological contract breach,Journal of Leadership and Organizational Studies, Vol. 12 No.1, PP:  24-36.##Tang, T. W., &amp; Tang, Y. Y. (2012). Promoting service-oriented organizational citizenship behaviors in hotels: The role of high-performance human resource practices and organizational social climates. International Journal of Hospitality Management, Vol. 31 No.3, PP:  885-895.##Turnley, W. H. &amp; Feldman, D. C. (1999). The impact of psychological contract violations on exit, voice, loyalty, and neglect, Human relations, Vol. 52 No. 7, PP:  895-922.##Vantilborgh, T. (2015). Volunteers’ Reactions to Psychological Contract Fulfillment in Terms of Exit, Voice, Loyalty, and Neglect Behavior. Voluntas: International Journal of Voluntary and Nonprofit Organizations, 26(2). PP:  604-628 (doi 10.1007/s11266-014-9441-6/)##Yang, J. T., Wan, C. S., &amp; Fu, Y. J. (2012). Qualitative examination of employee turnover and retention strategies in international tourist hotels in Taiwan, International Journal of Hospitality Management, Vol. 31 No.3, PP:  837-848.##Zagenczyk, T. J., Restubog, S. D., Kiewitz, C., Kiazad, K. &amp; Tang, R. L. (2011). Psychological Contracts as a Mediator between Machiavellianism and Employee Citizenship and Deviant Behaviors. Journal of Management, 40(4), PP:  1098-1122.## آقاجان‌پور، فاطمه و رضایی، حمیدرضا‌(1394). نقش مبادله رهبر پیرو در تمایل به ترک خدمت کارکنان دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد رشت، فصلنامه علوم مدیریت ایران، سال نهم، شماره 36، صص 119-101.## آتشی، حسین (1396). رابطه‌ی رهبری اصیل بر تمایل به ترک خدمت کارکنان با در نظر گرفتن نقش میانجی عجین شدن با شغل و هویت سازمانی، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.##افخمی اردکانی، مهدی و فرحی، رضا (1390). فرهنگ، تعهد سازمانی و تمایل به ترک خدمت کارکنان دانشی: طراحی و تبیین مدلی در پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت. علوم مدیریت ایران، سال6، شماره 24 ، صص 24-14.##اکبری، مرتضی، پورولی، بهروز، دیانتی، مژگان، محمدی، معصومه و رضایی، نیلوفر (1395). رهبری اصیل و سرمایه روان‌شناختی: تأثیر متغیر میانجی اعتماد و نقضِ قرارداد روان‌شناختی، نشریه مدیریت دولتی، دوره 8، شماره 3، صص 532-511.##خیراندیش، مهدی، سیدنقوی، میرعلی و صفری، سیاره (1396). الگوی عوامل پیشران تمایل به ترک خدمت نخبگان از دیدگاه مدیران در شرکت ملی پخش فراورده‌های نفتی، فصلنامه مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 8، شماره 31، صص 71-41.## رسولی، رضا،شهائی، بهنام و صفایی، مهناز (1391) عوامل مؤثر بر نیت ترک خدمت کارکنان در سازمان مرکزی دانشگاه پیام نور. نشریه مدیریت دولتی، دوره 4، شماره 9، صص 42 – 27.##شجاعی، سامره (1395). بررسی رابطه بین نقض قرارداد روان‌شناختی با رفتار شهروندی سازمانی و نیت جابه‌جایی با نقش تعدیلی فاصله قدرت. نشریه فرایند مدیریت و توسعه، دوره 29، شماره 2، صص 144-174.## صادقیان، سعید، شکری، صابر، شاکری، زهره وگل‌آرا، پورمجرب (1395). بررسی تأثیر اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی بر رضایت شغلی، نشریه مدیریت دولتی، دوره 8، شماره 1، صص 1807-1670.##کنعانی، آمنه (1396)، تأثیر اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی بر تمایل به ترک خدمت کارکنان در کسب و کارهای کوچک و متوسط، کنفرانس بین المللی مدیریت، اقتصاد کاربردی و تجارت، ایران: شیراز.## گل محمدی، عماد، رسوله وندی، محمدباقر، حاتمی، رضا و ملکشاهی، محمدرضا (1395). اثر اقدمات مدیریت منابع انسانی بر تعهد سازمانی کارکنان، مطالعات مدیریت بر آموزش انتظامی، سال نهم، شماره دوم (34)، صص 349-339.##هادی پیکانی، مهربان و خنیفر، علی (1396). تببین و اولویت‌بندی عوامل موثر بر ترک خدمت کارکنان کلیدی در شرکت‌های واگذار شده شرکت نفت به بخش خصوصی (مورد مطالعه: شرکت لوله سازی اهواز)، فصلنامه مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 8، شماره 31، صص 175-153.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>طراحی الگویی از پیشایندها و پیامدهای زایندگی در کار برای کارکنان شرکت ملی حفاری ایران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Designing a model of antecedents and consequences of thriving at work in employees of National Iranian Drilling Company‎</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف تحقیق حاضر طراحی الگویی از برخی پیشایندها و پیامدهای زایندگی در کار برای کارکنان شرکت ملی حفاری ایران بود. روش تحقیق به لحاظ هدف، کاربردی، به لحاظ نحوه جمع&#8204;آوری داده&#8204;ها از نوع پیمایشی و از نظر تجزیه و تحلیل داده&#8204;ها از نوع همبستگی بود. از بین کلیه کارکنان این شرکت 211 نفر به عنوان نمونه آماری در تحقیق حاضر شرکت کردند. تحلیل داده&#8204;های پژوهش با استفاده از الگویابی معادلات ساختاری و با نرم&#8204;افزارهای SPSS ویرایش 21 و AMOS ویرایش 21 انجام گرفت. شاخص های برازندگی نشان داد که &#160;الگوی فرضی پژوهش از برازش خوبی با داده&#8204;ها برخوردار است. یافته&#8204;های دیگر نشان دادند که در سطح اطمینان 95% متغیرهای جو اعتماد/ احترام، با ضریب 0/168، تصمیم &#173;گیری اختیاری با ضریب 0/397و بازخورد عملکرد با ضریب 0/193 با &#160;خودتعیینی رابطه مثبت دارند. همچنین، تصمیم &#173;گیری اختیاری و بازخورد عملکرد به ترتیب با ضرایب 0/333 و 0/215 با زایندگی در کار رابطه مثبت داشتند. نتایج بعدی نشان دادند که زایندگی در کار با ضریب تاثیر 0/302 با عملکرد شغلی و با ضریب تاثیر 0/239 با رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی رابطه مثبت دارند. تحلیل&#173;های مربوط به روابط میانجی نشان دادند که متغیرهای جو اعتماد/ احترام، تصمیم&#8204;گیری اختیاری و بازخورد عملکرد از طریق خودتعیینی و زایندگی در کار بر عملکرد شغلی و رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی تاثیر می گذارند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The aim of this study was designing a model of some antecedents and consequences of thriving at work for the employees of National Iranian Drilling Company(NIDC). In terms of objective, the research method was applied, in terms of data collection&#160;has been consumed a survey&#160;and in terms of data analysis was a descriptive study. Among employees of NIDC, 211 employees participated in the study. Data were analyzed through structural equation modeling (SEM) and using SPSS-21 and AMOS-21 software. Fit indices showed that the proposed model was fitted to the data. The other findings with confidence interval of %95 indicated that variables including: trust/respect climate with coefficient of .168, discretionary decision making with coefficient of .397, and performance feedback with coefficient of .193 were positively correlated with self-determination. In addition, discretionary decisions making with coefficient of .333, and performance feedback with coefficient of .215 had a positive correlation with thriving at work. More analyses revealed that thriving at work was correlated with both job performance, with coefficient of .302 and organizational citizenship behaviors, with coefficient of .239. Mediation analyses indicated that trust/respect climate, discretionary decision making, and performance feedback had an indirect effect on job performance and organizational citizenship behaviors through self-determination and thriving at work.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>121</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>146</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید اسماعیل</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>هاشمی</Family>
				<NameE>Seyed Esmaeil</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Hashemi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>چمران اهواز</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>esmaeil2140@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>نسیم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>خواجه پور</Family>
				<NameE>Nasim</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Khajepour</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>چمران اهواز</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>khajepour.nasim@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>کیومرث</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بشلیده</Family>
				<NameE>Kiumars</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Beshlideh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>چمران اهواز</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>K.beshlideh@scu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Climate of trust/respect</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Discretionary decision-making</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Performance feedback</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Thriving at work</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Job performance</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>جو اعتماد و احترام</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تصمیم‌گیری اختیاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بازخورد عملکرد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زایندگی در کار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عملکرد شغلی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abid, G. H. &amp; Ahmed, A. (2016). Multifacetedness of Thriving: Its Cognitive, Affective, and Behavioral Dimensions. International Journal of Information, Business and Management, 8(3), 121-130.##Alderfer, C. (1972). Existence, relatedness, and growth; human needs in organizational settings, 3rd ed., New York: Free Press.##Ammons, R. B. (1956). Effects of knowledge of performance: A survey and tentative theoretical formulation. Journal of General Psychology, 54, 279-299.##Ashford, S. J. &amp; Cummings, L. L. (1983). Feedback as an individual resource: Personal strategies of creating information. Organizational Behavior and Human Performance, 3, 370-398.##Baard, P. P. (2002). Intrinsic need satisfaction in organizations: A motivational basis of success in for-profit and not-for-profit settings. In E. L. Deci &amp; R. M. Ryan (Eds.), Handbook of self-determination research.##Bakker, A. B., Demerouti, E. &amp; Sanz-Vergel, A. I. (2014). Burnout and work engagement: The JD-R approach. Annual Review of Organizational Psychology &amp; Organizational Behavior, 11(1), 389-411.##Bandura, A. (1977). Social Learning Theory, Prentice-Hall Inc., Englewood Cliffs, NJ.##Benson, P. &amp; Scales, P. (2009). The definition and preliminary measurement of thriving in adolescence. The Journal of Positive Psychology, 4(1), 85-104.##Bowlby, J. (1979). The Making and Breaking of Affectional Bonds. Tavistock, London, UK.##Brown, K. W. &amp; Ryan, R. M. (2003). The benefits of being present: The role of mindfulness in psychological well-being. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 84(4), 822–848.##Bunderson, J. S. &amp; Sutcliffe, K. M. (2002). Why some teams emphasize learning more than others: Evidence from business unit management teams. Research on Managing Groups and Teams, 4(1), 49–84.##Calhoun, L. &amp; Tedeschi, R. (1998). Beyond recovery from trauma: Implications for clinical practice and research. Journal of Social Issues, 54(2), 357-371.##Carver, C. S. (1998). Resilience and thriving: Issues, models, and linkages. Journal of Social Issues, 54, 245-266.##Chen, B., Van Assche, J., Vansteenkiste, M., Soenens, B., &amp; Beyers, W. (2015b). Does psychological need satisfaction matter when environmental or financial safety is at risk? Journal of Happiness Studies, 16 (3), 745-766.##Chen, B., Vansteenkiste, M., Beyers, W., Boone, L., Deci, E., Kaap-Deeder, J., Duriez, B., Lens, W., Matos, L., Mouratidis, A., Ryan, R., Sheldon, K., Soenens, B., Petegem, S., &amp; Verstuyf, J. (2015). Basic psychological need satisfaction, need frustration, and need strength across four cultures. Motivation and Emotion, 39(2), PP: 216-236.##Cortina, L M., Magley, V. J., Williams, J., &amp; Langhout, R. (2001). Incivility in the workplace: Incidence and impact. Journal of Occupational Health Psychology, 6 (1), 64-80.##Deci E.	 L. &amp; Ryan, R. M. (2000). The ‘what’ and ‘why of goal pursuits: Human needs and the self-determination of behavior”, Psychological Inquiry, 11, 227-268.##Edmondson, A. (1999). Psychological safety and learning behavior in work teams. Administrative Science Quarterly, 44 (2), 350–383.##Farh, J., Podsakoff, P. M., &amp; Organ, D. W. (1990). Accounting for organizational citizenship behavior: Leader Fairness and Task Scope Versus Satisfaction . Journal of Management, 16 (4), 705-721.##Gagne, M. &amp; Deci, E. (2005). Self-determination theory and work motivation. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 26 (4), 331-362.##Hall, J. M., Roman, M. W., Thomas, S. P., Travis, C. B., Powell, J., Tennison, C. R.&amp; &amp; Martin, T. (2009). Thriving as becoming resolute in narratives of women surviving childhood maltreatment. American Journal of Orthopsychiatry, 79(3), 375-386.##Hofmann D. A, &amp; Morgeson F. P. (1999). Safety-related behavior as a social exchange: The role of perceived organizational support and leader–member exchange. Journal of Applied Psychology, 84, 286– 296.##Joseph, S. &amp; Linley, A. (2008). Trauma, recovery and growth: Positive psychological perspectives on posttraumatic stress. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley and Sons.##Kaplan, R. &amp; Kaplan. S. (1995). The Experience of Nature: A Psychological Perspective. Ulrich’s Books Inc., Ann Arbor, MI.##Maslow, A. (1943). A theory of human motivation. Psychological Review, 50 (4), 370–396.##Mayer, R. C. Davis, J. H. &amp; Schoorman, F. D. (1995). An integrative model of organizational trust. Academy of Management Review, 709–734.##Muraven, M.; Gagne, M. &amp; Rosman, H. (2008). Helpful self-control: Autonomy support vitality, and depletion. Journal of Experimental Social Psychology, 44(3), 573-585.##Paterson, D. G. (1992). The Scott company graphic rating scale. Journal of personnel research, 1, 361-376.##Porath, C. L., Shapiro, D. L. &amp; Duffy, M. K. (2004). When does perceived incivility lead to production deviance? A test of a system wide perspective. Paper presented at the annual meeting of the Academy of Management, New Orleans, LA.##Porath, C. L., Spreitzer, G., &amp; Gibson, C. (2011). Toward Human Sustainability: How Organizations Can Enable More Thriving at Work (accepted)”, Organizational Dynamics.##Porath, C., Spreizer, B., Gibson, C., &amp; Garnett, F.G. (2012). Thriving at work: toward its measurement, construct validation, and theoretical refinement. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 33 (2), 250-75. ##Quinn, R., Spreitzer, G. M., &amp; Lam, C. F. (2012). A Comprehensive Review and Integrative Framework of Energy at Work. Academy of Management Annals, 14, 337-396.##Rhoades, L. &amp; Eisenberger, R. (2002). Perceived organizational support: A review of the literature. Journal of Applied Psychology, 87 (4), 698-714.##Robischek, C. (1998). Personal growth initiative: The construct and its measure. Measurement and Evaluation in Counseling and Development, 30 (4), 183-198.##Rogers, C. (1961). On becoming a person: A therapist’s view of psychotherapy. Boston: Houghton Mifflin.##Ryan, R. M., Bernstein, J., &amp; Brown, K. W. (2010). Weekends, work, and well-being: Psychological need satisfactions and day of the week effects on mood, vitality, and physical symptoms. Journal of Social and Clinical Psychology, 29 (1), 95-122.##Ryan,	R. M. &amp; Deci, E. L. (2000). Self-determination theory and the facilitation of intrinsic motivation, social development and well-being. American Psychologist, 55(1), 68-78.##Ryff, C. D. (1989). Happiness is everything, or is it? Explorations on the meaning of psychological well-being. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 57, 1069-1081.##Saakvitne, K. W., Tennen, H., &amp; Affleck, G. (1998). Exploring thriving in the context of clinical trauma theory: Constructivist self‐ developmental theory. Journal of Social Issues, 54(2), 279–299.##Schoorman, F. D., Mayer, R. C.,, &amp; Davis, J. H. (1995). An integrative model of organizational trust. Academy of Management Review, 20(3), 709–734.##Sonenshein, S., Dutton, J., Grant, A., Spritzer, G., &amp; Sutcliffe, K. (2005). Narratives of growth at work: Learning from employees’ stories. Working paper, Ross School of Business, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI.##Spreitzer, G. M. &amp; Porath, Ch. L (2013). Self-Determination as Nutriment for Thriving: Building an Integrative Model of Human Growth at Work. The Oxford Handbook of Work Engagement, Motivation, and Self-Determination Theory. Edited by Marylène Gagné. 1-36.##Spreitzer, G. M. (1995). Psychological empowerment in the workplace: Dimensions, measurement, and validation. Academy of Management Journal, 38(5), 1442-1465.##Spreitzer, G., K. Sutcliffe, J. Dutton, S. Sonenshein, A. M., &amp; Grant, A. (2005). A socially embedded model of thriving at work. Organization Science 16(5), 537–549.##Thomas, S. P. &amp; Hall, J. (2008). Life trajectories of female child abuse survivors thriving in adulthood. Qualitative Health Research, 18(2), 149–166.##Vroom, V. H. (1964). Work motivation. Wiley, New York, NY.##Wood, R. &amp; Bandura, A. (1989). Social cognitive theory of organizational management. Academy of Management Review, 14(3), 361-384.##Zhang, Y. &amp; Chen, C. (2013). Developmental leadership and organizational citizenship behavior: Mediating effects of self-determination, supervisor identification and organizational identification. The Leadership Quarterly, 24(4), 534-543.##اصلانپور جوکندان، محمد، شهبازی، فاطمه، و ملکی، رضا (1390). رابطه نیرومندی در کار با سلامت و عملکرد شغلی در کارکنان یک شرکت صنعتی اهواز. یافته های نو در روان شناسی ،سال 7، شماره 21، زمستان 1390، 73-65.##شکرکن، حسین، نعامی، عبدالزهرا، نیسی، عبدالکاظم، و مهرابی زاده هنرمند، مهناز (1380). بررسی رابطه خشنودی شغلی با رفتار مدنی سازمانی و عملکرد شغلی در کارکنان برخی از کارخانه‌های اهواز، مجله علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز، 3(8)، 22-1.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>شناسایی و ارزیابی موانع مدیریت جانشین پروری در شرکت پتروشیمی شیراز با رویکرد ترکیبی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Identification and prioritizing Succession Management Barriers in Shiraz Petrochemical Company by mixed method </TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف پژوهش حاضر شناسایی و اولویت بندی موانع مدیریت جانشین پروری در شرکت پتروشیمی شیراز بود. روش پژوهش از نوع ترکیبی بود. در مرحله کیفی، با روش تحلیل مضمون و ابزار مصاحبه نیمه ساختار یافته به بررسی موانع جانشین پروری پرداخته شد. با استفاده از نمونه&#8204;گیری هدفمند و بر اساس قاعده اشباع ؛ نظرات 30 نفر از صاحب&#8204;نظران کلیدی و باتجربه این شرکت دریافت شد. بر اساس نتایج تحلیل مضمون، عدم حمایت و پشتیبانی مدیران اجرایی، سیاستهای سازمانی، تغییرات سریع سازمانی، تشریفات زائد اداری، دید کوتاه مدت و عدم وضوح و شفافیت، به عنوان موانع جانشین پروری شناسایی شدند. از معیارهای اعتبارسنجی کیفی؛ قابل قبول بودن و قابل اعتماد بودن و تحلیل عاملی تائیدی برای بررسی اعتبار مضامین استفاده شد. در بخش کمی پژوهش و برای اولویت&#8204;بندی موانع جانشین&#8204;پروری از روش پژوهش توصیفی پیمایشی استفاده شد. جامعه آماری در این بخش تمام کارکنان شرکت را شامل بود که بر اساس فرمول کوکران 183 نفر به روش نمونه&#8204;گیری تصادفی ساده انتخاب شدند. ابزار مورداستفاده در این بخش، مقیاس محقق&#8204;ساخته بر اساس تحلیل مضامین بخش کیفی بود. برای تعیین روایی پرسشنامه از روایی محتوا و برای تعیین پایایی آن از روش آلفای کرونباخ (با مقدار کلی 0/96) استفاده شد. نتایج این بخش با استفاده از تحلیل سلسله مراتبی نشان داد که مشکل عدم&#8204;حمایت از جانشین&#8204;پروری دارای بالاترین میانگین و مشکل تشریفات زائد دارای پایین&#8204;ترین میانگین بودند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The purpose of this study was to identify and prioritize the barriers of succession management in Shiraz Petrochemical Company. The mixed method has been. In qualitative stage, by means of thematic analysis and semi-structured interviewing, the obstacles of succession management were explored. The potential participants in this stage were 30 people including experts in the Shiraz Petrochemical Company who were selected through a purposeful sampling approach and based on the theoretical saturation rule. The results of the content analysis from interviews showed that barriers to succession management were included: lack of executive&#8217;s support, lack of organizational policies, organizational rapid changes, redundant administrative procedures, short term vision and lack of clarity and transparency. To validate acquiring themes qualitative validation criteria, reliability and confirmatory factor analysis were used. In the quantitative part, a descriptive survey method was used and the population consisted of all the employees from which 183 people were selected randomly. A researcher-made questionnaire based on qualitative component analysis has been used in this section. Content validity was used to determine the validity of the questionnaire. And, Cronbach's alpha method was used to determine the reliability of the questionnaire. Hierarchical analysis showed that lack of executive&#8217;s support had the highest mean and the problem of felony, had the lowest average among barriers of succession management.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>147</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>166</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>نصر</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Nasr</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>شرکت پتروشیمی شیراز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علیرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قاسمی زاد</Family>
				<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ghasemizad</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاداسلامی، واحدکازرون</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Ghasemizad@kau.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>succession management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Barriers</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Petrochemical Company</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>mixed method</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پتروشیمی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت جانشین پروری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>موانع</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رویکرد ترکیبی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ahrens, J. P., Landmann, A., &amp; Woywode, M. (2015). Gender preferences in the CEO successions of family firms: Family characteristics and human capital of the successor. Journal of Family Business Strategy, 6(2), 86-103.##Busine, M. &amp; Watt, B. (2005). Succession management: Trends and current practice. Asia Pacific Journal of Human Resources, 43(2), 225-237.##Cameron, C. (2017). Bridging Executive Succession Gaps: Factors that Most Accelerate Executive Development (Doctoral dissertation, Case Western Reserve University).##Creswell, J. W. &amp; Clark, V. L. P. (2017). Designing and conducting mixed methods research. Sage publications.##Diamond, A. (2006). Finding success through succession planning. Security Management, 50(2), 36-39.##Keller, J. (2018). Succession Planning Management. In Succession Planning (pp. 41-48). Palgrave Macmillan, Cham.##Lewis, R. E. &amp; Heckman, R. J. (2006). Talent management: A critical review. Human resource management review, 16(2), 139-154.##McCallin, A., Frankson, C., &amp; Bamford-Wade, A. 2009. Leadership Succession Planning: A Key Issue for the Nursing Profession. Nurse Leader, 7(6), 40-44. McKee, G., Kagan, A., &amp; Ghosh, A. (2019). Small asset credit :::::union::::: executive succession concerns. Journal of Co-operative Organization and Management, 7(1), 26-33.##McKee, G. &amp; Froelich, K. (2016). Executive succession planning: barriers and substitutes in nonprofit organizations. Annals of Public and Cooperative Economics, 87(4), 587-601.## Moreno, J. V. &amp; Girard, A. S. (2019). Capitalizing on an Existing Shared Governance Structure in Developing Leadership Succession Planning. JONA: The Journal of Nursing Administration, 49(4), 193-200.##Rothwell, W. J. (2011). Replacement planning: A starting point for succession planning and talent management. International Journal of Training and Development, 15(1), 87-99.##Rothwell, W. J. &amp; Kazanas, H. C. (2003). The strategic development of talent. Human Resource Development.HRD press##Shum, P. Bove, L. &amp; Auh, S. (2008). Employees' affective commitment to change: The key to successful CRM implementation. European journal of marketing, 42(11/12), 1346-1371.##Tafti, M. M., Mahmoudsalehi, M., &amp; Amiri, M. (2017). Critical success factors, challenges and obstacles in talent management. Industrial and Commercial Training, 49(1), 15-21.##Taylor, T. &amp; McGraw, P. (2004). Succession management practices in Australian organizations. International Journal of Manpower, 25 (8), 741-758.##Turner, P. (2019). Linking Leadership and Succession Planning. In Leadership in Healthcare (pp. 233-262). Palgrave Macmillan, Cham. #### حسینی, سیدحسن، شائمی برزکی، علی و نصر اصفهانی، علی (1397). طراحی مدل نظام مدیریت جانشین‌پروری مبتنی بر شاخص‌های بومی- سازمانی. پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی, 10(1)، صص 50-25.##زبردست، محمد (1392). چالش برنامه ریزی و مدیریت جانشین در ادارات آموزش و‌پرورش استان کردستان. مجله رفتار سازمانی در آموزش و پرورش،دوره 1(1) ، صص 94-77.##قلی‌پور، آرین، پورعزت، علی‌اصغر و سبک‌رو، مهدی (1390). کاربست مدل میدان نیرو در برنامه‌ریزی برای جانشین‌پروری. پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی, 3(1)، صص 139-119. ##میرمحمدی، سید محمد و حسن‌پور، اکبر (1390 ). نظام اداری ایران: تحلیلی بر مشکلات و چالشها؛ فصلنامه چشم انداز مدیریت دولتی، شماره 8، زمستان 90، 22-9.##ناصحی فر، وحید، دهقانپور فراشاه، علی و سنجری، احمدرضا (1390). ساخت و اعتباریابی شاخص اندازه گیری گستردگی مدیریت جانشین پروری براساس طبقه بندی بهترین تجارب. پژوهش های مدیریت در ایران. ۱۵ (۳) ، 209-191.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>مدل مفهومی مدیریت دانش از دیدگاه منابع انسانی در موسسات  آموزشی- تحقیقاتی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Conceptual Model of Knowledge Management from the Perspective of Human Resources in Educational-Research Institutions</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>این مقاله &#160;به طراحی مدل مفهومی مدیریت دانش از دیدگاه منابع انسانی شاغل در موسسات آموزشی - تحقیقاتی می&#173;پردازد. روش تحقیق از نوع توصیفی- پیمایشی بود و جامعه آماری پژوهش شامل156 نفراز کارشناسان&#160; و مدیران&#160; یک&#160; موسسه تحقیقاتی -آموزشی بود که به روش تصادفی ساده &#160;و از طریق پرسشنامه محقق ساخته مورد پرسش قرار گرفتند. یافته&#173;های پژوهش &#160;بیانگر آن است که &#160;عوامل&#160; پنج گانه دانش آشکار و&#160; ضمنی، فرهنگ به اشتراک گذاشتن دانش، زیر ساخت های فناوری ارتباطات و اطلاعات، آموزش کارکنان &#160;و &#160;ساختار رسمی سازمان در فرآیند مدیریت دانش سازمانی تاثیر دارند. رگرسیون چند متغیری همزمان، نشان داد که از دیدگاه منابع انسانی از بین عوامل پنج گانه موثر بر مدیریت دانش، دو عامل دارا بودن دانش آشکار وضمنی و فرهنگ به اشتراک گذاشتن دانش، پیش بینی کننده مدیریت دانش سازمانی در موسسه هستند .</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>This paper focuses on designing a conceptual model of knowledge management from the point of view of human resources employed in educational-research institutes. The research method was descriptive-survey study and the statistical population of this study consisted of 56 experts and managers of an educational research institute. They were asked by simple random sampling method through a researcher-made questionnaire. The research findings indicate that the five factors of explicit and implicit knowledge, culture of sharing Knowledge, communication and information technology infrastructure, employee training and organizational structure are affected by organizational knowledge management process. Concurrent Multivariate Regression showed that among the five factors affecting knowledge management, two factors with explicit knowledge and knowledge sharing culture are predictors of organizational knowledge management at the institute.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>167</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>186</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مجتبی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رجب بیگی</Family>
				<NameE>Mojtaba</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rajabbeigi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>موسسه مطالعات بین المللی انرژی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>rajabbaigy@iies.net</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>پروانه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>گلرد</Family>
				<NameE>Parvaneh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Gelard</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تهران جنوب</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ابطحی نژاد</Family>
				<NameE>Seyed Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Abtahinezhad</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران شمال</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Tacit Knowledge- Explicit Knowledge- Knowledge Management– Knowledge Contribution</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دانش آشکار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دانش ضمنی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت دانش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اشتراک دانش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ajiferuke, I. (2003). Role of information professionals in knowledge   management programs: Empirical evidence from Canada, Informing Science Journal, 6,147–157.##Argote, A.(1993).  Group and organizational learning curves: individual, system and environment components, British Journal of social psychology, vol.32, 31-5.##Blair, D. C. (2002). Knowledge management: Hype, hope, or help? Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology, 53(12), 1019–1028.##Blecker, Th. &amp; Neumann, R. (2000). Interorganizational knowledge  Management —Some perspectives for knowledge oriented strategic   management in virtual organizations. In Y. Malhotra (Ed.), Knowledge management and virtual organizations (pp. 63–83). Hershey, London: Idea Group Publishing.##Chen, C. (2004). The effects of knowledge attribute, alliance characteristics, and absorptive capacity on knowledge transfer performance R&amp;D Management, 34(3), 311–321.##Chua, A. Y. K. (2009). The dark side of knowledge management initiatives.  Journal of Knowledge Management, 13(4), 32–40.##Calitz, A.P.  &amp; Cullen, M. (2017). The application of a knowledge management framework to automotive original component manufactures. Journal of information, knowledge and management, vol.12, 337-365. ##Dalkir, K. (2005). Knowledge management in theory and practice,  Burlington : Elsevier  Butterworth-Heinemann. ##Davenport, H.T. &amp; Prusak, L.(2000). Working Knowledge, Harvard Business Press, 2nd edition.##Ekbia, H. R. &amp; Hara, N. (2007). The quality of evidence in knowledge  management research: Practitioner versus scholarly literature. Journal of Information Science, 34(1), 1–17.##Ermine J. L , (2010). Methods and tools for knowledge management in research centers. Telecom business school , Electronic journal of knowledge management , vol. 8, Issue 3, 293-306.##Helupic, V., Pouloudi, A., &amp; Rzevski, G. (2002). Towards an integrated approach to knowledge management: ‘Hard’, ‘soft’ and ‘abstract’ issues. Knowledge and Process Management, 9(2), 90–102.##Hong J. C. &amp; Kuo C. l. (1999).  Knowledge management in the learning organization, The leadership and organization development Journal, 20(4), 207-215.##Jakubik, M. (2007). Exploring the knowledge landscape: Four emerging views of knowledge. Journal of Knowledge Management, 11(4), 6–19.##Jashapara, A. (2005). The emerging discourse of knowledge management: A new dawn for information science research?  Journal of Information Science, 31(2), 136–148. ##Kharabsheh,R., Bittel, N., Elnsour, W., Bettoni, M. &amp; Bernard, W. (2016). A comprehensive model of knowledge sharing. In Sandra Moffett &amp; Brendan Galbraith, Proceeding of the 17th European conference on knowledge management (455-461), Ulster University, Northern Ireland UK.##Liao, S. S., He, J. W., &amp; Tang, T. H. (2004). A framework for context  information  management. Journal of  Information Science, 30(6), 528–539.##Malhotra, Y.(2009). knowledge management .Retrieved from http://www.brint.com .##Martin, B. (2008). Knowledge management, In C. Blaise (Ed.),  Annual review of information science and technology (ARIST), Vol. 42, 371–424.##Matusik, S. F. &amp; Hill, C. W. L. (1998). The utilization of contingent  work, knowledge creation, and competitive advantage. Academy of Management Review, 23(4), 680–697.##Moaritsen, j. &amp; Thorsgaard L.H.(2005). The 2nd ware of Knowledge management: the management control of Knowledge, Accounting Research, 16(3), 379-394.##Nonaka, I. (1999). The dynamic of knowledge creation. In Ruggles, R. &amp; Hothouse, D. (Ed), The knowledge Advantage: 14 Visionaries Define Market Place in the New Economy, Capstone Publishing, Oxford, (PP: 64-87).##Nonaka,I.(2000). Organizational Knowledge Creation , Knowledge Advantage Conference, the National Security Agency. ##Perry, B. (2005). Information systems, organizational  management and information systems. CIMA publishing.##Radding, A.(1998). Knowledge Management: Succeeding in the Information-Based Global Economy, Computer Technology Research Corporation.##Rowley, J. (2007). The wisdom hierarchy: Representations of the DIKW hierarchy. Journal of Information Science, 33(2), 163–180.##Sarrafzadeh, M., Martin, B., &amp; Hazeri, A. (2006). LIS professionals and knowledge management: Some recent perspectives. Library Management, 27(9), 621–635.##Scott, W.R.(2002). Organizations: Rational, Natural, and Open Systems,  Prentice Hall, 5th edition.##Sveiby, K.E. (2001). A knowledge-based theory of the firm to guide in strategy, Journal of Intellectual Capital, Vol.2 No. 4, 344-58.##Widen-Wulff, G., Allen, D., Macevic, E., Moring, C., Papik, R., &amp; Wilson, T.(2005). Knowledge management/information management. In Leif Kajberg, &amp; Leif Lorring (Eds.), European curriculum reflections on library and information science education (PP: 121–130). Copenhagen: The Royal School of Library and Information Science.##داونپورت، اچ. تامس و پروساک، لارنس (1379). مدیریت دانش،  ترجمه حسین رحمان سرشت، تهران: انتشارات شرکت طراحی مهندسی و تأمین قطعات ایران خودرو(ساپکو)، چاپ اول.##رادینگ ، آلن (1386). مدیریت دانش؛ موفقیت در اقتصاد جهانی مبتنی بر اطلاعات، ترجمه محمد حسین لطیفی، تهران: انتشارات سمت، چاپ دوم.##فقیهی، ابوالحسن و رجب بیگی، مجتبی (1382). بالندگی سازمانی ؛رویکرد های نوین مدیریت در اندیشه و عمل ، تهران: نشر موسسه مطالعات و بهره‌وری منابع انسانی .##برومند کاخکی، احمد و اخوان، امیرناصر (1397). چالش ها و الزامات توسعه مدیریت دانش در شرکت ملی صنایع پتروشمی، فصلنامه علمی – پژوهشی مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال نهم، شماره 35، صص 212-187.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>رابطه ساختار سازمانی با مدیریت منابع انسانی و عملکرد؛ مطالعه ای در شرکت گاز استان فارس</TitleF>
		<TitleE> 
Relationship between Organizational Structure and Human Resource Management Processes and Performance; Case of the Gas Company in Fars Province
</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف از اجرای این پژوهش، بررسی ارتباط ساختار سازمانی با مدیریت منابع انسانی و عملکرد بود و برای آنجام آن، روش کاربردی از نوع توصیفی- پیمایشی مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. جامعه آماری این تحقیق را کارکنان شرکت گاز استان فارس تشکیل دادند که با نمونه&#8204;گیری تصادفی، تعداد270 نفر از کارکنان به روش تصادفی انتخاب شده و به پرسش&#8204;نامه&#8204;های استاندارد ساختار سازمانی، مدیریت منابع انسانی و عملکرد، پاسخ دادند. داده&#8204;های این تحقیق از طریق مدل&#8204;یابی معادلات ساختاری به روش تحلیل مسیر با استفاده از نرم&#8204;افزار spss و لیزرل مورد تجزیه&#8204; و تحلیل قرار گرفت. یافته&#8204;های تحقیق نشان داد که ارتباط مستقیمی بین فعالیت&#8204;های مدیریت منابع انسانی و ابعاد ساختار سازمانی وجود دارد. همچنین مدیریت منابع انسانی و ساختار سازمانی تأثیر مستقیمی بر عملکرد سازمان دارند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The purpose of this study was to investigate the relation between the organizational structure with the human resource management and the performance. The method used in this research has been an applied research and a descriptive-survey. The statistical population consisted of the employees of the gas company in Fars province and a sample of 270 randomly selected employees responded to standard questionnaires related to organizational structure, the human resource management and the performance. Data has been analyzed through structural equation modeling using path analysis applying SPSS and LISREL software. The findings showed that there is a direct relation between the human resource management activities and the organizational structure dimensions. In addition, the human resource management and the organizational structure have a direct effect on the organization's performance.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>187</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>206</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جاجرمی زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Jajarmi Zadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>پیام نور</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>m.jajarmizadeh@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>اعظم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>تدین</Family>
				<NameE>Azam</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Tadayon</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>پیام نور</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>a.tadayon18762@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Human Resources</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational Structure</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Performance</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ساختار سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عملکرد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abdul Ghani, V. &amp; Jayabalan, M. S. (2002). Impact of advanced manufacturing technology on organizational structure. Journal of High Technology and Management Research 13, 17–157.##Arthur, D. (1994). Effects of human resource systems on manufacturing  performance and turnover. Academy of Management Journal, 37(3), 670-687.##Ahmad , R. G. &amp; Schroeder, K. (2003). The impact of human resource management practices on operational performance: recognizing country and industry differences. Journal of Operations Management, 21(1), 19-43.##Abraham, Y., Mark, A., Vonderembse, B., &amp; Xenophon, A. (2003). The impact of organizational structure on time-based  manufacturing and plant performance. Journal of Operations Management 21, 281-306.##Annick, W. &amp; Marc, B.(2007). Impact of organizational structure on nurses job satisfaction: A questionnaire survey. International journal of nursing studies, 44(6), 1011-1020##Akhtar, S., Ding, D. Z., &amp; Ge, G. L. (2008). Strategic HRM practices and their impact on company performance in Chinese enterprises. Human Resource Management, 47(1), 15–32.##Child, J. (2008). Organization Structure, Environment, and Performance: The Role of Strategic Choice, Sociology, 6, 1-22.##Crantson, N.C. (2005). Academic managers and ethics: A question of making the right decision, Proceedings of the 2005 HERDSA Annual Conference, Sydney, 141-134. (Online at: www.eiconsortium.org.)##Daft, L. R. (2010). Organization theory and design. 10th ed, South- Western.##Dyer, L. (2008). Human Resource Management, Allynbocon, Boston. ##Fombrun, C.J., Tichy, M.M., &amp; Devanna, M. A. (1984). Strategic Human Resource Management, New York: John Wiley.##Jiang, K., Lepak, D. P., Han, K., &amp;Hong, Y.(2012). Clarifying the construct of human resource systems: Relating human resource management to employee performance, Human Resource Management Review, 22, 73–85.##Gresov, C. &amp; Drazin, R. (2007). Equifinality: Functional Equivalence in Organization Design, Academy of Management Review, 22, 403-428.##Hashim, J. (2010). Human resource management practices on organizational commitment The Islamic perspective, Personnel Review , 39(6), 785-799.##Harris, E. &amp; Ogbonna, M. (2001). Strategic human resource management, market orientation, and organizational Performance,  Journal of Business Research, 51(2), 157-166##Isaac, R. G., Herremans, I. M., Kline, D., &amp; Theresa, J. (2010). Intellectual Capital Management Enablers: A Structural Equation Modeling Analysis. Journal of Business Ethics, 93, 373-391.##Jayaram, C., Droge, S. K., &amp; Vickery, G. (1999). The impact of human resource management practices on manufacturing performance. Journal of Operations Management, 18(1), 1-20.##Keating, C. B. (2000). Improving practice a system-based methodology for structural analysis of health care operations. Journal of Management in Medicine. l4(3/4), 179-198##Kim, S.  &amp; Wright, P. M. (2011). Putting strategic human resource management in context: A contextualized model of high commitment work systems and its implications in China. Management and Organization Review, 7(1), 153–174.##Knies, E., Leisink, p., &amp; Schoot, R.S. (2017). People management: developing and testing a measurement scale, The International Journal of Human Resource Management, ,1-33##Koohborfardhaghi, S. &amp; Altmann, J. (2017). How Organizational Structure Affects Organizational Learning,Journal of Integrated Design and Process Science, 21 (1), 43-60##Lu, Y. &amp; Tao, R. (2017). Organizational Structure and Collective Action: Lineage Networks, Semiautonomous Civic Associations, and Collective Resistance in Rural China1, 122(6), 1726–1774.##March, J.  &amp; Simon, H. (2009). Organization, Cambridge, Blackwell##Mihm, J. L., Christoph, H., Wilkinson, D., &amp; Huberman, B. A. (2010). Hierarchical Structure##and Search in Complex Organizations, Management Science, 56(5), 831-848.##Mellahi, K. (2010). Introduction: Islam and human resource management, Personnel Review, 39(6), 685-691.##Ogbonna, M., Lloyd, C., &amp; Harris, R. (2003). Innovative organizational Structures and Performance: A case Study of Structural Transformation to Groovy Community Centers, Journal of Organizational Change Management: Volume: 16(5), 512-533.##Purcell, P.D. &amp; Baxall, D. (2004). Strategy and Human Resource Management, Mc Graw,214##Reich, R.B. (1990). Who is us? Harvard Business Review, January-February, 53-64.##Qingmin, H., Helmut, K., &amp; Juergen, M.(2012). How does organizational structure influence performance through learning and innovation in Austria and China, Chinese management studies, 6, 36-52.##Rios, C. M. (2012). Why do firms seek to share human resource management knowledge? The importance of inter-firm networks, Journal of Business Research, 67(2), 190-199.##Rose, T. &amp; Kumar, N. (2006). The influence of organizational and  human resource management strategies on performance, International Society for Performance Improvement, 7,18-29.##Robbins, S. P. (1998). Organization Theory, New York, Prentice Hall.##Wu, I. &amp; Lin, H. (2009). A strategy-based process for implementing knowledge management: An integrative view and empirical study. Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology, 60(4), 789-802.##Wang, D. &amp; Yang, S. (2008). Impact of organizational structure and HRM on organizational performance, International Engineering Management Conference, IEEE International Engineering Management Conference, Austin, 164-169.##Wright, P.M. &amp; Boswell, W. R. (2002). Desegregating HRM: A review and synthesis of micro and macro human resource management research. Journal of Management, 28(3), 247-276.##Wright, P., Mccormick, B., &amp; Sherman, W. (1999). The role of human resource practices in petro- chemical refinery performance, The Internatinal Journal of Human Resource Management, 10, 551-571.##اصیلی، غلامرضا، افخمی اردکانی، مهدی، ابراهیمی، محسن و ورمزیار، محسن (1395). تبیین مدل ساختاری مدیریت منابع انسانی در سازمان‌های پروژه‌محور، فصلنامه علمی پژوهشی مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 7، شماره 28، صص80-56.##اکبری، حسن (1397). بررسی رابطه بین مدیریت استراتژیک منابع انسانی و عملکرد سازمانی، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی بهشهر. ##امیر نژاد، قنبر و اژدری، پرستو (1396). بررسی ساختار سازمانی بر چابکی سازمانی با نقش میانجی فرهنگ ‌سازمانی، فصلنامه علمی- پژوهشی علوم اجتماعی، سال 11، شماره 1، صص296-273.##باتمانی، محمد امین، باباشاهی، جبار، اخوان علوی، سید حسین، یزدانی، حمیدرضا و زارعی متین، حسن (1397). تبیین ابعاد و عوامل مؤثر بر حرفه‌ای‌گرایی مدیریت منابع انسانی در سازمان‌های دولتی، فصنامه علمی_ پژوهشی مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال دهم، شماره 37، صص34-3.##ثموری مهاجر، مریم ‌(1379). بررسی رابطه بین ساختار سازمانی با فرهنگ سازمانی در مؤسسات دولتی، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه آزاداسلامی، کرمان، صص25-18##جزنی، نسرین (1384). مدیریت منابع انسانی ، چاپ چهارم، تهران: نشر نی.##حقیقی، محمد، قارلقی، ابراهیم، میراسدی، سمانه و نیک‌بخت، فاطمه (1389). بررسی رابطه میان ویژگی‌های بیانیه مأموریت سازمان و عملکرد سازمانی- مورد مطالعه: شرکت‌های فعال در صنعت غذایی تهران، پژوهش‌نامه مدیریت تحول، شماره 4،  صص186-166.##صانعی، مهدی (1392). بررسی رابطه بین اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی و عملکرد شغلی کارکنان بانک مرکزی جمهوری اسلامی ایران، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی شاهرود.##رابینز، استیفن (1381). تئوری سازمان، ترجمه سید مهدی الوانی و حسن دانایی‌فرد، تهران: انتشارات صفار. ##طیبی شیرمرد، مهدی و میرزایی، نورالدین (1396). بررسی رابطه ساختار سازمانی بر توانمندسازی کارکنان معاونت توسعه مدیریت شهرداری تهران، فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت شهری، سال 9، شماره 29، صص 79-67 .##میر سپاسی، ناصر (1385). مدیریت استراتژیک منابع انسانی و روابط کار، چاپ شانزدهم، تهران: میر##مرحمتی، سعات (1392). رابطه ساختار با خلاقیت سازمانی، مجله پزشکی هرمزگان، سال 17، شماره 2، صص 52-45.##مطلبی ورکانی، ابوطالب (1395). تأثیر مدیریت راهبردی نیروی انسانی بر چگونگی عملکرد کارکنان نیروی دریایی ارتش، فصلنامه علمی پژوهشی آموزش علوم دریایی، شماره 5، صص 39-28.##مشبکی، اصغر و موسوی مجد، سید محمد (1391). رابطه هماهنگی استراتژیک بین استراتژی‌های تجاری، استراتژی‌های منابع انسانی و ساختار سازمانی، مجله علمی پژوهشی مدیریت فرهنگ ‌سازمانی، دوره 10، شماره1، صص 27-12.##موسوی مجد، سید محمد (1390). رابطه‌ی ترکیب استرات‍ژهای منابع انسانی و ساختار سازمانی با عملکرد سازمانی در شرکت‌های دارویی پذیرفته شده در بورس، پایان‌نامه دکترا، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.##وکیلی، یوسف (1396). بررسی تأثیر اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی با عملکرد بالا بر عملکرد شغلی، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه خوارزمی.##هال، ریچارد اچ (1384).  سازمان، ساختار، فرایندها، ره‌آوردها، ترجمه علی پارسائیان و سید محمد اعرابی، چاپ چهارم، تهران :  دفتر پژوهش‌های فرهنگی.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی رابطه میان سبک‌های رهبری و عدالت سازمانی  با اعتماد کارکنان</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Study of the relationship between leadership styles and organizational justice with staff trust </TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی رابطه میان سبک&#8204;های رهبری و عدالت سازمانی با اعتماد کارکنان بود. این پژوهش از لحاظ ماهیت مساله و هدف، پژوهشی کاربردی محسوب می&#8204;شود و از لحاظ روش گردآوری داده&#8204;ها توصیفی-پیمایشی به&#8204;شمار می&#8204;رود. جامعه آماری پژوهش، کارکنان مدیریت پشتیبانی ساخت و تامین کالای شرکت ملی نفت ایران بود که با استفاده از روش نمونه&#8204;گیری تصادفی ساده و فرمول مورگان تعداد 244 نفر برای حجم نمونه انتخاب شدند. برای گردآوری اطلاعات از پرسشنامه&#8204;های استاندارد سنجش سبک رهبری&#8204;، اعتماد سازمانی و اعتماد استفاده شده است. تجزیه و تحلیل داده&#8204;ها با استفاده از روش&#8204; همبستگی پیرسون و با کمک نرم&#8204;افزارهایSPSS انجام شده است. نتایج حاصل از این پژوهش نشان داد که بین سبک&#8204;های رهبری (تحول آفرین و تبادلی) و عدالت سازمانی (توزیعی و رویه&#8204;ای) با اعتماد کارکنان در واحد مورد مطالعه ، رابطه معنی&#8204;داری وجود دارد. همچنین نتایج به&#8204;دست آمده از آزمون فریدمن نشان داد که عدالت رویه&#8204;ای با میانگین 4.69 در رتبه اول و عدالت توزیعی با 4.06 در رتبه دوم و نیز متغییر رهبری تحول آفرین با میانگین 3.76 و رهبری تبادلی با رتبه 3.29 از اهمیت متفاوتی برخوردار هستند .</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The objective of this research was to study the relationship between leadership styles and organizational justice and employees&#8217; confidence. It is consumed an applied research in terms of method and it is categorized as a descriptive-survey. The statistical population was the employees of the, Manufacturing Support and procurement Management Office of the National Iranian Oil Company which among them &#160;244 persons were selected as sample size using stochastic sampling method and the Morgan&#8217;s formula. The research information was gathered by standard questionnaires of leadership styles, organizational justice and employees&#8217; confidence. Research data was analyzed using descriptive and inferential statistical methods and SPSS software. This research revealed that there is a significant relationship between leadership styles (transformational and transactional), organizational justice (distributive and procedural) and employees&#8217; confidence in the case which has been studied. Also, the results obtained from Friedman's test showed that procedural justice with a mean of 4.69 in the first rank and distributive justice with 4.06 in the second rank and the transformational leadership variable with an average of 3.76 and exchange leadership with rank of 3.29 had a different significance.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>207</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>228</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علیرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مهرابی طالقانی</Family>
				<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mehrabi Taleghani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران شمال</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mehrabialireza34@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>محمدیان ساروی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohsen</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mohammadian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران شمال</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mo.dian@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Leadership styles</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Transformational leadership</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Transactional leadership</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational justice</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Distributive justice</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Procedural justice</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Employees’ confidence</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سبک‌های رهبری‌</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سبک رهبری تحول آفرین</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سبک رهبری تبادلی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عدالت سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عدالت توزیعی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عدالت رویه ای</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اعتماد کارکنان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Assad, R. &amp; Hubbell, A. (2005).  Motivating Factors: Perceptions of Justice and Their Relationship with Managerial and Organizational Trust, Communication Studies, 56, 1, 47–70.## Baek, Y.M. &amp; Jung, C.S. (2014). Focusing the meditating role of institutional trust promotes organizational commitment . The Social Science Journal, 52, 4, 481-489##Bass, B. M. &amp; Avolio, B. J. (1994). Improving Organizational Effectiveness through Transformational Leadership. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications.##Bass, B. M. &amp; Avolio, B. J. (2000). Multifactor Leadership Questionnaire (MLQ). Redwood City: Mind Garden.##Cheng, S. (2014). The mediating role of organizational justice on the relationship between administrative performance appraisal practice and organizational commitment, the International journal of human Resource management, 26, 8, 1131-1148.##Deconinck,  J. (2010). The Effect of Organizational Justice, Perceived Organizational Support, and Perceived Supervisor Support on Marketing Employees’ Level of Trust. Journal of Business Research, 63, 1349-1355.##Dedahanov, A. &amp; Rhee, J. (2015). Examining the relationships among trust, silence and organizational commitment, Management Decision, 53, 1843-1857##Dominick, E. (2014). The performance impact of supply chain agility and supply chain adaptability: the moderating effect of product complexity. International Journal Of Production Research, 27, 3028-3046.##Faisal Mahdi, A., Mohd Zin, M., Mohd Nor, M., Asmadi Sakat, A., &amp; Sulaiman Abang Naim, A. (2012). The Relationship Between Job Satisfaction and Turnover Intention. American Journal of Applied Sciences. 9. 1518-1526.##Gamble, J. &amp; Tian, A. (2015). Intra-national variation in organizational commitment: evidence from the Chinese context. The international journal of human resource management, vol. 26, no. 7, 948-970##Grill, A. (2010). The relationship between transformational leadership and employee. , International Journal of Contemporary Hospitality Management, Vol. 22 Issue: 2, pp.263-273.##Jiangm X., Gallon, J. &amp; Brooks, G. (2015). Relationships between organizational justice, organizational trust and organizational commitment: across-cultural study of china, South Korea and Australia, the international journal of human resource management, doi.org/10.1080/09585192.2015.1128457, 1-32##Johannessen, J. A., Olsen, B., &amp; Lumpkin, G. T. (2001).  Innovation as newness: What is new, how new, and new to whom? European Journal of Innovation Management, 4(1), 20-31. https://doi.org/10.1108/14601060110365547##Kim, T., Wang, J., &amp; Chen, J. (2018). Mutual Trust Between Leader and Subordinate and Employee Outcomes. Journal of Business Ethics, 149, 4, 945-958. (DOI 10.1007/s10551-016-3093-y)##Lee, C., Song, H., Lee, H., Lee, S., &amp; Bernhard, B .J. (2013). The impact of SCR on casino employee’s organizational trust, job satisfaction, and customer orientation: an empirical examination of responsible gambling strategies, International Journal of Hospitality Management ,33 , 406-415.##Mukherjee, k. &amp; Bhattacharya, R. (2013). Exploring the mediating effect of organizational trust between organizational justice dimension and affective commitment, Management And Labor Studies, 38 (1 &amp; 2), 63-79.##Niehoff, B.P. &amp; Moorman, R.H. (1993). Justice as a mediator of the relationship between methods of monitoring and organizational citizenship behavior. Academy of Management Journal, 36, 527-556.##Norman, S. , Avolio, B., &amp; Luthans, F. (2010).  The impact of positivity and transparency on trust in leaders and their perceived effectiveness, The Leadership Quarterly, 21, 350-364.##Othman, A. A., Sundram, V. P. K., Sayuti, N. M. &amp; Bahrin A. S., (2016). The Relationship between Supply Chain Integration, Just-In-Time and Logistics Performance: A Supplier’s Perspective on the Automotive Industry in Malaysia.  International Journal of Supply Chain Management, Vol. 58, N. 1, 44-51. https://www.researchgate.net##Palanski, M. &amp; Yammarino, F. (2009). Integrity and leadership: A multi-level conceptual framework, The Leadership Quarterly, 20, 405-420.##Pearce, C. L. , Sims Jr, H. P. , Cox, J. F. , Ball, G. , Schnell, E. , Smith, K. A., &amp;Trevino, L. (2003).  Transactors, transformers and beyond (A multi–method development of a theoretical typology of leadership), Journal of Management Development, Vol. 22, No. 4, PP: 273-307.##Ruder, G. J. (2003). The Relationship among Organizational Justice, Trust, and Role Breadth Self-Efficacy, Dissertation, Virginia: March.##Tekingunduz, S. , Top, M., Tengilimoglu, D., &amp; Karrabul, E. (2015). Effect of   organizational trust, job satisfaction, individual Variables on the organizational commitment in healthcare Service, journal of Total Quality Management, Published online: 20 Oct 2015 PP: 522-541 ##Tlaiss, H. &amp; Elamin, A. (2015).  Exploring the relationship between organizational citizenship behavior and organizational justice in the Islamic Saudi Arabian context, journal of management development, 34, 9, 1042-1060.##Utami, A.,  Bangun, Y., &amp; Lantu, D. (2014).  Understanding the Role of Emotional Intelligence and Trust to the Relationship between Organizational Politics and Organizational Commitment, Pericardia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 115, 378 – 386.##Vanhala, M., Heilmann, P., &amp; Salminen, H. (2016). Organizational trust dimension as antecedents of organizational commitment, knowledge and process management, 23, 1, 46-61.##حسن پور، علی (1391). نقش رهبری تحول گرا در توانمند سازی کارکنان، مدیر ایران، شماره 15،  صص 25-43.##دهقانیان، حامد، صبور، الهام و حجتی، علیرضا (1392). بررسی رابطه بین مولفه های  عدالت سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی در یک شرکت بیمه، پژوهشنامه بیمه، سال28، شماره 2، صص 183-153##رضایی، آذرمیدخت و شهامت، سروجهاد (1392)، پیش بینی رضایت شغلی پرستاران بر اساس هوش هیجانی و شایستگی. طب جنوب ، شماره 2 ،‌صص 137-128.##سید جوادین، سید رضا، عابدی، احسان، یزدانی، حمید رضا و پورولی، بهروز (1392). بررسی نقش میانجی اعتماد و تعهد سازمانی در رابطه بین عدالت سازمانی و رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی در بیمارستان ها، مدیریت بازرگانی، دوره 5، شماره 1، صص 118-105.##سیدین، سید حسام، احدی نژاد، بهمن، تورانی، سوگند و رجبی فرد، فاطمه (1393). رابطه عدالت سازمانی ادراک شده و بهره وری در بیمارستان های دانشگاه علوم پزشکی ایران، اخلاق زیستی، سال 4، شماره 13، صص116-97. ##شمس، شهاب الدین و اسفندیاری مقدم، امیر(1394). ارتباط ابعاد مختلف اعتماد سازمانی با رضایت شغلی کارکنان، مطالعات مدیریت(بهبود تحول)، سال 23، شماره 77، صص 185-171.## شقاقی، عبدالرضا و شفیعی، مسعود (1388). استراتژی افزایش مشارکت موثر و رقابتی بخش صنایع کوچک و متوسط در توسعه اقتصادی و صنعتی جمهوری اسلامی ایران، تهران: انتشارات رسا.##علیزاده ثانی، محسن، یحیی زاده فر، محمود و حسن زاده، مریم (1393). اثر تنوع ادراک شده بر عملکرد مالی تیم: نقش تعدیل گر اعتماد سازمانی، فصلنامه مطالعات رفتار سازمانی، سال 3، شماره 4( پیاپی 11)، صص 195-173.##قاسمی، احمدرضا (1393). بررسی نقش میانجی رفتار شهروندی سازمانی بر عدالت سازمانی و عملکرد شغلی، مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی، دوره 12، شماره 1، صص82-63.##کاظمی، مصظفی و رمضانی، یوسف (1391). بررسی رابطه بین اعتماد به مدیریت و به اشتراک گذاشتن دانش و نقش میانجی ترس از دست دادن اعتبار و مستند سازی دانش، پژوهش نامه مدیریت تحول ، سال 4، شماره 8، صص130-111.##نیازآذری،کیومرث (1390). اثر سبک رهبری درونی و تحول آمیز بر اخلاق کار، مجله روانپزشکی ، شماره 1، صص 33-15.##یعقوبی، مریم، سقاییان نژاد اصفهانی، سکینه، گرجی حسن، ابوالقاسم، نوروزی ، محسن و رضایی، فاطمه (1386). رابطه بین عدالت سازمانی و رضایت شغلی در بین کارکنان بیمارستان های منتخب دانشکده علوم پزشکی اصفهان، فصلنامه مدیریت سلامت،  شماره 35 ، صص32-25.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
