<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1398</YEAR>
<VOL>11</VOL>
<NO>42</NO>
<MOSALSAL>42</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>343</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بلوغ سرمایه انسانی در سازمان‌های تولیدی برتر و الزامات راهبردی آن</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The maturity of human capital in superior manufacturing organizations and its strategic implications</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>بلوغ سرمایه انسانی، تاثیر آن بر عملکرد و استراتژی سازمان و نحوه سنجش آن در دهه&#173; های اخیر مورد توجه محققان واقع شده است. به همین جهت پژوهش حاضر سنجش سطح بلوغ سرمایه انسانی در 80 سازمان&#173; برتر تولیدی ایران و احصای الزامات راهبردی متناسب با آن را هدف قرار داد. برای نیل به این هدف از تحلیل عاملی تاییدی، پیمایش به وسیله پرسشنامه بلوغ سرمایه انسانی و روش تحلیل شبکه استفاده شد. در نتیجه، مولفه &#173;های پرسشنامه تایید گردیده و با استفاده از پرسشنامه به دست آمده در نمونه 80 نفری از مدیران منابع انسانی سازمان &#173;های مذکور، سطح بلوغ سرمایه انسانی ضعیف ارزیابی شد. همچنین با روش تحلیل شبکه، مطابق با نظر 10 نفر خبره حوزه منابع انسانی عوامل موثر بر بلوغ سرمایه انسانی بدین ترتیب اولویت &#173;بندی شد: 1- ظرفیت یادگیری 2-بهینه&#173; سازی نیروی کار3-دسترسی به دانش 4- عجین&#173; سازی کارکنان و 5- شیوه اعمال رهبری، در نهایت با نظر 10 خبره دیگر در زمینه مدیریت استراتژیک و منابع انسانی و با توجه به نمرات پرسشنامه، استراتژی تدافعی بین گونه&#173; شناسی استراتژی &#173;های مایلز و اسنو پیشنهاد شد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The maturity of Human capital, its impact on performance and organization strategy, and how to assess this concept has been concerned by researchers in recent decades. Therefore, the present study aimed to assess the level of human capital maturity in Iran's top 80 manufacturing organizations and to identify the strategic implications for it. For this purpose, Confirmatory Factor Analysis Method, Surveying through the human capital maturity questionnaire and network analysis method has been used. The results of the first method validated the questionnaire's variables, and in a sample of 80 among human resource managers in sample organizations, the questionnaire assessed the level of the human capital maturity as low (the score was almost 54) and finally based on the opinions of 10 human resource experts, the network analysis method prioritized factors affecting human capital maturity in this way: 1-The capacity of Learning capacity, 2-workforce optimization, 3-Knowledge accessibility, 4-Employee engagement, 5-Leadership practices. At last, based on opinions of 10 HRM and strategic management experts, and scores of these organizations, the defensive strategy was suggested based on typology of strategies according miles and snow.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>3</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>32</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جوادی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Javadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه امام صادق(ع)</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>امام صادق(ع)</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>moh.javadi@isu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عادل</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>آذر</Family>
				<NameE>Adel</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>azar</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تربیت مدرس</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>azara@modares.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>اسدالله</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>گنجعلی</Family>
				<NameE>Asadollah</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ganjali</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه امام صادق (ع)</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>امام صادق(ع)</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>ganjali@isu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Human Capital</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Human Capital Maturity</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Human Capital Maturity Measure</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Miles and Snow Strategy</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Human Resources Management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Strategic Management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سرمایه انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بلوغ سرمایه انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سنجش بلوغ سرمایه انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>استراتژی مایلز و اسنو</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت استراتژیک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Andriessen, D. (2004). IC valuation &amp; measurement: classifying the state of the art. Journal of Intellectual Capital, 5(2), 230-242.##Baron, A. (2011). Measuring human capital, Strategic HR Review, 10(2), 30–35.##Bechtel, R. (2007). Calculating human capital: the market based valuation of the human resource , German Journal of Human Resource Research, 21(3), 206-231.##Bontis, N. (2001). Assessing Knowledge Assets: A Review of the Models Used to Measure Intellectual Capital. International Journal of Management Reviews, 3, 41 - 60.##Bucknall, H. &amp; Zheng, w. (2006). Magic numbers for human resource management Basic measures to achieve better results. Chichester: Wiley.##Cappelli , P. &amp; Keller, J. (2017). The Historical Context of Talent Management. In The Oxford Handbook of Talent Management, by David G. Collings, Kamel Mellahi &amp; Wayne F. Cascio, 608  ,Oxford: Oxford University Press.##Claver-Cortés,E., Zaragoza-Sáez, P., Molina-Manchón, H. &amp; Úbeda-García, M. (2015). Intellectual capital in family firms: human capital identification &amp; measurement. Journal of Intellectual Capital, 16(1), 199-223. ##Dilys , R. (2009). Human capital measurement: an approach that work. Strategic HR Review, 8(6), 5 – 11.##Drucker, P. (1994). Post-capitalist society. New York: HarperBusiness.##Felício, J., Couto, E., &amp; Caiado, J.(2014). Human capital, social capital &amp; organizational performance. Management Decision, 52 (2), 350 – 364.##Fitz-enz, J.A. (2009). The ROI of human capital. Measuring the economic value of employee performance. (2nd ed). New York: AMACOM.##Foster, S. (2013). HR Ready: Creating Competitive Advantage Through Human Resource Management, Lulu.com. Available online at https://books.google.com/books?id=HS-bBQAAQBAJ.##Gates,S.  &amp; Langevin, P. (2010). Human capital measures, strategy, &amp; performance: HR managers' perceptions. Accounting, Auditing &amp; Accountability Journal, 23(1),111-132.##Gomez-Mejia, L.R., Balkin, D.B., &amp; Cardy, R.L. (2012).  Managing human resources. (7th). Boston: Pearson.##Jackson, P. (2007). A systems approach for human capital management . VINE, 37(4), 399–403. ##Patrice, J. (2007). A systems approach for human capital management. Emerald Group Publishing Limited, 37(4),  399–403.##Krugman, P., Wells, R. &amp; Graddy, K. (2013). Essentials of economics. (3th). New York: Worth Publishers.##Kucharčíková, A., Tokarčíková, E., &amp; Blašková, M. (2015). Human Capital Management – Aspect of the Human Capital Efficiency in University Education. Procedia - Social &amp; Behavioral Sciences,177, 48-60.##Marr, B., Gray, D., &amp; Neely, A. (2003). Why do ﬁrms measure their intellectual capital?. Journal of Intellectual Capital, 4 (4), 441-464.##Massingham, P. &amp; Tam, L. (2015). The relationship between human capital, value creation &amp; employee reward. Jnl of Intellectual Capital, 16(2), 390–418.##Mathis, R.L. &amp; Jackson, J.H. (2010). Human Resource Management. (13th). Ohio: SouthWestern College Publishing.##Namasivayam, K. &amp; Denizci, B. (2006). Human capital in service organizations. Identifying value drivers. Jnl of Intellectual Capital,7(3), 381–393. ##Pietsch, G. (2007). Human capital measurement, ambiguity, &amp; opportunism: actors between menace &amp; opportunity. German Journal of Human Resource Research, 21(3), 252-273.##Rompho, B. &amp; Siengthai, S. (2012). Integrated performance measurement system for firm's human capital building. Journal of Intellectual Capital, 13(4), 482-514. ##Schultz, T. (1961). Investment in Human Capital: Reply. The American Economic Revie , 51(1), 1035–1039.##Stein, V. (2007). Human Capital Management: The German Way. German Journal of Human Resource Management: Zeitschrift für Personalforschung Personalforschung, 21(3) , 295–321. ##Vidotto, J., Aisenberg, F.H.., Selig, P., &amp; Bastos, R.C. (2017). A human capital measurement scale. Jnl of Intellectual Capita, 18(2), 316–329. ##Weber, S. (2014). Human capital depreciation &amp; education level. International Journal of Manpower, 35(5) , 613-642. ##Yasir, M. &amp; Majid, A. (2017). Impact of knowledge management enablers on knowledge sharing. World Journal of Entrepreneurship, Management &amp; Sustainable Development, 13(1), 16–33.##Ziyae, B. (2016). Presenting an evaluation model of human resource management’s effect on corporate entrepreneurship. World Journal of Entrepreneurship, Management &amp; Sustainable Development , 12(3), 228–242.##آذر، عادل و رجب‌زاده، علی(1389). تصمیم‌گیری کاربردی رویکرد MADM، تهران: نگاه دانش.##آذر، عادل، غلامزاده، رسول و قنواتی، مهدی (1391). مدل‌سازی مسیری-ساختاری در مدیریت: کاربرد نرم‌افزار Smart PLS، چاپ اول، تهران: نگاه دانش.##آذر، عادل و مومنی، منصور (1388). آمار و کاربرد آن در مدیریت، چاپ سیزدهم، تهران: سمت.##توکلی، عبدالله و گائینی، ابوالفضل(1392). مدیریت منابع انسانی: با رویکرد اسلامی، قم: پژوهشگاه حوزه و دانشگاه.##حسن‌زاده‌ثمرین، تورج و صحرانورد، علیرضا (1397). بررسی نقش میانجی بلوغ سازمانی در تاثیر سبک‌های رهبری بر تعهد سازمانی کارکنان (مورد مطالعه: مجموعه پتروشیمی‌های عسلویه)، مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، شماره 35، صص  104-84.##رضائیان، علی(1390) . مبانی سازمان و مدیریت، تهران: سمت.##سعادت، اسفندیار(1395). مدیریت منابع انسانی، تهران: سمت.##شیروانی، علی‌رضا و شفیعیه، مسعود (1389). بررسی و ارزیابی سطح بلوغ مدیریت سرمایه انسانی در سازمان‌های بخش دولتی شهر اصفهان، مدیریت بهره‌وری، شماره 4، صص 114-77.##کردنائیج، اسدالله (1396). تفکر و مدیریت استراتژیک؛ تئوری و عمل، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه تربیت مدرس.##گنجعلی، اسدالله، ابراهیمی، کریم و سرآبادانی‌تفرشی، حسین (1394). بررسی انتقادی مبانی انسان‌شناسی: پارادایم-های مدیریت منابع انسانی بر اساس نظریه انسان‌شناسی پارادایم رشد، اندیشه مدیریت راهبردی، شماره1، صص 174-147.##معصومی، عذرا (1390). بررسی تاثیر سرمایه انسانی بر رقابت‌پذیر شدن بانک: مطالعه موردی بانک کشاورزی استان گلستان، اسلام و پژوهش های مدیریتی ،شماره 2، صص 156-127.##مهربانی، فاطمه، قبادی، صغری و رضائیان، علی(1395). بررسی اثر و رابطه بین اقتصاد دانش بنیان و بهره‌وری کل عوامل تولید؛ مطالعه موردی کشورهای توسعه‌یافته، نوظهور و در حال توسعه، جستارهای اقتصادی، شماره11، صص160-125.##هیر، جوزف، هالت، توماس، رینگل، کریستین و سارستد، مارکو (1395). مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری کمتری مربعات جزئی، ترجمه عادل آذر و رسول غلام‌زاده، چاپ اول،  تهران: نگاه دانش. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>مدل‌سازی ایفای نقش مربی‌گری مدیریتی مدیران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Modeling the Executive Coaching Role of Directors</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>در سال&#8204;های اخیر بسیاری از شرکت&#8204;های پیشرو دریافته&#8204;اند که مدیران نقش حیاتی در پیشبرد اهداف و برنامه&#8204;های منابع انسانی داشته و مسئولیت توسعه کارکنان به مدیران آنها محول شده است. در راستای اجرای این مسئولیت، یکی از نقش&#8204;هایی که امروزه به مدیران واگذار گردیده است، مربی&#8204;گری &#8204;می&#8204;باشد. از این&#8204;رو مدل&#8204;سازی ایفای نقش مربی&#8204;گریِ&#8204;ِ مدیریتیِ مدیران در صنعت نفت ایران، هدف اصلی از انجام این پژوهش کیفی، براساس رویکرد نظریه داده بنیاد، در نظر گرفته شد. ابزار جمع&#8204;آوری داده&#8204;ها، مصاحبه&#8204;های نیمه&#8204;ساختار یافته بود. به&#8204;منظور گردآوری اطلاعات با به&#8204;کارگیری روش نمونه&#8204;گیری هدفمند و نمونه&#8204;گیری گلوله برفی، با 16 نفر از نخبگان دانشگاهی و خبرگان صنعت نفت مصاحبه صورت پذیرفت. تحلیل و پردازش داده&#8204;ها در سه مرحله کدگذاری باز، کدگذاری محوری و کدگذاری انتخابی انجام گرفت. یافته&#8204;های تحقیق حاضر نشان&#8204;دهنده 11 مقوله اصلی، 27 مقوله فرعی و 71 مفهوم در ایفای نقش مربی&#8204;گری مدیریتی برای مدیران بود.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>In recent years, many leading companies have found that managers and supervisors play a vital role in promoting human resource goals and programs, and have been entrusted with the development and training of employees to their executives. Today, one of the roles assigned to managers to implement this responsibility, is coaching. Therefore, modeling the executive coaching role of directors in Iran oil industry was the main objective of this qualitative research which was done based on grounded theory approach. The data collection tool was semi-structured interviews. Sixteen oil industry and academic experts were interviewed to collect information using purposeful sampling and snowball sampling. Data was gathered in three stages: open coding, axial coding and selective coding. The findings of the present study represented 11 main categories, 27 sub categories and 71 concepts for executive coaching role of directors.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>33</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>60</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>جهانگیری</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Jahangiri</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>موسسه عالی آموزش پژوهش مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>a.jahangiri@imps.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ذوقی</Family>
				<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Zoghi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>موسسه عالی آموزش پژوهش مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mahdiizoghi@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رنگریز</Family>
				<NameE>Hasan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rangriz</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>rangriz@khu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عبدالحمید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شمس</Family>
				<NameE>Abdolhamid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shams</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>موسسه عالی آموزش پژوهش مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>abh.shams@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Coaching</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Executive Coaching</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Executive Coaching Role</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Oil Industry</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Grounded Theory</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مربی‌گری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مربی‌گری مدیریتی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نقش مربی‌گری مدیران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>صنعت نفت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نظریه داده بنیاد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Anderson, D. &amp; Anderson, M. (2005). Coaching that counts. Burlington, MA: Elsevier Butterworth-Heinemann.##Axmit, M. (2004). Executive coaching: a catalyst for personal growth and corporate change. Business Journal online, London, 1-5.##Bacon, T. &amp; Spear, K. (2003). Adaptive coaching: the art and practice of a client – centered approach to performance improvement. Mountain View. CA: Davies – Black.##Bresser, F. (2010). The global business guide for the successful use of coaching in organizations. Frank Bresser Publishing, Cologne.##Caplan, J. (2003). Coaching for the future: How smart company's use coaching and mentoring. London, UK: Chartered Institute of Personnel and Development (CIPD).##Crane, T. G. (2007). The heart of coaching: using transformation coaching to create a high – performance culture (Third ed). San Diego: FTA Press.##Deans, F. &amp; Oakley, L. (2006). Coaching and Mentoring for Leadership Development in Civil Society, Practical Action Publishing, Executive coaching##Evered, r. d. &amp; Selman, J. C. (1989). Coaching and the art of management. Organizational Dynamics Journal, 18(2), 16- 32.##Edwards, L. (2003). Coaching the latest buzzword or a truly effective management tool, Industrial &amp; Commercial Training, Vol.35 Issue 7.298-301.##Ellinger, A. D., Beattie, R. S., &amp; Hamlin, R. G. (2014). The manager as coach. In E. Cox, T. Bachkirova &amp; D. Clutterbuck (Eds.), the Complete Handbook of coaching (2nd ed), London: Sage.##Ellinger, A. D., Beattie, R. S., Hamlin, R. G., Wang, Y., &amp; Trolan, O. (2006). The manager as coach: A review of empirical literature and the development of a tentative model of managerial coaching. In Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference on HRD.##Ennis, S., Goodman, R., Hodgetts, W., Hunt, J. M., Monsfield, R., Otto, J., &amp; Stren, L. (2010). Core Competencies of executive coach. Boston: executive Coaching, available from: www.executivecoachingforum.com.##Feldman, D. C. &amp; Lankau, M. J. (2005). Executive coaching: A review and agenda for future research. Journal of Management, 31, 829-848.##Grant, A. M. (2007). Enhancing coaching skills and emotional intelligence through training. industrial and commercial training, 39(5), 257- 266.##Griffiths, K. (2005). Personal coaching: A model for effective learning. Journal of learning Design. 1 (2), 55-65.##Gwyther–Jones, M. (2011). The practice of coaching by line managers a tool to improve employee performance, learning and development at Cardiff council. Master Thesis of Public Administration, Cardiff Business of School.##Joo, B. (2005). Executive Coaching: A Conceptual Framework from an Integrative Review of Practice and Research. Human Resource Development Review, 4 (4), 462-488.##Jones, R., Woods, S., &amp; Hutchinson, E. (2014). The influence of the Five Factor Model of personality on the perceived effectiveness of executive coaching, International Journal of Evidence Based Coaching and Mentoring, 12 (2), 109-121.##Kennedy, J. (2009). A definition of coaching. From: http://www.kennedy-coaching.com##Ladyskewsky, R. K. (2010). The manager as coach as a driver of organizational development. Leadership and Organization Development Journal, 31(4), 292 -306.##Macnamara, C. (2012). All about personal and professional coaching. Available from: http:// managementhelp.org/leading people/coaching.htm.##Marshall, m. k. (2007).  The Critical aspect of coaching outcomes. PHD Thesis in Leadership and Change Program, Antioch University.##Michelman, M. H. (2005). The emerging role of the internal coach. Consulting Psychology Journal, Practice and Research, 53, 240-250.##Michael, A. (2008). Mentoring and Coaching. The Chartered Institute of Management Accountants, Topic Gateway Series, No. 50.##Moen, F. &amp; Skaalvik, E. (2009). The Effect from Executive Coaching on Performance Psychology, International Journal of Evidence Based Coaching and Mentoring, 7(2), 31-49. ##Noe, R. A. (2010). Employee training and development. New York: McGraw – Hill.##Passmore, J. (2006). Excellence in coaching. Published by Association for coaching.##Peterson, D. B. &amp; Hicks, M. L. (1996). Leader as coach: strategies for coaching and developing others. Minneapolis, MN: Personnel Desiccation International.##Reyes, J.M., Courtney, L., &amp; Holladay, L.  (2016). Evaluating coaching’s effect: competencies, career mobility and retention, Leadership &amp; Organization Development Journal, 37(7).##Rogers, A. (2000). The ingredients of good coaching. Works Management, 53(6), 14-17.##Renard, L. (2005). Executive coaching for professional organizations. PHD thesis, School of Humanities, The American University of London.##Seifert, L. (1994). Perceptions of managerial coaching within selected workplaces, Dissertation Abstracts International.##Silverman, D. C. (2004). Executive coaching. In G.R. Ferris, M.R. Buckley, &amp; D.B. Fedor (Eds.), Human resources management: Perspectives, context, functions, and outcomes (4th ed. 356-364). Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice-Hall.##Stone, F. M. (2007). Coaching, counseling &amp; mentoring: How to choose &amp; use the right technique to boost employee performance. AMACOM; Second Edition.##Spencer, L. (2011). Coaching and training transfer: A phenomenological inquiry in to combined training-coaching programs. International journal of evidence based coaching and mentoring special issue, NO. 5, 1-18.##Swanson, R. A. &amp; Holton, E. F. (2001). Foundations of Human Resource Development, Berrett-Koehler Publishers.##Walker, A. (2011). An HR perspective on executive coaching for organizational learning. . International journal of evidence based coaching and mentoring, 9 (2), 67-79.##Wason, K. D. (2006). Coaching skills for managers &amp; supervisors. Handbook: Akow Consultiy.##Zeus, P. &amp; Skiffington, S. (2003). Establishing a coaching culture, includes extracts from new text book &quot;Behavioral Coaching&quot; published and copyrighted by McGraw Hill, New York, and from:http://www.1to1coachingschool.com/Coaching_Culture_in_the_workplace.htm.##استراوس، آنسلم و کوربین، جولیت (1393). اصول روش تحقیق کیفی، نظریه مبنایی- رویه‌ها و شیوه‌ها، چاپ سوم مترجم: بیوک محمدی، تهران: انتشارات پژوهشگاه علوم انسانی و مطالعات فرهنگی. ##خدامی، عبدالصمد (1392). طراحی و تدوین مدل سازمان مربی‌گرا (مورد مطالعه: صنعت بیمه ایران)، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه پیام نور مرکز.##فتحی واجارگاه، کوروش، خراسانی، اباصلت، دانشمندی، سمیه و آرمان، مانی (1393). بررسی و تبیین مدل مربی‌گری در آموزش منابع انسانی بر اساس نظریه داده‌بنیاد. مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی. سال 12، شماره 3، صص 398-375.## فرزادنیا، فرزانه،  صفایی موحد، سعید و  علی عسگری، مجید (1395). ارائه چارچوبی برای آموزش و توسعه منابع انسانی در پروژه‌های پیچیده ایران.  مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت. سال 7، شماره 28، صص 146- 131.##سعیدی کلوخی، طیبه (1394). وضعیت مربی‌گری در دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد.##سلطانی، منوچهر (1389). مربی‌گری در مدیریت، تهران: انتشارات یادواره کتاب.##کاظمی، عالیه و سعادت احمدنیا، فاطمه (1396). انتخاب گزینه‌های استراتژیک توسعه منابع انسانی با استفاده از روش‌های تصمیم‌گیری چندشاخصه (مورد مطالعه: صنعت نفت). مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 8، شماره 32، صص 50- 25.##کرس ول،جان دبلیو (1392). طرح پژوهش رویکردهای کیفی، کمی و ترکیبی، نوبت دوم، مترجمان: علیرضا کیامنش ومریم دانای طوس، تهران: انتشارات جهاد دانشگاهی واحد علامه طباطبایی.##موغلی، علیرضا، اکبراحمدی، سیدعلی، آذر، عادل و خدامی، عبدالصمد (1391). شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر ایجاد سازمان مربی‌گر. فصلنامه علمی پژوهشی مطالعات مدیریت (بهبود و تحول)، سال 23، شماره 71 ،صص 185- 161. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>ارائه مدل عِلّی عوامل سازمانی مؤثر بر تسهیم دانش؛ مطالعه‌ای در شرکت ملی مناطق نفت‌خیز جنوب</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Developing a causal model for organizational factors effecting on knowledge sharing (Case: The National Iranian South Oil Company)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>وجود رهبران تحول&#8204;آفرین که با ایجاد جوّ مبتنی بر اعتماد و بازآرایی فرهنگ سازمانی در جهت تقویت رفتارهای شهروندیِ سازمانی، منجر به تشویق کارکنان برای به اشتراک&#8204;گذاری دانش شوند، برای سازمان&#8204;ها ارزشمند است. هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی نقش رهبریِ تحول&#8204;آفرین بر تسهیم دانش در میان کارکنان شرکت ملی مناطق نفت&#8204;خیز جنوب با نقش واسطه&#8204;ایِ اعتماد سازمانی و رفتار شهروند سازمانی می&#8204;باشد. روش پژوهش از نوع توصیفی-همبستگی و جامعه آماریِ پژوهش، کارکنان سازمان مورد اشاره به تعداد 1500 نفر و نمونه آماری، 306 نفر از کارکنان بر اساس فرمول کوکران بود. جهت جمع&#8204;آوری اطلاعات از پرسش&#8204;نامه استاندارد استفاده شد. پایایی پرسش&#8204;نامه با استفاده از ضریب آلفای کرونباخ بررسی و تأیید گردید. تجزیه و تحلیل داده&#8204;ها با استفاده از نرم&#8204;افزار SPSS 25 برای آمار استنباطی و LISREL8.8 برای برازش مسیر انجام شد. نتایج حاصل از پژوهش نشان داد که اعتماد سازمانی و رفتار شهروند سازمانی، سهم واسطه&#8204;گری را در روابط رهبریِ تحول&#8204;آفرین و تسهیم دانش ایفا می&#8204;کنند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>&#160;
The existence of transformative leaders who are able to create an atmosphere of trust and rearrange the organizational culture in order to foster organizational citizenship behaviors which in turn can encourage the employees to willingly share knowledge within the organization is valuable in any organization. The purpose of the present study was to investigate the role of transformational leadership in knowledge sharing among the employees of the National Iranian South Oil Company with a mediating role of organizational trust and organizational citizen behavior. The research method was descriptive-correlational. The statistical population of this research was composed of 1500 people who were the staff of the organization. 306 employees were chosen as the statistical sample using the Cochran formula. A standard questionnaire was used to collect the data. The reliability of the questionnaire was checked and verified using Cronbach's alpha coefficient. The data was analyzed using SPSS-25 software for the inferential part and LISREL8.8 software was used to fit the path. The results of the research showed that organizational trust and organizational citizenship behavior played a mediating role in transformational leadership relationships and knowledge sharing.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>61</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>92</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>اردلان</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>فیلی</Family>
				<NameE>Ardalan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Feili</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>موسسه آموزش عالی آپادانا</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عباس</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ثابت</Family>
				<NameE>Abass</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sabet</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>موسسه آموزش عالی آپادانا</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Dr. sabeT@apadana.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>بنفشه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رستگار فر</Family>
				<NameE>Banafsheh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rastegarfar</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سیما</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>علی‌پور</Family>
				<NameE>Sima</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Alipour</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>موسسه آموزش عالی آپادانا</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Transformational Leadership</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational Citizen Behavior</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational Trust</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Knowledge Sharing</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رهبری تحول‌آفرین</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رفتار شهروند سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اعتماد سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تسهیم دانش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Appelbaum, S ., Bartolomucci, N., Beaumier, E ., Boulanger, J ., Corrigan, R ., Dore, I ., Girard, C .,  &amp; Serroni, C. ( 2004). Organizational citizenship behavior: a case study of culture, leadership and trust, management decision, 42(1), pp: 13-40.##Bass, B.M. (1997). Does the transactional-transformational leadership paradigm transcend organizational and national boundaries? American Psychologist, 52(2), pp: 130-139##Bass, B.M. &amp; Avolio,  B.J. (2000). MLQ: Multifactor Leadership Questionnaire, Mind Garden, 29.##Bass, B.M. &amp; Riggio, R.E. (2006). Transformational leadership. Psychology Press.##Baron, R. M. &amp; Kenny, D. A. (1986). The moderator–mediator variable distinction in social psychological research: Conceptual, strategic, and statistical considerations. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, 51(6), pp: 1173–1182.##Behnke, T.M. (2010). knowledge sharing Atwork :An Examination of Organizational Antecedents. Doctoral Dissertation research, Ambrose university.##Boenke, k. B. N., Distefano, J. J., &amp; Distefano, A. C. (2003). Transformational leadership. Leadership and Organizational journal, 1(24), pp: 5-6.##Buil, I., Martínez, E., &amp; Matute, J. (2019). Transformational leadership and employee performance: The role of identification, engagement and proactive personality. International Journal of Hospitality Management, 77, pp: 64-75.##Callaway, P. (2007). The relationship of organizational trust and job satisfaction: An analysis in the US federal work force. Universal-Publishers.##Campbell Pickford, H. &amp; Joy, G. (2016). Organizational Citizenship Behaviours: Definitions and Dimensions. ##Saïd Business School, Egrove Park, Oxford OX1 5NY. www.sbs.oxford.edu/mutuality.  ##Carreiro, H. &amp; Oliveira, T. (2019). Impact of transformational leadership on the diffusion of innovation in firms: Application to mobile cloud computing. Computers in Industry, 107, pp: 104-113.##Chen, X. P. &amp; Fahr, J. L. (2001). Transformational and transactional leader behaviors in Chinese organizations: differential effects in the people's republic of china and Taiwan. In Advances in global leadership (pp. 101-126). Emerald Group Publishing Limited.##Chidambaram, L. &amp; Tung, L. L. (2005). Is out of sight, out of mind? An empirical study of social loafing in technology-supported groups. Information Systems Research, 16 (2),  pp: 149–168.##Cho, J. &amp; Dansereau, F. (2010). Are transformational leaders fair? A multi-level study of transformational leadership, justice perceptions, and organizational citizenship behaviors. The Leadership Quarterly, 21(3), pp: 409-421.##Coun, M. M., Peters, P. C., &amp; Blomme, R. R. (2018). ‘Let’s share!’The mediating role of employees’ self-determination in the relationship between transformational and shared leadership and perceived knowledge sharing among peers. European Management Journal. ##Crawford, C.B. (2005) . Effects of transformational leadership and organizational position on knowledge management. Journal of Knowledge Management, 9(6), pp: 6 – 16.##Dennis, R. &amp; Bruce E. (2003). A Factor Analysis of Pago and Wong Servant Leadership instrument .Leadership &amp; organization Development Journal, 24(8), 455-459.##Desselle, S.P., Raja, L., Andrews, B., &amp; Lui, J. (2018). Perceptions of organizational culture and organizational citizenship by faculty in U.S.colleges and schools of pharmacy. Currents in Pharmacy Teaching and Learning, 10(4), pp: 403-412.##Dulewicz, V. &amp; Higgs, M. (2005). Assessing leadership styles and organizational context.  journal of Managerial Psychology, 20(2), pp: 105-123.##Engelbrecht, A. S. &amp; Schlechter, A. F. (2006). The relationship between transformational leadership, meaning and organisational citizenship behaviour. Management Dynamics: Journal of the Southern African Institute for Management Scientists, 15(4), pp: 2-16.##Gumusluoglu, L. &amp; Ilsev, A. (2009). Transformational leadership, creativity, and organizational innovation. Journal of business research, 62(4), pp: 461-473.##Hoof, B. &amp; Husman, M. (2009). Managing Knowledge Sharing: Emergent and engineering approaches. Information and Management, 46(1), pp: 1-8.  ##Howell, K. E. &amp; Annansingh, F. (2013). Knowledge generation and sharing in UK universities: a tale of two cultures ?. International Journal of Information Management, 33(1), pp: 32-39.##Hung, S. Y., Lai, H. M., &amp; Chang, W. W. (2011). Knowledge sharing motivations affecting R&amp;D employees’ acceptance of electronic knowledge repository. Behavior and Information Technology, 30 (2): 213–230. View at Google Scholar| View at Publisher.##Hung, S. Y., Ku, Y. C., &amp; Chien, J. C. (2012). Understanding physicians’ acceptance of the Medline system for practicing evidence-based medicine: A decomposed TPB model. International journal of medical informatics, 81(2), pp: 130-142.##Jena, L. K., Pradhan, S., &amp; Panigrahy, N. P. (2018). Pursuit of organisational trust: Role of employee engagement, psychological well-being and transformational leadership. Asia Pacific Management Review, 23(3), pp: 227-234.##Jochem, R., Geers, D., &amp; Heinze, P. (2011). Maturity measurement of knowledge-intensive business processes. The TQM Journal, 23(4), pp: 377-387.##Kark, R., Shamir, B., &amp; Chen, G. (2003). The Two Faces of Transformational Leadership: Empowerment and Dependency. Journal of Applied Psychology, 88(2), pp: 246-255. ##Kim, H. (2014). Transformational leadership, organizational clan culture, organizational affective commitment, and organizational citizenship behavior: A case of South Korea's public sector. Public Organization Review, 14(3), pp: 397-417.##King, W.R., Chung, T.R., &amp; Honey, M.N. (2008). Knowledge managementand organizational learning. international journal of management science, OMEGA, 36, pp: 167-172.##Kline,  R.B. (2011). Principies and practice of structural equation modeling. Second Edition, New York: The Guilford Press.##Lämsä, A. M. &amp; Pučėtaitė, R. (2006). Development of organizational trust among employees from a contextual perspective. Business Ethics: A European Review, 15(2), pp: 130-141.		##Lee, K. &amp; Allen, N. J. (2002). Organizational citizenship behavior and workplace deviance: The role of affect and cognitions. Journal of applied psychology, 87(1), 131.##Lin, H. F. &amp; Lee, G.G. (2009). Perceptions of senior managers toward knowledge sharing Behavior. Management Decision,   42 (1),  pp: 108-125.##Lin, C. P. (2008). Clarifying the relationship between organizational citizenship behaviors, gender, and knowledge sharing in workplace organizations in Taiwan. Journal of Business and Psychology, 22(3), pp: 241-250.##Lin, T.C. &amp; Hung, C.C. (2009). Understanding social loafing in Knowledge contribution from the perspective of justice and trust. Expert System with Application, 36(3), pp: 6156- 6163.##López-Domínguez, M., Enache, M., Sallan, J. M., &amp; Simo, P. (2013). Transformational leadership as an antecedent of change-oriented organizational citizenship behavior. Journal of Business Research, 66(10), 2147-2152.##MacKensie, S. B., Podsakoff, P., &amp; Praine, J. B. (1999). Do citizenship behaviors matter more for managers than salespeo-ple. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, 27(4), pp:  396–410.##McDermott, R. &amp; O'Dell, C. (2001). Overcoming culture barriers to sharing Knowledge. Journal of Knowledge Management. 5( 1), pp: 76 – 85.##McKnight, D.H., Choudbury, V., &amp; Kacmar, C. (2002). Developing and validating trust measures for e-commerce: an integrative typology. Information Systems Research, 13(3), pp: 334-361.##Modassir, A. &amp; Singh, T. (2008). Relationship of emotional intelligence with transformational leadership and organizational citizenship behavior. International Journal of Leadership Studies,4(1), pp: 3-21.##Nielsen, T. M., Hrivnak, G. A., &amp; Shaw, M. (2009). Organizational citizenship behavior and performance. the journal of Small Group Research, 40(5), pp: 555-577.##Niranjana, P. &amp; Pattanayak, B. (2005). Influence of learned optimism and organizational ethos on organisational citizenship behaviour: A study on Indian corporations. International Journal of Human Resource Development and Management, 5(1), pp: 85–98.##Organ, D. W. (1988). Organizational citizenship behavior: The good soldier syndrome. Lexington Books/DC Heath and Com.##Organ, D. W., Podsakoff, P. M., &amp; MacKenzie, S. B. (2005). Organizational citizenship behavior: Its nature, antecedents, and consequences. Sage Publications.##Podsakoff, P. M., Mackenzie, S. B., &amp; Bommer, W. H. (1996). Transformational leader behaviors and substitutes for leadership as determinants of employee satisfaction, commitment, trust, and organizational citizenship behaviors. Journal of Management, 22(2), pp: 259-298.##Ristic, K. (2009). The impact of perceived organizational support and trustworthiness on trust. Journal of management Research News, 32(7), pp: 656-669.##Rotsios, K. P., Sklavounos, N. S., &amp; Hajidimitriou, Y. A. (2014). Trust, knowledge transfer and control in IJVs: The case of four Greek firms. Procedia Economics and Finance, 9, pp: 231-241.##Sharkie, R. (2009). Trust in leadership is vital for employee performance. Management research News, 32(5), pp: 491-498.##Spector, P., Borman, W., &amp; Cimino, C. (2004). Emotional intelligence and leadership styles. Department of Psychology College of Arts and Sciences, available at Shannon Webb, pp: 65-79.##Tan, H. H. &amp; Lim, A. K. (2009). Trust in coworkers and trust in organizations. the Journal of Psychology, 143(1), pp: 45-66.##Van den Hooff, B. &amp; De Leeuw Van Weenen, F. (2004). Committed to share: commitment and CMC use as antecedents of knowledge sharing. Knowledge and process management, 11(1), pp: 13-24.##Wang, S. (2010). Knowledge sharing: A review and directions for future research. Human Resource Management Review, (20) 2, pp: 115 – 131.##Wasko, M. M. &amp; Teigland, R. (2004). Public goods or virtual commons? Applying theories of public goods, social dilemmas, and collective action to electronic networks of practice. Journal of Information Technology Theory and Application, 6(1), pp: 25–41.##Yilmaz, K. (2008). The relationship between organizational trust and organizational commitment in Turkish primary schools. Journal of Applied Sciences, 8(12), pp: 2293-2299.##Zhu, W., Newman, A., Miao, Q., &amp; Hooke, A. (2013). Revisiting the mediating role of trust in transformational leadership effects: Do different types of trust make a difference? The Leadership Quarterly, 24(1), pp: 94-105.##الوانی، سید مهدی و لرستانی، احسان (1394). بررسی تأثیر نگرش‌ شغلی بر تسهیم دانش و ارتباط آن با رفتار شهروندی سازمانی در بانک قوامین، فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه و تحول ،شماره20، صص 10-1.‎##الوانی، سید مهدی، عصار، محمدتقی و عابدینی، لیلا (1390). بررسی رابطه اعتماد با تسهیم دانش در معاونت آموزش ناجا و مراکز تابعه، فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت انتظامی، سال 6، شماره 3، صص 400-389.## امامی، مصطفی، جمالی، الهام و اصفهانی، محمد جواد (1392). بررسی رابطه بین اعتماد سازمانی و خلاقیت سازمانی، فصلنامه ابتکار و خلاقیت در علوم انسانی، سال3، شماره3، صص44-23.##بهادری، سیما و دهگان، محمود (1396). اثر رهبری تحول آفرین بر رفتار شهروندی سازمانی تحول محور (مورد مطالعه: سازمان فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات شهرداری تهران)، فصلنامه رسالت مدیریت دولتی، سال8، شماره 26، صص40-29.##پور، سمیرا و مرتضوی، سعید (1392). تبیین عوامل موثر بر نگرش و رفتار مبتنی بر تسهیم دانش(مورد مطالعه: پرستاران بیمارستان 17 شهریور)، فصلنامه مطالعات رفتار سازمانی، سال 2، شماره 3، صص 70-43.##تقوی فرد، محمد تقی، حاجیان، معصومه، پور سیاح، الهام و طحان، مرتضی (1393). نقش اعتماد سازمانی در تسهیم دانش بین کارکنان، فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، سال 3، شماره 10، صص 99-79. ##حسن زاده، رضا و علیزاده، سامان (1396). بررسی رابطه اعتماد سازمانی و مدیریت دانش در بین کارکنان اداری دانشگاه ارومیه، فصلنامه دانش شناسی، سال 10، شماره 36، صص 28-19.##حسین زاده، مهدی و طالع پسند، سیاوش (1395). اثر ساختاری رهبری تحول آفرین بر رفتار شهروندی سازمانی کارکنان کلانتری های غرب و شرق استان تهران: نقش میانجی تعهد سازمانی و رضایت شغلی، فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت انتظامی، سال 10، شماره 2، صص290-276. ## خیر اندیش، مهدی و کاملی، محمد جواد (1390). رهبری تحول آفرین؛ عاملی در موفقیت پروژه های مدیریت دانش، فصلنامه منابع انسانی ناجا، دوره 23، شماره 6، صص185-161.##داستان، نصیر، انصاف داران، فریده، شهبازی، معصومه و رفاهی، ژاله (1395). بررسی عوامل پیش بینی‌کننده در ایجاد اعتماد در روابط مدیران و دبیران دبیرستان‌های دخترانه متوسطه نظری، فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی رهیافتی نو در مدیریت آموزشی، دوره 25، شماره 7، صص 62-47.‎##دانایی فرد، حسن، الوانی، مهدی و آذر، عادل (1387). روش شناسی پژوهش کمی در مدیریت: رویکردی جامع، تهران: صفار اشراقی.##دانایی فرد، حسن، خائف الهی، احمد و حسینی، مجتبی (1390). تأملی بر ارتقاء تسهیم دانش در پرتو رفتار شهروندی سازمانی (مورد مطالعه: وزارت خانه مسکن و شهرسازی و وزارت خانه راه و ترابری)، فصلنامه پژوهش های مدیریت عمومی، سال 4، شماره14، صص 84-63. ##رابینز، استیفن پی (1378). مبانی رفتار سازمانی، ترجمه: علی پارساءیان، محمد اعرابی، تهران: دفتر پژوهش های فرهنگی.##رادمرد، قادر، افخمی اردکانی، مهدی و باران، صمد (1392). بهبود تسهیم دانش سازمان های تحقیق و توسعه نگاهی به نقش فرهنگ، عدالت و اعتماد سازمانی، فصلنامه مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 6، شماره 23، صص 188-163.##رجب پور، ابراهیم (1397). بررسی روابط بین فرهنگ سازمانی، سکوت سازمانی و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی (مورد مطالعه: پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت)، فصلنامه مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 9، شماره 36، صص 211-189.##رجبی فرجاد، حاجیه (1397). بررسی تاثیر رهبری تحول آفرین بر نگرش های شغلی با میانجی گری توانمند سازی روانشناختی، فصلنامه پژوهش های مدیریت عمومی، سال 11، شماره39، صص 180-157. ##رستگار، عباسعلی و مقصودی، طاهره (1395). بررسی تاثیر رهبری تحول آفرین بر نوآوری  سازمانی با میانجی گری تسهیم دانش، فصلنامه علمی- پژوهشی مطالعات مدیریت بهبود و تحول، دوره 25، شماره 80، صص182-157. ##شائمی، علی، خزایی پول، جواد، شعبانی نقت چالی، جواد، بالویی جام خانه، هادی و صالح زاده، رضا (1391). تأثیر تسهیم دانش بر نوآوری و عملکرد شرکت های کوچک و متوسط با رویکرد کارت امتیازی متوازن، فصلنامه علمی- پژوهشی مطالعات مدیریت بهبود و تحول، دوره 22، شماره 69، صص93-59.##شیرازی، علی، خداوردیان، الهام و نعیمی، محمد (1391). تأثیر اعتماد سازمانی بر بروز رفتارهای شهروندی سازمانی (مورد مطالعه: شرکت گاز استان خراسان شمالی)، پژوهش نامه مدیریت تحول، سال 4، شماره 7، صص 154-133.##صیف، محمد حسن، ثابت مهارلویی، عباس، رستگار، احمد، طالبی، سعید (1394). عوامل موثر بر تمایل به تسهیم دانش در بین اعضاء هیئت علمی دانشگاه علوم پزشکی شیراز، مجله ایرانی آموزش در علوم پزشکی، جلد 15، شماره5، صص 50-41.##فعال، آرمین، علی دوست قهفرخی، ابراهیم و جلالی فراهانی، مجید (1395). رابطه اعتماد سازمانی و مؤلفه های آن با بهره وری نیروی انسانی در ادارات ورزش و جوانان استان اردبیل، فصلنامه پژوهش های کاربردی در مدیریت ورزش، سال 5، شماره 3، صص 43-35.##کارگر شورکی، محمد حسین، حاجی محمد علی جهرمی، مقداد، ناظری، علی و رشیدی، محمد مهدی (1395). بررسی اثر ویژگی های شخصیتی بر روی تسهیم دانش و رفتار نوآورانه کارکنان، فصلنامه مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 7، شماره 28، صص 53-29.##مکی زاده، هادی، ابراهیمی، هادی، عباسی، اسد و باغبان، مهدی (1393). بررسی تاثیر سبک رهبری تحول آفرین بر اعتماد سازمانی (مطالعه موردی: سازمان ثبت اسناد و املاک شهر مشهد)، کنفرانس بین المللی علوم انسانی  مطالعات رفتاری.##نوروزی، محمد، صالحیان فرد، رقیه و قربانی فاراب، محمد تقی (1392). شناسایی و رتبه بندی عوامل موثر بر رفتار شهروندی سازمانی در پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت تهران، فصلنامه مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 6، شماره 23، صص98-67. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>ارائه مدل هم‌راستایی استراتژی‌های منابع انسانی با استراتژی‌های کلان سازمانی در شرکت ملی نفت ایران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Developing a Model for theAlignment of Strategies of HRM with Macro-level Strageies in  National Iranian Oil Company</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف مطالعه حاضر، ارائه مدل هم&#8204;راستایی استراتژی&#173; های منابع انسانی با استراتژی&#173; های کلان سازمانی بود. مشارکت&#8204;کنندگان در پژوهش، مدیران و خبرگان منابع انسانی شرکت ملی نفت ایران و شرکت&#8204;های تابعه آن بودند. نمونه مورد نیاز برای مصاحبه کیفی تا حد اشباع نظری و از طریق نمونه&#8204;گیری قضاوتی هدفمند به میزان 14 نفر گردآوری شد. تحلیل داده&#173; ها با نظریه داده&#8204;بنیاد صورت گرفت. از 272 گزاره معنادار حاصل از مصاحبه&#8204;ها، 329 کد استخراج شد که با حذف موارد تکراری، 188 خرده مقوله و 33 مقوله محوری احصاء شد که چهار مقوله مربوط به شرایط علّی، شش مقوله مربوط به شرایط زمینه&#8204;ای، هفت مقوله مربوط به استراتژی&#8204;ها، پنج مقوله مربوط به شرایط مداخله&#8204;گر، پنج مقوله مربوط به پدیده هم&#8204;راستایی و شش مقوله مربوط به پیامدهای هم&#8204;راستایی بود. مشخص شد که هم&#8204;راستایی استراتژی&#8204;های منابع انسانی با استراتژی&#8204;های کلان شرکت ملی نفت ایران در برگیرنده هم&#8204;راستایی استراتژیک از بالا به پایین و از پایین به بالا، هم&#8204;راستایی درونی، هم&#8204;راستایی سازمانی، هم&#8204;راستایی محیطی و هم&#8204;راستایی میان زیرسیستم&#8204;های منابع انسانی شرکت با شرکت&#173; های تابعه است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The purpose of this study was to develop a model of alignment of HR strategies with macro-level strategies. The population of the research were directors and human resources experts of the National Iranian Oil Company and its subsidiaries. The sample needed for qualitative interviews to the extent of theoretical saturation and collected through a targeted judgment sampling of 14 people. Data analysis was done with grounded theory. Among the 272 meaningful statements obtained from the interviews, 329 codes were extracted, eliminating repetitive cases of 188 subcategories and 33 axial categories, including 4 categories of causal conditions, 6 categories of underlying conditions, 7 categories of strategies, 5 categories of intervening conditions, 5 categories of alignment phenomenon, and 6 categories of the alignment outcomes. It was found that the alignment of human resources strategies with the macro strategies of the National Iranian Oil Company included the strategic alignment from top to bottom, from bottom to top, internal alignment, organizational alignment, environmental alignment, and alignment between the company's human resources sub-systems with subsidiaries.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>93</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>126</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد‌علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شاه‌حسینی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammadali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shahhoseini</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>shahhoseini@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حقیقی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Haghighi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mhaghighi@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سارا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مؤذن</Family>
				<NameE>Sara</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Moazen</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>s.moazen@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Human resource management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>HRM strategies</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Macro level strategy</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Strategic alignment</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>استراتژی‌های منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>استراتژی سطح کلان شرکت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>هم‌راستایی استراتژیک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Agnihotri, A.(2013). How much is strategic fit important?Business Strategy Series, 14(4), 99-105. ##Anuar, H. S. B. &amp; Kamruzzaman, M. (2017). improving organizational performance through strategic fit of it-business strategic alignment, International Journal of Economics, Commerce and Management, 5 (12), 123-145. ##Dang, V. T. &amp; Lin, C. S. (2017). Using hierarchical linear modeling to test the effect of overall strategic fit on firm performance in different industry, Chinese Management Studies, 11(4), 637-657. ##Garcia-Carbonell, N., Martin-Alcazar, F., &amp; Sanchez-Gardey, G. (2015). Is double fit a sufficient condition for SHRM success? The missing link between intended and implemented HRM strategy. International Journal of Organizational Analysis, 23(2), 264-284.##Gomes, E., Cohen, M., &amp; Mellahi, K. (2019). When Two African Cultures Collide: A Study of Interactions between Managers in a Strategic Alliance between Two African Organizations, Effective Pople Management in Africa, 12, 180-201. ## Gudergan, S. &amp;Teo, S. (2019), Human Resource Management Challenges in Strategic Alliances, International Journal of Human Resources Development and Management, 19 (2), 123-146. ##Han Loo, L. &amp; See Bech, L. (2013). The Effectiveness of Strategic Human Resource Management Practices on Firm Performance in the Malaysian Insurance Industry. International Journal of Academic Research in Business and Social Sciences. 3(5), 703-714.##Hill, A. &amp; Cuthbertson, R. (2011). Fitness map: a classification of internal strategic fit in service organisations,  Journal of Operations &amp; Production Management, 31(9), 991-1021. ##Hsieh, Y. &amp; Lin, K. H. (2017). The difference in strategic fit between Western and Asian countries-evidence from audit firms of Taiwan, World Review of Entrepreneurship, Managemement, and Sustainable Development, 13(4), 145-163.##Hua,H.Y. &amp; Ming,C.H. (2011). Strategic fit among business competitive strategy, human resource strategy, and reward system, Academy of Strategic Management Journal , 10 (2), 85-110.  ##Jhajharia, P. &amp; Kaur, R. (2015). Achieving Strategic-Fit between Business and Human Resource Strategies, International Journal of Humanities and Social Science Invention, 4(1), 53-61. ##Lee, F. H., Lee, T. Z., &amp; Wu, W. Y. (2010). The relationship between human resource management practices, business strategy and firm performance: evidence from steel industry in Taiwan, The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 21(9), 1351-1372.##Murad, M. M. I. &amp; Asaduzzaman, M. (2014). Human Resource Scorecard: A Road Map to Balanced Scorecard. World Journal of Social Sciences.  4(1), 70-79. ##Mwangi, W. &amp; Kiambati, K. (2015). Integrating Human Resource Management with Organizational Strategies. Global Journal of Management and Business Research: Administration and Management. 15(1), 26-32.##Nkhwangwa, L. C. T. (2014). Achieving strategic fit/integration between business strategies and human resource management (hrm) strategies in the banking sector, International Journal of Social Sciences and Management, 1(4), 143-159. ##Odiyo, W. J. O. (2013). Synergies Created by a Strategic Fit between Business and Human Resource Strategies: An Assessment of Transnational Tea Firms in Kenya, Ph.D Dissertation, Cambridge Business School. ##Pham, L. (2011). Impact of applying human resource management practices on equal sized state-owned enterprises’ financial performance in Vietnam. Journal of International Business Research, 10(2), 79-90.##Tarba, S. Y. &amp; Cooper, S.C.L. (2018). HRM practices in strategic partnerships, International Journal of Human Resource Management, 29 (2), 2305-2309.##Torres, I., Gutierrez, L. J., Montes, F. J. &amp; Lopez, F. J. (2016). Organizational learning and innovation as sources of strategic fit, Industrial Management &amp; Data Systems, 116(8), 1445-1467. ##Wang, D. S. &amp; Shyu, C. L. (2008). Will the strategic fit between business and HRM strategy influence HRM effectiveness and organizational performance?, International Journal of Manpower, 29(2), 92-110.##ابطحی، حسین و ابراهیمی، رضا (1395). طراحی الگوی هم‌راستایی استراتژی‌های منابع انسانی با استراتژی کلان بانک (مورد مطالعه بانک توسعه تعاون)، فصلنامه آموزش و توسعه منابع انسانی، دوره سوم، شماره 8، صص. 75-57. ##اعتمادی، فهیمه، ربیعی، علی و بختیاری، لطفعلی(1391). ارائه چارچوبی در همسویی استراتژیک فناوری اطلاعات با کسب‌و‌کار به روش کارت امتیازی متوازن (مطالعه موردی: مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات شرکت ملی نفت)، سال چهارم، شماره 14، صفحات. 36-9.  ##حسینی، مهرداد و بهفر، فرشید (1394). بررسی میزان همسویی استراتژی‌های منابع انسانی با استراتژی کلان شرکت (مطالعه موردی: شرکت ملی گاز ایران)، فصلنامه مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال ششم، شماره 23، صفحات. 216-189. ##سپهوند، رضا. (1397)، اثر هماهنگی استراتژیک بین استراتژی منابع انسانی، استراتژی سرمایه انسانی و استراتژی رفتار سازمانی بر عملکرد سازمان، رساله دکتری رشته مدیریت بازرگانی گرایش رفتار سازمانی و مدیریت منابع انسانی، دانشکده حسابداری و مدیریت، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی. ##سرعتی آشتیانی، نرجس، باباشاهی، جبار، یزدانی، حمیدرضا و کریمی، تورج(1397). ارائه مدلی برای شکل‌گیری همسویی افقی بین اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی، فصلنامه مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال دهم، شماره 38، صفحات. 38-3.##سلطانی، ایرج و عسگری، آزاده(1397). ارائه الگوی عملیاتی اندازه گیری میزان همسویی استراتژی‌های منابع انسانی با استراتژی‌های کلان سازمان (مطالعه موردی شرکت فولاد مبارکه)، پانزدهمین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت، 27-25 اردیبهشت ماه 1397، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی. ##سیدنقوی، میرعلی، خانباشی، محمد و صلواتی، محسن(1396). همسویی راهبرد عام منابع انسانی با  راهبرد زیرسیستم های منابع انسانی در صنایع غذایی کاله، دو فصلنامه پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی دانشگاه امام حسین، دوره 9، شماره 1، صص. 206-183.##عباسی، عباس، شیرازی، علی نقی و حسینی، فرشته (1396). تدوین استراتژی منابع انسانی در هماهنگی با استراتژی کسب وکار، فرهنگ و ساختار سازمانی، فصلنامه پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی دانشگاه جامع امام حسین، دوره نهم، شماره 2، صفحات. 46-21. ##کوره‌پز محمودآبادی سیرجان، میلاد (1395). هم‌راستایی استراتژیک بین روابط بازاریابی و مدیریت منابع انسانی در سازمان‌های خدماتی مالی، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد رشته مدیریت اجرایی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران.##کیانی مقدم، منصور، قلی پور، رحمت‌الله، جمشیدی، ناصر و بخشی‌زاده، علیرضا(1390). تناسب استراتژیک استراتژی-های سازمان و منابع انسانی، همایش ملی دریانوردی و حمل و نقل دریایی، 12 و 13 بهمن‌ماه 1390، دانشگاه دریانوردی و علوم دریایی چابهار. ##میرزاده، نادر و گایینی، محمد (1397). نقدی بر برخی موانع اجرای سیاست‌های کلی اصل 44 قانون اساسی: مورد کاوی شرکت ملی پالایش و پخش فرآورده‌های نفتی ایران، پژوهشنامه انتقادی متون و برنامه‌های علوم انسانی، سال 18، شماره 5، صص 251-217. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی نقش میانجی‌گری سرمایه اجتماعی در رابطه مدیریت دانش و عملکرد سازمانی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Investigating the Moderator Role of Social Capital in Knowledge Management and Organizational Performance Relationship</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف از پژوهش حاضر بررسی نقش میانجی&#8204;گری سرمایه اجتماعی در رابطه بین مدیریت دانش و عملکرد سازمانی بوده است. این تحقیق از نوع تحقیقات توصیفی &#8211; همبستگی است. جامعه آماری آن را کارکنان شرکت گاز طبیعی آغار و دالان تشکیل داده است . مطابق جدول کرجسی و مورگان تعداد نمونه 100 نفر تعیین شد و پرسش&#8204;نامه&#8204;ها به روش نمونه&#8204;گیری تصادفی ساده بین آنها توزیع گردید. یافته&#173; ها نشان می&#173;دهد که مدیریت دانش بر سرمایه اجتماعی و عملکرد سازمانی به&#8204;ترتیب با 0/633و 0/341، دارای تأثیر مثبت و معنادار می&#173;باشند و در این میان، نقش مؤلفه به&#8204;کارگیری دانش (0/916) و تسهیم دانش (0/868) پُررنگ&#8204;تر است. همچنین تأثیر مثبت و معنادار سرمایه اجتماعی بر عملکرد سازمانی نیز با 0/475 مورد تأیید قرار گرفت. از بین مؤلفه&#173; های سرمایه اجتماعی، مؤلفه روابط (0/902)، شبکه&#173; ها (0/877) و همکاری (0/838) بیشترین نقش را دارا می&#173; باشند. با تأیید نقش میانجیِ سرمایه اجتماعی، مشخص شد که مدیریت دانش دارای اثری غیرمستقیم برابر 0/300بر روی عملکرد سازمانی است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The purpose of this study was to investigate the role of social capital mediation in the relationship between knowledge management and organizational performance. This research is a descriptive-correlational study. The statistical population of this study was the employees of Agharan and Dalan Natural Gas Company. According to Krejcie and Morgan table, 100 people were randomly selected and the research questionnaire has been distributed among them.The findings indicated that knowledge management has a positive and significant effect on social capital and organizational performance, with a coefficient of 0.633 and 0.341, respectively, while the role of the component of knowledge application (0.916) and sharing Knowledge (0.886) is more noticable. Also, the positive and significant effects of social capital on organizational performance were confirmed by a coefficient of 0.447. Among the components of social capital, the component of relationships (0.902), networks (0.877) and cooperation (0.838) have shown the major role. Finally, knowledge management by confirming the mediating role of social capital has shown an indirect, positive and significant effect (0.300) on organizational performance.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>127</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>154</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>پیام</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شجاعی</Family>
				<NameE>Payam</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shojaei</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شیراز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شیراز</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>pshojaei@shirazu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مسلم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>باقری</Family>
				<NameE>Moslem</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Bagheri</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شیراز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شیراز</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>bagherimoslem@shirazu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهرداد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کیانی</Family>
				<NameE></NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE></FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه یزد</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>یزد</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Mehrdad.kiani@stu.yazd.ac</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>زهرا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>محیط قیری</Family>
				<NameE>Zahra</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mohit Ghiri</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شیراز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شیراز</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>zahra.mohit69@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Knowledge Management (KM) - Social Capital (SC) - Organizational Performance - Structural Equations Modeling (SEM)</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت دانش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سرمایه اجتماعی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عملکرد سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aiemmornsiriphong, S., &amp; Piemyat, S. (2012). Social capital: Means of social safety net and social protection in the communities. Journal of procedia Engineering, 32, 1152-1163.##Alavi, M., &amp; Leidner, D. E. (2001). Review: Knowledge management and knowledge management systems: Conceptual foundations and research issues. MIS quarterly, 25 (1), 107-136.##AL-Hakim, L. A. Y., &amp; Hassan, S. (2012). The relationships among knowledge management processes, innovation, and organisational performance in the Iraqi MTS. Knowledge Management International Conference (KMICe).##Allameh, S. M., &amp; Zare, S. M. (2011). Examining the impact of KM enablers on knowledge management processes. Procedia Computer Science, 3, 1211-1223.##Allen, R. S., Dawson, G., Wheatley, K., White, S. (2008). Perceived Diversity and Organizational Performance. Employee relation, 30 (1), 20-33.##Andrews, R. (2010). Organizational social capital, structure and performance, Human Relation, 63 (5), 583-608.##Asoh, D., Belardo, S., &amp; Crnkovic, J. (2007). Assessing knowledge management: Refining and cross validating the knowledge management index using SEM techniques. International Journal of Knowledge Management, 3 (2), 1-30.##Azizpour, M., Abdi, S., &amp; Khoda Bakhshi, N. (2013). Personality traits and human resource productivity at cultural organizations. International Journal of Management Research and Review, 3 (4), 2703-2706.##Bhatt, F. D. (2008). Knowledge management in organizations: Examining the interaction between technologies techniques, and people. Journal of knowledge management, 27, 23-37.##Bosma, N., Van Praag, M., Thurik, R., &amp; De Wit, G. (2004). The value of human and social capital investments for the business performance of startups. Small Business Economics, 23 (3), 227-236.##Chang, M. Y., Hung, Y. C, Yen, DC. D., &amp; Tseng, PT. (2009). The research on the critical success factors of knowledge management and classification, framework project in the Executive Yuan of Taiwan Government. Expert Systems with Applications, 9 (12), 5376-5386.##Chen, J., Zhu, Z., &amp; Yuan Xie, H. (2004). Measuring intellectual capital: a new model and empirical study. Journal of Intellectual capital, 5 (1), 195-212.##Choi, B., &amp; Hee-seok, L. (2003). An Empirical Investigation of KM Styles and their Effect on Corporate Performance. Information and Management, 40, 403-417.##Currie C., Zanotti C., &amp; Morgan A. (2012). Social determinants of health and well-being among young people. Health Behaviour in School-aged Children (HBSC) study: international report from the 2009/2010 survey, Copenhagen, WHO Regional Office for Europe. Health Policy for Children and Adolescents, 6.##Danchev, A. (2006). Social capital and sustainable behavior of the firm. Industrial Management &amp; Data System, 106(7), 953-965.##Danish, R. Q., &amp; Munir, Y. (2012). Impact of Knowledge Management Practices on Organizational Performance; an Evidence from Pakistan. International Journal of Scientific &amp; Engineering Research, 3 (8), 1-8.##Davenport, T. H., De Long, D. W., &amp; Beers, M. C. (1998). Successful knowledge management projects. MIT Sloan Management Review, 39 (2), 43.##Elgar, F. J., Davis, C. G., Wohl, M. J., Trites, S. j., Zelenski, J. M., &amp; Martin, M. S. (2011). Social capital, health and life satisfaction in 50 countries. Journal of Health &amp; Place, 17, 1044-1053.##Ellinger, AE., Musgrove, C. C., Ellinger, A.D., Bachrach, D.G, Baş, AB., &amp; Wang, YL. (2013). Influences of organizational investments in social capital on service employee commitment and performance. Journal of Business Research, 66 (8), 1124-1133.##Fugate, B. S., Stank, T. P., &amp; Mentzer, J. T. (2009). Linking improved knowledge management to operational and organizational performance. Journal of Operations Management, 27 (3), 247-264.##Gold, A. H., Malhotra, A. &amp; Segars, A. H. (2001). Knowledge management: an organizational capabilities perspective, Journal of Management Information Systems, 18 (1), 185-214.##Grant, R. M. (1991). The resource-based theory of competitive advantage: implications for strategy formulation. California management review, 33 (3), 114-135.##Hasanpour, F., Goodarzvand Chegini, M., Rezaee Dizgah, M., &amp; Akhavan Khodashahri, A. (2012). Therelationship between job stress and employee performance of emergency medicine centers (115) in Guilan province. Science Road Publishing Corporation, 1, 43-50.##Hersey, P., Blanchard, K., &amp; Johnson, D. (2008). Management of Organizational Behavior: Leading Human Resource, Prentice Hall.##Hersey, P., &amp; Goldsmith, H. M. (1980). The achieve system: a human-performance problem-solving model, Trends and Issues in OD: Current Theory and Practice, Pfeiffer/jossey-Bass.##Ho, L. A. (2008). What affects organizational performance? Industrial Management &amp; Data System, 108 (9), 1234-1254.##Hoe-Lian, D., Chua, A. Y., Luyt, B., &amp; Sian Lee, C. (2008). Knowledge access, creation and transfer in e-government portals. Online Information Review, 32 (3), 348-369.##Inkpen, A., &amp; Tsang, E. (2005). Social capital, networks, and knowledge transfer. Academy of Management Review, 30, 146–165.##Jabbour, Ch, J., Ch., Jugend, D., Jabbour, A., B., L., de, S., Gunasekaran, A., &amp; Latan, H. (2015) Green product development and performance of Brazilian firms: measuring the role of human and technical aspects. Journal of Cleaner Production, 87, 442-451.##Kheradmand, E., Valilou, M., &amp; Lotfi, A. (2010). The relation between quality of work life and job performance. Middle-East Journal of Scientific Research, 6 (4), 317-323.##King, W. R. (2009). Knowledge management and organizational learning, Springer US.##Lapina, I. (2014). Human resource management models: aspect of knowledge management and corporate social responsibility. Social and Behavioral Sciences, 110, 577-586.##Lazarova, M., &amp; Taylor, S. (2009), Boundaryless careers, social capital, and knowledge management: Implication for organizational performance. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 30 (1), 119-139.##Leana Carrie, R., &amp; Pil Frits, K. (2006). Social Capital and Organizational Performance: Evidence from Urban Public Schools. Organizational Science, 17 (3), 353-366.##Lee, H. J., &amp; Young. G. (2001). A Stage Model of Organizational Knowledge Management: A Latent Content Analysis. Expert Systems with Applications, 20, 299 – 311.##Lee, H., &amp; Choi, B. (2003). Knowledge management enablers, processes, and organizational performance: an integrative view and empirical examination. Journal of Management Information Systems, 20 (1), 179-228.##Lefebvre, V. M., Sorenson, D., Henchion, M., &amp; Gellynck, X. (2016). Social capital and knowledge sharing performance of learning networks. International Journal of Information Management, 36 (4), 570-579.##Lesser, E. L., &amp; Storck, J. (2001). Communities of practice and organizational performance. IBM systems journal, 40 (4), 830-834.##Liao, S., &amp; Wu, C. (2009). The Relationship among Knowledge Management, Organizational Learning, and Organizationa Performance, International Journal of Business and Management, 4(4), 64-76.##Lim, K.K., Ahmed, P.K., &amp; Zairi, M. (1999). Managing for quality through knowledge management. Total Quality Management, 10, 21-615.##Lustri, D. (2007). Knowledge Management model: Practical Application Competency Development. The Learning Organization, 14 (2), 186- 202.##Mardani, A., Nikoosokhan, S., Moradi, M., &amp; Doustar, M. (2018). The Relationship between Knowledge Management and Innovation Performance. The Journal of High Technology Management Research, 29 (1), 12-26.##Mike B., Rory R.-D., Doug F., &amp; Pam S. (2010). Conceptualizing ethical capital in social enterprise. Social Enterprise Journal, 6 (3), 250-264.##Mohamed, S. E. A. (2011). The Impact of social capital on customer Relationship Management Performance in the Egyptian financial sector: The University of Hull. Doctoral Thesis.##Muthuveloo, R., Shanmugam. N., &amp; Ping Teoh, A. (2017). The impact of tacit knowledge management on organizational performance: Evidence from Malaysia. Asia Pacific Management Review, 22 (4), 192-201.##Nahapiet, J., &amp; Ghoshal, S. (1998). Social Capital, Intellectual Capital and the Organizational Advantage. Academy of Management Review. 23 (2), 242-266.##Newman, A. (1999). Knowledge management: American Society for Training and Development.##Nonaka, I. &amp; Takeuchi, H., A (1994). Dynamic Theory of Organizational knowledge creation. Organization Sciences, 1, 14-37.##Noruzy, A., Majazi Dalfard, V., Azhdari, B., Nazari, S., &amp; Rezazadeh, A. (2013). Relations between transformational leadership, organizational learning, knowledge management, organizational innovation, and organizational performance: an empirical investigation of manufacturing firms. International Journal of Advanced Manufacturing Technology, 64 (5), 1073-1085.     ##Ooi, K.B. (2014). TQM: A facilitator to enhance knowledge management? A structural analysis, Expert Systems with Application, 41, 5167-5179.##Prahalad, C., &amp; Hammel, G. (1990). The core competence of the corporation. Harvard Business Review Journal, 68 (3), 79-90.##Putnum, R.D. (2000). Bowling alone, the collapse and revival of American community. New York: Simon Schuster.##Richard, J. P. (2009). Measuring Organizational Performance as a Dependent Variable: Toward Methodological Best Practice. Journal of Management, 35 (3), 718-804.##Riege, A. (2005). Three-Dozen Kknowledge Sharing Barriers Managers Must Consider. Journal of Knowledge Management, 1 (3), 18-35.##Sadeghi, M., Musavi, M., Samiie, S., &amp; Behrooz, A. (2013). Developing human resource productivity through organizational justice. Public Administration and Governance, 3 (2), 173-190.##Sarfarazi, M., Inalo, A. B., &amp; Khalili, M. R. (2012). Investigating Factors of the Performance of the Hormozgan Judiciary Staff influencing Client Satisfaction using the ACHIEVE Model. Journal of American Science, 8 (9), 864-872.##Sullivan J, P, H. &amp; Sullivan S, P, H. (2000). Valuing intangible companies: an intellectual capital approach. Journal of Intellectual capital, 1 (4), 328-340##Suzana, R., &amp; Kasim, R. (2010). The relationship of knowledge management practices, competencies and the organizational performance of government departments in Malaysia. Human and Social Sciences, 5(4), 219- 225.##Tong Ha, S., Lo, M. C., &amp; Wang, Y. C. (2016). Relationship between Knowledge Management and Organizational Performance: A Test on SMEs in Malaysia. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 224, 184-189.##Torabi Shahidi, H., Shabankareh, N., &amp; Momayez, A. (2013). Investigating the impact of performance management on human resource performance across head offices of Agricultural bank branches in Tehran. International Journal of Academic Research in Business and Social Sciences, 3 (8), 177-188##Turban, E., &amp; Maclean, E. (2004). Information Technology for management. 3rd, john wiley &amp; Sons Ine.##Wu, C.M, Ay, C.R. &amp; Lien, B.Y.H. (2009). The role of social capital and organizational learning in promoting innovation performance. Information Systems and Change Management, 4 (2), 171-186.##Yang, H., Phelps, C., &amp; Steensma, H. (2010). Learning from what others have learned from you: The positive effects of technological spillovers on originating firms. Academy of Management Journal, 53 (2), 371-389.##Zack, M., McKeen, J., &amp; Singh, S. (2009). Knowledge Management and Organizational Performance: An Exploratory Analysis. Journal of Knowledge Management, 13 (6), 392-409.##Zaied, A. N. H., Hussein, G. S., &amp; Hassan, M. M. (2012). The role of knowledge management in enhancing organizational performance. International Journal of Information Engineering and Electronic Business, 4 (5), 27.##احمدی بالادهی، سیدمهدی و رنجبرحسینی، عفت‌السادات (1394). سرمایه اجتماعی و رابطه آن با اجرای مدیریت دانش در ناجا، مطالعات مدیریت بر آموزش نظامی، شماره 2، صص 88-67.##بردبار، غلامرضا و زارعی، محبوبه (1392). بررسی تأثیر سرمایه اجتماعی سازمانی بر ارتقاء سطح مدیریت دانش در سازمان بهزیستی استان یزد، جامعه‌شناسی کاربردی، شماره 4، صص 227-224.##حمیدی‌زاده، علی، کوچک‌زاده، زهرا و حاج کریمی، فاطمه (1396). بررسی تأثیر سرمایه اجتماعی بر نوآوری سازمانی با تأکید بر نقش میانجیِ استراتژی‌‌های دوگانه مدیریت دانش، مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی، شماره 1، صص 94- 75.##خامدار، زهرا (1388). بررسی رابطه میان مدیریت آموزش و توسعه منابع انسانی با مدیریت دانش، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد دانشگاه تهران.##رضایی، روح‌الله، صلاحی‌مقدم، نفیسه و شعبانعلی فمی، حسین (1393). بررسی اثر مدیریت دانش بر عملکرد سازمانی در سازمان جهاد کشاورزی استان البرز، پژوهش‌های ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی، شماره 4، صص 91-77.##صفرزاده، حسین، تدین، اعظم و محمدی، مریم (1391). بررسی تأثیر استراتژی‌های مدیریت دانش بر نوآوری و عملکرد سازمانی (مطالعه موردی مراکز بهداشتی و درمانی شمال فارس)، طلوع بهداشت، شماره 1، صص 86-76.##فقیهی، ابوالحسن و فیضی، طاهره (1385). سرمایه اجتماعی: رویکردی نو در سازمان، دانش مدیریت، شماره 72، صص 46-23.##عباس‌پور، عباس و باروتیان، هدی (1389). بررسی رابطه ارتباطات اثربخش و عملکرد سازمانی بر اساس مدل اچیو در واحدهای ستادی شرکت ملی گاز ایران در سال 1388، مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، شماره 10، صص 38-7.##محمودزاده، سید مجتبی و افجه، سید علیاکبر (1390). الگوی اثرگذاری سرمایه اجتماعی بر عملکرد سازمان: شرکت‌های تابع صنعتی ایران خودرو، پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی، شماره 1 (2)، صص 22-1.##همتی، محمد (1385). ارزیابی میزان به‌کارگیری مولفه‌های مدیریت دانش در دانشکده‌های پردیس فنی تهران، ارائه شده در اولین کنفرانس ملی مدیریت دانش، تهران ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>رویکرد نوین استقرار نظام مدیریت دانش مبتنی بر متغیرهای زیرساخت‌ سازمانی در مدیریت منابع انسانی صنعت نفت ایران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>A New Approach to Deploying Knowledge Management System Based on Organizational Infrastructure Variables
in Human Resources Management of Iranian Oil Industry</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>پژوهش حاضر با هدف ساختاردهی مسئله استقرار نظام مدیریت دانش صنعت نفت با استفاده از رویکرد ترکیبی تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی و دیمتل به شناسایی عوامل مؤثر در قالب روابط علّی- معلولی به جهت درک و شناخت برنامه&#173;ریزان از موقعیت مسئله و تجسم ساختارهای ارتباطی پیچیده بین عوامل پرداخته است. بدین منظور ابتدا زیرساخت&#173;های سازمانی موثر بر استقرار نظام مدیریت دانش با استفاده از روش تحلیل عاملی با مشارکت کارکنان معاونت توسعه مدیریت و سرمایه&#173; انسانی وزارت نفت به کمک پرسشنامه و با جامعه آماری 263 نفر و نمونه 158 نفر جمع&#8204;آوری گردید. در گام بعدی میانگین و انحراف معیار داده&#173; ها و آزمون&#173; های لاوشه، کولموگروف- اسمیرنوف و شاپیرو-ویلکاکسون بررسی و مبتنی بر یافته &#173;های تحلیل عاملی سه عامل اصلی شامل فرهنگ سازمانی، منابع انسانی و ساختار سازمانی و 14 زیرساخت سازمانی شناسایی شد. سپس با استفاده از تکنیک دیمتل و با مشارکت تصمیم &#173;گیران درگیر مسئله نقشه اثر- ارتباط ترسیم و نمودار علّی- معلولی زیرساخت&#173; های سازمانی مؤثر بر استقرار نظام مدیریت دانش صنعت نفت استخراج گردید.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Purpose of this research was to structure the problem of establishing a knowledge management system in Oil industry using a combination of factor analysis and DEMATEL approach to identifying the effective factors in the form of causal relationships to understand planners from the problem position and visualization of structures a complex relationship between factors. Firstly, the organizational infrastructure affecting the establishment of the knowledge management system using exploratory factor analysis with participation of the Deputy Directorate for Development and Human Capital Management through a questionnaire with a statistical population of 263 people and a sample of 158 were gathered. Based on findings, three main factors including culture, human resources and organizational structure and 13 infrastructures influencing were identified. Then, with the participation of the decision makers using the DEMATEL technique, the map of the effect of the relationship between the effective organizational infrastructure and the causal relationship diagram was extracted.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>155</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>178</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>رضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>معینی جزنی</Family>
				<NameE>Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Moeini Jazaniz</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Moeini1354@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>احمدرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کسرایی</Family>
				<NameE>Ahmad Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Kasraee</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Kasrai49@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>طهمورث</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سهرابی</Family>
				<NameE>Tahmoures</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sohrabi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Dr.tsohrabi@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>احمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>اصلی زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Ahmad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Aslizadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد یادگار امام خمینی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Aslizadeha@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Implementation of knowledge management system</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational infrastructure</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Problem Structuring Method</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>DEMATEL</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>استقرار نظام مدیریت دانش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زیرساخت‌ سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رویکرد ساختاردهی مسئله</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تکنیک دیمتل.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Anderson, D. (2014). A social relationship conceptualization of trust and accountability in organization, Humanresource management review, Vol. 14, No. 1 pp 47-65.##Azar, A., Sa’adati, M., &amp; Nasiri, S.H. (2016). The key factors in the success of knowledge management system in the organizational health of the employees working in the public universities of Tehran, Management Issues in Healthcare System 2(2016) 34-42 ##Bassam, A. &amp; Alksasbeh, Z. (2018). Factors that influence the success of knowledge management implementation in Jordanian higher education institutions research. Journal of Applied Sciences, Engineering and technology 15(7):249-260 • July 2018##Chung, B. Y. (2017). An Analysis of Success and Failure Factors for ERP Systems in Engineering and Construction Firms. (Doctoral Dissertation) University of Maryland, College Park. Maryland, USA.##Davenport, T. (2010). Mission Critical, Harvard Business School Press, Boston, MA.##Dennis R.S. (2015). Development of servant leadership assessment instrument. leadership&amp; organization development journal Vol, 26. No5 pp.150-163.##Du, L. (2017). Acquiring competitive advantage in industry through supply chain integration: a case study of Yue Yuen Industrial Holdings Ltd. Information Management, Vol. 20, PP: 65##Ferrets, T.W., Ahire. S., &amp; De. P. (2016). Achieving success in large projects: implications from a study of ERP implementations. Interfaces, Vol.36, No.5, PP: 458–469##Finney, S. &amp; Corbett, M. (2017). ERP implementation: a compilation and analysis of critical success factors. Bus Process Management Journal, Vol.13, No.3, PP: 329–347.##Forrester, J.W. (2013). Industrial Dynamics, MIT Press, Cambridge, MA.##Ganeshan, R. &amp; Harrison, T.P. (2015). An Introduction to Supply Chain Management: Department of Management Sciences and Information systems, 303 Beam Business Building, Penn State University, University park, PA.##Gargeya, V. B. &amp; Brady, C. (2015). Success and Failure Factor of Adopting SAP in ERP System Implementation. Business Process Management Journal, Vol. 11, No. 5, PP: 501-516.##Kozjek, D. &amp; Ovsenik, M. (2017). Model of Knowledge Management Factors and their Impact on the Organizations’ Success . Organizacija, Volume 50 , Number 2, PP:134-146##Lambert, D.M. (2015). An evaluation of process-oriented supply chain management frameworks. Journal of Business Logistics, Vol. 26, No. 1, PP: 25–51. ##McAdam, R. &amp; McCreedy, S.(1999). A critical review of knowledge management models, The Learning Organization, Vol.6, No.3, PP: 91-100##Osterm, M. (2016). Servant leadership and work related outcomes, Journal of Business &amp; Industrial Marketing, 31(2). 219–231 (http://dx.doi.org/10.1108/JBIM-03-2014-0046)##Smith, B. M. N. &amp; Kuzinenko, T. N. (2014). Transformation and servant leadership content and contextual comporisons. Journal of leadership and organizational. Vol. 10, No, 4. PP: 80-91.##Spears, L. (1996). Reflections on Robert K. Greenleaf and servant- leadership. Leadership and Organization Development Journal, vol. 17, No. 7, PP.33-35. (https://doi.org/10.1108/01437739610148367)##Sterman, J. (2015). Modeling Managerial Behavior: Misperception of Feedback in a dynamic decision Making Environment. Management Science, Vol. 35 No. 3, pp: 321-339.##Sutton, C.D. &amp; Field, H. S. (2016). Individual differences in servant leadership the roles of values and personality, leadership &amp; organizational development journal Vol. 1 No.3, pp:700-716.	##Van Hoek, R.I. &amp; Christopher, H. (2011). Measuring agile capabilities in the supply chain. International Journal of Production Management, Vol. 21, No.1/2, pp: 126–147.##Waddell, Y. T., Ngo, H. U., &amp; Wong, C.H. (2016). Organizational justice, trust, and OCB A study of chinise workers in joint state – owned enterprises. Journal of World Business 41 pp 344-355.##Whang, S.J. (2017). The bullwhip effect in supply chains. Sloan Management Review, Vol. 38 No. 3, pp. 93-102.##Wiig, K. M. (1997). Knowledge Management: An introduction  and perspective.  journal of Knowledge Management, Vol.1, No.1, 6-14##Winston, B. (2015). A correlation of servant leadership leader trust and organization trust. leadership&amp; organization development journal, Vol 26. No, 1. Pp, 6-22.##Zhang, Q., Vonderembs, M.V., &amp; Lim, F.S. (2016). Spanning flexibility: supply chain information dissemination drives strategy development and customer satisfaction. Supply Chain##آذر، عادل، خسروانی، فرزانه و جلالی، رضا (1395). تحقیق در عملیات نرم رویکردهای ساختاردهی مسئله، چاپ دوم، تهران: انتشارات سازمان مدیریت صنعتی. ##احمدی، علی اکبر و صالحی، علی (1391). مدیریت دانش، چاپ اول تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه پیام نور.##استرمن، جان (1392). پویایی‌شناسی کسب و کار: تفکر سیستمی و مدل‌سازی برای جهانی پیچیده، ترجمه : کوروش برارپور مرضیه امامی، پریسا موسوی اهرنجانی، بنفشه بهزاد، حسن فغانی و لاله رضایی عدل. تهران: سازمان مطالعه و تدوین کتب علوم انسانی دانشگاه‌ها(سمت) ##ابراهیمی، بابک (1394). ضرورت به‌کارگیری ERP به‌منظور اشتراک اطلاعات در زنجیره تامین یک مطالعه موردی، تهران: دومین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات.##حیدری‌قره‌بلاغ، هادی (1394). الگوی پیاده‌سازی مدیریت زنجیره تامین در شرکت‌های کوچک و متوسط، فصلنامه تخصصی پارک‌ها و مراکز رشد، شماره 17، صص 50-43.##حاتمی، رضا. صفائی، بهزاد. غلامی، سعید.(1394). بررسی مدل‌های مدیریت دانش و ارائه مدل مفهومی مدیریت دانش به عنوان مزیت رقابتی با استفاده از رویکرد پویایی سیستم.دومین کنفرانس بین المللی مدیریت، اقتصاد و علوم انسانی. دوبی.##حیدری، سید محمد. خنیفر، حسین (1392). بررسی عوامل حیاتی موفقیت در پیاده‌سازی مدیریت دانش، فصلنامه علمی ـ پژوهشی مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی، دوره11، شماره 1، صص  184-149.##درّی، محسن و مصلّی، سمانه (1394). نقش ابزارهای ERP در اطلاعات مشترک زنجیره تامین، هماهنگی و بهینه‌سازی هزینه، اولین کنفرانس سیستم‌های برنامه‌ریزی منابع سازمان.##رازینی، روح الله و سینا، میلاد (1397). ارائه دسته‌بندی جامع از عوامل کلیدی از مدیریت دانش سازمانی، مدیریت راهبردی دانش سازمانی، شماره 1، صص 168-133. ##رحیمی‌قاضی‌کلایه، امیر، امیر‌افشاری، مهدی و رمضانی، علی (1392). شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی عوامل کلیدی زیرساخت به‌منظور استقرار نظام مدیریت دانش در سازمان‌های پروژه محور، مطالعات کمّی در مدیریت، شماره  4(1)، صص 60-41. ##رکنی‌جو، محمد، جعفری، محمدباقر، یزدانی، حمیدرضا و الوانی، مهدی (1396). واکاوی موانع پیاده‌سازی موفق مدیریت دانش در دانشگاه‌ها، نشریه مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی، شماره 15(2)، صص  464-445.##سالاری، نسیبه، پورسراجیان، داریوش، اولیا، محمدصالح و شکوهی، شهرام (1390). تعیین و اولویت‌بندی عوامل موثر بر موفقیت مدیریت دانش در پارک‌های علم و فناوری، نشریه رشد فناوری، دوره  7، شماره  27، صص 9-3. ##شفیعی‌نیک‌آبادی، محسن و فارسیجانی، حسن (1391). چارچوبی برای فرآیندهای مدیریت دانش در زنجیره تامین، پژوهشنامه پردازش و مدیریت اطلاعات، شماره 73، صص 642-611.##شکاری، محمدرضا، اسماعیلی‌گیوی، محمدرضا و کشاورز، حمید (1395). بررسی زیرساخت‌های مدیریت دانش و تاثیر آن بر هوش سازمانی در پژوهشگاه‌های وابسته به وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری، پژوهشنامه پردازش و مدیریت اطلاعات، شماره 31(4)، صص  1097-1075.##صالحی طالشی، محمد جواد، حسینعلی‌پور، مجتبی، اربابی، هانی (1396). شناسایی و سنجش زیرساخت های مدیریت دانش پروژه ها در سازمان های پروژه محور صنایع بالادستی نفت و گاز ایران. مدیریت و منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت،  شماره32(8)، صص 203-112##صلواتی، عادل و حق‌نظر، فرشته (1388). بررسی تحلیل عوامل زمینه‌ای موثر بر استقرار سیستم مدیریت دانش در واحدهای ستادی شرکت ملی نفت ایران، فراسوی مدیریت، شماره 3(10)، صص 104-77.##عمیدی، معصومه، هاشم‌زاده، غلامرضا و علیزاده، علی‌اکبر (1398). الگوی مدیریت دانش صنعت نفت با لحاظ دو بعد انسانی و فناوری بر اساس رویکرد نظریه داده بنیاد، فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 10، شماره 39، صص  124-98. ##غضنفری، مهدی  و فتح‌الله، مهدی (1390). نگرشی جامع بر مدیریت زنجیره  تامین، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران. ##فرهادی، محمد، رشیدی، محمدمهدی و اصیلی، غلامرضا (1391) چالش‌های جدید ارزیابی عملکرد و ارائه الگوی موثر در سازمان‌های تحقیقاتی،کنفرانس ملی مدیریت عملکرد.##قلیپور، آرین، پورعزت، علی‌اصغر و حضرتی، محمود (1388). بررسی تاثیر رهبری خدمت گزار بر اعتماد سازمانی و توانمندسازی در سازمان‌های دولتی ، نشریه مدیریت دولتی ، شماره 2، صص 118-103##کاظمی، مصطفی،  فیلی، اردلان، دشتی‌پور، محسن و دانشمند، هادی (1397). شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی عوامل موثر بر تسهیم دانش با رویکرد تصمیم‌گیری چند شاخصه، فصلنامه مدیریت سلامت، شماره 21(71)، صص 22-7. ##گودرزوند چگینی، مهرداد و فرحبد، بجاری (1392). بررسی عوامل موثر بر قابلیت مدیریت دانش در شرکت‌های تولیدی استان گیلان، نشریه فرآیند مدیریت توسعه، دوره 26، شماره 3، پیاپی 85، صص160-133##نجف‌بیگی، رضا،  صرافی‌زاده، اصغر و لاری، مسعود (1390). طراحی الگوی زیرساختی مورد نیاز به منظور پیاده‌سازی مدیریت دانش در سازمان، پژوهشنامه مدیریت تحول، شماره 3 (5)، صص  180-148. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>مدل‌سازی تفسیری – ساختاری برون‌سپاری منابع انسانی در شرکت پتروشیمی مارون</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Interpretative-Structural Modeling of Outsourcing Human Resources in Maroon Petrochemical Company</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف تحقیق مدل&#8204;سازی عوامل مؤثر در برون&#8204;سپاری منابع انسانی در شرکت پتروشیمی مارون بود. تحقیق از لحاظ هدف، کاربردی، از لحاظ نحوه گردآوری داده&#173; ها، توصیفی &#8211; اکتشافی و از نوع آمیخته بود. جامعه آماری تحقیق کارشناسان و خبرگان شرکت پتروشیمی مارون در حوزه منابع انسانی بودند که تعداد این افراد 15 نفر گزارش شد. تجزیه و تحلیل داده&#8204;ها با استفاده از مدل&#8204;سازی تفسیری ساختاری انجام گرفت. نتایج نشان داد که متغیرهای افزایش انعطاف&#8204;پذیری، کاهش هزینه&#173; های درون&#173; سازمانی و بهبود خلاقیت، دارای نقش مستقل در مدل بوده و بر متغیرهای میانجی و وابسته مدل تأثیر معناداری دارند. متغیرهای وابسته مدل عبارت بودند از: کاهش سرمایه&#173; گذاری تکنولوژی&#8204;، کسب وجهه مناسب و افزایش امنیت که علاوه&#8204;بر متغیرهای مستقل ذکرشده، تحت تأثیر متغیرهای میانجی (شامل عوامل ارتقای کیفیت محصولات، افزایش تغییر&#173;پذیری در نیازها، افزایش تغییرات در فناوری و استفاده از فناوری جدید، تمرکز بیشتر بر فعالیت&#173; های محوری، دستیابی به توانمندی&#8204;های جدید، بهبود عملکرد عملیاتی، استفاده از خدمات آموزشی، دستیابی به تجربه&#8204;های جدید، ارائه خدمات جدید، بهبود مدیریت، مدیریت ریسک و چابک&#8204;سازی سازمان) نیز قرار گرفتند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The research purpose was to identifying a model of factors affecting human resource outsourcing (HRO) in Maroon Petrochemical Company. The research is considered practical in terms of purpose and descriptive-exploratory based on mixed method, in terms of data collection. The statistical population was experts and experts of Maroon petrochemical company in the field of human resources. The number of these people was reported 15. For data analysis, interpretive-structural modeling was used. The results showed that the variables of increasing flexibility, decreasing organizational costs and improving creativity have an independent role in the model and on the intermediary and dependent variables of the model have a significant effect. The dependent variables of the model were: decrease of technology investment, gaining the good image and increasing security, in addition to the independent variables mentioned, influenced by the intermediary variables including factors product quality development, increasing the change need, increasing technological changes and the use of new technology, focusing more on core activities, achieving new capabilities, improving operational performance, using educational services, acquiring new experiences, providing new services, improving management, risk management and Agility organization.&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>179</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>210</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید نجم‌الدین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>موسوی</Family>
				<NameE>Seyed Najmeddin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mousavi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه لرستان، خرم آباد</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>لرستان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mousavi.na@lu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>راضیه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>فعلی</Family>
				<NameE>Razieh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Feli</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه لرستان، خرم آباد</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>لرستان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Feli.ra@fc.lu.ac.ir- raziehfeli@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Human resources outsourcing</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>outsourcing drivers</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>interpretive- Structural modeling</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Maroon Petrochemical Company.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>برون‌سپاری منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>محرک‌های برون‌سپاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل‌سازی تفسیری – ساختاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پتروشیمی مارون.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abdul‐Halim, H., Che‐Ha, N., Geare, A., &amp; Ramayah, T. (2016). The pursuit of HR outsourcing in an emerging economy: The effects of HRM strategy on HR labour costs. Canadian Journal of Administrative Sciences/Revue Canadienne des Sciences de l'Administration, 33(2), 153-168.##Agwu, E. &amp; Ohaegbu, A.V. (2015). Strategic management of the benefits and challenges of HR Outsourcing in Effective Organizational Management. Journal of Business Studies Quarterly, 7(2), 85-108.##Alanazi, A. A.(2016), Organizational learning as a Mediator of the Relationship between HR Outsourcing and Organizational Performance. International Journal of Business and Technopreneurship, 6(3), 473-482.##Bagińska, I. (2018). Business management using HR outsourcing. World Scientific News, 104, 68-77.##Basadur,M., Gelade, G., &amp; Basadur, T.(2013). Creative Problem-Solving Process Styles, Cognitive Work…Demands, and Organizational Adaptability, the Journal of Applied Behavioral Science, 50(1), 80-115.##Berber, N. &amp; Slavić, A. (2016). Human resource (HR) outsourcing in European compensation management in the light of CRANET research. Acta Polytechnica Hungarica, 13(3), 207-225.##Beregszaszi, J. &amp; Polay, D. H. (2012). Human Resource Outsourcing in Times of Economic Turbulence-a Contemporary Review of Practice. International Journal of Human Resource Studies, 2(1), 46.##Hindle, J. (2005). HR outsourcing in operation: critical success factors. Human Resource Management International Digest, 13(3), 39-42.##Irwin, K. C., Landay, K. M., Aaron, J. R., McDowell, W. C., Marino, L. D., &amp; Geho, P. R. (2018). Entrepreneurial orientation (EO) and human resources outsourcing (HRO): A “HERO” combination for SME performance. Journal of Business Research, 90, 134-140.##Kamaleddine, K. &amp; Soubjaki, M. (2018), The Impact of HR Functions Outsourcing (Recruitment, Training and Organizational Development) On HR Management Effectiveness in Private Sector. IOSR Journal of Business and Management, 20(5), 78-79.##Koch, J., Dell, D. J., &amp; Johnson, L. K. (2004). HR outsourcing in government organizations: Emerging trends. In Early Lessons'', the Conference Board, New York, 1-40. ##Mahmud, K., Billah, M. M., &amp; Chowdhury, S. M. R. (2012). Human resource outsourcing: a study on telecommunication sector in Bangladesh. International Journal of Business and Management, 7(10), 74-84.##Nyarangi, E. (2017). Assessment of perceptions of human resource outsourcing on organizational performance in selected multinationals in Nairobi. Journal of Human Resource and Leadership, 1(4), 52-71.##Ohaegbu, A.V. &amp; Agwu, E. (2015). Strategic management of the benefits and challenges of HR outsourcing in effective organizational management. Journal of Business Studies Quarterly, 7(2), 85-105.##Okeke-Ezeanyanwu, J. A. (2017). Impact of Outsourcing on Organizational Productivity in Private and Public Sector Organizations in Anambra State. African Journal of Education, Science and Technology, 3(4), 112-116.##Parry, G. &amp; Roehrich, J. (2009). Towards the strategic outsourcing of core competencies in the automotive industry: threat or opportunity? 9(1), 40-53.##Patel, C., Budhwar, P., Witzemann, A., &amp; Katou, A. (2017). HR outsourcing: The impact on HR's strategic role and remaining in-house HR function. Journal of Business Research, 103, 397-406.##Siew-Chen, S. &amp; Seow-Voon,Y. (2016). Exploring Human Resource Outsourcing Trends in Malaysia. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 224, 491-498.##Woodall, J., Scott-Jackson, W., Newham, T., &amp; Gurney, M. (2009). Making the decision to outsource human resources. Personnel Review, 38(3), 236-252.##اعوانی، علیرضا، شهاب، محمدرضا و دانایی، ابوالفضل (1396). شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی عوامل تأثیرگذار بر چابکی سازمان بر پایه برون‌سپاری (مورد مطالعه: شرکت گاز استان سمنان)، فصلنامه علمی – پژوهشی مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، (34)9، 144-115.##آرمان، مانی، حسینی، سید یعقوب و تنگستانی، الهام (1395). تأثیر سرمایه اجتماعی و بلوغ منابع انسانی بر مدیریت منابع انسانی پایدار (مورد مطالعه: شرکت‌های فعال در صنعت پتروشیمی)، مدیریت سرمایه اجتماعی، (1)3، 138-113.##تقی‌زاده، هوشنگ و صادقی باروجی، زین‌العابدین (1390). ارزیابی وضعیت مدیریت برون‌سپاری مطالعه موردی: شرکت پالایش نفت تبریز، دو ماهنامه علمی – پژوهشی دانشگاه شاهد، (50)18، 206-191.##تورانی، سوگند، ملکی، محمدرضا، قدوسی مقدم، سارا و گوهری، محمدرضا (1388). مقایسه کارایی و اثربخشی داروخانه مرکز آموزشی درمانی فیروزگر پیش و پس از برون‌سپاری، مدیریت سلامت، (38)12، 70-59.##سایت روابط عمومی شرکت ملی صنایع پتروشیمی (1395)، http://www.nipna.ir.##نرگسیان، عباس، پورعزت، علی اصغر، و رسولی پرشکوه، آزاده (1396). مطالعه مزایا و معایب برون‌سپاری فرایند جذب منابع انسانی در شرکت ارتباطات سیار ایران، فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مدیریت سازمان‌های دولتی، (2)5، 90-79. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>کشف ابعاد جوّ عاطفی سازمان در شرکت ملی پخش فرآورده‌های نفتی ایران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Discovering the Dimensions of Emotional Climate of Organization 
in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>این تحقیق با هدف کشف ابعاد جوّ عاطفی سازمان در شرکت ملی پخش فرآورده&#8204;های نفتی ایران انجام پذیرفت. جامعه آماری تحقیق دربرگیرنده کلیه کارکنان این شرکت در منطقه خراسان رضوی است که 19 نفر از آنان با استفاده از نمونه&#8204;گیری هدفمند تا رسیدن به اشباع نظری و کفایت نمونه&#8204;گیری، مورد مصاحبه قرار گرفتند. جمع&#8204;آوری داده&#8204;ها از طریق مصاحبه&#8204;های عمیق نیمه&#8204;ساختاریافته انجام شد و تحلیل آنها با استفاده از تحلیل محتوای کیفی قراردادی صورت گرفت. یافته&#8204;های تحقیق نشان داد که ابعاد جوّ عاطفی سازمان را می&#8204;توان در قالب هشت بُعد اصلی شامل جوّ امید سازمانی، جوّ اعتماد سازمانی، جوّ ترس سازمانی، جوّ خشم سازمانی، جوّ عشق سازمانی، جوّ تعجب سازمانی، جوّ شادی سازمانی، و جوّ امنیت سازمانی دسته&#8204;بندی نمود. درک این ابعاد زمینه مدیریت جوّ عاطفی سازمان در راستای اهداف سازمانی را فراهم می&#8204;سازد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>This study aimed to explore the dimensions of emotional climate of organization in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company (NIOPDC). The statistical population consisted of all employees of NIOPDC in Khorasan Razavi District, and the sample was selected using purposeful sampling method up to the theoretical saturation with the sampling adequacy of 19 people. Data were collected through semi - structured interviews, and the analysis was done by qualitative content analysis. The findings showed that the dimensions of emotional climate of organization can be grouped into eight main dimensions including organizational hope climate, organizational trust climate, organizational fear climate, organizational anger climate, organizational love climate, organizational surprise climate, organizational happiness climate, and organizational security climate. Understanding these dimensions provides the basis for managing the emotional climate of organization in line with organizational goals.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>211</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>240</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدحسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>دهنوی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Hossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Dehnavi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>فردوسی مشهد</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mh.dehnavi@yahoo.com.</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شیرازی</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shirazi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>فردوسی مشهد</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>a-shirazi@um.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>شمس الدین شمس الدین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ناظمی</Family>
				<NameE>Shamsoddin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Nazemi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>فردوسی مشهد</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>nazemi_shm@um.ac.ir.</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>Fariborz</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>Rahimnia</Family>
				<NameE>Fariborz</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rahimnia</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>فردوسی مشهد</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>r-nia@um.ac.ir.</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational climate</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>emotional climate of organization</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>qualitative content analysis</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>emotions.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>جوّ سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>جوّ عاطفی سازمان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تحلیل محتوای کیفی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عواطف.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ashkanasy, N. M. &amp; Humphrey, R. H. (2011). Current emotion research in organizational behavior: Emotion Review, 3(2), 214-224.##Ashkanasy, N. M. &amp; Nicholson, G. J. (2003). Climate of fear in organizational settings: Construct definition, measurement and a test of theory. Australian Journal of Psychology, 55(1), 24-29.##Ashkanasy, N. M., Wilderom, C. P., &amp; Peterson, M. F. (2000). Handbook of organizational culture and climate. Thousand Oaks: SAGE Publications, Inc.##Ashton-James, C. E. &amp; Ashkanasy, N. M. (2008). Affective events theory: a strategic perspective in Emotions, Ethics and Decision-Making, 1(34). Emerald Group Publishing Limited.##Barsade, S., Brief, A. P., Spataro, S. E., &amp; Greenberg, J. (2003). The affective revolution in organizational behavior: The emergence of a paradigm. Organizational behavior: A management challenge, 1, 3-50.##De Rivera, J. (1992). Emotional climate: Social structure and emotional dynamics. John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Elo, S., Kääriäinen, M., Kanste, O., Pölkki, T., Utriainen, K., &amp; Kyngäs, H. (2014). Qualitative content analysis: A focus on trustworthiness. SAGE open, 4(1), 1-10.##Espinoza, J. A. (2012). Influence of the Emotional Climate on the Affective Organizational Commitment. Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú: http://repositorio.pucp.edu.pe/index/handle/123456789/ 166800.##Ferris, R. (1988). How organizational love can improve leadership. Organizational Dynamics, 16(4), 41-51.##Fisher, C. D. (2010). Happiness at work. International journal of management reviews, 12(4), 384-412.##Gibson, D. E. &amp; Callister, R. R. (2010). Anger in organizations: Review and integration. Journal of management, 36(1), 66-93.##Gibson, D. E., Schweitzer, M. E., Callister, R. R., &amp; Gray, B. (2009). The influence of anger expressions on outcomes in organizations. Negotiation and Conflict Management Research, 2(3), 236-262.##Gould, R. V. (2000). Revenge as sanction and solidarity display: An analysis of vendettas in nineteenth-century Corsica. American Sociological Review, 682-704.##Hartel, C., Ashkanasy, N. M., &amp; Zerbe, W. (Eds.). (2005). Emotions in organizational behavior: Psychology Press.##Härtel, C. E., Gough, H., &amp; Härtel, G. F. (2008). Work-group emotional climate, emotion management skills, and service attitudes and performance. Asia Pacific Journal of Human Resources, 46(1), 21-37.##Liu, X. Y., Härtel, C. E., &amp; Sun, J. J. M. (2014). The workgroup emotional climate scale: Theoretical development, empirical validation, and relationship with workgroup effectiveness. Group &amp; Organization Management, 39(6), 626-663.##Härtel, C. E. &amp; Liu, X. Y. (2012). How emotional climate in teams affects workplace effectiveness in individualistic and collectivistic contexts. Journal of Management &amp; Organization, 18(4), 573-585.##Hochschild, A. (1983). The Managed Heart. Berkeley: University of California Press. ##Izard, C. E. (1990). The Substrates and Functions of Emotion Feelings William James and Current Emotion Theory. Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin, 16(4), 626-635.##Kahn, R. L., &amp; Cannell, C. F. (1957). The dynamics of interviewing; theory, technique, and cases. Industrial and Labor Relations Review, 12(4), 662.##Kanyangara, P., Rimé, B., Philippot, P., &amp; Yzerbyt, V. (2007). Collective rituals, emotional climate and intergroup perception: Participation in “Gacaca” tribunals and assimilation of the Rwandan genocide. Journal of Social Issues, 63(2), 387-403.##Kelly, J. R. &amp; Barsade, S. G. (2001). Mood and emotions in small groups and work teams. Organizational behavior and human decision processes, 86(1), 99-130.##Kipfelsberger, P., Herhausen, D., &amp; Bruch, H. (2016). How and when customer feedback influences organizational health. Journal of Managerial Psychology, 31(2), 624-640.##Ludema, J. D., Wilmot, T. B., &amp; Srivastva, S. (1997). Organizational hope: Reaffirming the constructive task of social and organizational inquiry. Human Relations, 50(8), 1015-1052.##Liu, X. Y., Härtel, C. E., &amp; Sun, J. J. M. (2014). The workgroup emotional climate scale: Theoretical development, empirical validation, and relationship with workgroup effectiveness. Group &amp; Organization Management, 39(6), 626-663.##Louis, M. R. (1980). Surprise and sense making: What newcomers experience in entering unfamiliar organizational settings. Administrative science quarterly, 226-251.##Mark, S., Philip, L., &amp; Adrian, T. (2009). Research methods for business students. England: Pearson Education Limited.##Mayer, R. C., Davis, J. H., &amp; Schoorman, F. D. (1995). An integrative model of organizational trust. Academy of management review, 20(3), 709-734.##Meirovich, G. (2012). Creating a favorable emotional climate in the classroom. The International Journal of Management Education, 10(3), 169-177.##Páez, D., Ruiz, J. I., Gailly, O., Kornblit, A., Wiesenfeld, E., &amp; Vidal, C. M. (1996). Trauma político y clima emocional: una investigación transcultural. Psicología Política, 12, 47-69.##Phillips, L. D. (2015). Empowerment and coworker response to leader tactic and organizational hope. Emerging Leadership Journeys, 8(1), 22-45.##Pirola-Merlo, A., Härtel, C., Mann, L., &amp; Hirst, G. (2002). How leaders influence the impact of affective events on team climate and performance in R&amp;D teams. The leadership quarterly, 13(5), 561-581.##Pirson, M. &amp; Malhotra, D. (2011). Foundations of organizational trust: What matters to different stakeholders?. Organization Science, 22(4), 1087-1104.##Rafaeli, A. &amp; Sutton, R. I. (1987). Expression of emotion as part of the work role. Academy of management review, 12(1), 23-37.##Rafaeli, A. &amp; Sutton, R. I. (1989). The expression of emotion in organizational life. Research in organizational behavior, 11(1), 1-42.##Ruiz, J. I. (2007). Emotional climate in organizations: applications in Latin American Prisons. Journal of Social Issues, 63(2), 289-306##Shaery-Eisenlohr, R. (2007). Imagining Shi ‘ite Iran: Transnationalism and Religious Authenticity in the Muslim World. Iranian Studies, 40(1), 17-35.##Silverman, D. (2005, September). Instances or sequences? Improving the state of the art of qualitative research. In Forum Qualitative Sozialforschung/Forum: Qualitative Social Research, 6(3). 1-16.##Smith, E. R., Seger, C. R., &amp; Mackie, D. M. (2007). Can emotions be truly group level? Evidence regarding four conceptual criteria. Journal of personality and social psychology, 93(3), 431.##Spiess, J. K. A. (2011). The Effect of Emotional Climates in Leader-Follower and Employee-Customer Relationships in a Service Context , Doctoral dissertation, Dissertation no. 3936, University of St. Gallen- PP 1-154.##Stempel, G. H. &amp; Westley, B. H. (1989). Research methods in mass communication. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall.##Sutton, R. I. &amp; Rafaeli, A. (1988). Untangling the relationship between displayed emotions and organizational sales: The case of convenience stores. Academy of Management journal, 31(3), 461-487.##Tran, V. (2010). The role of emotional climates of joy and fear in team creativity and innovation. Working Papers CEB, 10.##Weiss, H. M. &amp; Cropanzano, R. (1996). Affective events theory: A theoretical discussion of the structure, causes and consequences of affective experiences at work. Research in Organizational Behavior, 18,1-74..##Yurtsever, G. &amp; De Rivera, J. (2010). Measuring the emotional climate of an organization. Perceptual and motor skills, 110(2), 501-516.##باردن، لورانس (1374). تحلیل محتوا، مترجمان: محمد یمنی‌دوزی سرخابی، ملیحه آشتیانی، تهران: مرکز چاپ و انتشارات دانشگاه شهید بهشتی.  ##تبریزی، منصوره (1393). تحلیل محتوای کیفی از منظر رویکردهای قیاسی و استقرایی. فصلنامه علوم اجتماعی. شماره 64، صص 138-107.##حافظ نیا، محمدرضا (1387). مقدمه‌ای بر روش تحقیق در علوم انسانی، چاپ چهاردهم. تهران: سمت.##رنجبر، هادی، حق‌دوست، علی‌اکبر، صلصالی، مهوش، خوش‌دل، علیرضا، سلیمانی، محمدعلی و بهرامی، نسیم(1391). مجله علمی پژوهشی دانشگاه علوم پزشکی ارتش جمهوری اسلامی ایران، سال دهم، شماره سوم، صص 250-238. ##گل افشانی، ناهید، و مظفری، زینب (1385). روایی و پایایی در پژوهش کیفی. نشریه مدیریت فردا. سال 4. شماره 13و14. صص 43-33. ##نوشادی، ایمان (1390). تحلیل محتوای کیفی. پژوهش، سال 3، شماره 2، صص 44-15. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>مدلسازی انتظارات و اولویتهای منابع انسانی شرکت ملی نفت ایران به روش چهار ماتریسی (QFD )</TitleF>
		<TitleE>QFD Modeling of Expectations and Priorities of National Oil Company Human Resources (Four Matrix)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>&#160; هدف اصلی این پژوهش ارائه مدلی برای انتظارات و اولویت &#173;های منابع انسانی شرکت ملی نفت ایران به روش گسترش عملکرد کیفیت (QFD) در جهت مهندسی کیفیت نظام رفاهی و روش پژوهش به صورت ترکیبی (کیفی و کمی) بود. در ابتدا به روش دلفی و مصاحبه با خبرگان (15نفر) شاخص&#8204;های رفاهی استخراج و در ادامه این شاخص&#8204;ها با نیازهای نیروی انسانی (208 نفر) به صورت پرسشنامه، مورد تطابق قرار گرفت. در تحقیق حاضر، نمونه آماری در بخش کیفی، خبرگان&#160; بخش رفاهی شرکت نفت بودند که در انتخاب آنان، مسائلی چون زمان، در دسترس بودن مصاحبه&#8204;شوندگان و میزان همکاری آن&#8204;ها مورد توجه بود که بر طبق استانداردهای پژوهش &#173;های کیفی حد کفایت و اشباع آن&#8204;ها 15نفر به دست آمد. پس از تهیه پرسشنامه نهایی از شاخص&#173; های خبرگان در بخش کمّی تعداد پرسشنامه &#173;ها از طریق فرمول کوکران به دست آمد. تایید پایایی با استفاده از آلفای کرونباخ با مقدار بیش از 0.7 و آزمون روایی از طریق بررسی بارهای عاملی و نمرات AVE انجام شد. برای اطمینان در ماتریس خانه کیفیت (HOQ)، نیازهای فنی ایجاد شد و برای ساختن ماتریس خانه کیفیت برنامه &#173;های کیفیت خدمات رفاهی مورد پردازش قرار گرفت. در مدل نهایی مشخص گردید که قابلیت استفاده از خدمات اینترنتی (جی پی اس، صفحات مجازی، محتوای آنلاین، اطلاع&#8204;رسانی آنلاین و... ) یکی از انتظارات کلیدی منابع انسانی است که بر دیگر انتظارات اثرگذار است. همچنین مولفه&#8204;های 18گانه با توجه به نوع رابطه در دسته&#8204;بندی مربوطه خود دارای تاثیر مثبت یا منفی (قوی و متوسط) بر انتظارات منابع انسانی هستند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>&#160;The main purpose of this study was to provide a model for the expectations and priorities of human resources in National Iranian Oil Company by QFD for quality engineering of welfare system. The research method was qualitative and quantitative. At first, welfare indices were extracted from Delphi method and interviews with experts (n = 15) and then these indices were matched with the needs of human resources (n = 208) as a questionnaire. In the present study, the statistical sample in the qualitative section were the experts of the Oil Company's welfare department whose issues, such as time, availability of the interviewees, and the extent of their cooperation were considered. 15 people. After preparing the final questionnaire of expert indices in the quantitative part the number of questionnaires was obtained by Cochran formula. Reliability was confirmed using Cronbach's alpha of greater than 0.7 and validity test was performed by examining factor loadings and AVE scores. To ensure the quality of the home matrix (HOQ), technical requirements were created and the welfare service quality plans were processed to build the quality home matrix. In the final model it was found that the usability of internet services (GPS, virtual pages, online content, online information, etc.) is one of the key human resource expectations that influences other expectations. Also, the 18 components, depending on the type of relationship in their respective categories, have a positive or negative (strong and medium) impact on human resource expectations., have a positive or negative (strong and medium) impact on human resource expectations.&#160;The main purpose of this study was to provide a model for the expectations and priorities of human resources in National Iranian Oil Company by QFD for quality engineering of welfare system. The research method was qualitative and quantitative. At first, welfare indices were extracted from Delphi method and interviews with experts (n = 15) and then these indices were matched with the needs of human resources (n = 208) as a questionnaire. In the present study, the statistical sample in the qualitative section were the experts of the Oil Company's welfare department whose issues, such as time, availability of the interviewees, and the extent of their cooperation were considered. 15 people. After preparing the final questionnaire of expert indices in the quantitative part the number of questionnaires was obtained by Cochran formula. Reliability was confirmed using Cronbach's alpha of greater than 0.7 and validity test was performed by examining factor loadings and AVE scores. To ensure the quality of the home matrix (HOQ), technical requirements were created and the welfare service quality plans were processed to build the quality home matrix. In the final model it was found that the usability of internet services (GPS, virtual pages, online content, online information, etc.) is one of the key human resource expectations that influences other expectations. Also, the 18 components, depending on the type of relationship in their respective categories, have a positive or negative (strong and medium) impact on human resource expectations., have a positive or negative (strong and medium) impact on human resource expectations.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>241</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>262</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کلانتر</Family>
				<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Kalantar</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>kalantar_hossein@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>زین العابدین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>امینی</Family>
				<NameE>Zainul Abedin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Amini</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد ساوه</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Drsajadamini@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>احسان</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ساده</Family>
				<NameE>Ehsan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد ساوه</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>E.sadeh@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Expectations and Priorities</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Human Resources</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>NIOC</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Quality Performance Improvement</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>QFD</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>انتظارات و اولویت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شرکت ملی نفت ایران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>گسترش عملکرد کیفیت.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abualoush, S. H., Obeidat, A. M., Tarhini, A., Masadeh, R., &amp; Al-Badi, A. (2018). The role of employees ‘empowerment as an intermediary variable between knowledge management and information systems on employees performance. VINE Journal of Information and Knowledge Management Systems, 48(2), 217-237.##Akao, Y. (2004). Quality Function Deployment: Integrating Customer requirements into Product Design. New York, NY: Productivity Press, Inc.##Akao, Y. &amp; Mizuno, S. (1994). QFD: The Customer-Driven Approach to Quality Planning &amp; Deployment. Tokyo: Asian Productivity Organization##Anil, A., &amp; Satish, P. (2016). Investigating the relationship between TQM practices and firms performance: A conceptual framework for Indian organizations. Procedia-Technology, 24, 554-561.##Booz, A. &amp; Hamilton, R. (1982). New Products Management for the 1980s. Hill Pub. New York.##Büyükozkan, G. &amp; Berkol, C. (2017). Designing a sustainable supply chain using an integrated analytic network process and goal programming approach in quality function deployment. Expert Systems with Applications,38, 13731-13748.##Hauser, J. R. &amp; Clausing, D. (1988). The house of quality.’ Harvard Business Review, pp. 63-73.##Hulland, J. (1999). Use of partial least squares (PLS) in strategic management research: A review of four recent studies. Strategic Management Journal, 20(2), 195-204.##Jia, G. &amp; Bai, M. (2011). An approach for manufacturing strategy development based on fuzzy. Computers &amp; Industrial Engineering, 60, 445-454.##Leba, M., Ionica, A., &amp; Edelhauser, E. (2013). QFD– Method for eLearning systems evaluation. Procedia -Social and Behavioral Sciences, 83, 357 – 361.##Matzler, K. (2004). The asymmetric relationship between attribute-level performance and overall customer satisfaction: a reconsideration of the importance-performance analysis. Industrial Marketing Management, 33(4), 271–277.##Mehrjerdi, Y.Z. (2010). Applications and extensions of quality function deployment. Assembly Automation, 30(4), 388–403.##Paryani, K., Masoudi, A., &amp; Cudney, E. A. (2010). QFD application in the hospitality industry: A hotel case study’ Quality Management Journal, 17 (1).132-146.##Ramanathan, R. &amp; Jiang, Y. (2009). Incorporating cost and environmental factors in quality function deployment using data envelopment analysis. Omega International Journal of Management Science, 37(3),711–723##Shil, N. &amp; Das, B. (2008). A Study of Customer Satisfaction with Regard to Banking: An Application of QFD. The Icfaian Journal of Management Research, 6(8), 7-26.##Tan, K.C. &amp; Shen, X. X. (2000). Integrating Kano’s model in the planning matrix of quality function deployment. Total Quality Management, 11(8).66-97.##Tontini, G. &amp; Silveira, A. (2005). Identification of critical attributes of success in products and services: an alternative to importance–performance analysis. BALAS Annual Conference. Madrid##Tsoukatos, E. &amp; Rand G. K. (2007). Cultural influences on service quality and customer satisfaction: Evidence from Greek Insurance. Managing Service Quality, 17,467-485.##Wang, H. &amp; Wang, J. (2014). Combining fuzzy AHP and fuzzy Kano to optimize product varieties for smart cameras: A zero-one integer programming perspective. Applied Soft Computing, 22, 410-416.##Warwick, M.G. (2007). Quality Function Deployment’ Section 6, Product excellence using six sigma. NY, USA.##Yeşilada, A. &amp; Yurdakul, D. (2009). Improving Healthcare Service Quality: An Application of Integrating Servqual and Kano Model in to Quality Function Deployment. International Journal of Business Research, 9(7), 156-165.##Zarei, M., Fakhrzad, M., &amp; Jamali Paghaleh, M. (2011). Food supply chain leanness using a developed QFD model. Journal of Food Engineering, 102(1): 25- 33.##دانایی، ابوالفضل و همتی، فاطمه (1397). مدل‌سازی ریاضی انتخاب پیمانکاران در پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت، مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال ۱۰، شماره 38، صص 235-213.##زنجیرچی، سیدمحمود و ترابی‌فارسیجانی، زهرا (1387). رویکرد QFD در بهبود کیفیت خدمات بانکی، ماهنامه تدبیر، سال 19، شماره 193، صص  176-145.##فرمهینی فراهانی، احمد، مضطرزاده، فتح الله و بهرامی، محسن (1398). شناسایی و تحلیل عوامل موثر بر توانمندسازی پژوهشگران برای توسعه آینده؛ مورد مطالعه: یکی از مراکز پژوهشی صنعت نفت،  مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 10، شماره 39، صص28-1. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>آسیب شناسی فرآیندهای منابع انسانی با استفاده از مدل بلوغ قابلیت کارکنان در شرکت نفت خزر</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Pathology of Human Resources Processes Using the People Capability Maturity Model (PCMM) in Khazar Oil Company</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>پایش مستمر فرآیندهای منابع انسانی از مهمترین وظایف مدیران منابع انسانی به شمار می&#8204;رود که کاربرد زیادی در برنامه&#8204;ریزی مناسب برای این حوزه در سازمان ها دارد. در همین راستا، آسیب&#173;شناسی وضعیت موجود فرآیندهای منابع انسانی با استفاده از الگوی بلوغ قابلیت کارکنان در شرکت نفت خزر به عنوان یکی از شرکت های عملیاتی حوزه نفت و گاز ایران، هدف این مطالعه قرار گرفت. تحقیق حاضر ازنظر هدف، کاربردی و از نظر روش جمع آوری داده ها، توصیفی از نوع پیمایشی مقطعی به شمار می رود. جامعه آماری این تحقیق را مدیران و کارشناسان رسمی شرکت نفت خزر مشتمل بر 97 نفرتشکیل داده است. ابزار اصلی گردآوری اطلاعات، پرسشنامه ای مشتمل بر 45 سوال بود که روایی آن توسط اساتید حوزه منابع انسانی و تعدادی از متخصصان مدیریت منابع انسانی صنعت نفت تایید شد و پایایی آن با استفاده از ضریب آلفای کرونباخ با مقدار 0/96تأیید گردید. حجم نمونه با استفاده از فرمول کوکران 78 نفر برآرود گردیده و پرسشنامه تحقیق بین این افراد به صورت تصادفی توزیع گردید. اطلاعات بدست آمده با استفاده از آزمون کولموگروف اسمیرنوف ، آزمون تی و آزمون ANOVA با کمک نرم&#8204;افزار &#160;SPSS 23 مورد تحلیل قرار گرفت. یافته&#173; های تحقیق حاکی از آن بود که شرکت نفت خزر از نظر بلوغ فرآیندهای منابع انسانی در سطح دوم این مدل قرار دارد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Continuous monitoring of human resources processes is one of the most important tasks of HR managers, which is widely used in HR planning in organizations. In this regard, investigating the current status of human resources processes using the people capability maturity model in Khazar Oil Company, as one of the operating companies in the field of oil and gas of Iran, has been considered as the goal of this research. This study is consumes an applied research in terms of its purpose and descriptive-survey in terms of data collection method. The statistical population of this study consisted of 97 managers and official experts of Khazar Oil Company. The main tool of data collection was a questionnaire consisting of 45 questions that its validity was confirmed by human resource professors and some human resource management experts and its reliability was confirmed by Cronbach's alpha coefficient of 0.96. The sample size was 78 persons based on Cochran formula. The research questionnaire was distributed among them randomly. The data were analyzed by descriptive and inferential methods (Kolmogorov-Smirnov &#38; T-test &#38; ANOVA) using SPSS 23 software. The findings of the study indicated that Khazar Oil Company is at the level 2 of this model in terms of maturity of human resources processes.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>263</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>288</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سیامک</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>برادران</Family>
				<NameE>Siamak</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Baradaran</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد دماوند</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>dr_baradaran@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>معصومه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حبیبی</Family>
				<NameE>Masoomeh Masoomeh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Habibi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>موسسه مطالعات بین المللی انرژی، وزارت نفت</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>masoomehabibi@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>People Capability Maturity Model (PCMM)</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Human Resources</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Pathology</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Khazar Oil Company.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>الگوی بلوغ قابلیت‌ کارکنان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آسیب‌شناسی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شرکت نفت خزر.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Armstrong, M. (2009). Armstrong's handbook of human resource management practices (Eleventh edition, Philadelphia: Kogan Page Limited.##Bititci, U. S., Garengo, P., Ates, A., &amp; Nudurupati, S. (2015). Value of maturity models in performance measurement.  International Journal of Production Research, Vol.53, Issue 10, 3062-3085. (https://doi.org/10.1080/00207543.2014.970709)##Chen , Y. &amp; Wang, Y. (2016). Application and development of the people capability maturity model level of an organization. Total Quality Management &amp; Business Excellence , Volume 29, 2018 - Issue 3-4, 329-345. (https://doi.org/10.1080/14783363.2016.1184568)##Curtis, B., Hefley, W.E., &amp; Miller, S. (2007). The People Capability Maturity Model: Guidelines for Improving the Workforce. Delhi, India: Dorling Kinlersleg.##Curtis, B., Hefley, W.E., &amp; Miller, S. (2009). People Capability Maturity Model (P-CMM). Version 2.0, Second Edition. Software Engineering Institute.##Dingquan, Y., Lu, M., &amp; Xiwei, X. (2012). Study on the Maturity of People Capability in Innovative Enterprises. Journal on Innovation and Sustainability. Vol 3, No. 1, 53-60.  (DOI: https://doi.org/10.24212/2179-3565.2012v3i1p53-60)##Dutta, K., Baruah, N., &amp; Baruah, J.B. (2018). A Rigorous Study of P-CMM in Indian IT Industry. International Journal of Engineering Research and Development, Vol. 14, Issue 1, 44-50.##Harrison, M.I., (2005). Diagnosing Organizations: Methods, Model, and Process. Applied Social Research Methods Series, v 8.3 rd. Edition, California: SAGE publication.##Tripathi, Padma. (2014). Application of People Capability Maturity Model in I.T Industry. Adhyayan: A Journal of Management Sciences. Vol.4, No. 1, 10-20. (DOI: https://doi.org/10.21567/adhyayan.v4i1.10201)##Turetken, O. &amp; Demirors, O. (2004). People Capability Maturity Model &amp; Human Resource Management Systems: Do they benefit each other? Human Systems Management. Vol. 23, 179-190##افتخاری، غلامحسین (1393). بررسی سطح بلوغ سرمایه انسانی شرکت ملی پخش فرآورده‌های نفتی غرب استان مازندران (منطقه چالوس) با استفاده از مدل P-CMM . پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی.##افخمی، احمد (1391) . ارزیابی نظام مدیریت منابع انسانی شرکت نفت آغاجاری با استفاده از مدل بلوغ قابلیت افرادPCMM  . پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، پردیس آموزش های نیمه حضوری، به راهنمایی میرعلی سیدنقوی. ##بخشی، جواد، نایبی، محمدامین و موسی خانی، مرتضی (1388). ارزیابی مدیریت منابع انسانی از طریق الگوی بلوغ قابلیت ها (P-CMM) در سازمان های کوچک و متوسط. فصلنامه آینده پژوهشی مدیریت، دوره 20، شماره 1 (پیاپی 80)، صص 89-75.##  بریجن، زیبا و مهرعلیزاده، یدالله (1394). آسیب شناسی منابع انسانی با بهره گیری از الگوی بلوغ قابلیت کارکنان در شرکت ملی نفت مناطق نفت خیز جنوب همراه با ارائه راهکارها، دومین همایش بین المللی مدیریت و فرهنگ توسعه، 1394.##بیگی نیا، عبدالرضا و جنیدی جعفری ، مهدی (1388). آسیب شناسی منابع انسانی با هدف بهبود و توسعه ( مورد مطالعه: بانک ملت). پنجمین کنفرانس بین المللی توسعه منابع انسانی، تهران.##دانایی‌فرد، حسن، الوانی، سید مهدی و آذر، عادل (1395). روش‌شناسی پژوهش کمی در مدیریت: رویکردی جامع ( چاپ یازدهم). تهران: انتشارات اشراقی.##دهقانیان، حامد؛ پورتیموری، زهرا؛ عیوضلو، منصوره (1392). ارائه روشی پویا جهت ارزیابی قابلیت‌های سازمان. دومین اجلاس مدیران تحقیق، توسعه و فناوری، تهران.##رحیمی، حمید (1390). آسیب شناسی سازمانی دانشگاههای منتخب دولتی شهر اصفهان و ارتباط آن با سلامت سازمانی و کیفیت محیط کار. پایان نامه دکتری رشته مدیریت آموزشی، دانشگاه اصفهان، چاپ نشده.##رشیدی، محمد مهدی، ابیلی، خدایار و نریمانی، مهدی (1392). کاربرد مدل بلوغ مدیریت برای آسیب‌شناسی وضع موجود سرمایه انسانی برتر در صنعت نفت. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 4، شماره 16، صص 108-85##رشیدی، محمدمهدی و برادران، سیامک (1394). مدیریت استعدادها، مفاهیم، چالش‌ها و راهکارها. تهران: هزاره سوم اندیشه.##سلطانی، ایرج و بهرامی نژاد جونقانی (1389). تأثیر بلوغ سازمانی بر سرآمدی سازمان در شرکت فولاد مبارکه، فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت ( بهبود و تحول)، دوره 17، ش 62، صص 193-163.##شکاری، غلامعباس، شیبانی‌فر، محمدشهاب (1392). سطح بلوغ شرکت گاز خراسان رضوی در فرآیند مدیریت عملکرد براساس مدل بلوغ قابلیت های کارکنان (P-CMM). چشم انداز مدیریت دولتی، شماره13، ص 157-129##طیرانی دربندی، بهرام (1393). پایش بلوغ منابع انسانی از طریق مدل بالندگی توانمندی افراد (p-cmm) ) در بانک انصار، پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد ، دانشگاه سیستان و بلوچستان ، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری.##فرازی انارکی، سمیه (1392). بررسی و ارزیابی سطح بلوغ مدیریت سرمایه انسانی در شرکتهای بخش خصوص اصفهان. پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت ، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شاهرود.##قریشیان، زهره سادات (1394). سنجش سطح بلوغ قابلیتهای منابع انسانی بانک سپه شعب شهر مشهد با استفاده از مدل بلوغ قابلیتهای منابع انسانی (P-CMM). پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت تحول، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شاهرود.##قلی پور، آرین (1395). مدیریت منابع انسانی: مفاهیم، تئوری ها و کاربردها. تهران: انتشارات سمت.##کرتیس، بیل، هفلی، ویلیام و میلر، سالی (1389). الگوی تکامل توانایی نیروی انسانی (P-CMM). ترجمه: محمد عشقی و مارینا فرهودی زاده. تهران: انتشارات سرآمد.##نجفی زاده ، محمدمحسن  ؛ زاهدی ، سیدمحمد (1395). آسیب شناسی نظام مدیریت عملکرد کارکنان در دانشگاه علوم‌ پزشکی قزوین با استفاده از مدل سه‌ شاخگی. فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه و تحول، شماره 25، صص 69-59 ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>عوامل موثر بر پذیرش آموزش الکترونیکی در کارکنان شرکت خطوط لوله و مخابرات نفت اصفهان</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Factors influencing the Acceptance of E-learning among the Employees of Isfahan Oil Pipelines Company</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف این تحقیق تعیین تأثیر عوامل سازمانی ادراک شده(حمایت مدیریتی و حمایت سازمانی)، وابستگی وظیفه&#8204;ای و خودکارآمدی کامپیوتری بر قصد پذیرش آموزش الکترونیکی با نقش میانجی هنجار فردی در شرکت خطوط لوله و مخابرات نفت اصفهان بود. این پژوهش، از نوع توصیفی-همبستگی بود. جامعه مطالعه کارمندان شرکت خطوط لوله و مخابرات نفت استان اصفهان را شامل می&#8204;گردید که تعداد آنها 250 نفر بود. تعداد 165 نفر به&#8204;عنوان نمونه و به روش نمونه&#8204;گیری در دسترس تعیین شد و پرسش&#8204;نامه بومی&#8204;سازی شده توزیع شد. در نهایت، &#160;تعداد150 پرسش&#8204;نامه جمع&#8204;آوری گردید. پس از تأیید روایی و پایایی، از نرم&#8204;افزار SPSS &#160;وSmartPLS &#160;برای تحلیل آماری استفاده گردید. یافته&#8204;ها نشان داد که عوامل سازمانی ادراک&#8204;شده و وابستگی وظیفه&#173;ای بر قصد پذیرش آموزش الکترونیکی با نقش میانجی هنجار فردی در شرکت خطوط لوله و مخابرات نفت اصفهان تأثیر دارد ولی نقش واسطه&#8204;ایِ هنجار فردی در مورد رابطه دو متغیر خودکارآمدی کامپیوتری و قصد پذیرش آموزش الکترونیکی تأیید نشد. 
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>This research aimed to determine the relationship between perceived organizational support (management support and organizational support), task interdependente and computer self-efficacy with behavioral intention to adopt e-learning system with the mediating role of individual norms in Isfahan Oil and Gas Pipeline Company. The research population was consisted of 250 employees and after the adoption and adaptation of the questionnaire, and using non-random sampling, 165 questionnaires were distributed and 150 usable questionnaires were returned. After the confirmation of validity and reliability, the data were analyzed by SPSS and SmartPLS. The results illustrated that the mediating role of individual norms in the relationship between organizational factors and task interdepenete with acceptance intention were supported while its mediation role between computer-self efficacy and acceptance intention was not statistically supported.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>289</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>314</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مریم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بداخانیان</Family>
				<NameE>Marym</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Badakhnian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی،، واحد اصفهان،خوراسگان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>m.badakhanian@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حمیدرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>پیکری</Family>
				<NameE>Hamid Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Peikari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد اصفهان،خوراسگان</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>omid726@yahoo.com.</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Training</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Task interdepenete</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational support</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Self-efficacy</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Isfahan Oil and Gas Pipeline Company</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آموزش الکترونیک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>وابستگی وظیفه‌ای</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>حمایت سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>خودکارآمدی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شرکت خطوط لوله و مخابرات نفت اصفهان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ajzen, I. &amp; Fishbein, M. (1975). Understanding Attitudes and Predicting Social Behavior, Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice-Hall.##Anjum, A. &amp; Naqvi, G. (2012). Impact of perceived supervisor support on organizational citizenship behavior: Mediating role of trust. The Asian conference on Psychology &amp; the behavioral, Osaka, Japan, 249- 261.##Arshadi, N. (2011). The relationships of perceived organizational support (POS) with organizational commitment, in-role performance, and turnover intention: Mediating role of felt obligation. Journal of Procedia- social and behavioral sciences, 30, 1103- 1108.##Arshadi, N. &amp; Hayavi, G. (2013). The effective of perceived organizational support on effective commitment and job performance: mediating role of OBSE. Journal of Procedia- social and behavioral sciences, 84, 739- 743.##Bandura, A. (1986). Social foundations of thought and action: A social cognitivetheory. Prentice-Hall: New Jersey.##Compeau, D.R. &amp; Higgins, C.A (1995). Computer self-efficacy: development of a measure and initial test, MIS Quarterly, 19 (2), 189–211.##Davis, F.D., Bagozzi, R.P., &amp; Warshaw, P.R. (1989). User acceptance of computer technology: a comparison of two theoretical models. Management science, 35 (8), 982-1003.##DeRouin, R.E., Fritzsche, B.A., &amp; Salas, E. (2005). E-learning in organizations, Journal of Management, 31 (6), 920–940.##Fishbein, M, Ajzen, I. (1975). Belief, Attitude, Intention, and Behavior: An Introduction to Theory and Research, Addison-Wesley, Reading &amp; M.A.##Goodhue, D. &amp; Thompson, R.  (1995). Task-Technology Fit and Individual Performance . Management Information Systems Quarterly, 19(2), 213-236. ##Grabe, M. &amp; Grabe, C. (2008). Integrating technology for meaningful learning. 5th ed. Boston: Houghton Mifflin Company.##Igbaria, M. T., Guimaraes, G.B., &amp; Davis, M. (1995). Testing the determinants of micro Computer usage via a structural equation model, Journal of Management Information Systems 11 (4), 87–114.##Jumaadzan, N. &amp; Zaleha Fasiha, F. (2011). E-learning encouragement factors andacademic performance. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 18, 307-315.##Keengwe, J. &amp; Anyanwu, L. (2007). Computer technology-infused learning enhancement Journal of Science Education and Technology, 16(5), 387-393.##Kim, B.G., Park, S.C., &amp; Lee, K.J. (2007). A structural equation modeling of the Internet acceptance in Korea, Electronic Commerce Research and Applications, 6, 425–432.##Kleintop, W.(1993).The Acceptance of New Information Technologies by End Users (Electronic Mail), Ph.D. Thesis, Temple University.##Kong, H. J., Gatling, A., Kim, J., &amp; Harrah, W. (2014). The impact of supervisory support on organizational commitment, career satisfaction, and turnover intention for hospitality frontline employees. Journal of Human resources in hospitality &amp; tourism, 14 (1), 68-89.##Lee, B. C., Yoon, J. O., &amp; Lee, I. (2009). Learners’ Acceptance of Elearningin South Korea: Theories and Results. Computers &amp; Education, 53, 1320–1329.##Lee, S. &amp; Kim, B.G. (2009). Factors affecting the usage of intranet: a confirmatory study, Computers in Human Behavior, 25 (1), 191–201.##Lin, F.H. &amp; Wu, J.H. (2004). An empirical study of end-user computing acceptance factors in small and medium enterprises in Taiwan: analyzed by structural equation modeling, Journal of Computer Information 498–108.##Mbengo, L. &amp; Pinigas, F. (2014). E-learning Adoption by Lecturers in Selected Zimbabwe State Universities: An Application of Technology Acceptance Model. Journal of Business Administration and Education, 6(1), 2201-2958.##Overbeek, S.P., Bommel, P.V., &amp; Proper, H.A. (2008). Matching cognitive characteristics of actors and tasks in information systems engineering, Knowledge-Based Systems, 21 (8), 764–785.##Rusbasan, D. R. (2010). Help boss, I’m stressed! Measuring types of perceived supervisor support and how day related to subordinates’ workplace stress. USA: University of Connecticut, Storrs.##Shafiq, M., Zia-pur- Rehman, M., &amp; Rashid, M. (2013). Impact of compensation, training and development and supervisor support on organizational commitment. Journal of Compensation &amp; benefits review, 45 (5), 278- 285.##Song, S. (2008). Work Unit's Knowledge Processing Style: An Empirical Examination of its Determinants, International Journal of Knowledge Management, 4(2), 1-16##Sun, H. &amp; Leeper, P. (2006). Applying Markus and Robey’s casual structure to examine user technology acceptance research: A new approach. Journal of Information Technology Theory and Application, 8(2), 21-40##Talukder, M. (2012). Factors affecting the adoption of technological innovation by individual employees: An Australian study, Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 40, 52 – 57.##Tarhini, A., Hone, K., &amp; Liu, X. (2013). User acceptance towards web-based learning systems. Procedia Computer Science, 17, 189-197.##Taylor, S. &amp; Todd, P.A. (1995). Assessing IT usage: the role of prior experience, Management Information Systems Quarterly, 19 (4), 561–570.##Thompson, R.L., Higgins, C.A., &amp; Howell, J.M. (1991). Personal computing: towards a conceptual model of utilization, MIS Quarterly, 15 (1), 125–142.##Tisknakis, M. &amp; Kouroubali, A. (2009). Organizational Factors Affecting Successful Adoption of Innovative E-Health Services: A Case Study Employing the FITT Framework. Int. J. Medical Informatics, 78, 39-52. ##Tomte, C. &amp; Hatlevic, O. (2011). Gender- differences in self-efficacy ICT related to various ICT-user profiles in Finland and Norway: How do self-efficacy, gender.##Venkatesh, V. (2000). Determinants of perceived ease of use: integrating control, intrinsic motivation, and emotion into the technology acceptance model, Information Systems Research, 11 (4), 342–365.##آشتیانی، هادی(1384). توصیف و الویت‌بندی عوامل انگیزش شغلی معلمان تربیت بدنی نیشابور بر اساس نظریه هرزبرگ، پایان‌نامه منتشرشده کارشناسی ارشد تربیت بدنی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی.##اسکوئیان، معصومه(1391). بررسی عوامل درون‌سازمانی موثر بر کارآفرینی سازمانی، کنفرانس ملی کارآفرینی و مدیریت کسب و کارهای دانش بنیان. بابلسر - شرکت پژوهشی طرود شمال.##الهی، شعبان، کنعانی، فاطمه و شایان، علی(1390). طراحی چارچوبی برای عوامل موثر بر گرایش دانشجویان مجازی به یادگیری الکترونیکی و سنجش آن، فصلنامه پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی در آموزش عالی، سال 17، شماره 60، صص 80-59.##بشیریان، سعید، جلیلیان، فرزاد، براتی، مجید و غفاری، مهدیه (1393). تحلیل فاکتورهای پیش‌بینی‌کننده‌ی قصد استفاده از آموزش الکترونیکی در بین اعضای هیات علمی با بهره‌گیری از تئوری رفتار برنامه‌ریزی شده، مجله‌ی توسعه‌ی آموزش در علوم پزشکی، سال 7، شماره 15، صص 12-10. ##خداداد حسینی، سید حمید، نوری، علی و ذبیحی، محمدرضا (1392). پذیرش آموزش الکترونیکی درآموزش عالی: کاربرد نظریه جریان، مدل پذیرش فناوری وکیفیت خدمات الکترونیکی، فصلنامه پژوهش و برنامه‌ریزی در آموزش عالی، سال 19، شماره 69، صص 136-111.##خیراندیش، مهدی(1390). الگوی امکان‌سنجی اجرای آموزش‌های مجازی، فصلنامه راهبردهای آموزش، سال 4، شماره 3، صص 142-137.##سید جوادین، سیدرضا و یزدانی، شمسی(1384). بررسی عوامل موثر بر قصد استفاده مشتریان از خدمات بانکداری(مطالعه موردی بانک سامان). دانش مدیریت، سال 18، شماره 70، صص 61-45. ##سرلک، محمدعلی، رضایی، سیاوش، و شهیدی، حمیدرضا(1391). عوامل موثر بر سبک پردازش دانش در واحدهای کاری شرکت بیمه البرز و شعب آن در تهران، فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، سال 4، شماره 4، صص34-19.##شاه‌حسینی، محمدعلی، استیری، مهرداد، و کشفی، مریم‌السادات(1395). بررسی تأثیر حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده و حمایت سرپرست ادراک شده بر تعهد سازمانی و عملکرد فردی کارکنان، فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، سال 8، شماره 2، صص 391-373.##زکی، محمدعلی(1389). خودکارآمدی کامپیوتر: سنجش و جایگاه آن در مدل پذیرش فناوری اطلاعات: مطالعه موردی دانشجویان دختر و پسر دانشگاه های اصفهان و آزاد اسلامی شهررضا، توسعه آموزش در علوم پزشکی، سال 7، شماره 15 ، صص 21 -10.##قهرمانی، محمد (۱۳۸۸). مدیریت آموزش سازمانی، تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه شهید بهشتی.##علیزاده، ماه‌منیر، فقیه‌آرام، بتول و مهدی‌زاده، امیرحسین (1394). شناسایی عوامل سازنده گرایش به آموزش الکترونیکی در بین استادان دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد اسلامشهر، فصلنامه فن‌آوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات در علوم تربیتی، سال 5، شماره 3، صص 99-83.##عباس‌زادگان، محمد و ترک‌زاده، جعفر(1388). ارزیابی نیازمندی‌ها در سازمان‌ها، شرکت سهامی انتشار، صص 32-24. ##عموزاد، محمد، قرمانی، محمد، و گلی‌نژاد، الهام (1393). بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر آمادگی یادگیری الکترونیکی درکارکنان شرکت ملی صنایع پتروشیمی، فصلنامه مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 5، شماره 22، صص 57-30.##فتحی، رضا و صیف، محمد حسن (1396). مدل علّی پذیرش و بهکارگیری یادگیری مجازی درکارکنان: نقش تناسب فناوری–شغل، خودکارآمدی وهنجارذهنی، فصلنامه آموزش و توسعه منابع انسانی، سال 4، شماره 12، صص 165-149.##مومنی‌راد، اکبر و علی‌آبادی، خدیجه(1389). تضمین کیفیت در آموزش الکترونیکی با بهره‌گیری از استانداردهای آموزش الکترونیکی، سال 3، شماره 3، صص92-87.##محمدخانی، کامران، محمد داودی، امیرحسین، و جلالی، عاطفه(1393). ارزیابی عوامل موثر بر موفقیت آموزش مجازی در پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت، فصلنامه اطلاعات و ارتباطات در علوم تربیتی، سال 5، شماره 1، صص 162-143.##هداوند، سعید، وکاشانچی، علی(1392). عوامل موثر بر یادگیری الکترونیکی، نشریه علمی-پژوهشی راهبردهای آموزش در علوم پزشکی، سال 6، شماره 2، صص 93-89. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>عوامل تأثیرگذار بر تعهد سازمانی و نقش عدالت سازمانی در ارتقای آن</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Factors Affecting Organizational Commitment and the Role of Organizational Justice in Promoting</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی عوامل تأثیرگذار بر تعهد سازمانی و نقش عدالت سازمانی در ارتقای آن انجام گرفته است. لذا، از حیث هدف، کاربردی محسوب می شود. جامعه آماری تحقیق شامل کارکنان متخصص شاغل در شرکت&#8204;های پتروشیمی واقع در منطقه ویژه اقتصادی انرژی پارس (عسلویه) بود و حجم نمونه بر اساس فرمول کوکران، 260 نفر به&#8204;دست آمد. پژوهش در دو مرحله انجام گرفت؛ در مرحله اول، جهت شناسایی عوامل تأثیرگذار بر تعهد سازمانی از پرسش&#8204;نامه محقق ساخته با ضریب آلفای کرونباخ 0/831استفاده گردید. به&#173; کمک تحلیل عاملی 25 مؤلفه تأثیرگذار بر تعهد سازمانی با ضریب تبیین75% و در چهار دسته کلی 1) عوامل ساختاری/ مدیریتی 2) عوامل مرتبط با شغل 3) عوامل محیطی و فیزیکی و 4) عوامل فردی شناسایی گردیدند. یافته&#173; های حاصل نشان داد که مؤلفه &#171;رعایت عدالت سازمانی&#187; از دسته عوامل &#171;ساختاری/ مدیریتی&#187; بیشترین درجه تأثیرگذاری را در تعهد سازمانی دارد. در مرحله دوم پژوهش به بررسی نقش عدالت سازمانی در تعهد سازمانی پرداخته شد. داده&#8204;ها به&#8204;کمک پرسش&#8204;نامه&#8204;&#8204;های تعهد سازمانی آلن و می&#8204;یر(1990) و عدالت سازمانی نیهوف و مورمن(1993) با ضرایب آلفای کرونباخ به&#160;&#173;ترتیب 0/786 و 0/835 جمع&#8204;آوری شد و &#160;به&#8204;منظور تحلیل آنها از ضریب همبستگی پیرسون، تحلیل رگرسیون، آزمون تی و تحلیل واریانس استفاده گردید. نتایج حاکی از آن بود که بین عدالت سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی در سطح اطمینان 99% رابطه مثبت و معناداری وجود داشته و رعایت عدالت سازمانی تأثیر چشمگیری در ارتقای تعهد سازمانی کارکنان متخصص در شرکت &#173;های پتروشیمی واقع در منطقه عسلویه دارد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The present study was conducted to investigate the factors affecting organizational commitment and the role of organizational justice in promoting it. Purposeful study is an applied research. The statistical population consisted of specialists working in petrochemical companies located in Pars Special Economic Region (Assaluyeh). The sample size was 260 according to the Cochran formula. The research was conducted in two stages. In the first step, a researcher-made questionnaire was used to determine factors influencing organizational commitment using 0.831 Cronbach's alpha coefficient. So that 25 factors affecting organizational commitment through factor analysis by explaining %75 of the factors were classified into four general categories: (1) structural / managerial factors; (2) factors related to occupation; (3) environmental and physical factors; (4) individual factors. The findings showed that the organizational justice as a component of organizational / managerial factors has the highest degree of impact on organizational commitment. In the second stage, the role of organizational justice in promoting organizational commitment was studied. Data were collected by Allen &#38; Meyer (1990) and Organizational Justice Questionnaire Niuoff &#38; Morman (1993) with Cronbach's alpha coefficient of 0.786 and 0.835, and analyzed by Pearson correlation coefficient, analysis Regression, T-test and ANOVA.The results indicated that there was a positive and significant relationship between organizational justice and organizational commitment at %99confidence level.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>315</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>343</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>منصوری</Family>
				<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mansoori</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه هرمزگان، بندرعباس</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>هرمزگان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Mansoori.hossein@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational Justice</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational Commitment</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>petrochemical companies</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Pars Special Economic Region.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عدالت سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تعهد سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کارکنان متخصص</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شرکت‌های پتروشیمی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>منطقه ویژه اقتصادی انرژی پارس.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Akroyd, D., Legg, J., Jackowski, M. B., &amp; Adams, R. D. (2009). The impact of selected organizational variables and managerial leadership on radiation therapists' organizational commitment, Radiography, 15 (2), 113-120.##Armenio, R. &amp; Miguel, P. C. (2008). Work place Spirituality and Organization Commitment. Journal of Organizational Change Management, 21 (l), 53-75.##Baron, R. A. &amp; Greenberg, J. (1990). Behavior in Organization: Understanding and Managing the Human Side of Work, Third Edition. Toronto: Allyn and Bacon. ##Benkhoff. A. (1996). Ignoring commitment is casting. Human Relation, 44 (6), 701–851.##Brashear, T. G., Brooks, C. M., &amp; Boles, J. S. (2004). Distributive and Procedural Justice in a Sales Force Context Scale development and validation. Journal of Business Research, 57 (1), 86-93.  ##Carry, J. P., Wakefield, D.S., Price, J.L., &amp; Mueller, C. W. (1986). On the Causal Ordering of job satisfaction and organizational Commitment. Academy of Management Journal, 29 (4), 847–858.##Chen, X. N. &amp; Francesco A. M. (2003).The relationship between the three components of commitment and employee performance in China. J Vocat Behaves, 62(3), 490-510.##Chen, X. N. &amp; Francesco, A. M. (2000). Employee demography, organizational commitment, and turnover intentions. Hum Relation, 35(6), 869-887.##Cichy, R. F., Cha, J., &amp; Kim, S. (2009). The relationship between organizational commitment and contextual performance among private club leaders. International Journal of Hospitality Management, 28 (1), 53–62.##Colquitt, J. A., Greenberg, J., &amp; Zapata-Phelan, C. P. (2005). What is organizational justice? A historical overview. In J. Greenberg &amp; J. A. 5- Colquitt (Eds.), Handbook of organizational justice (pp. 3–56). Mahwah, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.##Cropanzano, R, Prehar, C.A., &amp; Chen, P.Y, (2002). Using social exchange theory to distinguish procedural from interactional justice. Group and Organization Management, 27, 324-351.##DeConinck, J. (2010). The effect of organizational justice, perceived organizational support, and perceived supervisor support on marketing employees' level of trust. Journal of Business Research, 63(12), 1349-1355.##Derry. J. P. &amp; Iverson, R. D. (1998). Antecedents and Consequences of dual and Unilateral Commitment: A Longitualinal Study. University of Melbourne. ##Gautam, T., Van Dick, R., &amp; Wagner, U. (2004). Organizational identification and organizational commitment: Distinct aspects of two related concepts. Asian Journal of Social Psychology, 7, 301-315.##Jamal, M. (2011). Job stress, Performance and Organizational Commitment in a multinational company: An Empirical study in two countries. International Journal of Business and Social Science, 2 (20), 20-29.##Johnson, N. B. &amp; Duffy, M. K. (2005). Employee commitment and organizational policies. Management Decision, 43(2), 203-219.##Joiner, T.A. &amp; Bakalis, S. (2006). The antecedents of organizational commitment: The case of Australian casual academics. International Journal of Educational Management, 20(6), 439-452.##Laura J. E. &amp; Lind, A. (2002). The Injustice of Others: Social Reports and the Integration of Others Experiences in Organizational Justice Judgments. Organizational Behavior and Human Design Processes, 89(1), 906-924.##Lee, S. H., Lee. T. W., &amp; Lum, C. F. (2008). The effects of employee services on organizational commitment and intentions to quit. Personnel Review, 37(2), 222-237.##Liao, H. &amp; Rupp, D. E. (2005). The impact of justice climate and justice orientation on work outcomes: Across-level multifoci framework. Journal of Applied Psychology, 90 (3), 242-256.##Maryama, N. H. B., Zawawi, N., Hitam, M., &amp; Jody, J. M. (2011).Organizational Commitment and Job Burnout Among employees in Malaysia. IACSIT Press, 1, 185-187.##Mathieu, J.E. &amp; Zajac, D.M. (1990). A Review and Meta-Analysis of the Antecedents, Correlates and Consequences of Organizational Commitment. Psychological Bulletin, 2 (1), 171-194.##Maureen L. &amp; Ambrose, E. (2002). Contemporary Justice Research: A New Look at Familiar. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision, 89(1), 803- 812. ##Mayer, D, Nishii, L, Schneider, B., &amp; Goldstein, H. (2007). The precursors and Products of justice climates: Group leader antecedents and employee attitudinal consequences. Personnel Psychology, 60 (3), 929-963.##McDowall, A. &amp; Fletcher, C. (2004). Employee development: an organizational justice perspective. Personnel Review, 33(1), 8-29.##McMurray, A. J., Scott, D.R., &amp; Pace, R.W. (2004). The relationship between organizational commitment and organizational climate in manufacturing. Hum Resource Dev Quart, 15(4), 89-473.##Meyer, J. P., Stanley, D. J, &amp; Herscovitch, L. (2002). Affective continuance and normative commitment to the organization: A meta-analysis of antecedents, correlates, and consequences. Journal of Vocational Behavior, 61 (4), 20-52.##Meyer, J. P., Allen Natalie.J., &amp; Smith Catherine. A. (1993). Commitment to organization and occupation. Journal of Applied psychology, 78(4), 538-551.##Mowday, R.T. (1999). Chicken, Pigs, Breakfast and Commitment. The Organizational Behavior Newsletter, 10, P. 3.##Mowdey, R.T., Porter, L.W., &amp; Steers, R.M. (1982). Employee- Organization Linkage of Commitment, Absenteeism and Turnover, New York: Academic Press.##Parish, J. T., Cadwallader, S., &amp; Busch, P. (2008). Want to, need to, and ought to: employee commitment to organizational change. Journal of Organizational Change Management, 21(1), 32-52.##Paul A. K. &amp; Anantharaman, R. N. (2004). Influence of HRM practice on organizational commitment: A study among software professionals in India. Hum Resource Manage, 14 (4), 46-87.##Pool, S. &amp; Pool, B. (2007). A management development model: Measuring organizational commitment and its impact on job satisfaction among executives in a learning organization. Journal of Management Development, 26(4), 353-369.##Robbins, S. P. (1991). Organizational Behavior: Concepts, controversies, and applications. Fifth Edition. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall.##Sitter, V.L. (2003). Communication Style as a Predictor of Interactional Justice. Paper presented at the International Leadership Studies Conference. August. Retrieved on 8 October, 2009 from http://www.regent.edu/acad/sls/publications/conference_proceedings/international_leadership_conference/2003pdf/sitter_communication_style.pdf ##Somes, M. J. &amp; Brinbaum, D. (1998). Work-related Commitment and Job Performance: It’s also the Nature of the Performance that Counts. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 19 (1), 621-634.##Vuuren, M. V., Jong, M. D.T., &amp; Seydel, E. R. (2007). Direct and indirect effects of supervisor communication on organizational commitment. Corporate Communications: An International Journal, 12 (2), 116-128.##احمدی زهرانی، مریم و کاوه، امید (1397). رابطه بین رهبری پدرسالارانه و سکوت کارکنان با تأکید بر نقش تعدیل‌کننده عدالت سازمانی.  فصلنامه مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 10، شماره 38، صص 212-189.##تقی‌زاده، جهان، رسولی، رضا و بابایی، شاهرخ (1394). تأثیر عدالت سازمانی و امنیت شغلی بر تعهد سازمانی از طریق اعتماد به مدیران. فصلنامه پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی، سال 7، شماره 2، صص 77-53.##دژبانی، آرزو (1394). بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر تعهد سازمانی کارکنان ناجا.  فصلنامه دانش انتظامی پلیس، شماره 2، صص 96-75.##رجب‌پور، ابراهیم، چرختاب‌مقدم، جهانشاه و ملایی، امیر حمزه (1398). تأثیر مؤلفه‌های مدیریت استعداد بر رضایت شغلی و تعهد سازمانی کارکنان دانشی؛ مورد مطالعه: پژوهشگاه صنعت نفت. فصلنامه مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، سال 10، دوره 8، شماره 39، صص 196-175.##رمزگویان، غلامعلی و حسن‌پور، کاووس (1392). بررسی رابطه بین تعهد و عملکرد کارکنان در وزارت امور اقتصاد و دارایی. مجله اقتصادی، شماره 3و4، صص 48ـ 3.##شفیعی نیک، اصغر (1392). تحلیل رابطه مؤلفه‌های درون‌سازمانی با تعهد سـازمانی و عملکرد مدیران ناجا در حوزه ستاد و صف. مطالعات مدیریت انتظامی، سال 8، شماره 3، صص 377-341.##صیادی تورانلو، حسین، جمالی، رضا و منصوری، حسین (1388). بررسی رابطه کیفیت زندگی کاری و تعهد سازمانی (مطالعه موردی: کارکنان آموزش و پرورش یزد). فصلنامه علوم تربیتی (مجله علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی)، دوره 5، شماره 1، صص 136-113.##طاهری، زکیه و رهگذر، حسن (1397). بررسی رابطه نوع فرهنگ سازمانی با تعهد سازمانی و توانمندسازی کارکنان پالایشگاه گاز پارسیان در سال 1391. فصلنامه مدیریت فرهنگی، دوره 7، شماره 40، صص 116-103.##مدنی، حسین و زاهدی، محمدجواد (1384). تعیین اولویت عوامل مؤثر بر تعهد کارکنان، مجله جامعه‌شناسی ایران، دوره 6، شماره 1، صص 33-3. ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
