<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>6</volume>
<number>23</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی نقش میانجی حمایت سازمانی در رابطه بین ادراک رفتار سیاسی سازمانی با رضایت و عملکرد شغلی </title_fa>
	<title>Investigating the Role of Organizational Support in the Relationship between Perceived Organizational Political Behavior with Satisfaction and Job Performance</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.5pt;&quot;&gt;در تحقیق حاضر نقش میانجی حمایت سازمانی در رابطه بین ادراک رفتار سیاسی سازمانی با رضایت و عملکرد شغلی کارکنان مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. جامعه آماری تحقیق حاضر 130 نفر از کارکنان شرکت نفت استان آذربایجان غربی بودند. با توجه به حجم محدود جامعه آماری، تمام اعضای جامعه مورد نظر به عنوان نمونه آماری در نظر گرفته شد. برای سنجش ادراک رفتار سیاسی سازمانی از پرسشنامه فریس و ککمر، برای سنجش حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده از پرسشنامه آیزنبرگر، جهت سنجش عملکرد شغلی کارکنان از پرسشنامه رایت،ککمر، مک مهان و دلی ویو و در سنجش رضایت شغلی از پرسشنامه برایفلید و روته استفاده شد. در این تحقیق مدلی براساس ادبیات تحقیق ارائه گردید؛ داده&#8204;های تحقیق حاضر از برازش مدل حمایت کردند و یافته&#8204;های ذیل به دست آمد: ادراک رفتار سیاسی در بالاترین سطح سازمانی با حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده رابطه منفی و معنی&#8204;دار دارد؛ ادراک رفتار سیاسی در سطح بالاتر از سطح جاری با حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده رابطه منفی و معنی&#8204;دار دارد؛ ادراک رفتار سیاسی در سطح جاری با حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده رابطه منفی و معنی&#8204;دار دارد و حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده با عملکرد و رضایت شغلی کارکنان رابطه مثبت و معنی&#8204;دار دارد. نتیجه تحقیق حاکی از آن است که حمایت سازمانی در رابطه بین ادراک رفتار سیاسی سازمانی با رضایت و عملکرد شغلی نقش میانجی را ایفا می کند.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>In this study the relationship between perceived organizational politic with job satisfaction and employee's performance among West Azerbaijan Province petroleum employment was investigated. To conduct this investigation, the Ferries and Kacmar questionnaire for perceived organizational politics; the Eisenbereger questionnaire for perceived organizational support; Wright, McMahan, Deleeuw questionnaire for job satisfaction were distributed among the 130 company's personal. The study achieved a 100% retune rate, with a total of 77/7% surveys used for data analysis. Data analysis were done with LISEL and findings verified the fitness of the proposed research model and showed that: there were a negative significance relationship between perceived organizational politics at one level up form in organization with perceived organizational support; there were a negative significance relationship between perceived organizational politics at ones level with perceived organizational support. There was a positive significance relationship between perceived organizational supports with employee's performance. Results indicated that perceived organizational supports is a mediator between the relationship of politics perceptions with job satisfaction and employee's performance</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>ادراک رفتار سیاسی سازمانی , حمایت سازمانی , رضایت شغلی , عملکرد شغلی , کارکنان شرکت نفت استان آذربایجان غربی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Perception political organizational behavior- Organizational support - Job satisfaction - Job performance -West Azerbaijan Province petroleum employees</keyword>
	<start_page>119</start_page>
	<end_page>138</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-311-6&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hassani </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حسنی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003021</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003021</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه ارومیه</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Abolfazl  </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ghasemzadeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ابوالفضل</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>قاسم زاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003022</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003022</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید مدنی آذربایجان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Rahim </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Shirazi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رحیم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>شیرازی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003023</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003023</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه ارومیه</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
