@article{ 
author = {Iranzadeh, Soleim},  
title = {Identifying and Ranking Empowerments of Employees Using ISM Approach
(Case Study: Tabriz Oil Refining Company)}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this research is to identify and empowerments of relationship managers in Tabriz Oil Refining Company. The target population included all managers are Tabriz Oil Refining Company. To collect the data necessary to identify the components of the questionnaire was used. The validity for validity and reliability was calculated using Cronbach's alpha coefficient.&#160; The statistical community managers Tabriz Oil Refining Company is the number of directors is 68 that using the Bartlett 46 of them were selected as sample. In order to collect data to identify the components of research, draw the primary diagram and table form adjacency relations of the company's survey. For this purpose, a questionnaire was used. Kolmogorov-Smirnov test to achieve the purpose of research, T-test to identify the components and techniques Interpretive Structural Modeling (ISM) to the level of relations of the components used. The results show that between twenty one&#160; method of empowerment extracted from the literature, Thirteen Ways of more importance to other methods of empowering. The results of the study show, Components of &#34;accountability&#34; and &#34;according to merit&#34; are located on the first level that Indicate the high influence of these two variables. The indices of &#34;education,&#34; &#34;lead managers&#34; and &#34;employee involvement&#34; as the most influential managers in Tabriz Oil Refinery's empowerment indicators. Finally, using MICMAC variables were analyzed in terms of power and dependency. Finally, using MICMAC variables were analyzed in terms of power and dependency.},  
Keywords = {Empowerment lack of role ambiguity education interpretive structural modeling MICMAC analysis},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {3-26}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-45-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-45-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Moradi, Mortez},  
title = {Evaluate the Impact of Organizational Silence on Behavioral Variables 
(Case Study: Pars Oil and Gas Company)}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this study is to investigate the potential effects of organizational silence on behavioral variables. For this purpose, variables such as; anti-citizenship behaviors (ACB), job dissatisfaction (JD), cognitive dissonance (CD) and job stress (JS) were studied. Questionnaires were distributed between employees of Pars Oil and Gas Company. In order to test the hypothesis, LISREL software and Path Analysis Model (PAM) is used. The findings indicates that organizational silence has a significant positive effect on anti-citizenship behaviors, job dissatisfaction, cognitive dissonance and job stress. Job dissatisfaction has meaningful positive effect on cognitive dissonance and anti-citizenship behaviors. Findings also indicates that cognitive dissonance has meaningful positive effect on job stress and anti-citizenship behaviors. Finally, the effect of job stress on anti-citizenship behaviors was meaningful and positive. This study reveals that organizational silence is an unpleasant phenomenon that has negative consequences.},  
Keywords = {Organizational Silence Anti-Citizenship Behaviors Job Dissatisfaction Cognitive Dissonance Job Stress},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {27-49}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-46-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-46-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Abili, khodayar and gholamalilavasani, masoud and gholami, khaled and Hosseini, Seyed jamal},  
title = {The Study of Effectiveness Training Courses Supervisions’ and Suggestions Suitable Solutions in Order to its Improvement 
(Case Study: National Iranian Gas Company)}, 
abstract ={In the recent day, Training and Human Resource Empowerment in industrial and productive companies shaped as a real fact and the human being accepted&#160; it. This fact was formed in a form of formal and planed programs, such as short term or long term programs operated but the effectiveness is the most important part of every training programs, so it can lead the programs and design the other part of the training program. This paper the study of effectiveness instructional courses supervisions in Iranian Gas National Company in 2012 and suggestions suitable solutions in order to its improvement. The method of the research was descriptive survey. The research sample has included 80 sample ones of staff supervisor of NIGC.&#160; In this study to collect data from a researcher made questionnaire which is based on three components of individual, educational, organizational characteristics and was based on Transmission model of education of Holton. The data analysis description and deductive statistics (one sample t-test) and SPSS 16 were used for the statistical analysis of the data. On sample T-test results showed that the level of individual components and component properties&#160; enterprise-level features appropriate and the other two features training and assessment have the better situation than the individual features.},  
Keywords = {Effectiveness Training supervision Effectiveness assessment  models National Gas Company},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {51-74}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-47-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-47-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Fayyazi, Marjan and Afshar, Zahr},  
title = {E-recruitment in Top Petroleum Organizations}, 
abstract ={The aim of this study is to assess the status of the e-recruitment in&#160; top petrochemical organizations. The top petrochemical organizations were selected from Industrial Management in 1392 and their organizational website content analysis. The&#160; top petrochemical organizations&#160; were selected based on the ranking of Industrial Management in 1390 and their website of the organizations, were studied through content analysis method. The results reveal that in total of 23 organizations, 15 organizations have been part of the e- recruitment. Also, The top petrochemicals organizations have more attention to human resources policies and practices, Tracking information, announced the result and recruitment process and in contrast, the above said organizations have been less attention to send resume, the online test and type of employment},  
Keywords = {electronic recruitment information technology petrochemical industry and top organizations

},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {75-100}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-48-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-48-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Safari, Ali and Rad, Shima and Golshahi, Behnam},  
title = {Investigating the Effect of Social Marketing on Reducing Counter-Productive Work Behaviors of Employees 
(Case Study: Pasargad Oil Company)}, 
abstract ={Present paper has been done in order to investigate the effect of social marketing on reducing counter-productive work behaviors of employees in Pasargad Oil Company. This paper is a descriptive- correlational study. Statistical population consist of employees of Pasargad Oil Company. Data gathering instrument is a 32 Question questionnaire to measure social marketing and a 44 question questionnaire to measure counter-productive work behaviors. Its validity was confirmed based on content and construct method and its reliability was confirmed based on Coronbakh- alfa method. Data analyze were done by Amos 22 software and structural equation modeling. Results showed that social marketing has a negative effect on counter- productive work employees. Also the results of other hypothesis revealed that social marketing made reduce counter- productive behavior individualistic and self-organization and by changing employee attitude to organizational citizenship behavior in addition to reducing negative effects, it makes enhance employees effectiveness and organizational health and its advantages reach to society.},  
Keywords = {social marketing counter-productive work behaviors employees Pasargad Oil Company},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {101-122}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-49-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-49-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Karami, Mohsen and Shafiee, Saee},  
title = {Studying the Relationship Between Social Capital and Organizational Health of Employees of N.I.O.C}, 
abstract ={The aim of this study is to investigate the relationship between social capital and organizational health of the National Iranian Oil Company's employees. The method was descriptive survey and of the correlation type. The statistical population was the National Iranian Oil Company employees in Tehran that 270 of them were selected through Cochran's formula as the sample and they were studied using a simple random sampling method. Data collection tools were Hoy and Feldman organizational health questionnaire (1996) and Heisman and Hoff social capital questionnaire (2009). Validity of the questionnaires was confirmed through the content validity by the judgment of the elite and review of the literature and reliability was calculated and approved through Cronbach's alpha. In this study, description of data was done using descriptive statistics and central indices, average and standard deviation and the Pearson correlation test and regression were used to assess hypotheses. The results showed that there is a significant positive relationship between social capital and organizational health of employees at the National Iranian Oil Company. It is recommended that policymakers and planners in organizations have special attention to the issue of social capital to improve organizational health.},  
Keywords = {Social Capital Organizational Health NIOC Hoy and Feldman},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {123-141}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-50-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-50-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Eidi, Fatemeh and AhmadiKhalilMahalleh, Reza and MasoumiAghbelagh, Sepideh},  
title = {The Effect of Business Ethics on The Development of Intellectual Capital}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this paper is to explore the impact of Business Ethics on Development of Intellectual in Iranian oil pipeline and telecommunication company (IOPTC). we used questionnaire for gathering data&#160; and 150 of 91 responded to the questionnaire. In order to test the validity of the questionnaire we used Confirmatory factor analysis and Cronbach&#8217;s Alpha was used to assess the reliability. The results show that Business Ethics has a positive and significant effect on Development of Intellectual and all hypotheses were confirmed.},  
Keywords = {Business ethics Intellectual capital Organisational Capital Social Capital Human Capital},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {143-162}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-51-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-51-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Mohammadi, Behnam},  
title = {An Investigation on the Relationship Between Proactive Personality, Perceived Supervisor Support With Job Performance and the Moderating Effects of Proactive Behavior}, 
abstract ={Because of many changes in the needs raised in organizations and uncertainty in working places, the proactive and self-leading behaviors have progressively received significance. The purpose of the present study is to conduct an investigation on the relationship between proactive personality, Conscientiousness, Perceived Supervisor Support with Job satisfaction and Performance and the moderating effects of Proactive Behavior. The participants of this survey were 260 official and contractual personnel of Bid Boland gas refinery selected based on the hierarchical sampling method. In this survey, the following instruments were used: proactive personality scale, Perceived Supervisor Support scale, proactive behavior questioner and job performance questioner. The evaluation of the proposed patterns was done with the use of path analysis method. The results supported the relationship between patterns and collected data. The results revealed that proactive behavior moderated the relationship between Proactive Personality and Perceived Supervisor Support with Job Performance},  
Keywords = {Proactive Personality Perceived Supervisor Support Job Performance Proactive Behavior},
volume = {7},
Number = {27}, 
pages = {163-181}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-52-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-52-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

