@article{ 
author = {Dortaj, Fariborz and Shariat, Sara and AbbasPour, Abbas and Delavar, Ali and Sadipour, Esmaeil},  
title = {Explaining and Presenting the Strategist training Model in The National Iranian Oil Company Based on Grounded Theory}, 
abstract ={One of the approaches that is currently being addressed not only in Iran but in the world is the problem of creating a perspective and strategy formulation. In this regard, the role of strategists in the organization is very important. So, the main goal of this qualitative research was &#34;developing a strategic training model at the national Iranian oil company&#34;, based on grounded theory approach, and secondary aims included identifying dimensions (main categories), causal conditions, confounding factors (adversary and deterrent), strategies and implications for the development of strategists in national Iranian oil company; Although, identifying the most important components of the main category, which is strategic thinking. This research is in the category of applied research in terms of purpose, in the category of exploratory research in term of level and methodologically located in the category of qualitative research with grounded theory and systematic approach. The research data were collected through semi-structured interviews (24 experts from industry and university) from study sample, then by coding, we have identified the dimensions, the main categories and the subcategories and concepts associated with each of the codes obtained. After the axial and selective coding table was obtained, the paradigm model was realized and the type of relationship between dimensions and components of strategist development was achieved. The findings of the research showed 11 main categories and 24 sub categories and 98 concepts, which are in the form of a paradigmatic model including: causal conditions (individual factors, organizational factors and discourse), the central category of strategic thinking (systemic vision, conceptual thinking, prospective and philosophical attitude), Interventive factors (external and internal environment), background factors (cultural context, learning context, psychological factors and organizational independence, strategies of talent identification and absorption and maintenance) and consequences (development of strategic thinking and establishment of monitoring system) in national oil company and showed the relationship between its various dimensions. The findings of this study led to the exploration of a model for development of strategists at the National Iranian Oil Company.},  
Keywords = {Experts, strategic thinking, oil industry, and Grounded Theory},
volume = {9},
Number = {33}, 
pages = {3-34}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-110-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-110-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {ZareiMatin, Hassan and Yazdani, Hamidreza and Ataei, Bahareh},  
title = {Developing a model for justice leadership in the oil industry using the Grounded theory (Case study: Iranian Oil Pipeline and Telecommunication Company)}, 
abstract ={Cconsidering the growing significance of human capital in the oil industry, the irrefutable role of leadership in guiding, maintaining and motivating employees, and also; increasing positive outcomes, progressing performance of organization and the growing importance of the study of organizational justice, which are intertwined in leadership research, the purpose of this article has been developing a model of justice leadership in the oil industry using a qualitative research method based on the grounded theory. Iranian Oil Pipeline and Telecommunication Company was considered as a population and based on the purposive sampling and snowball technique, using the organizational justice questionnaire, 16 managers and supervisors with the highest score were selected and interviewed. After conducting the interview and, using the grounded theory Method with Emphasizing on the leadership process, the conceptual model of the justice leadership process was designed from 104 final extracted codes in the form of 29 concepts, 7 subcategories and 6 categories. &#160;},  
Keywords = {Leadership, Leadership Process, Organizational Justice, Justice Leadership, Grounded Theory.},
volume = {9},
Number = {33}, 
pages = {35-64}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-136-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-136-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {RajabiFarjad, Hajieh and ImaniKhoo, Shabnam},  
title = {The Impact of Servant Leadership on Employee Perception of Organizational Justice 
(Case: Oil Ministry Staff)}, 
abstract ={Servant leaders emphasize the service to others and sacrifice personal interests for the interests of others in order to empower individuals with greater freedom, self-control and self-serving as service leaders. The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of servant leadership on employee perceptions of organizational justice. The research method was applied in terms of purpose and in terms of correlation method. The statistical population consisted of all the staff of the Oil Ministry of Iran, in headquarters, which numbered 800 employees. Using a Morgan table, the sample size was 260 people. They were selected using simple random sampling. For collecting data, two standard questionnaires used by Barbuto and Wheeler (2006) and organizational justice Niehoff and Moorman (1993) has been applied. The validity of the questionnaires computed through Cronbach's Alpha was 79/0 and 84/0 respectively. Examining the information and testing the hypotheses was done by using multiple regression tests, Structural Equation Modeling, and using the PLS software, two parts of the measurement model and structural part were performed. The results of the research indicated that the servant leadership affects employees' perceptions of organizational justice. Also, each aspect of servant leadership (wisdom, self-sacrifice, persuasive representation, emotional healing, stewardship, and promise) affects organizational justice Which respectively have a significant tendency toward sacrifice, sacrifice, emotional healing, stewardship and promise, persuasive representation and wisdom.},  
Keywords = {servant leadership, wisdom, self-sacrifice, represented persuasive, emotional healing, stewardship and secure servers, organizational justice.},
volume = {9},
Number = {33}, 
pages = {65-86}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-210-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-210-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Sadeghi, Heshmatollah and Mousavi, Seyed Najmaldin and Nazarpouri, Amir Houshang and Hakkak, Mohamm},  
title = {Investigating the Cultural Rifts Among Organizational Subcultures    (Case: The Central Office of IOPTC)}, 
abstract ={According to the main role of culture as an affecting factor on organizational relationships and personnel performance, the purpose of this study has been analyzing organizational subcultures and rifts among them using a locally-developed model founded on work practices. To do this, first, the existence of functional and hierarchical subcultures was investigated and proved based on the researcher-developed model using Kruskal Wallis and Mann &#8211;Whitney U tests and then, cultural rifts among the subcultures were calculated. The analysis performed within SPSS on 255 responses to the research questionnaire in the central office of IOPTC. According to the results, the highest level of cultural rift among functional subcultures was in development dimension and its lowest level was in bureaucracy dimension. Also, the highest level of cultural rift among managers&#8217; and employees&#8217; subcultures was in participation dimension and its lowest level has been observed in stress dimension. Having knowledge about subcultures and rifts among them provides possibilities for correcting cultural practices for better organizational adaptation to environment, decreasing misunderstandings between subcultures especially between managers&#8217; and employees&#8217; subcultures and also, help managers to take more effective decisions.},  
Keywords = {Organization, Subculture Analysis, Functional Unit, Organizational Hierarchy, Cultural Rift.},
volume = {9},
Number = {33}, 
pages = {87-110}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-211-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-211-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {TaheriGoudarzi, Hojjat},  
title = {Investigating the Effect of Work-Family   
Conflict and Work-Family Support on Job Satisfaction and Job Performance of  National Iranian Drilling Company Employees}, 
abstract ={This research was conducted to explain the effect of work-family conflict and work-family support on job satisfaction and job performance in National Iranian Drilling Company&#8217;s employees. In terms of purpose this study is applied and in terms of nature and method it is descriptive-survey. The statistical population of the study includes 5817 employees of the National Iranian Drilling Company. Using Morgan sample size table, 361 peoples were selected as statistical samples by a combination of proportional stratified random sampling and non-probability convenience sampling. For data gathering, standard questionnaires of work-family conflict by Boles et al. (2001), Job performance by Babin et al. (1998), job satisfaction by Hartline and Ferrell (1996), and work-family support by Grzywacz &#38; Marks (2000), with reliability coefficients of Cronbach's alpha 0.84, 0.81, 0.83 and 0.79, were used respectively.&#160; By simple linear regression and structural equation modelling using SPSS software and using Amos technique, the results of data analysis showed that work-family conflict and family-work conflict had a negative effect on job satisfaction and work-family support and family - work support had a positive effect on job satisfaction. Also, job satisfaction effects on job performance.},  
Keywords = {work-family conflict, work-family support, job satisfaction, job performance.},
volume = {9},
Number = {33}, 
pages = {111-132}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-213-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-213-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Kalani, Simin Dokht and Oreizi, Hamid Rez},  
title = {Coping Styles with Job Stress and  Work - Family Conflict}, 
abstract ={The aim of present study has been comparison of work &#8211; family conflict among people with healthy (G: good health, S: sparing) and unhealthy (A: ambitious, B: burnout) patterns of work behavior. Within this scope, 137 employees of Imam Khomeini Oil Refinery Company of Shazand were selected by stratified random sampling and responded to research tools. The instruments were the measure of work&#8211;family conflict and Work-related Behavior and Experience Patterns Questionnaire (AVEM). The data were analyzed using variance analyze. Results showed that among research sample, there are 45 G pattern, 48 S pattern, 21 A pattern A and 23 B pattern and G and S types have lower means of work-family conflict than A and B types. According to the results, the coping style of employees with their work stress and strain, affects their experience of work-family conflict.},  
Keywords = {work – family conflict, work stress, coping style, healthy Patterns of work behavior, unhealthy Patterns of work behavior.},
volume = {9},
Number = {33}, 
pages = {133-156}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-214-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-214-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Vahdati, Hojjat and MousaviNejaz, Seyed Hadi and Hassani, Ali Akbar},  
title = {Examining the Role of Social Capital in Enhancing Human Resources Productivity: Focusing on the Mediator Role of Organizational Culture and Knowledge Management}, 
abstract ={Due to the importance of human resources productivity especially in Iranian Oil&#8217;s National Company and the related companies and its direct relationship with economic growth of the country, the present research deals with investigating the effective factors (social capital, organizational culture and knowledge management) on productivity of Qazvin Oil Products Distribution Company. In this research, population concluded all employees of this company in 1394 where the sample size was estimated as 153 using Cochran formula. Moreover, questionnaire and stratified sampling method were used in order to gather data. To test the model and research hypotheses, structural equation modelling (SEM) was applied using Amos software. Analysis results indicated the direct and significant effect of social capital on organizational culture, knowledge management and human resources productivity. Also, results showed that knowledge management had a positive mediator role in influencing the social capital and organizational culture on human resources productivity as well as the organizational culture could increase the effect of social capital on human resources productivity. Focusing on the different role of the mediator variables of organizational culture and knowledge management in promoting human resources productivity among the case study society members, the current article has been assumed innovative and could play an important role in management by filling the current gap.},  
Keywords = {Social Capital, Organizational Culture, Knowledge Management, Human Resource Productivity.},
volume = {9},
Number = {33}, 
pages = {157-184}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-215-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-215-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Gholami, Beheshteh and Norouzi, Daryoush},  
title = {Virtual Training &#38; Satisfaction of Learning: An Experience In National Iranian Oil Company}, 
abstract ={This research aimed to determine virtual training effect on the satisfaction of National Iranian Oil Company's personnel from training courses. The method of this research has been causal-comparative with two groups of study and comparison. The research sample was including 108 of company&#8217;s personnel participating virtual training courses in 1394 as study group, and the same number which was participated in attendance training courses as comparison group. The sample was selected from 5 provinces of Iran with. The level of personnel satisfaction measured by a researcher made questionnaire. Research data was analyzed by descriptive statistical methods (i.e. mean, standard deviation, charts) and inferential statistical methods (Kolmogorov Smirnoff and Mann-Whitney U test). The results showed that there is a significant difference of level 99% between two groups. Therefore we can conclude that virtual training has a positive effect on employee's satisfaction. Findings showed that three dimension of training satisfaction (course context, presentation method &#38; Feedback) have a positive influence on employee's satisfaction.},  
Keywords = {virtual training, employee's satisfaction, National Iranian Oil Company.},
volume = {9},
Number = {33}, 
pages = {185-212}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-216-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-216-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Poursadegh, naser and Asghari, naser and khodabandeh, saee},  
title = {Introducing a Model Organizational Silence Management at the Social Security Organization}, 
abstract ={Despite various developments in the public sector in recent years, low productivity of government agencies has been the main concern of Iranian policy makers. Employee silence and indifference towards the fate of an organization and its programs and lack of effective understanding between employees and management is an alarm of imminent reduction in organizational performance affecting the whole society at a macro level. This research attempts to provide a model to cover different dimensions of organizational silence. Organizational silence management is an important part of organizational behavior management which directly affects organizational decision-making. Survey research method and structural equation modeling were used and data were collected using a researcher-made questionnaire. The sample consisted of 354 male and female employees of the headquarters of the Iranian Social Security Organization. The questionnaire was designed on the basis of existing theories and using exploratory factor analysis method in 174 items. Using confirmatory factor analysis method, the components were confirmed and the final model was determined after confirmation of the components and sub-components. The final model offers a way to understand organizational silence and helps managers and policy makers reduce this phenomenon in their organization and create the spirit of work and effort among their staff. Managers can utilize this theory to eradicate organizational silence. This theory helps organization theorists achieve testable hypotheses in more comprehensive research.},  
Keywords = {Organizational silence, organizational management, organizational components, Iranian Social Security Organization, data-based theorizing.},
volume = {9},
Number = {34}, 
pages = {3-30}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-197-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-197-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Samari, Narjes Khatoon and Safarzadeh, Hossei},  
title = {Examining of The effect of staff\'s Trust to the managers on Organizational Silence 
(Case: National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company)}, 
abstract ={Reduction of staffs&#8217; trust prevents them sharing their experience and knowledge to solve the issues in an organization and sharing their ideas to have desirable organizational changes. Thus, this research aimed at investigating the relationship between the employees&#8217; trust in managers and organizational silence. Indeed, in this research the effect of employees&#8217; perception of managers&#8217; character that according to Mayer et al, (1995) including: &#160;ability, benevolence and integrity, were studied on defensive and acquiescence silence. To cover this aim, the selected sample included 282 employees of central branch of National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company (N.I.O.P.D.C) and the required data was gathered by a questionnaire and analyzed by Structural Equations Methods. Our study showed that increasing the trust of employees in managers reduces the organizational silence of staff. In addition, if the trust in managers increase, the defensive silence reduces, while acquiescence silence increases. According to the results, managers can improve their recognition of the silence environment in organizations which can lead to the change in behavior and increasing trust in managers resulting in not only creating positive employees' perception of managers&#8217; character but also, the willingness to share knowledge, experience and information. Finally, this can increase organizational performance.},  
Keywords = {Ability - Acquiescence silence – Benevolence - Defensive silence – Integrity -Organizational trust },
volume = {9},
Number = {34}, 
pages = {31-52}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-257-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-257-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Alirahimi, Mohammad Mehdi and Amirkhani, Amirhossein and Rasouli, Rez},  
title = {Designing a Model for Turnover Reduction
In Iranian Oil Terminals Company (IOTC)}, 
abstract ={The purpose of the present study was designing a model for turnover reduction in Iranian Oil Terminals Company (IOTC) to reduce the direct and indirect costs of turnover and to take steps to improve organizational effectiveness. This study was conducted using Delphi method. According the Delphi panel, from the 12 experts related to the subject, was asked to validate the indexes of organizational turnover over the successive rounds of Delphi. The Delphi method was completed after the third round and a favorable consensus was reached. Finally, the conceptual model was designed from Delphi of experts on indigenous indices affecting the reduction of organizational turnover of IOTC&#8217; personnel (selected from the set of factors and indicators from previous researches and projects) and within the framework of the effects of the ethical work climate of DeConinck (2011) and Zhang et al. (2013)&#8217; ethical leadership model.},  
Keywords = {Turnover, Ethical Leadership, Organizational Ethics, Organizational Commitment, Trust},
volume = {9},
Number = {34}, 
pages = {53-82}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-258-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-258-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Rangriz, Hassan and Abdollahi, Bijan and Zeinabadi, Hasanreza and Teimouri, Nazani},  
title = {Studying the influential variables in Designing Pattern of Recruitment and Selection of Human Resources Based on Merit System in Petrochemical Companies}, 
abstract ={The goal of Recruitment and Selection of human resources based on the merit system is to identify the competencies necessary for excellent performance at key posts throughout the organization. Using this Solution, HRM seeks to explore the skills, knowledge and attributes that directly contribute to the organization's success and the configuration of human resources activities around those competencies. So, this research aimed at identifying influential variables in designing pattern of competency based recruitment and selection of human resources in petrochemical companies. Using grounded theory as a qualitative method approach, and after interviewing with panel of experts, eight factors affecting the competency-based recruitment and selection model have been identified. Then for best implementation of the pattern, the systematic pattern of Competency Based Recruitment and Selection of Human resource in petrochemical companies was also provided.},  
Keywords = {Recruitment and Selection - human resources- Influential variables in Recruitment – Competency – Grounded Theory},
volume = {9},
Number = {34}, 
pages = {83-114}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-259-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-259-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Avani, Alireza and Shahab, Mohammadreza and Danaei, Abolfazl},  
title = {Identifying and Ranking Factors Affecting Organizational Agility Based on Outsourcing
(Case study: Semnan Province Gas Company)}, 
abstract ={The best and newest way of survival and success of organizations is their concentrat and focus on organizational agility. Organizational agility is a conscious and comprehensive response to the changing needs of competitive markets and the success of the opportunities that the organization gains. Since recognizing the factors affecting organizational agility can help to obtain the necessary information in turbulent and disorder environments and to capture the advantages of changing trends, the present study seeks to measure organizational agility in Semnan Province Gas Company emphasizing the outsourcing process. Accordingly, the main question of the present research is whether outsourcing is effective on organizational agility in Semnan Province Gas Company? The research method of this study was survey and data gathering tool was a questionnaire. The statistical population of the study was the official personnel of the Gas Company of Semnan province (150 people). Finally, 112 people were selected by stratified random sampling method. Results from Regression analysis showed that 36 percent of changes in dependent variable of organizational agility have been related to the independent variable of organizational outsourcing. Among the four dimensions of outsourcing, two variables were effective on changes of dependent variables. These two variables based on impact severity included: learning aspect and inner processes aspect. Also, it was demonstrated that the other variables including customers and financial variables have no effect on organizational agility.},  
Keywords = {Outsourcing - Organizational Agility - Scrolling - Gas Company-Management},
volume = {9},
Number = {34}, 
pages = {115-144}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-260-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-260-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Darvishi, Maryam and ZiaeeBideh, Alirez},  
title = {Investigating the role of green intellectual capital in developing different type of organizational innovation with regard to the environmental aspect
(Study in oil, gas and petrochemical in Khuzestan province)}, 
abstract ={After increasing of concerns about environment from consumers, governments and communities around the world, manufacturing companies start to develop environmental friendly programs such as development of green products, green brand, green technology and green innovation. Literature review showed that unlike doing many studies regarding the relationship between intellectual capital and innovation in organizations, researchers paid little attention to the environmental aspects of these concepts. So this study aimed to investigate the role of Green intellectual capital in different type of organizational innovation with regard to the environmental aspects. The population of this research is all companies active in the oil, gas and petrochemical industries in Khuzestan province, which includes 38 companies. Also in this study census method is used to gather required data. Finally collected data were analyzed with smartpls software and conceptual model was tested. The final results of this study showed that intellectual capital can enhance all types of environmental innovation including managerial innovation, product innovation, technological innovation and process innovation.},  
Keywords = {green intellectual capital, green managerial innovation, green product innovation, green technological innovation, green process innovation},
volume = {9},
Number = {34}, 
pages = {145-170}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-261-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-261-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {NorouziC.A, Elham and Roshan, Seyed Aligholi and Vafadar, Mil},  
title = {Measuring the Intellectual Capital in Iranian Oil Terminals Company to Identify the Ways of Maximization of its Value}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this study has been to measure the intellectual capital in Iranian Oil Terminals Company (IOTC) to identify the ways of increasing its value. For this purpose the variables of the research were defined by exploring the background research and theoretical framework, and after that the primary model for the research was designed based on the model of Moon and Kym (2006). This research has been done using a descriptive survey method. The sample in this study has been employees of IOTC in Khark, including 214 individuals. The Smart PLS software was used to validate the proposed model. The results of data analysis indicated that the triple aspects of intellectual capital which considered as human capital (HC), structural capital (SC) and relational capital (RC) have had considerable effect on company&#8217;s intellectual capital. The most effective component of intellectual capital was relational capital, human capital and structural capital, respectively.},  
Keywords = {Intellectual capital, Iranian Oil Terminals Company, Human capital, Relational capital, Structural capital.},
volume = {9},
Number = {34}, 
pages = {171-194}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-262-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-262-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Beykzad, Jafar and Rezvan, Seyed Nader and Yavari, Ali},  
title = {Evaluating Psychological Empowerment of Managers and its Effects On their Attitudes toward Strategic Planning in theDepartment of Human Resources Development of National Iranian Oil Company}, 
abstract ={The aim of present study has been to evaluate psychological empowerment of managers and its effects on their attitudes toward strategic planning in the Department of Human Resources Development of National Iranian Oil Company. Hence, psychological empowerment of managers was defined based on Whetten and Cameron&#8217;s (1998) theory in five dimensions: Sense of meaning, Sense of competence, Sense of self-determination, sense of impact, sense of trust and attitude toward strategic planning process was defined based on Dincher, Tat Oglu and&#160; Gloucester&#8217;s (2006) model. In this regard, two main hypotheses and five sub-hypotheses were set. Statistical population of the study (n=542) involved all managers employed in this Department. Sample size of the study was obtained 225 using Cochran relation, being selected by classified random sampling method. The data collection tool was a questionnaire. The reliability of the questionnaire was obtained by using Cronbach's alpha for questions related to psychological empowerment of managers and strategic planning attitudes of 0/889 and 0/909. One group t-test, Colmogrov-Smirnoff, Pearson Corelation and Regression tests were used at inferential level to test the research hypotheses. Results of the study indicated that psychological empowerment of the managers is at above average level. Moreover, findings of the study revealed that three aspects of psychological empowerment of the managers (i.e. sense of competence (0/287), sense of self-determination (0/182) and sense of meaning (0/567)) affect their attitude toward strategic planning. However, two factors of trust and efficacy, from among aspect of psychological empowerment of the managers, on their attitude toward strategic planning was rejected in the Department of Human Resources Development of National Iranian Oil Company.},  
Keywords = {Attitude, NIOC, Psychological Empowerment of Managers, Strategic Planning.},
volume = {9},
Number = {34}, 
pages = {195-214}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-263-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-263-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {AhmadiZahrani, Maryam and Nazemi, Shams-e-din and Rahimnia, – Fariborz and Mortazavi, Saee},  
title = {Uncovering of the mentorship behavior characteristics of managers in Isfahan Oil Refinery Company}, 
abstract ={The concept of &#8220;Mentorship behavior of managers&#8221; is significant in organizational behavior and human resource management literature in which diverse opinions are expressed by many human resource scholars throughout the world. This study was performed with a mixed exploratory approach by using the conventional content analysis in qualitative section. The purpose of this qualitative study was to explore the mentorship behavior characteristics of managers in Isfahan Oil Refinery Company using content analysis&#8217;s systematic design. For this purpose, a semi-structured and in-dept interview with 20 managers of the Company was conducted. The analysis of research data led to a group of initial themes as well as categories through a coding process. Research analysis of semi-structured interviews indicated that mentorship behaviors of the managers under study may be classified under five behaviors including: resonant behavior, perfectionist behavior, self-management behavior, rolling-based behavior and influencing behavior, while each of these behaviors are in turn composed of different concepts. After discovering the category of model presented in the qualitative stage، 80-item questionnaire was designed and regulated to qualitatively validate the extracted model and it was provided for 191 employees under the supervision of senior and middle managers by available sampling method and finally, the validity of the model was qualitatively verified.},  
Keywords = {The mentorship behavior characteristics, mentoring, conventional approach, Isfahan Oil Refinery Company},
volume = {9},
Number = {35}, 
pages = {3-32}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-304-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-304-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Aghadavood, Seyed Rasool},  
title = {Studying the Effects of Employees Happiness Management System on Employees\' Performance Based On Steers\' Model (Case: Isfahan Branch Gas Company)}, 
abstract ={According to the increasing changes and developments in organizations, the managers are seeking to improve the staff performance to a large degree. In this way, they want to increase the functionality of organization production. Rise of happiness among staff which is a field of study in psychology and human resource management, has recently become important for managers and employees. Happiness in workplace comes when a person uses his abilities and talents to achieve his goals. The purpose of this research is to answer the question of whether employees' happiness affects their job performance. In this research, Richard M. Steers' model has been used. The research method is descriptive-correlation, practical in terms of nature, and sectional in terms of time period. The statistical population of the study consisted of employees of Isfahan's gas company with 800 employees and a sample selection of 256 people based on the sample size formula and random stratified sampling method. The information gathering method included library studies and a researcher-made questionnaire. The validity of questionnaire was determined by the experts and the reliability of the research tool was calculated using Cronbach's alpha coefficient (0.82). Finally, all ten hypotheses related to the effect of happiness components on performance have been confirmed. In rating of variables, learning factor and job interest had the highest mean with 6.38 and 6.9, respectively.},  
Keywords = {happiness, learning, job desire, organizational performance, organizational justice, Gas Company},
volume = {9},
Number = {35}, 
pages = {33-58}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-305-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-305-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Mahdad, Ali and Adibi, Zahra and Saffari, Soroosh},  
title = {Predicting of Self – Efficacy through Perceived Organizational Support and Self – Esteem (Case: Isfahan province Gas Company)}, 
abstract ={Research in relation of self-efficacy and the identification of factors affecting it, has been of interest to researchers due to its role and its impact on many behavioral variables in the workplace. Accordingly, this research carried out with the aim of predicting self &#8211; efficacy through perceived organizational support and self &#8211; esteem. Research method was descriptive-correlational and statistical population was all employees of Isfahan province Gas Company. Using convenience sampling, 248 subjects were selected. &#160;They were assessed by perceived organizational support questionnaire (Eisenberger et al., 1986), self - esteem questionnaire (Rosenberg, 1965) and self - efficacy questionnaire (Sheerer &#38; Maddux, 1982). Data were analyzed by use of Pearson correlation coefficient and stepwise regression analysis. Results showed that there was significant relationship between Perceived organizational support and self - efficacy (p&#60;0.01), perceived organizational support and self - esteem (p&#60;0.01), self - esteem and self - efficacy (p&#60;0.01). Moreover results of stepwise regression analysis showed that there were multiple relationship between perceived organizational support, self &#8211; efficacy and self &#8211; esteem (p&#60;0.01) and perceived organizational support and self &#8211;esteem could predict 30% of self &#8211; efficacy&#8217; variances. According to these findings, for increasing employees&#8217; self &#8211; efficacy in organizations, we should pay more attention to employees&#8217; self &#8211; esteem and organizational support.},  
Keywords = {Perceived organizational support, self - efficacy, self- esteem, Gas Company},
volume = {9},
Number = {35}, 
pages = {59-82}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-306-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-306-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {HassanzadehSamarin, Toraj and Sahranavard, Alirez},  
title = {Investigating the Mediating Role of Organizational Maturity on the Impact of Leadership Styles on Employee Organizational Commitment (Case: Assaluyeh Petrochemical Complex)}, 
abstract ={The human resources domain has interactions and communications with different functional and operational areas in organizations and can therefore have a significant impact on the performance of organizations and the achievement of organizational goals. Therefore, organizations need effective and efficient managers and employees in order to achieve their goals for comprehensive growth and development. In this research, we intend to investigate the mediating role of organizational maturity on the impact of leadership styles on employees' organizational commitment in Assaluyeh Petrochemical Complex. By studying the related literature in the areas of research, we considered the Avolio and Bass (2004) model (Transformational and Transactional Leadership Styles) in order to determine the leadership style of managers ; and the Allen &#38; Meyer (1990) organizational commitment pattern (emotional commitment, continuous commitment, normative commitment) as a basis for assessing the status of Organizational commitment of staff ; and we applied the human resource capability model (P-CMM) to determine the level of employees' organizational maturity. Data was analyzed using Smart-PLS software. The results showed that there is a significant relationship between leadership style of managers with organizational commitment of employees in Assaluyeh petrochemical complex. Also, organizational maturity has a mediator role in the impact of leadership styles on organizational commitment of employees in Assaluyeh Petrochemical Complex.},  
Keywords = {Organizational Maturity, Transformational Leadership Styles, Transactional Leadership Style , Organizational Commitment , Assaluyeh Petrochemical Complex},
volume = {9},
Number = {35}, 
pages = {83-104}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-307-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-307-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Amirghodsi, Sirous and BonyadiNaeini, Ali},  
title = {Investigating the relationship between emotional intelligence, organizational commitment and job satisfaction of employees with the demographic factors (case: Iranian Central Oil Fields Company (ICOFC))}, 
abstract ={The research is going to compare the levels of emotional intelligence, organizational commitment and job satisfaction of employees of Iranian Central Oil Fields Company (I. C. O. F. C) according to different demographic factors such as age, job experience, education, organizational position, and gender. Research type is applied-developing and on the other hand, is consumed as a descriptive-survey. The population of the research was Iranian Central Oil Fields Company employees and acording to the Morgan table, 359 employees randomly have been selected and standardized questionnaires were distributed among them. The results indicated that emotional intelligence and job satisfaction have significant differences while it comes to age, job experience, organization position and gender. In addition, organizational commitment did'nt reach desired score, but it showed magnificent differences considering age, job experience, education and position. Based on findings, by increasing age, organizational position and job experience the emotional intelligence of the employees have improved. Also, by promoting their positions, job satisfaction and organizational commitment has increased. On the other hand, while age and experience have increased an increase in job satisfaction was detected. Emotional intelligence and Job satisfaction of the male employees have been more than those of female employees. Results show comparing to those with higher education, people who have diploma or associate's degree show more commitment to the organization.},  
Keywords = {emotional intelligence, organizational commitment, job satisfaction, demographic factors.},
volume = {9},
Number = {35}, 
pages = {105-134}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-308-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-308-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {HajiMohammadaliJahromi, Meghdad and Kharazinia, Mohammadali},  
title = {Studying the institutionalization of HSE culture among the Staff of Tehran Gas Company}, 
abstract ={In recent years, there have been many advances in the Iranian gas company on issues related to safety, health and environment (HSE), but there has not been a proper decision-making structure, and decentralization and reworking have been carried out. The main objective of this study was to investigate the institutionalization of the safety, health and environment culture among the staff of the Tehran Gas Company. The research carried out in this paper is a descriptive-survey research based on the the field research. The statistical population of the research was the staff of the staff of Tehran Gas Company consisting of 775 people. At first, by using the exploratory factor analysis method and through the optimization of the main axes and the rotation of the varimix, dimensions of the HSE culture were identified among the staff of the Tehran Gas Company including eight factors. Then the ranking of HSE culture was computed from the highest to the lowest based on the results of Friedman's analysis: the status of supervisors and managers; the managerial commitment; the staff's ability; the staff's attitude towards the HSE culture; the status of the communication; the status of employee participation; the reporting and priority of safety, health and environment. Finally, by using the T-test, the institutionalization of each dimension of the culture was investigated. The results showed that all of these dimensions were institutionalized, except for the ability of employees in the Tehran Gas Company.},  
Keywords = {HSE culture- Staff of the Gas Company-institutionalization of HSE culture},
volume = {9},
Number = {35}, 
pages = {135-156}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-309-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-309-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {kamalipoor, Mahsa and Safari, Ali and Esmaelian, Majid and Bahramikiya, Ghasem},  
title = {Ranking and Comparing Factors Affecting Entrepreneurial Behavior by Using Multi-Dimensional Scaling (Case: Parsian Gas Refinery Company)}, 
abstract ={Considering the different dimensions of entrepreneurial behavior in organizations, it can help incresing productivity and growth that is one of the main goals of any organization and lead to creative and innovative thinking about value creation in the organization. In this regard, the present research was conducted with the purpose of ranking and comparing the factors which affect organizational entrepreneurial behavior in Parsian Gas Refinery Company&#8217;s deputy offices and independent units. This research has been considered applied in terms of aim and descriptive survey in terms of design. The population of interest was comprised of the managers, supervisors, and staff members of Parsian Gas Refinery Company, adding up to 385 people, of whom 169 were selected as the sample of the study. The data collection tool was a researcher-made questionnaire, which was administered using stratified sampling method. The results obtained through investigating the hypotheses by means of multi-dimensional scaling showed that independent units and Engineering Deputy Office act similarly in terms of factors affecting entrepreneurial behavior. Operations Deputy Office acts quite differently from independent units and Engineering Deputy Office in this regard. In addition, Administrative and Support Deputy Office also acts differently from Operations Deputy Office as well as independent units and Engineering Deputy Office. &#160;Finally, we have concluded with presenting the results of ranking deputy offices and independent units based on factors affecting entrepreneurial behavior.},  
Keywords = {Entrepreneurial Behavior, Organizational Entrepreneurship, Entrepreneurial Atmosphere, Networking Behavior, Organizational Structure.},
volume = {9},
Number = {35}, 
pages = {157-186}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-310-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-310-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {BoroomandKakhaki, Ahmad and Akhavan, Amirnaser},  
title = {Challenges and Requirements of Knowledge Management Development at National Petrochemical Company (horizon of 1404)}, 
abstract ={The intense of competitiveness in the business environments and its serious changes have made knowledge management a soloution for rescuing the organizational capital. Knowledge management in terms of its fundamental importance is required to be developed. The purpose of this research was to investigate the future of knowledge management and extract the challenges of the National Petrochemical Company in order to achieve the desired future of KM by using field research . In this way, research tools such as interviews and questionnaires as well as library studies have been used. This step has been achieved by measuring the current adaptability of the company and analyzing its gap with the primitive consistent status of &#34;Value-based KM&#34;. At the end, solutions were proposed in two areas: culture and organizational structure. These solutions emphasize the strengthening of organizational social awareness as well as enhancement of human resources capabilities for recording and promoting value-added knowledge (in two industrial and organizational categories).},  
Keywords = {Challenges- Future-Knowledge Management Development- Petrochemical Industry.},
volume = {9},
Number = {35}, 
pages = {187-212}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-311-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-311-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Dianat, Mohammad and Seyedjavadin, Seyed Reza and Shahhoseini, Mohammad Ali},  
title = {Designing Competency Model for Project Managers in Petroleum Industry}, 
abstract ={Due to rapid environmental changes and the large scope of project activities in the petroleum industry, project management is of particular importance. One of the essential and important factors for the success of projects is to focus on the behavioral characteristics, and in other words, the competencies of project managers. In this regard, designing a model of project managers' competencies in the petroleum industry of Iran has been considered in this research. The research methodology is an applied method, based on the goals, and is a mixed method (qualitative-quantitative), regarding to the collecting data method. In the qualitative part, the statistical population included all project managers, managers Senior, and Minister's deputy in the Petroleum industry, 14 of them were selected through purposeful sampling and using snowball technique as a statistical sample of the study. The data collection tool was a deep interviewing in qualitative part. Content analysis was used to analyze the interview data. The reliability of the qualitative part considerd by responder's review. In the quantitative part of the research, the statistical population of the study was composed of all poject managers working in the Iran Petroleum. of the oil industry project that had enough experience in the field. Among them 170 persons were selected randomly as a research sample. The data collection tool was a researcher-made questionnaire in the quantitative part. The results of quantitative analysis led to the production of 394 key concepts that were categorized 152 items in 15 main components. Finally, these main key categories were classified into six key items: 1. background factors, 2. environmental faualctors, 3. causal factors, 4. pivotal phenomenon 5.Strategies, and 6. achievements and outcomes. The quantitative results showed that the amount The fitness index for the whole model was calculated as 60percent, which indicates that the overall fitness of the model is acceptable.},  
Keywords = { Designing – Competency Model - Project Management- Petroleum Industry},
volume = {9},
Number = {36}, 
pages = {3-40}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-385-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-385-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {ParsaZiabari, Leila and Etebarian, Akbar and HadiPeykani, Mehraban and ZamaniMoghadam, Afsaneh},  
title = {The Formulation of Retirement Management Model 
(Case:Refah Kargaran Bank)}, 
abstract ={&#160;The aim of this research was to develop a retirement management model in the Workers' Refah Bank. In terms of its purpose, the method is a combination of the phenomenological method in the quantitative part and descriptive-correlation method, in the quantitative part of research. The statistical population of the research in the qualitative section has been 39 people including: close-to-retirement (15 people), during retirement (8 people) and retirees (16 people). Snowball method has been used until reaching saturation of information. The population of research in the quantitative section for close to retirement stage was 115, for retirement stage, 30 persons and for after retirement stage was 1175 people. The sample size was 92, 28 and 285, respectively, based on random sampling for each of these three groups. The data collection tool was semi-structured interview in the qualitative part and the questionnaire, in the quantitative part of research. Validity of the questionnaires was reviewed by using content validity-contextual validity as well as structural validity. The reliability of the questionnaires was calculated through Cronbach's alpha, which was calculated for all three questionnaires above 0.8 which indicates their good reliability. &#160;In order to analyze the data in the qualitative section, the 7-step quantitative method of Colaizzi was used and in the quantitative part, statistical tests such as factor analysis, mean and variance test, cross-sectional test and model quality test were used. Finally, dimensions and components of our model were identified and confirmed for close-to-retirement (concerns, expectations, and expectations) during retirement (concerns, needs and motives, expectations) and for after-retirement (challenges, expectations, personal strategies). &#160;},  
Keywords = {Retirement - close-to-retirement - during retirement – after-retirement – phenomenology – Colaizzi model},
volume = {9},
Number = {36}, 
pages = {41-74}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-394-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-394-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Rahimian, Hamid and abspour, Abbas and Taheri, Mortaza and Najafi, Ali},  
title = {Investigating and Analysing Instructional Design and Workplace Learning Models and Selection of Adaptive Model to Optimize Organizational Training in Petrochemical Industry}, 
abstract ={The present research aimed to analyze instructional design,workplace learning, and selecting the optimum model of learning for human resources training in petrochemical industry.The previous roles have become faint and new opportunities have appeared in petrochemical industry by starting the process of privatization and changing the nature of the company from holding to a governance and development organization. So, the main questions in this study were: what is the similarity among the world popular models about instructional design and workplace learning models? What is the most adaptive model about training and workplace learning in petrochemical industry? Therefore, a qualitative meta-synthesis approach has been used to reply these questions. This process was conducted in two steps. Its first step was conducted by Sandelowski and Barroso method in 2007. The second step was conducted by analysis of documents, observation, and experts' views using Maxqda software. Finally, the related adaptive model to the characteristics of petrochemical industry was offered including five dimentions of: performance analysis, performance design, performance development, performance implementation, and performance monitoring which were adopted from 70:20:10, Mager and human performance technology models. Regarding the dominant systematic approach in instructional design and workplace learning model, and considering of performance conception in all designing processes, it seems that the present study,as the first study in this field, can have an effective role in organizational training.t &#160;},  
Keywords = { instructional design - workplace learning - Meta-synthesis- 70:20:10 Guide- Mager Model- human performance technology model},
volume = {9},
Number = {36}, 
pages = {75-102}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-386-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-386-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {joudzadeh, Mahta and Yaghoubi, Nour mohammad and Roshan, Seyed Aliqoli and Nadaf, Mehdi},  
title = {Providing a Native Framework for the Culture of Productivity in the National Company Southern oil fields}, 
abstract ={Productivity is the key indicator of the performance of organizations at each level, which is considered a mental concept. By changing the patterns of thought, one could hope to improve productivity and change individual and organizational performance. A closer look at what common values, attitudes, norms, and beliefs among members of the organization will make everyone consistently work towards the goals of the organization intelligently. This is of particular importance in the oil industry, which is the economic reliance of our country. This research aims to provide a framework for the native culture of productivity, with a qualitative research approach. For this purpose, after studying the history of research and performing semi-structured interviews through targeted sampling among the experts of the National Iranian South oilfields Company and University, the dimensions of the native framework of the culture of productivity were determined through content analysis of directional and tabular content. Finally, a coherent framework based on organizational values ​​(including the value of a tool that includes &#34;ethical or interpersonal values ​​and merit values ​​or social adequacy&#34; and ultimate values ​​that includes &#34;individual values ​​and social values ​​or interactions Interpersonal &#34;) has been constructed. Also, the attitude (including beliefs, emotional dimension and behavioral dimension), norms (including formal norms (law), informal norms (habits) and social norms (customs)) as well as symbols (including stories, customs, physical symbols and Language) were presented},  
Keywords = {Architecture- Culture- Productivity- Content Analysis- National Oil Company of Southern Oilfields },
volume = {9},
Number = {36}, 
pages = {103-136}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-387-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-387-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Khalili, Karam},  
title = {Effect of Toxic Leadership on Social Loafing with Mediating Role of Employee\' Soldiering (Case: Ilam Petrochemical Company)}, 
abstract ={The main purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of toxicity leadership style on social loafing the role of mediation in employees&#160;soldiering&#160;.&#160;This research is&#160;an applied research,&#160;based on the purpose of the research and is&#160;a&#160;field research,&#160;based on the nature of the method.&#160;The statistical population of this research includes employees of Ilam Petrochemical Company, which are 600 people. For example, using Morgan table, 234 people were selected based on simple random sampling.&#160;The data collection tool was a standard questionnaire whose validity was confirmed by experts and confirmed by Cronbach's alpha coefficient. For data analysis, Liserl software has been used.The results show that the&#160;toxicity&#160;leadership style has a positive and significant effect on social&#160;loafing&#160;and&#160;employees'&#160;soldiering. Also,&#160;employees'&#160;soldiering&#160;has a positive and significant impact on employees' social&#160;loafing.},  
Keywords = {Toxic Leadership- Social loafing-Employee Soldiering},
volume = {9},
Number = {36}, 
pages = {137-158}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-395-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-395-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Habibi, Masoomeh and Narimani, Mehdi},  
title = {Investigating the Relationship Between Organizational Trust and Employees’ Attitudes With Regard to the Mediating Role of the
Psychological Contract}, 
abstract ={Awareness of employees’ attitudes has always been used as one of the important management tools in organizations. Because, employees’ attitudes can affect their behavior in the workplace. Therefore, it's important to understand what factors can affect it. In this regard, due to the increasing level of employees' maturity in many organizations and becoming knowledge-based, two factors of organizational trust and psychological contracts in this research have been considered and their relationship with employees’ attitudes has been studied. In this process, by analyzing the theoretical foundations and the relationship between the factors and components constituting each of the variables studied, the conceptual model of the research has been extracted and tested in one of the companies of the National Iranian Oil Company. The research method used in this research has been descriptive correlational. The results indicate a positive and significant relationship between the three variables of organizational trust, psychological contracts and occupational attitudes with each other. Also, the mediating role of psychological contract in the relationship between organizational trust and job attitudes was also confirmed},  
Keywords = { organizational trust- employees’ attitudes- psychological contract.

},
volume = {9},
Number = {36}, 
pages = {159-188}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-397-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-397-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Mokhtari, Ebrahim},  
title = {Exanimating the relationship between organizational culture, organizational silence and Organizational citizenship behavior
(Case: Research Institute of Petroleum Industry)}, 
abstract ={This study aimed to&#160;investigate the relationship&#160;between&#160;organizational culture&#160;and organizational&#160;silence&#160;organizational citizenship behavior.&#160;This research is applied in terms of the purpose and&#160;is a survey, based on&#160;data collection methods,&#160;using&#160;structural&#160;equation modeling.&#160;Statistical population included all&#160;the&#160;staff&#160;in Research Institute of Petroleum Industry.&#160;According to the Morgan's table samples were chosen by random sampling method and finally&#160;272&#160;questionnaires&#160;were distributed and analyzed.&#160;In order to collect data, it has been used Denison's organizational culture questionnaire ,&#160;Vandain's organizational Silence questionnaire and Organ's questionnaire for&#160;organizational citizenship behavior&#160;,&#160;based on five point scales (from very high to very little). ). Face and content validity have been used to evaluate questionnaires Validity. Also, Cronbach's alpha was used to establish the reliability of instruments،&#160;0.89،&#160;0.76 and 0.82 for each questionnaire, respectively. Data was analyzed by&#160;using the&#160;statistical softwares&#160;SPSS and LISREL.&#160;Results showed that there is direct and meaningful relationship between Organizational Culture with Organizational Silence and&#160;organizational citizenship behavior.&#160;Also,&#160;there is&#160;negative&#160;and meaningful&#160;relationship between&#160;organizational&#160;silence&#160;and organizational citizenship behavior.},  
Keywords = {Organizational Culture - Organizational Silence - Silence employees - organizational citizenship behavior},
volume = {9},
Number = {36}, 
pages = {189-212}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-396-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-396-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Hosseini, Mirza Hassan and Keshavarz, - Elham},  
title = {Identifying and ranking of factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship with the aim of corporate performance improvement using Fuzzy AHP technique (Case: Coil manufacturing industry.)}, 
abstract ={Todays, under the competitive conditions, organizational entrepreneurship can play an important role in the success of organizations and make them differentiate from others. Therefore, gaining of knowledge about the factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship is of particular importance. Accordingly, the purpose of this research was to identify and rank the factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship and determine their importance and priority in order to improve the company's performance. For this purpose, after studying the theoretical foundations and research background in this area, the factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship that help improve company performance were identified in three groups: structural, background and behavioral factors. In the next step, the priority and importance of each of these factors was evaluated using the fuzzy hierarchical process analysis technique and by a survey of experts from active and top companies in the field of steel industry. The results indicated that the most important factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship with the aim of improving and enhancing the company's performance were: structural factors, underlying factors and then behavioral factors. Among the structural factors, the most important factors were: structure of entrepreneurial organization, decision making and control, reward system. On the other hand, political factors / government, infrastructures, communications, access to resources were identified as the most important underlying factors. Finally, the most important behavioral factors were organizational culture, management support, riskiness, managerial characteristics, employee characteristics},  
Keywords = {Entrepreneurship - organizational entrepreneurship - corporate performance - FAHP},
volume = {9},
Number = {36}, 
pages = {213-242}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-388-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-388-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2018}  
}

