<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>7</volume>
<number>27</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی ارتباط بین سرمایه اجتماعی و سلامت سازمانی در کارکنان ستاد شرکت ملی نفت ایران</title_fa>
	<title>Studying the Relationship Between Social Capital and Organizational Health of Employees of N.I.O.C</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;h2 dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;line-height:normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;هدف از تحقیق حاضر بررسی ارتباط بین سرمایه اجتماعی با سلامت سازمانی در کارکنان شرکت ملی نفت ایران می باشد. روش تحقیق حاضر توصیفی پیمایشی و از نوع همبستگی است. جامعه آماری، کارکنان شرکت ملی نفت ایران شاغل در شهر تهران است که270 نفر از آنان از طریق فرمول کوکران به عنوان نمونه انتخاب شده و با روش نمونه گیری طبقه ای که به صورت تصادفی صورت گرفت، مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته اند. ابزار گردآوری اطلاعات پرسشنامه سلامت سازمانی هوی و فیلدمن و پرسشنامه سرمایه اجتماعی هوف و هایسمن می باشد. توصیف داده&#8204;ها با استفاده از آماره&#8204;های توصیفی و شاخص های مرکزی، میانگین و انحراف معیار صورت گرفته و از آزمون همبستگی پیرسون به منظور سنجش فرضیات استفاده شد. نتایج نشان می دهد بین سرمایه اجتماعی با سلامت سازمانی کارکنان شرکت ملی نفت ایران شاغل در ستاد تهران رابطه مثبت و معناداری وجود دارد. پیشنهاد می گردد سیاست گذاران و برنامه ریزان در سازمانها به منظور بهبود سلامت سازمانی در سازمان شان به مقوله سرمایه اجتماعی توجه ویژه ای داشته باشند.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:51.75pt;text-indent:-51.75pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>The aim of this study is to investigate the relationship between social capital and organizational health of the National Iranian Oil Company's employees. The method was descriptive survey and of the correlation type. The statistical population was the National Iranian Oil Company employees in Tehran that 270 of them were selected through Cochran's formula as the sample and they were studied using a simple random sampling method. Data collection tools were Hoy and Feldman organizational health questionnaire (1996) and Heisman and Hoff social capital questionnaire (2009). Validity of the questionnaires was confirmed through the content validity by the judgment of the elite and review of the literature and reliability was calculated and approved through Cronbach's alpha. In this study, description of data was done using descriptive statistics and central indices, average and standard deviation and the Pearson correlation test and regression were used to assess hypotheses. The results showed that there is a significant positive relationship between social capital and organizational health of employees at the National Iranian Oil Company. It is recommended that policymakers and planners in organizations have special attention to the issue of social capital to improve organizational health.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa> سرمایه اجتماعی , سلامت سازمانی , ستاد شرکت ملی نفت , پرسشنامه هوی و فیلدمن</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Social Capital Organizational Health NIOC Hoy and Feldman</keyword>
	<start_page>123</start_page>
	<end_page>141</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-25-56&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohsen </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Karami </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کرمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002043</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002043</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد مرکزی تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name> Saeed </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Shafiee </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سعید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>شفیعی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>saaeed25@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002044</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002044</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد مرکزی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
