<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <ArticleSet>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2020</Year>
				<Month>2</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The maturity of human capital in superior manufacturing organizations and its strategic implications</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>3</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>32</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Javadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>moh.javadi@isu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Adel</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>azar</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>azara@modares.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Asadollah</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ganjali</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>ganjali@isu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The maturity of Human capital, its impact on performance and organization strategy, and how to assess this concept has been concerned by researchers in recent decades. Therefore, the present study aimed to assess the level of human capital maturity in Iran's top 80 manufacturing organizations and to identify the strategic implications for it. For this purpose, Confirmatory Factor Analysis Method, Surveying through the human capital maturity questionnaire and network analysis method has been used. The results of the first method validated the questionnaire's variables, and in a sample of 80 among human resource managers in sample organizations, the questionnaire assessed the level of the human capital maturity as low (the score was almost 54) and finally based on the opinions of 10 human resource experts, the network analysis method prioritized factors affecting human capital maturity in this way: 1-The capacity of Learning capacity, 2-workforce optimization, 3-Knowledge accessibility, 4-Employee engagement, 5-Leadership practices. At last, based on opinions of 10 HRM and strategic management experts, and scores of these organizations, the defensive strategy was suggested based on typology of strategies according miles and snow.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Human Capital, Human Capital Maturity, Human Capital Maturity Measure, Miles and Snow Strategy, Human Resources Management, Strategic Management</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-810-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-810-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2020</Year>
				<Month>2</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Modeling the Executive Coaching Role of Directors</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>33</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>60</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Jahangiri</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>a.jahangiri@imps.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mehdi</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Zoghi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>mahdiizoghi@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hasan</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Rangriz</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>rangriz@khu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Abdolhamid</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Shams</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>abh.shams@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>In recent years, many leading companies have found that managers and supervisors play a vital role in promoting human resource goals and programs, and have been entrusted with the development and training of employees to their executives. Today, one of the roles assigned to managers to implement this responsibility, is coaching. Therefore, modeling the executive coaching role of directors in Iran oil industry was the main objective of this qualitative research which was done based on grounded theory approach. The data collection tool was semi-structured interviews. Sixteen oil industry and academic experts were interviewed to collect information using purposeful sampling and snowball sampling. Data was gathered in three stages: open coding, axial coding and selective coding. The findings of the present study represented 11 main categories, 27 sub categories and 71 concepts for executive coaching role of directors.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Coaching, Executive Coaching, Executive Coaching Role, Oil Industry, Grounded Theory</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-811-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-811-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2020</Year>
				<Month>2</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Developing a causal model for organizational factors effecting on knowledge sharing (Case: The National Iranian South Oil Company)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>61</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>92</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ardalan</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Feili</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Abass</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Sabet</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Dr. sabeT@apadana.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Banafsheh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Rastegarfar</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Sima</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Alipour</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>&#160;
The existence of transformative leaders who are able to create an atmosphere of trust and rearrange the organizational culture in order to foster organizational citizenship behaviors which in turn can encourage the employees to willingly share knowledge within the organization is valuable in any organization. The purpose of the present study was to investigate the role of transformational leadership in knowledge sharing among the employees of the National Iranian South Oil Company with a mediating role of organizational trust and organizational citizen behavior. The research method was descriptive-correlational. The statistical population of this research was composed of 1500 people who were the staff of the organization. 306 employees were chosen as the statistical sample using the Cochran formula. A standard questionnaire was used to collect the data. The reliability of the questionnaire was checked and verified using Cronbach's alpha coefficient. The data was analyzed using SPSS-25 software for the inferential part and LISREL8.8 software was used to fit the path. The results of the research showed that organizational trust and organizational citizenship behavior played a mediating role in transformational leadership relationships and knowledge sharing.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Transformational Leadership, Organizational Citizen Behavior, Organizational Trust, Knowledge Sharing</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-812-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-812-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2020</Year>
				<Month>2</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Developing a Model for theAlignment of Strategies of HRM with Macro-level Strageies in  National Iranian Oil Company</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>93</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>126</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammadali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Shahhoseini</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>shahhoseini@ut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Haghighi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>mhaghighi@ut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Sara</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Moazen</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>s.moazen@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to develop a model of alignment of HR strategies with macro-level strategies. The population of the research were directors and human resources experts of the National Iranian Oil Company and its subsidiaries. The sample needed for qualitative interviews to the extent of theoretical saturation and collected through a targeted judgment sampling of 14 people. Data analysis was done with grounded theory. Among the 272 meaningful statements obtained from the interviews, 329 codes were extracted, eliminating repetitive cases of 188 subcategories and 33 axial categories, including 4 categories of causal conditions, 6 categories of underlying conditions, 7 categories of strategies, 5 categories of intervening conditions, 5 categories of alignment phenomenon, and 6 categories of the alignment outcomes. It was found that the alignment of human resources strategies with the macro strategies of the National Iranian Oil Company included the strategic alignment from top to bottom, from bottom to top, internal alignment, organizational alignment, environmental alignment, and alignment between the company's human resources sub-systems with subsidiaries.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Human resource management, HRM strategies, Macro level strategy, Strategic alignment</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-813-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-813-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2020</Year>
				<Month>2</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Moderator Role of Social Capital in Knowledge Management and Organizational Performance Relationship</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>127</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>154</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Payam</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Shojaei</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>pshojaei@shirazu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Moslem</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Bagheri</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>bagherimoslem@shirazu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Mehrdad.kiani@stu.yazd.ac</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Zahra</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mohit Ghiri</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>zahra.mohit69@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to investigate the role of social capital mediation in the relationship between knowledge management and organizational performance. This research is a descriptive-correlational study. The statistical population of this study was the employees of Agharan and Dalan Natural Gas Company. According to Krejcie and Morgan table, 100 people were randomly selected and the research questionnaire has been distributed among them.The findings indicated that knowledge management has a positive and significant effect on social capital and organizational performance, with a coefficient of 0.633 and 0.341, respectively, while the role of the component of knowledge application (0.916) and sharing Knowledge (0.886) is more noticable. Also, the positive and significant effects of social capital on organizational performance were confirmed by a coefficient of 0.447. Among the components of social capital, the component of relationships (0.902), networks (0.877) and cooperation (0.838) have shown the major role. Finally, knowledge management by confirming the mediating role of social capital has shown an indirect, positive and significant effect (0.300) on organizational performance.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Knowledge Management (KM) - Social Capital (SC) - Organizational Performance - Structural Equations Modeling (SEM)</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-814-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-814-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2020</Year>
				<Month>2</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>A New Approach to Deploying Knowledge Management System Based on Organizational Infrastructure Variables
in Human Resources Management of Iranian Oil Industry</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>155</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>178</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Reza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Moeini Jazaniz</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Moeini1354@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ahmad Reza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Kasraee</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Kasrai49@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Tahmoures</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Sohrabi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Dr.tsohrabi@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ahmad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Aslizadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Aslizadeha@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Purpose of this research was to structure the problem of establishing a knowledge management system in Oil industry using a combination of factor analysis and DEMATEL approach to identifying the effective factors in the form of causal relationships to understand planners from the problem position and visualization of structures a complex relationship between factors. Firstly, the organizational infrastructure affecting the establishment of the knowledge management system using exploratory factor analysis with participation of the Deputy Directorate for Development and Human Capital Management through a questionnaire with a statistical population of 263 people and a sample of 158 were gathered. Based on findings, three main factors including culture, human resources and organizational structure and 13 infrastructures influencing were identified. Then, with the participation of the decision makers using the DEMATEL technique, the map of the effect of the relationship between the effective organizational infrastructure and the causal relationship diagram was extracted.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Implementation of knowledge management system, Organizational infrastructure, Problem Structuring Method, DEMATEL</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-815-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-815-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2020</Year>
				<Month>2</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Interpretative-Structural Modeling of Outsourcing Human Resources in Maroon Petrochemical Company</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>179</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>210</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyed Najmeddin</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mousavi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>mousavi.na@lu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Razieh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Feli</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Feli.ra@fc.lu.ac.ir- raziehfeli@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The research purpose was to identifying a model of factors affecting human resource outsourcing (HRO) in Maroon Petrochemical Company. The research is considered practical in terms of purpose and descriptive-exploratory based on mixed method, in terms of data collection. The statistical population was experts and experts of Maroon petrochemical company in the field of human resources. The number of these people was reported 15. For data analysis, interpretive-structural modeling was used. The results showed that the variables of increasing flexibility, decreasing organizational costs and improving creativity have an independent role in the model and on the intermediary and dependent variables of the model have a significant effect. The dependent variables of the model were: decrease of technology investment, gaining the good image and increasing security, in addition to the independent variables mentioned, influenced by the intermediary variables including factors product quality development, increasing the change need, increasing technological changes and the use of new technology, focusing more on core activities, achieving new capabilities, improving operational performance, using educational services, acquiring new experiences, providing new services, improving management, risk management and Agility organization.&#160;</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Human resources outsourcing, outsourcing drivers, interpretive- Structural modeling, Maroon Petrochemical Company.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-816-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-816-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2020</Year>
				<Month>2</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Discovering the Dimensions of Emotional Climate of Organization 
in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>211</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>240</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad Hossein</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Dehnavi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>mh.dehnavi@yahoo.com.</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Shirazi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>a-shirazi@um.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Shamsoddin</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Nazemi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>nazemi_shm@um.ac.ir.</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Fariborz</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Rahimnia</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>r-nia@um.ac.ir.</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>This study aimed to explore the dimensions of emotional climate of organization in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company (NIOPDC). The statistical population consisted of all employees of NIOPDC in Khorasan Razavi District, and the sample was selected using purposeful sampling method up to the theoretical saturation with the sampling adequacy of 19 people. Data were collected through semi - structured interviews, and the analysis was done by qualitative content analysis. The findings showed that the dimensions of emotional climate of organization can be grouped into eight main dimensions including organizational hope climate, organizational trust climate, organizational fear climate, organizational anger climate, organizational love climate, organizational surprise climate, organizational happiness climate, and organizational security climate. Understanding these dimensions provides the basis for managing the emotional climate of organization in line with organizational goals.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Organizational climate, emotional climate of organization, qualitative content analysis, emotions.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-817-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-817-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2020</Year>
				<Month>2</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>QFD Modeling of Expectations and Priorities of National Oil Company Human Resources (Four Matrix)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>241</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>262</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hossein</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Kalantar</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>kalantar_hossein@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Zainul Abedin</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Amini</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Drsajadamini@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ehsan</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Sadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>E.sadeh@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>&#160;The main purpose of this study was to provide a model for the expectations and priorities of human resources in National Iranian Oil Company by QFD for quality engineering of welfare system. The research method was qualitative and quantitative. At first, welfare indices were extracted from Delphi method and interviews with experts (n = 15) and then these indices were matched with the needs of human resources (n = 208) as a questionnaire. In the present study, the statistical sample in the qualitative section were the experts of the Oil Company's welfare department whose issues, such as time, availability of the interviewees, and the extent of their cooperation were considered. 15 people. After preparing the final questionnaire of expert indices in the quantitative part the number of questionnaires was obtained by Cochran formula. Reliability was confirmed using Cronbach's alpha of greater than 0.7 and validity test was performed by examining factor loadings and AVE scores. To ensure the quality of the home matrix (HOQ), technical requirements were created and the welfare service quality plans were processed to build the quality home matrix. In the final model it was found that the usability of internet services (GPS, virtual pages, online content, online information, etc.) is one of the key human resource expectations that influences other expectations. Also, the 18 components, depending on the type of relationship in their respective categories, have a positive or negative (strong and medium) impact on human resource expectations., have a positive or negative (strong and medium) impact on human resource expectations.&#160;The main purpose of this study was to provide a model for the expectations and priorities of human resources in National Iranian Oil Company by QFD for quality engineering of welfare system. The research method was qualitative and quantitative. At first, welfare indices were extracted from Delphi method and interviews with experts (n = 15) and then these indices were matched with the needs of human resources (n = 208) as a questionnaire. In the present study, the statistical sample in the qualitative section were the experts of the Oil Company's welfare department whose issues, such as time, availability of the interviewees, and the extent of their cooperation were considered. 15 people. After preparing the final questionnaire of expert indices in the quantitative part the number of questionnaires was obtained by Cochran formula. Reliability was confirmed using Cronbach's alpha of greater than 0.7 and validity test was performed by examining factor loadings and AVE scores. To ensure the quality of the home matrix (HOQ), technical requirements were created and the welfare service quality plans were processed to build the quality home matrix. In the final model it was found that the usability of internet services (GPS, virtual pages, online content, online information, etc.) is one of the key human resource expectations that influences other expectations. Also, the 18 components, depending on the type of relationship in their respective categories, have a positive or negative (strong and medium) impact on human resource expectations., have a positive or negative (strong and medium) impact on human resource expectations.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Expectations and Priorities, Human Resources, NIOC, Quality Performance Improvement, QFD</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-818-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-818-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2020</Year>
				<Month>2</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Pathology of Human Resources Processes Using the People Capability Maturity Model (PCMM) in Khazar Oil Company</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>263</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>288</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Siamak</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Baradaran</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>dr_baradaran@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Masoomeh Masoomeh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Habibi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>masoomehabibi@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Continuous monitoring of human resources processes is one of the most important tasks of HR managers, which is widely used in HR planning in organizations. In this regard, investigating the current status of human resources processes using the people capability maturity model in Khazar Oil Company, as one of the operating companies in the field of oil and gas of Iran, has been considered as the goal of this research. This study is consumes an applied research in terms of its purpose and descriptive-survey in terms of data collection method. The statistical population of this study consisted of 97 managers and official experts of Khazar Oil Company. The main tool of data collection was a questionnaire consisting of 45 questions that its validity was confirmed by human resource professors and some human resource management experts and its reliability was confirmed by Cronbach's alpha coefficient of 0.96. The sample size was 78 persons based on Cochran formula. The research questionnaire was distributed among them randomly. The data were analyzed by descriptive and inferential methods (Kolmogorov-Smirnov &#38; T-test &#38; ANOVA) using SPSS 23 software. The findings of the study indicated that Khazar Oil Company is at the level 2 of this model in terms of maturity of human resources processes.
&#160;</Abstract>
	<Keywords>People Capability Maturity Model (PCMM), Human Resources, Pathology, Khazar Oil Company.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-848-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-848-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2020</Year>
				<Month>2</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Factors influencing the Acceptance of E-learning among the Employees of Isfahan Oil Pipelines Company</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>289</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>314</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Marym</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Badakhnian</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>m.badakhanian@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hamid Reza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Peikari</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>omid726@yahoo.com.</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>This research aimed to determine the relationship between perceived organizational support (management support and organizational support), task interdependente and computer self-efficacy with behavioral intention to adopt e-learning system with the mediating role of individual norms in Isfahan Oil and Gas Pipeline Company. The research population was consisted of 250 employees and after the adoption and adaptation of the questionnaire, and using non-random sampling, 165 questionnaires were distributed and 150 usable questionnaires were returned. After the confirmation of validity and reliability, the data were analyzed by SPSS and SmartPLS. The results illustrated that the mediating role of individual norms in the relationship between organizational factors and task interdepenete with acceptance intention were supported while its mediation role between computer-self efficacy and acceptance intention was not statistically supported.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Training, Task interdepenete, Organizational support, Self-efficacy, Isfahan Oil and Gas Pipeline Company</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-849-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-849-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2020</Year>
				<Month>2</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Factors Affecting Organizational Commitment and the Role of Organizational Justice in Promoting</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>315</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>343</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hossein</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mansoori</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Mansoori.hossein@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The present study was conducted to investigate the factors affecting organizational commitment and the role of organizational justice in promoting it. Purposeful study is an applied research. The statistical population consisted of specialists working in petrochemical companies located in Pars Special Economic Region (Assaluyeh). The sample size was 260 according to the Cochran formula. The research was conducted in two stages. In the first step, a researcher-made questionnaire was used to determine factors influencing organizational commitment using 0.831 Cronbach's alpha coefficient. So that 25 factors affecting organizational commitment through factor analysis by explaining %75 of the factors were classified into four general categories: (1) structural / managerial factors; (2) factors related to occupation; (3) environmental and physical factors; (4) individual factors. The findings showed that the organizational justice as a component of organizational / managerial factors has the highest degree of impact on organizational commitment. In the second stage, the role of organizational justice in promoting organizational commitment was studied. Data were collected by Allen &#38; Meyer (1990) and Organizational Justice Questionnaire Niuoff &#38; Morman (1993) with Cronbach's alpha coefficient of 0.786 and 0.835, and analyzed by Pearson correlation coefficient, analysis Regression, T-test and ANOVA.The results indicated that there was a positive and significant relationship between organizational justice and organizational commitment at %99confidence level.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Organizational Justice, Organizational Commitment, petrochemical companies, Pars Special Economic Region.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-850-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-850-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
 </ArticleSet>
 
  
  
  
  
 