<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1393</YEAR>
<VOL>5</VOL>
<NO>19</NO>
<MOSALSAL>19</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>255</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>مدیریت استعدادها در صنعت نفت ایران: عوامل اثرگذار و راهبرد کلان</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Talent Management in Iranian oil industry: effected factors and main orientation</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>مدیریت استعدادها یکی از جدیدترین مباحث مدیریت منابع انسانی است که در سال&#8204;های اخیر توانسته است توجه بسیاری از فعالان این حوزه را در جهان به خود جلب نماید. پیاده&#8204;سازی موفق این نظام می&#8204;تواند آثار فراوانی در ایفای نقش راهبردی حوزه مدیریت منابع انسانی سازمان داشته باشد. صنعت نفت ایران به عنوان یکی از مهمترین مجموعه&#8204;های اقتصادی و فنی در کشور، زمینه&#8204;های فراوانی برای پیاده&#8204;سازی این نظام دارد. این مقاله با مصاحبه با خبرگان صنعت نفت کشوربا استفاده از نمونه گیری گلوله برفی و تحلیل محتوای کیفی آنها تلاش کرده است تا با بررسی عوامل محیطی و سازمانی اثرگذار بر اجرای نظام مدیریت استعدادها در صنعت را یادآور شود و جهت&#8204;گیری کلان مورد نیاز برای پیاده&#8204;سازی آن را تعیین کند. محققین این عوامل اثرگذار را در 3 سطح محیط عمومی صنعت نفت، چالش های موجود منابع انسانی صنعت نفت و تعریف استعداد در صنعت دسته بندی و رویکرد توسعه ای رقابتی را برای اجرای نظام مدیریت استعدادها در صنعت نفت کشور پیشنهاد کرده اند.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>Talent Management is one of the most recent development in HRM which many human resource specialists in the world are working on it. Successful implementation of TM has a great impact on strategic human resource management. Iranian oil industry, with its considerable economic and technological importance, has a great capability to use this system. &#160;In this paper, based on deep interview with oil industry experts, using snowball technique and qualitative methodology, we tried to study environmental and organizational factors which impacts on TM main orientation implementation in Iranian oil industry. We classified this factors in environmental factors in general environment of the industry, challenges in oil industry HRM and definition of talent in it. At last, we propose a competitive orientation for TM in Iranian oil industry</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>9</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>37</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مسلم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>باقری</Family>
				<NameE>Moslem</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>bagheri</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شیراز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شیراز</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>bagherimoslem@shirazu.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>علیشیری</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Mahdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>alishiri</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>روح الله</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>تولایی</Family>
				<NameE>Rohollah</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>tavallaee</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهیدبهشتی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شهیدبهشتی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سیامک</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>طهماسبی</Family>
				<NameE>Siamak</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>tahmasebi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه امام صادق(ع)</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>امام صادق(ع)</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>talent- talent management-talent management approaches- oil industry</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>استعداد</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت استعدادها</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رویکردهای مدیریت استعدادها</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>صنعت نفت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Blass, E.(2009). Talent management : cases and commentary. Basingstoke England ; New York: Palgrave Macmillan.##Bob Orr, B. M. (2007). &quot;Talent Management Challenge in the Oil and Gas Industry.&quot; Wiley Periodicals, Inc: 18-23.##Collings, D. G., &amp; Mellahi, K. (2009). Strategic talent management: A review and research agenda. Human Resource Management Review , 304–313.##Given, L. M. (2008). The Sage encyclopedia of qualitative research methods. Los Angeles ; London, SAGE.##Garrow, V. H., Wendy. 2008. Talent Management: Issues of focus and fit. Public Personnel Management(37): 389-402.##Klugman, J. (2010). The Real Wealth of Nations: Pathways to Human Development. New York, United Nations Development Programme (UNDP).##Ma¨kela¨, K., Bjo¨rkman, I., &amp; Ehrnrooth, M. (2009). How do MNCs establish their talent pools? Influences on individuals’ likelihood of being labeled as talent. Journal of World Business , 1-9.##Peter Parry, V. D., and Andrew Clark (2006). &quot;Crisis in the Oil and Gas Industry.&quot; from http://www.strategy-business.com/article/li00003?gko=d0843.##Peter Peek, P., Global Labour Monitor, and Patrick Gantès, Secretary-General, (2009). &quot;Whatever Happened to the Skills Crisis in the Oil and Gas Industry?&quot;. from http://www.cres.ch/Talent%20and%20Technology.pdf.##Preece, D., Chuai, X., &amp; Iles, P(2009). Talent Management and HRM in Multinational companies in Beijing: Definitions,differences and drivers. Journal of World Business##Ooi, C. S. S. 2010. Surviving the war for talent in Asia : how innovation can help. Upper Saddle River, NJ: IBM Press/Pearson.##Resler, C. A. (2007). &quot;Quantifying the Workforce Crisis in Upstream Oil and Gas.&quot; from http://www.spe.org/spe-app/spe/tt/vol1/no3/workforce.htm.##(1997)The Economist guide to economic indicators : making sense of economics. New York  Wiley##Smilan.sky, J. (2007). Developing Executive Talent, Best Practices from Global Leaders, Jossey-Bass, John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd, The Atrium, Southern Gate, Chichester, England ##Karacay-Aydin, G. (2009). Mentoring in Talent Management: Implications for Female Employees and Employees from Less Advantaged Socioeconomic Backgrounds. The Business Review , 13 (1), 231-237.##Silzer, R. F., &amp; Dowell, B. E. 2010. Strategy-driven talent management : a leadership imperative (1st ed.). San Francisco: Jossey-Bass.##Priem, R., Butler, JE. 2001. Is The Resource-Based &quot;View&quot; A Useful Perspective for Strategic Management Research? Academy of Management Review 26: 22####استعداد-لغتنامه دهخدا. (بدون تاریخ). بازیابی در  26 آذر, 1388، از لغتنامه دهخدا ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>طراحی مدلی جهت امکان سنجی اجرای نظام دورکاری
( مطالعه موردی : شرکت خطوط لوله و مخابرات نفت ایران )
</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Designing a method for feasibility study of teleworking system implementation
case study : Iranian oil pipeline & telecommunication company 

</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>این پژوهش در صدد است تا مدلی ارئه نماید که بر اساس آن میزان آمادگی بالقوه کارکنان یک سازمان را جهت پیشنهاد کار از راه دور سنجش نموده و امکان اجرای نظام دورکاری رابررسی نماید. بنابراین ابتدا ادبیات بین المللی دورکاری مطالعه و شاخص های مؤثر، استخراجمی گردد. در گام بعدی یک مدل سلسله مراتبی با قابلیت سنجش درجه آمادگی کارکنان جهت دورکار شدن طراحی و ابعاد و عناصر آن تعریف شده و با استفاده از نظر متخصصان و مدیران سازمانی و خبرگان دانشگاهی و در قالب تکنیک های تصمیم گیری ضرایب اهمیت هر یک از این مولفه&#8204;ها تعیین می گردد و در نهایت مدل طراحی شده در قالب یک پرسشنامه موزون در شرکت مورد مطالعه (خطوط لوله و مخابرات نفت ایران) اجرا و درجه آمادگی بالقوه آنان جهت موفقیت در طرح دورکاری ارزیابی شده و مستعدترین آنها به ترتیب جهت پیشنهاد دورکار شدن رتبه بندی می گردند. علی رغم این هدف مهم یافته های پژوهش نشان می دهد که بین مهارتهای رایانه ای و شرایط و فرهنگ خانوادگی کارکنان با تمایل آنان به دورکاری رابطه معناداری مثبت وجود دارد و کارمندان با سابقه به سازمانشان متعهد تر می باشند و&#160; البته کارکنان زن&#160; بیشتر از مردان متمایل به دورکاری هستند. در انتها نیز مهمترین عوامل عدم تمایل کارکنان به دورکاری از منظر آنان شناسائی و اولویت بندی می شوند</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>This paper is seeking to present a procedure to assessthe potential preparation of the employees of an enterprise for suggestion of remote working and consider the possibility of teleworking system execution. Therefore, at first, the international teleworking literature was studied and effective indices were extracted and localized. At the next stage, a hierarchic model with the capability of measuring the employees&#8217; preparation level for teleworking was designed and its elements and dimensions were defined and the coefficients of each elements was determined by the experts and organizational managers and academic personos&#8217; Ultimately, the designed model was implemented as a balanced questionnaire in July 2012 in Iranian Oil Pipeline &#38; Telecommunication Company and their potential preparation level was evaluated for success in teleworking schema and the most talented employees were graded respectively for suggesting the telework. In addition to this objective, the most important findings of this study indicated that a positive relationship exists between computer skills and employees&#8217; familial status and culture and their tendency to telework, and the experienced employees are more obliged to the enterprise and woman employees have tendency to the teleworking more than the men. Finally, the most important agents of non-tendency of the employees to the teleworking was identified and prioritized as their viewpoint</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>39</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>71</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>میرزاحسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حسینی</Family>
				<NameE>MirzaHasan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Hosseini</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>پیام نور</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>ir_Hosseini@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>احمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سلاجقه پور</Family>
				<NameE>Ahmad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Salajeghepour</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه پیام نور</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>پیام نور</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Method- Teleworking- Job Specifications-Personal Characteristics- Skill</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Information & Communication Technology-Home and Family Condition- Organizational Culture-Personal Tendency</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدل</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دورکاری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>خصوصیات شغل</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ویژگیهای شخصیتی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مهارت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شرایط خانه و خانواده</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فرهنگ سازمانی و تمایل شخصی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Timothy D. Golden (2006) Avoiding depletion in virtual work: Telework and the intervening impact of work exhaustion on commitment and turnover intentions , Journal of Vocational Behavior 69 (2006) 176–187##Timothy D. Golden , John F. Veiga (2008) , The impact of superior–subordinate relationships on the commitment, job satisfaction, and performance of virtual workers . The Leadership Quarterly 19 (2008) 77–88 ; Lally School of Management &amp; Technology, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, 110 8th Street, Troy, NY 12180-3590, United States##Lee , Bongsik Shin , Kunihiko Higa (2007) Telework vs. central work: A comparative view of knowledge accessibility , Decision Support Systems 43 (2007) 687–700## Book :  Jack M. Nilles ,  Managing Telework: Strategies for Managing the Virtual Workforce , Wiley - )1998-08-31 (    ##Blake, M, Cookman, N &amp; Huynes, D (1999). Teleworking directory. London: British library science Reference information service. ##Blanpain, Roger. (1995). The social implications of teleworking (I): The Legal and contractual situations of teleworkers in the member states of the European :::::union:::::. European foundation for the improvement of living and working conditions. ##Deluce, David, R. Early, J. Lee, K. Longeston. (2001), Toward Telecummuting? A feasibility study for the University of Waterloo. [University of Waterloo]  ##Keliner, M. (2001) “Routers, firewalls and loading devices help telecommuters and road warriors secure their data and computers” Government Computer News 20 (27) pp58-.Transactions on Professional Communication, 42 (4) December, pp 223-239. ##Henderson, D. K., and Mokhtarian, P. L. (1996), Impacts of Center-Based Telecommuting on 8 Travel and Emissions: Analysis of the Puget Sound Demonstration Project, Transportation Research D, Vol. 1, No. 1, pp. 29-45. ##Huws, U (1997). Teleworking: guidelines for good practice. Brighton: The institute for Employment Studies.##Huws, Ursula; Werner B. Korte; and Simon Robinson. (1990). Telework: Towards the Elusive Office. Chichester: John Willy &amp; sons.. ##Moon, C &amp; Stanworth, C (1997). Ethical issues of teleworking.' Business Ethics 6 (1), January.pp. 31-41. ##Morgan, Robert E. (2004), Teleworking: an assessment of the benefits and challenges. European Business Review. Vol.16 No.4. ##Nilles j, Carlson F, Gray P &amp; Hanneman G (1976), The Tecommunications Transportation Trade-off, New York, John Wiley. ##Nilles j (1990), The State of California Telecommuting Pilot Project Final Report, JALA Associates, Inc, 971 Stonehill Lane, Los Angeles, CA, 90049-1412. ##Pophal, Lin Grensing. (2002), Telecummuting: Managing off-site staff for small business. International self-counsel. ####اتمان قلیچ، ایثار،(1388)، مقاله&quot; دورکاری (کار از راه دور): مزایا و راهکارها.##بلیک، مونیکا (1380)، کتاب &quot;دورکاریبرایکتابدارانو اطلاعرسانان&quot; ترجمه نادر نقشینه،. تهران: مرکز اطلاعات و مدارک علمی ایران. چاپ اول.##حجازی ، سیدرضا ( 1388 ) ارزیابی تکنولوژی در شرکتهای کوچک و متوسط ، سازمان مدیریت صنعتی##سعادت ، اسفندیار، (1380) ، کتاب &quot; مدیریت منابع انسانی &quot; ، سازمان مطالعه و تدوین کتب علوم انسانی دانشگاه ها ##سهرابی، بهمن، (1382)، کتاب &quot;دورکاری&quot;، ویراستار:علی حسین قاسمی، مرکز اطلاعات و مدارک علمی ایران.##مارتینو ، (1382) کتاب &quot; کار از راه دور &quot; ، مترجم : مصطفی لو ، موسسه کار و تأمین اجتماعی##میرغفوری ، سید حبیب اله ( 1385 ) ، شناسایی و رتبه بندی عامل های موثر  در گماشته نشدن زنان به پست های مدیریتی در سازمانهای دولتی## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی عوامل موثر بر اجرای برنامه ریزی استراتژیک منابع انسانی در شرکت ملی پخش فرآورده های نفتی ایران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The survey of effective factors on Strategic human resource planning Implementation in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company (N.I.O.P.D.C)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>تحقیق حاضر بر بررسی عوامل موثر بر اجرای برنامه ریزی استراتژیک منابع انسانی در شرکت ملی پخش فرآورده های نفتی ایران متمرکز می باشد. در این پژوهش از نظریه های لی و گا و موسس و ساینلان در رابطه با عوامل موثر بر اجرای برنامه ریزی استراتژیک منابع انسانی و نظریه های استینر و کریستوفر در خصوص اجرای برنامه ریزی استراتژیک منابع انسانی به عنوان چارچوب نظری با ده فرضیه در نظر گرفته شده است. جامعه آماری تحقیق حاضر کارکنان شرکت ملی پخش فرآورده های نفتی ایران است که تعداد آنها 301 نفر می&#8204;باشد. حجم نمونه آماری با استفاده از فرمول کوکران 173 برآورد و به روش نمونه گیری تصادفی طبقه ای انتخاب شده است. ابزار جمع آوری اطلاعات پرسشنامه ایی است که با توجه به تعریف عملیاتی عوامل موثر بر اجرای برنامه ریزی استراتژیک منابع انسانی در شرکت ملی پخش فرآورده های نفتی ایران، نظریه های لی و گا، موسس و ساینلان و کریستوفر تنظیم گردیده، که پس ازسنجش روایی و پایایی آن دراختیار جامعه مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. پرسشنامه ها، جمع آوری و اطلاعات حاصله تلخیص، طبقه بندی و با استفاده از آمار توصیفی و استنباطی(آزمون های کولموگورف اسمیرنوف،آر پیرسون، رو اسپیرمن، رگرسیون دو متغیره و t تک نمونه ای) مورد تجزیه و تحلیل قرار گرفت. تمرکز این پژوهش بر اجرای برنامه ریزی استراتژیک منابع انسانی است و در حقیقت بر آن نیستیم که این برنامه ریزی چه مسایل و مشکلاتی را قرار است از سر راه منابع انسانی بر دارد. نتایج حاصل بیانگر آن است که میزان اجرای برنامه ریزی استراتژیک منابع انسانی در شرکت ملی پخش فرآورده های نفتی ایران بالاتر از متوسط است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The main pupose of this research is to survey of effective factors on Strategic human resource planning Implementation in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company (N.I.O.P.D.C). In order to this survey, lee&#160; &#38; Gough &#38; Moses &#38; Sinelane theories and for survey of effective factors on HR, Stainer and Christopher theories have been used with ten phrases as theorical framework.Statistical society of this research is the employees of NIOPDC whom are 301 persons. The volume of statistical sample calculated with Cockran&#8217;s equation of 173 ones and with categorized random sampling has been chosen. The instrument of data gathering is the questionnaire which arranged whith mentioned theories as operational definitions of of effective factors on Strategic human resource planning Implementation in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company (N.I.O.P.D.C) which delivered to statistical society after justifiability and reliability tests. Then questionnaires collected, summarized, categorized and analyzed with descriptional and deductive statistics.Results expresses that six factors such as CEO cooperation on strategic planning of HR in NIOPDC, team cooperation of HR strategic planning of employees, employees and management&#8217;s obligations in HR strategic planning, change management in HRM strategic planning and attention to cultural dimentions in HR strategic planning are effective in HR strategic planning at NIOPDC.
&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>73</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>102</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>جعفر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بیک زاد</Family>
				<NameE>Jafar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Beikzad</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Beikzad_jafar@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علیرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سید مفید</Family>
				<NameE>Ali Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Seyed Mofid</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Strategic human resource planning- Implementation key factors- National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company (N.I.O.P.D.C)</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>برنامه ریزی استراتژیک منابع انسانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عوامل کلیدی اجرا</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شرکت ملی پخش فرآورده های نفتی ایران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Bai, R, j, and Lee, G, G, (2003), organizational Factor influencing the quality of the IS/IT strategic planning process industrial Management and Data systems ,Vol .103 No. 8, pp. 622- 632.##Bian's, global,  )2007(, Management Tools and Trend Survey, Strategy and Leadership, Vol35, No5, pp. 23- 24.##Fry L, Fred and Stoner R, Charles, (1995), Strategic Planning for New and Small Business, Upstart Publishing Company, INC, pp. 62- 64. ##Johnson, Rick, (2007), Strategic Planning key Success Factors and how to Avoid ten Common Mistakes, Sunday, pp. 16- 21. ##Hensey, Melleville, (1991),  Essential Success Factors for Strategic Planning, Journal of Management in Engineering, Vol.7, No.2, PP. 77–167. ##Hrebiniak, LawrenceG, (2006), Obstacles to Effective Strategy Implementation, Organizational Dynamics, Vol. 35, No.1, PP.12-31. ##Lee, G, G, and Bai, R. J, (2003), Organizational mechanism for successful IS/IT strategic planning in the digital era, Management Decision,Vol.41, No.1, pp. 32- 42.##Lee, G, G, and Gough, T, (1993). An integrated framework for information systems planning and its initial application&quot;, Journal of formation Technology, Vol. 8, pp. 227-240.##Len,NixonMarch, (2004), Change Management:Theory and Practice Business Date.Vol. 12, No 1, PP. 1-4. ##Risseeuw, P and Masurel, E, (1994), The role of planning in small firms: empirical evidence from a service industry, Small Business Economics 6, PP. 313-322.##Roger A, Kaufman and Hugh Oakley-Browne and Ryan Watkins and Doug Leigh, )2003(, Strategic Planning for Success, Published by John Wiley, PP.40-56.##Roper, S, (1997), Strategic initiatives and small business performance: an exploratory analysis of Irish companies, Entrepreneurship and Regional Development 9, PP. 353-364.##Sampler, J.L, (1998), Redefining industry structure for the information age Strategic Management Journal 1 (4), PP. 343-355.##Schendel, D, (1996), Evolutionary perspectives on strategy, Strategic Management Journal 17, PP. 3-4.##Short, J, C and Ketchen, D.J and Palmer, T.B, )2002(, The role of sampling in strategic management research on performance, a two-study analysis Journal of Management 28, PP. 363–385.####بانت، آلن و جی هینز، استیفن، سید محمد، اعرابی و سعید موسوی، (1386)، برنامه ریزی استراتژیک منابع انسانی، تهران،انتشارات نیل، چاپ اول.##برایسون ، جان ام، عباس، منوریان، (1372)، برنامه ریزی استراتژیک بر سازمان های دولتی و غیر انتفاعی، تهران ، مرکز آموزش مدیریت دولتی، چاپ اول.##برتراند، الیور، سید حسین، ابطحی و جواد، عین آبادی، (1385)، برنامه ریزی نیروی انسانی (روش ها - تجربیات -مهارتها)، تهران، انتشارات سازمان یونسکو، چاپ اول.##بریس، نیکلا و کمپ، ریچارد و سلنگار، رزمری، خدیجه، علی آبادی و سیدعلی، صمدی، (1388)، تحلیل داده های روانشناسی با برنامه spss، تهران، نشر دوران، چاپ دوم.##بنیسون، مالکم و کیسون، جاناتان، علیرضا، جباری، (1387)، برنامه ریزی نیروی انسانی، تهران، نشر افکار، چاپ دوم.##بیلو، پاتریک جان، منصور، شریفی کلوبی، (1376)، راهنمای اجرایی برنامه ریزی استراتژیک، تهران، نشر آردین، چاپ اول.##پاتریک، ج.بیلو، منصور، شریفی کلوی، (1376)، راهنمای اجرایی برنامه ریزی استراتژیک، تهران، نشر آردین، چاپ اول.##پیرس، جان و رابینسون، ریچارد کنت، سهراب، خلیلی شورینی (1380)، برنامه ربزی و مدیریت استراتژیک، ، تهران، انتشارات یادواره کتاب، چاپ سوم.##جیمز، دبلیو واکر، خدابخش، داشگرزاده، (1375)، برنامه ریزی استراتژیک منابع انسانی، تهران، انتشارات موسسه نشر فرهنگی زند، چاپ اول.##حقیقی، محمد و منوریان، (1388)، عباس بررسی عوامل موثر بر موفقیت برنامه ریزی استراتژیک در شرکت ملی گاز ایران، نشریه مدیریت بازرگانی، دوره 1،تهران، شماره3، صص 39-54.##رابینز، استیفن، علی، پارساییان و سید محمد، اعرابی، (1378)، رفتار سازمانی، تهران، دفتر       پژوهش های فرهنگی، چاپ سیزدهم.##زمینی، سمیرا،(1389)،  بررسی مقایسه ای از ادراک از ریسک مشتریان از سیستم بانکداری الکترونیکی و سیستم بانکداری سنتی در شعبات بانک کارآفرین شهرستان تبریز، کارشناسی ارشد، انشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد بناب.##سعادت، اسفندیار، (1375)، مدیریت منابع انسانی، مدیریت منابع انسانی، تهران، انتشارات سمت، چاپ اول.##سلطانی، ایرج،(1386)، مبانی برنامه ریزی استراتژیک منابع انسانی، تهران، انتشارات ارکان دانش، چاپ اول.##سید جوادین، سید رضا، (1384)، برنامه ریزی نیروی انسانی، تهران، انتشارات دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، چاپ چهارم.##شانی، مرتضی، (1383)، برنامه ریزی استراتژیک برای مدیران، تهران، سازمان مدیریت صنعتی، چاپ اول.##فاوگ، دیویس، سید جمال الدین، طبیبی و علی، ماهر و محمدرضا، ملکی، (1383)، اجرای برنامه استراتژیک، تهران، سیمای فرهنگ، چاپ اول.##کافمن، راجر و هرمن، جری، فریده، مشایخ و عباس، بازرگان، (1374)، برنامه ریزی استراتژیک در نظام آموزشی، بازرگان، تهران، انتشارات مدرسه، چاپ اول.##کولوبندی، عبدالله، (1374)، نکاتی درباره برنامه ریزی استراتژیک، تهران ، نشریه تدبیر، شماره60.##لیدنسی،  ولز دنیس، سید جمال الدین، طبیبی و محمدرضا، ملکی، (1383)، مدیریت استراتژیک برای مدیران ارشد، تهران، سیمای فرهنگ، چاپ اول.##منوریان، عباس، (1369)، فرایند برنامه ریزی استراتژیک، فصلنامه مدیریت دولتی، تهران، انتشارات مرکز آموزش مدیریت دولتی، شماره10.##میرسپاسی، ناصر، (1382)، مدیریت استراتژیک، منابع انسانی و روابط کار (با تجدید نظر کلی)،        تهران، انتشارات میر، چاپ بیست و یکم.##والا، آگار و سنزو، دی  و رابینز، استیفن، سید حسین، ابطحی و حشمت، خلیفه سلطانی، (1386)، برنامه ریزی نیروی انسانی، تهران، انتشارات تحقیقات و آموزش مدیریت، چاپ اول.##هاینز، استیفن جی، جواد، کسروی، (1376)، توفیق در برنامه ریزی استراتژیک، تهران، انتشارات  انجمن مدیران صنایع، چاپ اول.##یاراحمدی خراسانی، مهدی،(1386)، برنامه ریزی منابع انسانی؛ اولویت مدیران آینده ساز، نشریه  مدیریت، تهران، شماره 129-130.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF> ارزشیابی اثربخشی دوره های آموزش ضمن خدمت شرکت ملی گاز ایران بر اساس سه الگوی پاتریک، فیلیپس و سیپ</TitleF>
		<TitleE> Evaluation of the effectiveness of the on-the- job training courses in NIGC based Kirkpatrick, Phillips and CIPP models</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>هدف از پژوهش حاضر &#171;ارزشیابی اثربخشی دوره های آموزش ضمن خدمت شرکت ملی گاز ایران بر اساس سه الگوی پاتریک، فیلیپس و سیپ&#187; بوده است.
جامعه آماری ما عبارتست از کلیه کارکنان شرکت ملی گاز ایران که در 6 ماهه نخست سال 90 در دوره های آموزشی کوتاه مدت ضمن خدمت این سازمان، شرکت نموده اند. با توجه به اطلاعات بدست آمده در کل کشور حدود 10350 نفر جزو جامعه قرار می گرفتند که طبق نمونه گیری خوشه ای شرکت گاز استان تهران با جامعه 1195 نفری انتخاب شد و از این شرکت با استفاده از روش نمونه گیری تصادفی ساده و بر طبق جدول مورگان تعداد 291 نفر بعنوان نمونه پژوهشی انتخاب شدند.در این پژوهش جهت گردآوری اطلاعات از نمونه مورد نظر از ابزار پرسشنامه استفاده گردید. نتایج پژوهش حاکی از این است که دوره های آموزشی شرکت ملی گاز ایران در عامل های واکنش، یادگیری، رفتار، نتایج، زمینه، فرایند و برونداد فاقد اثربخشی لازم بوده و فقط در دو عامل درونداد و سودآوری اثربخشی لازم را دارا بوده است.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The objective of this research is &#34;effectiveness evaluation of on-the job- training courses of National Iranian Gas Co. based on 3 patterns of Kirkpatrick, Phillips and CIPP&#34;.The statistical society is the employees of the National Iranian Gas Co. who attended the short term training courses in the first 6 months of the year 1390With reference to the obtained data about 10350 people includes in this research in all the country, of whom based on the sampling, a number 1195 people from Tehran Province's Gas Co. were elected and the company elected 291 people based on Morgan's Table with the methods of random selection method as the research sample.Survey questions were used for the data collection of the mentioned sample.
The results of the research shows that the training courses of the National Iranian Gas Co. were not sufficiently effective in factors of reactions, learning, behavior, results, procedure and relevant our-put and has been effective only in two In-put and profitability factors.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>103</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>130</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مجید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>همه مرادی</Family>
				<NameE>Majid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Hamemoradi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهیدبهشتی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شهیدبهشتی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hamemoradi@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>اباصلت</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>خراسانی</Family>
				<NameE>Abasalt</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Khorasani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهیدبهشتی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شهیدبهشتی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>کوروش</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>فتحی واجارگاه</Family>
				<NameE>Kourosh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>FathiAjargah</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه شهیدبهشتی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شهیدبهشتی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Evaluation- Effective- On-the-Job Training-Kirkpatrick-Jack Phillips-CIPP</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ارزشیابی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اثربخشی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آموزش ضمن خدمت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کرک پاتریک</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>جک فیلیپس</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>CIPP</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Armstrong, Michael. (2010). &quot;Armstrong's essential human resource management practice&quot;, London: Kogan Page##Bates.R.A. (2004). The development of a generalized learning transfer system inventory, Human resource development quarterly, Vol8, p4##Cole, Gerald. (2002)&quot;. Personnel and human resource management&quot;. London: Continum##Foxon, Marguerite, Cooper &amp; Lybrand. (1991). Evaluation of training and development program, Australian journal of educational technology.##Messmer, Max. Bogardus, Anne. Isbell, Connie (2007). &quot;Human resource management&quot;. New Jersey: John Wiley &amp; song, Inc##Phillips, J.J &amp; Phillips, P.P. (2008). &quot;Providing the value of HR (how and why to measure ROI)&quot;. Alexandria, Virginia: Society for human resource management##Phillips, P.P. et al (2007). &quot;the ROI field book (strategies for implementing ROI in HR and training)&quot;, Burlington: Elsevier##Phillips, Patricia Pulliam. (2003). &quot;Training evaluation in the public sector&quot;, Doctoral Dissertation, University of the Southern Mississippi##Stewart, Greg. L &amp; Brown, Kenneth. G (2009). &quot;Human resource management: Linking strategy to practice&quot;. United States of America: John Wiley &amp; sons##ابیلی، خدایار. (1389). مدیریت منابع انسانی (با تأکید بر رویکردهای نوین)، تهران؛ انتشارات سازمان مدیریت صنعتی##بزاز جزایریف سید احمد. (1384). بررسی و ارزیابی اثربخشی دوره های آموزشی برگزار شده در شرکت ملی فولاد ایران، تهران؛ سومین کنفرانس بین المللی مدیریت##جزنی، نسرین. (1389). مدیریت منابع انسانی، تهران؛ نشر نی##خراسانی، اباصلت و حسن زاده، سودابه. (1389). آسیب شناسی اثربخشی آموزشی در سازمانهای ایرانی از دیدگاه کارشناسان و مدیران، مشهد؛ اولین کنفرانس مدیران آموزش و پژوهش##سرمد، زهره و بازرگان، عباس و حجازی، الهه. (1384). روشهای پژوهش در علوم رفتاری، تهران؛ نشر آگه##سیف، علی اکبر. (1385). اندازه گیری، سنجش و ارزشیابی آموزشی، تهران؛ نشر دوران##صباغیان، زهرا و اکبری، سهیلا. (1389). آموزش جامع سازمانی(بارویکرد آموزش بزرگسالان)، تهران؛ انتشارات سمت##عباس پور، عباس. (1388). مدیریت منابع انسانی پیشرفته (رویکردها، فرایندها و کارکردها)، تهران؛ انتشارات سمت##عباس زادگان، محمد و ترک زاده، جعفر. (1388). نیازسنجی آموزشی در سازمانها، تهران؛ شرکت سهامی انتشار##عباسیان، عبدالحسین. (1385). اثربخشی دوره های آموزشی، مجله تدبیر، شماره 170##محمدی، داوود. (1382). برنامه ریزی آموزش ضمن خدمت کارکنان در سازمانها و مؤسسات و صنایع، تهران؛ انتشارات پیام و پیوند نو## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی عوامل موثر بر بهره وری منابع انسانی دانشگر شرکت ملی نفت ایران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>An investigation into factors influencing knowledge workers’ productivity
(Case study: national Iranian Oil Company)
</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی عوامل موثر بر بهره وری نیروهای دانشگر شرکت ملی نفت ایران به روش توصیفی پیمایشی صورت گرفته است. تعداد 90 نفر از کارشناسان واحدهای ستادی شرکت ملی نفت ایران از طریق روش سرشماری کامل انتخاب و به سوالات پرسشنامه که پایایی آن از طریق ضریب آلفای کرنباخ مورد تائید قرار گرفته بود پاسخ دادند. داده های حاصل به دو شیوه توصیفی و استنباطی تحلیل شده اند. &#171;t تک متغیره&#187; محاسبه شده در سطح a=0/05&#160;مبین معناداری تاثیر عوامل فردی؛ شایستگی، رضایت شغلی، توان و مهارت بر بهره وری نیروهای دانشگر شرکت ملی نفت ایران در حد خیلی زیاد بوده است. هم چنین &#171;t تک متغیره&#187; محاسبه شده در سطح a=0/05مبین معناداری تاثیر عوامل سازمانی؛ مشارکت، انگیزش، ارتباطات سازمانی، آموزش بر بهره وری نیروهای دانشگر شرکت ملی نفت ایران در حد خیلی زیاد بوده است. نتایج &#171;t تک متغیره&#187; محاسبه شده در سطح a=0/05&#160;مبین معناداری تاثیر عوامل شغلی؛ کار با معنی و چالش برانگیز، آزادی و استقلال عمل و وضوح نقش بر بهره وری نیروهای دانشگر شرکت ملی نفت ایران در حد خیلی زیاد بوده است. در نهایت آزمون فریدمن ضمن معنادار نشان دادن اظهارات پاسخگویان، اولویت&#8204; بندی عوامل موثر بر بهره وری نیروهای دانشگر را به ترتیب شامل؛ عوامل فردی، عوامل شغلی و عوامل سازمانی نشان داد. 

&#160;</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The present paper aims at studying factors affecting knowledge workers&#8217; productivity in national Iranian Oil Company, using descriptive survey method. 90 experts working at staff divisions were sampled, using census method and responded to a reliably confirmed questionnaire. One sample t test revealed at &#945;= 0.05 that individual level factors, such as competence, job satisfaction, proficiency have a highly significant effect on oil company knowledge workers&#8217; productivity. Also one sample t test revealed at &#945;= 0.05 revealed that organization level factors, such as involvement, motivation, organizational communication, and training have highly significant effect on oil company knowledge workers&#8217; productivity. one sample t test revealed at &#945;= 0.05 revealed that job factors, such as meaningful and challenging job, job autonomy, and job clarification have highly significant effect on oil company knowledge workers&#8217; productivity.
Indicating participants&#8217; responses&#8217; significance, Freedman&#8217;s test ranked factors influencing knowledge workers&#8217; productivity as follows: individual factors, jobrelated factors, and organizational factors</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>131</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>160</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>خدایار</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ابیلی</Family>
				<NameE>Khodayar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Abili</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>abili_hrm@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی اصغر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حیات</Family>
				<NameE>Aliasghar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Hayat</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه خوارزمی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>خوارزمی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علیرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>یوز باشی</Family>
				<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Yozbashi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>individual factors- organizational factors- job factors- productivity- knowledge workers- national Iranian Oil Company</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عوامل فردی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عوامل سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عوامل شغلی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بهره وری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نیروهای دانشگر</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شرکت ملی نفت ایران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abdel-Wahab, Mohamed S., Dainty, Andrew R.J., Ison, Stephen G., Bowen, Patrick and Hazlehurst, Guy (2008). Trends of skills and productivity in the UK construction industry. Engineering, Construction and Architectural Management,Vol. 15 No. 4, pp. 372-382##Aghazadeh, Seyed-Mahmoud(2007). Reflective Practice, Re-examining the training side of productivity improvement:evidence from service sector. International Journal of Productivity and Performance Management, Vol. 56 No. 8, pp. 744-757##Antikainen ,Riikka., Lappalainen, Sanna., Lönnqvist, Antti., Maksimainen, Kati., Reijula, Kari., Rauva, Erkki Uusi(2008). Exploring the relationship between indoor air and productivity. SJWEH Suppl,  no 4,pp 79–82##Appelbaum ,Steven H. Molson, John. Adam, Jacques. Javeri, Nadeem. Lessard, Michel. Lion, Jean-Pascal. Simard, Michel ; Sorbo, Silvana (2005). A Case Study Analysis of the Impact of Satisfaction and Organizational Citizenship on Productivity, Management Research News, Vol. 28 No. 5##Bhatti, Komal Khalid and Qureshi, Tahir Masood (2007). Impact of Employee Participation on Job Satisfaction, Employee Commitment and Employee Productivity, International Review of Business Research Papers, Vol.3 No.2, Pp. 54 – 68##Bheda, Rajesh., Narag A.S and Singla M.L(2003). Apparel manufacturing: a strategy for productivity improvement. Journal of  Fashion Marketing and Management, Vol 7 No.1 pp12-22##Cascio,Wayne (1998). Managing Human Resources: Productivity Quality of work, profits. Fifth Edition##Davenport, T. (2002), “Can you boost knowledge work’s impact on the bottom line? Management Update, Vol. 7 No. 11, pp. 3-5##Davenport, Tom H (2006). Improving Knowledge Worker Performance, President’s Chair in Information Technology and Management, Babson College##Diewert, W. E. (1992). The measurement of productivity, Bulletin of Economic Research, vol. 44(3), pp163–198##Djellal, Faridah and Gallouj, Faïz (2008). Measuring and Improving Productivity in Services) Issues, Strategies and Challenges (, Edward Elgar Publishing, Inc. UK.##Drucker P.F.(1999). Knowledge-Worker Productivity: The Biggest Challenge, California Management Review. Vol.41, N.2, pp79-94##Enshassi, Adnan.,Mohamed, Sherif., Abu Mustafa,  Ziad and Mayer Peter Eduard.(2007). Factors Affecting Labour Productivity In Building Projects In The Gaza Strip. Journal of Civil Engineering And Management, Vol XIII, No 4, 245–254##Hammer, M., Leonard, D., &amp; Davenport, T. (2004). Why don’t we know more about knowledge? MIT Sloan Management Review, 45(4), 14-18##Horwitz, Frank M., Heng,  Chan Teng.,  Quazi, Hesan Ahmed(2003). Finders, Keepers? Attracting, Motivating And Retaining Knowledge Workers, Human Resource Management Journal, Vol. 13 No. 4, 2003, Pp 23-44##Kaci ,Mustapha (2006). Understanding Productivity: A Primer, Published by authority of the Minister responsible for Statistics Canada##Kilic, Hasan; Okumus, Fevzi (2005). Factors influencing productivity in small island hotels Evidence from Northern Cyprus, International Journal of Contemporary Hospitality Management, Vol. 17 No. 4##Kumar, S. Anil., Sauresh, N(2008). Production and operations management(With skill development, Caselets and Cases). Published by New Age International (P) Ltd., Publishers. Second Edition.##LEMA, N. M. (1995) Construction of labor productivity modeling, University of  Dar Elsalaam.##LIM, E. C.; ALUM, J. (1995) Construction productivity: issues encountered by contractors in Singapore. International, Journal of Project Management, 13(1), p. 51–58.##Liu, M.M Anita., Chiu ,W.M. &amp; Fellows, Richard(2007). Enhancing commitment through work empowerment, Engineering, Construction and Architectural Management, Vol. 14, No. 6, pp.568-580 ##Mohanta, G.C., Kannan V., Thooyamani K.P.(2006). Strategies for Improving Productivity of Knowledge Workers – An Overview, Website: www.Strength Based Strategies##Otote, Albert Oni Igbinadolor, (2008). Impacts of Environmental Turbulence and Interpersonal Orientation on Nurses Productivity in a Canadian Health-Care Organization, a Dissertation Presented in Partial Fulfillment of The Requirements for the Degree Doctor of Business Administration##Ramı´rez ,Yuri W. Nembhard, David A. (2004). Measuring knowledge worker productivity A taxonomy.  Journal of Intellectual Capital, Vol. 5 No. 4, pp. 602-628.##Rana, Arif Iqbal ( 1997). Common Factors In Productive Firms: Lessons From Four Case Studies, CMER Working Paper Series, Centre For Management and Economic Research, Lahore University Of Management Sciences.##Robinson, Janette Roberts(2009). Does Employee Development Affect Propensity To Leave? : A Study Of Knowledge Workers. A Dissertation Presented in Partial Fulfillment of the Requirements for the Degree Doctor of Philosophy; Capella University##Roelofsen, Paul (2002). The impact of office environments on employee performance: The design of the workplace as a strategy for productivity enhancement, Journal of Facilities Management, Vol. 1 No. 3 , P P 2 4 7 – 2 6 4##Savery , Lawson K(1998). Management and productivity increases, Journal of Management Development, Vol. 17 No. 1.##Schonewille,Mark (2001).Does training generally work? Explaining labor productivity effects from schooling and training, International Journal of Manpower, Vol. 22 No. 1/2, pp. 158-172.##Stuhlman Daniel (2006). Helping you turn data into knowledge : Knowledge Management Terms, Website www.home.earthlink.net/ ddstuhlman/defin1.htm##van der Voordt, Theo J. M.) 2004), Productivity and employee satisfaction in flexible workplaces, Journal of Corporate Real Estate; Vol. 6 No. 2, pp. 133–148.##Walters, Marlon M (2007). Leadership and Productivity: An Examination of Leader Member Exchenge Model, A Dissertation Presented in Partial Fulfillment of The Requirements for the Degree Doctor of Philosophy##Wood, Nancy E (2008). A study on The Relationship between Perceived Leadership Styles s of Hospital Clinical Leaders and Perceived Empowerment, Organizational Commitment, and Job Satisfaction of subordinate Hospital Nurses in a Management Position, A Dissertation presented in Partial Fulfillment of the Requirements for the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy.####ابطحی، حسن و کاظمی، بابک(1375). بهره وری. تهران: موسسه مطالعات و پژوهش های بازرگانی.## ابیلی، خدایار و جاهد، حسینعلی(1388). تعیین عوامل سازمانی مرتبط با بهره وری مدیران میانی(مورد: شرکت ایران خودرو). مجله روان شناسی و علوم تربیتی دانشگاه تهران. سال39، شماره 1. ##ابیلی، خدایار و موفقی، حسن(1386). دریچه ای بر مفاهیم نوین مدیریتی(با تاکید بر منابع انسانی)،چاپ دوم، تهران، انتشارات سارگل##احمد زاده، سلیمان(1386). شناسایی و اولویت بندی عوامل موثر بر بهره وری کارکنان وزارت راه و ترابری(ستاد مرکزی). پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه تهران##امامی میبدی، علی(1379). اصول اندازه گیری کارایی و بهره وری. تهران، انتشارات موسسه مطالعات و پژوهشهای بازرگانی.##امینی، علی رضا و حجازی آزاد، زهره(1386). تحلیل و ارزیابی نقش سلامت و بهداشت در ارتقاء بهره وری نیروی کار در اقتصاد ایران. فصنامه پژوهشهای اقتصادی ایران، سال نهم، شماره 30، صص. 163-137##آراسته، عبدالله(1386). بازنگری در بهره وری. مجله تدبیر، شماره 182##بهرامی، سیما(1385). اولویت بندی عوامل موثر بر بهره وری منابع انسانی با استفاده از فنون تصمیم گیری چند شاخصه(MADM) در شرکت برق منطقه ای خوزستان. پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد، موسسه تحقیقات و آموزش مدیریت.##تقی زادگان(1380). عوامل بنیادی در بهره وری. همایش تحول اداری و بهره وری. شیراز. انتشارات سازمان مدیریت و برنامه ریزی استان فارس.##خاکی، غلامرضا، (1388). مدیریت بهره وری (تجزیه و تحلیل آن در سازمان). تهران: نشر کوهسار.##خرقانی، سعید و سلسله، مینو(1388). مدیریت دانش و چالش نگهداری دانشگران سازمانی. دومین کنفرانس ملی مدیریت دانش. تهران. مرکز همایش های بین المللی رازی##رحمانی، جعفر و باقی نصرت آبادی، علی(1377). نکات موثر در مدیریت کارآمد. قم:  نشر خرم.##رضایی، اردشیر(1382). مدیریت سازمانها و بهره وری نیروی انسانی. مجله تدبیر، شماره 131##رئیسی، پوران و موسی زاده، محمود(1385). بررسی عوامل موثر بر افزایش بهره وری واحد های بهداشتی درمانی شهرستان بهشهر. مجموعه مقالات نخستین همایش ملی بهره وری و توسعه. جلد دوم. تبریز، انتشارات سازمان مدیریت و برنامه ریزی آذربایجان شرقی.##شکری، مصطفی(1375). بررسی شیوه های عملی ارتقای بهره وری نیروی انسانی. شیوه های عملی ارتقای بهره وری نیروی انسانی. تهران، مرکز آموزش مدیریت دولتی.##طاهری، شهنام(1383). بهره وری و تجزیه و تحلیل آن در سازمان. تهران، نشرهستان##طیبی، سید جمال الدین و باغبانیان، عبدالوهاب(1381). بررسی عوامل موثر بر میزان بهره وری نیروی انسانی در بیمارستانهای دانشگاه علوم پزشکی شیراز از دیدگاه کارکنان بخش های اجرایی در سال 1380، اولین همایش کشوری مدیریت منابع انسانی در بیمارستان.##علاء الملکی، مهناز؛ یوسفی، بهپور و ذاکریان، عباس(1381). شناخت و مقایسه راههای افزایش بهره وری نیروی انسانی در دانشگاه علوم پزشکی و خدمات بهداشتی درمانی سمنان. اولین همایش کشوری مدیریت منابع در بیمارستان. ##نرگسیان، عباس(1386). بررسی تاثیر انواع فنون آموزش بر بهره وری منابع انسانی دانشگاه تهران. پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد دانشگاه تهران## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی  تاثیر رهبری تحول آفرین بر نوآوری منابع انسانی در سازمان (مورد مطالعه: شرکت ملی گاز ایران)
</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Impact of Transformational Leadership on Organizational Innovation: A Study of the National Iranian Gas Company</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>&#160;هدف از این پژوهش بررسی تاثیر رهبری تحول &#173;آفرین بر نوآوری سازمانی در میان مدیران میانی و ارشد اجرایی شرکت ملی گاز ایران است. این پژوهش از نظر هدف کابردی، از نظر نحوه&#173; ی گردآوری داده &#173;ها از نوع توصیفی-پیمایشی و از لحاظ داده های جمع آوری شده از نوع کمی می باشد. .جامعه آماری پژوهش را کلیه مدیران میانی و ارشد شرکت ملی گاز ایران تشکیل می دهد که 400 نفر می &#173;باشد و با استفاده از فرمول کوکران تعداد 227 نفر به عنوان نمونه آماری انتخاب شده است. برای تحلیل داده ها از مدل معادلات ساختاری و روش حداقل مجذورات جزئی (PLS) استفاده شد. یافته&#173; های پژوهش حاکی از ارتباط معنی دار بین این دو متغیر بوده وتعداد چهار فاکتور مورد بررسی قرار گرفته که براساس مدل معادلات ساختاری، شاخص &#173;های نفوذ آرمانی، انگیزش الهام &#173;بخش، ترغیب ذهنی و ملاحظات فردی نقش موثری بر نوآوری سازمانی دارد</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>This paper aims to investigate the effect of transformational leadership on organizational innovation among line and senior managers of national Iranian gas company. This study is practical in terms of the objective, descriptive survey in terms of gathering data procedure and finally quantitative with regards to the gathered data. Our research population contains all of the line and senior managers of national Iranian gas company who are about 400 people. The Cochran formula was employed to calculate 227 people as the statistical sample of our paper. Structural equation modeling (SEM) and partial least squares (PLS) was used for analyzing our data. Our findings indicate the significant impact of transformational leadership on organizational innovation. Moreover, theanalyseof four factors: idealized influence, inspirational motivation, intellectual stimulation and individual consideration exhibit the significant role of them on organizational innovation.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>161</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>197</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مبینی دهکردی</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mobini dehkordi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>ali@mobini.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عامر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>دهقان نجم آبادی</Family>
				<NameE>Amer</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Dehghan najmabadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>amerdehghan@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علیرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>محمدی</Family>
				<NameE>AliReza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mohammadi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>پیران</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Piran</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Transformational Leadership- Organizational Innovation- The National Iranian Gas Company</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رهبری تحول آفرین</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نوآوری سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شرکت ملی گاز ایران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Agbor, E. (2008). &quot;Creativity and Innovation: The Leadership Dynamics&quot;, Journal of Strategic Leadership, Vol. 1, No. 1,  pp: 39-45.##Akin, M., Bloemhof-Ruwaard, J., &amp; Wynstra, F. (2009). &quot;The impact of supply chain related factors on environmental performance of manufacturing firms in turkey&quot;, Paper presented at the 18th IPSERA Conference.##Amabile, T.M., (1999). &quot;How to kill creativity&quot;, Harvard Business  Review on   Breakthrough Thinking, Harvard Business School Press, Boston, pp: 1-28.##Andiliou, A., Murphy P.K. (2010). &quot;Examining variations among researchers’ and teachers’ conceptualizations of creativity: A review and synthesis of contemporary research&quot;, Education  Research  Review, Vol. 5, pp: 201-219.##Andriopoulos, C., &amp; Lowe,  A.  (2000).   &quot;Enhancing   organizational creativity:  the process of perpetual challenging&quot;, Management Science, Vol. 38, pp: 734−743.##Avolio, B.J., W. Zhu, W. Koh, and P. Bhatia, (2004). Transformational leadership and organizational commitment: Mediating role of psychological empowerment and moderating role of structural distance&quot;, Journal of Organizational Behavior, Vol. 25, No. 8, pp: 951-968.##Ahmed, A.M., Abdalla H.S. (1999). &quot;The role of innovation in crafting the vision of the future&quot;, Eng Manag J, Vol, 37, pp: 34-50.##Armbruster, H., Bikfalvi, A., Kinkel, S., Lay, G. (2008). &quot;Organizational innovation: The challenge of measuring non-technical innovation in large-scale surveys&quot;, Tecnovation, Vol. 28, pp: 644–657.##Baregheh, A., Rowley, J., Sambrook, S. (2009 ). &quot;Towards a multidisciplinary definition of innovation&quot;, Management Decision Vol. 47, No. 8, pp: 1323-1339.##Bass, B. M. (1985). &quot;Leadership and  performance beyond expectations&quot;, New York, NY: Free Press.##Bass, B. M., &amp; Riggio, R. E. (2006). &quot;Transformational Leadership&quot;, Mahwah, New Jersey, Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.##Chao, C.Y; Lin Y.S; Cheng, Y.L; Tseng. Y.C. (2011). &quot;Employee innovation, supervisory leadership, organizational justice, and organizational culture in Taiwan’s manufacturing industry&quot;, African Journal of Business Management, Vol.5, No. 6, pp: 2501-2511.##Chin, W.W. (1998). &quot;Issues and option on structural equation modeling&quot;, Management information systems quarterly , Vol. 22, No. 1.##Chin, W. W., Marcolin, B. L., &amp; Newsted, P. R. (1996). A partial least squares latent variable modeling approach for measuring interaction effects: Results from a Monte Carlo simulation study and voice mail emotion/adoption study. In J. I. DeGross, S. L. Jarvenpaa, &amp; A. Srinivasan (Eds.), Proceedings of the Seventeenth International Conference on Information Systems (pp. 21–41). Cleveland, OH: Association for Information Systems.##Elenkov, D. S., &amp; Manev, I. M.  (2005). &quot;Top management leadership and influence on innovation: The role of sociocultural context&quot;. Journal of Management, Vol. 31, No. 3, pp: 381-402.##Elkins, T. and R.T. Keller, (2003).&quot; Leadership in research and development organizations: A literature review and conceptual framework&quot;, The Leadership Quarterly, Vol. 14, No. 4-5, pp: 587-606.##Eyal, O., &amp; Kark, R. (2004). &quot;How do transformational leaders transform organizations? A study of the relationship between leadership and  entrepreneurship&quot;, Leadership &amp; Policy in Schools, Vol. 3, pp: 211-235.##Garcı´a-Morales, V.J., Matı´as-Reche, F., Hurtado-Torres, N. (2008). &quot;Influence of transformational leadership on organizational innovation and performance depending on the level of organizational learning in the pharmaceutical sector&quot;, Journal of Organizational Change Management, Vol. 21 No. 2, pp: 188-212.##García-Morales V.J., Jiménez-Barrionuevo, M., Gutiérrez -Gutiérrez, L. (2011). &quot;Transformational leadership influence on organizational performance through organizational learning and innovation&quot;, Journal of  Business Research, doi:10.1016/j.jbusres.2011.03.005.##Gill, A., Flaschner A. B., Shah, C., Bhutani, I. (2010). &quot;The Relations of Transformational Leadership and Empowerment with Employee Job Satisfaction: A Study among Indian Restaurant Employees&quot;, Business and Economics Journal, Vol. 2010: BEJ-18.##Gumusluoglu, L; Ilsev, A. (2009). &quot;Transformational Leadership, Creativity, and Organizational Innovation&quot;, Journal of Business Research, Vol. 62, pp: 461-473.##Hersey ,P., Blanchard ,K., Dewey, J. (1996). &quot;Management of organizational behavior, New Jersey : Prentice – Hall.##Horwitz, I.B., Horwitz, S.K., Daram, P., Brandt, M. L., Brunicardi, F C., And Awad , S.S. (2008). &quot;Transformational , transactional , and passive-avoidant leadership characteristics of a surgical resident cohort; Analysis using the multifactor leadership questionnaire and implications for improving surgical education curriculums”, Journal of Surgical Research, Vol. 148, No.1, pp:49-59.##Hsiao, H.C., Chang, J.C. (2011). &quot;The role of organizational learning in transformational leadership and organizational innovation&quot;, Asia Pacific Educ. Rev, Vol. 12, pp: 621–631.##Hulland, j. (1999). &quot;Use of partial least squares (PLS) in strategic management research: A review of four recent studies&quot;, Strategic management journal, Vol. 20, No. 2, pp: 195-204.##Jaskyte, K. (2004). &quot;Transformational Leadership, Organizational Culture, and Innovativeness in Nonprofit Organizations&quot;, Nonprofit Management &amp; Leadership, vol. 15, No. 2, pp: 153-168.##Jung, D.I., Chow, C., Wu, A. (2003). &quot;The role of transformational leadership in enhancing organizational innovation: Hypotheses and some preliminary findings&quot;, The Leadership Quarterly, Vol. 14, pp: 525–544.##Jung, D. I., Wu, A., Chow, C. (2008). &quot;Towards understanding the direct and indirect effects of CEOs' transformational leadership on firm innovation&quot;, The Leadership Quarterly, Vol. 19, pp:582–594. ##Jimenez, J.D., Valle, R.S., Hernandez, M.E. (2008). &quot;Fostering Innovation: The role of market orientation and organizational learning&quot;, European Journal of Innovation Management, Vol. 11, No. 3, pp: 389-412.##Khan, R., Ur Rehman, A., Afsheen., F. (2009). &quot;Transformational leadership and organizational innovation: Moderated by organizational size&quot;, African Journal of Business Management Vol.3, No. 11, pp: 678-684.##Koene, B.A.S., Vogelaar, A.L.W. and Soeters, J.L. (2002). &quot;Leadership effects on organizational climate and financial performance:: Local leadership effect in chain organizations. The Leadership Quarterly, Vol. 13, No. 3, pp: 193-215.##Kreitner, R., &amp; Kinicki, A. (2006). &quot;Organizational behavior: Key concepts, skills and best practices&quot;, (2nd ed.). Boston: McGraw-Hill.##Ling, Y., Simsek, Z., Lubatkin, M. H., &amp; Veiga, J. F. (2008). &quot;Transformational leadership’s role in promoting corporate entrepreneurship: examining the CEO-TMT interface&quot;, Academy of Management Journal, Vol. 51, No. 3, pp:557–576.##Magliocca, L.A., Christakis, A.N. (2001). &quot;Creating transforming leadership for organizational change: the cogniscope system approach&quot;, System Research and Behavioral Science, Vol. 18, pp: 259- 277.##Matzler, K., Schwarz, E., Deutinger, N., Harms, R. (2008). &quot;The relationship between transformational leadership, product innovation and performance in SMEs&quot;, Journal of Small Business and Entrepreneurship, Vol. 21, No. 2, pp: 139-151.##McDonough, E.F. (2000), &quot;Investigation on factors contributing to the success of cross-functional teams&quot;, Journal of Product Innovation Management, Vol. 17, pp: 221-235.##Michaelis, B., Stegmaier, R., Sonntag, K. (2010). &quot;Shedding light on followers’ innovation implementation Behavior&quot;, Journal of Managerial Psychology, Vol. 25, No. 4, pp: 408-429.##Moriano, J.A., Molero, F. (2011). &quot;The influence of transformational leadership and organizational identification on entrepreneurship&quot;, Intentional Entrepreneurship Management  Journal, DOI 10.1007/s11365-011-0196-x.##Nienke M.M., Alan J. D., Peter J.C.S. (2010). &quot;Occupying the Principal Position: Examining Relationships Between Transformational Leadership, Social Network Position, and Schools' Innovative Climate&quot;, Educational Administration Quarterly, Vol, 46, No. 5, pp: 623– 670.##Nielsen, K., Cleal, B. (2011). &quot;Under which conditions do middle managers exhibit transformational leadership behaviors? An experience sampling method study on the predictors of transformational leadership behaviors&quot;, The Leadership Quarterly, Vol. 22, pp:344-352.##Ojasalo, J. (2008). &quot;Management of innovation networks: a case study of different ##Approaches&quot;, European Journal of Innovation Management, Vol. 11, No. 1, pp: 51-86.##Paulsen, N., Maldonado, D., Callan, V.J., Ayoko, O. (2009). &quot;Charismatic leadership, change and innovation in an R&amp;D organization&quot;, Journal of Organizational Change Management, Vol. 22, No. 5, pp: 511–523.##Perry-Smith, J. (2006). &quot;Social yet creative: the role of social relationships in facilitating individual creativity&quot;, Academy of Management Journal, Vol.49, pp: 85−102.##Pfeffer, J. (1998). &quot;The human equation: Building profits by putting people first&quot;, Boston, MA: Harvard Business School.##Puranam, P., Singh, H., &amp; Zollo, M. (2006). &quot;Organizing for innovation: managing the coordination-autonomy dilemma in technology acquisitions&quot;, Academy of Management Journal, Vol. 49, pp: 263−280.##Richard C.M., Yam, W.L., Esther, P.Y., Tang, A., Lau, K.W. (2011). &quot;Analysis of sources of innovation, technological innovation capabilities, and performance: An empirical study of Hong Kong manufacturing industries&quot;, Research Policy, Vol. 40, pp:391–402.##Sarros, J. C., Cooper, B. K., &amp; Santora, J. C. (2008). &quot;Building a climate for innovation through transformational leadership and organizational  culture&quot;, Journal of Leadership and Organizational Studies, Vol. 15, pp:145 – 158.##Skakon, J., Nielsen, K., Borg, V., &amp; Guzman, J.  (2010). &quot;Are leaders’ wellbeing, behaviors and style associated with the affective wellbeing of their employees?&quot;, A systematic review of three decades of research&quot;, Work &amp; Stress, Vol. 24, pp: 139-147.##Shin, S., &amp; Zhou, J. (2003). &quot;Transformational leadership, conservation, and creativity: evidence from Korea&quot;, Academy of Management Journal, Vol. 46, pp:703−714.##Stone, A. G., Russell, R. F., Patterson, K. (2004). &quot;Transformational versus servant leadership: a difference in leader focus&quot;, Leadership &amp; Organization Development Journal, Vol. 25, pp:349-361.##Tenenhaus, M., Vinzi, V. E., Chatalin, Y. M., &amp; Lauro, C. (2005).  &quot;PLS path modeling&quot;, Computational statistics &amp; Data analysis, Vol. 48, No. 1, pp: 159-205.##Ussahawanitchakit, P. (2008). &quot;Impacts of organizational learning on innovation orientation and firm efficiency: an empirical assessment of accounting firms in Thailand&quot;, International Journal of Business Research, Vol: 8, No. 4.##Weng, R.H., Huang, J.A., Kuo, Y.H., Huang, C.Y., Huang Y.C. (2011). &quot;Determinants of technological innovation and its effect on hospital performance&quot;, African Journal of Business Management, Vol. 5, No. 11, pp:4314-4327.##Yu Lin, C. (2007 ). &quot;Factors affecting innovation in logistics technologies for logistics service providers in China&quot;, Journal of Technology Management in China, Vol. 2, No. 1, pp: 22-37.##Zarei, A. (2007). &quot;Study of relationship between thinking styles organizational innovation in Shiraz school managers&quot;, Dissertation MSc of management, Shiraz University [In Persian].######رضوانی، حمید رضا؛ گرایلی نژاد، رضا. (1390). ارائه الگویی برای گونه شناسی انواع نوآوری سازمانی، فصلنامه تخصصی پارک ها و مراکز رشد، سال هفتم، شماره 28، ص 26-21.##موغلی، علیرضا (1383). رهبری تحول آفرین و ابزار سنجش آن. مجله مطالعات مدیریت، پاییز و زمستان 1383  شماره 43 و 44.##یوکل، گری (1382). مدیریت و رهبری در سازمان ها، ترجمه محمد ازگلی، قاسم قنبری، تهران: موسسه چاپ و انتشارات دانشگاه امام حسین## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>زمینه های انسانی، نهادی و اجتماعی  تولید و انتشار دانش و قابلیت های فناورانه در صنعت نفت ایران (1357-1387)</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Social and institutional context of technological capabilities and knowledge creation in Iran oil industry (1979-1908)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>مقاله حاضر به وضعیت دانش وزمینه های اجتماعی کسب قابلیت های فناورانه در یکی از بخش های مهم کشور یعنی صنعت نفت می پردازد.با بررسی وتحلیل مقالات علمی چاپ شده در فصل نامه انجمن نفت ایران تا سال1357&#160; وبررسی سایر نهاد های مرتبط، نخست سیمای وضعیت علمی وفناورانه&#160; این صنعت ترسیم می گردد.آنگاه نظام تولید وانتشار دانش واجزای تشکیل دهنده آن در زمینه ای تاریخی واجتماعی تحلیل می گردد.نتیجه آنکه علی رغم فعالیت های برجسته وموثر علمی وفنی در این بخش به ویژه از سوی انجمن مذکور بخش های سیاست گذار و پژوهشی دیگر نتوانسته اند جهت علمی ودانشی این بخش را به سوی تولید ونشر دانش روز وفناوری محور ودر نتیجه کسب قابلیت های نوآورانه ودانشی که زمینه ساز توسعه فناوری است سوق دهند.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>In this essay the situation of petroleum knowledge creation and dissemination in Iran oil industry and its technological capabilities have been investigated. This configuration and trend has been studied by a documentary method and content analysis of the scientific articles that published in&#160; a distinguished&#160; journal of Iran oil industry&#160; and so the related structures during&#160; 1979-1908.the result is that ,however&#160; so many brilliant activities and technological&#160; outputs&#160; in this sector developed but the policy makers and research-oriented&#160; sections couldn't&#160; go ahead&#160; and the set the direction of industry to a knowledge and technology oriented trend and&#160; sector .so it&#160; couldn't reach to the innovation capabilities that are the foundation of technology development in oil industry.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>199</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>226</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مهدی زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammadreza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mehdizadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mahdizam@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رضوی</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rezavi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم وتحقیقات</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد علوم وتحقیقات</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Iran oil industry's institutions- knowledge-technological capabilities- research- Iran petroleum association</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>صنعت نفت ایران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دانش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تحقیق</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>انجمن نفت ایران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تولید وانتشار دانش</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>قابلیت های فناورانه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Costa,Irona et al(2001) FDI And Technological Capabilities In The Brazilian Industry, DRUID – Nelson and Winter Conference - June 2001.##Crinson,Mark(1997) Abadan: planning and architecture under the Anglo-Iranian Oil Company,planning prespective,vol.12,no.3,1 july,pp.341-359##Dahlman, C.J., B. Ross-Larson, and L.B. Westphal.(1987) &quot;Managing Technological Development: Lessons from Newly Industrializing Countries.&quot; World Development 15 (1987), no. 6: 759-775.##Ehsani Kaveh(2003) , Social Engineering and the Contradictions of Modernization in Khuzestan's Company Towns: A Look at Abadan and Masjed-Soleyman, International Review of Social History, 48(2003), pp.361-399 has seen in www.iranian.com.##Fransman, Martin (1984). Technological capability in the Third World: an overview and introduction to some of the issues. In: Fransman, Martin E King, Kenneth (Eds.). Technological capacity in the Third Word. London : Macmillan, 1984. p. 3-30.##Katz, J.(1984) &quot;Domestic Technological Innovation and Dynamic Comparative Advantage: Further Reflections on a Comparative Case Study Program.&quot; Journal of Development Economics 16 (1984), no. 1: 13-38.##Katz, J., ed.(1987) Technology Generation in Latin American Manufacturing Industries. London: Macmillan##Lall, S. (1992). Technological capabilities and industrialization. World Dev., 20(2), 165-186##Lall, S. (2000). Technological Change and Industrialization in the Asian Newly Industrializing Economies:Achievements and Challenges. In Technology, Learning &amp; Innovation –Experiences of Newly Industrializing Economies (L.Kim and R.R. Nelson, ed.), Chap.2, pp.13-68. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge.##Salomon, J.-J.; Sagasti, F.R.; Sachs-Jeantet, C.(1994),The Uncertain Quest: Science, Technology and Development. United Nations University Press, Tokyo, Japan.##Dantas Eva , Bell Martin  (20011), The Co-Evolution of Firm-Centered Knowledge Networks and Capabilities in Late Industrializing Countries: The Case of Petrobras in the Offshore Oil Innovation System in Brazil , World Development,Volume 39, Issue 9, September 2011, Pages 1570-1591.## Mohamed A.S , et al (2010) Modeling technology transfer for petroleum industry in Libya: An overview Scientific Research and Essay Vol. 5 (2), pp. 130-147, 18 January, 2010, Available online at http://www.academicjournals.org/SRE##روحانی ,فواد (1352)؛ تاریخ ملی شدن صنعت نفت ایران,شرکت سهامی کتاب های جیبی ##روحانی ,فواد (2536) ,صنعت نفت ایران: 20 سال پس از ملی شدن, شرکت سهامی کتاب های جیبی.##شرکت ملی نفت ایران(1344)تاریخچه ومتن قراردادهای مربوط به نفت ایران،انتشارات شرکت ملی نفت ایران##شرکت ملی نفت ایران(1355) تازه های نفت؛روابط عمومی.##عباسی شهنی،دانش(1374)،تاریخ مسجد سلیمان: تاریخ تحولات صنعت نفت،انتشارات هیرمند.##فرشادگهر، ناصر(1381) سیری در قراردادهای نفتی ایران ، انتشاراتپژوهشکده امور اقتصادی.##لهسایی زاده،عبدالعلی(1385)جامعه شناسی آبادان،چاپ دوم،چاپ اول 1384 نشر کیان مهر.##مستوفی، باقر(2001) صنعت پتروشیمی ایران: از آغاز تا آستانه انقلاب، مصاحبه با باقر مستوفی، نخستین مدیرعامل شرکت ملی پتروشیمی ایران، بنیاد مطالعات ایران.##مینا ،پرویز(1998/1377) ، تحول صنعت نفت ایران : نگاهی از درون، مصاحبه با پرویز مینا، ویراستار: غلامرضا    افخمی، بنیاد مطالعات ایران.##نامه انجمن صنعت نفت(1339) اساسنامه واعضای هیئت موسس واعضای  انجمن نفت ایران،ش یک.##نامه صنعت(2535) ویژه نامه اول فروردین 2535(1355)##هفته نامه یاداشت روز(1353)، ش 2797  ص 2 ،  6/6/1353،روابط عمومی شرکت ملی نفت ایران.##وزارت نفت(1385) نفت وتوسعه ، اداره کل روابط عمومی وزارت نفت## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر رهبری معنوی بر عدالت سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی کارکنان شرکت گاز استان اردبیل</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Study of Spiritual Leadership Impact on Organizational Justice and Organizational Commitment of Employees of company Gas Ardabil Province</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>تحقیق حاضر با هدف تعیین تأثیر رهبری معنوی بر عدالت سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی کارکنان شرکت گاز استان اردبیل انجام شده است. روش تحقیق توصیفی بوده و جامعه آماری این تحقیق شامل کلیه کارکنان رسمی شرکت گاز استان اردبیل می باشد. نمونه آماری با توجه به محدود بودن حجم جامعه آماری، با استفاده از رابطه تعیین حجم نمونه در جامعه&#173; های محدود 70 نفر تعیین شده است. این&#160; تعداد با استفاده از روش نمونه گیری تصادفی ساده انتخاب شده اند. برای جمع &#173;آوری داده &#173;های لازم از سه پرسشنامه استفاده شده است. روایی پرسشنامه &#173;ها به صورت روایی سازه ای و پایایی آن&#173;ها با استفاده از ضریب آلفای کرونباخ و به تفکیک مولفه&#173; های رهبری معنوی، عدالت سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی محاسبه شده است. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داد ه &#173;ها از آزمون&#173; های رگرسیون تک متغیره و کلموگروف- اسمیرنوف استفاده شده است. نتایج یافته های پژوهش نشان داده است که رهبری معنوی بر عدالت سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی تأثیر دارد.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>The present study aimed to assess the impact of spiritual leadership on organizational justice and organizational commitment of Gas Company employees of Ardabil province. The research method was descriptive and statistical population includes all official personnel of Gas Company. The research sample includes 70 people selected by the sampling formula in limited population. These numbers are selected using Simple Random Sampling. For collecting intransitive data, three questionnaires were used. To its validity if formal validity and reliability using Cronbach's alpha coefficient and the breakdown of the moral component leadership, organizational justice and organizational commitment has been calculated. For analysis of these data simple variable Regression and Kolmogorov-Smironov test has been used. Results indicate that spiritual leadership has an impact on organizational justice and organizational commitment.</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>227</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>255</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>هوشنگ</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>تقی زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Hooshang</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>taghizadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>Taghizadeh@iaut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>عبد الحسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شکری</Family>
				<NameE>abdolhossein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>shokri</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تبریز</Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>دانشگاه آزاد تبریز</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ایران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>spiritual leadership- organizational justice- organizational commitment</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رهبری معنوی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عدالت سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تعهد سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Allen, N.J. &amp; Meyer, J.P (1990), &quot;The measurement and antccedents  of  affective, continueance  and  normative  commitments to the organization&quot;. Journal  of  occupational  Psychology, Vol.63, No.1 , pp.1-18.##Colquitt, J. A (2005),  on  the  Dimensionality  of  organizational  Justice: A construct  Validation  of  a  Measure, Journal  of  Applied  Psychology, Vol.86, No. 3, pp. 386-400.##Daft, R. l., &amp; Lengel, R.H (1998), Fusion leadership: Unlocking the subtle forces   that  change people and organization، San  Francisco, CA: Berret- Koehler.##Dent. E.B, Higgins .M .E, Wharff .D.M (2005), Spirituality and Leadership:An Empirical Review of Definitions, Distinctions, and Embedded Assumptions, The Leadership Quarterly, Vol.16, No.5, 625-653.##  DeConinck, J.B. &amp; Stilwell, C. D (2004), Incorporating organizational justice, role states, pay satisfaction and supervisor satisfaction in a model of turnover intentions, Journal of Business Research, No.57, No. 3, pp. 225– 231.##Fields, D., M. Pang &amp; Chiu, C (2001), Distributive and procedural justice as predictors of employee outcomes in Hong Kong. Journal of Organization Behavior, No. 21, pp. 574 – 562.##Fry,L.W.&amp; Matherly,L.L (2006), Spiritual  leadership  and organizational Performance: An Exploratory  study, Tarleton state  university- central Texas. ##Fry,  L.  w (2003), Toward  a  theory  of  Sprititual   leadership,  The   leadership  Quarterly,  Vol. 14, No.6, pp.693-727.##Fry, L.  W., Vittuci, S. &amp; Cedillo, M (2005), Spiritual   leadership  and army   transformation: Theory  measurement, and  establishing  a  baseline,  The   leadership  Quartery  Vol.16, pp.835-862.##Greenbreg, J., &amp; Scott, k. s (2001), Why do workers bite the hands that feed them? employee theft as a social exchange process, in B.M  Staw and L.L Cummings (Eds.), Research in  Organizational Behavior, Vol. 18, Greenwich, CT:JAI Press.##Gilliland, S (2008), The tails of justice: A critical examination of the dimensionality of organizational  justice constructs. Human Resource Management Review, Vol. 18, No.4, pp. 271-281.##Greenberg. J. &amp; Baron. A. (2000), Behavior in organizations. New Jersy.##Gibbons, P (2001), spirituality at work: A pre-Theoritical overview, Msc. Thesis- Birnbeck  college, university  of London, Aug. employee  citizenship?. Journal of  Applied  Psychology, Vol.76, pp. 845-855.##Gumusluoglu, L., Karakitapoğlu-Aygün, Z. &amp; Hirst, G (2012), Transformational leadership and R&amp;D workers' multiple commitments: Do justice and span of control matter?, Journal of Business Research, In press.##Tyler, T. R., &amp; Lind, E. A (1998). The social psychology of proci 9 dural justice. Newyork: plenum press.##Tatum, B. Charles; Eberlin, Richard; Kottraba, Carin; Bradberry, Travis(2003)،Leadership،decision making،and organizational justice Management Decision vol. 41 issue 10 December 01, pp. 1006-1016.##Luthans, F (2008), Organizational behavior. Boston: McGraw Hill.##Mowday, R. T., Steers, R.M., &amp; Porter, L.W (1979), The measurement of   organizational commitment، Journal  of  vocational  Behavior, Vol.14, No.1, pp. 224-247.##Schaubroeck, J., D.R. May &amp; Brown, F.W (1994), Procedural justice explanations and reactions to economic hardship: a field experiment, Journal of Applied Psychology, No. 79, pp. 455- 460.##-Ponnu.C. H. and Chuah.C.C (2010), Organizational commitment, organizational justice and##employee turnover in Malaysia،Vol. 4,No.13, pp. 2676-2692.##Robbins. I (2003), Spirituality, and Religion Interest Group's Proposed Minutes, From the Academy of Management's August 5, Management, pp.5-39.####افجهء، سید علی اکبر(1385)، مبانی فلسفی و تئوری‌های رهبری و رفتار سازمانی، چاپ چهارم، انتشارات سمت، صص 333- 317.##امیرخانی، طیبه و پورعزت، علی اصغر(1387)، تأملی بر امکان توسعه سرمایه اجتماعی در پرتو عدالت سازمانی در سازمان‌های دولتی، نشریه مدیریت دولتی، شماره 1، ص 19-32.##انصاری، محمد اسماعیل؛ باقری کَلجاهی، علی و مسلم صالحی(1389)، تعهد سازمانی از دیدگاه نظریه پردازان و نقش راهبردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی در بهبود آن، دو ماهنامه توسعه ی انسانی پلیس، سال هفتم، شماره 31، ص 46-40.##-بهرام زاده، حسین علی و یادگاری، منصوره(1387)، تحلیل رابطه عدالت سازمانی با تعهد سازمانی، مدیریت فردا، شماره 21،ص 64-55.## پورعزت، علی اصغر(1387) ، مختصات حکومت حق مدار در پرتو نهج البلاغه امام علی (ع)، تهران، شرکت انتشارات علمی و فرهنگی.##حسین‌زاده، علی(1385)، عدالت سازمانی، تدبیر، شماره 190، صص 23- 18.##رابینز، استیفن(1378)، مبانی رفتار سازمانی، ترجمه علی پارسائیان و محمد اعرابی، دفتر پژوهش های فرهنگی، جلد دوم.##رضائیان، علی( 1384)، انتظار عدل و عدالت سازمانی، تهران، انتشارات سمت.##رضائیان، علی(1386)، مبانی مدیریت رفتار سازمانی، انتشارات سمت.##رهنمای رودپشتی، فریدون و محمود زاده، ناصر (1387)، توسعه منابع انسانی  مطالعه موردی، تعلق و تعهد سازمانی و رقابت پذیری، تهران، سازمان مدیریت صنعتی،صص133-122.##رابینز، استیفن (1389)، مدیریت رفتار سازمانی (جلد اول)، ترجمه علی پارساییان و سید  محمد اعرابی، چاپ بیست و ششم تهران، انتشارات دفتر پژوهش های فرهنگی.##رنجبریان، بهرام(1375)، تعهد سازمانی، مجله دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصادی دانشگاه اصفهان، سال دهم، شماره 12، ص 57-41.##سید جوادین، سیدرضا(1384)، مروری جامع بر نظریه های مدیریت و سازمان، انتشارات نگاه دانش، چاپ دوم.##سید جوادین، سیدرضا؛ فراحی، محمد مهدی  و طاهری عطار، غزاله(1387)، شناخت نحوه تاثیر گذاری ابعاد عدالت سازمانی بر جنبه های گوناگون رضایت شغلی و سازمانی، نشریه مدیریت بازرگانی، شماره 1، صص 55-70.##ضیائی، محمد صادق، نرگسیان، عباس و آیباغی اصفهانی، سعید (1387)، نقش رهبری معنوی در توانمند سازی کارکنان دانشگاه تهران، نشریه مدیریت دولتی، دوره 1، شماره1،ص 86-67.##گل پرور، محسن (1388)؛ فرا انگیزه های عدالت سازمانی در کارکنان و مدیران صنایع و سازمان ها، مجله علوم انسانی، شماره 65، ص 11-34.##گل پرور، محسن و نادی، محمد علی (1388)، رابطه شناخت عدالت و رفتارهای مشتری مداری در پرستاران مدیریت سلامت،  ش 12، صص 70-61.##مومنی، منصور و قیومی، فعال(1386)، تحلیل های آماری با استفاده از spss، تهران، انتشارات کتاب نو.## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
