<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>8</volume>
<number>29</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی معیارهای اعطای تسهیلات مسکن در صنعت نفت با استفاده از پژوهش آمیخته</title_fa>
	<title>Identification and Ranking of Criteria for Distributing Mortgage Loan Among Applicants in the Iranian Petroleum Industry Based On a Mixed Methodology Study</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;صنعت نفت که از دیرباز در اعطای تسهیلات رفاهی- درمانی پیشگام بوده است به موضوع تامین مسکن مناسب به عنوان یکی از نیازهای اساسی کارکنان و خانواده آن&#8204;ها توجه و اهتمام جدی داشته است. علیرغم قدمت و اهمیت مساله، در بررسی ادبیات موضوع پژوهش جامعی که معیارهای اعطای تسهیلات مسکن به کارکنان را جمع&#8204;آوری و دسته&#8204;بندی نموده و بر اساس آن روشی برای رتبه&#8204;بندی ارایه داده باشد، یافت نشد. با توجه به در هم تنیدگی ابعاد و پیچیدگی تعیین، تفسیر و دسته&#8204;بندی معیارهای اعطای تسهیلات مسکن ضرورت دارد روشی کیفی بمنظور استخراج،&#8204; بررسی و جمع&#8204;آوری معیارهای موثر بر انتخاب کارکنان جهت اعطای تسهیلات مسکن در صنعت نفت در کنار روشی کمّی بمنظور اولویت&#8204;دهی و رتبه&#8204;بندی معیارهای شناسایی شده بکارگرفته شود. لذا از روش تحقیق آمیخته اکتشافی در این پژوهش استفاده شده است. در حقیقت با ترکیب روش &amp;laquo;مصاحبه پژوهش کیفی&amp;raquo; که تاکنون به طور وسیعی در مطالعات سازمان و مدیریت مورد استفاده قرار گرفته است و نیز روش کمّی &amp;laquo;تصمیم&#8204;گیری چند شاخصه خاکستری&amp;raquo; دستیابی به اهداف پژوهش میسر گردیده است. استفاده از روش تصمیم&#8204;گیری چند شاخصه خاکستری ارائه شده، بدون نیاز به انجام مقایسات زوجی معیارها امکان ارزیابی ریاضیاتی داده&#8204;های غیر قطعی (وابسته به قضاوت خبرگان) بمنظور رتبه&#8204;بندی معیارها را فراهم ساخته است..&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Providing the oil and gas industry personnel with housing services and opportunities has been one of the most important supporting services offered by the Ministry of petroleum historically. Mortgage lending is one of these housing opportunities. In fact the vast majority of home purchases among the petroleum industry personnel are made with the help of the mortgage loans. Reviewing the administrative background of distributing the mortgage loans among applicants shows that a comprehensive research on the criteria and methodology of selecting candidate personnel has not been accomplished. So, in this study a mixed methodology approach was adopted to identify and rank the important criteria for Distributing Mortgage Loan among Applicants in the Iranian Petroleum Industry. First, the qualitative research interviews were conducted to collect the experts' opinions in order to identify and classify the related criteria. Second, a quantitative methodology was used in order to rank the identified criteria using &amp;quot;Grey Multi Attribute Decision Making&amp;quot; approach.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa> تسهیلات مسکن , وام مسکن , روش تحقیق آمیخته , رتبه بندی معیارها</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Grey Multi Attribute Decision Making (GMADM) Mortgage LoanCriteria Identification and Ranking</keyword>
	<start_page>99</start_page>
	<end_page>115</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-160-6&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Azadeh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Dabbaghi </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>آزاده</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>دباغی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>dabbaghi@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846002084</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002084</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>مطالعات بین المللی انرژی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
