<ici-import>
 <journal 	issn="2588-4409"/>
 <issue number="35" volume="9" year="2018" publicationDate="2018-06-01T10:20:15" numberOfArticles="8">
			<article externalId="A-10-25-26">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>واکاوی نوین ویژگی‌های رفتار مرشدانه مدیران در شرکت پالایش نفت اصفهان و اعتبارسنجی آن</title>
						<abstract>مفهوم &#171;رفتار مرشدانه مدیران&#187; در ادبیات رفتار سازمانی و مدیریت منابع انسانی جایگاه قابل&#8204;توجهی داشته و اندیشمندان عرصه ی مدیریت نظرات متفاوتی در مورد آن ارائه کرده&#8204;اند. پژوهش حاضر در تلاش است تا ویژگی&#8204;های رفتار مرشدانه مدیران را از زوایای نوینی واکاوی نماید. این پژوهش با رویکرد آمیخته اکتشافی و با استفاده از رویکرد تحلیل محتوای قراردادی در بخش کیفی انجام شده است. برای این منظور ضمن انجام مصاحبه نیمه&#8204;ساختاریافته عمیق با 20 نفر از مدیران شرکت پالایش نفت اصفهان، مجموعه&#8204;ای از مضامین اولیه طی فرایند کدگذاری گردآوری و سپس از درون آن&#8204;ها مقوله&#8204;هایی استخراج گردید. نتایج حاصل از کدگذاری&#8204;ها و تحلیل داده&#8204;ها نشان داد که ویژگی&#8204;های رفتار مرشدانه مدیران متفاوت بوده و بر مبنای تفاوت&#8204;ها، در قالب پنج ویژگی رفتاری با عناوین، &#171;رفتار همنوایانه&#187;، &#171;رفتار کمال&#8204;گرایانه&#187;، &#171;رفتار خودمدیرانه&#187;، &#171;رفتار نقش&#8204;مدارانه&#187; و &#171;رفتار اثرگذارانه&#187; طبقه&#8204;بندی گردید به طوری که هریک از این رفتارها خود در برگیرنده مفاهیم دیگری است. پس از کشف مقوله&#8204;های مدل ارائه شده در مرحله کیفی، به&#8204;منظور اعتبارسنجی کمی مدل استخراج شده، پرسشنامه&#8204;ای مشتمل بر 80 گویه، طراحی و تنظیم شد و در اختیار 191 نفر از زیرمجموعه تحت سرپرستی مدیران ارشد و میانی به صورت نمونه&#8204;گیری در دسترس قرار گرفت و اعتبار مدل به صورت کمی نیز &#8204;تأیید شد.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-304-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>32</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>رفتار مرشدانه مدیران</keyword>
<keyword>مرشدیت</keyword>
<keyword>تحلیل محتوای قراردادی</keyword>
<keyword>شرکت پالایش نفت اصفهان</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Uncovering of the mentorship behavior characteristics of managers in Isfahan Oil Refinery Company</title>
						<abstract>The concept of &#8220;Mentorship behavior of managers&#8221; is significant in organizational behavior and human resource management literature in which diverse opinions are expressed by many human resource scholars throughout the world. This study was performed with a mixed exploratory approach by using the conventional content analysis in qualitative section. The purpose of this qualitative study was to explore the mentorship behavior characteristics of managers in Isfahan Oil Refinery Company using content analysis&#8217;s systematic design. For this purpose, a semi-structured and in-dept interview with 20 managers of the Company was conducted. The analysis of research data led to a group of initial themes as well as categories through a coding process. Research analysis of semi-structured interviews indicated that mentorship behaviors of the managers under study may be classified under five behaviors including: resonant behavior, perfectionist behavior, self-management behavior, rolling-based behavior and influencing behavior, while each of these behaviors are in turn composed of different concepts. After discovering the category of model presented in the qualitative stage، 80-item questionnaire was designed and regulated to qualitatively validate the extracted model and it was provided for 191 employees under the supervision of senior and middle managers by available sampling method and finally, the validity of the model was qualitatively verified.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-304-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>3</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>32</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>The mentorship behavior characteristics</keyword>
<keyword>mentoring</keyword>
<keyword>conventional approach</keyword>
<keyword>Isfahan Oil Refinery Company</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Maryam</name>
	<surname>Ahmadi Zahrani</surname>
	<email>maryam_ahmadi2266@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Shams-e-din</name>
	<surname>Nazemi</surname>
	<email>nazemi_shm@um.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>– Fariborz</name>
	<surname>Rahimnia</surname>
	<email>r-nia@um.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>3</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Saeed</name>
	<surname>Mortazavi</surname>
	<email>@um.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>4</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-25-27">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>بررسی تأثیر مدیریت شادمان سازی (نشاط) بر عملکرد کارکنان شرکت گاز منطقه دو اصفهان بر مبنای مدل استیرز</title>
						<abstract>شادمان سازی پرسنل به عنوان یک حوزه مطالعاتی در روانشناسی و مدیریت منابع انسانی، اهمیت زیادی برای مدیران و کارکنان پیدا کرده است. شادی در محیط کار زمانی حاصل می&#8204;شود که فرد جهت دستیابی به اهداف کاری ، از توانایی ها و استعدادهای خود استفاده نماید. هدف این تحقیق پاسخگویی به&#160; این سوال است که آیا شادمان سازی (نشاط) پرسنل بر عملکرد شغلی آنها تاثیر دارد. در این پژوهش از مدل ریچارد ام. استیرز استفاده شده است. روش انجام این تحقیق از نوع توصیفی همبستگی از شاخه میدانی، از لحاظ ماهیت، کاربردی و از لحاظ زمان، مقطعی می&#8204;باشد. جامعه آماری تحقیق شامل کارکنان شرکت گاز منطقه دو اصفهان با 800 نفر کارمند و انتخاب نمونه ای 256 نفره بر اساس فرمول تعیین حجم نمونه و به روش نمونه گیری طبقه ای تصادفی بود. شیوه گردآوری اطلاعات شامل مطالعات کتابخانه ای و ابزار پرسشنامه محقق ساخته بود. روایی محتوائی و صوری توسط صاحب نظران&#160; و پایایی ابزار تحقیق با ضریب آلفای کرونباخ (082/) محاسبه گردید. در نهایت، هر ده فرضیه مربوط به تاثیر مولفه های شادمان سازی بر عملکرد مورد تائید قرارگرفته و در رتبه بندی متغیرها عامل یادگیری و علاقه به کار به ترتیب با 6/38 و 6/09 رتبه ، بیشترین میانگین را داشته اند.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-305-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>33</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>58</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>شادمان سازی (نشاط)</keyword>
<keyword>یادگیری</keyword>
<keyword>علاقه به کار</keyword>
<keyword>عملکرد سازمانی</keyword>
<keyword>عدالت سازمانی</keyword>
<keyword>شرکت گاز</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Studying the Effects of Employees Happiness Management System on Employees\' Performance Based On Steers\' Model (Case: Isfahan Branch Gas Company)</title>
						<abstract>According to the increasing changes and developments in organizations, the managers are seeking to improve the staff performance to a large degree. In this way, they want to increase the functionality of organization production. Rise of happiness among staff which is a field of study in psychology and human resource management, has recently become important for managers and employees. Happiness in workplace comes when a person uses his abilities and talents to achieve his goals. The purpose of this research is to answer the question of whether employees' happiness affects their job performance. In this research, Richard M. Steers' model has been used. The research method is descriptive-correlation, practical in terms of nature, and sectional in terms of time period. The statistical population of the study consisted of employees of Isfahan's gas company with 800 employees and a sample selection of 256 people based on the sample size formula and random stratified sampling method. The information gathering method included library studies and a researcher-made questionnaire. The validity of questionnaire was determined by the experts and the reliability of the research tool was calculated using Cronbach's alpha coefficient (0.82). Finally, all ten hypotheses related to the effect of happiness components on performance have been confirmed. In rating of variables, learning factor and job interest had the highest mean with 6.38 and 6.9, respectively.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-305-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>33</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>58</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>happiness</keyword>
<keyword>learning</keyword>
<keyword>job desire</keyword>
<keyword>organizational performance</keyword>
<keyword>organizational justice</keyword>
<keyword>Gas Company</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Seyed Rasool</name>
	<surname>Aghadavood</surname>
	<email>aghadavood@dehaghan.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-25-28">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>پیش‌بینی خودکارآمدی از طریق عزت نفس و حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده (مورد مطالعه: شرکت گاز استان اصفهان)</title>
						<abstract>به دلیل نقش و تاثیر خودکارآمدی بر بسیاری از متغیر های رفتاری در محیط کار، پژوهش در مورد آن و شناسایی عوامل تاثیر گذار بر آن مورد توجه پژوهشگران قرار گرفته است. به همین جهت، این پژوهش با هدف بررسی امکان پیش بینی خودکارآمدی از طریق عزت نفس و حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده به اجرا در آمد. روش پژوهش از نوع توصیفی - همبستگی بوده و جامعه&#8204;ی آماری پژوهش را کارکنان شرکت گاز استان اصفهان به تعداد 733 نفر تشکیل داده است. نمونه&#8204;ی پژوهش بر اساس جدول حجم نمونه به حجم جامعه آماری میچل و جولی (2007)، شامل 248 نفر از کارکنان این سازمان بود که با استفاده از نمونه&#8204;گیری در دسترس انتخاب شدند. ابزارهای پژوهش شامل پرسشنامه&#8204; های حمایت سازمانی (آیزنبرگر و همکاران،1986)، عزت نفس روزنبرگ (1965) و خودکارآمدی عمومی (شرر و مادوکس،1982) بود. داده&#8204;ها از طریق ضریب همبستگی پیرسون، تحلیل رگرسیون گام به گام مورد تحلیل قرار گرفت. یافته&#8204;ها نشان داد که بین حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده و خودکارآمدی، بین حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده و عزت نفس و بین عزت نفس و خودکارآمدی رابطه معناداری وجود دارد (0/01p&#60;). همچنین بین حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده، عزت نفس و خودکارآمدی رابطه چندگانه ترکیبی وجود دارد (0/01p&#60;) . حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده و عزت نفس توانستند تا 30 درصد از واریانس خودکارآمدی را تبیین کنند. بنابراین، میتوان چنین نتیجه گیری نمود که برای افزایش خودکارآمدی ، می&#8204;توان عزت نفس کارکنان و حمایت سازمانی را افزایش داد.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-306-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>59</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>82</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>خودکارآمدی</keyword>
<keyword>حمایت سازمانی ادراک شده</keyword>
<keyword>عزت نفس</keyword>
<keyword>شرکت گاز</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Predicting of Self – Efficacy through Perceived Organizational Support and Self – Esteem (Case: Isfahan province Gas Company)</title>
						<abstract>Research in relation of self-efficacy and the identification of factors affecting it, has been of interest to researchers due to its role and its impact on many behavioral variables in the workplace. Accordingly, this research carried out with the aim of predicting self &#8211; efficacy through perceived organizational support and self &#8211; esteem. Research method was descriptive-correlational and statistical population was all employees of Isfahan province Gas Company. Using convenience sampling, 248 subjects were selected. &#160;They were assessed by perceived organizational support questionnaire (Eisenberger et al., 1986), self - esteem questionnaire (Rosenberg, 1965) and self - efficacy questionnaire (Sheerer &#38; Maddux, 1982). Data were analyzed by use of Pearson correlation coefficient and stepwise regression analysis. Results showed that there was significant relationship between Perceived organizational support and self - efficacy (p&#60;0.01), perceived organizational support and self - esteem (p&#60;0.01), self - esteem and self - efficacy (p&#60;0.01). Moreover results of stepwise regression analysis showed that there were multiple relationship between perceived organizational support, self &#8211; efficacy and self &#8211; esteem (p&#60;0.01) and perceived organizational support and self &#8211;esteem could predict 30% of self &#8211; efficacy&#8217; variances. According to these findings, for increasing employees&#8217; self &#8211; efficacy in organizations, we should pay more attention to employees&#8217; self &#8211; esteem and organizational support.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-306-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>59</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>82</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>Perceived organizational support</keyword>
<keyword>self - efficacy</keyword>
<keyword>self- esteem</keyword>
<keyword>Gas Company</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Ali</name>
	<surname>Mahdad</surname>
	<email>amahdad@khuisf.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Zahra</name>
	<surname>Adibi</surname>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Soroosh</name>
	<surname>Saffari</surname>
	     <order>3</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-25-29">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>بررسی نقش میانجی بلوغ سازمانی در تاثیر سبک‌های رهبری بر تعهد سازمانی کارکنان (مورد مطالعه : مجموعه پتروشیمی‌های عسلویه)</title>
						<abstract>حوزه منابع انسانی از تعاملات و ارتباطات متقابلی با حوزه&#8204;های کارکردی و عملیاتی مختلف در سازمان&#8204;ها برخوردار می&#8204;باشد و از همین روی می&#8204;تواند اثرگذاری شایان توجهی بر عملکرد سازمان&#8204;ها و دستیابی به اهداف سازمانی داشته باشد. بنابراین، سازمان&#8204;ها به مدیران و کارکنان اثربخش و کارآمدی نیاز دارند تا بتوانند به اهداف خود در جهت رشد و توسعه همه جانبه دست یابند. در این پژوهش قصد داریم به بررسی نقش میانجی بلوغ سازمانی در تاثیر سبک&#8204;های رهبری بر تعهد سازمانی کارکنان در مجموعه پتروشیمی&#8204;های عسلویه بپردازیم. بواسطه بررسی ادبیات موضوع در حوزه&#8204;های تحقیق، از الگوی سبک رهبری اولیو و باس (2004) (سبک رهبری تحول&#8204;آفرین و تبادلی) به&#8204;منظور تعیین سبک رهبری مدیران، از الگوی تعهد سازمانی آلن و می&#8204;یر (1990) (تعهد عاطفی، تعهد مستمر، تعهد هنجاری) به&#8204;عنوان مبنای سنجش وضعیت تعهد سازمانی کارکنان و از الگوی قابلیت&#8204;های منابع انسانی (P-CMM) به&#8204;منظور تعیین سطح بلوغ سازمانی کارکنان بهره گرفته شد. داده&#8204;ها با استفاده از نرم&#8204;افزار Smart-PLS تجزیه و تحلیل شدند. نتایج بدست آمده نشان داد بین سبک&#8204;های رهبری مدیران با تعهد سازمانی کارکنان در مجموعه پتروشیمی&#8204;های عسلویه رابطه معناداری وجود دارد. همچنین بلوغ سازمانی در تاثیر سبک&#8204;های رهبری بر تعهد سازمانی کارکنان در مجموعه پتروشیمی&#8204;های عسلویه نقش میانجی دارد.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-307-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>83</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>104</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>بلوغ سازمانی</keyword>
<keyword>سبک‌های رهبری تحول آفرین</keyword>
<keyword>سبک رهبری تبادلی</keyword>
<keyword>تعهد سازمانی</keyword>
<keyword>مجموعه پتروشیمی‌های عسلویه</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Investigating the Mediating Role of Organizational Maturity on the Impact of Leadership Styles on Employee Organizational Commitment (Case: Assaluyeh Petrochemical Complex)</title>
						<abstract>The human resources domain has interactions and communications with different functional and operational areas in organizations and can therefore have a significant impact on the performance of organizations and the achievement of organizational goals. Therefore, organizations need effective and efficient managers and employees in order to achieve their goals for comprehensive growth and development. In this research, we intend to investigate the mediating role of organizational maturity on the impact of leadership styles on employees' organizational commitment in Assaluyeh Petrochemical Complex. By studying the related literature in the areas of research, we considered the Avolio and Bass (2004) model (Transformational and Transactional Leadership Styles) in order to determine the leadership style of managers ; and the Allen &#38; Meyer (1990) organizational commitment pattern (emotional commitment, continuous commitment, normative commitment) as a basis for assessing the status of Organizational commitment of staff ; and we applied the human resource capability model (P-CMM) to determine the level of employees' organizational maturity. Data was analyzed using Smart-PLS software. The results showed that there is a significant relationship between leadership style of managers with organizational commitment of employees in Assaluyeh petrochemical complex. Also, organizational maturity has a mediator role in the impact of leadership styles on organizational commitment of employees in Assaluyeh Petrochemical Complex.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-307-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>83</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>104</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>Organizational Maturity</keyword>
<keyword>Transformational Leadership Styles</keyword>
<keyword>Transactional Leadership Style</keyword>
<keyword>Organizational Commitment</keyword>
<keyword>Assaluyeh Petrochemical Complex</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Toraj</name>
	<surname>Hassanzadeh Samarin</surname>
	<email>to_hassan@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Alireza</name>
	<surname>Sahranavard</surname>
	<email>alirezasahranavard1393@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-25-30">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>بررسی رابطه هوش هیجانی، تعهد سازمانی و رضایت شغلی با ویژگی های جمعیت شناختی کارکنان ( مورد مطالعه: شرکت نفت مناطق مرکزی ایران)</title>
						<abstract>هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی مقایسه ای تفاوت هوش هیجانی، تعهد سازمانی و رضایت شغلی کارکنان شرکت نفت مناطق مرکزی ایران به تفکیک متغیرهای جمعیت شناختی (سن، سابقه خدمت، تحصیلات، پست سازمانی و جنسیت) می باشد. نوع تحقیق کاربردی بوده و از بعد روش، توصیفی - پیمایشی است. جامعه آماری پژوهش، کارکنان این شرکت نفتی بوده است که تعداد 359 نفر حجم نمونه به طور تصادفی ساده و با استفاده از جدول مورگان انتخاب شده و پرسشنامه&#8204;های استاندارد بین آنان توزیع شده است. بررسی نتایج نشان داد که دو متغیر هوش هیجانی و رضایت شغلی ضمن قرار گرفتن در وضعیت مطلوب ، در بین گروه های مختلف سنی، سابقه خدمت، پست سازمانی و جنسیت دارای تفاوت معناداری بوده اند. لیکن، متغیر تعهد سازمانی از وضعیت مطلوب کمی فاصله داشته ولی میزان آن بین گروه های مختلف سنی، سابقه خدمت، تحصیلات و پست سازمانی دارای تفاوت معناداری می&#8204;باشد. نتایج تحقیق حاکی از آن است که هر چه سن، پست سازمانی و سابقه شغلی فرد بیشتر می شود، هوش هیجانی وی نیز ارتقا پیدا کرده است. همچنین با ارتقاء پست سازمانی افراد، رضایت شغلی و تعهد سازمانی آن&#8204;ها افزایش یافته است. از طرف دیگر با افزایش سن و سابقه کاری، رضایت شغلی نیز افزایش داشته است. یافته ها همچنین نشان از آن داشت که میزان هوش هیجانی و رضایت شغلی کارکنان مرد بیشتر از کارکنان زن بوده و افراد دارای تحصیلات فوق دیپلم و دیپلم دارای تعهد سازمانی بالاتری نسبت به کارکنان با سطح تحصیلات بالاتر می باشند.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-308-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>105</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>134</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>هوش هیجانی</keyword>
<keyword>تعهد سازمانی کارکنان</keyword>
<keyword>رضایت شغلی</keyword>
<keyword>ویژگی های جمعیت شناختی</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Investigating the relationship between emotional intelligence, organizational commitment and job satisfaction of employees with the demographic factors (case: Iranian Central Oil Fields Company (ICOFC))</title>
						<abstract>The research is going to compare the levels of emotional intelligence, organizational commitment and job satisfaction of employees of Iranian Central Oil Fields Company (I. C. O. F. C) according to different demographic factors such as age, job experience, education, organizational position, and gender. Research type is applied-developing and on the other hand, is consumed as a descriptive-survey. The population of the research was Iranian Central Oil Fields Company employees and acording to the Morgan table, 359 employees randomly have been selected and standardized questionnaires were distributed among them. The results indicated that emotional intelligence and job satisfaction have significant differences while it comes to age, job experience, organization position and gender. In addition, organizational commitment did'nt reach desired score, but it showed magnificent differences considering age, job experience, education and position. Based on findings, by increasing age, organizational position and job experience the emotional intelligence of the employees have improved. Also, by promoting their positions, job satisfaction and organizational commitment has increased. On the other hand, while age and experience have increased an increase in job satisfaction was detected. Emotional intelligence and Job satisfaction of the male employees have been more than those of female employees. Results show comparing to those with higher education, people who have diploma or associate's degree show more commitment to the organization.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-308-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>105</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>134</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>emotional intelligence</keyword>
<keyword>organizational commitment</keyword>
<keyword>job satisfaction</keyword>
<keyword>demographic factors.</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Sirous</name>
	<surname>Amirghodsi</surname>
	<email>sirous_a@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali</name>
	<surname>Bonyadi Naeini</surname>
	<email>Bonyadi@iust.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-25-31">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>بررسی میزان نهادینه شدن فرهنگ بهداشت، ایمنی و محیط زیست دربین کارکنان ستادی شرکت گاز تهران</title>
						<abstract>در سال&#8204;های اخیر پیشرفت&#8204;های زیادی در شرکت گاز ایران در مورد مسائل مرتبط با ایمنی، بهداشت و محیط زیست (HSE) صورت گرفته است. با این حال ساختار تصمیم&#173;سازی مناسبی وجود نداشته و عدم تمرکز و دوباره کاری&#173;های بسیاری انجام شده است. هدف اصلی این پژوهش بررسی میزان نهادینه شدن فرهنگ ایمنی، بهداشت و محیط زیست در میان کارکنان ستادی شرکت گاز تهران بوده است. تحقیق انجام شده در این مقاله یک تحقیق توصیفی-پیمایشی و از شاخه تحقیقات میدانی است. جامعه&#173; آماری پژوهش حاضر کارکنان ستاد شرکت گاز تهران مشتمل بر 775 نفر می&#8204;باشند. برای این&#8204;منظور ابتدا با استفاده از روش تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی و از طریق عامل&#8204;یابی محورهای اصلی و چرخش واریمکس ابتدا ابعاد فرهنگ HSE در میان کارکنان ستادی شرکت گاز تهران شامل هشت بعد شناسایی شدند. سپس رتبه&#8204;بندی عوامل تشکیل دهنده&#173; فرهنگ HSE از بیش&#8204;ترین به کم&#8204;ترین بر اساس نتایج تحلیل فریدمن به ترتیب: وضعیت سرپرستان و مدیران؛ تعهد مدیریت؛ توانمندی کارکنان؛ نگرش کارکنان نسبت به فرهنگ HSE؛ وضعیت ارتباطات؛ وضعیت مشارکت کارکنان؛ گزارش&#8204;دهی و نسبت ارجحیت ایمنی، بهداشت و محیط، ارایه شده است. در نهایت با استفاده از آزمون تی به بررسی نهادیه شدن هر یک از ابعاد فرهنگ مربوطه پرداخته شد که نتایج نشان می&#8204;دهد، تمامی ابعاد یاد شده به جز بعد توانمندی کارکنان در شرکت نهادینه شده&#173; اند.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-309-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>135</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>156</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>فرهنگ ایمنی</keyword>
<keyword>بهداشت و محیط زیست (HSE)</keyword>
<keyword>کارکنان ستادی شرکت گاز تهران</keyword>
<keyword>نهادینه شدن فرهنگ HSE</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Studying the institutionalization of HSE culture among the Staff of Tehran Gas Company</title>
						<abstract>In recent years, there have been many advances in the Iranian gas company on issues related to safety, health and environment (HSE), but there has not been a proper decision-making structure, and decentralization and reworking have been carried out. The main objective of this study was to investigate the institutionalization of the safety, health and environment culture among the staff of the Tehran Gas Company. The research carried out in this paper is a descriptive-survey research based on the the field research. The statistical population of the research was the staff of the staff of Tehran Gas Company consisting of 775 people. At first, by using the exploratory factor analysis method and through the optimization of the main axes and the rotation of the varimix, dimensions of the HSE culture were identified among the staff of the Tehran Gas Company including eight factors. Then the ranking of HSE culture was computed from the highest to the lowest based on the results of Friedman's analysis: the status of supervisors and managers; the managerial commitment; the staff's ability; the staff's attitude towards the HSE culture; the status of the communication; the status of employee participation; the reporting and priority of safety, health and environment. Finally, by using the T-test, the institutionalization of each dimension of the culture was investigated. The results showed that all of these dimensions were institutionalized, except for the ability of employees in the Tehran Gas Company.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-309-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>135</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>156</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>HSE culture- Staff of the Gas Company-institutionalization of HSE culture</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Meghdad</name>
	<surname>Haji Mohammadali Jahromi</surname>
	<email>Jahromi@damavandiau.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammadali</name>
	<surname>Kharazinia</surname>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-25-32">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>رتبه‌بندی و مقایسه عوامل اثرگذار بر ایجاد رفتار کارآفرینانه با استفاده از روش مقیاس‌گذاری چندبعدی (موردمطالعه: شرکت پالایش گاز پارسیان)</title>
						<abstract>توجه به ابعاد مختلف رفتار کارآفرینی در سازمان&#8204;ها، می&#8204;تواند به رشد و بهره&#8204;وری که از مهم&#8204;ترین اهداف هر سازمانی می&#8204;باشد، کمک کند و با ایجاد تفکری خلاق و نوآورانه به ارزش&#8204;آفرینی در سازمان منجر شود. در همین راستا، این پژوهش با هدف رتبه&#8204;بندی و مقایسه عوامل اثرگذار بر ایجاد رفتار کارآفرینانه سازمانی در شرکت پالایش گاز پارسیان انجام&#8204; شده و از نظر هدف، کاربردی و بر اساس ماهیت و روش، توصیفی- پیمایشی است. جامعه آماری پژوهش متشکل از مدیران، سرپرستان و کارکنان شرکت پالایش گاز پارسیان به تعداد 385 نفر بوده و حجم نمونه 169 نفر در نظر گرفته شد که به روش طبقه&#8204;ای متناسب با حجم انتخاب شدند. ابزار گردآوری اطلاعات، پرسشنامه محقق ساخته با روایی و پایایی قابل قبول بوده است. نتایج حاصل از بررسی فرضیه&#8204;ها با استفاده از روش مقیاس&#8204;گذاری چندبعدی، نشان داد که واحدهای مستقل و معاونت مهندسی از نظر عوامل اثرگذار بر ایجاد رفتار کارآفرینانه شبیه به هم عمل می&#173;کنند. معاونت عملیات نسبت به واحدهای مستقل و معاونت مهندسی متفاوت است. همچنین معاونت اداری و پشتیبانی با معاونت عملیات، مهندسی و واحدهای مستقل متفاوت است. درنهایت، نتایج رتبه&#8204;بندی معاونت&#8204;ها و واحدها بر اساس عوامل اثرگذار بر رفتار کارآفرینانه ارائه &#8204;شده است.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-310-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>157</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>186</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>رفتار کارآفرینانه</keyword>
<keyword>کارآفرینی سازمانی</keyword>
<keyword>جو کارآفرینانه</keyword>
<keyword>رفتار شبکه‌سازی</keyword>
<keyword>ساختار سازمان</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Ranking and Comparing Factors Affecting Entrepreneurial Behavior by Using Multi-Dimensional Scaling (Case: Parsian Gas Refinery Company)</title>
						<abstract>Considering the different dimensions of entrepreneurial behavior in organizations, it can help incresing productivity and growth that is one of the main goals of any organization and lead to creative and innovative thinking about value creation in the organization. In this regard, the present research was conducted with the purpose of ranking and comparing the factors which affect organizational entrepreneurial behavior in Parsian Gas Refinery Company&#8217;s deputy offices and independent units. This research has been considered applied in terms of aim and descriptive survey in terms of design. The population of interest was comprised of the managers, supervisors, and staff members of Parsian Gas Refinery Company, adding up to 385 people, of whom 169 were selected as the sample of the study. The data collection tool was a researcher-made questionnaire, which was administered using stratified sampling method. The results obtained through investigating the hypotheses by means of multi-dimensional scaling showed that independent units and Engineering Deputy Office act similarly in terms of factors affecting entrepreneurial behavior. Operations Deputy Office acts quite differently from independent units and Engineering Deputy Office in this regard. In addition, Administrative and Support Deputy Office also acts differently from Operations Deputy Office as well as independent units and Engineering Deputy Office. &#160;Finally, we have concluded with presenting the results of ranking deputy offices and independent units based on factors affecting entrepreneurial behavior.</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-310-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>157</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>186</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>Entrepreneurial Behavior</keyword>
<keyword>Organizational Entrepreneurship</keyword>
<keyword>Entrepreneurial Atmosphere</keyword>
<keyword>Networking Behavior</keyword>
<keyword>Organizational Structure.</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mahsa</name>
	<surname>kamalipoor</surname>
	<email>Mahsa.kamalipoor@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali</name>
	<surname>Safari</surname>
	<email>a.safari@ase.ui.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Majid</name>
	<surname>Esmaelian</surname>
	<email>M.esmaelian@ase.ui.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>3</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ghasem</name>
	<surname>Bahramikiya</surname>
	<email>g_bahramikia@yahoo.com</email>
	     <order>4</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>



			<article externalId="A-10-25-33">
			<type>OTHERS_CITABLE</type>
			
					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>چالش‌ها و الزامات توسعه مدیریت دانش در شرکت ملی صنایع پتروشیمی (افق ایران 1404)</title>
						<abstract>فضای رقابت شدید حاکم بر کسب و کار و تغییرات جدی آن، مدیریت دانش را به ناجی سرمایه دانشی سازمان&#8204;ها مبدل ساخته که ضمن اهمیت ذاتی، نیازمند تکامل، توسعه و بلوغ آینده نگرانه است. هدف از این تحقیق، جریان&#8204;شناسی آینده مدیریت دانش و استخراج چالش&#8204;ها و موانع کامیابی شرکت ملی صنایع پتروشیمی در جهت نیل به آینده مطلوب مدیریت دانش بوده است که با مطالعه میدانی محقق شده است. در این مسیر از ابزارهایی نظیر مصاحبه و پرسشنامه و همچنین مطالعات کتابخانه&#8204;ای بهره برده شده است. این آسیب&#8204;شناسی از طریق سنجش سازگاریِ فعلی شرکت و تحلیل شکاف آن با وضعیت اولیه&#8204;ی سازگار با توسعه &#34;مدیریت دانش بر مدار ارزش&#8204;&#34; حاصل شده است که در انتها، راهکارهای پیشنهادی آن در دو حوزه فرهنگ و ساختار سازمانی ارائه می&#8204;شوند. این راهکارها بر تقویت هوشیاری اجتماعی سازمان و همچنین ارتقای توانمندی&#8206;&#8204;های منابع انسانی در جهت ثبت و ترویج دانش&#8204; ارزش&#8204;آفرین (در دو مقوله صنعتی و سازمانی) تأکید کرده است.&#160;</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-311-fa.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>187</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>212</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>چالش</keyword>
<keyword>آینده</keyword>
<keyword>توسعه مدیریت دانش</keyword>
<keyword>صنعت پتروشیمی</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				

					<languageVersion language="fa">
						<title>Challenges and Requirements of Knowledge Management Development at National Petrochemical Company (horizon of 1404)</title>
						<abstract>The intense of competitiveness in the business environments and its serious changes have made knowledge management a soloution for rescuing the organizational capital. Knowledge management in terms of its fundamental importance is required to be developed. The purpose of this research was to investigate the future of knowledge management and extract the challenges of the National Petrochemical Company in order to achieve the desired future of KM by using field research . In this way, research tools such as interviews and questionnaires as well as library studies have been used. This step has been achieved by measuring the current adaptability of the company and analyzing its gap with the primitive consistent status of &#34;Value-based KM&#34;. At the end, solutions were proposed in two areas: culture and organizational structure. These solutions emphasize the strengthening of organizational social awareness as well as enhancement of human resources capabilities for recording and promoting value-added knowledge (in two industrial and organizational categories).</abstract>
						<pdfFileUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-311-en.pdf</pdfFileUrl>
						<publicationDate>2018-07-21T10:20:15</publicationDate>
						<pageFrom>187</pageFrom>
						<pageTo>212</pageTo>
				<keywords>
<keyword>Challenges- Future-Knowledge Management Development- Petrochemical Industry.</keyword>
</keywords>
				</languageVersion>
				


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Ahmad</name>
	<surname>Boroomand Kakhaki</surname>
	<email>a.borumand@outlook.com</email>
	     <order>1</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Amirnaser</name>
	<surname>Akhavan</surname>
	<email>akhavan@aut.ac.ir</email>
	     <order>2</order>
        <instituteAffiliation></instituteAffiliation>  
	    <role>AUTHOR</role>
	 </author>
	</authors>


	</article>


	</issue>
 </ici-import>
 
  
  
  
  
 