<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" 

"journalpublishing3.dtd">

<article 
article-type="research-article"
dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en" 
xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
>

<front>

<journal-meta>

  <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">1</journal-id>
  <issn>2251-8886</issn>

  <publisher>

	<publisher-name>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher-name>
  </publisher>

</journal-meta>



<article-meta>

  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">29</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Relationship between Cultural Intelligence and Social Capital
(Case Study: NIOPDC)
</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> Tabarsa</surname>
		<given-names>Gholamali </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Hadizadeh Moghadam</surname>
		<given-names> Akram </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Basiji</surname>
		<given-names> Asal </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Karimi</surname>
		<given-names>Yadollah </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>25</issue>

  <fpage>3</fpage>

  <lpage>28</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>30</day>
				  <month>04</month>
				  <year>2013</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>29</day>
				  <month>04</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

This study investigates the relationship between cultural intelligence and social capital. Since social capital is one of the most valuable assets of an organization and considered to have a critical role in corporate competitive advantage, reviewing its components seems necessary. Unfortunately in Iran, a country with variety of different cultures, the concept of cultural intelligence is still immature and most of people mistakenly consider cultural intelligence only as cultural differences. In this study we examine the relation between social capital and cultural intelligence as two important elements of human resource studies for the first time. To do so we have chosen staff of NIOPDC (National Iranian Oil Production Distribution Company) as our sample population .Results from different surveys in this company show that there is a positive and meaningful relationship between main variables of the study, Social Capital and Cultural Intelligence. This meaningful relation could be an appropriate guidance for human resource manageress and also can help strategists to find best solutions to improve staff cultural intelligence in such organizations and enjoy the accumulation of social capital as the result.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">30</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Learning Processes as the Driving Force behind Strategic Innovation
(Case Study: Research Centers of Iran’s Oil Industry)
</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> Mobini Dehkordi</surname>
		<given-names>Ali </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Davari </surname>
		<given-names>Ali </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Ahmadi</surname>
		<given-names>Shahab </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>25</issue>

  <fpage>29</fpage>

  <lpage>46</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>17</day>
				  <month>04</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>18</day>
				  <month>05</month>
				  <year>2015</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

&#160;
The present research focuses on evaluating the effects of learning processes on strategic innovation. Strategic innovation is about changing business models, creating markets without competition and a big surge of value proposition to customers.Learning processes entails explorative, assimilative, transformative, and exploitative processes. Through evaluating of our hypotheses, we came to the conclusion that Learning processes affect strategic innovation; exploitative learning is the only part of learning processes with no effect on strategic innovation. Also, combinative capabilities mediates the relationship between learning processes and strategic innovation. Research centers of Iran&#8217;s oil industry was the case study of this research
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">31</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Effect of HRM on Building Technological Capability in RTOs
(Case Study: RIPI)
</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Afkhami Ardakani</surname>
		<given-names>Mehdi  </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Noori</surname>
		<given-names>Behrooz   </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Varmazyar</surname>
		<given-names>Mohsen </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>25</issue>

  <fpage>47</fpage>

  <lpage>75</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>15</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2013</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>09</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Human resource management and development is one of the most important factors of technological capability in research and technology organizations. Development of this factor enhances the mechanism of organization technological capability building. This research evaluates the roles of human resource management and development processes on technological capability building mechanism in Research Institute of Petroleum Industry of Iran (RIPI). DEMATEL technique is applied to determine the relation of human resource management and development and technological capability building mechanism factors with survey of experts. The results show that education, development and promotion and recruitment are the most effective human resource management processes on technological capability building mechanism. Therefore, improvement of these factors leads to development of organizational culture, knowledge management system, and more effective support of top managers on technological capability building.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">32</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Investigate the Factors Influencing Employees Attitudes towards Organizational Knowledge Sharing In Pension Fund of Oil Industry
</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Sanatigar </surname>
		<given-names>Hoda </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Soltani</surname>
		<given-names> Iraj </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>25</issue>

  <fpage>77</fpage>

  <lpage>97</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2013</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>23</day>
				  <month>11</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The aim of this study isto evaluate the employee's attitude toward knowledge sharing. In other words, the factors influencing people's attitudes toward knowledge sharing were identified. The research method is descriptive correlative and causal-comparative. The Statistical population are all employees of Oil Industry Pension Fund (N = 331). And the statistical sample (n = 123) were randomly selected and finally 106 questionnaires were answered. To determine the validity of the study, expert&#8217;s opinions were collected. And in the design and development questions, comments professors were applied. Also Cronbach's alpha was used to measure the reliability of the questionnaire. And obtained coefficient (92/3) showed that the questionnaire has good reliability. The results show that attitudes about knowledge sharing that the majority of the fund's employees (72 percent) have been positive terms about knowledge sharing. According to the study, There is a significant relationship between cultures (with a correlation coefficient 2/23), Structure (6/32), leadership (5/27), teamwork (5/39) and social trust (9/33) with an attitude of knowledge sharing. And personal characteristics (gender, age, education, work experience, job) did not show a significant relationship with attitude and knowledge sharing
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">33</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Suggesting a Model to Assessment of Effective Factors on Employee’s Motivation for Participating in In-Job Trainings
(Case Study: I.O.T.C)
</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Tange Karam</surname>
		<given-names>Bijan i </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Amirianzade</surname>
		<given-names> Moghgan  </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>25</issue>

  <fpage>99</fpage>

  <lpage>123</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>29</day>
				  <month>10</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>18</day>
				  <month>11</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The purpose of&#160; this research&#160; was to&#160; Suggesting a model to assessment of effective factors on Iranian Oil Terminals Company employees,s motivation for participating in in-job training courses. A descriptive research is a correllation method.The statical population of this research included all formal employees&#160; of&#160; I.O.T.C who graduate from high school or above.The statical population was 1100 people who 285 people of them have been selected according to Kerjsi &#38; Morgan table. Sampling method in this research has been simple randomly sampling.The tools used in this research were two questionaires made by researcher.The Cronbach's Alpha for both questinaires were 0.866 and content validity have been validated by expert proffessors, and some of I.O.T.C expert&#160; employees. It was also confirmed by factor analysis. To test the proposed hypotheses correlations, regression have been used.The finding suggest that training factors, expectancy, intrinsic instrumentality and organizational factors effect on employees motivation to participate in training course.And also result show that the training factors is the optimal prediction factor to motivate the employees to participate in training course.It has been recommended to I.O.T.C&#160; training managers and planners to focus on training factors, expectancy, intrinsic instrumentality and organizational factors.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">34</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>The evaluation of Effective Strategic ThinkingIn Managers of NIORDC
</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Moosakhani</surname>
		<given-names> Morteza  </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Iran Negad Parizi</surname>
		<given-names>Mehdi  </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> Ghasempour</surname>
		<given-names>Akbar</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>25</issue>

  <fpage>125</fpage>

  <lpage>144</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>18</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>06</day>
				  <month>05</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

This study was conducted to effective strategic thinking in National Iranian Oil Refining &#38; Distribution Company&#8217;s managers (NIORDC) based on Liedtka model and has been done through literature review and expert opinion. This research is a descriptive and applied research. The population in this study was the limited number of managers, deputies; heads of departments and senior experts, there is no sample. &#160;&#160;Then the validity and reliability of questionnaire were tested by using SPSS software. The research hypotheses were tested through descriptive and inferential statistics and the research results indicated that:The strategic thinking in National Iranian Oil Refining &#38; Distribution Company&#8217;s managers is high. It can be said that the first hypothesis is significant .Regarding the second hypothesis, the effectiveness of the strategic thinking of managers, there was no difference between the views of experts and managers about the variable, however
The amount of T statistic for variable of thinking In Time, intelligent Opportunism,&#160; hypothesis driven &#38; main variable of strategic thinking were significant at 95% confidence level, so they indicated that there was a meaningful difference between the views of experts and managers about those variables. The statistic amount of those variable become positive and indicates the respons of experts more effectiveness than managers
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">35</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>The Effects of Organizational Rumors on the Job Performance of Employees
(Case study:P.O.G.C)
</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> Ale Davood </surname>
		<given-names>Seyed Rasool</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname> Davoodi</surname>
		<given-names>– Seyed Mohammad Reza</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Nouroozi </surname>
		<given-names>Hasan </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mahmoodi</surname>
		<given-names>Navid </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>25</issue>

  <fpage>145</fpage>

  <lpage>174</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>26</day>
				  <month>11</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>04</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2015</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Rumor is one of the factors which has always been hidden from the eyes and attention of the organization and its managers and its importance in crisis because of mental and emotional communication in the organization is ignored. Gossip and disperse it among the indicators that can measure the degree of healthy relationships within the organization .The goal of present study was to investigate the effects of organizational rumor on the performance of SOUT pars gas complex employees using a descriptive survey method. The statistical universe of this study was consisted of all 5 refinery-administrative staff, operation management. The number of participants in total was 2300 persons. A classified random sampling method and a sample size proportional to statistical population have been selected.&#160; Then using Cochran formula from 2300 persons, 330 persons were chosen. In order to collect data from the participants, a questionnaire were distributed among them.After collecting some advices from supervisors and faculty advisors and also opinions of some professors at University and then applying their views on the questionnaire, at first stage important questions about the impact of organizational rumors on job performance were identified including spirit of distrust, the pressure on the employees from the administration, worry and anxiety, decreased productivity, lack of job security for personnel of SPGC. After providing the questionnaire at the second stage, the responses collected based on the sample space. Then the data were collected from the responses. This data were analyzed using several tests including correlation, Friedman test, T test with two independent groups, variance analysis and also using 16 SPSS software. Some important results are as follows: There is a direct relationship between gossip and decreased job performance and the coefficient of determination obtained indicates that 30 percent of the variation can be explained by a drop in job performance by the rumors. Significant differences were seen in the opinions of the staff on the effect of organizational rumors on employees' performance according to work experience and work place. work experience and workplace provide significant difference on the above scores. However, the difference between scores measured based on age. edgucation level and marital status are not significant
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">36</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Management</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>The Study of the Relationship between Organizational Culture and Knowledge Management Process
(Case Study: NIOC Exploration Directed
</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mahdieh</surname>
		<given-names>Omid  </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Salimi </surname>
		<given-names> Ghasem </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Rostami</surname>
		<given-names>Yar Hossein </given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2015</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>7</volume>

  <issue>25</issue>

  <fpage>175</fpage>

  <lpage>201</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>21</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>04</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2015</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

In the age of information and knowledge economy the intellectual capital of companies are critical in attaining survival and growth, not the physical capitals. In the today complex and turbulent environment, organization must be able to use their existing knowledge maximally and try towards creating and developing new knowledge. For this purpose, organizational culture is one the factors that paly an essential role in success of knowledge management activities. This research was conduct to investigate the relationship between organizational culture and knowledge management process in NIOC Exploration Directed. This research is descriptive (survey) and cross sectional. To questionnaires (organizational culture and knowledge management) were distributed in sample organization and the total number of 137 were used in analysis. The finding shows that hierarchical culture is the dominant cultural type in the organization and there is a significant relationship between organizational culture types and knowledge management activities. Although there is a significant relationship among knowledge storage, application, sharing, evaluation and organizational culture, there is no supporting evidence for the positive relationship between knowledge acquiring, transforming and organizational culture
</body>

</article>

