<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <records>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>34</issue>
	<startPage>3</startPage>
	<endPage>30</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Introducing a Model Organizational Silence Management at the Social Security Organization</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>naser Poursadegh</name>
	<email>dr.naser.poursadegh@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>naser Asghari</name>
	<email>naser.asgari60@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>saeed khodabandeh</name>
	<email>skh_sso@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
             Supreme National Defense University    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
             Shahid Sattari University of Aeronautical Engineering    
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
             Social Security Organization    
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Despite various developments in the public sector in recent years, low productivity of government agencies has been the main concern of Iranian policy makers. Employee silence and indifference towards the fate of an organization and its programs and lack of effective understanding between employees and management is an alarm of imminent reduction in organizational performance affecting the whole society at a macro level. This research attempts to provide a model to cover different dimensions of organizational silence. Organizational silence management is an important part of organizational behavior management which directly affects organizational decision-making. Survey research method and structural equation modeling were used and data were collected using a researcher-made questionnaire. The sample consisted of 354 male and female employees of the headquarters of the Iranian Social Security Organization. The questionnaire was designed on the basis of existing theories and using exploratory factor analysis method in 174 items. Using confirmatory factor analysis method, the components were confirmed and the final model was determined after confirmation of the components and sub-components. The final model offers a way to understand organizational silence and helps managers and policy makers reduce this phenomenon in their organization and create the spirit of work and effort among their staff. Managers can utilize this theory to eradicate organizational silence. This theory helps organization theorists achieve testable hypotheses in more comprehensive research.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-197-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Organizational silence</keyword>
	<keyword>organizational management</keyword>
	<keyword>organizational components</keyword>
	<keyword>Iranian Social Security Organization</keyword>
	<keyword>data-based theorizing.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>34</issue>
	<startPage>31</startPage>
	<endPage>52</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Examining of The effect of staff\'s Trust to the managers on Organizational Silence 
(Case: National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Narjes Khatoon Samari</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hossein Safarzadeh</name>
	<email>hr.safarzadeh@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Reduction of staffs&#8217; trust prevents them sharing their experience and knowledge to solve the issues in an organization and sharing their ideas to have desirable organizational changes. Thus, this research aimed at investigating the relationship between the employees&#8217; trust in managers and organizational silence. Indeed, in this research the effect of employees&#8217; perception of managers&#8217; character that according to Mayer et al, (1995) including: &#160;ability, benevolence and integrity, were studied on defensive and acquiescence silence. To cover this aim, the selected sample included 282 employees of central branch of National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company (N.I.O.P.D.C) and the required data was gathered by a questionnaire and analyzed by Structural Equations Methods.
Our study showed that increasing the trust of employees in managers reduces the organizational silence of staff. In addition, if the trust in managers increase, the defensive silence reduces, while acquiescence silence increases. According to the results, managers can improve their recognition of the silence environment in organizations which can lead to the change in behavior and increasing trust in managers resulting in not only creating positive employees' perception of managers&#8217; character but also, the willingness to share knowledge, experience and information. Finally, this can increase organizational performance.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-257-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Ability - Acquiescence silence – Benevolence - Defensive silence – Integrity -Organizational trust</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>34</issue>
	<startPage>53</startPage>
	<endPage>82</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Designing a Model for Turnover Reduction
In Iranian Oil Terminals Company (IOTC)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Mehdi Alirahimi</name>
	<email>mm.alirahimi@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Amirhossein Amirkhani</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Reza Rasouli</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of the present study was designing a model for turnover reduction in Iranian Oil Terminals Company (IOTC) to reduce the direct and indirect costs of turnover and to take steps to improve organizational effectiveness. This study was conducted using Delphi method. According the Delphi panel, from the 12 experts related to the subject, was asked to validate the indexes of organizational turnover over the successive rounds of Delphi. The Delphi method was completed after the third round and a favorable consensus was reached. Finally, the conceptual model was designed from Delphi of experts on indigenous indices affecting the reduction of organizational turnover of IOTC&#8217; personnel (selected from the set of factors and indicators from previous researches and projects) and within the framework of the effects of the ethical work climate of DeConinck (2011) and Zhang et al. (2013)&#8217; ethical leadership model.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-258-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Turnover</keyword>
	<keyword>Ethical Leadership</keyword>
	<keyword>Organizational Ethics</keyword>
	<keyword>Organizational Commitment</keyword>
	<keyword>Trust</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>34</issue>
	<startPage>83</startPage>
	<endPage>114</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Studying the influential variables in Designing Pattern of Recruitment and Selection of Human Resources Based on Merit System in Petrochemical Companies</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Hassan Rangriz</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Bijan Abdollahi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hasanreza Zeinabadi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Nazanin Teimouri</name>
	<email>teimouri.mba87@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The goal of Recruitment and Selection of human resources based on the merit system is to identify the competencies necessary for excellent performance at key posts throughout the organization. Using this Solution, HRM seeks to explore the skills, knowledge and attributes that directly contribute to the organization's success and the configuration of human resources activities around those competencies. So, this research aimed at identifying influential variables in designing pattern of competency based recruitment and selection of human resources in petrochemical companies. Using grounded theory as a qualitative method approach, and after interviewing with panel of experts, eight factors affecting the competency-based recruitment and selection model have been identified. Then for best implementation of the pattern, the systematic pattern of Competency Based Recruitment and Selection of Human resource in petrochemical companies was also provided.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-259-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Recruitment and Selection - human resources- Influential variables in Recruitment – Competency – Grounded Theory</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>34</issue>
	<startPage>115</startPage>
	<endPage>144</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Identifying and Ranking Factors Affecting Organizational Agility Based on Outsourcing
(Case study: Semnan Province Gas Company)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Alireza Avani</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammadreza Shahab</name>
	<email>mr.shahab@semnanian.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Abolfazl Danaei</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The best and newest way of survival and success of organizations is their concentrat and focus on organizational agility. Organizational agility is a conscious and comprehensive response to the changing needs of competitive markets and the success of the opportunities that the organization gains. Since recognizing the factors affecting organizational agility can help to obtain the necessary information in turbulent and disorder environments and to capture the advantages of changing trends, the present study seeks to measure organizational agility in Semnan Province Gas Company emphasizing the outsourcing process. Accordingly, the main question of the present research is whether outsourcing is effective on organizational agility in Semnan Province Gas Company?
The research method of this study was survey and data gathering tool was a questionnaire. The statistical population of the study was the official personnel of the Gas Company of Semnan province (150 people). Finally, 112 people were selected by stratified random sampling method.
Results from Regression analysis showed that 36 percent of changes in dependent variable of organizational agility have been related to the independent variable of organizational outsourcing. Among the four dimensions of outsourcing, two variables were effective on changes of dependent variables. These two variables based on impact severity included: learning aspect and inner processes aspect. Also, it was demonstrated that the other variables including customers and financial variables have no effect on organizational agility.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-260-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Outsourcing - Organizational Agility - Scrolling - Gas Company-Management</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>34</issue>
	<startPage>145</startPage>
	<endPage>170</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Investigating the role of green intellectual capital in developing different type of organizational innovation with regard to the environmental aspect
(Study in oil, gas and petrochemical in Khuzestan province)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Maryam Darvishi</name>
	<email>darvishi@iauo.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Alireza Ziaee Bideh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">After increasing of concerns about environment from consumers, governments and communities around the world, manufacturing companies start to develop environmental friendly programs such as development of green products, green brand, green technology and green innovation. Literature review showed that unlike doing many studies regarding the relationship between intellectual capital and innovation in organizations, researchers paid little attention to the environmental aspects of these concepts. So this study aimed to investigate the role of Green intellectual capital in different type of organizational innovation with regard to the environmental aspects. The population of this research is all companies active in the oil, gas and petrochemical industries in Khuzestan province, which includes 38 companies. Also in this study census method is used to gather required data. Finally collected data were analyzed with smartpls software and conceptual model was tested. The final results of this study showed that intellectual capital can enhance all types of environmental innovation including managerial innovation, product innovation, technological innovation and process innovation.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-261-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>green intellectual capital</keyword>
	<keyword>green managerial innovation</keyword>
	<keyword>green product innovation</keyword>
	<keyword>green technological innovation</keyword>
	<keyword>green process innovation</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>34</issue>
	<startPage>171</startPage>
	<endPage>194</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Measuring the Intellectual Capital in Iranian Oil Terminals Company to Identify the Ways of Maximization of its Value</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Elham Norouzi C.A</name>
	<email>stu.nourouzi@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Seyed Aligholi Roshan</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Milad Vafadar</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of this study has been to measure the intellectual capital in Iranian Oil Terminals Company (IOTC) to identify the ways of increasing its value. For this purpose the variables of the research were defined by exploring the background research and theoretical framework, and after that the primary model for the research was designed based on the model of Moon and Kym (2006). This research has been done using a descriptive survey method. The sample in this study has been employees of IOTC in Khark, including 214 individuals. The Smart PLS software was used to validate the proposed model. The results of data analysis indicated that the triple aspects of intellectual capital which considered as human capital (HC), structural capital (SC) and relational capital (RC) have had considerable effect on company&#8217;s intellectual capital. The most effective component of intellectual capital was relational capital, human capital and structural capital, respectively.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-262-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Intellectual capital</keyword>
	<keyword>Iranian Oil Terminals Company</keyword>
	<keyword>Human capital</keyword>
	<keyword>Relational capital</keyword>
	<keyword>Structural capital.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>9</volume>
	<issue>34</issue>
	<startPage>195</startPage>
	<endPage>214</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Evaluating Psychological Empowerment of Managers and its Effects On their Attitudes toward Strategic Planning in theDepartment of Human Resources Development of National Iranian Oil Company</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Jafar Beykzad</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Seyed Nader Rezvan</name>
	<email>sn_rezvanl@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Yavari</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The aim of present study has been to evaluate psychological empowerment of managers and its effects on their attitudes toward strategic planning in the Department of Human Resources Development of National Iranian Oil Company. Hence, psychological empowerment of managers was defined based on Whetten and Cameron&#8217;s (1998) theory in five dimensions: Sense of meaning, Sense of competence, Sense of self-determination, sense of impact, sense of trust and attitude toward strategic planning process was defined based on Dincher, Tat Oglu and&#160; Gloucester&#8217;s (2006) model. In this regard, two main hypotheses and five sub-hypotheses were set. Statistical population of the study (n=542) involved all managers employed in this Department. Sample size of the study was obtained 225 using Cochran relation, being selected by classified random sampling method. The data collection tool was a questionnaire. The reliability of the questionnaire was obtained by using Cronbach's alpha for questions related to psychological empowerment of managers and strategic planning attitudes of 0/889 and 0/909. One group t-test, Colmogrov-Smirnoff, Pearson Corelation and Regression tests were used at inferential level to test the research hypotheses. Results of the study indicated that psychological empowerment of the managers is at above average level. Moreover, findings of the study revealed that three aspects of psychological empowerment of the managers (i.e. sense of competence (0/287), sense of self-determination (0/182) and sense of meaning (0/567)) affect their attitude toward strategic planning. However, two factors of trust and efficacy, from among aspect of psychological empowerment of the managers, on their attitude toward strategic planning was rejected in the Department of Human Resources Development of National Iranian Oil Company.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-263-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Attitude</keyword>
	<keyword>NIOC</keyword>
	<keyword>Psychological Empowerment of Managers</keyword>
	<keyword>Strategic Planning.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
 </records>
 
  
  
  
  
 