@article{ 
author = {Farmahinifarahani, Ahmad and Moztarzadeh, Fatollah and Bahrami, Mohse},  
title = {Identifying, Measuring, and Analyzing the Factors Affecting Researchers Empowerment; 	 
The Case of a Research Center in the Oil Industry}, 
abstract ={Considering the increasing role of researchers and their empowerment in developing the competitive advantage of the companies, identifying and analyzing the factors affecting the empowerment of researchers was considered as the main objective of this research. The present study is considered an applied research in terms of its purpose and descriptive, in terms of data-collection is. The survey method has been ued and data collection tool was a questionnaire. The statistical population consisted of researchers at a research center in petroleum industry. By studying the related literature and using the previous researches, 28 factors influencing the empowerment of the researchers were identified and analyzed using factor analysis. Then, the factors influencing the empowerment of the researchers in this center were measured in three groups: occupational factors, organizational factors and individual factors. Then, using factor analysis, factor loading of each index of these factors was calculated. After that, the results were extracted; the status of these factors and their indicators at this center was analyzed. Finally, given the fact that the current situation in all three groups was less than the average, recommendations for conducting corrective actions were proposed to the research executives for future development. &#160;},  
Keywords = {Competence, Empowerment of Researchers, Personal Factors, Job Factors, Organizational Factors, the Oil Industry, Future Development},
volume = {10},
Number = {39}, 
pages = {1-28}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-219-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-219-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Sadeinia, Naser and Chenari, Vahid and Makvandi, Foad and Hemati, Mohamm},  
title = {Meta Synthesis and Fuzzy Interpretive Structural Modeling of Talent Supply Chain Management in National Iranian Oil Company}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this paper was to present the talent supply chain management model of the National Iranian Oil Company. In term of aim, this research is considered an applied and developmental research based on mixed method. The statistic population in qualitative step consisted articles in domstic and foreign scientific information bases related to talent management and in Quantitative step the human resources experts of company. The statistical samples for Meta synthesis included 12 articles related to talent supply chain management, which was determined through a multi-stage refinement of 109 papers and for Fuzzy interpretive structural modeling 22 HRM experts were selected by purposeful and judgmental method. Based on the research findings, talent supply chain network structure, talent supply chain key processes, managerial elements, core functions, talent supply chain performance and talent supply chain strategies are dimensions of the talent supply chain management model. In the presented model, the structure of the talent supply chain network has the highest driving power and the performance of talent supply chain management has the highest dependence degree. &#160;},  
Keywords = {Talent Management, Talent Supply Chain Management Model, Meta Synthesis, Fuzzy Interpretive Structural Modeling                },
volume = {10},
Number = {39}, 
pages = {29-62}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-235-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-235-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Ahmadi, Seyed Aliakbar and sadrmansoori, saeed and darvish, hassan and rajabbaigy, mojtab},  
title = {Exploring the Managerial Competencies in the Process of Talent Identification in Petroleum Industry of Iran}, 
abstract ={The petroleum industry of Iran, due to its special contribution to GDP and for its optimal performance, needs talented people in the leadership and managial roles for the future of petroleum industry.&#160;So, the main purpose of this research was to design an effective model for identifying the talent pool of Managers and determinants of managerial talent potentials among petroleum industry staff. The research method is considered practical, in terms of purpose and descriptive-exploratory type by using mixed method, in terms of data collection. At the qualitative stage of this research, the statistical sample was 30 experts from the Management Development Center of Petroleum Industry. They were selected by non-random snowball method to form a Delphi panel and at the quantitative stage, 126 of the humane resources managers of the petroleum industry were randomly selected. After reviewing studies related to the concept of talent management, 107 criteria were derived from the history and literature of the research. These criteria were categorized using Delphi method and exploratory factor analysis and were categorized in different groups. The findings of this research showed that the talent management model in Petroleum Industry has 9 main dimensions and 63 components which can explain 79% of potential management variances in total. &#160;},  
Keywords = {talent management, assessment center, talent pool, Iran oil industry},
volume = {10},
Number = {39}, 
pages = {63-96}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-582-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-582-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {amidi, masoume and hashemzadeh, golamreza and Alizadeh, Aliakbar},  
title = {Knowledge Management Pattern for Oil Industry Based On Grounded Theory Considering Technical and Human Related Issues}, 
abstract ={One of the most crucial strategic challenges of organizations for achieving success and competitive advantage is related to knowledge management (KM) activities. Oil Industry of Iran is responsible for producing, retaining and using huge amount of knowledge. In order to manage it effectively, it is necessary to use a customized KM pattern which is fit into specific factors of the organization. The main objective of this study is to present a customized knowledge management pattern for Iranian Oil Industry for the first time using grounded theory considering both human-related and technical issues. Needed information is gathered by semi-structured interviews with 22 oil industry experts and reviewing 60 recent papers. By using open and selective coding, components of final model and their relations were found. Results of the study included 160 open codes consisting 21 main concepts and 4 secondary concepts which were formed in &#8220;reasonal situations&#8221;, &#8220;intervention situations&#8221;, &#8220;strategies&#8221;, &#8220;central components&#8221; and &#8220;results&#8221;. &#160;},  
Keywords = {Knowledge Management Model, Grounded Theory, Oil Industry.},
volume = {10},
Number = {39}, 
pages = {97-126}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-383-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-383-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Seif, Mohammad Hasan and Rastegar, Ahmad and Akbari, Ehsan and Tajvaran, Marzieh},  
title = {A model for predicting attitude of desire to change based on components of spirituality in the workplace and organizational commitment in the oil pipelines and telecommunications company of Fars district}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this research was to investigate the effects of spirituality in the workplace component of desire to change the attitude according to the mediating role of organizational commitment. This research based on its goal is considered a practical research which consumed a descriptive and correlative research based on data gathering. The oil pipelines and telecommunications company of Fars district employees' (350 persons) were the statistical population of this research. The number of samples was counted 125 persons using the Cochran formula, and sampling was done by simple random method. Data collection was done by combination of three standardized questionnaires in a Likert 5 scales score. The research data was analyzed by using lisrel 8.5. All variables affecting the desire to change attitudes by employees in the oil pipelines and telecommunications company of Fars district were evaluated based on a conceptual model. Finally, the conceptual model according to indices of goodness of fit was approved. According to the estimates of the coefficients of the direct and indirect effects, the highest direct effect on willingness to change attitudes was related to &#8220;continuance commitment&#8221; (.35) and the lowest indirect effect have been &#8220;working interest&#8221; (.08).},  
Keywords = {Spirituality in the Workplace, Organizational Commitment, Desire to Change},
volume = {10},
Number = {39}, 
pages = {127-148}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-679-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-679-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Hakkak, Mohammad and Sepahvand, Reza and zare, Farjam and moosavi, Seyed najmeddi},  
title = {The role of organizational toxic climate on organizational inertia with regard to the mediator role of the organizational silence}, 
abstract ={Today, change is considered as a constant thing in organizations. Organizations will block their progress in the event that they do not have the changeable feature and ability to modify, and remain in their original framework. this characteristic of invariability and stagnation in the organization refers to organizational inertia. The purpose of this study was to analyze the role of organizational toxic climate on organizational inertia &#160;with considering the role of mediator of organizational silence. The purpose of the present study in terms of purpose is practical, and in terms of collecting data is a descriptive research type and is a branch of survey research. The statistical population of the research is 220 employees of the official staff of South Zagros Oil and Gas production Company in Shiraz that with using of simple random sampling method was selected 134 individuals. Data were collected with using a standard questionnaires that Structural equation modeling and Smart PLS software were used to analyze them. The conceptual model of research has a favorable fit. The results of this study show that organizational toxic climate has a positive and significant relationship with organizational silence and organizational inertia. Findings indicate that there is a positive and significant relationship between organizational silence and organizational inertia. &#160;},  
Keywords = {Organizational Toxic Climate, Organizational Inertia, Organizational Silence},
volume = {10},
Number = {39}, 
pages = {149-174}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-175-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-175-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2019}  
}

@article{ 
author = {rajabpour, ebrahim and CharkhtabMoghadam, Jahanshah and HamzeMollaie, Amir},  
title = {Effect of Talent Management Components on Job Satisfaction and Organizational Commitment of Knowledge Worker 
	 A Case in Research Institute of Petroleum Industry}, 
abstract ={Talent management is one of the solutions presented to utilize human resources as the most important assets of the organization. Therefore, the aim of this research was to investigate the effect of talent management components on job satisfaction and organizational commitment of Knowledge Workers. The research is considered an applied research based on its object and a survey, based on data collection methods and methodologically is considered in the category of quantitative research and positivism. Research population was 700 people including knowledge workers at Research Institute of Petroleum Industry, among whom 202 people were randomly selected. To collect data, it has been used the researcher made questionnaire for talent management, Minnesota's job satisfaction questionnaire and Allen &#38; Meyer questionnaire for organizational commitment, based on Likert five point scales (from very high to very little). Face and content validity was used to evaluate questionnaires Validity. Also, Cronbach's alpha was used to establish the reliability of instruments. Results showed that there are strong positive causal effect on talent management components and job satisfaction (Except of absorption talent) and also on talent management components and organizational commitment (Except of appraisal talent). &#160;},  
Keywords = { Talent Management, Knowledge Worker, Job Satisfaction, Organizational Commitment, Research Institute of Petroleum Industry},
volume = {10},
Number = {39}, 
pages = {175-196}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-173-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-173-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2019}  
}

