<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2019</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>38</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارائه مدلی برای شکل‌گیری همسویی افقی بین  اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی</title_fa>
	<title>Providing a Model for Shaping Horizontal Alignment among Human Resources Management Practices
</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;در مدیریت منابع انسانی وجود دو نوع تناسب و همسویی ضروری بر شمرده شده است؛ همسویی عمودی که به هم&#8204;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman,serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;&#8204;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;جهت بودن راهبردها و اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی با راهبردها و اهداف کلان سازمانی اشاره دارد و همسویی افقی که به همسویی درونی بین اقدامات متنوع مدیریت منابع انسانی با هم توجه دارد. با توجه به نتایج اثربخش و هم&#8204;افزای ناشی از اقدامات همسو و یکپارچه منابع انسانی، شناسایی ابعاد شکل&#8204;دهنده و تقویت&#8204;کننده همسویی افقی در اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی و ارائه یک مدل مطلوب و جامع برای آن، جزو پژوهش&#8204;هایی است که انجام آن اجتناب&#8204;ناپذیر است. پژوهش حاضر نیز بدین منظور و با استفاده از روش کیفی فرا&#8204;ترکیب صورت گرفته است. مهمترین تعاریف از مفهوم همسویی وهمسویی افقی و نیز مدل&#8204;ها و تئوری&#8204;های مرتبط با آن، که توسط پژوهشگران مختلف ارائه شده، شناسایی و بررسی گردیده و نقاط قوت و ضعف آن&#8204;ها در مقایسه با یکدیگر مشخص و در نهایت مدل پیشنهادی به نحوی طراحی شده که تا حد ممکن تعریف جامعی از همسویی افقی و ابعاد موثر بر تحقق آن را در بین اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی در برگیرد. مهمترین مزیت این الگوی پیشنهادی در این است که تمامی تعاریف از مفهوم همسویی و مفاهیم معادل آن و نیز همسویی افقی را بررسی و ترکیب کرده و ابعاد شکل&#8204;گیری همسویی افقی شامل یکپارچگی فرآیندی، یکپارچگی معماری و پیکره&#8204;بندی و یکپارچگی اجرایی را به&#8204;صورت جامع مورد بررسی قرار داده است.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
Two types of fitness and alignment are essential in human resource management. Vertical alignment that points to the consistent of HRM strategies and activities with corporate strategies and goals and, horizontal alignment that is related to the consistency among various practices of human resource management. With regard to effective results and synergies resulting from consistent and integrated HR practices, identifying the dimensions of horizontal fitness in human resource management practices, providing a desirable and comprehensive model is inevitable. The present study was carried out for this purpose by using qualitative meta-analysis method. So that the most important definitions of the concept of alignment and horizontal alignment, as well as the models and theories related to it, have been identified and investigated. Then their strengths and weaknesses compared with each other and, finally, the proposed model was designed in such a way that includes a comprehensive definition of horizontal alignment and its effective dimensions. The main advantage of the proposed model is that it combines all definitions of the concept of alignment and horizontal alignment, and investigates horizontal integrity dimensions among human resource management practices, including process integrity, architectural and configuration integrity, and executive integrity in a comprehensive manner.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa> همسویی, همسویی افقی یا درونی,  یکپارچگی  فرآیندی, یکپارچگی معماری و پیکره‌بندی , یکپارچگی اجرایی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Alignment, Internal or horizontal Alignment, Process Integrity, Architectural, Configuration Integrity, Executive Integrity</keyword>
	<start_page>3</start_page>
	<end_page>38</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-193-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Narjes  </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Sorati Ashtiani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>نرجس</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سرعتی آشتیانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>sorati.ashtiani@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846004079</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004079</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Jabbar </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Babashahi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>جبار</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>باباشاهی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>j.babashahi@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846004080</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004080</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hamidreza </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Yazdani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حمیدرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>یزدانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>hryazdani@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846004081</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004081</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Tooraj</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name> Karimi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>تورج</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کریمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>tkarimi@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846004082</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004082</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
