<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>33</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تأثیر رهبری خدمتگزار بر ادراک کارکنان از عدالت سازمانی (مورد مطالعه: کارکنان ستاد وزارت نفت)</title_fa>
	<title>The Impact of Servant Leadership on Employee Perception of Organizational Justice 
(Case: Oil Ministry Staff)</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;letter-spacing:-.1pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.5pt;&quot;&gt;رهبران خدمتگزار روی خدمت&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;letter-spacing:-.1pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.5pt;&quot;&gt;&#8204;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;letter-spacing:-.1pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.5pt;&quot;&gt;&#8204;رسانی به دیگران تأکید می&#8204;&#8204;کنند و منافع شخصی را فدای منافع دیگران می&#8204;کنند تا افراد از درایت و اختیار و سلامت بیشتری برخوردار شوند و خودشان تبدیل به رهبرانی خدمتگزار شوند. پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی تأثیر رهبری خدمتگزار بر ادارک کارکنان از عدالت سازمانی انجام شده است. روش پژوهش از نظر هدف کاربردی و از نظر روش همبستگی بوده است. جامعه آماری شامل کلیه کارکنان ستاد وزارت نفت است به تعداد 800 نفر بود که از طریق جدول مورگان حجم نمونه 260 نفر برآورد شده است که با استفاده از روش نمونه&#8204;گیری تصادفی ساده انتخاب شدند. برای گردآوری داده&#8204;ها از پرسشنامه&#8204;های استاندارد رهبری خدمتگزار باربوتو و ویلیر (2006) و عدالت سازمانی نیهوف و مورمن (1993) استفاده شد که روایی آنها به ترتیب از طریق آلفای کرونباخ79/0 و 84/0 محاسبه شده است. آزمون فرضیه&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;letter-spacing:-.1pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.5pt;&quot;&gt;&#8204;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;letter-spacing:-.1pt;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.5pt;&quot;&gt;ها با استفاده از آزمون رگرسیون چندگانه، روش مدل سازی معادلات ساختاری و به کمک نرم افزار پی ال اس در دو بخش مدل اندازه گیری و بخش ساختاری انجام پذیرفت. نتایج تحقیق حاکی از آن بود که رهبری خدمتگزار بر ادارک کارکنان از عدالت سازمانی تأثیر دارند. همچنین هر یک از ابعاد رهبری خدمتگزار(خردمندی، ایثارگری، بازنمایی اقناعی، التیام بخشی عاطفی، مباشرت و پیشکاری) بر عدالت سازمانی تأثیر دارد که به ترتیب گرایش ارزشی به ایثارگری و فداکاری، التیام بخشی عاطفی، مباشرت و پیشکاری، بازنمایی اقناعی و خردمندی بیشترین تاثیر را بر عدالت سازمانی داشته&#8204;اند.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Servant leaders emphasize the service to others and sacrifice personal interests for the interests of others in order to empower individuals with greater freedom, self-control and self-serving as service leaders. The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of servant leadership on employee perceptions of organizational justice. The research method was applied in terms of purpose and in terms of correlation method. The statistical population consisted of all the staff of the Oil Ministry of Iran, in headquarters, which numbered 800 employees. Using a Morgan table, the sample size was 260 people. They were selected using simple random sampling. For collecting data, two standard questionnaires used by Barbuto and Wheeler (2006) and organizational justice Niehoff and Moorman (1993) has been applied. The validity of the questionnaires computed through Cronbach's Alpha was 79/0 and 84/0 respectively. Examining the information and testing the hypotheses was done by using multiple regression tests, Structural Equation Modeling, and using the PLS software, two parts of the measurement model and structural part were performed. The results of the research indicated that the servant leadership affects employees' perceptions of organizational justice. Also, each aspect of servant leadership (wisdom, self-sacrifice, persuasive representation, emotional healing, stewardship, and promise) affects organizational justice Which respectively have a significant tendency toward sacrifice, sacrifice, emotional healing, stewardship and promise, persuasive representation and wisdom.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>رهبری خدمتگزار , خردمندی , ایثارگری , بازنمایی اقناعی , التیام بخشی عاطفی , مباشرت و پیشکاری , عدالت سازمانی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>servant leadership, wisdom, self-sacrifice, represented persuasive, emotional healing, stewardship and secure servers, organizational justice.</keyword>
	<start_page>65</start_page>
	<end_page>86</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-25-20&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Hajieh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rajabi Farjad</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حاجیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رجبی فرجاد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>hajiehrajabi@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002173</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002173</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علوم انتظامی امین</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Shabnam</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>ImaniKhoo</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>شبنم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ایمانی خو</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002174</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002174</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
