<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <records>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>43</issue>
	<startPage>3</startPage>
	<endPage>24</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Human Capital Development Model in Ministry of Petroleum of Iran</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Vahid Hajilo</name>
	<email>vahid_sun62@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Gholamreza Memarzadeh Tehran</name>
	<email>gmemar@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Zahra Moghim</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The human resources of any organization are the most valuable factor of production and the main source of competitive advantage, so planning for its development is essential. This study was designed to provide a model for human capital development. The research is applied and descriptive in terms of data collection. This was a descriptive-descriptive survey research using a semi-structured questionnaire and interview. In the first stage, an open questionnaire was prepared to identify the human capital development status in Iran Ministry of Petroleum of Iran. Then, a second questionnaire was designed to extract the relationships between variables, to determine the weighting coefficients of the indices and to present the mathematical model of the research.The statistical population was the experts from Ministry of Petroleum of Iran and based on the specific conditions, a number of its experts were selected as statistical sample. Systems dynamics approach was used to design the model. By using Vensim software, scenario writing was done. Finally, six scenarios were considered and among them &#34;Improvement of training and development software programs&#34; was identified as the strongest scenario and the &#34;Improvement of staffing capability&#34; was selected as the most attractive scenario. According to the results, the Ministry of Petroleum must first empower its staff to develop its human capital. Since empowerment is both objective and subjective, therefore, employees' mental capacity and self-esteem must be enhanced by increasing their skill level and empirical ability to achieve an acceptable level of productivity.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-877-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Human Capital Development</keyword>
	<keyword>Systems Dynamics</keyword>
	<keyword>Scenario Writing</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>43</issue>
	<startPage>25</startPage>
	<endPage>54</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Designing a Conceptual Framework for Employees\' Self-development Behavio; a Case in the Khorasan Razavi, North and South Gas Company</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Ahmad Momeni</name>
	<email>momeni_a@mail.um.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Azar Kafashpour</name>
	<email>kafashpor@um.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Gholamreza Malikzadeh</name>
	<email>ekzadeh@um.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Alireza Kharakian</name>
	<email>khorakian@um.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The concept of &#34;self-development behavior and the voluntary development of employees&#34; has a special position in the literature of organizational behavior and organizational resource management; and management scholars and experts have different views on this. The main purpose of the present study was to present a conceptual framework for employees' self-development behavior. This research was done with qualitative approach and thematic analysis. The study population consisted of 425 employees of Khorasan Razavi, North and South Gas Company. Purposeful sampling method was used for this study. The sample consisted of 21 employees with theoretical knowledge and practical experience in self-development behavior. In-depth semi-structured interviews were used to collect data. Based on the results of the research, self-development behavior was categorized into ten key categories of organizational commitment, self-awareness, self-efficacy, self-organization, empowerment, self-efficacy, flexibility, self-learning, resilience, and optimism. The antecedents of self-development behavior were also categorized into three categories: individual, organizational and extracurricular. The results of self-development behavior were also identified in three categories: individual, organizational and extracurricular.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-884-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Self-development Behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>Self-directed Behavior</keyword>
	<keyword>Self-empowerment</keyword>
	<keyword>Human Resource Development</keyword>
	<keyword>Voluntary Development of Employees.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>43</issue>
	<startPage>55</startPage>
	<endPage>86</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Presentation of the Competency Model of Leaders in a Quantum Organization</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Seyyed Hassan Mousavi</name>
	<email>mousavi139036@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Iraj Soltani</name>
	<email>soltani134@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mehraban Hadi Peykani</name>
	<email>paykani2323@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of this study was to present a competence model for leaders of quantum organizations. This research was exploratory and mix method (qualitative and quantitative). In the qualitative part of the statistical society, the research was conducted by professors of management from different universities and the statistical population of the quantitative part of the research consisted of the managers of the companies affiliated to the oil industry in Isfahan. The sampling was carried out in a multistage targeted manner based on classification method Fits the volume. The data gathering tool consisted of two researcher-made questionnaires. Their formal and content validity was confirmed by professors in management in the field of quantum organization and competence of the leaders. Reliability of the questionnaires was calculated by calculating the Cronbach's alpha coefficient, all of which were above 0.70 and were desirable. The competency model of the quantum organization leaders was presented using structural equation modeling technique with 5 competence dimensions: individual, interpersonal, managerial, analytical / perceptual, technical, and 57 competencies of leadership.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-879-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Quantum Leadership Skills</keyword>
	<keyword>Competency of Leaders</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>43</issue>
	<startPage>87</startPage>
	<endPage>108</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Identification and Structural Pattern of Top Managers\' Psychological Traits in the Oil Industry</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Alborz Moghtader Mansouri</name>
	<email>alborz.moghtader@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Gholamreza Rahimi</name>
	<email>:  dr.rahimii48@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Nader bohlouli</name>
	<email>nabohlooli@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Farhad Nezhad Irani</name>
	<email>nezhadiranif@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Nowadays, psychological traits of managers are among the factors that influence the success of organizations and are a key element of human resource empowerment. The current research aimed to identify psychological traits of Top managers in Oil fields of West Azerbaijan province which has been studied by the combined method (quantitative - qualitative). In the qualitative section, postmodern paradigm, phenomenological strategy, and latent content analysis technique by semi- structured (in-depth) interview (to the theoretical saturation level) with 16 cases of top managers and&#160; purposive sampling method was used for sampling and theoretical saturation was obtained from interviews with 10 individuals. In the quantitative section, using the structural equation modeling by partial least squares method, the reliability and validity of the obtained tool was confirmed. The interviews were analyzed through open coding and axial coding using MAXQDA12 and the Smart Pls2 software has been used to confirm the tool. The psychological Traits of Top Managers in the study community were identified in the four components of altruism, ambition, foresight and compatibility with others and a structural model based on these components was presented and the reliability and fit of the newly created model were evaluated.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-881-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Psychological Features</keyword>
	<keyword>Top Managers</keyword>
	<keyword>Oil Industry</keyword>
	<keyword>Phenomenology.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>43</issue>
	<startPage>109</startPage>
	<endPage>138</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Design a Model for Developing Leadership Competency for Steel Industry Managers Using the Grounded Theory</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Javad Soleimani</name>
	<email>soleymanni@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Seyed Reza Seyed Javadin</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohamad Ali Shah Hoseini</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of this research was to make and provide a model for developing the competence of the leadership of the steel industry managers. The methodology of this research was applied and exploratory in terms of the purpose and data gathering method was mixed. In qualitative stage, after a deep interview, data gathering has been done based on the Grounded Theory and by using a questionnaire of 12 questions. It was in accordance with the systematic approach of Strauss and Corbin. After coding process, 180 initial propositions or concepts were identified according to open coding and 32 categories were derived from their combination, which were the origin of the axial coding. After that, Six main components or dimensions of the model were designed. Finally the systematic model of the leadership competency development of the steel industry managers was designed. The statistical population of the research in the qualitative stage included all experts of the steel industry that were interviewed according to non-probability sampling and the snowball technique. 21 persons&#160; were selected and the deep interviews were done. In the second stage, sample size was 155 and after statistical analysis and structural equations, the fitting of the designed model was verified by using the PLS software.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-880-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>leadership</keyword>
	<keyword>competency</keyword>
	<keyword>leadership competency</keyword>
	<keyword>leadership development</keyword>
	<keyword>Steel industry</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>43</issue>
	<startPage>139</startPage>
	<endPage>160</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Identification and Evaluation of Factors Affecting Talent Management in Iran\'s National Gas Industries
(Case: Fajr Jam Refining Company)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Abdoljavad Khalili</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Abdolkhalegh Golami</name>
	<email>gh.khalegh@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Karamallah Daneshfard</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The purpose of this study was to identify and measure the factors affecting talent management in the national gas industry. So, the qualitative and quantitative approaches have been used. Delphi approach in the qualitative part and the Shannon entropy in the quantitative part have been used. For this purpose, a team of 15 experts, including organizational managers as well as academic professors, was selected and the Delphi approach steps have done according to their views. The result of this section, it has been identified 42 variables within the 10 key variables of personal development, organizational strategy, recruitment and selection, performance management, training, compensation, discipline, political factors, labor supply, and laws and regulations that have influenced talent management. Based on the results of the Delphi approach, the effect of the 10 factors on talent management was equal, while some factors may be more effective than others. So, the weighting of the main variables based on the Shannon entropy method according to the opinions of 10 experts was considered. The results showed that performance management has the highest importance and personal development has the lowest importance in talent management.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-876-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Talent Management</keyword>
	<keyword>Delphi Approach</keyword>
	<keyword>Shannon Entropy</keyword>
	<keyword>National Gas Industries.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>43</issue>
	<startPage>161</startPage>
	<endPage>180</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Effect of Workplace Spirituality on Comprehensive Mental Health of Employees; A Case in Pazargad Petrochemical Company in Asaluyeh</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Hosein Taajabadi</name>
	<email>ht171819@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Omid Mohebimanesh</name>
	<email>mohebimanesh@mut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">This study aimed to investigate the effect of workplace spirituality on comprehensive mental health of employees and its three main dimensions (emotional well-being, psychological well-being, and social well-being). This research is consumed an applied research and the survey method has been used for data collection. Structural equation modeling was used to analyze the data and test hypotheses. The statistical population of the research included employees of Pazargad petrochemical company located in Asalouyeh. The sample size was determined based on Morgan's table. Finally, 238 employees were selected using simple random sampling. Data gathering tool was Milliman questionnaire for workplace Spirituality and Keyes, continuum-short questionnaire for comprehensive mental health. The validity of both questionnaires has been evaluated in terms of face, content and construct. For reliability testing, Cronbach's alpha coefficient has been used. The value of this coefficient was 0/81 for Millenium questionnaire and 0/84 for Keyes questionnaire. The collected data were analyzed using SPSS25 and Amos23 software. Findings show that the workplace spirituality variable has a significant coefficient impact of 68% on the comprehensive mental health of employees. All the secondary research hypotheses were also confirmed.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-878-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>workplace spirituality</keyword>
	<keyword>comprehensive mental health</keyword>
	<keyword>emotional well-being</keyword>
	<keyword>psychological well-being</keyword>
	<keyword>social well-being</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>43</issue>
	<startPage>181</startPage>
	<endPage>206</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Fuzzy Clustering of Job Occupations in National Iranian South Oil Company; Strategic Sourcing in Talent Supply Chain Management</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Nasser Saedinia</name>
	<email>n.saedinia93@iau-shoushtar.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Vahid Chenari</name>
	<email>vchenari@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Foad Makvandi</name>
	<email>Foadmakvandi@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Hemati</name>
	<email>m.hemati@semnaniau.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Talent management is one of the most important challenges faced by management of companies. Uncertainty in predicting competencies that are critical for companies and the inability to accurately estimate the voluntary of talents turnover, has required adapting concepts from the supply chain management, such as supply and strategic sourcing in talent management. The purpose of this research was to cluster the job occupations of the National Iranian South Oil Company (NISOC) in order to provide suitable strategies for sourcing talents in each cluster. This study is considered a quantitative applied research. The research strategy was c-means fuzzy clustering method. The statistical population was all human resources staff in NISOC and the statistical sample consisted of 80 experts from human resources section which have been selected by purposive method. Based on the findings, the job occupations were categorized into four clusters of routine, leverage, bottleneck and critical occupations, and suitable strategies for supplying and sourcing talents for each cluster were proposed.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-888-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Fuzzy clustering</keyword>
	<keyword>Job Occupations</keyword>
	<keyword>talent supply chain management</keyword>
	<keyword>National Iranian South Oil Company</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>43</issue>
	<startPage>207</startPage>
	<endPage>238</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Impact of Authentic Leadership on Risk Perception of Employees with the Mediating Role of Safe Climate in Ilam Petrochemical Company</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Reza Sepahvand</name>
	<email>sepahvand.re@lu.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Behrouz Mousazadeh</name>
	<email>mousazadeh.be@fc.lu.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">This study investigated the impact of of authentic leadership on risk perception of employees with the mediating role of safe climate in Ilam Petrochemical Company. The present study is considered a descriptive survey in terms of purpose, and applied in terms of data collection. The statistical population consisted of Ilam Petrochemical Company's official and contract staff with about 700 personnel. According to the Morgan table, 250 people were selected through simple random sampling. Four standard questionnaires were used for measuring the data and PLS software was used for data analysis. The composite reliability of the constructs was more than %76 the total Cronbach's alpha was %77 and the convergent validity of the variables was above %68 Findings showed that authentic leadership had a positive and significant relationship with safety climate and explained %71 of safety climate change. Safety climate has a negative and significant relationship with risk perception and authentic leadership has a significant negative relationship with risk perception. Also, the role of respondents' personality as a moderating variable on employees' perception of risk was confirmed. Finally, the mediating relationship between authentic leadership and risk perception was shown to be high.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-883-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Authentic leadership</keyword>
	<keyword>risk perception</keyword>
	<keyword>safety organizations</keyword>
	<keyword>critical situations</keyword>
	<keyword>Ilam Petrochemical.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>43</issue>
	<startPage>239</startPage>
	<endPage>264</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">A Study on the Rate and Causes of Workers\' Burnout in Satellite Jobs (Case: Iranian Offshore Oil Company in Sirri Island)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mehdi Sadeghi</name>
	<email>mehdi58sad@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Abbas Dadras</name>
	<email>abbas_dadras@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ahmadali Asadpour</name>
	<email>asadpour.a@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The burnout issue of employees of the satellite staff is one of the most important issues in the management of human resources. Thus, the rate of employees' burnout in the Iranian Offshore Oil Company (Siri Operational Area) and the causes of its occurrence among the employees were discussed in this research Data gathering was done through a standard burnout questionnaire by Maslach and Jackson (1994) and the researcher-made questionnaire an occupational burnout in satellite jobs.The statistical sample consisted of 305 employees. Data were analyzed and evaluated by using Friedman variance analysis, Chi square test, Fisher test (ANOVA test) and Scheffe follow up test. The results of this study indicated that various causes among the five classes of occupational burnout etiology in the satellite careers affect its formation. Burnout of the company's staff is due to individual causes, occupational characteristics, organizational characteristics, and economic and social factors. Also, there was no confirmation of job burnout due to work environment factors.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-889-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Burnout</keyword>
	<keyword>Satellite Jobs</keyword>
	<keyword>General health of the employees</keyword>
	<keyword>Iranian Offshore Oil Company</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>43</issue>
	<startPage>265</startPage>
	<endPage>294</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Identify and Rank the Barriers to Knowledge Sharing
(Case Study: Telecommunication Office of the National Iranian South Oilfields Company)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Reza Mirzaee</name>
	<email>Rezamirzaee58@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Fariba Nazari</name>
	<email>Nazari_lib@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The objective of this research was to identify and rank the barriers knowledge sharing by using the fuzzy hierarchy analysis method. This research is consumed an applied-developmental research, in terms of objective and the descriptive-survey in terms of nature. The research population included all managers of telecommunication projects of Telecommunication Office of National Iranian South Oil Company, participated directly in knowledge acquisition and sharing. The population size was determined to be 30 people. The census method was used and sampling was not performed due to the population size. The tools used in this research were two researcher-developed questionnaires, including the Delphi fuzzy technique and fuzzy hierarchy analysis. Data were analyzed using Excel software. Results indicated that individual barriers with a weight of 0.439 ranked first, technological barriers with a weight of 0.351 ranked second and organizational barriers with a weight of 0.210 ranked third.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-890-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>knowledge sharing</keyword>
	<keyword>individual barriers</keyword>
	<keyword>organizational barriers</keyword>
	<keyword>technological barriers.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher>Institute for International Energy Studies</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</journalTitle>
	<issn>2251-8886</issn>
	<eissn>2588-4409</eissn>
	<publicationDate>2020-06</publicationDate>
	<volume>11</volume>
	<issue>43</issue>
	<startPage>295</startPage>
	<endPage>323</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Designing Work-Life Balance Model with Qualitative Research Approach
(Case Study: Mazandaran Province Gas Company)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Hamed Mohammadi</name>
	<email>Mohammadi.h.16@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The main purpose of this paper is to develop the model of work-life balance in Mazandaran Province Gas Company as a service and project-oriented company. In the present study, a qualitative method based on grounded theory strategy has been used, because the researcher has used systematically collected conceptual data to explain the model. The field method was used for data collection by interview tools and the statistical population consisted of 25 managers and experts of the study company. Researcher developed a credible theory of work-life balance using an inductive approach to data collection and for this purpose, after the open coding, concepts and categories were extracted and in the axial coding stage these categories were presented in the form of axial phenomena, causal conditions, contextual conditions, and confounding conditions. The story line and paradigm were then drawn.</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-891-en.html</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Work-Life Balance</keyword>
	<keyword>Grounded theory</keyword>
	<keyword>Mazandaran Province Gas Company</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
 </records>
 
  
  
  
  
 