@article{ 
author = {Sanjari, Ahmad Reza and Alizadeh, Aliakbar and Jokar, Maryam Jokar},  
title = {The Investigation of Relationship between Talent Management and Performance Upgrade of Elite Staffs in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company (NIOPDC)}, 
abstract ={Talent management helps organizations qualified people with appropriate skills worked in a proper occupational position to attain the intended goals. Thus, main purpose of this study is to determine the relationship between the talent management (recruitment and identification, selecting, developing, keeping and application) and performance improvement (financial, knowledge-oriented, and behavioral) of elite staffs of NIPODC. Methods of this study is descriptive and correlation type. Statistical society consists of all the Distinguished Alumni who were employed through Elite Selection System between years of 1380 and 1390 who are 112 people, out of this number, 87 people were selected through Simple random sampling in proportion with society volume and questionnaires were distributed amongst them. The research results show a positive and significant relationship between components of talent management and performance improving. In spite of such relationship; the results of tests show that the indexes such knowledge-oriented performance, recruiting and identifying, developing, keeping and application of elite staffs are not in a good condition and should be reinforced.&#160;},  
Keywords = {Talent management – Performance - Elite staff},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {9-29}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-339-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-339-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2015}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Golabli, Madineh},  
title = {The Survey of Relationship between Time Management with Job Stress and Performance of Male and Female Employees in Material &#38; Procurement Management of N.I.S.O.C}, 
abstract ={Nowadays, factors such as economic globalization and creation of global markets, rapid changes of technologies, become-knowledgeable organizations, expansion of e-commerce, rapid and easy access of the consumer to goods and services, and change of their social requirements have caused a severe competition among businesses followed by a stress on these organizations` personnel. Thus, aside the organizations` social responsibility for their personnel physical and mental health, one of the pioneer organizations` strategies in the economic competition is to reduce the personnel stress in order to eliminate negative consequences such as the loss of efficiency .consequently, since optimum time management controls and regulates the stresses and daily influx of tasks as well as reducing the individuals` anxiety and finally their stress in addition to have a n effective role in improving their efficiency. Three hypotheses were proposed and a significance level was considered for them. The method of this study is a correlation one and Olmsted's time management, Parker and DeCurtis ` job stress and Patterson `s job efficiency self-evaluation questionnaires were used for data collection. statistical society of this study is all personnel of National Iranian South Oilfields company`s supply and goods Affairs Department (477 ones) of which 250 ones were selected using the stratified random sampling .228 ones filled and returned the distributed questionnaires. Descriptive statistical methods (tables of frequency, percent, average, and etc.) were used to extract the results of questionnaires and inferential statistical methods (Pearson correlation coefficients (were used test the hypotheses and data analysis. Using the statistical methods above and SPSS software, all data were analyzed. Results indicated that there is a significant relationship between time management and job stress of male and female employees; there is a significant relationship between time management and efficiency of male and female employees; and there is a significant relationship between job stress and efficiency of male and female employees. Finally, suggestions were presented to improve the time management and efficiency and reduce the job stress of the personnel.&#160;},  
Keywords = {Time Management - job stress - job performance},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {31-52}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-340-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-340-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2015}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Mokhtari, Maryam and Sadeghnia, Asiyeh and Roozbehi, Saadat},  
title = {Study the Relationship between Organizational Justices 
Perception and Organizational Citizenship Behavior}, 
abstract ={Organizations can&#8217;t develop production and effectiveness of their own without voluntary willingness of people to cooperate. Because, people do their duties based on acceptable rules and regulations of an organization in forced mod. But people express their effort energy and knowledge to flourish their abilities in favor of the organization in voluntary cooperation. Since organizational citizenship behavior (OCB) OR voluntary citizenship behavior (VCB) is out of the requirements of employees main role that results in higher productivity of man power. In this study have been investigated the relationship between organizational justice perception and organizational citizenship behavior. In this study survey and documentary methods have been used. The statistic population was 420 employees of G.O.G.P That 201 men selected based on Morgan chart as sample and studied with simple random sampling. Standardized questionnaire was used to gather the information. Descriptive results of the study shows that average of employees organizational justice perception is lower than the average and employees score of organizational citizenship behavior is higher than the average. Analytical results of the study confirm the relationship between perceptions of procedural justice. Perception of interactional justice and total components of perception of justice with organizational citizenship behavior. But theories of perception of distributive justice, age, gender, marital status, ethnicity and education of employees with organizational citizenship behavior have been rejected. The results of the study were compared with similar previous studies and in order to improve the perception of organizational justice. Some proposals and presented. &#160;},  
Keywords = {Perception of organizational justice - organizational citizenship behavior- oil company - Ghachsaran},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {53-82}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-341-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-341-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2015}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Sepahvand, Reza and Arefnezhad, Mohse},  
title = {Examine the Relationship between Types Human Resource Strategies on Employee Participation (Case Study: National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Lorestan Region)}, 
abstract ={Today, participating in the organization's staff is one of the most basic ways to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of administrative and managerial countries, organizations and companies. According to increasing importance of human resources in organizations, this study was to investigate the relationship between human resource strategies with the participation of employees in the National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Lorestan region and provide solutions needed. In this study were used the Hussey model with four human resource strategies: task-oriented, model-based, developmental and evolutionary. With the design Questionnaire about Human resource strategy and employee participation and distribution, collection and analysis using structural equation modeling software Amos18 relationships between variables is explained. The statistical population includes staff National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Lorestan region that using the Cochran formula was selected the number of 126 persons. In this study sampling has been randomly .The results showed that confidence level of 95% between transformative and development strategy with employee involvement is a positive relationship and between strategies model-based and task-oriented model there is a negative relationship. &#160;},  
Keywords = {human resources- human resources strategy- employee participation},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {83-107}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-342-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-342-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2015}  
}

@article{ 
author = {AfkhamiArdakani, Mahdi and Varmazyar, Mohsen and MighaniNejad, Alirez},  
title = {Preparing Model Seniority Relative to Tenure Supervision Job Case Study: RIPI}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this research is, selecting managements in research institute of petroleum industry (RIPI) according with main factors. These main factors are determined by reviewing the literature, and filling the questionnaires. The factor analysis (FA) method is applied to analysis information. According to the result of FA, main factors are classified in three categories: knowledge, skills, and attributes. Each of these categories consist different concepts, and conceptual levels. &#160;},  
Keywords = {Competency – Seniority –Selection - Factor Analysis (FA) –Knowledge – Skills - Attributes.},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {109-131}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-343-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-343-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2015}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Rabiee, Ali and Zahedi, Shamsosadat and Amini, Ami},  
title = {Examine the Relationship between Human Resources Culture and Knowledge Management at the National Level and Organizational Level (Case Study of Institute for International Energy Studies (I.I.E.S)}, 
abstract ={Today, culture as an infrastructure is a key role in the implementation of knowledge management in organizations. One reason for the lack of success in the implementation of knowledge management in Iranian organizations, organizational culture is both unaware of the situation in general view and Iranian national culture indicators in Special view. This study examines the relationship between the components of culture in national and organizational aspects of knowledge management deals in Institute for International Energy Studies (IIES) as one of the important and effective institutes and think tank of oil industry. This is an applied an also developmental survey research and is conducted in the field. The cultural model of Daniel Denison was chosen to evaluate the organizational culture and The Building Blocks of Knowledge Management model which was presented by Probst and others was used to evaluate knowledge management. To test the hypothesis with a sample size of 83 patients in the managers and experts of this Institute were randomly selected sampling. Then Check the status of the data synchronization by using the Pearson correlation test was used. After that, hypotheses and correlation between variables was tested.},  
Keywords = {Culture - Organizational Culture – Knowledge - Knowledge Management},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {133-154}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-344-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-344-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2015}  
}

@article{ 
author = {NarengiSani, Fatemeh and Rashidi, Mohammad Mehdi and Youzbashi, Alirez},  
title = {The Multiple Relations between Psychological Capital, Transformational Leadership and Employee Creativity (Case Study: The Institute for International Energy Studies)}, 
abstract ={The current research has conducted with the aim of examining the multiple relationships between psychological capital, transformational leadership and creativity in the institute of international energy studies. Using of correlation research method, 50 experts have been selected purposely (not randomly). After collecting questionnaire and based on research aims Research, data have been analyzed by the statistical methods such as one-sample t test, regression analysis and Structural equation modeling. &#160;The results show that 1) the situation of psychological capital and its dimensions, transformational leadership and its dimensions and creativity are desirable, 2) according to employee, among psychological capital and transformational capital dimensions, resilience, self-efficacy, Individual consideration, Idealized Influence, Intellectual Stimulation have more importance. 3) Transformational leadership has direct effect on psychological capital and creativity but psychological capital doesn&#8217;t have any effect on employee creativity. &#160;},  
Keywords = {Psychological capital - transformational leadership – employee creativity},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {155-177}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-345-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-345-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2015}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Abili, Khodayar and Nadery, Abolqasem and Asarzadeh, Rez},  
title = {A Study On The Relationship Between On-  The  -Job Training And Knowledge Management In Iranian Offshore Oil Company And Give Suitable Suggestions For Its Improvement}, 
abstract ={In the knowledge-based era knowledge management (KM) is considered as the primary task of organizations that strive to utilize their intellect capitals effectively. Hence, educated human resources can help to appropriate and to be enablers of KM and facilitating of Knowledge Creation, Storage Sharing and implementation. On the job training as systems of human resources development have considered in Iranian Offshore Oil Company for many years that now ,the recent research wants to study on the relationship between on the job training (OJT) and knowledge management in Iranian Offshore Oil Company and its improvement. At the end of this study we have given suggestions to solve the interruption of this correlation and improve it. The research type is a descriptive survey and correlation type. A sample of 140subjects was selected as statistical sampling. Questionnaire made by was used among employees of company selected by random sampling. The questionnaire was modified to be appropriate for this study, and then its reliability was assessed by using Cronbach's alpha coefficient. In order to analyze the data, T-test with for samples and Pearson correlation coefficient, were used. Findings indicate that: 1. OJT and KM both of them have acceptable and desirable situation in all components beside sub factors: have significant correlation between OJT andKM2. Regarding the results of first question of survey that shows poor professional state, some suggestions were proposed according to literature and results of research to improve between OJT and KM.&#160;},  
Keywords = {On_the_Job Training - Knowledge Management - Iranian Offshore Oil Company},
volume = {6},
Number = {22}, 
pages = {179-208}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-346-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-346-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2015}  
}

