<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>36</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>شناسایی و رتبه بندی عوامل موثر بر کارآفرینی سازمانی با هدف ارتقاء عملکرد شرکت با استفاده از تکنیک سلسه مراتبی فازی</title_fa>
	<title>Identifying and ranking of factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship with the aim of corporate performance improvement using Fuzzy AHP technique (Case: Coil manufacturing industry.)

</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;در شرایط رقابتی جهان امروز، کارآفرینی سازمانی نقش مهمی در موفقیت سازمانها و ایجاد تمایز آنها از سایرین می تواند داشته باشد. از همین رو ، کسب شناخت از عوامل موثر بر کارآفرینی سازمانی از اهمیت ویژه ای برخوردار می باشد. بر همین اساس، شناسایی و رتبه بندی عوامل موثر بر کارآفرینی سازمانی و تعیین درجه اهمیت و اولویت&amp;nbsp; آنها در جهت بهبود عملکرد شرکت، هدف این پژوهش قرار گرفته است. برای این منظور پس از مطالعه مبانی نظری و پیشینه تحقیقات در این حوزه ، عوامل موثر بر کارآفرینی سازمانی که به بهبود عملکرد شرکت کمک می کنند، در سه دسته عوامل ساختاری، زمینه ای و رفتاری شناسایی شدند. در مرحله بعد، اولویت و اهمیت هریک از این عوامل با استفاده از تکنیک تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی و با نظرسنجی از خبرگان شرکتهای برتر فعال در صنعت فنرسازی مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفت. نتایج حاکی از آن بود که &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;مهم ترین عوامل موثر بر کارآفرینی سازمانی با هدف بهبود و ارتقاء عملکرد شرکت به ترتیب اهمیت عبارتند از : عوامل ساختاری، عوامل زمینه ای و سپس عوامل رفتاری. در بین عوامل ساختاری، مهم ترین عوامل به ترتیب عبارت بودند از : &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;ساختار سازمان کارآفرین، تصمیم گیری وکنترل، سیستم پاداش. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;از سوی دیگر، &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;عوامل سیاسی / دولت ، زیر ساخت ها ، ارتباطات، &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;دسترسی به منابع به عنوان مهم ترین عوامل زمینه ای شناسایی شدند. در نهایت، مهم ترین عوامل رفتاری به ترتیب عبارت بودند از :&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:13.0pt;&quot;&gt;فرهنگ سازمانی، حمایت مدیریت، خطر پذیری، ویژگی های مدیران، ویژگی های کارکنان.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Todays, under the competitive conditions, organizational entrepreneurship can play an important role in the success of organizations and make them differentiate from others. Therefore, gaining of knowledge about the factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship is of particular importance. Accordingly, the purpose of this research was to identify and rank the factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship and determine their importance and priority in order to improve the company's performance. For this purpose, after studying the theoretical foundations and research background in this area, the factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship that help improve company performance were identified in three groups: structural, background and behavioral factors. In the next step, the priority and importance of each of these factors was evaluated using the fuzzy hierarchical process analysis technique and by a survey of experts from active and top companies in the field of steel industry. The results indicated that the most important factors affecting organizational entrepreneurship with the aim of improving and enhancing the company's performance were: structural factors, underlying factors and then behavioral factors. Among the structural factors, the most important factors were: structure of entrepreneurial organization, decision making and control, reward system. On the other hand, political factors / government, infrastructures, communications, access to resources were identified as the most important underlying factors. Finally, the most important behavioral factors were organizational culture, management support, riskiness, managerial characteristics, employee characteristics</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>کارآفرینی, کارآفرینی سازمانی, عملکرد شرکت, تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Entrepreneurship - organizational entrepreneurship - corporate performance - FAHP</keyword>
	<start_page>213</start_page>
	<end_page>242</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-311-51&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name> Mirza Hassan </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hosseini </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>میرزاحسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حسینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ri.hosseini@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002667</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002667</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>- Elham </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Keshavarz</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>الهام</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کشاورز</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002668</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002668</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
