<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title> Human Resource Management in Oil Industry </title>
<link>http://www.iieshrm.ir</link>
<description>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry - Journal articles for year 2018, Volume 10, Number 37</description>
<generator>Yektaweb Collection - https://yektaweb.com</generator>
<language>en</language>
<pubDate>2018/12/10</pubDate>

					<item>
						<title>Explaining Dimensions and Factors of Human Resource Management Professionalism in Public Organizations: A Meta-Synthesis</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=606&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Professionalism in Human Resource Management field is a key concept in Public Organizations. Despite the limited attitudes of top managers toward HR experts, new realities of global organizations have highlighted professional status of HR. The main objective of this research was to explain and identify affecting factors and its dimensions in public organizations. In conducting so, this research has been carried out using a qualitative method (Meta-analysis). In order to collecting data and information in this study, the main tool was the past documents in this field, which generally consisted of 36 articles. The content analysis has been used for data analyzing. The results indicated that the factors affecting the professionalism of HR can be divided to three general categories including: environmental, organizational and individual; and Also its dimensions consist of nine dimensions (governing body, ethical code, independence, certification, legal status, contribution to Society, the body of knowledge, research base and identification). Finally, based on the findings of the study, suggestions have been presented.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</description>
						<author>Seyyed Hossein  Akhavan Alavi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>A Review of Organizational Ambidexterity and Performance 

</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=607&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>The success, growth and long-term survival of an organization depend on its ability to exploit current capabilities and simultaneously explore the new competencies&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; Numerous articles have been devoted to the study of organizational ambidexterity in innovation, organizational and strategic management literature. Some indicated the important role of ambidexterity in organizations' performance. Others brought up that it is not so significant, and this question is yet to be answered. So far, several literature reviews and meta-analysis have been conducted on this construct, which has been focused on limited specific aspects. But to the best of our knowledge, there is no comprehensive review of both qualitative and quantitative studies which include all types of performance and also highlight the different conceptualization of organizational ambidexterity. Therefore, this comprehensive systematic review of 134 qualitative and quantitative studies during 1991-2016 has pursued two major goals: First identifying different conceptualizations of exploration and exploitation, and second, identifying the causes of different effects of organizational ambidexterity on performance in previous studies. The review results found 15 different conceptualizations of exploration&amp;ndash;exploitation; and also six reasons for the different results of previous research on the impact of organizational ambidexterity on performance have been identified, including measurement of organizational ambidexterity, level of analysis, research design, implementing organizational ambidexterity, performance measurement, and organizational ambidexterity conceptualization, each with its own dimensions</description>
						<author>Seyed Reza  Hejazi </author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Effect of Authentic Leadership on the Organizational Learning of the Employees regarding the Intermediate role of Organizational Intelligence </title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=608&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of authentic leadership on organizational learning regarding the mediating role of organizational intelligence. The present research is considered descriptive in terms of its purpose and a survey in terms of data collection. The data gathering tools were standard questionnaires of Authentic Leadership (Valmba et al, 2006), Organizational Intelligence (Albrecht, 2001), and Diane Niefe's Organizational Learning Questionnaire (2001). The likert 5 scale has been used to measure the variables. The statistical population of this study including 400 persons was the official staff of the second refinery in South Pars Gas Company. Using the Cochran formula, 119 people were selected as the final sample of the study. In order to analyze the collected data, SPSS software and structural equation test have been used. The results showed that authentic leadership has a significant effect on organizational intelligence and learning. Also, the mediating role of organizational intelligence was confirmed by the significance of the relationships.</description>
						<author>Naser  Poursadegh </author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Explaining the model of Antecedents and Consequences of work-life balance (case study: Iranian Gas National Company)

</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=609&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Today, &amp;nbsp;many demographic and sociological changes such as increasing the number of women, working couples, long working hours, and the complexity of technology in the workplace have been occurred, which National Iranian Gas Company (NIGC) is also influenced by them and seeks to find out the work-life balance and ways to improve it. Therefore, explaining and surveying the model of antecedents and consequences of work-life balance in Iranian Gas National Company has been considered as the goal of this research. The research method was descriptive &amp;ndash; correlation. Statistical population was employees of NIGC including 2172 individuals. Among them 327 people were selected by stratified random sampling method. Data was gathered through standard questionnaires and analyzed by using structural equation modeling and SPSS and LISREL software. The results indicated that job characteristics, core self-evaluations and the protean career orientation have a significant positive effect on work-life balance, and work-life balance also has a significant positive effect on job satisfaction, family satisfaction and organizational pride of employees. Also, organizational pride has a significant positive effect on job satisfactioToday, &amp;nbsp;many demographic and sociological changes such as increasing the number of women, working couples, long working hours, and the complexity of technology in the workplace have been occurred, which National Iranian Gas Company (NIGC) is also influenced by them and seeks to find out the work-life balance and ways to improve it. Therefore, explaining and surveying the model of antecedents and consequences of work-life balance in Iranian Gas National Company has been considered as the goal of this research. The research method was descriptive &amp;ndash; correlation. Statistical population was employees of NIGC including 2172 individuals. Among them 327 people were selected by stratified random sampling method. Data was gathered through standard questionnaires and analyzed by using structural equation modeling and SPSS and LISREL software. The results indicated that job characteristics, core self-evaluations and the protean career orientation have a significant positive effect on work-life balance, and work-life balance also has a significant positive effect on job satisfaction, family satisfaction and organizational pride of employees. Also, organizational pride has a significant positive effect on job satisfaction. &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
n. &lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description>
						<author>Hamidreza  Irani</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Designing an Intelligent Organizational Model 
In Gas Extraction Operational Zone of Nar&amp;Kangan
</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=610&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Effective and efficient use of knowledge capitals is one of the the most important challenges facing modern organizations, and an attempt to create a new generation of organizations that called &amp;quot;smart organizations&amp;quot;, is considered as mandatory requirements of the knowledge age. The main objective of the present study was to present an organizational intelligence model in the Nar&amp;kangan gas exploitation area. The rsearch method in terms of purpose was applied and in terms of data collection was descriptive-survey. The main instrument for collecting data was a researcher-made questionnaire based on Organizational Intelligence Models Raj and Santi (&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;2001&lt;/span&gt;), Matsuda (&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;1992&lt;/span&gt;), Halal (&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;2000&lt;/span&gt;) and Albrecht (&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;2003&lt;/span&gt;) and interviewed. The statistical population of the study consisted &amp;nbsp;of &amp;nbsp;57 managers and supervisors familiar with the management issues and theoretical foundations of the research in the operational zone of Nar&amp;Kangan gas exploitation. Among them, 35 people who had more familiarity with the subject of this research were selected through a targeted sampling method. The research findings indicated that final model of organizational intelligence in the Nar&amp;kangan gas exploitation area includes components of the importance and use of knowledge, focusing on self-managed teams, organizational structure, focusing on information technology, organizational communication and unity and agreement in the form of structural intelligence variable, and the components of belonging and belief in employee&amp;rsquo;s progress, organizational memory, individual capabilities, social capabilities, organizational cognition, and the behavior of leaders and managers in terms of human intelligence variable.</description>
						<author>Saeed  Pakdel</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>Relationship between Organizational Silence &amp; Leadership Style Regarding the Moderating Role of Personality</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=611&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Although the employees are expected to contribute in organizations development by utilizing their knowledge, ideas, and comments, so often they prefer to remain silent. This research was designed to investigate the moderating role of personality in the relationship between organizational silence and leadership style at Research Institute of Petroleum Industry (RIPI). In this practical study, we gathered descriptive data by questionnaire, and utilized the structural equation modeling (SEM) technique to look at the correlations among data points. The random sampling technique has been used to gather 115 data points among the target population of 350 employees at RIPI. It has been used a combination of Leadership Style questionnaire (Bass &amp; Avilio, 2000), Personality questionnaire (L.R. Goldberg, 1993), and Organizational Silence (M. Vakola and D. Bouradas, 2005) for gathering data. Reliability and validity of data were investigated by using the cronbach's alpha test and AVE test, respectively. The results indicated that the transformational and transactional leadership style has a significant reverse relationship with the organizational silence, while the relationship between non-interventional leadership style and organizational silence was insignificant. Furthermore, the introvert personality has a significant direct relationship with organizational silence. The results showed that for the staff with introvert personality, the non-interventional leadership style amplifies their silence and vice-versa. The personality variable in transformational and transactional leadership style has a moderating effect on the leadership-silence relationship as well.</description>
						<author>Reza  Shariati </author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>The Effects of the Employees’ Corporate Social Responsibility Perception on the Job Performance: A Case in The South Zagros Oil &amp; Gas Company


</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=612&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of employees&amp;rsquo; corporate social responsibility perceptions on job performance with considering the mediating role of variables such as quality of work life, organizational citizenship behavior, and affective commitment among employees of the Southern Zagros Oil and Gas Company. This research, in terms of purpose is considered applied and in terms of collecting information, is a descriptive-correlation research. Data were collected through a researcher-made questionnaire. The reliability of research tool was confirmed by Cronbach's alpha coefficient test (0.79) and the formal validity was confirmed by the opinion of the professors and the construct validity through fitting the model of measurement.The statistical population was 700 employees of headquarter staff of South Zagros Oil &amp; Gas Company. Using Cochran formula, 248 of them were selected as statistical sample by simple random sampling method. SPSS and Amos software were used to analyze the data. Based on the results of the structural equation analysis, all the hypotheses have been confirmed. The hypothesis based on this fact that &amp;quot;organizational citizenship behavior has a significant effect on job performance&amp;quot;, with the coefficient of 0.77, has shown the highest path coefficient. The second hypothesis, based on the fact that &amp;quot;understanding social responsibility of staff has significant effect on affective commitment&amp;quot; with the coefficient of 0.65 has shown the least path coefficient. The results showed that the employees should be socially responsible for increasing their job performance. On the other hand, the social responsibility of employees by affecting the quality of employee's work life, effective commitment and organizational citizenship behavior also make changes in job performance.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;</description>
						<author>Morteza  RaeiDehaghi</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
					<item>
						<title>The Effect of Perceived Organizational Justice on Employee’s Productivity with Mediating Role of Social Capital

</title>
						<link>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_id=613&amp;sid=1&amp;slc_lang=en</link>
						<description>Due to the importance of employee&amp;rsquo;s productivity in companies and its direct relationship with economic growth of the country, this research has done investigating the effect of organizational social capital and perceived organizational Justice on employee&amp;rsquo;s productivity in Gas Company of Kerman province. In terms of objective, this study was an applied research, and in terms of data collections a kind of correlation-descriptive research. The statistical population of the research consisted of 192 employees in Gas Company of Kerman province among which 128 employees were selected as sample size according to Krejcie and Morgan table. The sampling method was a simple random sampling. Data gathering tools were three standard questionnaires of organizational justice, organizational social capital and employee&amp;rsquo;s productivity that the construct validity of the questionnaires had been approved. Also, the reliability of the questionnaires using Cronbach&amp;rsquo;s Alpha and composite reliability calculated (0.851, 0.877), (0.867, 0.89) and (0.899, 0.912), respectively. Descriptive and inferential statistical (structural equation modeling) had been used to analyze the data. The results showed that perceived organizational justice beyond its direct effect exerts indirect effect on employee&amp;rsquo;s productivity through organizational social capital. Also, the result of the bootstrapping test showed that organizational social capital has the mediator role in the effect of perceived organizational justice on employee&amp;rsquo;s productivity.&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description>
						<author>Amin  Nickpour</author>
						<category></category>
					</item>
					
	</channel>
</rss>
