@article{ 
author = {Safari, Hosein and Jafarnejzad, Ahmad and yazdanpanah, Ahmadali and Bayati, Ali},  
title = {Relationship Between Competent Project Managers and Performance of Projects:
Risk Management Competency,
Important but Neglected}, 
abstract ={Performance improvement is an area which has been addressed considerably by researchers. However, HR performance Improvement has had less important compared to other resources of organizations. There is no doubt that effective training is the best way to improve and boost human resource performance in workplaces. A manager is competent if he /she demonstrates required competency of his/her job. But, the most important point is that whether having competent project managers can result in desirable performance of their projects or not. The authors in the first step have defined competency, project manager competency, and project performance and maturity. Then, they have evaluated maturity of projects as well as competency of project managers of a state company as a case study (subsidiary of Iran Oil Ministry). Finally, they have determined the most important area of PM competency and also has examined relation between project managers&#8217; competencies and projects&#8217; performance or maturity. The results show that having competent project managers can improve performance of project for which they work and risk management is the most important project management competency.},  
Keywords = {Competent project managers project performance competency},
volume = {8},
Number = {29}, 
pages = {3-31}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-61-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-61-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Gholipor, Rahmatollah and Heidari, Ali and Seyednaghavi, Mirali and Narimani, Mehdi},  
title = {Designing Human Resources Risk Management Model in the Transition from Public to Private Sector Based on Grounded Theory 
(The Case of the Oil and Gas Industry)}, 
abstract ={This study aims to develop a model for risk management of human resources in the transition from public to private for Oil and Gas Company. Qualitative research method based on grounded theory has been used. To collect data, semi-structured interviews have been done and statistical analysis was performed by Strauss and Corbin and paradigmatic model. Sampling technique has been theoretical sampling and was conducted by using targeted technique (judgment) and snowball (chain) .Finally,17 interviews were conducted with former and current senior managers and human resources experts and oil and gas industry brokers who have been involved in the privatization process. Analysis of the data obtained from interviews during the open, axial and selective coding process, for developing human resources risk management model based on grounded theory contained 6 concepts and 28 dimensions.},  
Keywords = { The transition period the oil and gas industry human resources risk models enterprise risk management techniques},
volume = {8},
Number = {29}, 
pages = {33-58}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-62-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-62-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Aghaz, Asal and Kooshki, Amirrez},  
title = {Factors Contributing to the Motivation and Retention of Knowledge Workers in National Iranian Gas Company of Qazvin Province}, 
abstract ={&#160; The purpose of this study is to investigate the factors contributing to the motivation and retention of knowledge workers in National Iranian Gas Company of Qazvin Province (NIGC-Qazvin); as well to study and prioritize the current practices (as is) and ideal values (should be) of these factors from the viewpoint of knowledge workers. The population of this survey consisted of the knowledge workers working at NIGC-Qazvin. Questionnaires were used to collect the required data. Interpersonal interaction, general working condition, personal development, empowerment, task and compensation identified as the most important motivators for knowledge workers working at NIGC-Qazvin. In addition, results indicated significant differences between current practices and ideal values. Finally, some practical guidelines have been proposed for proper use of motivation and retention methods in the case of knowledge workers.},  
Keywords = { knowledge workers motivation retention National Iranian Gas Company of Qazvin Province},
volume = {8},
Number = {29}, 
pages = {59-78}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-63-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-63-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Lajevardi, Seyed Jalil and Kokabi, Samieh},  
title = {Studying the Role of Emotional Intelligence in the Quality of Decision Making of Managers
(Case: Institute of International Energy Studies}, 
abstract ={Since decision making is one of key tasks of the managers in an organization and it has been the core of the management, the related factors which affects is have always been of interest for the researchers. Thus in this paper, the relationship between emotional intelligence and decision making style (based on rational, intuitive, dependency, momentary and avoiding decision making styles) of the managers of the Institute of International Energy Studies have been studied. For this purpose, among 50 managers of the International Institute for Energy Studies, 44 managers were selected as the statistical sample. Emotional intelligence data were collected by using the Siberia sharing emotional intelligence questionnaire and decision making style data were gathered by Scott and Bruce decision making questionnaire. The content validity of the two questionnaires was reviewed and confirmed by the opinion of the professionals and technical people. For checking of questionnaire, Cronbach's alpha was calculated by SPSS software. The emotional intelligence questionnaire was 0.81 and for decision making style questionnaire 0.76. Pearson correlation test was used to explain the relationship between emotional intelligence and five decision making styles. The results show that there is a meaningful and negative relationship between emotional intelligence and rational and avoiding decision styles of decision making of managers. There is a meaningful and positive correlation between emotional intelligence, and intuitive and momentary decision making style of managers. There was no meaningful relationship between emotional intelligence and dependency decision making style in this study. In this study structural equations model is used because in the present study an independent variable (emotional intelligence) with a variety of dimensions are conceded , and each dimension in sub-hypotheses is take&#160; as an independent variable that its effect on dependent variables (types of decision-making styles) shall be examined. &#160;},  
Keywords = { Emotional intelligence Rational Intuitive Dependent  Emotional Avoiding decision making style},
volume = {8},
Number = {29}, 
pages = {79-97}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-64-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-64-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Dabbaghi, Azadeh},  
title = {Identification and Ranking of Criteria for Distributing Mortgage Loan Among Applicants in the Iranian Petroleum Industry Based On a Mixed Methodology Study}, 
abstract ={Providing the oil and gas industry personnel with housing services and opportunities has been one of the most important supporting services offered by the Ministry of petroleum historically. Mortgage lending is one of these housing opportunities. In fact the vast majority of home purchases among the petroleum industry personnel are made with the help of the mortgage loans. Reviewing the administrative background of distributing the mortgage loans among applicants shows that a comprehensive research on the criteria and methodology of selecting candidate personnel has not been accomplished. So, in this study a mixed methodology approach was adopted to identify and rank the important criteria for Distributing Mortgage Loan among Applicants in the Iranian Petroleum Industry. First, the qualitative research interviews were conducted to collect the experts' opinions in order to identify and classify the related criteria. Second, a quantitative methodology was used in order to rank the identified criteria using &#34;Grey Multi Attribute Decision Making&#34; approach.},  
Keywords = {Grey Multi Attribute Decision Making (GMADM) Mortgage LoanCriteria Identification and Ranking},
volume = {8},
Number = {29}, 
pages = {99-115}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-65-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-65-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Sanatigar, Hoda and HadiPeykani, Mehrban and Gholamzadeh, Darioush},  
title = {Investigate and Testing the Model of Organizational Agility for the 
Pension Fund of Oil Industry}, 
abstract ={&#160; The purpose of this study has been evaluating and testing organizational agility model for the Iranian pension funds. In fact, the fundamental questions are: what are the dimensions and components of organizational agility for the studied organizations? How the retirement organization could be agile and what are its characteristics? In order to answer these questions, at first by reviewing the literature, studying the research relevant to agility, a framework was provided. Then, the relationship between variables and facts inferred, by using factor analysis and the application of smart PLS, was tested and approved. And finally the proposed model was presented with the following component dimensions: Leadership Agility (with five components of setting agility background, creating collaboration, creativity, self-leadership, creating synergy); agility in service delivery (with four components of speed, competence and quality, flexibility and innovation, accountability); workforce agility (with four components of intelligence and knowledge, flexibility, cooperation, competence); cultural agility (with five components of cooperation and training, flexibility, competence, innovation and creativity, transparency and trust); Agility of organizational factors (with three components of flexible structure, clear and smooth rules and instructions, modern methods and processes), agility in communication and information technology (with two components of high-speed and updated hardware and infrastructure, software and appropriate and timely programs).},  
Keywords = { Model of Organizational Agility Pension Funds Oil Industry Factor Analysis},
volume = {8},
Number = {29}, 
pages = {117-142}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-66-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-66-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {EbrahimiBalani, Mehdi and Shahbazmoradi, Saeed and karoubi, Zahr},  
title = {Measuring National Iranian Oil Company employees’ job satisfaction based on 
“HAY” Model
Measuring National Iranian Oil Company employees’ job satisfaction based on 
“HAY” Model}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this study was to measure job satisfaction of&#160;&#160; National Iranian Oil Company subsidiaries and staff units based on HAY model. This study was conducted in 1391. It included permanent and temporary staff of central units and the subsidiaries of NIOC. This study took 5093 members of the group mentioned above (randomly).&#160; The tool for this study was Hay's job satisfaction questionnaire. The Freed Man test was used to compare and rate each of the dimensions of job satisfaction.&#160; For comparison and analysis of job satisfaction of the demographic groups Kruskal -Wallis and Man-Whitney was used. The results showed the rankings of Oil Company subsidiaries and staff units based on their job satisfaction. Also every dimensions of job satisfaction for each company was ranked..},  
Keywords = {Job satisfactionHay Model National Iranian Oil Company},
volume = {8},
Number = {29}, 
pages = {143-166}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-67-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-67-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Montazeri, Mohammad and Pasandipour, Ne},  
title = {investigating the relationship between organizational intelligence and organizational learning among the employees of Iranian Oil Pipelines and Telecommunication Company (IOPTC) – south east region}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this study was investigating the relationship between organizational intelligence and organizational learning among the employees of Iranian Oil Pipelines and Telecommunication Company (IOPTC) &#8211; south east region. Research method was descriptive and statistical population included 350 full time employees of IOPTC, and according to Krejcie and Morgan&#8217;s table a sample with 183 subjects estimated. To collect data, organizational learning questionnaire established by Peter Senge (2005) and organizational intelligence questionnaire established by Albrecht (2002) were used. The collected data analyzed using Pearson's correlation coefficient and multiple structural equations modeling statistical methods in AMOS software. Pearson's correlation test results indicated that there is a direct relationship between willingness to change, common destiny, organizational morale, organizational performance, application of knowledge, unity and agreements, and organizational learning. Also, structural equation modeling results indicated that there is a positive and significant relationship between organizational intelligence and organizational learning. Also, the relationship between common destiny, organizational pressures and unity and agreement with organizational learning confirmed. Among the components of organizational intelligence, willingness to change has a higher correlation with organizational learning, which indicates that the more organizational learning in an organization, the more willingness to change among the employees.},  
Keywords = { Organizational Learning Organizational Intelligence Willingness to Change Common Destiny Organizational Morale Organizational Performance Unity And Agreement Application Of Knowledg},
volume = {8},
Number = {29}, 
pages = {167-189}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-68-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-68-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2016}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {Development of a Personnel Appointment and Promotion structural Model for first line management level 
(case study: National Iranian Oil Company)}, 
abstract ={Promotion and appointment of appropriate human resources to accurately and objectively, one of the main factors leading to the success of organizations. Decide on the appointment and promotion of staff according to merit factor in organizations is a matter of days. This study aims to develop a model for the promotion and appointment of staff to first line management level based on individual and organizational components was performed. For the present study were all employees of National Iranian Oil Company that was established in the &#160;first line management career of those surveyed were in 1521. Among the different variables of literature, management experience, job rank, work experience and merit with dependent variable (position rank) showed significant relationship. After study of the variables, was developed scoring instructions. data obtained from scoring instructions using SPSS 22 and LISREL softwares were analyzed. Direct and indirect effects and overall effects of professional experience, job rank, work experience and competence on the dependent variable (position rank) were studied. Results show that independent variables and Mediator variable(job rank) had a significant effect on the dependent variable. The other obtained results, data were fit and proper indices with model.},  
Keywords = {Specialized experience, job rank, job experience, competence and  position rank},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {3-25}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-71-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-71-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {Competency Model of Managers and Human Resource Professionals in
Gas Company in East Azerbaijan Province Using ISM Technique}, 
abstract ={Undoubtedly, the most important competitive advantage of organizations in the world of today's rapid changes is having a competent human factor. This is the most important strategic factor that cannot be easily imitated and it could affect the success and sustainable development of organizations. Hence, the success of any organization is dependent on the development of human resources and the development of human resources in any organization and even in every country will not be possible without understanding and discovery capabilities, capabilities and competencies of this great and potential capital. In other wors, due to the special and strategic status of human resource managers and coping with the CEO, communicating with all employees and other managers , their competencies will be very importance. For this purpose, designing and development of competencies models for HR managers would be necessary to meet the needs of organizations in today's rapidly changing conditions. In the present study, after identifying the competencies required by managers and human resources specialists in the gas company of East Azarbaijan, they were ranked by HR managers and non-human resources managers using the ISM technique. The statistical population of this research was all managers and supervisors of the company in high, intermediate and operational levels of the organization including 60 persons.&#160; Due to the limited statistical community, the whole society was considered as the research sample. The results of data analysis showed that among the twenty factors extracted from the research literature in this research and based on a distributed questionnaire, ten factors have been identified as the most important competencies of the managers and human resources specialists of the gas company of East Azarbaijan Province of Iran. The ISM technique was then used to identify the relationship between the factors affecting employee empowerment implementation.},  
Keywords = {Competency Model, Human Resource Managers, HR Professionals, ISM Technique.},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {27-50}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-72-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-72-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {Survey the Effect of Talent Management on Organizational Citizenship Behavior
(Case study: Yazd Gas Company)}, 
abstract ={In recent years, human is known as one of the most important of competitive factors, in order to increase efficiency and productivity in organizations. According to the importance of this subject in Gas Company, the aim of this research is survey the effect of talent management`s dimensions as the last wave in human resources on organizational citizenship behavior. Structural equation modeling was used for this purpose. The population of this survey are all staff of Yazd Gas Company, which among them, were selected 122 people as sample. Findings show, there is a significant relationship between all dimensions of talent management, except attract, on organizational citizenship behavior. Unlike talent management, organizational citizenship behavior is in good situation. According to the findings, managers of this organization, can increase their efficiency and productivity in attract and training of human resources by reduce their costs and only by alignment and retention through control and regular feedback, increase organizational citizenship behavior.},  
Keywords = {Human resource, talent management, organization customer behavior, Structural equation modeling.},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {51-74}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-73-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-73-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {Investigating Affecting and Influential Factors on Organizational Cynicism Among Staff of National Iranian oil Products Distribution Company (NIOPDC)}, 
abstract ={The aim of this study was to investigate the effecting factors and being affected factors on organizational cynicism in National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company. The statistical population in this study was included all employee in the National Iranian Oil Products Distribution Company including 1246 people. The sample size was determined by Morgan and Krejcie of 297 people. Data collection was conducted by literature review and fieldwork. Data collection tool has been the questionnaire. Questionnaire validity has been verified using formal validity and construct validity, and questionnaire reliability checked by using Cronbach's alpha coefficient .To test the research hypotheses, structural equation model was used. The results of the research showed that psychological factors (perceived organizational politics, deviation from the psychological contract) have an impact on organizational cynicism. Also, organizational cynicism attitudes outcomes, and behavioral outcomes (job satisfaction, organizational commitment, destructive behavior of employees) were impressive.},  
Keywords = {organizational cynicism- perceived organizational politics- deviation from the psychological contract- job satisfaction.},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {75-98}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-74-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-74-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {Identification of the factors related to transfer of training to work environment amongst the employees of National Petrochemical Company}, 
abstract ={Organizations have long been devoting significant financial resources to organizing organizational training. But the development of human resources is not achieved by conducting general and specialized training. Today, training is expected to provide the desired behavioral changes in the staff. Studies show that many educational programs do not create desirable behavioral changes in the staff. This means that employees are not able to transfer their learning to their work environment. The effectiveness of training is heavily reliant on the assumptions that occur in its transmission to the workplace. Therefore, one of the best ways to achieve educational effectiveness is to increase the transfer rate of education. Therefore, in this research, we have identified factors affecting the transfer of education. The research method was a survey and the statistical population included500 people who participated in the courses of Petrochemical Research and Technology Company in three cities of Tehran, Arak and Mahshahr. Among them, 217&#160; persons were selected through stratified random sampling method.&#160; In the research process, 27&#160; factors influencing the transfer of education were identified by reviewing the related literature. By implementing three stages of Delphi technique, these factors decreased to 18&#160; factors. Then, for identifying facilitating and preventing factors of transfer of training, a questionnaire was developed with 62&#160; items. The results showed that of among the 18&#160; identified factors, 7 factors were weak as facilitators, 9&#160; factors were considered as weak barriers, one factor as a strong barrier and one factor as a strong facilitator in this organization. Also, the results of exploratory factor analysis showed that the factors related to the transfer of training were grouped in five levels: individual, supportive, educational, reward system and progression, which resulted in the presentation of a new typology of factors influencing the transfer of training.},  
Keywords = {Transfer of training, facilitation and barrier factors, Petrochemical Research and Technology Organization.},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {99-122}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-75-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-75-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {Presentation of a framework for reward payments based on the performance using BSC-ANP approach in the Iranian Oil Terminal Company}, 
abstract ={The present study was carried out to Presentation of a framework for reward payments based on the performance in the Iranian Oil Terminal Company. This research is considered applicable in terms of purpose, in terms of data collection is Descriptive-survey. In this study, after reviewing literature and interviews with senior managers of company and identifying evaluation criteria's, map of network relationships in order to distributing reward in units and sections of organization has been introduced as a native framework. In addition, has been used BSC-ANP approach to ranking criteria and alternatives (organization units) in order to distribute the rewards. The results show that among the units of company &#34;loading and export operations&#34; and &#34;naval operation&#34; are more important than other units. Also section of &#34;main processes&#34; with an average ratio of 8% has first priority in reward payment. Represented framework makes reward payment in relation to performance evaluation of employee examined in various dimensions and come out of steady state.},  
Keywords = {Reward, Analytic Network Process, Balance Scorecard, Iranian Oil Terminals Company},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {123-143}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-76-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-76-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {},  
title = {Investigating the Mediating Role of Leader-Member Exchange (LMX) in Direct and Indirect Relationship of Ethical Climate with Role Stress in Staff Employees of National Iranian Oil Company (NIOC)}, 
abstract ={Nowadays, ethical and moral values observance is the major and effective factor on the attitudes and behaviors of employees in the workplace. The aim of this research is investigating the mediating role of leader-member exchange in the direct and indirect relationship between ethical climate with role stress. This research is a correlational study. The statistical population is all the staff employees of National Iranian Oil Company (NIOC). The participants of this study include 300 employees who were selected by stratified random sampling method. The instruments used in this study were Ethical Climate, Role Stress, and Leader-Member Exchange Questionnaires. Data were analyzed by Pearson correlation and Structural Equation Modeling (SEM). Structural equation modeling analyses indicated that the proposed model fits the data properly. The results supported the direct relationship of ethical climate and role stress and also this relationship was mediated through the leader-member exchange.},  
Keywords = {Ethical Climate, Role Stress, Leader-Member Exchange (LMX).},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {145-160}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-77-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-77-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Jalilian, Hamidreza and Morady, Morteza and Morady, Ali and Fatahi, Jamal},  
title = {The Factors Affecting the Organizational Belonging of Personnel in Kermanshah Province Gas Company and presenting a Conceptual Model for its Evaluation}, 
abstract ={With regard to the chaos and competitive environment of organizations, managers do not have much time to control employees, hence, motivated, conscientious, committed and belongs employees to the organization are the most important competitive advantage in organizations . Several factors such as individual factors and organizational factors have been considered&#160; as the consequences for the organization belonging precedence and are listed in different sources; The present study sought to evaluate the impact of individual and organizational factors on the organization belonging and the consequences of it and eventually belonging enterprise operational model. This research is considered a descriptive- survey, and on basis of purpose is a developmental -applied research. The statistical population was 480 employees of Kermanshah Province Gas Company that 288 persons were selected as sample. Path analysis was used to analyze the data. Test results showed that organizational factors affect belonging and its consequences, but the impact of individual factors were not confirmed. It was also found that organizational belonging is most effective to organizational outcomes.},  
Keywords = {organizational belonging organizational factorspersonal factors Gas Companies},
volume = {8},
Number = {30}, 
pages = {161-185}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-78-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-78-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {PourSadegh, Naser},  
title = {Comparative Study between Abusive Supervision and Social Loafing}, 
abstract ={The present article is based on a conducted comparative study between abusive supervision and social loafing among A Public sectore Company&#8217;s staff. This study is designed through the comparative-analysis approach based on survey method. The statistical population of this study is among 250 &#160;The Company&#8217;s staff. The measurement tool used in this study is a questionnaire including 3 personal information questions and 15 questions regarding testing the hypothesis. The reliability of the questionnaire, based on Cronbach's&#160;alpha, is 0.912. Kolmogorov&#8211;Smirnov&#160;Test is used to study the normal distribution of data, and the Pearson&#160;Correlation Coefficient Test is used to test the hypothesizes of the present study, in this regard,&#160; SEM analysis is used for its fitting. The result gained through the present study shows that there is a meaningful and direct relationship between abusive supervision and social loafing among The Company&#8217;s staff. In the same vein, the results gained through the fitting SEM show that for one unit change in abusive supervision variable, there is, then, 0.82 changes in social loafing variable.},  
Keywords = {abusive supervision, social loafing, supervision style},
volume = {8},
Number = {31}, 
pages = {3-39}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-146-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-146-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {kheirAndish, Mehdi and SeyedNaghavi, Mir Ali and Safari, Sayareh},  
title = {Driving factors’ pattern of the elites’ inclination towards turnover from the viewpoint of NIOPCS directors}, 
abstract ={The importance of human resource has highlighted &#8220;turnover&#8221; issue in most organizations. Today the high rate of desertion is regarded as an organizational problem. Undoubtedly, the elites&#8217; turnover imposes huge costs on organizations. Therefore, it is essential to identify the causes of their turnover. The purpose of this study is to identify the causes of elite&#8217;s desertion, and its impact on the inclination of the staff of NIOPDC to desert. The present study is descriptive in terms of purpose, applied in terms of function, and survey research in terms of method. The questionnaire was formulated based upon survey literature and survey elites&#8217; opinions. The reliability value of 0.885 was calculated using Cronbach&#8217;s Alpha. The statistical population includes directors of NIOPDC (Tehran), 105 of which were chosen as sample using Cochran formula. The results obtained from data analysis using Confirmatory Factor Analysis and Path Analysis indicated that occupational and organizational factors have a meaningful impact on the staff desertion. Personal factors, on the other hand, had no meaningful impact.},  
Keywords = {turnover, elites, organizational factors, occupational factors, personal factors},
volume = {8},
Number = {31}, 
pages = {41-71}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-147-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-147-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {SharifiRad, Mohammad Sadegh and Mortazavi, Saeed and RahimNia, Fariborz and Farahi, Mohammad Mehdi},  
title = {Disclosure of the Context of Implicit Theories of Leadership from the Perspectives of the Employees of the National Iranian Oil Distribution Company of Kerman Region and Its Validation}, 
abstract ={Implicit theories of leadership as a series of cognitive structures that differentiate leaders from non-leaders have significant implications for followers as well as human resource management. In this regard, the present research attempted to identify and present the characteristics and capabilities of ideal leaders from the viewpoint of followers. Data collection was done using semi-structured interviews with 15 heads of units and employees of Iran's Oil Distribution Company in Kerman area. Exploratory blended research strategy was selected and used as a contractual content analysis tool. The texts of the interviews were compiled, had been written and coded, and then categories and themes were extracted; the results of coding and data analysis were classified into two themes of positive prototypes and negative prototypes. In the lowest level, 28 units of thoughts were discovered. Categories for positive pre-models include &#34;charismatic&#34;, &#34;humanistic&#34;, &#34;committed to securing,&#34; &#34;emotional maturity,&#34; &#34;high decision-making power,&#34; and for negative patterns of titles, &#34;self-protecting&#34;, &#34;deceitful&#34; and &#34;narrow&#34;. After the discovery of the categories of implied leadership theories in the qualitative stage, a quantitative validation of the model was developed and a 28-item questionnaire was designed and distributed among 128 samples under the supervision of units' heads, and the validity of the model was confirmed.},  
Keywords = {Implicit Theories of Leadership, Positive Prototypes, Negative Prototypes, National Iranian Oil Distribution Company of Kerman Province},
volume = {8},
Number = {31}, 
pages = {73-105}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-148-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-148-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {SalehZadeh, Reza and Shahin, Arash and Jahanbazi, Afshi},  
title = {Investigating the Impact of Managers’ Reverse Behaviors on Employees’ Organizational Indifference
 (The Case of Study: Isfahan Province Gas Company)}, 
abstract ={Studies have shown that in the recent decades managers&#8217; behaviors and their impacts on employees&#8217; outcomes are important topics in the organizational behavior and applied psychology domains and are discussed in different leadership theories. The aim of this research was to investigate the impact of managers&#8217; reverse behaviors on employees&#8217; organizational indifference in Isfahan Province Gas Company. This study used a mixed method research (i.e. qualitative and quantitative methods). First, through the interviews with employees and using thematic analysis, the managers&#8217; behaviors were identified. Next, based on the identified behaviors and Kano model the type of each behavior was classified and according to this classification the managers&#8217; reverse behaviors were identified. Then the impact of managers&#8217; reverse behaviors on employees&#8217; organizational indifference was investigated by Structural Equation Modeling (SEM) using AMOS software. Based on the results of the interviews, 46 managers&#8217; behaviors were identified out of which ten behaviors were must-be; five behaviors were one-dimensional, eighteen behaviors were attractive and thirteen behaviors were reverse type. Also, the results showed that managers&#8217; reverse behaviors have a significant positive effect on organizational indifference (b=0.86).},  
Keywords = {Reverse Behavior, Organizational Indifference, Kano Model, Isfahan Province Gas Company},
volume = {8},
Number = {31}, 
pages = {107-127}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-149-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-149-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Sepahvand, Reza and Mohammadyari, Zohreh},  
title = {Identifying and ranking  the factors influencing on interests of work and work engagement of employees of National Iranian Gas Company (case study: gas company employees of Ilam)}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this study is Identifying and ranking&#160; the factors influencing on interests of work and work engagement of employees of National Iranian Gas Company. The research method is mix method (qualitative - quantitative). The population in qualitative part includes human resources experts and managers of the National Gas Company and in quantitative section includes all staff of the National Gas Company. Grounded Theory was used for analyzing data in qualitative section and Identifying factors. In quantitative section, for examining the effectiveness of identifying factors influencing on interests of work and work engagement of employees , structural equation modeling has been applied by using LISREL software and for ranking Identifying factors Fuzzy AHP was used. The results showed that four main factors influencing the interests of work and work engagement include; organizational Resources, personal resources, career resources and competencies and supervisors and colleagues support. Among these factors, the most effective factor has been organizational resources.},  
Keywords = {interests of work, work engagement of employees, organizational Resources, personal resources, career resources, support},
volume = {8},
Number = {31}, 
pages = {129-152}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-150-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-150-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {HadiPeykani, Mehrban and Khanifar, Ali},  
title = {Explanation and prioritization of the factors affecting key employees’ turnover intention in privatized firms of National Oil Company (case study: Ahvaz pipe industrial Company)}, 
abstract ={Regarding the importance of organizational turnover, the related physical and spiritual costs in long term, and necessity for prediction and control of turnover to retain key employees, the present study was conducted to investigate, explain and prioritize the factors affecting employees&#8217; turnover intention in Ahvaz pipe industrial Company in the context of a correlation type applied survey. Data were collected by submitting a questionnaire among 271 employees. The results of data analysis by SPSS and LISREL software confirmed construct validity of the research variables and revealed that feeling of working with organization has the highest priority with Friedman rank of 5.498; followed by supervisor&#8217;s characteristics (3.994), work-related shocks (3.902), and job properties (3.856). Job-related feelings and emotions had the lowest importance.},  
Keywords = {},
volume = {8},
Number = {31}, 
pages = {153-175}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-151-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-151-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Pooya, Alireza and Norouzi, Marziyeh},  
title = {Typology of human resources performance evaluation indices (Case study: Fars Province Gas Company)}, 
abstract ={Each organization to determine the quality of your work had an urgent need to evaluate the system. A correct understanding of the needs and the proper management of human resources in organizations is key to success. The aim of this study is to identify and categorize the factors affecting employee performance evaluation is using factor analysis. After reviewing the literature, 62 factors affecting the performance, were identified and were reduced to 45. Using factor analysis These factors were divided into 8 main indicator Which include Personality factors, performance management, Teamwork, Commitment and ethical values of the organization, Communication skills, Information and knowledge management, Designing products and services based on customer needs and expectations. Finally, using SEM The research model was confirmed.},  
Keywords = {Performance evaluation, human resources, factor analysis, Typology},
volume = {8},
Number = {31}, 
pages = {177-205}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-152-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-152-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {BeigiNia, Abdolreza and GhaziZadeh, Mostafa and Hayati, Shoeib},  
title = {Studying and Prioritizing the Effective Organizational Factors on Human Resource Retention (Case Study: Pars Special Economic Energy Zone)}, 
abstract ={The objective of this research has been identifying and prioritizing organizational factors affecting the retention of human resource in Pars Special Economic Energy Zone. The population was 1,000 at the time of study and the sample was estimated 283 using sampling from a finite population (Cochran method). For data&#160; collection, a 59-item researcher made questionnaire was used to identify factors affecting the human resource retention. SPSS software, Kolmogorov-Smirnov test, T-test and ANOVA were used to for data analysis and Friedman method was also utilized to prioritize factors. Results of this study indicated that organizational factors indicators affecting human resource retention in the study organization included payments, social support, job stress, independence, physical conditions of the workplace, management style and supervision, promotion opportunities and organizational justice, respectively.},  
Keywords = {Human Resource Retention, Organizational Factors, Pars Special Economic Energy Zone },
volume = {8},
Number = {31}, 
pages = {207-230}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-153-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-153-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Babashahi, Jabbar and Yazdani, Hamidreza and Tahmasebi, Reza and RajabPour, Ebrahim},  
title = {Designing of Competency model for knowledge workers in RIPI}, 
abstract ={Human capital is the most important competitive advantage in the twenty-first century. In other words, organizations gain a competitive advantage in the marketplace, if they could attract the best knowledge workers, develop and retain them. Competencies paradigm is a new approach to integrate the system to achieve this goal. As well, Research Institute of Petroleum Industry (RIPI) as a knowledge-based organization needs to empower knowledge workers in order to fulfill the objectives of the research and development of the oil industry. This study aimed to identify and design the competency model of knowledge workers in the three categories of researchers, scientific boards and managers. Strategy of this study has been case study and the method of data analysis has been theme technique. The study population groups were included outstanding managers, experts&#8217; researchers, faculty members and consultants. Interviews were conducted with them by using purposive sampling and snowball to the point of saturation. Based on the research findings, competency models were classified into different categories of knowledge workers in the two sets of basic competencies and core competencies. Also, core competencies was divided in three main categories including knowledge workers &#34;individual characteristics&#34;, &#34;knowledge&#34; and &#34;skill&#34;. Each of these main categories was made up of numerous competencies.},  
Keywords = {knowledge worker, competency, competencies of knowledge workers, RIPI},
volume = {8},
Number = {32}, 
pages = {3-24}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-165-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-165-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Kazemi, Aliyeh and SaadatAhmadnia, Fatemeh},  
title = {Selection of strategic alternatives for human resources development in oil industry by using MADM techniques}, 
abstract ={The significance of human resources and their development in the progress of communities and organizations are of utmost importance. Managers should adopt the correct and optimized strategies for development of human resources as the most important factor in providing quality and efficiency in public and business organizations and eventually the major foundation of economical, social and cultural development. In the present study, the strategic alternatives of human resources development in oil industry of Iran have been investigated using several different multi-attribute decision making methods including AHP, SAW, TOPSIS and ELECTRE. For this purpose, eleven strategic alternatives have been specified by experts and prioritized based on the four following factors: time, cost, staff resistance and manager acceptance. Ultimately, Borda&#8217;s method has been used for final ranking and combination of the strategic alternatives. The results showed that stratic choices including right planning, job turnover, increasing salaris and compensates have the higher priority.},  
Keywords = {development of human resources, multi attribute decision making, AHP, SAW, TOPSIS, ELECTRE, Borda’s Method.},
volume = {8},
Number = {32}, 
pages = {25-50}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-166-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-166-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Soltani, Farzaneh and Shahin, Arash and ShaemiBarzoki, Ali},  
title = {Designing a Talent Excellence Model Using Systematic Literature Review and Qualitative Meta Synthesis in Isfahan province Gas Company}, 
abstract ={This study has been considered to design a talent excellence model. Despite the common sense of excellence in the field of human resources and various awards at national level and organizational studies, comprehensive studies in the field of talent excellence have not been carried out. A systematic review and meta-synthesis of qualitative research have been used as the corresponding approach in this study to analyze the results and findings of previous researchers; and with the seven steps of this method, talent excellence model has been examined and classified in the 8 criteria, 30 sub-criteria. For quality control in qualitative meta-synthesis in this study, the GASP and kappa method has been used. Based on a scale of 50 points of CASP, selected articles were evaluated in terms of quality. For assessing the reliability of designed model, the Kappa index was used. Kappa index value was calculated 0.7477 showing that it has been at the valid level of agreement. Finally, in order to confirm the model in the Gas Company of Isfahan Province, we interviewed with the managers and experts of the Gas Company and analyzed the finding by the method of thematic analysis. Also, using the relative coefficient of CVI and CVR, the validity of the logical content of the model was confirmed according to university professors.},  
Keywords = {Excellence, talent, Systematic review, Meta-synthesis},
volume = {8},
Number = {32}, 
pages = {51-84}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-167-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-167-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Nezafati, Navid and GanbarTehrani, Nasim and Davari, Shifr},  
title = {Identfying and ranking the effective factors in knowledge sharing between the counterpart organizations (Case study: Petrochemical Industry)}, 
abstract ={One of the main elements of the knowledge management, is sharing the knowledge inside the organization or with the other organizations which has some advantages such as: access to the competitive knowledge, achieving value and synergy, and not sharing the knowledge in the industries, especially petrochemical industry, in which the active companies require high amount of knowledge for the execution of different projects, will result in the waste of capital, impose of extra costs and the reduction of productivity. So, the goal of this research has been the identification and ranking the effective factors in knowledge sharing in the counterpart organizations. In order to achieve this goal, the library studies were conducted and the factors related to the owner and gainer of the knowledge, the content factors, the cooperation base factors and the technology infrastructures factors, were identified. For explaining the effectiveness of the factors, field studies were conducted in this research by a 25-questions questionnaire. After distributing and gathering the questionnaires, its factor validity and reliability was calculated by SPSS software. At the next step, for explaining the effectiveness of the factors, the single-sample t-test was used and determined that all factors were effective. Then, by using Friedman test, the effective factors were rated, and the cultural and suitable environment of the organization that gains the knowledge was ranked in the first, and the amount of the ambiguity in the knowledge was ranked in the last.},  
Keywords = {knowledge sharing, effective factors on knowledge sharing, petrochemical industry},
volume = {8},
Number = {32}, 
pages = {85-116}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-168-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-168-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {AmirGhodsi, Sirous and Maleki, Ali and BonyadiNaeeni, Ali and Esfandiari, Mohammas Jav},  
title = {Investigating the influence of knowledge management practices on the psychological empowerment of human resources by moderating role of demographic variables in Iranian Central Oil Fields Company (I. C. O. F. C)}, 
abstract ={Psychological empowerment is one of the useful tools for improving the effectiveness of the organization's staff and their quality. Psychological empowerment is affected by numerous factors including knowledge management. The present research investigated the impact of knowledge management practices on the psychological empowerment of human resources by moderating role of demographic variables in Iranian Central Oil Fields Company (I. C. O. F. C). The method in this study insisted applied-developing research method and on the other hand, descriptive-survey. The goal population has been the Company&#8217;s staff of ICOFC including 5480 employees. By Cochran&#8217;s formula 359 employees have randomly been selected. Standardized questionnaires including: Knowledge management of Khaki and psychological empowerment of human resources of have been used. The reliability of questionnaires proved by Cronbach&#8217;s Alpha that for the variables of knowledge management and psychological empowerment were 0.903 and 0.884, respectively. The results showed that knowledge management has an effect on psychological empowerment and its components. The effect&#8217;s intensity of knowledge management on psychological empowerment's components has been 0.788, 0.772, 0.754, 0.742, and 0.703 respectively for sense of trust, sense of efficacy, sence of competency, sense of self-determination, and sense of meaning. The partial correlation test results showed that there is no moderating role for demographic variables in the relationship between knowledge management and the psychological empowerment.},  
Keywords = {knowledge management, psychological empowerment, human resource, structural equation modeling},
volume = {8},
Number = {32}, 
pages = {117-148}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-169-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-169-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Ghorbanizadeh, Vajhollah and KheirAndish, Mehdi and AdnanRad, Azam},  
title = {Factors affecting retention of knowledge workers with the aim of developing work life quality plans at the Institute For International Energy Studies}, 
abstract ={Today, knowledge workers are the most important assets of organizations and managers should make efforts to maintain these employees. Considering the importance of this issue, this paper investigated the maintenance of knowledge workers, using an approach to develop the work life quality. In order to design the conceptual model, some previous studies have been exploited to select the variables. The main question has been whether the improvement of knowledge workers&#8217; work life quality affects their persistence. In order to answer this question, a questionnaire was distributed among a random sample of 66 knowledge workers of the Institute for International Energy Studies , and collected data were analyzed using structural equation modeling. Findings indicated that there is a significantly direct relationship between the development of job factors of work life quality and the persistence of knowledge workers.},  
Keywords = {Knowledge, Knowledge Workers, quality of work life, persistence of Knowledge Workers.},
volume = {8},
Number = {32}, 
pages = {149-176}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-170-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-170-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {SalehiTaleshi, Mohammad Javad and HosseinaliPour, Mojtaba and Arbabi, Hani},  
title = {Identification and evaluation of projects knowledge management infrastructures in project-based organizations of Iranian oil &#38; gas industry in upstream}, 
abstract ={The purpose of this research is identification, evaluation and comparing the reality of &#34;projects knowledge management infrastructures&#34; in some project-based organizations of iranian oil &#38; gas industry in upstream. Applying &#160;quantitative method and survey strategy, projects knowledge management infrastructures in project-based organizations of iranian oil &#38; gas industry in upstream were monitored. Khnowledg management infrastructure questionnaires were completed in 41 upstream organizations in oil &#38; gas industry of Iran. Results showed that among infrastructures, &#34;organizational culture&#34; and &#34;human resource&#34; had the highest score and &#34;structure&#34; had the lowest score. Consulting organizations, general contractor, construction management, design-build contractor, and employer ranked consequently, one to five in terms of suitability of knowledge management structures. From a public and private perspective, private organizations ranked first and then semi-private and public organizations in the next place in terms of knowledge management infrastructure. But none of these two rankings were statistically significant.},  
Keywords = {Project Knowledge Management (PKM), Project-Based Organization (PBO), Oil & Gas Upstream Industries},
volume = {8},
Number = {32}, 
pages = {177-204}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-171-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-171-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

@article{ 
author = {Sadeghi, Mohammad Taghi and MovahediSobhani, Farzad and RajabZadehGhatari, Ali and Shirazi, Hossei},  
title = {Investigating the mediating role of knowledge absorptive capacity on relationship between human resource management policies and organizational performance
(Case Study: Qom Province Gas Company)}, 
abstract ={Today, employees are the main capital of each organization that enables them to improve their competitive performance by utilizing their competent human resources. In this way, Training and development of competent human resources have been related to organizational performance in implementing human resource management policies, effectively, to be a base of creating creativity and innovation in organization. In other ways, in rapid changing markets, knowledge and knowledge absorption capability have a critical role in creating innovation opportunities and competitive advantage of companies. Given the importance of this issue in the gas company the purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of HRM policies on organizational performance and explain the mediating role of knowledge absorptive capacity in this regard. The statistical population of the research is all Official staff of Qom Gas Company that 85 of them participated in this survey based on Cochran's formula. Three questionnaires (HRM policies, organizational performance and knowledge absorptive capacity) were used to collect data. Validity of the questionnaire was verified formally and contently. Reliability was gained by calculating the Cronbach's value of 0.87. The analyzes were performed by using the LISREL software to evaluate the structural equation model. Findings indicate that there is a positive and significant relationship between research variables and knowledge absorption capability in the relationship between HRM and organizational performance has a mediating role.},  
Keywords = {Human Resource Policies- Knowledge Absorption Capability- Organizational Performance},
volume = {8},
Number = {32}, 
pages = {205-232}, 
publisher = {Institute for International Energy Studies},
url = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-172-en.html},  
eprint = {http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-172-en.pdf},  
journal = {Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry},  
issn = {2251-8886}, 
eissn = {2588-4409}, 
year = {2017}  
}

