<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <ArticleSet>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>8</Volume>
			<Issue>29</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Relationship Between Competent Project Managers and Performance of Projects:
Risk Management Competency,
Important but Neglected</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>3</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>31</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hosein</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Safari</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>safarih@ut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ahmad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Jafarnejzad</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ahmadali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>yazdanpanah</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Bayati</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Performance improvement is an area which has been addressed considerably by researchers. However, HR performance Improvement has had less important compared to other resources of organizations. There is no doubt that effective training is the best way to improve and boost human resource performance in workplaces. A manager is competent if he /she demonstrates required competency of his/her job. But, the most important point is that whether having competent project managers can result in desirable performance of their projects or not. The authors in the first step have defined competency, project manager competency, and project performance and maturity. Then, they have evaluated maturity of projects as well as competency of project managers of a state company as a case study (subsidiary of Iran Oil Ministry). Finally, they have determined the most important area of PM competency and also has examined relation between project managers&#8217; competencies and projects&#8217; performance or maturity. The results show that having competent project managers can improve performance of project for which they work and risk management is the most important project management competency.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Competent project managers project performance competency</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-61-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-61-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>8</Volume>
			<Issue>29</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Designing Human Resources Risk Management Model in the Transition from Public to Private Sector Based on Grounded Theory 
(The Case of the Oil and Gas Industry)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>33</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>58</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Rahmatollah</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Gholipor</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>rgholipor@ut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Heidari</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mirali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Seyednaghavi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mehdi</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Narimani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>This study aims to develop a model for risk management of human resources in the transition from public to private for Oil and Gas Company. Qualitative research method based on grounded theory has been used. To collect data, semi-structured interviews have been done and statistical analysis was performed by Strauss and Corbin and paradigmatic model. Sampling technique has been theoretical sampling and was conducted by using targeted technique (judgment) and snowball (chain) .Finally,17 interviews were conducted with former and current senior managers and human resources experts and oil and gas industry brokers who have been involved in the privatization process. Analysis of the data obtained from interviews during the open, axial and selective coding process, for developing human resources risk management model based on grounded theory contained 6 concepts and 28 dimensions.</Abstract>
	<Keywords> The transition period the oil and gas industry human resources risk models enterprise risk management techniques</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-62-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-62-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>8</Volume>
			<Issue>29</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Factors Contributing to the Motivation and Retention of Knowledge Workers in National Iranian Gas Company of Qazvin Province</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>59</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>78</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Asal</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Aghaz</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>a.aghaz@aut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Amirreza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Kooshki</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>&#160;
The purpose of this study is to investigate the factors contributing to the motivation and retention of knowledge workers in National Iranian Gas Company of Qazvin Province (NIGC-Qazvin); as well to study and prioritize the current practices (as is) and ideal values (should be) of these factors from the viewpoint of knowledge workers. The population of this survey consisted of the knowledge workers working at NIGC-Qazvin. Questionnaires were used to collect the required data. Interpersonal interaction, general working condition, personal development, empowerment, task and compensation identified as the most important motivators for knowledge workers working at NIGC-Qazvin. In addition, results indicated significant differences between current practices and ideal values. Finally, some practical guidelines have been proposed for proper use of motivation and retention methods in the case of knowledge workers.</Abstract>
	<Keywords> knowledge workers motivation retention National Iranian Gas Company of Qazvin Province</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-63-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-63-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>8</Volume>
			<Issue>29</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Studying the Role of Emotional Intelligence in the Quality of Decision Making of Managers
(Case: Institute of International Energy Studies</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>79</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>97</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyed Jalil</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Lajevardi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Samieh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Kokabi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>s_kokabi@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Since decision making is one of key tasks of the managers in an organization and it has been the core of the management, the related factors which affects is have always been of interest for the researchers. Thus in this paper, the relationship between emotional intelligence and decision making style (based on rational, intuitive, dependency, momentary and avoiding decision making styles) of the managers of the Institute of International Energy Studies have been studied. For this purpose, among 50 managers of the International Institute for Energy Studies, 44 managers were selected as the statistical sample. Emotional intelligence data were collected by using the Siberia sharing emotional intelligence questionnaire and decision making style data were gathered by Scott and Bruce decision making questionnaire. The content validity of the two questionnaires was reviewed and confirmed by the opinion of the professionals and technical people. For checking of questionnaire, Cronbach's alpha was calculated by SPSS software. The emotional intelligence questionnaire was 0.81 and for decision making style questionnaire 0.76. Pearson correlation test was used to explain the relationship between emotional intelligence and five decision making styles. The results show that there is a meaningful and negative relationship between emotional intelligence and rational and avoiding decision styles of decision making of managers. There is a meaningful and positive correlation between emotional intelligence, and intuitive and momentary decision making style of managers. There was no meaningful relationship between emotional intelligence and dependency decision making style in this study. In this study structural equations model is used because in the present study an independent variable (emotional intelligence) with a variety of dimensions are conceded , and each dimension in sub-hypotheses is take&#160; as an independent variable that its effect on dependent variables (types of decision-making styles) shall be examined.
&#160;</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Emotional intelligence Rational Intuitive Dependent  Emotional Avoiding decision making style</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-64-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-64-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>8</Volume>
			<Issue>29</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Identification and Ranking of Criteria for Distributing Mortgage Loan Among Applicants in the Iranian Petroleum Industry Based On a Mixed Methodology Study</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>99</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>115</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Azadeh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Dabbaghi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>dabbaghi@ut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Providing the oil and gas industry personnel with housing services and opportunities has been one of the most important supporting services offered by the Ministry of petroleum historically. Mortgage lending is one of these housing opportunities. In fact the vast majority of home purchases among the petroleum industry personnel are made with the help of the mortgage loans. Reviewing the administrative background of distributing the mortgage loans among applicants shows that a comprehensive research on the criteria and methodology of selecting candidate personnel has not been accomplished. So, in this study a mixed methodology approach was adopted to identify and rank the important criteria for Distributing Mortgage Loan among Applicants in the Iranian Petroleum Industry. First, the qualitative research interviews were conducted to collect the experts' opinions in order to identify and classify the related criteria. Second, a quantitative methodology was used in order to rank the identified criteria using &#34;Grey Multi Attribute Decision Making&#34; approach.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Grey Multi Attribute Decision Making (GMADM) Mortgage LoanCriteria Identification and Ranking</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-65-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-65-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>8</Volume>
			<Issue>29</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Investigate and Testing the Model of Organizational Agility for the 
Pension Fund of Oil Industry</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>117</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>142</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hoda</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Sanatigar</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>hodasanatgar@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mehrban</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Hadi Peykani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Darioush</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Gholamzadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>&#160;
The purpose of this study has been evaluating and testing organizational agility model for the Iranian pension funds. In fact, the fundamental questions are: what are the dimensions and components of organizational agility for the studied organizations? How the retirement organization could be agile and what are its characteristics? In order to answer these questions, at first by reviewing the literature, studying the research relevant to agility, a framework was provided. Then, the relationship between variables and facts inferred, by using factor analysis and the application of smart PLS, was tested and approved. And finally the proposed model was presented with the following component dimensions: Leadership Agility (with five components of setting agility background, creating collaboration, creativity, self-leadership, creating synergy); agility in service delivery (with four components of speed, competence and quality, flexibility and innovation, accountability); workforce agility (with four components of intelligence and knowledge, flexibility, cooperation, competence); cultural agility (with five components of cooperation and training, flexibility, competence, innovation and creativity, transparency and trust); Agility of organizational factors (with three components of flexible structure, clear and smooth rules and instructions, modern methods and processes), agility in communication and information technology (with two components of high-speed and updated hardware and infrastructure, software and appropriate and timely programs).</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Model of Organizational Agility Pension Funds Oil Industry Factor Analysis</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-66-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-66-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>8</Volume>
			<Issue>29</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Measuring National Iranian Oil Company employees’ job satisfaction based on 
“HAY” Model
Measuring National Iranian Oil Company employees’ job satisfaction based on 
“HAY” Model</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>143</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>166</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mehdi</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ebrahimi Balani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Saeed</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Shahbazmoradi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Zahra</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>karoubi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>zkaroubi@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to measure job satisfaction of&#160;&#160; National Iranian Oil Company subsidiaries and staff units based on HAY model. This study was conducted in 1391. It included permanent and temporary staff of central units and the subsidiaries of NIOC. This study took 5093 members of the group mentioned above (randomly).&#160; The tool for this study was Hay's job satisfaction questionnaire. The Freed Man test was used to compare and rate each of the dimensions of job satisfaction.&#160; For comparison and analysis of job satisfaction of the demographic groups Kruskal -Wallis and Man-Whitney was used. The results showed the rankings of Oil Company subsidiaries and staff units based on their job satisfaction. Also every dimensions of job satisfaction for each company was ranked..</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Job satisfactionHay Model National Iranian Oil Company</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-67-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-67-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>8</Volume>
			<Issue>29</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>investigating the relationship between organizational intelligence and organizational learning among the employees of Iranian Oil Pipelines and Telecommunication Company (IOPTC) – south east region</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>167</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>189</LastPage>
		<Language>OTHER</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Montazeri</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Neda</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Pasandipour</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>neda 192156@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The purpose of this study was investigating the relationship between organizational intelligence and organizational learning among the employees of Iranian Oil Pipelines and Telecommunication Company (IOPTC) &#8211; south east region. Research method was descriptive and statistical population included 350 full time employees of IOPTC, and according to Krejcie and Morgan&#8217;s table a sample with 183 subjects estimated. To collect data, organizational learning questionnaire established by Peter Senge (2005) and organizational intelligence questionnaire established by Albrecht (2002) were used. The collected data analyzed using Pearson's correlation coefficient and multiple structural equations modeling statistical methods in AMOS software. Pearson's correlation test results indicated that there is a direct relationship between willingness to change, common destiny, organizational morale, organizational performance, application of knowledge, unity and agreements, and organizational learning. Also, structural equation modeling results indicated that there is a positive and significant relationship between organizational intelligence and organizational learning. Also, the relationship between common destiny, organizational pressures and unity and agreement with organizational learning confirmed. Among the components of organizational intelligence, willingness to change has a higher correlation with organizational learning, which indicates that the more organizational learning in an organization, the more willingness to change among the employees.</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Organizational Learning Organizational Intelligence Willingness to Change Common Destiny Organizational Morale Organizational Performance Unity And Agreement Application Of Knowledg</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-68-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-68-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
 </ArticleSet>
 
  
  
  
  
 