<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <ArticleSet>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>40</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Designing a Meta Model for Strategic Human Resource Development based on the CIIP Framework by Reviewing Previous Studies</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>3</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>36</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mahdieh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Asadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>asadi.mahdieh@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hamidreza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Yazdani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>hryazdani@ut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Moghadamzadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>amoghadamzadeh@ut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hasan</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Zarei Matin</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>matin@ut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>This study tended to provide a comprehensive and systematic model for SHRD based on the CIIP model. To this mean, a targeted review of the definitions, frameworks and models of (SHRD) was carried out. The research method was qualitative meta-synthesis. For data collection, secondary data sources called previous documents were explored. The method of data analysis was a combination of quantitative and qualitative content analysis. The study population consisted of all the articles on the SURD topic, published in ISI journals, books and foreign dissertations between the years 1989-2017. Based on the CIIP framework, researchers recognized several subcategories for each of the four categories of &#34;context&#34;, &#34;input&#34;, &#34;process&#34;, and &#34;product&#34; mentioned in various foreign studies, repeatedly. As a result, a final integrated model was presented and validated on the basis of these categories and relevant subcategories. This metamodel is applicable to HRD professionals to help them determine which &#34;contexts&#34; and &#34;inputs&#34; are required to consider before a successful implementation of strategic human resource development, to help them determine the required &#8220;processes&#8221; and &#8220;mechanisms&#8221; during implementation, and to help them determine the final products.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Strategic human resource development (SHRD), CIPP Framework, Targeted review, Meta-Synthesis, Quantitative and qualitative Content analysis.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-717-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-717-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>40</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Model of Professional Ethics Development by Identifying its Effective Factors</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>37</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>64</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Naser</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Poursadegh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>dr.naser.poursadegh@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Vahide</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Behvarnaia</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>vahidehbahavarnia@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Rashid</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Zolfaghari Zafarani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to exploration the effective factors in the development of professional ethics and modeling this case. This research is considered exploratory-descriptive based on its goal and functional-developmental, based on the result. It has been done based on a combination method, by using a researcher-made questionnaire and content analysis. At first step, effective factors in the development of professional ethics were identified by content analysis of experts' perspectives. The statistical population consisted of 220people from international affairs staff of National Iranian Oil Company. According to Morgan's table and by using purposeful sampling 136 people was selected. Validity of the questionnaire has been checked by experts and the reliability was confirmed according to the amount of Cronbach's alpha coefficient (0.7). The results showed that cultural, basic, value, organizational and managerial factors are effective in the development of professional ethics and management factors are more effective in developing professional ethics based on path coefficient (0.85) and is consumed as a strong variable.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Professional Ethics, Oil Ministry, National Iranian Oil Company</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-718-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-718-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>40</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Designing Entrepreneurial organizational culture model based on Grounded Theory; A Case in Gas Company of Sistan and Baloochestan Province</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>65</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>96</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyed Aligholi</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Rowshan</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>salirowshan@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Malihe</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Shahriari</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>shahriary.malihe@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The entrepreneurial culture enhances organizational productivity by creating systems of shared values. Since a comprehensive model for the entrepreneurial culture has not been presented yet, and due to the importance of the Gas Company of Sistan and Bluchestan as a service organization, using a qualitative research method with an applied approach an entrepreneurial culture model for this company has been presented. This research, regarding the purpose is applied and regarding the nature is a descriptive survey. In order to design the research model, a semi-structured interview method was executed with 12 experts and the obtained information was analyzed based on the grounded theory. Data was categorized in the five dimensions: organizational enthusiasm, stakeholder alignment, learning and development support, cooperation and cohesiveness, and opportunity driven changes, and 14 components. The content validity of the model was verified by university professors and research group of the organization and the stability model was also measured through the Kappa index.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Entrepreneurial culture, Organizational enthusiasm, Stakeholder alignment, Learning & development support, Cohesiveness and opportunity driven change, Grounded theory</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-719-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-719-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>40</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Human Resource Management Practices and organization Turnover Intentions; A review of the mediating role of Psychological Contract Breach</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>97</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>120</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hassan</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Rangriz</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>rangriz@khu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mehdi</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mohazabi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>mmg.mohazabi@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The main goal of this research has been investigating the impact of human resource management practices on the employee turnover intentions by considering psychological contract breach in the gas company of Rasht. So, it's considered an applied research, in terms of its goals, a descriptive survey, in terms of information gathering and correlational in terms of the interrelation between the research variables. The statistical population in this research included all the administrative staff of Gas Company in Rasht (totally 210 people). Systematic sampling has been used. In order to collect information, standard questionnaires were used. Using AMOS software, statistical analysis revealed that human resource management practices and its dimensions have a negative effect on psychological contract breach. Also, the impact of human resource management practices and its dimensions on employees' turnover intentions were also negative. The critical value of the indirect effect of human resource management practices and the employees' turnover intentions through the mediating variable of the psychological contract breach (2.10) showed that psychological contract breach plays a mediating role between mentioned two variables.</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Human Resource Management Practices, Psychological Contract Breach, Organization Turnover Intentions, Gas Company of Rasht City</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-720-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-720-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>40</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Designing a model of antecedents and consequences of thriving at work in employees of National Iranian Drilling Company‎</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>121</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>146</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyed Esmaeil</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Hashemi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>esmaeil2140@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Nasim</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Khajepour</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>khajepour.nasim@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Kiumars</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Beshlideh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>K.beshlideh@scu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The aim of this study was designing a model of some antecedents and consequences of thriving at work for the employees of National Iranian Drilling Company(NIDC). In terms of objective, the research method was applied, in terms of data collection&#160;has been consumed a survey&#160;and in terms of data analysis was a descriptive study. Among employees of NIDC, 211 employees participated in the study. Data were analyzed through structural equation modeling (SEM) and using SPSS-21 and AMOS-21 software. Fit indices showed that the proposed model was fitted to the data. The other findings with confidence interval of %95 indicated that variables including: trust/respect climate with coefficient of .168, discretionary decision making with coefficient of .397, and performance feedback with coefficient of .193 were positively correlated with self-determination. In addition, discretionary decisions making with coefficient of .333, and performance feedback with coefficient of .215 had a positive correlation with thriving at work. More analyses revealed that thriving at work was correlated with both job performance, with coefficient of .302 and organizational citizenship behaviors, with coefficient of .239. Mediation analyses indicated that trust/respect climate, discretionary decision making, and performance feedback had an indirect effect on job performance and organizational citizenship behaviors through self-determination and thriving at work.</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Climate of trust/respect, Discretionary decision-making, Performance feedback, Thriving at work, Job performance</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-721-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-721-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>40</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Identification and prioritizing Succession Management Barriers in Shiraz Petrochemical Company by mixed method</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>147</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>166</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Nasr</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Alireza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ghasemizad</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Ghasemizad@kau.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to identify and prioritize the barriers of succession management in Shiraz Petrochemical Company. The mixed method has been. In qualitative stage, by means of thematic analysis and semi-structured interviewing, the obstacles of succession management were explored. The potential participants in this stage were 30 people including experts in the Shiraz Petrochemical Company who were selected through a purposeful sampling approach and based on the theoretical saturation rule. The results of the content analysis from interviews showed that barriers to succession management were included: lack of executive&#8217;s support, lack of organizational policies, organizational rapid changes, redundant administrative procedures, short term vision and lack of clarity and transparency. To validate acquiring themes qualitative validation criteria, reliability and confirmatory factor analysis were used. In the quantitative part, a descriptive survey method was used and the population consisted of all the employees from which 183 people were selected randomly. A researcher-made questionnaire based on qualitative component analysis has been used in this section. Content validity was used to determine the validity of the questionnaire. And, Cronbach's alpha method was used to determine the reliability of the questionnaire. Hierarchical analysis showed that lack of executive&#8217;s support had the highest mean and the problem of felony, had the lowest average among barriers of succession management.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>succession management, Barriers, Petrochemical Company, mixed method </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-722-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-722-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>40</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Conceptual Model of Knowledge Management from the Perspective of Human Resources in Educational-Research Institutions</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>167</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>186</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mojtaba</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Rajabbeigi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>rajabbaigy@iies.net</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Parvaneh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Gelard</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyed Ali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Abtahinezhad</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>This paper focuses on designing a conceptual model of knowledge management from the point of view of human resources employed in educational-research institutes. The research method was descriptive-survey study and the statistical population of this study consisted of 56 experts and managers of an educational research institute. They were asked by simple random sampling method through a researcher-made questionnaire. The research findings indicate that the five factors of explicit and implicit knowledge, culture of sharing Knowledge, communication and information technology infrastructure, employee training and organizational structure are affected by organizational knowledge management process. Concurrent Multivariate Regression showed that among the five factors affecting knowledge management, two factors with explicit knowledge and knowledge sharing culture are predictors of organizational knowledge management at the institute.</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Tacit Knowledge- Explicit Knowledge- Knowledge Management– Knowledge Contribution</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-723-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-723-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>40</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Relationship between Organizational Structure and Human Resource Management Processes and Performance; Case of the Gas Company in Fars Province</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>187</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>206</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohsen</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Jajarmi Zadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>m.jajarmizadeh@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Azam</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Tadayon</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>a.tadayon18762@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to investigate the relation between the organizational structure with the human resource management and the performance. The method used in this research has been an applied research and a descriptive-survey. The statistical population consisted of the employees of the gas company in Fars province and a sample of 270 randomly selected employees responded to standard questionnaires related to organizational structure, the human resource management and the performance. Data has been analyzed through structural equation modeling using path analysis applying SPSS and LISREL software. The findings showed that there is a direct relation between the human resource management activities and the organizational structure dimensions. In addition, the human resource management and the organizational structure have a direct effect on the organization's performance.</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Management, Human Resources, Organizational Structure, Performance</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-724-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-724-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName>Institute for International Energy Studies</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>2251-8886</PISSN>
			<EISSN>2588-4409</EISSN>
			<Volume>10</Volume>
			<Issue>40</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>9</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Study of the relationship between leadership styles and organizational justice with staff trust</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>207</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>228</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Alireza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mehrabi Taleghani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>mehrabialireza34@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohsen</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Mohammadian</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>mo.dian@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The objective of this research was to study the relationship between leadership styles and organizational justice and employees&#8217; confidence. It is consumed an applied research in terms of method and it is categorized as a descriptive-survey. The statistical population was the employees of the, Manufacturing Support and procurement Management Office of the National Iranian Oil Company which among them &#160;244 persons were selected as sample size using stochastic sampling method and the Morgan&#8217;s formula. The research information was gathered by standard questionnaires of leadership styles, organizational justice and employees&#8217; confidence. Research data was analyzed using descriptive and inferential statistical methods and SPSS software. This research revealed that there is a significant relationship between leadership styles (transformational and transactional), organizational justice (distributive and procedural) and employees&#8217; confidence in the case which has been studied. Also, the results obtained from Friedman's test showed that procedural justice with a mean of 4.69 in the first rank and distributive justice with 4.06 in the second rank and the transformational leadership variable with an average of 3.76 and exchange leadership with rank of 3.29 had a different significance.</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Leadership styles, Transformational leadership, Transactional leadership, Organizational justice, Distributive justice, Procedural justice, Employees’ confidence </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-725-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://iieshrm.ir/article-1-725-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
 </ArticleSet>
 
  
  
  
  
 