<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>Human Resource Management in Oil Industry</title>
<title_fa>مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت</title_fa>
<short_title>Human Resource Management in The Oil Industry</short_title>
<subject>Literature &amp; Humanities</subject>
<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>2251-8886</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online>2588-4409</journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii></journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi></journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid></journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>374</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>6</volume>
<number>23</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>other</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>شناسایی شایستگی های استراتژیک مدیران ارشد صنعت پتروشیمی</title_fa>
	<title>Identifying Strategic Competencies of Top Managers in Petrochemical Industry</title>
	<subject_fa>مديريت</subject_fa>
	<subject>Management</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;با توجه به سیاستهای کلان کشور در خصوص کاهش وابستگی ها به فروش نفت خام به منظور توسعه هرچه بیشتر صنعت پتروشیمی و با عنایت به ویژگیهای خاص این صنعت از جمله تکنولوژی- محور بودن، مواجهه با تغییرات سریع و رقابت شدید در منطقه، ضروری است که شرکتهای فعال در صنعت پتروشیمی با هوشمندی و چابکی بیشتر برنامه ریزی کرده و گام های پیش رو را محکم تر و هدفمند بردارند. اما امروزه در حوزه مدیریت اعتقاد برا ین است که شایستگی های مدیریت عالی سازمان نقش مهمی در موفقیت شرکتها می تواند داشته باشد. هدف از این پژوهش شناسایی شایستگی های مدیران ارشد صنعت پتروشیمی است که در هر چه بهتر انجام دادن فرآیند مدیریت استراتژیک کمک نموده و موجب عملکرد بهتر و تحقق اهداف استراتژیک سازمان آنها می شود.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;در این&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;پژوهش پس از بررسی مطالعات پیشین، چارچوب اولیه ای جهت شناسایی شایستگی های مدیریتی استخراج شد. پس از آن سعی &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;گردید&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt; تا با انجام مصاحبه های عمیق با مدیران عامل شرکتهای برتر صنعت پتروشیمی که طی 4 سال متوالی بر اساس فرآیند جایزه تعالی صنعت پتروشیمی و گزارشات شرکتهای برتر ایرانی در &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:times new roman,serif;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;imi-100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt; انتخاب شده بودند، شایستگی های لازم &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10pt;&quot;&gt;شناسایی&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10pt;&quot;&gt; و با استفاده از&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10pt;&quot;&gt; تحلیل مضمون&amp;nbsp; تحلیل گردیدند.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:b nazanin;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:10.0pt;&quot;&gt;به منظور اعتبار یابی یافته های حاصل از مصاحبه ها نتایح بصورت پرسشنامه تدوین و در بین خبرگان دانشگاه و صنعت پتروشیمی توزیع گردید ودر نهایت شایستگی های شناسایی شده در پنج بعددانش، مهارت، تجربه،نگرش وویژگیهای فردی در 10 مولفه اصلی دانش راهبردی ،دانش تخصصی، دانش عمومی،مهارت های ادراکی،مهارت های انسانی و ارتباطی،مهارت های اجرایی،ویژگی های اخلاقی،ویژگی های شخصیتی ،تجربه و نگرش وهمچنین، 54 مولفه فرعی دسته بندی شدند&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Based on the macroeconomic policies of the country regarding eliminating reliance on the sale of crude oil and in order to further develop the petrochemical industry and considering the special features of this industry including its technology based nature, facing fast changes and strong competition in the region, it is necessary for the active petrochemical companies to make plans with more intelligence and speed and take their future steps more strongly and objectively. However, today it is believed in the management field, that the competencies of the organization&amp;rsquo;s top management can play an important role in the success of the companies.&lt;br&gt;
This research aims to recognize the competencies of senior managers in petrochemical industry, which helps improving process of strategic management and results in better performance as well as realization of the organization&amp;rsquo;s strategic objectives.&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In this research, having reviewed the studies already, a preliminary framework was developed to recognize the management competencies. In the next step, through conducting in-depth interviews with managing directors of the petrochemical companies which has been selected for 4 consequent years as superior companies, based on the&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;ldquo;Excellence Award&amp;rdquo; process in petrochemical industry and the reports on Iranian superior companies, selected in imi-100, it was tried to identify the competencies required&amp;nbsp; and Thematic Analysis technique has been used for initial analysis of these competencies&lt;br&gt;
In order to examine the reliability of the interviews findings, the results were edited and distributed in the form of questionnaires among the university and petrochemical industry elites. The identified competencies in five dimensions of knowledge, skills, experience, attitude and personal characteristics were finally categorized in 10 principal parameters including strategic knowledge, professional knowledge, general knowledge, conceptual skills, communication and human skills, executive skills, moral features, personality&amp;nbsp; features, experience and attitude and also 54 subsidiary parameters.&amp;nbsp;&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شایستگی‌ , شایستگی های استراتژیک , مدیران ارشد , صنعت پتروشیمی </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Competency- Strategic competencies- senior managers- petrochemical industry</keyword>
	<start_page>217</start_page>
	<end_page>242</end_page>
	<web_url>http://iieshrm.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-311-10&amp;slc_lang=other&amp;sid=1</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Behroz </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Dorri </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>بهروز</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>دری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001954</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001954</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Masoumeh </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Habibi </last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>معصومه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حبیبی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001955</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001955</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>موسسه مطالعات بین المللی انرژی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Maryam </first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Bahrami nasab</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مریم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بهرامی نسب</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>M_MAHYA@YAHOO.COM</email>
	<code>10031947532846001956</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001956</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
