<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>50</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تبیین مبانی نمود فرهنگ در معماری بومی ایران و ارتباط آن با ایجاد حس تعلق به مکان</title_fa>
	<title>Explanation of the basics of culture in Iranian native architecture and its relation with the creation of a sense of belonging to place </title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;معماری امروز با توجه به تحولات و تغییرات قرن حاضر، ریشه در گذشته خود ندارد. در تعامل با فرهنگ بومی نبوده و دچار فاصله زیادی با آن گشته است؛ لذا از هیجانات تعلق&amp;shy;زای ساکنین به فضاها کاسته شده و حس تعلق به عنوان عاملی برای تبدیل فضاها به مکان&amp;shy;هایی با خصوصیات حسی و رفتاری ویژه برای افراد کمرنگ گردیده است. علیرغم معماری گذشته که بخشی از فرهنگ در آن نهفته و فرم معماری به عنوان بستری برای انتقال پیام فرهنگی بود. هدف از این پژوهش دستیابی به چیستی روش های بومی سازی ناشی از فرهنگ در معماری گذشته و چگونگی تاثیر آنها در عامل حس تعلق به مکان در معماری امروز می باشد. تحقیق حاضر از حیث ماهیت کیفی بوده و روش آن به صورت توصیفی- تحلیلی می باشد و از منابع کتابخانه ای و اطلاعات میدانی به منظور جمع آوری اطلاعات بهره گرفته شده است. نتایج حاصل از این پژوهش نشان می &amp;shy;دهد مولفه های بومی سازی فرهنگ در معماری گذشته ایران عبارتند از: ارتباط چهارگانه با خود، دیگران، طبیعت و خداوند، محرمیت، امنیت، درونگرایی، مرکزیت، انعکاس، هندسه، سلسله مراتب، شفافیت، تداوم و سیر از ظاهر به باطن. پس از تمرکز بر مفهوم حس تعلق به مکان و دسته بندی و تعریف عوامل محیطی، فردی و معنایی تاثیر گذار بر آن پژوهشگر ریشه های مشترک مولفه های بومی سازی فرهنگ را در عوامل فوق می یابد و مدل نظری حاصل از آن تدوین می گردد؛ که با به کارگیری آن ها می توان در ارتقای حس تعلق به مکان فضاهای امروزی موثر واقع شد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Today's architecture has no roots in its past, given the changes and changes of the present century. In the interaction with local culture, it has been subject to a considerable distance; hence, the emotion of residents to spaces has decreased and the sense of belonging as a factor for the transformation of spaces to spaces with specific sensory and behavioral properties has been eroded. In spite of past architecture, this is part of the culture embedded in it and the architecture form as a platform for conveying cultural message. The aim of this study is to find the methods of culture in past architecture and how they affect the sensing of belonging to the location in today s architecture. The present study is qualitative in nature and its method is descriptive - analytic and its method is derived from library sources and field information in order to collect information. the results of this study show that the elements of localization of culture in past architecture are: with self, others, nature and god,&amp;nbsp; security, self - centrality, reflection, geometry, hierarchy, transparency, continuity, continuity and after focusing on the concept of belonging to location and classification and definition of environmental, individual and semantic factors affect the determinants of culture in the aforementioned factors and the theoretical model is formulated; utilizing them can be effective in enhancing the sense of belonging to the location of modern spaces.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>فرهنگ, فرهنگ بومی, معماری بومی, حس تعلق  </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>culture, indigenous culture, indigenous architecture, sense of belonging </keyword>
	<start_page>33</start_page>
	<end_page>46</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-70&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>غلامرضا </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>علی‌محمدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008478</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008478</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رکسانا </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عبدالهی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008479</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008479</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
