<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2019</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>53</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>امکان سنجی تولید انرژی پاک بیوگاز از فضولات حیوانی در روستاهای ایران از نظر کارشناسان دامداری</title_fa>
	<title>Feasibility study for the production of bio gas as a clean energy from animal waste in Iran's villages for livestock experts</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:42.55pt;&quot;&gt;محدودیت منابع فسیلی و رشد سریع مصرف انرژی در جهان از جمله عواملی است که پژوهشگران را برای دستیابی به منابع جدید و قابل تجدید انرژی ترغیب می کند. بیوگاز یکی از منابع تجدیدپذیر است که می تواند در روستاها برای دامداران بسیار مفید و کاربردی باشد هدف این مطالعه امکان سنجی تولید انرژی پاک بیوگاز از فضولات حیوانی در روستاهای ایران از نظر کارشناسان دامداری می باشد&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; در اجرای این پژوهش از فن پیمایش استفاده شده است. جامعه آماری کارشناسان دامداری چهار استان ایران بودند (337 نفر)، که نمونه آن براساس جدول مورگان و با نمونه گیری تصادفی طبقه ای 181 نفر شد. براساس یافته ها، هشت معیار برای امکان سنجی تولید بیوگاز از فضولات حیوانی استخراج گردید که شامل اجتماعی ـ فرهنگی، اقتصادی، فنی و مهارتی، زیست محیطی، اقلیمی، زیرساختی، اطلاع رسانی و ترویج و آموزش بودند. همچنین، اهمیت هر یک از معیارها از نظر کارشناسان در استان ها مشخص گردید که در استان فارس معیار اجتماعی ـ فرهنگی، در استان خراسان رضوی معیار زیرساختی ، در استان گلستان، اقتصادی و در استان کرمانشاه معیارهای زیرساختی و اقلیمی از اهمیت بیشتری برخوردار بودند. پیشنهاد میگردد برای امکان پذیری اجرای بیوگاز در ایران گروهها و تشکل دامداران تشکیل گردد،&amp;nbsp; ارائه تسهیلات و تأمین منابع مالی انجام شود. مراکزی جهت پشتیبانی و تربیت متخصصین ماهر در زمینه راه اندازی، نگهداری و تعمیر دستگاه بیوگاز ایجاد گردد. همچنین با توجه به اهمیت بیوگاز بعنوان یک انرژی پاک، توصیه می شود تحقیقات آینده بر ابعاد اجتماعی مؤثر بر اجرای بیوگاز تمرکز بیشتری داشته باشند. &amp;nbsp;شرایط سازگاری و توسعه بیوگاز در مناطق مختلف بررسی شود و ارزیابی اثرات اجتماعی اجرای بیوگاز نیز مانند همه طرحهای توسعه ای انجام گردد.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:-36.0pt;&quot;&gt;The limitation of fossil resources and the rapid growth of energy consumption in the world are among the factors that encourage researchers to access new and renewable energy sources. Biogas is one of the most renewable resources that can be used in farms for ranchers. The purpose of this study is to determine the feasibility of producing clean energy from biogas from animal waste in Iranian villages for livestock experts. Fingerprinting has been used in this research. The statistical population of the livestock experts was four provinces of Iran (337 people), who&amp;rsquo;s sample was 181 according to Morgan table and stratified random sampling. Based on the findings, eight criteria for the feasibility of biogas production were extracted from animal waste, including socio-cultural, economic, technical, skill, environmental, climatic, infrastructure, information, promotion and education. Also, the significance of each criterion in experts in the provinces revealed that in the province of Fars socio-cultural criteria, in Khorasan Razavi province, infrastructure indicators, in Golestan province, economic and in Kermanshah province, the criteria of infrastructure and climate were more important. It is recommended that groups and organizations of livestock breeders be formed in Iran to make biogas available, provide facilities and provide financial resources. Centers to support and train skilled specialists in the field of installation, maintenance and repair of the biogas plant. Also, given the importance of biogas as a clean energy, it is recommended that future research be focused on the social dimension affecting the implementation of biogas. The conditions for the adaptation and development of biogas in different regions should be examined and the assessment of the social impacts of the implementation of biogas, like all development projects, should be carried out.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa></keyword_fa>
	<keyword></keyword>
	<start_page>291</start_page>
	<end_page>304</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-2456-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>نسیم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ایزدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846009252</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846009252</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حشمت الله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سعدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846009253</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846009253</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
