
	<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"	xmlns:cr_unixml="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2020-07-22T10:24:45+04:30</responseDate>
	<request metadataPrefix="cr_unixml" verb="ListRecords" set="10.1002">http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?mag_id=13&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</request>
	<ListRecords>
		
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-473</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Organizational Structure Design of Medium-Sized Municipalities in Iran Performance</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Farrokh</given_name>
					<surname>Qoochani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Aziz</given_name>
					<surname>Behzadi</surname>
					<email>behzadi.a@chmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Nowadays communications, decision-making, reporting manner and hierarchy are controlled by organizational structure getting an inside into such structure means getting an insight over the whole organization. It serves as a platform for operation of plans and strategies and also determines links among personnel or executive body of the organization. In line with developments in other elements, organizations must keep thinking of developing their organizational structures. As public, non-governmental entities, municipalities pursue the goal of urban welfare and paving the way for establishment of a mechanism that helps cities achieve sustainable development and growth. These entities constantly need a structure that is tailored to their missions, goals, duties and central activities.  Having a review on the concept of ‘structure’ and ‘thematic dimensions’ in former structure of municipalities and having introduced medium-sized municipalities as developmental entities, this paper conducts a comparative study on executive body of municipalities in order to gain a picture of central activities that municipalities are involved. In sum, this research finds that major characteristics of this structure include incorporation of new parts through vertical and horizontal differentiations, change of view to municipalities as organizations with social responsibilities, incorporation of new parts with the intention to remove parallel tasks as well as reduced expending and financial independence of municipalities.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>municipality</keyword>
	<keyword> structure</keyword>
	<keyword> organization</keyword>
	<keyword> horizontal differentiation</keyword>
	<keyword> vertical differentiation </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>7</first_page>
								  <last_page>14</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-474</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Cultural changes in urban management and nongovernmental organizations (NGOs)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Mohammad Taqi</given_name>
					<surname>Haji Amoo Assar</surname>
					<email>taghiasar@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Ali</given_name>
					<surname>Moradi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Problem and objective: Analysis of cultural challenges and presenting appropriate strategies for coping therewith, as much as is necessary will be a hard work and access thereto is difficult. Investigation of cultural changes and its relationship with NGOs and presenting an appropriate strategy for coping therewith is the topic of this study. Nowadays, the greatest threat against us is cultural threat and within this period of time, main questions that may solve this problem, is that why the topic of NGOs and its relationship with culture is important? And why culture in our country is taken into consideration sensitively? And what is the philosophy of propounding such topics in the conferences? Methodology: this study was applied based on analytical-descriptive method. In this study, content analysis was used that in fact is a method therein the content of study object is described and perceived exactly and deeply. The objective of this study is recognizing the text or written work’s characteristics realistically and obtaining conclusions thereof. Results: In this paper, the grounds of cultural changes and relationship between cultural changes and NGOs were analyzed. In continue, vulnerability of cultures was discussed and analyzed. 
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Culture</keyword>
	<keyword> NGOs</keyword>
	<keyword> Cultural Security</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>15</first_page>
								  <last_page>28</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-475</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Privacy of House in Islamic Culture with Emphasis on Iranian Citizens Perception</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Behrooz</given_name>
					<surname>Mansoori</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Seyyed Mohammad Reza</given_name>
					<surname>Nasir Salami</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Ali Akbar</given_name>
					<surname>Saremi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Shaahin</given_name>
					<surname>Ilka</surname>
					<email>shahinilka@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The house is a microcosm of culture and civilization because the primary elements of society, individuals organized along with the family lines, are born, raised and educated in them. The strength of the institutions of the family and house denotes the strength of a society and the verve of its cultural and civilizational agenda. Similarly, frailties in the institutions of the family and house denote frailties in a society and in its cultural and civilizational agenda. The house dominion is where people rise and fall, that is to say, where people either succeed or fail in managing and conducting the most crucial aspects of their lives. Housing is where the epicenter of the rise and fall of cultures and civilizations lies. Thus, some of the chief causes of the decline of Islamic culture and civilization, if properly examined, could be related, one way or another, to the complex subject of housing and its own decline and its causes. Likewise, some of the main cures and catalysts for the revival of Islamic culture and civilization could be found right in the subject of reviving genuine Islamic housing. Indeed, Islamizing housing today could be a turning point, as well as an engine of growth, insofar as a total recovery and revival of Muslim cultural and civilizational consciousness and involvement at a world stage is concerned. According to Islamic teachings, human being moves towards perfection if conditions conducive to His/her calmness are realized at home. According to this view, 'house' represents 'family' and a Muslim's home is regarded as Sacred and private. There is an inherent tendency in human being towards privacy, the most important of which is realized at home. Therefore, if privacy is trespassed at home, it may no longer serve as a home. As traditional houses have assumed a more architectural manifestation due to religious principles, identifying these principles and converting them into housing rules and regulations are among the major concerns of urban planners. In this paper also we are going to speak about Islamic idea of privacy of housing, has tried to pay attention to Modern Architecture ideas which is the dominant style in Muslims land.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Islamic architecture</keyword>
	<keyword> house and family: privacy</keyword>
	<keyword> Iranian house.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>29</first_page>
								  <last_page>44</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-475-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-476</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Investigation of Urban Renewal and Regeneration Management Policy Changes in City of Tehran (Between 1990-2014)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Haniyeh</given_name>
					<surname>Hoodsony</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mojtaba</given_name>
					<surname>Rafieian</surname>
					<email>rafiei_m@modares.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Mohammadreza</given_name>
					<surname>Poor Jafar</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Urban regeneration and renewal is one of the urban development subjects that have undergone substantial changes in last decades in its approaches and also management process. Despite these global changes, policy making in this field of urban development have been delayed in Iran. In the last three decades, the spread of distressed urban areas in Tehran and their vulnerability against earthquake caused them to be among urban management’s superior priorities. From 1990s, simultaneously with changes caused by socio-economic changes occurred after war and start of “Construction Era” in political contexts, the first urban renewal project was implemented in form of a highway construction plan by municipality with a concentrated and top-down approach. After that urban renewal policies have undergone great changes. The role of actors and power relations among them had also changes in this process. In this article, reviewing urban policy documents of these periods, we also reviewed distinctive experiences of each period in this 25-year duration (from 1990 to 2014) with content analysis and documentary studies and also case study approach. We also used qualitative methods for the analysis, particularly deep interview with experts and stakeholders of each project, analyzing distinctive indicators of studied cases, and finally revealed power relations among stakeholders of each project. These studies show that four periods are recognizable in this period in which changes in urban regeneration and renewal policy, in actors of each period and their role and power relations are clear and explain new paradigms created in urban regeneration and renewal management in Tehran. 
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Urban Regeneration</keyword>
	<keyword> Urban Renewal</keyword>
	<keyword> Urban Policy</keyword>
	<keyword> Local Organization</keyword>
	<keyword> Power of Influence</keyword>
	<keyword> Tehran. </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>45</first_page>
								  <last_page>60</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-477</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>The role of regionalism in improvement of Mashhad management with an emphasis on the efficiency of Mashhad municipality districts</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Mohammad Rahim</given_name>
					<surname>Rahnama</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Vahid</given_name>
					<surname>Poor Toroqi</surname>
					<email>vahid.yo1364@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Ali</given_name>
					<surname>Rezaii Moqoddam</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Development of urbanization and rise of cities and urbanism during the last decade have added new dimensions to urban issues and have led to increasing importance of monitoring, conduction of urban development and organization of towns and their surrounding regions. In the meantime, the procedures of favorable life management play the most important role in improvement of human habitats and sustainable urban development, since the regulatory factors in urban plans and procedures of dealing with urban problems stem from the efficiency of urban management. One of the new ways of management is decentralized urban management which contributes to realization of desired goals of urban administration through division of tasks and responsibilities. Furthermore, unified and integrated management of big cities like Mashhad is not possible and requires its division into small units. Provision of better and more efficient services to the citizens requires urban divisions at different levels, so that these services may be presented and managed more evenly in all parts of the city, in accordance with their hierarchy.  Meanwhile, the regionalism policy that has been implemented in Mashhad Municipality since 1386 has been an attempt to achieve this end by dividing the 13 municipality districts into 42 regions. This study is an attempt to evaluate the success of this policy and the extent of success in execution of the decentralized management. For this purpose, the efficiency and performance of different regions in Mashhad was evaluated using the DEA method and constant returns of scale and variable returns of scale methods. The results of this study suggest that so far, regionalism has failed to achieve decentralized management completely, and some Mashahd municipality districts could not fall within the efficiency frontiers, while the policy has led to increasing complexity (geographic and vertical) in the structural dimensions of the municipality. 
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>regionalism</keyword>
	<keyword> urban management</keyword>
	<keyword> DEA model</keyword>
	<keyword> efficiency</keyword>
	<keyword> DEAFRONTER software</keyword>
	<keyword> Mashhad</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>61</first_page>
								  <last_page>74</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-478</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Solution to Material Durability and Energy Consuming Optimization Based on New Technology in Urban Management System</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>S.B.</given_name>
					<surname>Ahmadi</surname>
					<email>sbahmadi@modares.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>R</given_name>
					<surname>Falsafi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>R</given_name>
					<surname>Morad Poor</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
Energy consumption share in construction part and dependent industries is about 40 percent of total energy consuming in Iran which is significant compared to other industries such as transportation, agriculture and therefore is of important. As energy consumption reduction and material durability improvement leads to cost reduction from one hand and environment pollution reduction on the other hand, is considered as one of the most substantial concerns in the field of construction. Energy consuming reduction needs energy consuming pattern modification besides new technology utilization for efficiency improvement of energy consumers and also lifetime enhancement of urban furniture and elements. The article results contributes to right management of energy consuming in urban environment by a brief look to solar energy utilization as a supplier and some new technologies as energy consumption reducers and introduces the best methods to manage their usage.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>energy management</keyword>
	<keyword> consumption optimization</keyword>
	<keyword> solar energy</keyword>
	<keyword> new technology</keyword>
	<keyword> Nano technology</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>75</first_page>
								  <last_page>84</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-479</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Evaluation of Urban Green Space on Economic Price in Neighborhoods, Region 1, Tehran</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Reza</given_name>
					<surname>Keshavarz Nourooz Poor</surname>
					<email>rezakeshavaez6@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
Urban green space is one of the important solicitude for urban planners and designers due to their effects on quality of life. This research used HPM model to estimate economic value of urban green space, in a case study of trees in Velenjak residential place, Tehran Metropolitan Area in Iran. View determined the  spread  tree  on  the  public spaces and neighbourhoods improve residential land use  value  about  1.5 MRials  rsulting  a  positive  neighbourhood  externality  of  studied green spaces and trees. Developed model in this study is capable to popularization on the same region, in order to qualitative value estimation of open spaces. 

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>urban spaces</keyword>
	<keyword> HPM model</keyword>
	<keyword> tree</keyword>
	<keyword> economic value</keyword>
	<keyword> Tehran.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>85</first_page>
								  <last_page>94</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-480</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Sustainable Disaster Risk (SDR) Reduction for Developing Countries with emphasis on land system Resilience (LSR) on future study approach Case Study: Rural and Urban Settlement</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Abolfazl</given_name>
					<surname>Moqimi</surname>
					<email>moghimi.ab@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
With increasing frequency, the developing countries and the people living there are being affected by disasters. More and more often, development efforts are being destroyed. The reason for this trend is their growing vulnerability, which in turn is the result of economic and social development processes, such as the expansion of settlements and agricultural land in risk areas. The economic and social consequences of these disasters for the people in our partner countries last for years. To break and, if possible, reverse this trend, international organizations, governments and NGOs in the developing countries are increasingly upgrading the priority of disaster risk management for policy, and taking concrete preventive measures to reduce the risk to the population. This paper examined the concept of disaster and its management in the light of sustainable development with particular reference to Iran. It enumerated the different human and natural phenomena that could be characterized as disasters. It was discovered that, while hazard and/ or disasters possess anthropogenic origins, their consequences are felt on both human and the physical environments. In all cases, the human tolls have been significant. The paper highlighted the important elements of a typical Disaster Management Information System in Iran. After presenting a typology of disasters in Iran, the paper, advocated for a workable disaster management information system.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Disaster Management</keyword>
	<keyword> Risk</keyword>
	<keyword> Hazards</keyword>
	<keyword> Vulnerability.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>95</first_page>
								  <last_page>114</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-310</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Assessment and Location of Rural Waste Management Systems (Case Study: Ilam Province)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>alireza</given_name>
					<surname>D.astane</surname>
					<email>astaneali@ut.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>saeed</given_name>
					<surname>Bazgeer</surname>
					<email>sbazgeer@ut.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The growing trend of rural waste generated in the country requires careful considerations about rural waste management and emphasizes its role in preserving the environment. Due to the large number of villages and small amount of the rural waste, collecting rural waste needs spatial planning so that it could cover a vaster area through economic and shared use of equipments. The main goal of the present study is to examine potential assessment and location of rural waste management system in Ilam province. Methodology of the research is a combination of developmental and measurement methods whose dominant approach are the measurement factors. Statistical population of the current study included all the residential villages, which were 627, overall, and all of them were examined throughout this research. The required information was accumulated through a questionnaire. Village chiefs (head of the rural administrations: 398 people) and informed people (in villages without an administration: 229 people) and members of the village council (390people) were the ones who filled out the questionnaires. Additionally, in order to define the appropriate standards of collecting village waste, the required data was collected from among 65 directors of the village ::::union::::s, municipality experts, rural administrations’ members, and the City Hall of Ilam province. To determine the satisfaction level of villagers with the quality of services provided by waste management system of the village, a single-sample Chi Square Test was prepared. Besides, in this study, for assessing scenarios for covering the services of waste management system of the village, network analysis in Arc GIS software has been used as well. Results of the research indicate that although 26 villages in this province did have the equipments for carrying the waste, these services are only used by villages that directly own the so-called equipments, and other villages of the province are deprived of that. Besides, the results show that if the present equipments are properly allocated and used, relevant services can be provided for all the villages of the province.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Waste Management</keyword>
	<keyword> Rural</keyword>
	<keyword> Network Analysis</keyword>
	<keyword> Ilam Province</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>115</first_page>
								  <last_page>126</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-310-en.doc</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-481</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Intrinsic appraisal of quality in the field of urban development in region Islamic Azad Universities</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Seyyed Ahmad</given_name>
					<surname>Hashemi</surname>
					<email>seyed_hashemi@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
Present research investigates intrinsic quality in region1 Islamic Azad Universities and presents a pattern to improve quality of universities. In present research, we appraise professors, and students, ideas about educational, administrative-financial, student, research and cultural factors. Present research is survey- descriptive. Its statistical society consists of 78440 students of undergraduate study fields in region1 Islamic Azad Universities in 2011-2012. The sample equals 382 students. We selected them based on Cochran formula and by using cluster random sampling. The data collected by one questionnaire that is made by the researcher based on liker’s spectrum. Questionnaire used after determination of their validity and stability (students 0.84) by the specialists. The analysis of data carried out using descriptive statistics (frequency, the percent of frequency, mean, skew, median, and standard deviation), inferential statistics (T-test and one-side variance analysis in significant level 0.05) and SPSS software. The results of research show that: In students, opinion, the efficacy of student, research programs is lower than average, the efficacy of educational programs is average and the efficacy of cultural and administrative –financial programs is higher than average.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Intrinsic appraisal</keyword>
	<keyword> students</keyword>
	<keyword> region1 Islamic Azad Universities</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>127</first_page>
								  <last_page>132</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-482</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Measuring Iran\'s Industrial Clusters Competitiveness: Through Porterian Diamond Framework and Factors</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Farhad</given_name>
					<surname>Khodadad Kashi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mohammad Hosein</given_name>
					<surname>Poor Kazemi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Ali</given_name>
					<surname>Qasemi</surname>
					<email>ghasemi@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Competitiveness is divided into two broad categories named as macroeconomic and microeconomic competitiveness. Microeconomic competitiveness indicators have a direct impact on company productivity within which sate of cluster development is the most important pillar of microeconomic competitiveness that are introduced by Michael Porter and it's framework as Diamond Model. The Diamond reveals almost every things matters for competitiveness and based on six indices and 24 sub-indices. In This article by the way of DEMATEL technique and MATLAB software the priority of 6 indices and 24 sub-indices has been showed in 47 industrial clusters (in 19 provinces) and interaction of these indices and sub-indices also has been depicted. This priority is as below: 1-Demand conditions, 2-Role of Government, 3-Factor conditions, 4- Context for strategy and rivalry, 5-Chance, 6- related and supporting industries. This priority for 6 indices and 24 sub-indices could be used as a toolkit by policy makers to enhance regional economic development so that those factors should be used that have most effect on regional economy and leased influence form exogenous factors.  
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Competitiveness</keyword>
	<keyword> Industrial Clusters</keyword>
	<keyword> Diamond Model</keyword>
	<keyword> DEMATEL</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>133</first_page>
								  <last_page>146</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-351</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Assessing the Sustainability of Urban Neighborhoods in 17 District of Tehran city Using ANP Model</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Zohreh</given_name>
					<surname>Fanni</surname>
					<email>z-fanni@sbu.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Koorosh</given_name>
					<surname>Akhavaan Heidari</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Akbar</given_name>
					<surname>Heidari</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Neighborhood development is considered as one purpose of sustainable urban development (SUD) and a key action to reach the sustainability. This approach (SUN), enhance this new approach that the city's problems can be expected in return to the neighborhood concept. Applied methodology is based on descriptive-analytical, case study and librarian methods. In continuous, it was used of interview with experts and officials for assessing sustainability rates in Neighborhoods of 17 districts in Tehran city using analytic network process and Delphi methods. In this study, 25 different indicators in the size of sociocultural, economical and Physical-environmental dimensions have been studied for measuring sustainability. Results showed that there are significant difference among neighborhoods, in terms of different dimensions of sustainability. Also, the results indicated that Yaft-Abad Neighborhood by achieving the highest score (0.574) had first rank and Fallah Neighborhood with the lowest score (0.719) of the final award and ranked as the most disadvantaged Neighborhood of distinct in accordance with sustainability indicators. Finally, in the end of this presented some solve ways.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>SUN</keyword>
	<keyword> SUD</keyword>
	<keyword> ANP Model</keyword>
	<keyword> Urban Neighborhoods </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>147</first_page>
								  <last_page>158</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-351-en.doc</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-483</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Analysis of Passive Defense in Plants and Equipment in Rasht</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Mohammad Taqi</given_name>
					<surname>Rahnamaee</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Parvaneh</given_name>
					<surname>Zivyar</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Sabereh</given_name>
					<surname>Salaah Kaar</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Hasan</given_name>
					<surname>Hoseini Amini</surname>
					<email>amini1388@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
Metropolitan city of Rasht as the largest nucleus of population density in Gilan province place most of the manpower, investment, economic and infrastructure projects. The same subject make necessary to study the main arteries and land usage of Rasht city of in terms of passive defense. Passive defense as a set of preventive measures cause to increases deterrence, reducing vulnerability, sustain essential activities, promote national stability and easing crisis Management against the threat and military, natural and human action. According to research that deals with the vital arteries of the Rasht city in terms of passive defense, at first it was necessary to predicted threat scenarios for demand centers (centers vulnerable to threats). Therefore, the future threats that may be suffered were identified in Rasht. Then due to the type of threat, risk-taking, damage radius, impact intensity, importance and priority, different area of Rasht (study area) valuated using experts and pundits and using AHP model. In this process, the risk place of Rasht in three areas (high risk, medium risk, low risk) was identified in GIS medium. Finally, the position of each demand center associated with critical artery, area risk, supply centers (aid in crisis) and arrangement manner, access, distribution, and proximity to Main Street were examined. The study showed that in current condition, the main artery and branches in Rasht due to stars pattern of the city and nearby land use, accordance with the standards and considerations of passive defense, are not in direction to suitable respond to possible crises.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Metropolitan city of Rasht</keyword>
	<keyword> passive defense</keyword>
	<keyword> vital arteries</keyword>
	<keyword> Risk area</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>159</first_page>
								  <last_page>170</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-293</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Evaluation Indicators of Good Urban Governance Case Study: The Central Area of Region 10of Tehran Metropolitan</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Esmaeil</given_name>
					<surname>Shieh</surname>
					<email>es_shieh@iust.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Sadaf</given_name>
					<surname>Tabatabaee</surname>
					<email>sadaf_tabatabaee78@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Mehid</given_name>
					<surname>Saidi</surname>
					<email>mehdi.saidi87@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			With forecasting the settlement of more than 66 percent of  the population of the world in cities over the next 10 years, the world is becoming a global city. So many problems would be involved in the future of urban management. Researchers presume good governance as the best solution for their management problems of metropolitans Therefore, considering the components of the theory of good governance, urban management will benefit from it in the planning. The goal of this article is evaluating the indicators of good urban governance in the central area of region 10 of Tehran metropolitan. In order to achieve this goal, we’ve used theoretical concepts, theories, frameworks, guidelines, recommendations, and different indicators related to good urban governance and its components in the urban environment that have been studied in the beginning. To evaluate the urban governance, eight primary factors including integrity participation, satisfaction, training and high efficiency, control and monitoring, accountability, participation, clarity, actualize,feasibility, quality and desirability of environment have been considered, and sub-criteria have been developed for each factor. data were collected using a questionnaire. Afterwards, by the preparation of the database and making use of factor analysis in SPSS, indicators were classified. Using linear regression analysis, the relation between factors with overall satisfaction was assessed. Furthermore, to improve governance in the central area of region 10 of Tehran, prioritizing and ranking indicators for organizing the study area have been investigated.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Evaluation</keyword>
	<keyword> Indicators</keyword>
	<keyword> Good urban governance</keyword>
	<keyword> Region 10 of Tehran</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>171</first_page>
								  <last_page>182</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-293-en.docx</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-484</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Factors affecting the explanation of Tehran’s spatial structure: Case of Region 3 of Tehran </title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Esmail</given_name>
					<surname>Nasiri</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Ahmadreza</given_name>
					<surname>Yazdani</surname>
					<email>yazdani_sin492000@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Seyyed Ali</given_name>
					<surname>Safavi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The term “physical development and land use” was primarily raised in the Western countries so that governments could monitor the way the land is used and to maintain property rights. However, with rapid growth of urbanization and development of urban and regional planning the dimensions and the contents of the concept have expanded day by day. The central and practical core of urban planning is the land use planning not only is categorized as a type of functional planning but also serves as a guide to direct urban development programs.  Urban land use planning refers to an organizing plan to arrange urban activities in order to achieve specific objectives and it plays a determinant role in physical development. The process of preparing the urban development plans is essentially reviewed and explained in a form of macro-planning process. Accordingly, given the centrality of the issue in line with the analysis of physical development in the Region 3 in Tehran, by recognizing the current opportunity and analyzing the characteristics and structure of the region under study, the present study tried to explain the issue and ultimately to explain the production in this area. The main goal of the present study is to recognize spatial structure of the Region 3 of Tehran in order to extract the potential problems and finally to devise the intended plan. 
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>spatial structure</keyword>
	<keyword> Tehran region</keyword>
	<keyword> explanation.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>183</first_page>
								  <last_page>196</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-485</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Identification and design of factors influencing nationalist of consumer by protection approach from small and medium enterprises (SMEs)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Ozhan</given_name>
					<surname>Karimi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mohammad</given_name>
					<surname>Mahmoodi Meimand</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Ali Akbar</given_name>
					<surname>Jokar</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Mehdi</given_name>
					<surname>Mahmood Zadeh</surname>
					<email>mahmoudzadih2004@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Supporting production and consumption of domestic goods is always a top priority in our country's economic and trade policy and a common approach in this regard, political and legal support and encourage the consumption of domestic goods by utilizing and stimulate patriotic feelings and pushing these feelings to use domestic goods and establish business of entrepreneurs. On this basis, the main problem of this study is to identify the components of the nationalist of consumer culture in support of small and medium enterprises. In this regard, and to respond to the problem mentioned the aim of this study is to take advantage from the research literature and referring to the opinions of experts, a model for nationalist of consumer culture in support of small and medium enterprises design. For achieve to purpose mentioned the Delphi method was used. Present results of Delphi, seven factors influencing nationalist consumer in supporting small and medium enterprises to include programing in the national media, teaching religious teaching to youth raising the social value of Iranian products, banning the propaganda of foreign products, requiring executive agencies to the use of domestic goods, enhance the functional value of Iranian products and enhance the emotional value of Iranian products detected.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Small and medium enterprises</keyword>
	<keyword> making culture</keyword>
	<keyword> nationalist of consumer </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>197</first_page>
								  <last_page>208</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-486</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Analysis of architectural structure and urban design (mosque - shrine) of Khwaja Abu Nasr Parsa in Timurid period of Iran in Balkh, Afghanistan </title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Fereshteh</given_name>
					<surname>Kharrazi Qadim</surname>
					<email>f.kharrazi@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
The shrines are monument of the deceased person which are constructed for respecting and honoring the memory of the deceased person and rely on spiritual concepts such as eternality, death etc. In this paper, attempt has been made to analyze architectural structure   of Khwaja Abu Nasr Parsa in Balkh, Afghanistan which was part of Iran in the Timurids period and Khorasan (one province in Iran) region. This period is one of the most important periods for application of the shrine monuments. This shrine is one of the most important shrines in the Timurids period and probably is one of the known historical monuments of Balkh and also plays role of mosque which is called a kind of shrine mosque.  Research method of this paper is historical documentary and its analysis method is descriptive –analytical. So, all types of decorations and architectural physical elements of this monument are studied and results from magnificence are given.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>shrine</keyword>
	<keyword> Abu Nasr Parsa</keyword>
	<keyword> Balkh</keyword>
	<keyword> Timurids period</keyword>
	<keyword> Iran</keyword>
	<keyword> Afghanistan</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>209</first_page>
								  <last_page>220</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-488</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title> Examine the Relationship between the Process-Oriented Organizations by Strategy Formation as a Formal Process</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Seyyed Ali Akbar</given_name>
					<surname>Ahmadi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Alireza</given_name>
					<surname>Ali Ahmadi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Shams Alsadat</given_name>
					<surname>Zahedi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Arta</given_name>
					<surname>Aboonabi</surname>
					<email>abunabei@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			This article examines the role of management in business processes in relation to the process-oriented organization and strategy formation as a formal process (strategic planning). A questionnaire designed to measure these variables after the validity and reliability among a sample of 183 managers, officials and experts in working systems, information technology and strategic planning in major firms of Iran Khodro Industrial Group distributed. The method of research is cross-correlation and path analysis used to test research hypotheses. The results showed that process-oriented organization through management in business processes the pattern of the process of managing business processes involved on strategy formation as a formal process. Finally, to enhance the process maturity and effective strategic planning proposals have presented to managers.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>process-oriented organization</keyword>
	<keyword> business process management</keyword>
	<keyword> school planning</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>221</first_page>
								  <last_page>236</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-489</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Studying the importance of the tourism industry for sustainable urban development (Case Study - coastal town: Chalus)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Maryam</given_name>
					<surname>Danesh Nejad</surname>
					<email>meryam.daneshnejad@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Keramat allah</given_name>
					<surname>Ziari</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
Todays, sustainable development is one of the principles which are considered by scholars. This means that the future of humanity is very important to maintain living standards, so that it can no longer operate as before and use the human environment. Therefore the effects of tourism should be studied perfectly to minimize its threat and maximize opportunities and strength points and this would not be realized in case of cooperation of countries. To achieve sustainable development of cultural tourism, all segments of a society should engage based on the principles of sustainable development planning to turn it into a popular culture. Sustainable development and tourism have organic communication with each other. UNWTO defines sustainable development as a kind of development which meets to needs without affecting the interests of future generations and their needs. Tourism as a social and cultural reality has both positive and negative functions in society. &quot;Enjoying the spaces, seeing different effects and customs, understanding the ways of life, preserving cultural resources are the most important functions and benefits of this sector in society. This paper intends to consider urban tourism and its role in development addresses sustainable, tourism types and defines sustainable development and sustainable urban development, urban tourism and examines the relationship between sustainable development and urban tourism  and because urban tourism is one of the most important activities and programs for sustainable development and planning for it is one of the requirements in our country due to climatic variation, historical, cultural, ethnic and religious differences.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>sustainable development</keyword>
	<keyword> tourism</keyword>
	<keyword> urban tourism.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>237</first_page>
								  <last_page>244</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>13-490</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>14</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>39</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Evaluating and revisiting the public government: a policy feedback perspective</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Majid</given_name>
					<surname>Farahani</surname>
					<email>farahani.maj@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Seyyed Mehdi</given_name>
					<surname>Alvani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Morteza</given_name>
					<surname>Moosa Khani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Gholam Reza</given_name>
					<surname>Memar Zadeh Tehran</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Existing models of quality evaluation in public sector are mainly derived from the approaches within private sector. These models which represented by the New Public Management (NPM) paradigm, don&amp;rsquot reflect the fundamental values of public administration, which are the very essence of the discipline and contrasting it from private sector. These core values, such as democratic citizenship, are labeled as &amp;ldquonon-performance&amp;rdquo aspects of quality by existing market-oriented quality models and, hence, are abandoned from evaluation. Following on the changes have occurred in ways of governing, which is identified as &amp;ldquopublic governance&amp;rdquo, this study suggests that quality evaluation in this area of governance should be based not only on measuring policy outputs and process, but also on evaluating political outcomes of public services, specifically those related to democratic citizenship. Government, however, plays a considerable role in governance network. Thus, the quality of ways through which government plays its role matters and, consequently, should be assessed.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>public governance</keyword>
	<keyword> policy</keyword>
	<keyword> policy feedback.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>9</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>245</first_page>
								  <last_page>252</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
			
		</ListRecords>
		</OAI-PMH>
		 
  
  
  
  
 