<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" 

"journalpublishing3.dtd">

<article 
article-type="research-article"
dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en" 
xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
>

<front>

<journal-meta>

  <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">1</journal-id>
  <issn>1607-2227</issn>

  <publisher>

	<publisher-name> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher-name>
  </publisher>

</journal-meta>



<article-meta>

  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">146</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>The role of public spaces of high-rise residential buildings in increasing the residents’ social interactions (Case study: International Tower of Tehran)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Kashfi</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Ali</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>b</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Hoseini</surname>
		<given-names>Seyed Baqer</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>c</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Noroozian Maleki</surname>
		<given-names>Saeed</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>d</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic>b</italic>

	</sup>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic>c</italic>

	</sup>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic>d</italic>

	</sup>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>7</fpage>

  <lpage>18</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>05</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Due to the growth of city population and a sharp rise in land cost, families living in high-rise buildings have been on the increase over the last several years. Therefore, people have always looked for the ways to reduce the negative health effects of living in high stories. One of the most important factors that could play a key role in reducing these effects is public open spaces in the residential areas. A well-designed open space can make them appropriate for residents’ social interactions. These spaces can be regarded as the continuation of private lives that their existence is necessary for a residential complex. The hypothesis of this study was that the residents’ social interactions decrease by gradual increase in height. International tower of Tehran was selected as the case study and the impact of increasing height on social interactions was studied. The questionnaires were randomly distributed among 70 residents of the tower. After collecting the questionnaires, the data and information related to each question were categorized. The result of analyzing the data showed that a gradual increase in height has a linear relation with the social interaction of residents. Finally, according to this relation, and also in order to prevent a decline in social interactions between residents, some strategies were suggested to promote the level of social interactions in high-rise residential complexes.
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">157</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Reviews of management developing approaches in coastal areas</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Bemanian</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Reza</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>e</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Kalavi</surname>
		<given-names>Aylaar</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>f</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Oshkooh</surname>
		<given-names>Hosein</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>g</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic>e</italic>

	</sup>University of Tarbiat Modares 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic>f</italic>

	</sup>University of Tarbiat Modares 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic>g</italic>

	</sup>University of Tarbiat Modares 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>19</fpage>

  <lpage>38</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>15</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>15</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Coastal areas consider as a strategic and important region of each country. Proximity of water and land always was the origin of human societies’ formation. Currently, in the rapidly changing world the emphasis shifts on urban issues according to strategy and urban management, especially management of coastal development. Iran considering wide costal area in the north and south is no exception. According to Bandar Turkmen’s strategic location in the region and its social and cultural context in northern of Iran is subject to change in order to meet urban, tourist, transport etc. needs. Lack of a proper strategy to manage costal area’s future development provides the necessary of developing a comprehensive strategy for managing the coastal areas. In this study, using qualitative methods, descriptive features of coastal areas discuss and new model to determine the development strategy provide. The results of study identified the appropriate strategy for development of Bandar Turkmen is revitalization and improvement strategies with an emphasis on creating new functionality in this coastal area. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">176</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Priority Assessment of Influential Architectural Factors in Metro stations on Users’ Satisfaction Case Study: First and Second Lanes of Tehran Metro Network</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mardomi</surname>
		<given-names>Karim</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>h</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Qamari</surname>
		<given-names>Hesaam</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>i</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic>h</italic>

	</sup>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic>i</italic>

	</sup>University of Texas, America 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>39</fpage>

  <lpage>52</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>30</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>30</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The goal of this study is to investigate the influential factors on users' satisfaction of Tehran metro stations. Speed, timing and technical issues of the trains in metro stations besides its architecture can affect the improvement of the users' satisfaction. However the focus of this study is to investigate the architectural factors which contribute to improvementof users' travel satisfaction in metro network toward the goals of sustainable urban transportation. The importance of this subject matter is because of the interrelationship of metro stations as the public urban spaces with the social life. The metro stations in Tehran play an important role in social life of the people. Therefore, the users’ satisfaction is an important issue which should be considered. To do so, the related literature of the subject was reviewed and then the influential factors of users’ satisfaction were defined. Next, the experts in this field were interview in order to revise and complete the factors. In the next step, the users of specific metro stations in Tehran filled out the questionnaire forms to evaluate the factors. Finally, the collected data were analyzed and scaled in order to evaluate their priorities and according to the results, design considerations were recommended. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">177</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Urban integrated management in arranging of Informal settlement in Iran moderate cities (Zanjan and Hamadan)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Daviran</surname>
		<given-names>Esmail</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>j</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Kazemian</surname>
		<given-names>Gholamreza</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>k</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Meshkini</surname>
		<given-names>Abolfazl</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>l</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Rokn Al Din Eftekhari</surname>
		<given-names>Abdolreza</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>m</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Kalhornia</surname>
		<given-names>Bijan</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>n</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic>j</italic>

	</sup>University of Tarbiat Modares 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic>k</italic>

	</sup>Tabatabai University 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic>l</italic>

	</sup>University of Tarbiat Modares 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic>m</italic>

	</sup>University of Tarbiat Modares 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic>n</italic>

	</sup>Kermanshah University 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>53</fpage>

  <lpage>68</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>30</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>30</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Integrated management of urban management is also Synergic, with the participation of all stakeholders and influential city in the institutional framework, institutional and legal order to determine the steady level of urban management for city livability. This article is intended to scrutiny the management structure of the metropolitan cities of Iran (Zanjan and Hamedan) in arranging informal settlements with an integrated management approach.research method is survey- quantity method that achieves documents and field data collection has been done. Society statistical is members of the informal settlement enabling head quarters,(public and state sectors), community institutes people that living in informal settlements and economic actors (private sector) based in the tissues. Sample size estimates for the public sector and 18 public organizations for public and state sectors and samples for private sector and 620 samples for people that using the depletion method and the average test data analysis were performed. Results of the study show that in the middle of Iran's cities, urban integrated management has been the traditional function of attitude. This type of attitude and organization design and development urban issues in the tissues is an informal settlement. From the collaborating institution (institutional synergy) as a precondition for implementation of integrated management is now integrated in the urban poor and urban-based lifecycle management is situated. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">178</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Analysis of interacting with the management structure of city genealogy of aesthetic Strategic and operational strategies of global navigation</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Behzadfar</surname>
		<given-names>Mostafa</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>o</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Ilka</surname>
		<given-names>Shahin</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic>p</italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Ilka</surname>
		<given-names>Shahab</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic>o</italic>

	</sup>Iran University of Science and Technology 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic>p</italic>

	</sup>Sama Technical and Vocational College, Islamic Azad University, Varamin 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Sama Technical and Vocational College, Islamic Azad University, Varamin 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>69</fpage>

  <lpage>90</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>30</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>30</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Now look at the lack of systematic and comprehensive plans, affluent and urban development projects, uncoordinated bureaucracy and official bodies scattered wide and influential in the field of urban management, lack of awareness of citizens and business users - than the exercise of his rights and civil society oversight and participation in the design and construction of the major obstacles in the path of urban beautification and good urban Landscape. This article was written based on the need for a meta-analytic review and sample and data collection tools: library studies and documents have benefited. The findings show Strong structural pattern recognition of outstanding architectural design and its various sections, such as, the apparent relationship between the components of form, color, dimensions, size, quality, material, graphics, designs, compliance with rules designed and Methodologies resolution elements: changes in form, conflicts appearance, color and paper, proportions, design and coordination: the manufacture, use, maintenance, design rational selection of suitable materials, manufacturing processes and applications design aesthetic, meaningful and valuable (without visual disturbance), And beautification of the most important indicators are being considered In the end, strategies and solutions to improve the current situation in Iran is presented. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">179</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Strategic Revision of Urban Services Context of Local Management of Iran, Emphasizing the Urban Waste Case Study: Mashhad Metropolitan</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Azizi</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Mehdi</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Motevaseli</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Mehdi</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>College of Fine Arts, Tehran University 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>University Research Scholar Index 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>91</fpage>

  <lpage>112</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>30</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>30</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Strategic Vision in management is not a choice but a necessity. To be of this view, is to be of knowledge, deep thinking, comprehensive visioning, realistic view, and mature management competence. Management is a process which projects with scientific, realistic and comprehensive characteristics are its signs. In urban management, systematic view is an unavoidable principle. Desirable management of cities, particularly metropolitans, without IMS (Integrated urban Management System) is impossible and IMS is the system as the by-product of strategic view. This view is a burden on the shoulders of Mashhad’s managers in different contexts and issues such as urban services, and urban environment in the district of Mashhad Metropolitan. To make the ultimate use of the limited resources, this local management should naturally be able to choose its specific strategies, those strategies which are toward viewpoint of local management of Mashhad on one hand, and flourished from the missions of urban management on the other. Theoretically and methodologically, this study is based on structuralism and historic-formative analysis in macro scale and strategy, which is done through qualitative and document-library methods of research, aiming at attaining strategic programming methodology in urban waste management of Mashhad. Results show that recognition of Mashhad citizens’ priorities and requirements though creation of clean and sustainable environment must be the basis for the decision-makings in policy-making and planning for Mashhad metropolitan while is impossible without a strategic visioning. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">180</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Measuring accessibility to neighborhood facilities in Iran using Fuzzy Logic (A case study of Tabriz)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Lotfi</surname>
		<given-names>Sediqeh</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Manoochehri Miandoab</surname>
		<given-names>Ayoob</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Aahaar</surname>
		<given-names>Hasan</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Salaki</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Ali</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Mazandaran University 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Tehran University 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Azad University of Qazvin 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Tarbiat Moallem University of Tehran 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>113</fpage>

  <lpage>130</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>30</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>30</day>
				  <month>01</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Accessibility to urban public spaces and facilities can be one of the main factors for the users. There are a few studies in the country regarding to the subject, despite the importance of public accessibility. Public spaces are a vital part of our daily life in cities streets where we pass them every day to reach our work place, places where children play and religious locations where our holy duties take place. The main goal of this study is to measure accessibility quality to urban amenities and facilities (Neighborhood Parks, primary schools, health care centers, mosques, and sport clubs). Also the research aims to compare the quality of life in different urban structure of Tabriz. The methodology of the research is based on descriptive –analytical methods and for selection of samples, stratified random sampling was applied to select the samples. There has been a wide h in the current literature review regarding to the measuring quality of life and then the required maps were produced in GIS environment and Fuzzy technique was used to determine the quality of neighborhood accessibility to the facilities. Finally multi criteria techniques like TOPSIS and Entropy to better and easier analyses. The results revealed that there is considerable difference of among the neighborhoods regarding accessibility to facilities. Although accessibility to some of neighborhood facilities has been better in newly developed areas but the areas where rural settings still dominate some marginal neighborhoods the accessibility is very low. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">184</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>A research on interaction between land use management, urban transportation & traffic situation, Case study: Almas-e-shargh Commercial Center</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Asadi</surname>
		<given-names>Mahdieh</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Rahnama</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Rahim</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Legzian</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>131</fpage>

  <lpage>144</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>02</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>02</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The urban land use is one of the important factors of the city that through communicational networks and traffic flows is directly related to transportation system. In fact, urban transportation and land use factors are a system that decision in one affects the other one, and management in one of them can be effective in achieving the goals in the whole system. Therefore, that is needed to considered and managemened as integrated system. This article follows objectives, strategies and policies of land use management and its relationship with the urban transportation and traffic in Almas – e - shargh Commercial Center. The method of research was descriptive and applied one. For doing this research at first data collection carried out with literature review and field work survey. For research of traveling demand and traffic impacts of land-use management, we use the four-stage classical transformational model in the EMME/2 software. For Simulation this project have defined two different scenarios which their results show that Almas-e-shargh Commercial Centering outward of the city and executing strategies and land use management policies correctly, achieved its goals. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">185</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>An investigation of the motives for FAR contravention in Tehran</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Sarkheili</surname>
		<given-names>Elnaz</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Rafiian</surname>
		<given-names>Mojtaba</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Bemanian</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Reza</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>University of Tarbiat Modares 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>University of Tarbiat Modares 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>University of Tarbiat Modares 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>145</fpage>

  <lpage>162</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>02</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>02</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Non- compliance with building regulations is one of the major abnormalities in Tehran that its effects can be seen in different aspects and levels. There are different kinds of building contraventions in Tehran that FAR contravention is the most numerous among them. This paper aims to find some reasons for FAR contravention in the city through the consideration of the effect of social, economical motivations and the monitoring system about urban constructions on FAR contravention. Therefore, six indicators including level of awareness, violation of regulations with the aim of meeting the minimum needs of housing (housing related motives), violation of regulations with the aim of gaining financial profit (profit making motives), owner's income level, experience and expertise level of developers, and the quality of supervision and monitoring are determined and the information gathered through questionnaires answered by 150 persons whose cases were under investigation in the municipality and the information are analyzed through path analysis. According to the results, the FARTHEST contraventions have been occurred due to the low level of awareness of citizens about building bylaws and the importance of complying with them in Tehran. In addition, meeting the necessity to more covered space and room for housing or working, and the income level are the principal factors affecting on the occurrence of FAR contravention in the city. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">187</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Structural Analysis of Regenerated Street Networks of Deteriorated Areas in order to resolve Permeability problem and spatial isolation of these areas (A Case Study from Mashhad, Iran)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Abbaszadegan</surname>
		<given-names>Mostafa</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Bidraam</surname>
		<given-names>Rasool</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mokhtarzadeh</surname>
		<given-names>Safoora</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Iran University of Science and Technology 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Art University of Isfahan 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Art University of Isfahan 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>163</fpage>

  <lpage>178</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>02</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>02</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The main objective of this paper is to analyse street network structure of the deteriorated areas in order to resolve permeability problem and spatial isolation of these areas. Previous researches that investigated the problems of deteriorated areas concern about land use per capita indicated that low permeability of these areas is not about area of streets but, it is because of inadvertence towards the urban street network in developing new areas or regeneration of deteriorated areas. In both cases, insufficient network of streets and roads have been produced. The common solution to encounter shortage of permeability was widening existing streets or creating new streets. Previous research regarding resolving lake of access and isolation on deteriorated areas, have been failed because they did not carried a methodical approach toward identifying the structure problems of deteriorated areas. Regarding the above theoretical and technical shortcomings, this paper would answer to two fundamental questions: How could weaknesses of urban street structure on deteriorated areas can be round and can be resolved? Are there similar structural problems about permeability on all of the urban deteriorated areas? In order to answer to these questions, at first urban street structure of Mashhad has been analyzed utilizing Space Syntax method. This method identified the weaknesses and deficiencies of Mashhad's deteriorated structure. The results show that, there are significant differences between the structure of deteriorated areas and other parts of the city this differentiation helps to identify weaknesses in these areas. Also, analysis of urban street structure indicated that reasons of access weakness and permeability problems in various deteriorated areas are different, especially between central and suburban deteriorated areas. So, the problems of deteriorated areas cannot be resolved similarly. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">188</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Recognition of pedestrian-oriented movement for sustainability of dense urban zones</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Feizi</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Javad</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Rajabi</surname>
		<given-names>Azita</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Hoseini</surname>
		<given-names>Yasaman</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Islamic Azad University, Shahr-e Rey 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Islamic Azad University of Tehran 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Science and Research Branch, Islamic Azad University, Alborz 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>179</fpage>

  <lpage>194</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Today, the pedestrian oriented movement, whose goal is to retrieve and expand pedestrian spaces on the face of the city, and to recognize and give priority to pedestrians as first rate elements of the city, has turned into one of the axes of programming and urban design. Especially with the beginning of the third millennium, renewed necessity of pedestrian movement as the most healthy, economic and dynamic method of movement and inner city transportation has attracted experts and leaders of urban affairs. Factors such as significant increase in movement time, increase in accidents, increase in sound and visual pollution and air pollution which is getting close to the borders of creating health threats for humans, are the consequences of the unstable urban transportation system. In addition, obstacles such as lack of funding for infrastructure, lack of safety and security, improper positioning of spaces and buildings, legal and regulatory obstacles and finally, lack of credibility and social status exist in the path of development of the non-motorized transportation network. The results of the experiences of other countries indicate that stability cannot be reached only with changes in design, models of utilization and management of transportation systems, but with changes in mentality and way of thinking towards identification and evaluation of possible solutions for solving the problems of transportation. Therefore in this research we first have a brief overview of the concepts of sustainable urban transport, then we study walking and cycling and their effect as effective methods of non-motorized transportation, along with strategies for reaching sustainable development in desirable urban form, in the area of 2nd Sadeqieh square ( located in zone 2 of the municipality of Tehran) which have been analyzed and evaluated using a mixed model of SWOT and Likert, in order to use benefits of applying these strategies and developing them in the country. This research has been done with the support of the Institute of municipalities and village council of the country. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">189</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Evaluation the rule of Dehyariha in quality of life in rural areas case study: Keresf, khoda bande</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Farahani</surname>
		<given-names>Hosein</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Rostamkhani</surname>
		<given-names>Ahmad</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Zanjan University 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Zanjan University 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>195</fpage>

  <lpage>206</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The aim of this study was to evaluate the role of Dehyariha on quality of life in Karasf rural district in Khodabandeh city. In this regard, first the history of rural management in Iran and also Dehyariha and its duties as executives in the villages has been discussed and then the role of Dehyariha on villagers’ quality of life has been review and evaluation. This research is descriptive-analytical. Statistical society of this study is comprised of Karasf rural district in Khodabandeh city. The number of cases was selected according to proportion of households in each village. Reliability of research buoy was measured using Cronbach's alpha statistic that was equal to 0.875. SPSS software was used for data analysis. Mann Whitney U statistical test was used to compare the quality of life in rural areas. Also the eight indicators of educational, environmental, social support networks, economic, health and safety, residential environment, infrastructure and leisure has been reviewed and evaluated. Results showed significant differences between villages with and without Dhyariha in seven indexes of the compared eight indicators. From the buoys that reviewed in present study differences showed no significant only in the leisure index. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">190</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Evaluate the implementation of urban sustainability indicators in border areas (Case Study: Piranshahr City)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Kalantari Khalil Abad</surname>
		<given-names>Hosein</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Aboobakri</surname>
		<given-names>Taher</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Qaderi</surname>
		<given-names>Reza</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Poor Ali</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Ali</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Saeedi</surname>
		<given-names>Anvar</given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Jihad Tehran University 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Payam Noor University of Urmia 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Payam Noor University of Urmia 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>207</fpage>

  <lpage>222</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Today, paying attention to the cities and urbanization issues is one of the planning requirements in the nationwide following expansion of urbanization in recent centuries and burgeoning population. In this study, the issues and indicators of Piranshahr urban sustainable development is reviewed as one of the border cities of the country in South West Azerbaijan Province which has faced severe burgeoning population in the recent two decades. In this study, environmental, social, economic, institutional-structural indicators have been tested with the average selected urban indicators of the country through the use of Sign Test and Wilcoxon Test for the evaluation of Piranshahr urban sustainable development. The results of statistical tests indicate that despite rapid population developments of Piranshahr city and its fast burgeoning population in recent two decades, development of Piranshahr city has been made in line with the urban sustainable development and its development and population variability has been secured due to the provision of job and economic attractions through border and international transactions and is in line with the urban sustainability. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">191</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Categorizing The Key Indices For Establishing A Project Charter For Urban Project Management</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Falsafi</surname>
		<given-names>Reza</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Yazdanpanah</surname>
		<given-names>Ahmadali</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Ahmadi</surname>
		<given-names>Seyyed Badr Aldin</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Ahmadi</surname>
		<given-names>Loza</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>University of Tarbiat Modares 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Shahid Beheshti University 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>University of Tarbiat Modares 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>University of Tarbiat Modares 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>223</fpage>

  <lpage>238</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Investigating the requirements adopted from effective criteria and indices for national laws and regulations is needed for urban projects execution and these projects are followed by the least standard deviation. Project success and all staffs satisfaction are in fact the most important issues in urban projects as well as all kinds of projects. The most important factor is documentation of project existance reasons, goals, roles and responsibilities, stakeholders duties and authorities in the early stages of the project which is called project charter. In this article, which has used explorative method, after reviewing the project charter literature, various templates in 42 different projects in the world are investigated. Then we design the preparation step by step and derive the needed criteria and the result of the research is a suitable pattern for project charter preparation. Regarded that most of the projects in Iran have not included a project charter, the researchers of the paper have investigated the current effective factors used to prepare four big project charters by reviewing their documents and comparing them to designed model. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">192</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Analyzing of business cycle of private residential investment (Markov-switching vector auto regression model)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Akbari</surname>
		<given-names>Nemat Allah</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Yatmohammadian</surname>
		<given-names>Naser</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>University of Esfahan 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>University of Esfahan 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>239</fpage>

  <lpage>252</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Business cycles are the characteristics of the real estate market that get less attention in economics literature. Real estate market on the one hand is relatively high affected by economic business cycle and on the other hand significantly can affect economic as it can cause big financial crisis. Such importance of house market makes analyzing of real estate market Inevitable. In this paper close attention is paid to business cycle in real estate market in Iran and private residential investment behavior using Markov-switching VAR model is analyzed. Results achieved from Iran economy shows probability of staying in boom period is more than transition from it (95% vs. 5%) and probability of transition of stagnation period is more than staying in that (73% vs. 27%). According to these results expected duration of boom period is five time longer than expected duration of stagnation period. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">193</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Studying the relationship between skeletal scheme of residential complexes and sense of interest to the place among the residents</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Sadeqi Fereshteh</surname>
		<given-names>Roya</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Daneshgar Moqadam</surname>
		<given-names>Golrokh</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Dejdar</surname>
		<given-names>Omid</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Islamic Azad University of Hamedan 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Islamic Azad University of Hamedan 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Islamic Azad University of Hamedan 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>253</fpage>

  <lpage>264</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Space is a phenomenon which human give meaning to it during his life and is dependent on it. Dependence on location is influenced by space quality and design and it is created by individuals during specific time of their life. Between attachment to place and perception and understanding a place, there is a positive relationship, insofar as he recognizes himself by it. This study examines the relationship between physical design and sense of attachment to a place among residents of residential complexes. After addressing the existing theories on sense of space, using inductive approach and survey was tested hypothesis analytically. To obtain final results is applied a combined method in the form of a case study which correlation method is the main part of it. To study residential complexes, questionnaire for assessment of indicators was prepared and distributed among residents of the residential complexes. Then collected data was analyzed using SPSS software. Results show that among the six obtained indicators that are facilities and amenities, organization, quality of interior spaces, social interactions, type of access, view and visibility only two indices type of access and view can be considered as significant factors to increase sense of attachment to a place. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">194</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Analysis of quality of life in a rural - urban environment (case study: the Segzabad city)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Sajadi</surname>
		<given-names>Jila</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Faraji Mollai</surname>
		<given-names>Amin</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Azimi</surname>
		<given-names>Azadeh</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Shahid Beheshti University 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Tehran University 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Islamic Azad University, Shahr-e Rey 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>265</fpage>

  <lpage>284</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>03</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Analysis and evaluation of quality of life in rural-urban living environment is one of the major problems in urban and rural studies literature. In this context the aim of this study is analyze of quality of life in the Segzabad city to answer this question that to what extent improved quality of life this point lead to has been citizens. Methods This article is descriptive- analytical methods that to analysis and review of the studied subject was used statistical methods by SPSS software. Needed data has been collected in this research with use of both methods in the form of documents and field studies. Finally the results suggest that nearly 50 percent of the residents are getting positive comments to improve their quality of life after transform the Segzabad country to city place. 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">199</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Evaluation and Analysis of Mental Indicators of Urban Quality of Life (Case Study: Kashan City)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Khajeh Shahkoohi</surname>
		<given-names>Ali Reza</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Mahdavi</surname>
		<given-names>shahraam</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Soori</surname>
		<given-names>Farshad</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Samadi</surname>
		<given-names>Reza</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Golestan University 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Golestan University 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>University of Esfahan 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Golestan University 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>285</fpage>

  <lpage>296</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>08</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>08</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Quality of life is among the significant issues that was first paid attention to by the scholars with the widespread development of technology and industrialization process in Western countries and the studies in this regard has been increased and this significant issues is due to increasing importance of the studies performed in the field of quality of life in the monitoring of general policy and its role as an efficient tool in urban planning and management. One of the dimensions of the studies in the field of quality of life is related to its mental indicator, considering this dimension of the studies in quality of life, it can be accumulation of satisfaction in various areas of life. This study aims to evaluate quality of life in Kashan city using mental indicators which these indicators have been developed and analyzed in the framework of three economic, physical-environmental and social-cultural realms. The research method is a descriptive-analytical and survey one. Also, the statistical community in this study is Kashan city residents who 300 samples have been selected at random using Kerji and Mourgan Table and a questionnaire has been scattered among them. Therefore, to achieve a correct judgment, 19 indicators in three economic, physical-environmental and social-cultural realms have been used in this study. The results obtained from this study indicate that mental components show a significant relationship up to 99% level which most residents of Kashan city have a relative satisfaction about their quality of life. To examine the relationship between resident's economic-social conditions and their satisfaction of mental component of quality of life, multivariate regression test has been used, by which the obtained results showed a significant relationship between citizen's economic-social conditions (as the independent variable) and their satisfaction with the mental life components (as the independent variable). 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">200</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Pricing the services of Vehicle Technical Examination Centers</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Karamroodi</surname>
		<given-names>Mahmood</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Amini Shirazi</surname>
		<given-names>Hamed</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Iran University of Science and Technology 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Iran University of Science and Technology 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>297</fpage>

  <lpage>306</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>08</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>08</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

In order to price every service, first, the profits and the expenses which that service has for the society and the service providers, should be considered and then the service price can be decided on. Regarding the transportation service improvement in every country, opening Vehicle Technical Examination Centers has some advantages as increasing vehicle safety, economizing on use of energy, and improving environmental conditions, and as a result it increases public sense of satisfaction. Having this taken into account ,these advantages need to be considered in compare with the expenses .Regarding the fact that the price of these services in the country is not suitable and technical examination services are not efficient enough in the society, in this article, first, effective indices of pricing in Technical Examination Centers is introduced in two parts involving profits and the expenses originating from opening Vehicle Technical Examination Centers, and following that, each index (profits and expenses)is calculated for the base year and the plan period ,and a dynamic model is suggested according to the tendency of the vehicle owners to pay and the balanced price of the technical examination services for the years of 1388 to 1398 .In this method, the curve of vehicle owners' request is used to estimate the amount of balanced price of the vehicle technical examination services . 
</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">201</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Assessment of Types of Residential High Rise Buildings through their Impacts on Urban Image and Escape</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Rahnama</surname>
		<given-names>Mohammad Rahim</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname>Kazemi Khabiri</surname>
		<given-names>Khalil Allah</given-names>
	  </name> 

	  <xref ref-type="aff">
		<sup>
		  <italic></italic>

		</sup>
	  </xref>

	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad 
  
 
	<sup>
	  <italic></italic>

	</sup>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad International Unit 
  
 
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2012</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>10</volume>

  <issue>30</issue>

  <fpage>307</fpage>

  <lpage>319</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>08</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>08</day>
				  <month>02</month>
				  <year>2014</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Today, the growth of high rise buildings in most of metropolitans is visible and also has left many impacts. The vast impacts of these buildings on the town’s physic and space have been criticized by many scholars and specialists. Herewith, impacts on the town’s physic and space is one of the main ones left, as their construction may lead to the rise or plunge of the quality of the town. In this regard, attention to the location, planning and design base on the rules and principles, coordination with neighboring and their fabric, creation of urban space in neighboring via combination of identity and active environment, and providing desirable image and escape, are among the remarkable issues in high rise buildings from the perspective of the quality of urban image and escape. This article, despite identifying different aspects of impacts of residential high rise buildings on urban image and escape, and introduction of criteria and sub criteria, studies the types of residential high rise buildings in the new fabric of City of Mashhad (using analysis method of AHP). The results of the study are clarifying the different impacts of samples of residential high rise buildings on urban escape and image of Mashhad and negligence of different dimensions of urban image and escape in location finding, planning, construction and maintenance of them. Although it is determined that type of partial and diversified high rise buildings (Half High Rise) in comparison to the coherent and intense high rise buildings (Half High Rise) are of better contexts to leave positive impacts on urban image and escape. At the end, and according to the findings of the study, holistic principles and rules of programming, planning and construction of high rise buildings so as to the uplift of urban escape and image are proposed. 
</body>

</article>

