<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2013</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>31</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی ارتباط بین ابنیه شاخص شهری به کمک عناصر طبیعی، مورد مطالعه: منطقه پیرامون هسته قدیمی شهر کرج</title_fa>
	<title>Analyzing of Relationship among Important Buildings with Using of Natural Elements Case Study: The surrounding region of the old core of the city of karaj</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;با در نظر گرفتن عدم توجه برخی طرحهای شهری به ویژگی ها و پتانسیلهای طبیعی- تاریخی شهر در ارائه پیشنهادات طراحی و ناکارآمدی های حاصله در زندگی شهری، به نظر می رسد استفاده مناسب از این توان‌ها جهت افزایش کیفیت محیط و هویت شهر امری ضروری باشد. هسته قدیمی شهر کرج یکی از محدوده های ویژه ای است که هم ماهیت تاریخی دارد و هم ماهیت طبیعی، در واقع وجود عناصر طبیعی و تاریخی همجوار با یکدیگر در این محدوده، ویژگی منحصر به فردی را به محدوده مذکور داده است که با استفاده مطلوب از پتانسیلهای بیان شده می تواند نقش مهمی در هویت شهر کرج ایفا نماید. یکی از راههای ارتقاء کیفیت پتانسیلهای مذکور که در این پژوهش به آن اشاره شده است، ایجاد ارتباط مناسب بین عناصر شاخص به کمک پتانسیل محیط طبیعی می باشد. لذا در این پژوهش سعی شده است که در ابتدا ارتباط بین عناصر طبیعی و مصنوع بررسی شده و با توجه به اینکه استفاده از طبیعت در شهر می تواند یکی از راهکارهای ارتباط بین عناصر شاخص مصنوع و طبیعی باشد، به بحث اکولوژی شهری و ارتباط طبیعت و شهر و ایجاد شهر سبز پرداخته شود و در نهایت نکات کلیدی تجارب ایران و جهان در این زمینه به صورت اصول ارتباط بین عناصر شاخص طبیعی و مصنوع ارائه گردیده است. سپس با استفاده از روی‌هم گذاری لایه های عناصر فیزیکی و طبیعی و تاریخی، ارتباط عمودی و افقی لکه ها بررسی شده و در نهایت با استفاده از روش توصیفی- تحلیلی، از جاذبه های طبیعی هسته قدیمی کرج و تلفیق یافته ها جهت ایجاد ارتباط مطلوب بین عناصر شاخص محدوده و در نتیجه بهبود و تقویت استخوانبندی شهر کرج بهره گرفته شده است. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Considering the lack of attention of some urban projects to city natural-historic features and potentials in the offers of the design and resulting inefficiencies in urban life, it seems proper use of these potentials for increasing the quality and identity of the city is essential. The old core of the city of Karaj is considered one of the particular zones which includes natural and epochal identity, actually the existence of natural and historical elements adjacent to one another in this zone, give specific feature to pointed zone by using optimal the expressed potentials can bring about an important role to play in the identity of the City of Karaj. One of the ways to improve the quality of the expressed potentials that in this research study referred to is good relationship between the important elements with helping of the potential of the natural environment.  Therefore, this study has tried to consider in the beginning the relationship between the natural and artificial elements and according to the use of the nature in the city can be one of the strategies of the relationship between the important artificial and natural elements, in continue to discuss the urban ecology and the relationship of the nature and the city and the green city, and finally have been discussed the key points of Iran and world experiences in this context as the principles of the relationship between natural and artificial important elements, then using to overlay the layers of the physical and natural and historical elements, the vertical and horizontal relationship of stains is considered and finally from natural attractions of the old core of the city of Karaj with using the analytical – descriptive method and integrating the findings to create a good relationship between important elements of zone and thus improving and strengthening the framework of the city of Karaj have been used.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شهر کرج،  هسته قدیمی، عناصر شاخص،  اکولوژی شهر، شهر سبز.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>The old core of the city, Relationship, Important elements, urban ecology, green city</keyword>
	<start_page>189</start_page>
	<end_page>204</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-67-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Farkhondeh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Johari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>فرخنده</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>جوهری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>johari1402@gmail.com</email>
	<code>100319475328460071</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460071</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University School of Art and Architecture</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده هنر و معماری دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Poor Jafar</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>پورجعفر</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>pourja_m@modares.ac.ir</email>
	<code>100319475328460072</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460072</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University School of Art and Architecture</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده هنر و معماری دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Masnavi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مثنوی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460073</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460073</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده محیط زیست دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mehdi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Haqiqat Bin</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حقیقت بین</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460074</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460074</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده هنر و معماری دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
