<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>12</volume>
<number>33</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تاویلی پدیدارشناسانه بر تاویلگری مدیران شهری: نقدی بر روش شناسی کمیسیون ماده 5 و کارگروه در اقدام برای تغییر در طرح های شهری</title_fa>
	<title>Hermeneutical Phenomenology of Interpreting the Urban Managers: Criticizing on the Methodology and Process of Urban Changing Committee</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
هدف از این مقاله تحلیل روش‌شناسی حاکم در تغییرات طرح‌های توسعه شهری از طریق فرایند تفسیر و تاویل درخواست‌ها در کمیسیون های ماده 5 و کارگروه معماری و شهرسازی و کمیته‌های کار مربوطه است. این کمیسیونها در فرآیند بررسی تغییرات در طرح های توسعه شهری از روش تفسیر و تاویل پدیده‌ها استفاده می نمایند که در شکل کار دارای شباهت هایی با نمونه سایر کشورها دارد. اما در فرایند کار به دلیل خلاهای روش شناسانه، فرایندی، و فردی اقدامات این کمیسیون ها به فرایندی دولتی و دیوان‌سالارانه در تغییر طرح های توسعه شهری تبدیل میگردد. روش شناسی این مقاله مبتنی بر روش مشاهده ساختارمند و تحلیل محتوا استوار بوده که بدین اعتبار در مراحل متفاوت فرایندی، داده ها مورد تحلیل قرار می گیرند. یافته های این تحقیق بیانگر این هستند که مباحثی همچون نوع درخواست، دایره ارجاع دهنده، فضای حاکم بر درخواست در نوع تاویلگری و نوع تصمیم سازی تاثیرگذار بوده و فرایندی از پیش فهم و خود فهمی در جریان تفسیر درخواست ها با توجه به تخصص اعضا صورت می پذیرد که رسیدن به اصل موضوع تحول را مبهم می سازد. نتایج این تحقیق روشنگر این است که این گونه از کمیسیون ها، در ساختار دولت‌های رفاه، بر مبنای پذیرش تغییرات جزیی و بطئی در ساختار برنامه ریزی دولت های سرمایه مدار و به منظور پرهیز از تحولات بنیادین در ساختار فضایی شهرها تشکیل شده اند اما در ایران به دلیل ذات دولتی بودن این کمیسیون ها، جریانات تغییرات شهری به سمت رویکردهای دولتی و بورکراتیک سوق داده می شوند. به همین دلیل، توافقات اجماع گرایانه این کمیسیون ها بر پایه اغنایی- اقتدارگرایانه است و اساساً با اجماع مبتنی بر آزادی های گفتگو و مذاکره، و توافق در عین تفاوت،و سازش در عین اختلاف متفاوت است. 
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
The aim of this paper is to analyze the methodology and process of interpreting the members in Urban Changing Committee (Committee Article 5) on the requests of stakeholders and developers.  Members of UCC apply different methods for interpretation especially hermeneutic in similarity with relevant professions and situation in process of analyzing the requests however those reforming actions go to bureaucratic achievement on the urban development plans as regards deficiencies of methodological and procedural in the process. Methodology of this research is observation and content analysis as qualitative method with phenomenological hermeneutic approach to interpret the deducting process in interaction of members with request as text. Findings of research identified that some factors influences on the process of interpretation, decision making and decision taking in UCC including style of the request, manner of the presentation, stakeholders and developers condition, and inner anarchy of committee. Additionally, this paper identified that there is ambiguous in the mind of members of UCC such as analytical process on the requests, pre-understanding and self-understanding in the interpretation process. Results of research explained that UCC have formed in new liberalism government to establish gradually reformation in capitalistic region. Therefore, in this process, all actions adapt with the bureaucratic framework to make plans more governmental. Hence, consensus in this committee constructs on bureaucratic dominating than free-domical participations, consensus in differentiation, or collusion in conflict. Result of this research could apply by local government to revise on the current situation of UCC also by developing countries in the same situation to recognize and solve planning system in atmosphere of conflict among different power groups.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>هرمنوتیک پدیدار شناسانه, تاویل درخواست ها, کمیسیون های تغییر.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Hermeneutical Phenomenology, Interpreting of requests, Urban Changing Committee.</keyword>
	<start_page>127</start_page>
	<end_page>142</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-805-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Rahman</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Tafahomi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رحمان</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>تفهمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>tafahomi@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002235</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002235</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>پردیس بین المللی کیش دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hasan Aldin</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Lamit</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسن الدین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>لامیت</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002236</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002236</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تکنولوژی مالزی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
