<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>46</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>عوامل موثر برنوگرایی جوانان در فرهنگ شهرنشینی</title_fa>
	<title>Factors affecting the modernity of youth in urbanism culture</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>كاربردي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Applicable</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;کانون اصلی نوگرایی در هر جامعه کلان شهرهای آن جامعه است. لذا برای بررسی میزان نوگرایی افراد باید آن ها را در بطن شهرها مورد مطالعه قرار داد؛ زیرا شهرها دائماً درحال تغییر و تحول هستند. از این رو هدف این تحقیق بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر نوگرایی جوانان در فرهنگ شهرنشینی است. تحقیق حاضر به لحاظ هدف کاربردی، به لحاظ ماهیت توصیفی از نوع همبستگی و به لحاظ روش پیمایش است. جامعه آماری تحقیق را کلیه جوانان 29-15 ساله شهر تهران تشکیل دادند. بر اساس فرمول کوکران حجم نمونه 400 نفر تعیین شد که به روش نمونه گیری تصادفی طبقه ای انتخاب شدند. به منظور گردآوری داده ها از پرسشنامه ای شامل 30 گویه استفاده شد. روایی صوری و محتوایی گویه ها با استفاده از نظر کارشناسان بررسی، تأیید و اصلاح شد. آلفای کرونباخ متغیرهای تحقیق نیز بالای 7/0 بدست آمد که بیانگر هماهنگی درونی گویه ها و پایایی قابل قبول آن ها بود. تجزیه و تحلیل داده ها با استفاده از رگرسیون دو متغیره و با کاربرد نرم افزار &amp;nbsp;انجام گرفت. براساس نتایج ضریب تعیین تعدیل&amp;rlm;شده حاکی از این بود که متغیرهای میزان دینداری، میزان استفاده از رسانه های جمعی، پایگاه اجتماعی اقتصادی و میزان تحصیلات به ترتیب حدود 22%، 50%، 2/34% و 2/51% از تغییرات متغیر میزان نوگرایی جوانان را تبیین کرده است و ضریب رگرسیون استاندارد شده نیز مشخص کرد به ازاء یک واحد افزایش در میزان دینداری، میزان استفاده از رسانه های جمعی، پایگاه اجتماعی اقتصادی و میزان تحصیلات جوانان میزان نوگرایی آن&amp;shy;ها در فرهنگ شهرنشینی 23%، 55%، 1/48% و 8/61% افزایش می&amp;rlm;یابد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The main focus of metropolitan modernity in a society that society. In order to evaluate the modernization individuals should be studied in the context of cities, because cities are constantly changing and evolving. The aim of this study was to investigate the factors influencing youth culture modernization is urbanization. The purpose of this study was functional, descriptive and correlational in nature and in terms of the survey. The research population consisted of all youth 29-15 years in Tehran. Based on Cochran formula, the sample size w&lt;a name=&quot;_GoBack&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;as determined 400 that were selected by random sampling. In order to collect data from a questionnaire containing 30 questions was used. Face and content validity of items with comments of experts for review, approval and were modified. Cronbach's alpha variables were also the top 0.7, which represents the internal consistency of the items and their reliability was acceptable. Data analysis using bivariate regression and application software were conducted. The results adjusted coefficient of determination showed that the variables of religiosity, the use of mass media, socio-economic status and education level of approximately 22%, 50%, 2/34% and 2/51% of the variability %, 1/48% and 8/61% increased. Standardized regression coefficients also revealed that for every one unit increase in religiosity, the use of mass media, socio-economic status and education level of young people in the urban culture of modernity that 23%, 55%, 1/48% and 8 / 61% increase.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>نوگرایی, جوانان, فرهنگ شهرنشینی, عوامل اجتماعی- اقتصادی, عوامل فرهنگی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>modernity, youth, urban culture, socioeconomic factors, cultural factors</keyword>
	<start_page>169</start_page>
	<end_page>178</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-776-12&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>غفار </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زارعی </last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846006132</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846006132</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کریمیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846006133</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846006133</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
