<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>50</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تدقیق و بازتعریف شاخصه‌های انسجام کالبدی- اجتماعی محله در مجموعه های مسکونی بلندمرتبه </title_fa>
	<title>Identify and redefine the indicators of physical and social coherence of neighborhoods in high-rise residential complexes </title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;شهر مجموعه&amp;shy;ای از عوامل زنده و پویاست که هویت بخشی به آن در طول زمان حادث شده و&amp;nbsp; به دوره&amp;shy;های بعدی انتقال می یابد. شهر در طول زمان رشد می کند و در کنش متقابل با شهروندان قرار می&amp;shy;گیرد و چهره شهر آیینه چهره شهروندان و مخلوق روح خلاق ساکنان می&amp;shy;شود. با آغاز دوره سرمایه داری و علی الخصوص در دو قرن اخیر و مطرح شدن موضوعاتی نظیر جهانی شدن، شکل تولید و سبک زندگی شهرنشینان تغییر کرده و تغییرات بافتی و تراکمی به معنای امروزی آن پدید آمد. در دهه های اخیر با تغییر مفهوم محتوایی شهر، ازدیاد جمعیت شهرها و طرح انتقادهایی بر گسترش بی رویه و توسعه کم تراکم شهرها، سیاست های بلندمرتبه سازی به عنوان راهکاری در رویکردهای نوین برنامه ریزی قرار گرفت. استفاده فراگیر از این روش، به تدریج افزون بر کاربری های اقتصادی مانند کاربری صنعتی، اداری و تجاری دامنگیر کاربری&amp;shy;های مسکونی نیز گشت و به مناطق پیرامونی شهر نیز گسترش یافت. از سویی دیگر در کشوری همچون ایران که دارای الگوی کهنی در زمینه معماری و شهرسازی است و شهر مجموعه ای از محله های متجانس و همگن است که بر اساس روابط مناسب، شکل و وابستگی های قومی، مذهبی، حرفه ای یا سرزمینی در مکان مشخص مجتمع شده و هدایت و اصالت خود را سال ها به همین صورت نگه داشتند؛ افزایش فعالیت های بلندمرتبه سازی در طی سال های اخیر دغدغه ها و نگرانی هایی را به وجود آورده است و این نگرانی ها می تواند تبدیل به مسائل جدی و حتی بحرانی شوند. هدف پژوهش حاضر ارتقاء و ایجاد انسجام اجتماعی در مجموعه های مسکونی بلند مرتبه با بهره گیری از عناصر استخوانبندی و ساختار کالبدی به عنوان بستری جهت پیاده سازی طراحی شهری مشارکت مبنا می باشد. با بررسی متون معماری و شهرسازی به نظر می رسد برخی از اهالی نظر معتقدند توسعه شهری زمان حاضر را نمی توان در ادامه شهرسازی و توسعه شهری گذشته دید؛ لیکن گروهی از متخصصین معاصر کوشیده اند از میراث معماری و شهرسازی گذشته در آثار خود بهره ببرند. داشتن پیوستگی و انسجام یکی از اصلی ترین معیارهای کیفیت فضاهای شهری محسوب می شود. فضاهای سنتی و بومی عمدتا واجد چنین کیفیتی بودند. درحال حاضر، هم از لحاظ عملی و هم از لحاظ نظری فضاهای شهری و علوم مرتبط با طراحی محیطی در این زمینه دچار چالش های اساسی هستند.روش این پژوهش از نوع کیفی است که رویکرد آن توصیفی و تحلیلی است. به لحاظ شیوه داده پردازی از تکنیک دلفی بهره جسته که مدل تحلیلی آن بر اساس وحدت رویه در نظرات خبرگان است. دستاورد مهم این پژوهش استخراج معیارهای انسجام کالبدی-اجتماعی محله ایرانی از منظر خبرگان و اولویت بندی این معیارها جهت پیاده سازی و بسترسازی شاخصه های انسجام اجتماعی و کالبدی با رویکرد طراحی شهری مشارکت مبنا در مجموعه های مسکونی بلند مرتبه است و ارتقاء مشارکت و وضعیت اجتماعی در این مجموعه هاست.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The city is a collection of living and dynamic elements whose identity has fluctuated over time and transmitted to later periods&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; The city grows over time and interacts with citizens, and the city's mirror image is the image of citizens and the creator of the creative spirit&lt;a name=&quot;_GoBack&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of the inhabitants. With the onset of capitalism, and especially over the last two centuries, and the emergence of issues such as globalization, the form of production and lifestyle of the urban population have changed, and tissue changes and congestion in its current form have emerged. In recent decades, changing the concept of city content, increasing urban populations, and criticizing the lack of development and the development of low density cities, high-profile policies have been planned as a strategy for new approaches. The widespread use of this method gradually extended to residential areas in addition to economic uses such as industrial, administrative and commercial use, and extended to peripheral areas of the city. On the other hand, in a country like Iran, which has an old pattern in the field of architecture and urbanization, and the city is a set of homogeneous and homogeneous neighborhoods that, based on the appropriate relationships, form and ethnic, religious, occupational or territorial affiliations in a specific place of the complex They have been keeping their guides and authenticity for years; the rise of high profile activities has raised concerns and concerns over the past years, and these concerns can become serious and even critical issues. The methodology of this research is qualitative and its approach is descriptive and analytical. The purpose of this research is to promote and create social cohesion in high-rise residential complexes utilizing osteopenia elements and physical structure as the basis for implementation of urban design of base participation. By reviewing the texts of architecture and urbanism, it seems that some people believe that urban development of the present cannot be seen in the past urbanization and development of the past, but a group of contemporary experts have tried to use the legacy of architecture and urban planning in their works. Consistency and coherence are considered as one of the main criteria for the quality of urban spaces. Traditional and indigenous spaces were mostly of such quality. Nowadays, both practical and theoretically, urban spaces and science related to environmental design are facing a major challenge. In terms of data processing, Delphi's technique is based on its analytical model based on procedural unity in experts' opinions. The main result of this research is the extraction of the socio-social coherence criteria of the Iranian neighborhood from the perspective of experts and prioritizing these criteria to implement and establish the indicators of social and physical coherence with the urban design approach of participatory basis in high-rise residential complexes and promotion of participation and social status in these collections.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>محله, انسجام اجتماعی و کالبدی, مجموعه های مسکونی بلندمرتبه</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Neighborhood, social and physical cohesion, high-rise residential complexes</keyword>
	<start_page>237</start_page>
	<end_page>256</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-81&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مصطفی </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بهزادفر</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008503</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008503</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهران </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>علی‌الحسابی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008504</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008504</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سمیه </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فتحی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008505</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008505</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
