<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>50</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>مصالح گزینی بر اساس سازگاری بومی- شخصیتی (درس آموخته هایی از معماری بومی ایران)</title_fa>
	<title>Choosing materials based on indigenous compatibility - personality (lessons of Iranian indigenous architecture)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;انتخاب مصالح از جمله چالش های مهم در معماری معاصر است. تا جایی که در ضوابط نماسازی بناهای امروزی محدودیتهایی برای انتخاب و بکارگیری آن در نظر گرفته شده است. ورود انواع مصالح به کشور نیاز به مبنای بومی-زیباشناختی آن را ضروری می سازد. چراکه در صورت غفلت از این موضوع چهره اصیل شهرها دچار اغتشاش روز افزون خواهد شد. پژوهش حاضر با بررسی مبانی بومشناختی و انطباق آن با تئوری های شخصیت شناسی سعی در کشف تفاوت های بومی-شخصیتی انتخاب و بکارگیری مصالح گوناگون دارد. سوال تحقیق را می توان چنین مطرح نمود: تفاوت بین شخصیت های گوناگون در انتخاب، فراوری و بکارگیری مصالح چیست و در بناهای منتخب چگونه نمود یافته است؟ از آنجاییکه تزئینات نیز به عنوان عاملی برای کشف تفاوت ها در بکارگیری مصالح اهمیت دارد به تفاوت شخصیت ها در انتخاب ساختار تزئینات نیز پرداخته شده است. روش تحقیق در ایجاد و ساختار بندی مبانی نظری، استدلال منطقی و در استنباط تفاوت بین مصالح و تزئینات منبعث از گوناگونی شخصیتهای بومی تفسیری می باشد. در این پژوهش براساس مبانی استدلالی، خشکی بوم موجب متفکر و قضاوت گر شدن، رطوبت موجب احساسی و ادراکی شدن، سرما موجب برون گرا شدن و گرما موجب درون گرا شدن شخصیت پایه می شود. درون گرایی شخصیت پایه موجب استفاده از مصالح طبیعی، ایجاد تمایز اندک بین ظاهر مصالح، استفاده از مصالح تک رنگ و عدم تمایل به مصالح شاخص کننده می شود. برونگرایی شخصیت پایه موجب استقبال از مصالح جدید، استفاده از مصالح با رنگ های متنوع یا اصلاح رنگ مصالح و ایجاد تمایز بین بخشهای مختلف بنا با تغییر در نوع یا چینش مصالح می گردد. متفکر بودن و قضاوت گری در شخصیت پایه موجب عدم ریسک پذیری در انتخاب مصالح، استفاده از مصالح بافت دار در کنار مصالح صیقلی، تمایل به نشان دادن ترتیب هندسی مصالح با ایجاد وضوح در مرز قطعات و بندکشی ها می شود. احساسی و ادراکی بودن شخصیت پایه موجب ریسک پذیری در استفاده از مصالح جدید، تمایل به اندود کاری روی سفت کاری، استفاده از مصالح طبیعی یا کمتر فراوری شده، استفاده از مصالح با تضاد کم در رنگ و بافت می گردد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The choice of materials is one of the major challenges in contemporary architecture. As far as the criteria of present buildings are present, limits are considered to choose and apply it. The arrival of various materials in the country requires the indigenous - aesthetic basis of it. For in case of neglect of this, the original face of the cities will grow more turbulent. This study examines the ecological basis and its adaptation to personality theories tries to explore local - personality differences and use different materials. The question of the research can be suggested: How is the difference between different personalities in choosing, processing and applying materials, and how did selected monuments find? Since the ornamentation is also important as a factor to explore the differences in the use of materials, the difference of personalities in the selection of ornamentation is also addressed. The method of research in the creation and structure of theoretic bases, logical reasoning, and in inferring the difference between material and ornamentation originated from the diversity of native characters. in this study , based on the basis of reasoning, the land of canvas causes the thinker, the moisture causes sensation and perception, the cold, and heat cause an introvert to become an introvert. Basic personality introspection is the use of natural materials, making a difference in the appearance of materials, the use of monochrome materials, and lack of interest in indexing materials. A basic personality Extraversion is a welcome to new materials, use of materials to diversify or modify materials color and make distinctions between different parts according to changes in type or arrangement of materials. to be thoughtful and judgment in the base personality causes uncertainty in the choice of materials, the use of textured materials on the side of the smooth materials, the tendency to show the geometrical arrangement of materials by making clarity on the boundary of parts and components. The perception of the basis of the basic personality causes risk taking in the use of new materials, the tendency of to work, the use of natural or less processed materials, the use of material with little contrast in color and texture.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>بوم شناسی فرهنگی, شخصیت پایه, مزاج شناسی, مصالح, تزئینات.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>cultural ecology, basic personality, materials, ornamentation. </keyword>
	<start_page>351</start_page>
	<end_page>372</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-87&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدرضا </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عطایی همدانی </last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008522</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008522</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>وحید </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>شالی امینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008523</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008523</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حمزه نژاد </last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008524</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008524</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ویدا </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نوروز برازجانی </last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008525</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008525</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
