<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>15</volume>
<number>44</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>خوشه بندی و رتبه بندی پیمانکاران با استفاده از مدل های خوشه بندی و ویکور (مطالعه موردی: مسکن مهر شهر جدید هشتگرد)</title_fa>
	<title>Clustering and ranking contractors using data mining algorithm and VIKOR (Case study: Mehr housing Hashtgerd New Town)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;مدیریت بر اجرای طرح های مسکن مهر که نیازمند سرعت عمل بسیار زیاد و در حجم گسترده است تنها با دریافت و پردازش صحیح و به موقع داده ها و اطلاعات قابل اعتماد محقق خواهد شد. برنامه ریزی های بلند مدت مدیران در تمامی سطوح پروژه های مسکن مهر که مسیر حرکت و نحوه ی عملکرد کلیه ی دست اندرکاران طرح مسکن مهر را تعیین می کند بر مبنای تحلیل داده های موجود انجام می شود. شرکت عمران شهر جدید هشتگرد به عنوان یکی از بزرگترین متولیان طرح مسکن مهر در سطح کشور است و بنابراین اعمال مدیریت صحیح بر اجرای پروژه ها در این شهر بسیار حیاتی می باشد. با توجه به اینکه بیش از 80 پروژه ی مسکن مهر در شهر جدید هشتگرد در حال اجرا می باشد و با عنایت به اینکه عقد تفاهم نامه ها و شروع کار بیشتر مجریان پروژه ها در یک فرصت زمانی اندک صورت گرفته است بنابراین کسب اطلاعات صحیح در خصوص پیمانکاران و پروژه ها جهت اعمال سیاست های بلند مدت و اتخاذ رویه های یکپارچه بسیار حیاتی می باشد. در این تحقیق، ابتدا داده های مناسب در خصوص این پیمانکاران جمع آوری گردید و سپس با استفاده از روش های تحلیل خوشه ای تلاش شد تا یک خوشه بندی مناسب از پیمانکاران انجام گیرد و با اعتبار سنجی از صحت نتایج بدست آمده اطمینان حاصل شد. در نهایت با بکارگیری روش ویکور رتبه بندی پیمانکاران انجام شد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 0cm 0cm 0pt; text-align: justify; unicode-bidi: embed; direction: ltr;&quot;&gt;&lt;span b=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;font-family:;&quot;&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;The construction management of Mehr Housing projects, which has an increasing volume and is required to high speed, can be appropriately possible just through receiving and processing the reliable data and information on the right time. Long-term programs, which have been made by managers and can determine the whole levels of Mehr Housing projects, their executive process and the people&amp;rsquo;s operation who are involved in Mehr Housing project, are entirely on the basis of existing data mining. Hashtgerd New Town Development Corporation is one of the most fundamental administrators of Mehr Housing project throughout the country and therefore, an efficient construction management is essential to execute the projects in this town. Considering the fact that more than 80 projects of Mehr Housing project are being executed in Hashtgerd New Town and regarding that the memoranda of understanding have been contracted and operated in a short time, assembling the appropriate information in the field of contractors and projects is fundamental to apply the long-term policies and coherent methods. To cluster the contractors of Mehr Housing projects in this research, firstly the required data has been collected with regard to these contractors and then they have been clustered through cluster analysis method. Correctness of achieved findings has been certified through validation methods. Finally, contractors have been ranked in every cluster by VIKOR as a multiple criteria decision-making method. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مسکن مهر, خوشه‌بندی, رتبه بندی, شهر جدید هشتگرد, ارزیابی پیمانکار.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword> Mehr Housing, Clustering, Ranking, Hashtgerd New Town, Contractor Evaluation</keyword>
	<start_page>535</start_page>
	<end_page>546</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-918-52&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نصراللهی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004770</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004770</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدمهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مظفری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004771</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004771</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
