<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>36</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>مشارکت الکترونیکی در برنامه‌ریزی ومدیریت محله‌ای</title_fa>
	<title>E-participation in neighborhoods management and planning</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
به‌ منظور توسعه محله‌محور مشارکتی در گستره‌های وسیع کنونی که ارتباطات رودررو برای تمامی افراد جامعه مقدور نیست، بهره‌مندی از پتانسیل ارتباطات الکترونیکی با هدف مشارکت در برنامه‌ریزی و مدیریت شهر، امکان سطح بالاتری از مشارکت، به علت افزایش میزان اطلاعات و تعداد مشارکت‌کنندگان در فرآیندها را به وجود می آورد. هدف از این پژوهش، طرح مفهوم مشارکت الکترونیکی و ارزیابی کاربرد آن در مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی محلات تهران و ارائه الگویی به‌منظور بهره‌مندی از مزایای فناوری‌های نوین ارتباطی در جهت تسهیل مشارکت عمومی است. در این پژوهش،  شیوه‌های گوناگون کاربرد این ابزار توسط شهروندان در محله هایی از شهر تهران بررسی شده و راهکارهایی برای ارتقای سطح مشارکت الکترونیکی ارائه گردیده است. علاوه بر این‌ها، یک پایگاه مشارکت تعاملی درسطح محله انقلاب واقع در منطقه 11 تهران طراحی شده است. 
تحقیق حاضر به لحاظ رویکرد، تحقیقی کیفی و از منظر هدف، تحقیقی کاربردی است و از مطالعات اسنادی، مشاهده، بررسی تجارب، مصاحبه و همچنین یادداشت‌های میدانی در 10 محله منتخب در شهر تهران به‌منظور بررسی امکانات موجود و فهم سطح تعامل الکترونیکی آنها با هدف ارتقای وضعیت کنونی بهره برده است. مطابق با یافته‌های پژوهش، سطح تعامل و امکانات مشارکت الکترونیکی محلات مورد بررسی، پایین‌ است و کلیه وبلاگها و وبسایت‌های مورد بررسی صرفاً در حد  اطلاع‌رسانی فعالیت می‌کنند. در طراحی پایگاه نمونه محله انقلاب بر دسترسی شهروندان به یک پایگاه مشارکتی همراه با امکانات بحث، نظردهی و سایر تسهیلات مشارکتی مورد تأکید قرار گرفته است. در کنار شناسایی محدودیت‌های ارتباط واقعی شهروندان و مسئولان و اجرای پیشنهادات ارائه شده در خصوص امکانات سطوح بالای مشارکت الکترونیکی می‌توان انتظار داشت استقبال ساکنان محلات از پایگاه‌های مشارکتی نیز افزایش یابد. 


</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
To obtain participatory community based development in recent major areas where face to face interactions are not available for all members of society, participation of ICT services in urban planning and management, offers a higher level of partnership due to increase in the amount of information and the quantity of partners in processes. This article is trying to propose an electronic participaation concept and evaluation of its applications in Tehran’s neighborhood management and planning. In addition, it attempts to introduce a pattern to derive benefit from advantages of novel communication technologies to facilitate public participation. 
In this research, various methods of applying these tools will be discussed and some solutions are suggested to promote the e-participation level of people along with designing an interactive website for Enghelab neighborhood (District 11) in Tehran. This inquiry has a qualitative approach and uses library research, field works, observational studies, interviews and will study existing experiments.
Based on research findings in selected neighborhoods, the interaction level and e-participation facilities have been evaluated inadequate. All under study and neighborhood related weblogs and websites have an informative role rather than two way interaction between neighborhood and residents. Thus, the goals and approaches for Enghelab Website are based on access to a participatory website with discussion forums and other participatory facilities. Along with identifying the real communication constraints among citizens and officials by implementing the suggestions in high levels of e-participation, it is expected that residents’ acceptance of participatory websites will be increased.

</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مشارکت, مشارکت الکترونیکی, برنامه‌ریزی, وبسایت, محله انقلاب</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>participation, Electronic participation, planning, website, Enghelab neighborhood</keyword>
	<start_page>203</start_page>
	<end_page>222</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-251-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Naser</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Barak Poor</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ناصر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>برک پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>barakpur@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001407</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001407</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Art University of Tehran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه هنر تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mona</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Bolookat</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مونا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بلوکات</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mona.boloukat@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001408</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001408</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Art University of Tehran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه هنر تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
