<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>29</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی ایجاد محدوده پیشنهادی طرح ترافیک شیراز از منظر ساکنین شهر</title_fa>
	<title>The Assessment of Proposed Traffic Control Zone of the City of Shiraz from Citizens’ Viewpoint</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>حمل و نقل و ترافیک یکی از مهمترین مشکلات شهرهای بزرگ و بخصوص شهرهای کشورهای در حال توسعه مانند ایران است. این مشکلات که خود را غالبا به صورت شلوغی و ازدحام وسایط نقلیه، افزایش زمان سفر، کاهش ایمنی و افزایش آلودگی هوا نشان می دهند، مدیران شهری را بر آن داشته تا از روشهای متعددی به منظور مدیریت و کنترل ترافیک استفاده نمایند.  ایجاد محدوده های طرح ترافیک یکی از سیاستها و روشهایی است که برخی از شهرهای بزرگ به منظور کاهش ترافیک در محدودهای مرکزی بکار گرفته اند. اخیرا با تصمیم شورایعالی ترافیک کشور چند شهر بزرگ ایران از جمله شیراز قرار است در آینده نزدیک طرح ترافیک را در محدوده مرکزی خود به اجرا در آوردند. این مقاله به بررسی نقطه نظرات مردم در خصوص اجرای محدوده طرح ترافیک پیشنهادی شهر شیراز می پردازد. در این مطالعه تلاش بر آن بوده تا اولا میزان مقبولیت و حمایت مردم ازمحدوده  طرح ترافیک و ثانیا عوامل موثر بر آن مورد مطالعه قرار گیرند. داده های این مطالعه با استفاده از پرسشنامه ای که به همین منظور طراحی گردید، از نمونه ای از مردم ساکن و شاغل در شهر شیراز جمع آوری شده است. نتایج این مطالعه نشان می دهند گرچه عوامل چندی بر این مساله تاثیر گذار می باشند، با این حال درصد بالایی از پرسش شوندگان با اجرای این طرح موافق می باشند. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Transport and urban traffic is one of the most essential problems facing the mega cities particularly in the developing countries like Iran. These problems often present themselves in the form of traffic congestion, lengthening of travel time, reduction of safety and increase in air pollution. Hence city managers were set to employ different methods to manage and control traffic. Establishing traffic control zone is one of the methods and policies used in some large city centers to reduce traffic flow. Recently with the decision of the State Traffic High Council it is expected that some major cities in Iran including Shiraz implement traffic control zone in near future. This article examines peoples’ opinion regarding implementation of traffic control zone in Shiraz. In this study effort has been focused first to the extent of popularity and support of people for traffic control zone and secondly identifying the influencing factors on it. Data for this study was collected through questionnaire specifically designed for this purpose from samples of residents and working people in Shiraz.  Even though several factors affect the results, this study shows that a high percentage of those questioned concurred with the implementation of this plan.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>حمل و نقل شهری، محدوده طرح ترافیک، مرکز شهر، شیراز ، روش کنترل ترافیک.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Urban transportation, traffic control zone, city center, Shiraz, traffic control method.</keyword>
	<start_page>165</start_page>
	<end_page>178</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-141-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Asgary</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عسگری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>asgary@yurk.ca</email>
	<code>1003194753284600300</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600300</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>York University, Toronto, Canada</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه یورک، تورنتو، کانادا</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Seyed Mehdi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Moini</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>معینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600301</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600301</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>York University, Toronto, Canada</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه یورک، تورنتو، کانادا</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Goli</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>گلی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600302</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600302</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Shiraz University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شیراز</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
