<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2013</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>31</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارزیابی وضعیت هوش سازمانی در شهرداری های شرق مازندران</title_fa>
	<title>Status Evaluation of Organizational Intelligence in the east municipalities of Mazandaran</title>
	<subject_fa>عمومى</subject_fa>
	<subject>General</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;هدف از این پژوهش بررسی وضعیت هوش سازمانی در مدیریت شهری شرق استان مازندران بوده است. طبق نظر آلبرخت هوش سازمانی استعداد و ظرفیت یک سازمان در حرکت بخشیدن به توانایی ذهنی سازمان و تمرکز این توانایی درجهت رسیدن به رسالت سازمان می باشد. مولفه های هوش سازمانی بر اساس مدل آلبرخت عبارتند از: 1. چشم انداز استراتژیک، 2. سرنوشت مشترک، 3. میل به تغییر، 4. روحیه، 5. اتحاد و توافق، 6. کاربرد دانش و 7. فشار عملکرد. روش پژوهش، توصیفی- پیمایشی و نمونه های تحقیق شامل 133 نفر از کارکنان ستاد اداری پنج شهرداری نکا، رستم کلا، بهشهر، خلیل شهر و گلوگاه بوده اند که به روش نمونه گیری گروهی انتخاب شدند. ابزار تحقیق پرسش نامه هوش سازمانی آلبرخت با ضریب پایایی آلفای کرونباخ 918/0 بوده است. نتایج اصلی پژوهش نشان داد که: 1. بر اساس آزمون t تک نمونه با فاصله اطمینان 95 درصد، میانگین وضعیت هوش سازمانی و مولفه های آن در حد مناسبی بوده است؛ 2.بر اساس آزمون فریدمن، بین رتبه میانگین حداقل دو مولفه از مولفه های هوش سازمانی تفاوت معناداری وجود داشته است. رتبه بندی میانگین ها بر اساس مولفه ها عبارت بودند از: 1.فشار عملکرد، 2. روحیه، 3. اتحاد و توافق، 4.سرنوشت مشترک، 5. کاربرد دانش، 6. میل به تغییر، 7. چشم انداز استراتژیک. در نهایت یافته های پژوهش ضرورت توجه بیشتر به بهبود مستمر مولفه های هوش سازمانی و توسعه همزمان و متوازن این مولفه ها را نمایان ساخت. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>The purpose of this research was to survey the organizational intelligence in the east urban management of Mazandaran province. According to Albrecht, Organizational intelligence is the capacity of an organization to mobilize all of its brain power, and focus that brain power on achieving the mission. Organizational intelligence components based on Albrecht’s model included: 1.strategic vision, 2.shared fate,3. Appetite for change,4.heart, 5.alignment and congruence,6.knowledge deployment and 7.performance pressure. The research method was descriptive-survey and research samples including 133 administrative staffs in five municipalities of Neka, Rostamkola, Behshahr, Khalilshahr and Galogah, that were selected through Stratified sampling.Research tool was Albrecht’s organizational intelligence questionnaire with 0.918 Cronbach,s alpha reliability coefficient. Main results of the research showed that: 1.According to One-sample t test with 95 percent confidence interval the organizational intelligence and its components were in acceptable condition2.Based on Freidman’s test, there was significant difference between mean rank of at least two components of organizational intelligence components. Means ranking based on the components included: 1.Performance pressure, 2.Heart, 3.Alignment and congruence, 4. Shared fate, 5.knowledge deployment, 6.Appetite for change, 7.Strategic vision finally, research findings showed necessity of more attention to components of organizational intelligence continuous improvement and simultaneous and balanced development of this components.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>هوش سازمانی، شهرداری، مدیریت شهری، مازندران.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Organizational Intelligence, Municipality, Urban Management, Mazandaran</keyword>
	<start_page>175</start_page>
	<end_page>188</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-66-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mehdi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Sattari Qahfarrokhi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ستاری قهفرخی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>:  msattarighahfarrokhi@pnu.ac.ir</email>
	<code>100319475328460069</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460069</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>PNU</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Zamanian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علیرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زمانیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460070</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460070</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>PNU</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه پیام نور</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
