<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2013</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>32</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بهبود سیستم مدیریت پسماند شهر تهران با تأکید بر دفع نهایی</title_fa>
	<title>Evaluation and leveled the Effective Components in Rural Tourism Marketing, with Marketing Mix (7P)(Case Study: selected Provinces in mazandaran)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;یکی از چالش انگیز ترین بخش‌های سیستم مدیریت پسماند بویژه در شهرهای بزرگ، انتخاب روش دفع نهایی پسماند است. هدف از انجام این پژوهش شناسایی روش بهینه دفع نهایی پسماند شهر تهران است. بدین منظور، تقدم و تأخر روش‌های دفع نهایی پیشنهادی پسماند شهر تهران، با ترکیب تکنیک‌های تصمیم‌گیری چند معیاره تحلیل سلسله مراتبی و تاپسیس فازی تعیین گردید. قیاس روش‌های دفن در زمین، تولید RDF، بازیافت مواد همراه با دفن بقایا در زمین، تولید کمپوست و سوزاندن بدون استحصال انرژی بعنوان گزینه‌های تصمیم‌گیری انتخاب و با بگارگیری 4 گروه معیار اصلی شامل اثرات زیست محیطی، جنبه‌های اقتصادی، امور اجتماعی و ملاحظات تکنولوژیکی و 14 زیر معیار با هم مقایسه و رتبه‌بندی شدند. مقادیر ضریب نزدیکی حاصل از اجرای تکنیک تاپسیس فازی نشان داد که گزینه بازیافت مواد و دفن بقایا در زمین با ضریب نزدیکی 237/0 روش بهینه دفع نهایی پسماند شهر تهران است. تولید کمپوست، تولیدRDF، دفن در زمین و سوزاندن بدون استحصال انرژی بترتیب با ضرایب نزدیکی 212/0، 207/0، 195/0 و 148/0 در رتبه‌های بعدی جای گرفتند. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;The purpose of this study is to evaluate the present and desired rural tourism in selected Provinces in mazandaran with marketing mix. In the present study, the under-investigation components of marketing mix consist of seven components (7P) of place, planning and management, evidences and physical facilities, publicity, people and staffs, price, and products. In line with this, field study and descriptive-analytic research method have been used, and the data has been collected according to researcher-made 48-question questionnaire in which the related items have been chosen regarding the features of geographical tourism. The staffs of Cultural Heritage and Tourism Organizations and Municipality were the sample and all of them have been tested from among the experts at this issue (N=90). The data analysis has been carried out by SPSS Software, and Mean Tests, Chi-Square, Wilcoxon and Friedman. To measure the significant difference between marketing mix items in two present and desired conditions by Wilcoxon test is an indication of the difference between the two compared conditions. Friedman test has been used for ranking the amount of effectiveness of components in the development of rural tourism and the results show the high importance of propaganda, people, and product components regarding the testable in having influence on the development of rural tourism in Babol, babolsar, mahmoodabad, and Sari provinces. Finally, it was found that the combination made of mixing the seven mentioned components with the significant level of 0/00 and the level of allowable error of 0/05 has the following capabilities firstly, it shows the present condition of rural tourism marketing in the region well. Secondly, it results in the promotion of the level of rural development through expanding rural tourism in the studied region. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>سیستم مدیریت پسماند، فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی، دفع نهایی پسماند، Fuzzy TOPSIS</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Rural Tourism, Marketing Mix (7P), Present and Desired Conditions, selected Provinces in mazandaran</keyword>
	<start_page>153</start_page>
	<end_page>162</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-89-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Vahed</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Dehqani Kazemi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>واحد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>دهقانی کاظمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Vdehghani@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600129</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600129</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده محیط زیست دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hamidreza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Jafari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حمیدرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>جعفری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600130</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600130</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده محیط زیست دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Zeinab</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Yaganekia</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>زینب</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>یگانه کیا</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600131</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600131</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده محیط زیست دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Esmail</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Salehi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>اسماعیل</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صالحی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600132</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600132</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده محیط زیست دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
