<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>48</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تدوین اصول و راهکارهای ارتقا امنیت پیاده‌راه ها در بافت تاریخی شهر رشت در جهت ارتقا کیفیت فضاهای شهری</title_fa>
	<title>Formulation of principles and strategies for improving the safety of pedestrians in the historical city of Rasht in order to improve the quality of urban spaces</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;یکی از مباحث اصلی در شهر ایجاد امنیت برای کلیه شهروندان است. این مهم ارتباط تنگاتنگی با کیفیت فضاهای شهری دارد به گونه ای که یکی از مولفه های اصلی سنجش کیفیت فضاها، بررسی میزان امنیت در آن ها است. میزان امنیت در بافت های تاریخی که در قلب مناطق متراکم شهرها واقع شده اند، اهمیت خاصی پیدا می&amp;shy;کند، چرا که کیفیت محیط زندگی بیشتر مردم در این مکانها سنجش می شود. هدف این تحقیق، تدوین اصول و راهکارهای ارتقا امنیت در پیاده&amp;shy;راه&amp;shy;ها در بافت های تاریخی می&amp;shy;باشد. این پژوهش از دارای نمونه موردی می باشد و شهر رشت و پیاده راه علم الهدی به همراه بافت تاریخی اطراف آن به عنوان نمونه انتخاب شده اند. روش تحقیق، توصیفی - تحلیلی بوده و جمع&amp;shy;آوری داده&amp;shy;ها، به روش کتابخانه&amp;shy;ای انجام شده است. در این پژوهش پس از شناخت و تحلیل ویژگی های شهر رشت و پیاده&amp;shy;راه علم الهدی، مولفه هایی در جهت ارتقا امنیت و ارتقا کیفیت فضاها در نظر گرفته شده است و در انتها راهکارهایی در&amp;nbsp; این زمینه&amp;shy;های مختلف خوانایی، تنوع، انعطاف پذیری، سرزندگی، نفوذپذیری، حس تعلق و ایمنی در ارتباط با ارتقا امنیت پیشنهاد گردیده است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;One of the main issues in the city is to create security for all citizens. This important relationship is closely related to the quality of urban spaces, so that one of the main components of measuring the quality of the spaces is to check the level of security in them. The level of security in the historical context, which is located in the heart of the densely populated cities, is of particular importance because the quality of the living environment of most people is measured in these places. The purpose of this research is to develop principles and strategies for improving the safety of pedestrians in historical textures. This research is a case study. The city of Rasht and the pedestal of Alam-al-Hoddi road along with the surrounding historical texture were selected as sample. The research method was descriptive-analytic and data collection was done in the form of a library. In this research, after Recognizing and analyzing the characteristics of Rasht city and the pedestrian of Al-Hoda, are considered as components for promoting security and improving the quality of the spaces. At the end, solutions in various fields of readability, diversity, flexibility, vitality, permeability The sense of belonging and safety in relation to the promotion of safety is proposed.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa> امنیت, کیفیت, بافت های تاریخی, پیاده راه, کیفیت فضاهای شهری.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Security, Quality, Historical Texture, Walkway, Quality of Urban Spaces</keyword>
	<start_page>205</start_page>
	<end_page>222</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-48&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>الهام</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>پورمهابادیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008196</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008196</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>احمدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008197</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008197</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید یوسف</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>امیری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008198</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008198</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
