<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>35</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارزیابی توزیع فضایی و مکانیابی درمانگاه های شهری با استفاده از مدل NETWORK ANALYST (نمونه موردی: شهر زنجان)</title_fa>
	<title>The Evaluation of Spatial distribution and allocation of urban medical centers using Network Analyst Model (A case study Zanjan city)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>امروزه یکی از مهمترین مسائل که میتواند به بهبود وضع شهرها و دسترسی مناسب ساکنین شهرها به خدمات را فراهم آورد توزیع مناسب خدمات شهری میباشد. یکی از مهترین خدمات که توزیع مناسب آن علاوه بر کاهش مشکلات و معضلات شهرها (ترافیک شهری و ...) به سلامتی ساکنین شهرها نیز کمک میکند دسترسی مناسب به مراکز درمانی میباشد. بایستی خدمات درمانی به گونه ای در شهرها توزیع شود که در کمترین زمان ممکن جمعیت ساکن در شهر به این کاربری دسترسی داشته باشند بنابراین توزیع مناسب این کاربری در سطح شهرها در جهت دسترسی مناسب ساکنین شهرها امری ضروری می‌باشد. در این پژوهش با استفاده از مدل Network Analyst به ارزیابی توزیع فضایی درمانگاههای شهری زنجان  و همچنین با استفاده از مدل تحلیلی سلسله مراتبی (AHP) به مکانیابی مراکز درمانگاهی جدید اقدام شده است. هدف از این پژوهش شناسایی محدوده‌های شهری زنجان که کم‌ترین دسترسی به درمانگاههای شهری را داشته و ارائه مکانهای پیشنهادی جهت ایجاد درمانگاههای شهری جدید می‌باشد. نتایج تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که قسمت‌های شمال غرب و شمال شرق شهر زنجان که اکثراً در دو دهه اخیر ساخته شده‌اند، کم‌ترین دسترسی به درمانگاههای شهری را دارا میباشند و در حدود 76242 نفر در شهر زنجان دسترسی مناسبی به این مراکز درمانی ندارند. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Today one of the most important issues that could improve access for residents of cities and towns to provide services are utilities distribution. One of the most important services in addition to the proper distribution of reduction of urban problems (traffic, etc.) will also help to urban residents health are convenient access to medical care. Healthcare service should be distributed in such a way that the urban population in the shortest possible time have access to this services therefore suitable distribution of these service in urban areas is essential for convenient access to urban residents. In this study, using a Network Analyst to assess the spatial distribution of urban healthcare centers in the Zanjan city has been evaluated and then using analytical hierarchy process (AHP) has been attempting to allocation of new medical centers. The aim of this study was to identify of limitations accessibility to urban medical centers in Zanjan city and then offer suggestions for places to build new urban medical centers. The results showed that North West and North East parts of the city of Zanjan, mostly built in the past two decades, have less access to urban medical centers And about 76,242 people in the city of Zanjan has not convenient access to medical Centers.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>توزیع فضایی, درمانگاههای شهری, شهر زنجان, مدل Network Analyst. </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Spatial Distribution, Urban medical centers, Zanjan, Network Analyst, AHP </keyword>
	<start_page>167</start_page>
	<end_page>180</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-24-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Rahim</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Gholamhosseini</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رحیم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>غلامحسینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>r.gholamhosseini@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001723</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001723</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>zanjan university</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه زنجان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohsen</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>ahadnejad</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>احدنژاد روشتی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ahadnejad@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001724</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001724</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>zanjan university</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه زنجان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>zolfi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زلفی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>alizolfi1365@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001725</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001725</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>zanjan university</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه زنجان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
