<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>37</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>کاهش خطرات زلزله با تاکید بر عوامل اجتماعی رویکرد تاب آوری (نمونه موردی منطقه 22 تهران)</title_fa>
	<title>Risk Reduction of Earthquake with Emphasis on Social Factors of Resilience (Case Study: District 22 of Tehran)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>مخاطرات طبیعی به دلیل شدت و زمان کوتاه اثرگذاری بر اجتماعات بشری تبدیل به یکی از دغدغه‌های اصلی برنامه‌ریزان و مدیران شهری در سال‌های اخیر شده‌اند، سهم کشور ما از این مخاطرات بیشتر مربوط به زلزله است.در زمان وقوع زلزله، ساعات و دقایق اولیه بعد از وقوع بسیار پراهمیت است، به همین منظور تقویت اجتماع ساکن در یک محیط نقشی تاثیرگذار در کاهش خطرات دارد و این مهم تنها از طریق آموزش، آمادگی و پذیرش شرایط پس از بحران، از سوی شهروندان به‌دست می‌آید. تاب‌آوری، به عنوان رویکرد و روشی مناسب در جهت کاهش خطرات حاصل از بحران‌ها و مخاطرات، به عنوان رویکرد پژوهش حاضر انتخاب شده‌است. هدف اصلی این پژوهش پس از معرفی تاب‌آوری و شناسایی ابعاد مختلف آن، و نیز معرفی شاخص‌های بعد اجتماعی این رویکرد، ارائه راهبردهای کاهش خطرات زلزله با تاکید بر عوامل اجتماعی رویکرد تاب آوری در منطقه 22 تهراناست. در این تحقیق، پس از تعیین شاخص‌های اجتماعی تاثیرگذار بر تاب‌آوری منطقه ٢٢،  با استفاده از داده‌های سرشماری سال 90، مصاحبه با مسئولان ذیربط و توزیع پرسشنامه میان 96 نفر از ساکنان به بررسی وضعیت این شاخص‌ها در منطقه 22 تهران پرداخته شده‌است. در تحلیل اطلاعات نیز توامان از روش‌های کمی و کیفی استفاده شده‌است. با توجه به تحلیل داده‌ها از طریق نرم‌افزار SPSS و نیز تحلیل محتوای مصاحبه‌های صورت گرفته، نتایج این پژوهش بیانگر وضعیت نسبتا مطلوب شاخص‌های سن، سطح آموزش، دلبستگی به مکان در سطح منطقه و وجود برنامه‌هایی برای بهبود وضعیت مشارکت، اطلاع‌رسانی مخاطرات، درک و دانش عمومی از خطر است. با این وجود همچنان شاخص‌هایی نظیر نحوه نگرش ساکنان به مقوله خطر و وضعیت گروه‌های خاص به توجه بیشتری نیاز دارند. بر این اساس راهبردهایی برای تقویت وضعیت فعلی و تاب‌آور ساختن منطقه از لحاظ اجتماعی در برابر زلزله ارائه شده‌است.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Natural hazards because of the severity and impact on communities in short time, have become one of the main concerns of planners and city managers in recent years, and we should notice that the earthquake is the most probable and destroyer hazard in our country. At the time of the earthquake, the first minutes and hours after the fact is extremely important, therefore strengthening the communities have a greater role in reducing risks, and this is accomplished only through education, preparation and adoption of the disaster, which should be achieved on behalf of the citizens. Resilience as a good way to reduce risks resulting from hazards and disasters, is selected as the research approach. Having introduced the resilience and identification of its dimensions, and social factors of approach, some strategies are provided for reducing earthquake risks with an emphasis on social factors resiliency in District 22 of Tehran in this paper. Therefore, after the choice of social indicators which affects on resiliency of District 22, with census data of 1390, interviews conducted officials and questionnaires distributed among 96 residents to check the status of the index in this area are discussed. According to data analysis through SPSS software and content analysis of the interviews that conducted, the results of this study demonstrated adequate situation of  indicators such as age, education level, attachment to place in the region and also it represents that there are plans for improvement of  public participation and dissemination of hazards information, understanding and knowledge of risk, although indicators such as residents' attitude to risk and  situation of specific groups  needs more attention. Based on the current situation, some strategies are provided in order to strengthen the resiliency of District22.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>تاب‌آوری, زلزله,  بعد اجتماعی, منطقه 22 تهران</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>District 22 of Tehran,Resilience, Social factors, Earth quake</keyword>
	<start_page>19</start_page>
	<end_page>34</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-253-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>sara</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Nikmard Namin</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سارا </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نیکمردنمین</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>s.nikmard@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001553</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001553</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Art</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>کرج. خیابان شهید بهشتی. خیابان شهید رجایی.کوچه چهارم. پلاک 21- کد پستی:35459-31976</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>naser</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>barakpur</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ناصر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>برک‌پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>barakpur@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001554</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001554</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Art</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه هنر-دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>majid</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>abdollahi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مجید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عبداللهی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>abdollahi647@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001555</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001555</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
