<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>28</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>سنجش ذهنی قابلیت پیاده مداری و مولّفه‌های تأثیرگذار بر آن در محلات؛ مطالعه موردی: محله چیذر </title_fa>
	<title>Perceptual measurement of neighborhood walk ability and its influential factors in neighborhoods (Case study: Chizar neighborhood)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;افزایش قابلیت پیاده مداری با توجه به منافع محیط زیستی، اجتماعی- فرهنگی، اقتصادی، ادراک محیطی و ارتقاء ایمنی و امنیتی که دارد، به موضوعی کلیدی در مباحث شهرسازی تبدیل شده است. لذا در این میان درک شاخص‌های تأثیرگذار بر قابلیت پیاده مداری شهرها و محلات از اهمیت خاصی برخوردار گشته است. هدف خاص این تحقیق درک مولّفه‌های تأثیرگذار در پیاده مداری محله از منظر ساکنین است. بدین ترتیب با سنجش تناوب پیاده روی هفتگی و خوشایندی آن به عنوان معیار‌های پیاده مداری محله (متغیر وابسته) و ارتباط آنها با ویژگی‌های محیطی (متغیر مستقل)، مولّفه‌های تأثیر گذار بر قابلیت پیاده مداری شناسایی می‌گردد. استخراج روابط با تکنیک پرسش‌گری از 200 ساکنِ محله چیذر بوده است. تحلیل روابط و مدلسازی توسط آزمون‌های همبستگی، تحلیل عاملی و رگرسیون خطی انجام پذیرفته است. برخلاف انتظار، رابطه‌ای بین تناوب و خوشایندی پیاده روی دیده نشد و ویژگی‌های تأثیرگذار بر این دو نیز متفاوت بود. بررسی هدف از پیاده روی به عنوان عامل مداخله گر تأثیر مهمی بر یافته-های تحقیق دارد. به گونه‌ای که نشان داد تناوب پیاده روی با تردد اجباری و خوشایندی با تردد اختیاری دارای رابطه معنی دار است. بررسی ویژگی‌های محیطی تأثیر گذار نشان می‌دهد که ویژگی‌های کالبدی، ترافیکی و شبکه راه‌ها بر تناوب پیاده روی موثرند. در حالیکه کیفیت‌های محیطی محله و ابعاد اجتماعی آن نقش بسزایی در خوشایندی پیاده روی دارند. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Walk ability has become one of the major concerns in urban planning, in recent years. Increasing walk ability is considered as a solution for many environmental problems such as global warming, air and noise pollution, dependence on fossil fuel, and mental and physical health of urban residents as well as improving the quality of urban spaces. The aim of this research is to understand the factors affecting neighborhood walk ability for residents. As criteria for neighborhood walk ability (dependant variable) and its relation with environmental characteristics (independent variable) the related walk ability criteria are recognized. Relationships were identified using data gathered from about 200 questionnaires filled by the Chizar neighborhood residents. Relationship analysis and modeling are conducted thorough correlation analysis, factor analysis and linear regression analysis. The findings of the study show that despite expectation, there was not any relationship between walking frequency and walking pleasantness the characteristics influencing these were also different. Considering the purpose of walking as an intervening variable, it was found that walking frequency is highly correlated with necessary activity and walking measurement is highly correlated with optional activity. Examining the environmental characteristics shows that the physical characteristics, traffic levels and road networks influence walking frequency. While neighborhood environmental quality and its social dimension highly contribute to walking pleasantness. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>قابلیت پیاده مداری، سنجش ذهنی، تحلیل عاملی، رگرسیون خطی، محله چیذر</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Walk ability, perceptual measurement, factor analysis, linear regression, Chizar neighborhood.</keyword>
	<start_page>297</start_page>
	<end_page>312</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-126-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Razieh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Reza Zadeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>راضیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رضا زاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600262</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600262</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Esfandiar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Zebardast</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>اسفندیار</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زبردست</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600263</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600263</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Urban College of Fine Arts, Tehran University campus</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده شهرسازی پردیس هنرهای زیبا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Laleh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Latifi Oskooi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>لاله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>لطیفی اسکویی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>latifi_urb86@arch.iust.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600264</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600264</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
