<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2019</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>53</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی و مدلسازی تغییرات کاربری زمین شهر خرم آباد تا سال 1404 با استفاده از مدل های
MLP، MARKOV و CA-MARCOV  </title_fa>
	<title>Investigation and modeling of land use changes in Khorramabad city by 1404 using MLP, MARKOV and CA-MARCOV models</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی و مدلسازی تغییرات کاربری زمین شهر خرم&amp;shy;آباد است. بدین منظور&amp;nbsp; با استفاده از سه تصویر ماهواره لندست سال&amp;shy;های 1365، 1380 و 1395 طبقات پوشش و کاربری زمین شهر خرم آباد و اطراف آن استخراج شده است. صحت کلی طبقه بندی برای تصویر مربوط به سال 1365، 93/89، سال 1380، 34/91 و سال 1395، 62/95 درصد به دست آمده است. به منظور مدلسازی تغییرات کاربری زمین شهر خرم آباد از لایه های ورودی ارتفاع، شیب، سایه روشن، فاصله از جاده، فاصله از اراضی ساخته شده، فاصله از اراضی کشاورزی، فاصله از اراضی جنگلی تنک و فاصله از اراضی کوهستانی استفاده شد. در ادامه از مدل های شبکه عصبی و &lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;CA-MARKOV&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; برای مدلسازی و پیش&amp;shy;بینی تغییرات کاربری زمین تا سال 1404 استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان دهنده این است که مدلسازی تغییرات کاربری زمین شهر خرم آباد با دقت بالای 65 درصد صورت گرفته است. لازم به ذکر است که این مقدار دقت برای پیش بینی و مدلسازی تغییرات کاربری زمین که پویا می باشد منطقی و مناسب می&amp;shy;باشد؛ چرا که علاوه بر متغیرهای که در این پژوهش و سایر پژوهش ها در نظر گرفته می شود عوامل دیگری مانند قوانین&amp;nbsp; مقررات شهرداری، بورس بازی زمین، سیاست&amp;shy;های کلان دولتی در امر مسکن و غیره در تغییرات کاربری/ پوشش زمین تاثیرگذار خواهد بود.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this study was to survey and model the land use change in Khorramabad city. For this purpose, using three Landsat satellite images of years 1986, 2001 and 2016, the cover and land cover classes have been extracted from Khorramabad city and around it. Overall classification accuracy for image corresponding to the year 1365, 93/89, 1380, and 34/91 of 1395, 62/95 percent is obtained. In order to model the land use changes in Khorramabad, the input layers of elevation, slope, shadow, distance from the road, distance from the built area, distance from the agricultural land, distance from the forestland and the distance from the mountainous terrain were used. In the following, neural network models and CA-MARKOV are used to model and predict land use changes by the year 1404. The results show a high accuracy of 65% for modeling land use change in Khorramabad city. It should be noted that this precision is reasonable for predicting and modeling land-use changes that is dynamic, because in addition to the variables considered in this research and other studies, other factors such as municipal regulations, The land stock exchange, state-owned large-scale housing policies, and so on, will have an impact on land use change.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa></keyword_fa>
	<keyword></keyword>
	<start_page>351</start_page>
	<end_page>368</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-2486-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>فیروز</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>دولت آبادی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846009330</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846009330</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>نبی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مرادپور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846009331</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846009331</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
