<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>34</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>کاربرد نظام زیبایی شناسی برگرفته از قرآن کریم در طراحی شهری</title_fa>
	<title>Application of Holy Quran aesthetic aspects in urban designing</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
هدف پژوهش امکان به کارگیری معانی و مفاهیم زیبایی شناسی قران کریم در طراحی شهری است. روش تحقیق مبتنی بر تحلیل متن قرآن کریم با محوریت تفاسیر موجود بوده است. با مطالعه دقیق معانی و مفاهیم زیبایی شناسی متن قرآن کریم در سه محور کلی واژگان و سامانه ها و نشانه ها؛ کاربرد آنها در طراحی شهری مورد پیشنهاد قرار گرفته است. واژگان مرتبط با زیبایی به کاررفته در متن قرآن کریم مشتمل بر پنج محور و دوازده واژه؛ سامانه های زیبایی مطرح شده در قرآن کریم در سه محور و دوازده سامانه؛ نشانه های زیبایی به کار رفته در قرآن کریم در بیست و یک محور؛ به شیوه تحلیل متن مورد بررسی قرار گرفته و به تناسب هر کدام پیشنهاداتی برای طراحی شهری ارائه گشته است. به کارگیری معانی و مفاهیم زیبایی شناسی قرآنی در فضاهای شهری، علاوه بر حس زیبایی شناسی منبعث از مفاهیم اسلامی در فضاهای زیستی شهری؛ سبب توجه و بازگشت به نظام ارزشی منطبق با هویت اسلامی در شهرسازی خواهد گردید. نتایج تحقیق بیانگر پتانسیل کاربردی معانی و مفاهیم زیبایی شناسی قرآن کریم در طراحی شهری است که در پژوهش تحت عنوان «نظام زیبایی شناسی طراحی شهری مبتنی بر قرآن کریم»، نام برده شده است.
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
The research aims to investigate feasibility of application of Holy Quran aesthetic concepts and aspects in urban designing. The research methodology is based on analysis of Quran and interpretations. By studying the aesthetic concepts and aspects in Quran in three categories of terms, semiotics and systems it is recommended to use these concepts in urban designing. Vocabularies and terms related to aesthetics are mentioned in Quran in five categories involving twelve vocabularies Quran aesthetic systems consist of three categories and twelve systems semiotics involve twenty one categories that they have been investigated as text analysis and propositions have been offered for urban designing accordingly. Application of Quran aesthetic concepts and aspects in urban spaces creates aesthetic feeling resulted from Islamic concepts in urban spaces and also it regenerates value systems based on Islamic identity in urban building. The results of this research indicate potential of application of Quran aesthetic concepts in urban designing that is investigated as “urban designing aesthetics based on holy Quran” in this research.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>زیبایی شناسی, قرآن کریم, نظام زیبایی شناسی مبتنی بر قرآن کریم, طراحی شهری, شهرسازی اسلامی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>aesthetics, Quran, Quran based aesthetics discipline, urban design, and Islamic urban design </keyword>
	<start_page>335</start_page>
	<end_page>358</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-772-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Hasan</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Sattari Sarbanqoli</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ستاری ساربانقلی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>sattari@iaut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846002120</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002120</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تبریز</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
