<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>48</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>دیدگاه هنری ـ جغرافیایی سهراب سپهری به مقوله شهر و معماری</title_fa>
	<title>Geographical view of Sohrab Sepehri in the category of city and architecture</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;اثر ادبی همواره، کانون بازتاب شهرها و فضای بیرون بوده است. در قرن حاضر، با توجه به مسائلی همچون جنگ، استعمار، ویرانی فضاهای شهری و بسیاری عوامل دیگر، شهر به عنوان رکن اصلی فضای زیست بشر، کانون توجه قرار می گیرد.&amp;nbsp; نویسندگان هریک به شیوه خود، تصاویری گاه واقعی و گاه تخیلی از شهرها را در اثر خویش خلق کرده&amp;shy;اند. از میان نویسندگانی که به توصیف مکان ها و شهرها پرداخته اند، سهراب سپهری، شاعر و نقاش چیره&amp;shy;دست، نمونه&amp;shy;ای بارز است. تعامل ادبیات و فضا سبب شکل&amp;shy;گیری نقد نوین جغرافیایی شده است. در نقد جغرافیایی، طبق اصل ارجاعیت، اثر ادبی با دنیای بیرون در تعامل است. تاثیر جهان بیرونی بر اثر ادبی یک سویه نیست؛ بلکه این تاثیر متقابل و پویا است. بدین ترتیب نه تنها دنیای بیرون بر اثر ادبی اثر می&amp;shy;گذارد؛ بلکه اثر ادبی نیز تصویری از فضای واقعی و بیرونی به مخاطب می دهد به عبارتی اثر ادبی بر درک متقابل فضای بیرونی تاثیرگذار است. در مقاله حاضر سعی بر آن است شهر و مکان در شعر سهراب سپهری مورد بررسی قرار گیرد. همچنین تلاش خواهد شد با بهره گیری از نقد جغرافیایی به عنوان روش تحقیق نوین در مطالعه فضاهای شهری، به تاثیر شهر بر شعر سهراب پرداخته شود و اینکه شهر در اثر ادبی به چه شیوه ای بازنمایی می&amp;shy;شود. درنهایت، به این پرسش کلی پاسخ داده خواهد شد. منظور از کنش متقابل شهر&amp;nbsp; و شعر نزد سهراب سپهری چیست.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Literary work has always been the focal point of reflection of cities and outer space. In the present century, with regard to issues such as war, colonialism, the destruction of urban spaces and many other factors, the city as the main pillar of the biological environment is the focus. Each author, in his own way, has created real and sometimes imaginative images of cities in his own way. Among the writers who describe the places and cities, Sohrab Sepehri, the poet and painter who is dominant, is a clear example. The interaction of literature and space has led to the formation of a new geographical critique. In geographical critique, according to the principle of referral, literary work is interacting with the outside world. The effect of the external world is not one-sided literary, but a mutual and dynamic effect. Thus, not only the outside world influences literary affairs, but literary work also gives a picture of the real and the external realm. In other words, literary influence affects the mutual understanding of outer space. In this article, we try to investigate city and place in poetry of Sohrab Sepehri. Also, it will try to use geographic criticism as a new research method in the study of urban spaces, to influence the city on Sohrab poetry and how the city is represented in literary form. Finally, this general question will be answered. What is meant by the interaction of the city and poetry with Sohrab Sepehri.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شهر, شعر, نقد جغرافیایی, ارجاعیت, سهراب سپهری.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>City, Poetry, Geographic Criticism, Referral, Sohrab Sepehri.</keyword>
	<start_page>433</start_page>
	<end_page>444</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-61&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کریمی فیروزجائی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007872</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007872</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>یوسف</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عالی عباس‌آباد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007873</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007873</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سمیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رستمی پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007874</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007874</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
