<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>34</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی و تحلیل عملکرد مدیریت شهری از منظر مشارکت محلی و شهروندمداری؛ مورد: شهر بابلسر</title_fa>
	<title>The analytical performance of urban management the valve of local participation citizen-based (case study: Babolsar city)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>با رشد شهرنشینی، ایجاد و توسعه ‌شهرها و تاثیرات مختلف آن بر جوامع شهرنشین لزوم توجه به برنامه‌ریزی مشارکتی، جهت استفاده از مسئولیت‌پذیری، مشارکت شهروندان، عدالت و حقوق شهروندی و پاسخ‌گویی به شهروندان، جهت توانمندسازیِ عملکرد مدیریت شهری، اهمیتی دوچندان می‌یابد. بنابراین از آنجایی‌که مدیریت شهری، ارتباط تنگاتنگی با جامعه شهری، شهروندمداری، تقویت مشارکت شهروندی و توجه به خواست و نظر شهروندان در اداره امور محلی و شهری دارد، مطالعه در این زمینه می‌تواند از اهمیت بسیاری برخوردار باشد. با این مقدمه، پژوهش حاضر نیز با علم به اهمیت مقوله شهروندمداری و موضوعات پیرامون مدیریت شهری و محلی، به بررسی این مهم در یکی از شهرهای شمالی ایران پرداخته است. پژوهش حاضر در شهر بابلسر به عنوان محدوده پژوهش، از لحاظ هدف، کاربردی، از لحاظ میزان و درجه کنترل متغیرها، میدانی و از لحاظ نحوه پردازش اطلاعات نیز از نوع تحقیقات توصیفی- همبستگی می‌باشد. روش مطالعه استفاده شده نیز اسنادی- تحلیلی و پیمایشی بوده که با هدف بررسی عملکرد مدیریت‌شهری از دریچۀ مشارکت محلی و شهروندمداری به بررسی مقوله آرمان مشارکت محلی و شهروندمداری در شهر مذکور پرداخته است. نتایج این مطالعه که بااستفاده از  ابزارهای نرم‌افزاریی مانند ArcGIS، SPSS و همچنین آزمون‌های آماری تحلیل واریانس یکطرفه (ANOVA)، کندال و پیرسون می‌باشد حاکی از آن است که وضعیت نواحی شهر بابلسر از منظر شهر شهروندمدار نتایج چندان مطلوبی ندارد؛ بطوری‌که این موضوع نشانگر آن است که شهر بابلسر بر اساس اصول شهروندمداری اداره نمی‌شود و اغلب شهروندان و نیز مدیران شهری آمادگی و زمینه ذهنی لازم برای درک شهر شهروندمدار را نیافته‌اند.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>With Growing urbanization, the creation and development of the city and its diffrent  impact on urban communities the need for participatory planning is most importance for  use of accountability, citizen, participation, rights and justice of civil, and accountability to citizens to empower urban management performance. Therefore as far as urban management, is associated with urban society, citizen-based, strengthen citizen participation and Attention to the request of the citizens for  manage local and urban governance, study in this context can be is important. With this interpretation, the present paper also with Knowing the importance of citizen-based and subjects surrounding urban and local management has been study on one of the northern cities of Iran.this present paper in Bobolsar as the case study, is applications in term of aim, this is field in term of the amount and grade of control variables and the data processing method of the study is descriptive – correlation. Method  was used to study has been documents - analysis that aimed to survey  the analytical performance of urban management the valve of  local participation and citizen-based has been  investigated the goal of local participation and citizen-based in this city.The results of the study by using the software ArcGIS, SPSS and statistical analysis of variance (ANOVA), and Pearson , Kendall, is expressing that Babolsar does not have ideal conditions in terms of citizen-based. So it shows that it is not handle by the principles of citizen-based and most of citizens and also city managers haven,t mental preparation and background necessary to understand the citizen-based city.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مدیریت شهری, شهرِ شهروندمدار, مشارکت شهروندی, شهر بابلسر.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>urban management, citizen-based city, citizen, participation, Babolsar city</keyword>
	<start_page>221</start_page>
	<end_page>236</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-367-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Taqi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rahnamaee</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدتقی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رهنمایی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002104</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002104</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mahdi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مهدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ali_mah7@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002105</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002105</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Masoomeh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mahdian Bahnamiri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>معصومه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مهدیان بهنمیری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002106</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002106</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه گلستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
