<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>15</volume>
<number>44</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارائه چهارچوب نظری مناسب ساختار فضایی بنادر و مناطق پسکرانه‌ای بر مبنای روش تحلیل‌محتوا </title_fa>
	<title>Explaining the Conceptual Model of Interactions among Ports and Their Hinterlands: A Study by Content Analysis Method</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;بنادر را می&amp;shy;توان دروازه&amp;shy;های اصلی ورود و خروج جریان&amp;shy;های فضایی برشمرد. این کانون&amp;shy;های فعالیتی، درصورتیکه بتوانند پیوند مناسبی با ساختار فضایی مناطق درون&amp;shy;سرزمینی ایجاد کنند، نه تنها می&amp;shy;توانند جریان های توزیع کالا را به خوبی هدایت کنند، بلکه نقش موثری در توسعه نواحی پسکرانه&amp;shy;ای خواهند داشت. در این میان، تمرکز و تاکید بر مولفه&amp;shy;های ساختار فضایی، می&amp;shy;تواند موجب رونق تعامل بنادر با قطب&amp;shy;ها و توسعه پسکرانه&amp;shy;های درون&amp;shy;سرزمینی شود. هدف از این پژوهش، شناسایی مولفه&amp;shy;های ساختار فضایی و تدوین یک چارچوب نظری مناسب از دیدگاه &amp;shy;های مطرح پیرامون ساختار فضایی بنادر- پسکرانه بر مبنای روش تحلیل&amp;shy;محتوا است. یافته&amp;shy;های پژوهش نشان می&amp;shy;دهد از میان مجموعه نظریه های ساختارفضایی، شش مولفه قابل شناسایی است که عبارتند از: قلمرو، کانون، محور ارتباطی، سازمان&amp;shy;یابی سطوح، تعامل و انتظام. با تلفیق هرکدام از این مولفه&amp;shy;ها، ابعاد جدیدی از ساختار فضایی سرزمین روشن می&amp;shy;شود که شامل تحرک فضایی، کاربری فضایی و فرم فضایی خواهد بود. تحرک فضایی بر مبنای پیوندها و روابط میان اجتماعات انسانی و کاربری فضایی بر مبنای فعالیت&amp;shy;های انسانی و زمین شکل می&amp;shy;گیرد. فرم فضایی نیز حاصل برهم کنش این دو بُعد در پهنه سرزمین است که در مقیاس&amp;shy;های مختلف به صورت پنهان یا آشکار نمایان می&amp;shy;شود. وجود مولفه انتظام آشکار و برنامه&amp;shy;ریزی&amp;shy;شده در ساختار فضایی یک منطقه، خود عاملی در تبیین بُعد جدیدی تحت عنوان پشتیبانی فضایی است. در حقیقت این بُعد مشخص&amp;shy;کننده تفاوت در ساختار فضایی یک منطقه درون&amp;shy;سرزمینی با ساختار فضایی بندر- پسکرانه است. وجود فضاهای پشتیبان در مناطق پسکرانه بندرگاهی، بر اساس تصمیم&amp;shy;سازی برنامه&amp;shy;ریزان فضایی و تصمیم&amp;shy;گیری سیاست&amp;shy;مداران، می&amp;shy;تواند زمینه لازم را برای ورود فضاهای جغرافیایی کمتر توسعه یافته به چرخه انطباق ساختار فضایی مهیا کند. در این حالت چهارچوب نظری جدیدی تحت عنوان چرخه تعامل در ساختار فضایی بندر- پسکرانه و مبتنی بر چهار بُعد ذکر شده بوجود می&amp;shy;آید که هدف آن تبیین مدل توسعه فضایی متوازن بندر و مناطق پسکرانه در مقیاس&amp;shy;های مختلف است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 0cm 0cm 0pt; text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot; new=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 115%; font-family:;&quot; times=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;Ports are of major gates of spatial flows. These nodes not only guide the distribution of goods within the supply chain, but also play an important role for developing their hinterlands. Lack of attention to these spatial relationships, especially in countries with endogenous development factors&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span new=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 115%; font-family:;&quot; times=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;,&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot; new=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 115%; font-family:;&quot; times=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt; reduces the importance of local hinterlands. This would also shrink the relations among ports and hinterlands at the local and regional scales. In this regard, identifying and highlighting the components of spatial structure lead to strengthen the relations between ports and hinterlands. Up to now, many articles have been written on Ports and Hinterlands that can be generally classified them into five categories: The role of ports and hinterlands within the supply chain and transportation; function and efficiency of ports; port-city relationships; management, policy-making, and governance of port-regions; and the trajectory of spatial structure of ports, hinterlands, and forelands. This study aims at identifying and weighing the factors of spatial structures and proposing an appropriate theoretical framework on the spatial structure of port-hinterland based on content analysis. The findings suggest six components of spatial structure: territory; node; corridor; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span new=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 115%; font-family:;&quot; times=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;activity&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN-GB&quot; new=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 115%; font-family:;&quot; times=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt; area; interaction; and discipline. Compilation of these components result new dimensions of spatial structure; such as spatial movement, spatial use and spatial form. Furthermore, during the development of port-hinterland relationships logistic spaces come into being, which enrich the flows of production, distribution, and consumption. Spatial movement depends on the relationship between nodes and communities. Also human activities on the land can form spatial use. Spatial form is based on interaction process between spatial movement and spatial use that can be appeared obviously or be hidden. In the regional structure, component of discipline with obvious outward can introduce a new dimension as &lt;/font&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;logistic&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt; spaces. In fact, dimension of &lt;/font&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;logistic&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt; space makes difference in spatial structure of port-hinterland compared to other spatial structures. Logistic spaces generally export spatial development flows to undeveloped geographical areas and adjust spatial structure of hinterlands. Overall, these dimensions generates a cycle entitled port-hinterland spatial structure, which can influence the entire spatial structure of a country. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>ساختار فضایی, بندر, پسکرانه, تحلیل محتوا. </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Port, hinterland, spatial structure, content analysis.</keyword>
	<start_page>19</start_page>
	<end_page>40</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1140-3&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مجتبی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>آراسته</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004913</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004913</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>هاشم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>داداش‌پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004914</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004914</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی اکبر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>تقوایی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004915</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004915</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
