<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>48</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تبیین راهکارهای موثر در بکارگیری ادراکات حسی در فرایند طراحی معماری با رویکرد پدیده شناختی</title_fa>
	<title>Defining effective strategies for using sensory Perception in architectural design process with phenomenological approach </title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:4.55pt;&quot;&gt;در رویکرد پدیده شناختی توجه به ماهیت پدیده مهم است. در نتیجه ثبت داده ها و قابلیت&amp;shy;های محیط به گونه&amp;shy;ای که بتوانند خواص خود را حفظ نمایند، کلیدی است. از این&amp;shy;رو ادراکات حسی و راهکارهای بکارگیری آنها در فرایند طراحی از اهمیت ویژه&amp;shy;ای برخوردار است. از سوی دیگر ارائه راهکارهای اصلی در تبدیل داده های کمی به کیفی و موثر در روند طراحی پدیده شناسانه و خلق معماری متکی بر ادراکات حسی ملاک عمل است. مسیر اصلی این پژوهش براساس نحوه برخورد با ادراکات حسی موجود در فضا به گونه&amp;shy;ای است که بتواند طراح را در روند طراحی بی واسطه با پدیده ها یاری رساند. با توجه به بررسی&amp;shy;های صورت گرفته می توان از جمله بهترین راهکارهای دستیابی به این مهم را انتخاب گزینه&amp;shy;های حسی در سایت دانست. داده&amp;shy;ها می&amp;shy;توانند به صورت نقاط و محدوده&amp;shy;ها و کریدورهای حسی در سایت عمل نمایند و از نیروهای مستتر در سایت نشات گرفته و طراح را در مسیر طراحی یاری رسانند. اینکه مسیر فرایند طراحی چگونه طراحی گردد و این رویکرد چگونه تاثیر گذار باشد با ارائه مدل های فرایند طراحی که معماران تعریف می نمایند، هماهنگ می گردد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Due to the nature of phenomenon in phenomenological approach is important. the research takes its course in a way that first, identification and method selection and selection of techniques based on new patterns, but on the basis of documents and information related to the main theories is carried out. The design process is based on two main stages and their subcategories, and the role of each has been reviewed with phenomenological approach. And finally, operation of strategic techniques including mapping technique as ways to convert the phenomenon to matter in the design process with a phenomenological approach to sensory perceptions is considered. As a result of this study, a model for the design process with phenomenological approach to sensory perceptions is presented which in turn contains strategies for conversion of phenomenon to matter in the process of architectural design. It is noteworthy that in the presented model, in the identification stage and selection of the requirements, discursive and argumentative approaches are relied upon in addition to sensory encounters with the subject. Finally, this study can present the following theory: design based on phenomenological approach to sensory perceptions is directly linked to the environmental factors. Therefore, the use of techniques and measurement tools of qualitative and quantitative criteria of environment such that preliminary data do not lose their properties and inherent nature is essential in the process of design and its implementation methodology. Presenting strategies in the design process with phenomenological approach to sensory perceptions can be designed, but not with certainty at all stages. The selection of the design process stages depends on the selection criteria and is subject to change and these strategies can be selected in the design process according to the needs and requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>ادراکات حسی, فرایند طراحی, رویکرد پدیده شناختی, کیفیت معماری </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>sensory </keyword>
	<start_page>245</start_page>
	<end_page>264</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-50&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>نجمه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زبردستان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007847</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007847</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>خسرو</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>موحد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007848</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007848</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>هادی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کشمیری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007849</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007849</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
