<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>15</volume>
<number>43</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی میزان دست یابی دولت به اهداف طرح مسکن مهر: مطالعه موردی شهر جدید پردیس تهران</title_fa>
	<title>Evaluating the Achievement of the Objectives of Mehr Housing Plan: Case Study of Pardis New City, Tehran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;یکی از نیازهای اساسی هر کشوری، تامین مسکن برای افراد جامعه است. فاکتورهای متعددی در تهیه مسکن مناسب برای تمامی اقشار جامعه وجود دارد که توجه به همه آن&amp;shy;ها از جمله وظایف مهم دولت&amp;shy;هاست. از مهم&amp;shy;ترین این عوامل می توان به مکان&amp;shy;یابی و تامین زمین مناسب برای ساخت شهرها و مناطق مسکونی، کاهش یا حذف بهای زمین از قیمت تمام شده مسکن و از همه مهم&amp;shy;تر قیمت&amp;shy;گذاری واحدها به طریقی که قدرت خرید را برای کلیه اقشار فراهم کند، اشاره کرد. یکی از طرح هایی که در طول سالیان گذشته به جهت تامین این نیاز اساسی در کشور پیاده شده است، طرح مسکن مهر است. هدف از انجام این پژوهش، بررسی میزان دست&amp;shy;یابی دولت به اهداف طرح مسکن مهر بوده و برای دست&amp;shy;یابی به این هدف مطالعه موردی شهر جدید پردیس تهران انجام گرفته است. تجزیه و تحلیل داده&amp;zwnj;های موجود در مورد شیوه&amp;zwnj;های پیاده&amp;zwnj;سازی پروژه مسکن مهر در شهر جدید پردیس، به وسیله نرم افزار &lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;SPSS&lt;/span&gt; انجام شد و نتایج نشان داد که پروژه مسکن مهر در تامین مسکن برای گروه های کم درآمد، حذف قیمت زمین از قیمت تمام شده مسکن و همچنین مکان یابی و تامین امکانات زیر بنایی موثر بوده است ولی در تامین تسهیلات بانکی ارزان قیمت و فراهم ساختن امکانات روبنایی موفق به دست یابی به اهداف موردنظر نگردیده است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 1em 0px; text-align: justify; line-height: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: &amp;quot;Garamond&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;; font-size: 13pt; mso-bidi-font-family: &amp;quot;B Mitra&amp;quot;;&quot;&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;One of the basic needs of each country is to prove house for individuals of the society. There are several factors which contribute to provide house for all classes of individuals. This issue is one of the important tasks of government. The most important factors in this field are location to construct the residential areas, proper and efficient usage of raw materials, provision of urban needs in new residential areas, most importantly, the pricing of the units in a way that provides purchasing power for all classes of individuals. One of the proposals in the past years in order to meet this basic need in the country is Mehr housing scheme. The aim of this study was to investigate the government achievement rate to the objectives of Mehr housing scheme. To achieve this goal, a case study of a new city Pardis in Tehran was conducted. Data analysis regarding implementation of Mehr housing project was conducted by SPSS, Lisrel software. The results displayed that Mehr housing project of new city pardis significantly reduce inequalities in housing, small investment, reduce costs of deprived households and increase the quality of housing.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مسکن مهر, شهر جدید پردیس, SPSS.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Mehr housing, new city pardis, SPSS, Lisrel</keyword>
	<start_page>445</start_page>
	<end_page>452</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1145-27&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>روح الله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نوری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003884</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003884</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مرضیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بوربوراژدری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003885</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003885</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بوربوراژدری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003886</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003886</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
