<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>48</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی مولفه های رهبری اخلاقی و ارائه مدل مطلوب</title_fa>
	<title>Identify and prioritize components of ethical leadership and providing optimal model</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;رهبری اخلاقی بر نحوه استفاده از قدرت اجتماعی توسط مدیران و سرپرستان در تصمیم&amp;shy;گیری&amp;shy;ها و اقدامات محیط کار و نحوه تأثیر و نفوذ آنها بر دیگران متمرکز است. هدف اصلی این تحقیق ارائه مدل سبک های رهبری سازگار با سازمان&amp;shy;های دولتی ایران است. این تحقیق از نظر هدف، از نوع کاربردی است و برحسب نحوه گردآوری داده&amp;shy;ها از نوع توصیفی- پیمایشی می&amp;shy;باشد. جامعه آماری این پژوهش شامل تعداد 30 نفر از خبرگان و مدیران اداره امور مالیاتی و اداره دارایی و امور اقتصادی استان های آذرایجان غربی و شرقی می&amp;shy;باشد. داده&amp;shy;ها توسط پرسشنامه گردآوری شدند و برای تجزیه تحلیل آنها از روش دلفی و مدلسازی ساختاری تفسیری استفاده گردید. نتایج نشان داد که از دید خبرگان 34 مولفه از طریق روش دلفی و با استفاده از پانل متخصصان به&amp;shy;عنوان مولفه&amp;shy;های رهبری اخلاقی انتخاب شدند و در مرحله دوم مولفه هایی چون دانش اخلاقی، استقرار استانداردهای اخلاقی، مصمم بودن در رفتارهای صحیح اخلاقی، توانایی درک مسایل اخلاقی، تکریم ارباب رجوع و عادل بودن در رهبری اخلاقی بیشترین اثر گذاری را داشتند و به ترتیب سطوح اول تا ششم را دارا شدند. با توجه&amp;nbsp; به نتایج تحقیق اولین و مهترین مولفه رهبری اخلاقی داشتن دانش اخلاقی می باشد تا رهبران فراتر از احساسات به ارائه رفتارهای صحیح اخلاقی مبتنی بر عقلانیت مبادرت ورزند و این خود نیز منجر به توانایی درک مسایل اخلاقی و بروز یکسری از ویژگی&amp;shy;های اخلاقی به مانند تکریم ارباب رجوع و عادل بودن و غیره می گردد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Ethical leadership focuses on how to use social power by managers and supervisors in decision making and action in the workplace and how it affects and influences others. The main objective of this research is to provide an optimal leadership model compatible with Iranian government agencies. This research is applied in terms of purpose and is descriptive-survey based on the data collection method. The statistical population of this research includes 30 experts and managers of the Tax Administration and the Department of Finance and Economic Affairs of the provinces of West and East Azarbaijan. Data were collected by a questionnaire and Delphi method and interpretive structural modeling were used to analyze them. The results showed that the experts from 34 components were selected through the Delphi method using the panel of experts as components of moral leadership, and in the second stage components such as ethical knowledge, the establishment of ethical standards, determination in ethical moral behaviors, ability to understand Ethical issues, customer reverence, and fairness in moral leadership had the most impact, respectively, with levels 1 to 6.According to the results of the research, the first and the most important component of ethical leadership is the existence of ethical knowledge, so that leaders, beyond sentiment, offer ethical behavior based on rationality, and this also leads to the ability to understand ethical issues and the emergence of a number of ethical features Like the reverence of the lord and righteousness, and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>رهبری اخلاقی, دانش اخلاقی, یادگیری اجتماعی </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Ethical Leadership, Ethical Knowledge, Social Learning</keyword>
	<start_page>225</start_page>
	<end_page>240</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-16&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سلیمانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008199</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008199</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>غلامرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>معمارزاده طهران</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008200</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008200</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عطایی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008201</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008201</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ابوالفضل</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کاظمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008202</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008202</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
