<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>46</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارزیابی انتقادی گرایش به معماری غرب در کاخ‌های دوره قاجار</title_fa>
	<title>A Critical Review of Tendency towards the Western Architecture in Palaces of Qajar Era</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>كاربردي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Applicable</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;معماری قاجار فصل تاریخی معماری ایران در گسست از سنت&amp;zwnj;های پیشین و همگام شدن با ره&amp;zwnj;آوردهای تمدن غرب محسوب می&amp;zwnj;شود. کاخ&amp;zwnj;های این دوره، به واسطه پیشرو بودن در انعکاس تحولات &amp;nbsp;معماری عصر خویش، مهم&amp;zwnj;ترین نقش را در انجام این دگردیسی ایفا کردند. این پژوهش به بررسی و نقد گرایش به معماری غرب در کاخ&amp;zwnj;های دوره قاجار پرداخته و در پی ارزیابی چیستی و چگونگی این گرایش از منظری انتقادی است. از روش تحقیق نمونه موردی و راهبردهای ترکیبی استفاده شده و گردآوری اطلاعات از طریق مطالعات کتابخانه&amp;zwnj;ای و تحقیقات میدانی میسر شده است. یافته&amp;zwnj;های پژوهش نشان می&amp;zwnj;دهد که دولت قاجار تاکید چندانی بر کسب پیشرفت&amp;zwnj;های تکنولوژیک و سازه&amp;zwnj;ای معماری غرب و انطباق آن با شیوه&amp;zwnj;های سنتی معماری ایران نداشت و بر اخذ مظاهر مادی آن تمدن اصرار می&amp;zwnj;ورزید. این رویکرد، که در اواخر دوره ناصری به اوج خود رسیده بود، موجب پیدایش بناهای سلطنتی کاملاً بیگانه در معماری ایران شد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Qajar architecture is considered as the historic season of Iranian architecture regarding the separation from the past traditions and keep pace with the achievements of the Western civilization. Qajar palaces, as the most progressive architectural works to attract the transformations of architecture in their era, played a vital role to change the values of Iranian architecture. This article investigates the tendency towards the Western architecture in palaces of Qajar Era and is looking for to evaluate the quiddity of this tendency from a critical view. The method in this research is case studies and combined strategies and the data collection has been prepared through the literature review and fieldwork. Research findings show that Qajar government did not have significant emphasis on gaining the technological and structural advances of the West and Qajar kings were limited and satisfied with superficial shifts to cover the weaknesses of their government. This approach, which rose to its peak at the late Naserid period, without having any concern for the evolution of the ancient patterns of Iranian architecture, finally weakened historical architectural traditions and caused to appearance of the completely alien and unfamiliar royal palaces in Iran.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>معماری ایران, معماری غرب, گرایش, سنت و تجدد, کاخ‌های قاجار.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Iranian architecture, Western architecture, tendency, tradition and modernity, Qajar palaces.</keyword>
	<start_page>179</start_page>
	<end_page>198</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-776-13&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سعادتی خمسه</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846006134</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846006134</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
