<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>52</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تبیین تحقق‌پذیری حکمروایی خوب شهری با تاکید بر هوشمندسازی مکان؛ موردکاوی شهر تهران.</title_fa>
	<title>Explanation of good governance of good urban governance with emphasis on location smart growth; case study: city of Tehran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات به عنوان عمده ترین محور تحول و توسعه هزاره سوم مطرح شده است&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; شهر الکترونیک و شهر هوشمند به عنوان یکی از مواهب فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات، این امکان را فراهم می کند که شخص توأمان در هر دو بُعد واقعیت و مجازی حضور داشته باشد و فراتر از حدود فضایی زمانی محل استقرار خود به درک فضا نائل شود&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; از جمله مواهب شهر هوشمند، تسهیل امور مدیریت شهری است بویژه که دیگر نمی توان با شیوه های سنتی، شهر را اداره نمود. پرسش آن است که با تغییرات جدید در حوزه فناوری در شهرهای کشور بویژه در کلانشهر تهران، آیا مدیریت شهری قادر است بهتر از گذشته، شهروندان را به مشارکت فرا خوانده، آنها را در تصمیمگیری&amp;shy;ها دخالت دهد و به ارتقا شاخصهای حکمروایی مطلوب شهری بیانجامد و اینکه مدل مفهومی پژوهش در اینجا شامل کدام متغیرها خواهد بود؟ پژوهش کنونی که برآمده از رساله بنام &amp;laquo;تبیین تحقق پذیری حکمروایی خوب شهری با تاکید بر هوشمندسازی مکان؛ موردکاوی شهر تهران&amp;raquo; می&amp;shy;باشد، به شیوه توصیفی تحلیلی و با رویکردهای کیفی و کمی انجام گردیده و نتایج آن نشانگر آن است که نخست، وضعیت حکمروایی از نظر متخصصان و خبرگان، مطلوب نیست (نمره میانگین 4.79 و انحراف معیار 0.21) و دیدگاه غالب آن است که هوشمندسازی کلانشهر تهران به تحقق حکمروایی مطلوب شهری خواهد انجامید.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Information and communication technology has been proposed as the main focus of the evolution and development of the third millennium. The e - city and smart city as one of the information and communication technologies allow the individual to be present in both dimensions of reality and virtual, and beyond the space space of its deployment to understanding space. Among the advantages of smart city is the facilitation of urban management practices, especially as it cannot be ruled by traditional practices. the question is that with new changes in the field of technology in the country's cities, especially in Tehran metropolis, would urban management be able to participate better than the past, make them involved in decision - making and develop indicators of optimal urban governance indicators and that the conceptual model of research here will consist of which variables? the present study, which is derived from the thesis called &amp;quot;explanation of good governance of urban governance with emphasis on location; city of Tehran&amp;quot; is done with qualitative and quantitative approaches, and its results indicate that, first, the status of governance is not optimal from experts and experts (mean mean 4.79 and standard deviation of 0.21) and the prevailing view is that the smart growth of Tehran metropolis to achieve optimal urban governance.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>حکمروایی خوب شهری, هوشمندسازی مکان, کلانشهر تهران</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>good urban governance, smart growth location, Tehran metropolis</keyword>
	<start_page>189</start_page>
	<end_page>204</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1816-95&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسین </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>هادی‌بیگلو </last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846009018</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846009018</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رحیم </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سرور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846009019</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846009019</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نوری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846009020</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846009020</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
