<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <ArticleSet>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Public spaces and social interactions enhancement (Case study: Kosar residential complex and Ekbatan residential complex-phase 2)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>7</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>22</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Abbas</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Yazdanfar</LastName>
	<Affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Baqer</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Hoseini</LastName>
	<Affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mostafa</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Zaroodi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>mostafa_zaroudi@arch.iust.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Based on the models which are presented in order to define the human needs, social interactions is one of the necessary issues. Disregarding the notions, beliefs, preferences and other aspect of different personalities which are thought to be the most important human behavior controllers in behavioral science theories, physical environment also has a potential impact related to the human behavior. In according to this, public spaces in residential areas, as the places that provide residents with the possibility of gathering together, could establish the social interactions among them. Ignoring this need of residents and also the environment’s capability for supporting this issue, may change physical environment into useless and empty spaces. This could cause dissatisfaction of the environment among inhabitants and consequently, would result to their absence in public spaces. The present study, investigated this issue in two residential complexes by using field survey, interviews, and questionnaire. Finally the data were analyzed by correlation coefficient and then the result presented. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>Public space, communal activity, social  interaction, environmental affordance</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-61-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-61-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Formulating a framework for Municipality capital action plan according to urban development plans Case study: Tehran</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>23</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>40</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyed Manaf</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Hashemi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Science and Research</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Habibollah</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Taherkhani</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>hataherkhani@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hadi</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Saidi Rezvani</LastName>
	<Affiliation>College of Fine Arts, Tehran University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Meissam</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Basirat</LastName>
	<Affiliation>College of Fine Arts, Tehran University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Multiyear urban programs are part of the overall framework of city planning and managing. These kind of programs are working as the means of linking the long term urban development plans and municipality annual budget. Coherent linkage between different kinds of urban plans guarantees the successful outcomes. In Iran, according to the Urban Development and Renovation Law, article 15 (approved in 1969), all municipalities have to prepare a five year plan for conducting the development and renovation operations in accordance to the city master plan. Based on these explanations, this paper tries to explore the necessities and different methods of mid-term city programs in the world and Iran with focus on case of Tehran Municipality. The article demonstrates that preparing mid-term program for municipality of Tehran with reference to Capital Investment Program approach can be appropriate for Tehran. This kind of plan can make linkage between newly approved city master plan and annual budget and illustrate a clear image of Tehran Municipality in future, besides the financial resources of capital projects. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>Capital Investment Plan, Municipality mod-term plan, Tehran</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-63-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-63-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of the unifying status and role of jumah mosque in increase of social capital case study: local mosque of Kerman city</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>41</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>56</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Shahin</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ilka</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University of Varamin</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>shahinillka@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Shahab</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ilka</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University of Varamin</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Prayers and worship to god and everything which relates humanity to his creator to achieve the pure life and its affiliations, spiritual tranquility, are the most important issues necessary to be presented in a city subjected to Islamic codes. In this article studies the impact of holding the unifying and spiritual ritual of jumah salat and the efficiency of mosques in increate of social capital based of its factors in the level of mosques of Kerman city. Sample population in the current study is 384 upper than 16 years old in habitants of local areas of Kerman city which are selected randomly. Research methodology and data collection tools are questionnaires which are analyzed by SPSS software, which in the level of inferential statistics &quot;candle test&quot; and &quot;chi due test&quot; are applied. Result of the study show a direct and meaningful correlation between variables of social capital, social trust, social participation and religious scale of people which are resulted by holding of jumah salat as a spiritual ritual. Therefore, it seems necessary to make possible the increase of social capital and its related and correlated factors by development of spiritual and religious programs which can help the attraction of citizens to mosques, especially teenagers and youngsters. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>social capital, social trust, social participation and religious scal.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-65-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-65-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Genealogy of qualitative social values of space\'s urban design with emphasis on public discourse</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>57</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>80</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Farah</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Habib</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mostafa</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Behzadfar</LastName>
	<Affiliation>School of Art and Architecture, Iran University of Science and Technology</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyed Ahmad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>FiroozAbadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Social Sciences</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hamideh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Foroozangohar</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>h_forouzangohar@hotmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Public space provides social relations, social capital and cultural and social discourse. Public space is the category between social society and governmental policy and connects the public problem of people and public opinion about democracy and logical aspects. These public spaces contain the common phenomena like: equity, unity, and social justice in urban spaces. In the other hand, the Criteria of Environmental Quality in Urban Design is the major aspect of urban design and the best quality urban democracy. These papers have been benefited descriptive and analytical research method and other research method that specified logical argument. So, in this paper, have been constructed the major of public space's factors.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>public space, urban space, urban discourse, the Criteria of Environmental Quality</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-66-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-66-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Survey Relation between Social Capital and Community Base Planning for the Degree of Master of Art in Urban Planning</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>81</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>100</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Razieh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Reza Zadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Iran University of Science and Technology</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Rezazadeh@iust.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Selseleh</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Iran University of Science and Technology</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>ubtin@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>At community-based development planning, vision of planning and management from below to up and based on empowerment and approach of asset – based with emphasis on human source, social capital and social participation of habitants of sections. On this direction, researcher considered Robert Putnam approach to social asset and measured it in selected sections in Tehran(five community: Gisha, Yaft abad, Saheb zaman, Farhangian, Sadeghiye) and amount tendency to community-based development on basis Review literature had quantitative. The axis of this research is survey social capital and tendency to community based development planning and direct and strong correlation between these variations had confirmed. On basis of results this research, when social capital of one community rises, tendency to community based development rises. On basis presented model of this research, social capital is good predictor for explanation tendency of people to community-based development planning. With consider to this results, could been resulted: If community based development planning policy as essential strategy in direction sustainable development of city and restructure joy to city society, had been emphasized by authorities of city, If authorities will consider to community-based development planning (on new standard city development), in first Authorities must consider to social capital and influence factors on forming it in city and section and with good fundamental, provided backgrounds for improvement it. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>asset based approach, community development, community-based  development planning, social capital</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-67-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-67-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The phenomena of Islamic urbanism and architecture to providing the reality of architectural building cosmological and epistemological approach</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>101</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>122</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Masood</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Masoodi Fard</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Science and Research Branch, Islamic Azad University, Shahrood</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>masoudifard@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Masood</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Koochakian</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>masood1790@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The cosmological and epistemological approach emphasis on wisdom concept of architecture the content of Islamic architecture is linguistic system that presents the reality of architectural building. So. In this Islamic city, the objector aspect of architecture presents the subjective aspect of Islamic city's rules like: functional and psychological aspects. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>architectural aspect, the reality of architecture, Islamic architecture.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-68-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-68-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Network Analysis Approach to the Governance of Ex-Urban Lands,(Case study: Karaj Urban Region)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>123</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>138</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Sheikhi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tabatabai University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>m-shaikhi81@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mahsa</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Shahsavarian</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tabatabai University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Arash</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Fazli Shams Abadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Severe weaknesses in relationship between organizations and overcoming of conflicts to the inter-organizational cooperation due to lack of planning and the establishment of an inter-organizational unofficial and informal relationship system are on no secrets as structural and pivotal defects in the administrative system of the country. This weak point is tangible and obvious in the management system and administration structure of cities and metropolitan areas more than other sectors. Therefore, this research studies the network of organizations, agencies and groups influencing exurban governance in Karaj urban area as a case study and tries to realize the problems in this network, based on two types of formal relationships between them. These relations which have been presented under the title of &quot;governance and referral&quot; are extracted from urban planning and urban management terms and also from responsibilities of organizations and agencies tasks. The presence or absence of these kind of relations as well as being single strain or mutual relations are entered as a zero-one matrix into UCINET software and are analyzed using the Netdraw software as a supplement to the UCINET software. This analysis shows the concentration of power and information in some organizations and agencies which marginalized others. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>urban governance, land management, network approach, network analysis</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-69-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-69-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Evaluation and leveled the Effective Components in Rural Tourism Marketing, with Marketing Mix (7P)(Case Study: selected Provinces in mazandaran)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>139</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>152</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mojtaba</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Qadiri Masoom</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Geography Faculty of Tehran University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Farshad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Soori</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Geography Faculty of Tehran University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>farshadsoory@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mirali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Shafii Arabi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University Branch of Chaloos</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mojtaba</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Bahrami</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University Branch of Chaloos</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the present and desired rural tourism in selected Provinces in mazandaran with marketing mix. In the present study, the under-investigation components of marketing mix consist of seven components (7P) of place, planning and management, evidences and physical facilities, publicity, people and staffs, price, and products. In line with this, field study and descriptive-analytic research method have been used, and the data has been collected according to researcher-made 48-question questionnaire in which the related items have been chosen regarding the features of geographical tourism. The staffs of Cultural Heritage and Tourism Organizations and Municipality were the sample and all of them have been tested from among the experts at this issue (N=90). The data analysis has been carried out by SPSS Software, and Mean Tests, Chi-Square, Wilcoxon and Friedman. To measure the significant difference between marketing mix items in two present and desired conditions by Wilcoxon test is an indication of the difference between the two compared conditions. Friedman test has been used for ranking the amount of effectiveness of components in the development of rural tourism and the results show the high importance of propaganda, people, and product components regarding the testable in having influence on the development of rural tourism in Babol, babolsar, mahmoodabad, and Sari provinces. Finally, it was found that the combination made of mixing the seven mentioned components with the significant level of 0/00 and the level of allowable error of 0/05 has the following capabilities firstly, it shows the present condition of rural tourism marketing in the region well. Secondly, it results in the promotion of the level of rural development through expanding rural tourism in the studied region. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>Rural Tourism, Marketing Mix (7P), Present and Desired Conditions, selected Provinces in mazandaran</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-70-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-70-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Evaluation and leveled the Effective Components in Rural Tourism Marketing, with Marketing Mix (7P)(Case Study: selected Provinces in mazandaran)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>153</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>162</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Vahed</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Dehqani Kazemi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Vdehghani@ut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hamidreza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Jafari</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Zeinab</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Yaganekia</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Esmail</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Salehi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The purpose of this study is to evaluate the present and desired rural tourism in selected Provinces in mazandaran with marketing mix. In the present study, the under-investigation components of marketing mix consist of seven components (7P) of place, planning and management, evidences and physical facilities, publicity, people and staffs, price, and products. In line with this, field study and descriptive-analytic research method have been used, and the data has been collected according to researcher-made 48-question questionnaire in which the related items have been chosen regarding the features of geographical tourism. The staffs of Cultural Heritage and Tourism Organizations and Municipality were the sample and all of them have been tested from among the experts at this issue (N=90). The data analysis has been carried out by SPSS Software, and Mean Tests, Chi-Square, Wilcoxon and Friedman. To measure the significant difference between marketing mix items in two present and desired conditions by Wilcoxon test is an indication of the difference between the two compared conditions. Friedman test has been used for ranking the amount of effectiveness of components in the development of rural tourism and the results show the high importance of propaganda, people, and product components regarding the testable in having influence on the development of rural tourism in Babol, babolsar, mahmoodabad, and Sari provinces. Finally, it was found that the combination made of mixing the seven mentioned components with the significant level of 0/00 and the level of allowable error of 0/05 has the following capabilities firstly, it shows the present condition of rural tourism marketing in the region well. Secondly, it results in the promotion of the level of rural development through expanding rural tourism in the studied region. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>Rural Tourism, Marketing Mix (7P), Present and Desired Conditions, selected Provinces in mazandaran</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-72-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-72-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Assess the social dimensions of urban neighborhoods in the context of social capital perspective case study: shiraz</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>163</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>184</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Majid</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Abdollahi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>abdollahi847@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Expansion of urbanism during late decade causes new challenges such the decrease in the identity feeling and society belonging, increment of environmental discordant, lack of ecologic adjustment and totally reduction of living quality in cities. Programming new approaches and theories and urban management for solving of above problems, usage of cooperative approach, social mobilization and the bottom-top programming have been considered at itself focus. Fulfillment of this approach needs definition of new division system of space on the urban management and programming framework which on the basis of traditional management experiences, neighborhood because of its theoretical values, applicable and programming aspects, it can be considered as the basic element and axis of this programming. necessity of Pay attention to this concept in the urban programming system is justified, for some reason such as establishment of integrated, cooperative and rationalist management, adaptation of cultural and social changes by necessity factors on the dwelling and living in cities especially today metropolis, attempt to the domestic and local values and attitudes, empowering of identity feeling and also social belonging. In this framework, the main purpose of the present thesis is review of historical changes, role and action, space organization of Iranian urban neighborhood during different period and effort for presentation of sustainable pattern of neighborhood living, agreement of socio-economical and cultural requirements of current years for urban development. As a result, these life conditions, values and foundations in urban neighborhood were undergoing and fundamental changes, by locating city and urban neighborhood to modern elements and symbols, establishment of polar structure in the urban neighborhood were accepted principle of that era. Structural elements and new operation in the urban neighborhood which has been outstanding during this period. New structural elements and functions were created in urban neighborhood space that didn’t exist before this experience, and management of neighborhood has been changed by establishment of new bureaucracy as a form of City Council and municipality. In fact, being less important the principles of Iranian native culture and replacing &amp; superiority of western thought in urban neighborhood structure, has played a key role and On the other hand, development with fundamental changes has had particularities of exotic development. Due to these conditions, it is possible to achieve to sustainable neighborhood pattern in the Iran cities perspective and specially metropolis with empowering propriety of social capital and factors on the basis of reliance, belonging, social cohesion of neighborhood, community oriented urban management in Iran and establishment of management system which has power and authority, cooperation, responsible, legitimate and institution oriented.</Abstract>
	<Keywords>neighborhood, local society, social capital, neighborhood governance, shape of neighborhood, sustainable neighborhood.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-77-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-77-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Assessing the spatial distribution of urban parks using network analysis (Case study: Tehran, Iran)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>185</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>196</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Esmail</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Salehi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Majid</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ramezani Mehrian</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>majidmehrian@ut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hadi</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Afrasyabi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Planning Center of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Majid</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Davoodi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Planning Center of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Reza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Basiri Mojdehi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Planning Center of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Urban parks and the accessibility to them are considered as the most important factors in evaluation of urban performance. Suitable accessibility to parks is depended on the spatial distribution of them in the urban accessibility network. In the most studies that have been done about assessing the spatial distribution of urban parks, simple buffering method which has a high level of errors is used to determine the service area. Considering these problems and concepts existed in graph theory, network analysis can be usefully utilized to assessing the spatial distribution of urban parks. Network analysis provides a useful instrument for assessing the distribution of urban parks. In this study, using accessibility network of Tehran city and defining the location of parks on it, the service area of each park was determined by network analysis. Serviceability indices-i.e. service area ratio, service population ratio and statistical indices-i.e. park area per capita, park area ratio were evaluated and the situation of the city regions were compared. Based on the results founded in this study, 43 percent of the residual areas in the study area are placed out of the urban park serviceability. The map of these areas was prepared to use in locating and introducing new urban parks. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>Urban Parks; Service area; Network analysis, Tehran city</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-80-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-80-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Sustainable Revenue, urban management challenges in realizing Vision 1404 (With an emphasis on revenues from investment and participation of citizens in Tehran)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>197</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>210</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Zarir</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Negin Tagi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University School of Economics</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>z-negintaji@sbu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hoonaan</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Hoseini</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Fatemeh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Hoseini</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Lack of attention to the problem of identifying and increasing sustainable revenues in major cities as Tehran is one of the major challenges in our way toward targets on sustainable management of urban areas in Vision 1404 Act. Section 5 of Tehran Master Plan, which is titled by Economic Development Of The City Of Tehran, emphasize on The issue of sustainable alternative sources of revenue to cover the expenses of city and at the same time it necessitate a steady decrease in the share of revenue from residential construction (density and barter sales). One of the sustainable sources of revenue in municipal management is revenue from investments and participations. This article, based on provided data by the Investment organization of the Tehran Municipality explores this issue in period of 1382-1388. The results showed that during the period, about 50 projects have been reached to the stage of contract and only 5 of them (only 10% of projects) have been operated. About 20 projects, which have reached to their completion due date are still on construction phase and 14 projects are in designing phase yet. It should be mentioned, the value of collaborative projects during 1389 and the first six months of 1390 have seen significant growth that is a good sign for the future managers of Tehran Municipality. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>Sustainable Revenue, Vision 1404, partnerships and investments, Tehran Municipality, Municipal Management.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-81-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-81-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The land capability assessment for the purpose of urban and rural expansion (case study: Shemiranat County)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>211</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>226</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Maleki</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tabatabai University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>mohamad1404@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Sheikhi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Faculty of Social Sciences Allameh Tabatabai University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Gholamreza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Latifi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Faculty of Social Sciences Allameh Tabatabai University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Toorash</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Sarvi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tabatabai University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Shemiranat County in the northeast of Tehran province is one of the tourism destinations in Iran. This area is outstanding for its considered ecological diversity and water supply. During these years, the residential expansion caused some threat to the fragile ecosystem of this area. Considering the inevitability increase in the construction to some extent in this county, determining the appropriate zones for urban and rural development would lessen the subsequent costs. In this article, we used 8 criterions in the GIS environment. The classification of these criterions was done by means of Fuzzy Desirability Functions. The relative importance of each criterion has been calculated by Fuzzy AHP technique. Also, limitation criterions have been applied via Boolean logic. The results suggest that only 12 percent of this area meets the relative requirements for urban and rural land use. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>ecological capability, land use, Fuzzy layers, Fuzzy AHP, GIS, MCDM.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-82-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-82-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Application of Grey Clustering and Radial Basic Functions in economical zoning of Tehran Megalopolis concentrating on Credit and Financial Institutes installation</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>227</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>244</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ghadir</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ashoor Nejad</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tehran University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Rahilali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Abbaspoor</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Technical Faculty of Tehran University campus</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>abaspour@ut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The importance of local decisions and their effects on different corporations and services is best known. Selection of suitable places makes it easier for the corporations to find and catch more customers, and hence, credit and financial institutes are always seeking the most proper locations for their activity centers. Achieving this goal depends mainly on identifying the effective criteria and effectiveness of each of the mentioned factors. This research is up to introduce a model in order to identify the optimum zones for installation of banks and credit and financial institutes' branches using objective and subjective methods. In the first step, after identifying effective criteria and economical factors based on the pattern of customers and managers spatial behavior, spatial data were collected. In the subjective method, weight of each criterion was calculated using the Analytical Hierarchy Process (AHP) after fulfillment of a paired comparative questionnaire by the expert. For spatial modeling and zoning the Grey Clustering Analysis (GCA) was used. Also, in the objective method the RBFLN neural network was used for spatial modeling. The Boolean combination function &quot;AND&quot; was used to combine the results of the two former methods. The results of combining the optimum classes constitutes of primary proposed zones. This process was conducted on each of the 22 regions of Tehran. Finally the model was evaluated for both objective and subjective methods, which suggest the significant performance of the model. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>Gray Cluster Analysis (GCA), Fuzzy Analytic Hierarchy Process (Fuzzy AHP), RBFLN neural network, Zoning, credit and financial institute.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-83-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-83-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Investigation on quality of information management in municipalities,Emphasis on GIS\'s abilities A case of: Babolsar</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>245</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>262</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mostafa</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Qadami</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Mazandaran University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Ghadami56@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Saeed</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Azadi Qataar</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tehran University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>Sazadi65@gmail.com </AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mehdi</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ahmadian</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Isfahan University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Accessing and using updated and precise information is counted as important factors in decision making and planning process. This issue gets more important in cities, because of complexity and diversity of a huge amount of Information which is used in urban decision makings. Despite of GIS's abilities as a strong decision making support system it has not been respected truly by urban managers especially in small and medium size cities in Iran. This paper aimed to investigates quality of information management in a small size municipality (Babolsar) regard to GIS's abilities. Sample units of the case municipality are: official, urban development and public services units. A survey was conducted on staffs using interview and expert checklist. T student test and descriptive statistics were used. The results show, the case municipality suffers from serious weaknesses based on information quality indicators (regarding to GIS's abilities). Some of weaknesses are inflexibility, security, data processing and analysis, data management system, structure of database as well as outputs. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>data and information, quality of information management system, GIS, Babolsar municipality.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-84-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-84-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Introducing a model for planning and designing garden-cities in Iranian system of urbanism</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>263</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>288</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ahmad</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Khalili</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tehran University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>ahmadkhalili@ut.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mastooreh</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Qoli Poor</LastName>
	<Affiliation>University of Art, Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>ms.gholipour@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Arezoo</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Tagik</LastName>
	<Affiliation>University of Art, Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>arezoo_tajik60@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Nader</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Zali</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Urban Development Department, University of Guilan</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>zalinader1@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Since approving the blueprint of &quot;Baghshahrha&quot;or &quot;Baghestanha&quot; plans by Supreme Council of urbanism in 2010, preparation of these plans had been stood in the agenda of agencies and engineering consultants. Although, garden city plans of some provinces encountered performing challenges but in planning the garden city plans's policies of Iran, a special study is essential. Therefore the article is to produce a model for designing and planning of these settlements. In order to achieve this goal the authors, at first, are to reviewing the status of the debate in the urbanism literature of Iran and the world extract required factors and appropriate criterion to circumstances of Iran. Then, these indicators are converted to a closed questionnaire and professionals, educators and experts will be questioned. It is worth mentioning that the results of the survey through statistical analysis - factor analysis and regression analysis – will provide optimal model. This is an applied research that using quantitative research methods and analytical approach. The population for this study includes about 100 expert professionals. According to the pattern of designing and planning of garden cities of Iran, obtained from the research, at first, by forcasting residential and employment conditions for all social groups in the garden cities and then establishing services, healthcare, educational, administrative and military needs of the villagers in these settlements, should be created some functional attractions in these places. Therefore, part of the urban population could be accommodated in garden cities and also, rural population would be absorbed to live there. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>garden city, rural city, sustainable development, new urbanism, smart growth</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-85-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-85-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Qualitative and Quantitative Assessment of Research Paper of Urban Management Journal</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>289</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>298</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad Reza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Bemanian</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Faculty of Arts University Tarbiat Modares</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>bemanian@modares.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Farial</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ahmadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Faculty of Arts University Tarbiat Modares</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Asad Poor</LastName>
	<Affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The main goal of the current research is to evaluate the quality and quantity of the research paper of Urban Management Journal between years 2008 to 2012. To achieve this goal, eight parameters such as paper content and field, number of authors, scientific grade of the first author, scientific institution of the first author, accepted time of the paper, research method and resources have been analyzed and finally the results have been presented via excel software. The results of the paper indicate that 40% of papers are about urban design basics, 21.6% of them are about urban management, 17% are about case study analysis in urban design. It also shows that most of papers have 2 authors (39%). It should be mentioned that the most first author of papers are associate professor. 38% of all published papers have been published by Tarbiat Modares University. Master degree theses researches have published more articles in this journal (8 papers) and only 1 paper published based on PhD researches. During these five years only 4 papers have been extracted from research projects. Finally its hold says that, 44% of papers have been published less than 6 months. As a result some guidance has been recommended to improve journal qualitatively. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>qualitative and quantitative evaluation, research paper, qualitative and quantitative analysis, research method, statistical analysis</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-86-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-86-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Urban infill development of borujerd city</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>299</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>310</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hamidraze</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Saremi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Faculty of Arts University Tarbiat Modares</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>saremi@modares.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Most of cities in our country have been faced some problems such as unplanned and physical disruption. These studies have been shown that the recent physical expansion of the city is because of the natural growth of the population, immigrations from villages, and finally exceeding to farms and garden that have been located around the cities. Despite, one of the important reasons of instability in our cities is abandoned wide areas or with none-urban landuse. This fabric has been led to instability in some factors such as economic, social, and physical in our cities. These spaces are instable in natural disasters such as flood and earthquake. Also don’t provide basic needs of residents. In this research by approaching of infill development, was studied capacity of Borujerd city in order to appropriate guidance of urban development. Research method: the kind of this research is applied and the method of research is &quot;descriptive – analytical. Also data collection method has been done library (using of books, papers, internet and etc) and field (questionnaire, view). Result: infill development in borujerd is possibility .also preparation of housing and physical- spatial development is possibility. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>Infill development, borujerd city , estimate of housing</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-87-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-87-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Strengthen the local management solutions to empower informal settlements case study: mahmoodabad, isfehan</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>311</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>326</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Maryam</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Esmailian</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Sama Technical and Vocational College, Islamic Azad University, Varamin</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Omid</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Ahadian</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University of Hamedan</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>omid_ahadian@gmail.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Reza</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Shaker Ardakani</LastName>
	<Affiliation>School of Art and Architecture, Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Informal settlement, the negative consequences of urbanization in the contemporary world and especially the rapid industrialization and regional disparities have been created. The present study of informal settlements in Iran and the world and how it is taking shape Mahmoodabad neighborhoods in 12 municipalities of case studies. In this regard, the proposed approaches to the study area have been organizing and empowerment. This study used descriptive research - analysis, survey and field study of 300 questionnaires (sample size) is obtained. The following analyzes were carried out using the analysis tool Mahmoodabad of various sizes, the proposed regularization of informal settlements is presented in the form of empowerment strategies </Abstract>
	<Keywords>Local management, empowerment, informal settlements, Mahmoud Abad, Isfahan.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-88-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-88-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>11</Volume>
			<Issue>32</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2013</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Introducing Model for Evaluating the Quality of Public Spaces Resulting from the Regeneration of Urban Natural Environments Based on Components of Sustainable Landscape</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>327</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>350</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Shahindokht</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Barqjelveh</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Institute of Environmental Science martyr Beheshti University</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>s-barghjelveh@sbu.ac.ir</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Nima</FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName>Sayad</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Islamic Azad University of Tehran</Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails>nimasayad@yahoo.com</AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Natural environments are considered among the most important ecological structures of the cities, and if planned correctly, they can result in the sustainability of urban natural processes. This paper, while introducing a new component model for evaluating the quality of natural public spaces, applies its fundamental principles to a particular case study. As well as comparing existing component models, the study examines the component model of sustainable landscape with an emphasis on landscape’s excellence eco-environmental-societal processes, providing the excellence conditions of ‘biological interfaces’, ‘flow of matter and energy’ and ‘societal interactions’. In assessing the model, the Analytic Network Process (ANP) is used to either make the model of internal-external relations or use feedback processes. For gathering the information the study uses the methods of questionnaire, case observation and literature review. The results show that lack of attention to bio-spatial-social interrelations of urban natural spaces causes many damages in continuous sustainability of city’s urban landscape. </Abstract>
	<Keywords>Quality assessment; Component model; Urban sustainability</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-89-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-89-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
 </ArticleSet>
 
  
  
  
  
 