<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>15</volume>
<number>43</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>نظام حقوقِ شهرسازی ایران در پرتو قوانین و مقررات اسلامی (تبیین الگوی برهم‌کنش حقوق عمومی و خصوصی)</title_fa>
	<title>Iranian civil rights system in the light of Islamic laws and regulations (Explanation the pattern of the interaction between public and private rights)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin-right: -42.55pt;&quot;&gt;قوانین و مقررات حاکم بر نظام شهری به عنوان فصل مشترک مطالعات حقوقی و شهرسازی به شمار می&amp;shy;آید. از سوی دیگر، نظام شهرسازی به عنوان یکی از کلیدی&amp;shy;ترین عناصر ارتباطی بین دولت و ملت، بر پایه&amp;zwnj;ی حقوق خصوصی و حقوق عمومی، تناسبات بین مردم و نهادهای عمومی را انتظام می&amp;shy;بخشد. بازشناسی ابعاد ساختاری و محتوایی حقوق عمومی و خصوصی در نظام شهرسازی کشور، نیازمند پاسخ به این پرسش است که؛ ضوابط و مقررات شهرسازی کشور در پرتو قوانین و مقررات اسلامی از چه ماهیتی برخوردار است؟ روش&amp;shy;شناسی پژوهش مبتنی بر فرایندی است که تفسیر نظام شهرسازی کشور را در قالب نظم حاکم بر منابع حقوقی مورد تحلیل قرار می&amp;shy;دهد. این تحلیل، کیفی بوده و با به&amp;zwnj;کارگیری تکنیک استدلال منطقی و روش مطالعات اسنادی صورت می&amp;shy;پذیرد. واکاوی و بازشناسی کنشگران حاکم بر فضاهای خصوصی و عمومی شهرها از یک&amp;zwnj;سو و بازتعریف مبانی و منابع حاکم بر حقوق عمومی و خصوصی در نظم قانونی کشور از سوی دیگر، ما را به الگو و رهیافتی نو در باب مطالعات حقوق شهری هدایت می&amp;zwnj;کند. این رهیافت، با تأمین نیازهای متعدد و سازگاری منافع متنوع بین دو حوزه خصوصی و عمومی، تجلی آرمان&amp;shy;های حقوق شهری را منجر می&amp;zwnj;شود.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;ftn1&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left: -2.3pt;&quot;&gt;Rules and regulations governing the urban systems are considered as a common point of Legal Studies and Planning. On the other hand, urban system as one of key elements of the relationship between the state and the nation regulates the proportionality between people and public based on private low and public low. To recognize the structure of public and private law in the urban system of the country it is necessary to answer the question &amp;ldquo;what is the entity of the urban rules and regulations of country in the light of Islamic laws and regulations?&amp;rdquo; the methodology of research based on the system interpretation of the urbanization of the country is in order of governing on the legal sources. This analysis is qualitative and determined using Logical reasoning technique and documentary studies method. Analysis of the actors of the private and public spaces of cities on the one hand and the redefinition of the public and private rights in the legal order of country on the other hand, guides us to the new pattern and approach regarding the rights of urban studies. This approach, by providing multiple needs and Compatibility varied interests between the private and public spheres, leads to the manifestation of civil rights ideals.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مقررات شهرسازی, قوانین اسلامی, حقوق عمومی, حقوق خصوصی, الگوی برهم‌کنش.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Regulation of Urbanism, Islamic law, public law, private rights, pattern of the interaction.</keyword>
	<start_page>31</start_page>
	<end_page>50</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1145-4&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رضا </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خیرالدین</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003829</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003829</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ابراهیم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>دلایی میلان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003830</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003830</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
