<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>28</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>کاربرد روش‌های تصمیم‌گیری چند معیاره در برنامه‌ریزی شهری و منطقه‌ای با تاکید بر روش‌های TOPSIS و SAW </title_fa>
	<title>Application of the Multiple Criteria Decision Making Methods in the Urban and Regional Planning Emphasizing TOPSIS and SAW Methods</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;تصمیم‌گیری یکی از مهمترین وظایف مدیریت است. یکی از دلایل موفقیت برخی از افراد و سازمان‌ها اتخاذ تصمیم‌های مناسب است. از این رو، ضرورت وجود روش‌هایی علمی که انسان را در این زمینه یاری کند، کاملاً محسوس است. این امر منجر به توجه محققین در دهه‌های اخیر به «مدل‌های چند معیاره» (MCDM) برای تصمیم‌گیری‌های پیچیده شده است. این روش ها برای تصمیم گیری در شرایطی که معیارهای متضاد، انتخاب بین گزینه‌ها را با مشکل مواجه سازد، مورد استفاده قرار می گیرد و کاربردهای متعددی در علوم مختلف دارد. هدف از این مقاله بررسی کاربرد مشخصی از این روش‌ها در برنامه ریزی شهری و منطقه ای یعنی در انتخاب مکان مناسب اسکان می باشد. برای این منظور ابتدا معیارهای لازم جهت مکان یابی شناسایی شد و سپس با استفاده از نظر متخصصان و خبرگان وزن معیارها بدست آمد. نتایج بدست آمده نشان می دهد که با استفاده از این روش ها می توان مسائلی را که با گزینه ها یا راهکارهای متعددی سروکار دارند مورد تجزیه و تحلیل قرار داده و اولویت بندی گزینه‌ها را انجام داد. همچنین نتایج بدست آمده نشان داد روش‌های تصمیم گیری چند معیاره با توجه به سادگی، انعطاف‌پذیری، به کارگیری معیارهای کیفی و کمی به طور همزمان و استفاده از چندین معیار سنجش به جای یک معیار سنجش می تواند در بررسی موضوعات مربوط به برنامه ریزی شهری و منطقه ای کاربرد مطلوبی داشته باشد. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Decision making is one of the most important duties of management. Appropriate decision making is one of the reasons of success of people and organizations. So, the necessity of existing of the scientific methods that can help man in this subject is obvious. This subject led to attention of researchers to the multiple criteria models (MCDM) for complicated decision makings in the recent decades. These methods have been used for decision making in the condition that the selection of the options are difficult due to the antonym criteria and have various applications in the different sciences. The objective of this paper is exploring of the specific application of these methods in the urban and regional planning, i.e. in the selection of the proper site for the residence. For the selection of the site, initially necessary criteria are determined. Then using the expert’s viewpoints the weights of criteria are calculated. The results showed that using these methods the analyzing and doing priority processing for problems that deal with several options would be possible. Also the results showed that the multiple criteria decision making can have proper application in the analysis of subjects related to the urban and regional planning due to simplicity, flexibility, and use of the quantitative and qualitative criteria simultaneously and several criteria instead of one criterion. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>تصمیم گیری چند معیاره، برنامه ریزی شهری، مکان یابی، SAW، TOPSIS.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Multiple decision making, urban planning, Site selection, SAW, TOPSIS.</keyword>
	<start_page>285</start_page>
	<end_page>296</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-68-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mehdi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Nojavan</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نوجوان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>nojavan_mehdi@alumni.ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600259</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600259</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده محیط زیست دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali Asghar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mohammadi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی اصغر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>محمدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600260</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600260</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch of Tehran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Esmail</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Salehi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>اسماعیل</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صالحی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600261</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600261</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University, Faculty of Environmental</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده محیط زیست دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
