<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" 

"journalpublishing3.dtd">

<article 
article-type="research-article"
dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en" 
xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
>

<front>

<journal-meta>

  <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">1</journal-id>
  <issn>1607-2227</issn>

  <publisher>

	<publisher-name> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher-name>
  </publisher>

</journal-meta>



<article-meta>

  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2301</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Analyzing the Role of Organizational Culture, National Culture and Citizenship Culture in the Cultural Policymaking of the Metropolitan Municipalities of the Islamic Republic of Iran</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>5</fpage>

  <lpage>20</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The aim of this research is to analyze the role of organizational culture, national culture and citizenship culture in the Cultural Policymaking of the Metropolitan Municipalities of the Islamic Republic of Iran. The current research, in terms of purpose, is set in the applied research group and in terms of collecting data, is a description of solidarity group in which the modeling of the path-structural equations for hypotheses testing and model fitting is used. The statistical population of the study consists of all the planners, experts, and deputies of the cultural and social field working in the metropolitan municipality (3 metropolises, Tehran, Shiraz, Isfahan) with 3000 people. By using the law of 10, 610 people have been selected as the sample by a stratified sampling method. The data gathering tool was a questionnaire, which its reliability was determined using Cronbach Alpha coefficient and the validity of the questionnaire was confirmed using content validity using the knowledge of experts familiar with the subject of the research. Also, SPSS22 and Lisrel 8.80 software was used to determine the correlation and analysis of the data. The results of the data analysis have confirmed all the research hypotheses: organizational culture, citizenship culture and national culture have a positive and significant impact on cultural policy making.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2302</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>energy Efficiency Evaluation of Green Roof in Iran Case Study: Tehran, Tabriz, Ramsar, Bandar Abbas </article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>21</fpage>

  <lpage>34</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

One of the solutions proposed to reduce energy consumption in large cities is the construction of a green roof. This research aims to introduce the green roofing system and its role in reducing the thermal energy transfer and the phenomenon of urban Thermal Island, to study the thermal effect of using green roofs Compared to conventional conventional roofing. The research method has been quantitative and analytical research in the areas related to the green, descriptive and qualitative research, and in the software-related areas of quantitative research and analytical method, and to prove the hypothesis that &amp;quot;green roof and its design play an effective role in Reducing heat transfer &amp;quot;has been used to simulate the design of the 1-sheet. A typical roofed roof with some specific details (polystyrene and polyethylene) is analyzed and their heat transfer in four cities representing major climates In Iran (Tehran, Tabriz, Bandar Abbas and Ramsar) has been studied. The results of the research show that green roofs have the most impact on the cold and humid climate (Ramsar) with 22% and the least impact in cold and mountainous climate (Tabriz) with a 14% reduction in energy consumption. In addition, the amount of cooling loss in hot and humid climate (Bandar Abbas) was lower than other three climates of Iran (Tehran, Tabriz, Ramsar) and in cold and mountainous climate (Tabriz) compared to other three climates (Tehran, Ramsar, Bandar Abbas) And also the most reduction in the heating load in the cold and humid climate (Ramsar) and the lowest in warm and dry climate (Tehran).

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2303</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Urban Safety Spectrum From the passive defense perspective Using the Antropy-COPRAS model, (case study: Ahwaz metropolis)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>35</fpage>

  <lpage>48</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>


Urban safety is one of the most basic Global Society Forecasts&amp;nbsp; For human-centered planning . Studies done in the world show The vulnerability of different groups People residing in the city's squares, Depending on the level of&amp;nbsp; life And their social and physical status They vary from place to place. In this regard, the present study The issue of urban safety has been studied in terms of passive defense. The research method of this research is a combination of descriptive, documentary and analytical methods and the nature of developmental-applied. The statistical population of the study is Ahwaz metropolitan areas. Which identifies the vulnerability of the metropolitan areas of Ahvaz from the passive defense perspective. Finally, analysis of the data with the Antropy-COPRAS model And SmartPLS, GIS, Visio, Grafer, SPSS and EXCEL software. To determine urban safety the impact of urban structure and variables was determined. In the next step Considering the two factors of weight and distance from the ideal Effective level was determined. Which is based on the results of the Antropy-COPRAS model Urban safety level between (0 and 1) The highest was (0.97%)And the lowest (0.007%) belongs to Ahwaz two district Also, the maximum distance of &amp;ldquo;the desired option from the ideal point&amp;rdquo; There are 5 metropolitan areas in Ahwaz And next to the eight area. The state of the sensitive metropolis of Ahwaz is shown The most administrative and educational users are in the 6th district of Ahwaz Municipality. And have the highest health use in the 8th, 5th and 4th district of Ahwaz municipality, respectively

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2304</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Relationship between Social-Spatial Mental Schema and Observers' Tranquility in Urban Green Highways (Case Study: Modarres Highways)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>49</fpage>

  <lpage>63</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The aim of this article is to investigate the relationship between the observers&amp;rsquo; tranquility and creating mental schemas in the corridor of the green urban highway. Tranquility is the one that can cause memories and sense of belonging by locating in mind. Being unique and criterion cause quick images to remain in minds and these elements cause the space to become an indicator of spatial identity. To become a tranquiller and memorable space and to remain in minds some schemes should be created in minds and this is the fundamental condition. Furthermore, the space should have a definite and unique identity. Statistical analysis included descriptive and inferential techniques. The findings show that, in designing the urban highways paying attention to spatial-social schemas is one of the main components for generating tranquil of highway margin by criteria. According to the results of the analysis of experimental findings, it seems that considering spatial-social schemes are one of the main components of creating a reliable and tranquil environment for bystanders who visit routes such as highways. According to the results of this study, there is a linear relationship and a high correlation between tranquility and creating mental spatial and social schemes. It means to make a space tranquil and memorable some schemes should be created in minds to make the space effective and persistent. Several sequences and focus points in the special parts can lead us to have a convergence mental schema.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2305</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Modeling people trips mode choice for entry into the central metropolis Tehran congestion charging zone</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>65</fpage>

  <lpage>80</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

One of the methods of controlling traffic in central and high traffic areas of major cities is creating central congestion charging zone and the ban on entry private car into this zone at certain hours of the day. This interdictions and control infrastructure constraints cause significant problems for residents and who has been working in the central zone of the cities. This interdictions and traffic constraints cause many urban systems and regional and local problems in Tehran, because of importance of those changes this study is to evaluate and assess the influence of central Tehran congestion charging zone on the mode choice of people trips for entry into the zone. In this context, the questionnaires were collected from the central zone of Tehran and for modeling of mode choice in this study, due to the discrete nature of data, multinomial logit model was used and the implementation of this model was done using the TransCAD software. The results showed that business dependence on the automobile, the number of passengers in the car, having an entry permit to the congestion zone and the amount of commute to the congestion zone are including influencing parameters on the use of private cars in order to enter the study area. Model evaluation showed estimated mode matches with people selected mode at 84%.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2306</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Analysis the Role of space Integration in Social Relation of the Traditional Houses of Kashan</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>81</fpage>

  <lpage>92</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The subject of this article is examine and analyze the role of space integration in the social relations of traditional houses of Kashan, in order to use their specific pattern in contemporary houses. The relation between the space configuration and social relationship in contemporary houses to have desirable spatial qualities requires the recognition of specific pattern in integration of spaces in successful samples. The sample that has adaption in culture and behavior of citizen and can be used in today&amp;rsquo;s houses. In order to achieve this purpose, we must identify the factors that affecting the integration of spaces and structural patterns of Qajar houses of Kashan and do comparative analysis of these patterns in according to the needs and requirements of today&amp;rsquo;s housing. This study is based on the concept of space configurations. The integration of spaces indicated the degree of privacy and generality of them is one of the most important components in this theory. The method that used in this research is an interpretive-historical method with the technic of analysis content. To analyze the integration we used the space-syntax plug-in in grasshopper software and by using analyze of the graphic graphs of 19 samples of traditional houses of Kashan that selected as targeted clusters. The results of this research indicate that the space of the Qajar houses had a good homogeneity.&amp;nbsp;
The result of analysis in two software&amp;rsquo;s, Space-Syntax and Depth map have the same result of integration and the separation of public and private spaces. By using these two software and analyze the traditional houses of Kashan the following results can be deduced: -All of the studied houses have the homogeneity number more than 5, so all of the traditional houses of Kashan that studied in this paper have an appropriate homogeneity and distribution and can considered as patterns for today&amp;rsquo;s home communications. -Houses that have four general arena, public, semipublic, semi private and private area and have appropriate depth and integration of these spaces are homogeneous and have a desirable distribution. &amp;ndash;Any space that requires more privacy has more depth and less integrating. Public spaces and joints of houses have lower depth of other spaces and have more integration. &amp;ndash; After the communicating spaces, between all kind of rooms in traditional houses, which include the hall, Panj dari, Se dari, Do dari and the room, the hall have the highest integration and then the Panj dari, Se dari, Do dari and the room are in the next rank of integration, so the hall and Panj dari in the most houses are the guest rooms and they are in semi-private arena and Se dari, Do dari and the room respectively are the most private spaces and it can be result that to have an appropriate integration and desirable social relationship the contemporary houses require all four arenas.

&amp;nbsp;

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2307</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Problem Solving of deteriorated urban areas is the most important stage in the participation of residents for success in renovation programs (Case stude: Shahid Khob Bakht neighborhood)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>93</fpage>

  <lpage>108</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Nowadays, the renovation of deteriorated urban areas is no longer regarded as a mere physical action on these urban textures. Because the experience gained in Iran and the world over the past decades has shown that the rule of partial thinking, the lack of attention to the dimensions of the participation of renovation programs, and the reduction of its dimensions to the physical renewal, just transfer the problems to somewhere else. Therefore, with regard to the above issues, the hypothesis of this paper was that the problem solving of deteriorated urban areas was urged to encourage people to participate, and the plan of the municipality of Shahid Goodakht was evaluated as the first experience of collaborative renewal in Iran. In this paper, the hybrid research method (exploratory blend) was used to answer this hypothesis and quantitative analysis of the content analysis method was used to transform the qualitative findings. Quantitative analysis of statistical methods was performed using SPSS software and the hypothesis test by T test and Chi square. Quantitative analysis of statistical methods was performed using SPSS software and the hypothesis test by T test and Chi square. After that, the final results were presented based on quantitative findings and qualitative analyzes and problem-solving phase in the renovation plans, as a stage of recognizing the needs and problems of the residents, and their ability to meet the needs of renovation policies, was also confirmed.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2308</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>The Application of ‘Integrated Urban Design Process’ in the Regeneration of Historic Urban Places; Case Study: Sang-e-Siāh Historic Pathway Public Spaces</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>109</fpage>

  <lpage>126</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The integrated urban design process could be considered as a crucial interaction between &amp;ldquo;substance&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;procedure&amp;rdquo; in all the creative designs revealed during the history of urban design in which the substantive approach has gradually been shifted into a more procedural one. This new situation had been widely adapted by the ever-growing revitalizing approach, searching a new life for many of old and deteriorated urban fabrics and places. The integrated approach could lead the urban design through a revitalizing process which might be also interpreted as the regeneration of the spatial structure of a city. In this research the convergence of urban design and urban regeneration has been incarnated in the integrated urban design process for regenerating historic places. In this article after reviewing the related literature a list of integrated qualities of urban design has been proposed to be used as an imperative goal for the urban regeneration and conservation of historic and heritage areas. To achieve such a task the method was to organize an integrated urban design process in order to apply all the qualities listed before in the redesign and the regeneration of historical urban spaces of a chosen part of the old city of Shiraz situated in the Sang-e-Siah historic quarter.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2309</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>An Analysis of Land Use Change and Its Impact on the 3rd Metropolitan Area of Tehran</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>127</fpage>

  <lpage>144</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The spatial organization of urban habitats is a direct result of social, economic, and political processes. The organization of the internal component of a spatial dispersal can be affected. The location of each component is shaped together with each other in conjunction with spatial organization. The main functions of man, especially the economic, social, commercial, and service functions, are through their activities, the vision of the environment takes shape, form and system of its own. Following the prevalence of the ideas of ecosystemism and sustainable development in the world, this attitude gradually penetrated into public opinion and planning that land is not a private commodity. It is also the most important commonwealth and the mainstay of all the activities of citizens and the means necessary to research the aspirations and aspirations of humanity in the present and future. In this regard, the purpose of this research is to analyze and evaluate the utilization of urban lands of the region based on the city's physical divisions and to determine the degree of adaptation of applications. The research methodology is descriptive-analytical And using the documentary and library method to collect information Finally, using multi-criteria modeling techniques, the information is analyzedThe criterion of the relative relative contribution of construction activities due to the destruction and renovation in the whole construction area and the consequences of it with a score of 0.4270 can be ranked first.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2310</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>comparative evaluation of urban management performance in Iranian provinces
(Case study: cities of Khorasan Razavi province)
</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>145</fpage>

  <lpage>158</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

This research is purposeful, applied and developmental, and in terms of method, a descriptive correlation type that collects data in the field of field research and documentation. The statistical population of this study consists of 27 municipalities in the cities of Khorasan Razavi province, which is a total number that is considered by the municipalities' self-assessment function The data collection tool is the registered data of the standardized guideline of the municipal organization of the country which has 187 questions in seven dimensions and is the annual year of the year 95 of Khorasan Razavi province and documents. For data analysis, descriptive statistics and inferential statistics have been used. All statistical analyzes were performed using SPSS and amos software.The results show a positive and significant effect of urban services and administrative affairs, human resources on the performance of municipalities in Khorasan Razavi province in the low development group, positive and significant impact of urbanization, financial affairs, contracts and development projects, transportation and traffic, administrative affairs, human resources and approvals The council issues general and managerial issues with the performance of the municipality of Khorasan Razavi in the middle development group and has a positive and significant effect on administrative affairs, human resources and performance of the municipality of Khorasan Razavi province in the high development group.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2311</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Evaluation of Pedestrian Access in Land use with Transit-Oriented Development Approach (Case study: Zone 6 of Tehran)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>159</fpage>

  <lpage>172</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The quality of pedestrian access in urban areas as one of the main pillars in the theory of Transit-Oriented Development (TOD), affects the ability and motivation of individuals to use public transportation. The evaluation of pedestrian access to public transport station centers has considered as the main goal of this research. A set of pedestrian access parameters for public transportation, including walking distance, number of transit stations, transport penetration, parking, connectivity, and transport modes have been reviewed. In addition, using self-organized neural network (SOM) technique, clustering and then analyzing the quality level of each cluster based on the characteristics of each parameter has discussed. In order to evaluate the results, studies on zone 6 of Tehran have been implemented. The results show that about 37% of the area is at the best pedestrian access level, 35% at good level, 26% in moderate level and only 2% in weak level.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2312</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Earthquake effect analysis on high urban structures with emphasis on dynamic analysis</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>173</fpage>

  <lpage>188</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Due to increasing the population and the necessity of developing urban areas, how to deal with natural disasters is one of the major concerns of urban communities. Urban growth is continually changing from living conditions on Earth. the damage and damage caused by the earthquake in cities in many cases showed that a high percentage of injuries were directly or indirectly related to the undesirable condition of planning and detection and reduction of urban risks. Indeed, it can be said that major causes of damage and damage due to earthquake safety should also be sought in the lack of principles, programs and city planning projects. The main purpose of this study is nonlinear dynamic evaluation of the behavior of the concrete shell under the influence of distance and near fault. for this purpose, three models are designed with thickness of 5, 7.5 and 10 cm in order to evaluate the effect of the thickness, arrangement and type of reinforcing bars as well as seismic intervals. In order to evaluate their efficiency in each stage after the nonlinear dynamic analysis, the explicit form on the models is determined using abacus software. the introduced concrete materials have plastic properties as well as the type of crack propagation in concrete, and it is applied to the structural problem of implicit dynamic analysis, where the stiffness of the shell structure changes with deformations. the results of this study indicate that changing the location of the shell structures with low thickness in the region is more than that of the near - field earthquake and the shell structures will not experience significant spatial changes when they encounter the near nature of shock loads, but in the case of continuous rotation and escalation phenomena in the building materials, it will result in changes in the final location and failure of these structures.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2313</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Explanation of good governance of good urban governance with emphasis on location smart growth; case study: city of Tehran</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>189</fpage>

  <lpage>204</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Information and communication technology has been proposed as the main focus of the evolution and development of the third millennium. The e - city and smart city as one of the information and communication technologies allow the individual to be present in both dimensions of reality and virtual, and beyond the space space of its deployment to understanding space. Among the advantages of smart city is the facilitation of urban management practices, especially as it cannot be ruled by traditional practices. the question is that with new changes in the field of technology in the country's cities, especially in Tehran metropolis, would urban management be able to participate better than the past, make them involved in decision - making and develop indicators of optimal urban governance indicators and that the conceptual model of research here will consist of which variables? the present study, which is derived from the thesis called &amp;quot;explanation of good governance of urban governance with emphasis on location; city of Tehran&amp;quot; is done with qualitative and quantitative approaches, and its results indicate that, first, the status of governance is not optimal from experts and experts (mean mean 4.79 and standard deviation of 0.21) and the prevailing view is that the smart growth of Tehran metropolis to achieve optimal urban governance.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2314</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Native ecological and ecological architecture principles in the design of residential complexes in Iran to improve their quality</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>205</fpage>

  <lpage>218</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Avoiding nature and natural systems in the daily life of urban people is considered as one of the most important concerns of contemporary times. Architectural and urban spaces should be an area for direct contact with the natural world; a world that is born in the context of primitive nature and includes a set of natural factors and processes. Unfortunately, the contemporary world, due to the avoidance of ecosystems and natural processes, does not have any consequences for humans, except numerous environmental problems, impoverished urban spaces, and the presence of architectures that are not adapted to the natural needs of mankind. Housing is one of the most important architectural spaces that have suffered serious damage during the process of industrialization and modernization. Housing as one of the real phenomena, is one of the first issues that humankind has always been trying to transform and find a meaningful answer to it, because housing is considered as one of the basic needs of every human being, and indeed one of his basic needs after food and clothing. Therefore, attention to housing is important not only as a shelter, but also as an area that can provide the necessary conditions for individual development of each family member, as well as their mental and emotional needs. One of the solutions to improving the quality of residential environment of the present era is using new architectures such as ecologic and biophilic. These architectures can be responsive to the mental and emotional needs of contemporary humans due to their relationship with the nature and to some extent provide favorable conditions for the lives of applicants for housing. The method used in this study based on its purpose is applied research method, and based on its nature, is descriptive-analytic research and data collection is based on the study of library resources and their content analysis. The results of this research indicate that by localizing the principles and criteria of ecologic and biophilic architecture based on the quality indicators of housing in Iran and applying these native principles in the design and implementation of residential complexes, their qualitative status can be upgraded, and also provided more favorable conditions for the inhabitants of these complexes.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2315</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Review how to compensate veterans and the disabled from the lack of effective management of the urban environment.</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>12</month>

	<year>2018</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>17</volume>

  <issue>52</issue>

  <fpage>219</fpage>

  <lpage>229</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>28</day>
				  <month>12</month>
				  <year>2018</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Human beings have always suffered from discrimination and injustice and the elimination of these injustices is considered one of the most important tasks of law. Citizenship is realized when all people have a community of all civil and political rights and easy access to opportunities in life in terms of economic and social. Groups of vulnerable groups of society, like the disabled and sacrifices, have always been deprived of full access to &amp;nbsp;due to its conditions and status and lack of access to many places as well as the lack of adaptations for living environment. In this regard, there has been a strong internal and international level of law which has specifically emphasized and supported the rights of this group of individuals. It is evident that the purpose of this document is not to give special and special privileges to these individuals, but adopting a suitable approach to support the disabled for achieving equal and equal rights. In the meantime, what is important is the legal encounter with this issue, not a clash of pity, compassion and charity. In the context of an important discussion of the life environment of the disabled and veterans, it must be acknowledged that access to the residential and urban environment without hindrance to the disabled is an elusive dream, and despite the fact that in some cities and places some positive actions have been made to fulfill the above agenda, but still architects and do not look at the disabled in society. This is tangible and tangible in all sectors of service provider. Therefore, the important issue we have discussed in this paper is how to compensate the sacrifices of veterans and the disabled, due to the lack of adaptations in the urban environment, which shows the environmental significance of the environment in the lives of the disabled and the veterans and the civil liability caused by it. in this study, we found that according to jurisprudence and law, these people have the right to receive three categories of damages that are physical, spiritual and physical, and in addition to the use of normal means to compensate for damages to the condition before the loss of damages and the loss of blood, it can be used as a loss of loss to the loss of blood.

</body>

</article>

