<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>28</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی راهکارهای بهبود و سازماندهی یکپارچه بافت فرسوده ساحلی؛ نمونه موردی بندرعباس</title_fa>
	<title>Integrated improvement strategies of deteriorated coastal cities (Case study: Coast of Bandar Abbas)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;بافت ساحلی بندر عباس به عنوان لبه یک شهر ساحلی و از آن مهم‌تر به مثابه پیشانی ارتباطات برون مرزی ایران از اهمیت بسزایی برخوردار است. این بافت به دلیل موقعیت سوق‌الجیشی خود می‌تواند به عنوان تجلیگاه فرهنگ و تمدن ایرانی مطرح گردد. علیرغم طرح‌های موضوعی و موضعی متعددی که در سال‌های اخیر در ساحل بندر عباس تعریف شده و نیز برخلاف تلاش‌های بی‌شائبه طراحان و سازندگان در راستای به روز کردن طرح‌های در دست احداث ساحلی، سیمای فرسوده و آکنده از اغتشاش این بخش از سواحل کشور نشان از فقدان مدیریت یکپارچه در سازماندهی این بافت دارد. آگاهی از مقتضیات طراحی در بافت‌های ساحلی،‌ مشخصات فرهنگی، شرایط اقلیمی، مسائل هویتی، ملاحظات اقتصادی و الزامات زیست ‌محیطی و همچنین اشراف به فناوری‌های روز و مصالح نوین در سازماندهی بافت فرسوده و واجد ارزش تاریخی ساحل بندر عباس بسیار حائز اهمیت است. بدین منظور مقاله حاضر اقدام به بررسی شرایط وضع موجود ساحل بندر عباس در کلیه محورهای فوق نموده و سعی دارد در راستای سازماندهی ساحل با رویکرد مدیریت یکپارچه راهکارهایی را ارائه دهد. روش تحقیق مبتنی بر مطالعه میدانی و هدفمند در شهر بندر عباس است. در این مقاله پس از معرفی الگوها و معیارهایی چند، ارزیابی و تحلیل داده‌ها بر اساس جدول SWOT صورت گرفته و در نهایت براساس این معیارها مبادرت به استخراج چند استراتژی اساسی شده است. سپس به منظور تحقق بخشیدن به استراتژی‌ها در بازه‌های زمانی کوتاه، میان و بلند مدت به تعیین راهکارها و اقدامات اجرایی پرداخته‌ایم. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;As an edge of a seaport and much more important as a frontline of international communication, Coastal texture of Bandar Abbas is of great importance. Due to its strategic location, this texture can be easily defined as an expression of Iranian Culture and civilization. Despite the recent years Local and subject oriented plans of Bandar Abbas coastal zone, and also designers and Constructorsefforts aimed to Upgrading and revising under construction coastal plans, yet the old ruined confusing landscape of these Iranian coastal zones, indicate such a lack of integrated management of this urban texture. The knowledge of design requirements in coastal zone, its cultural characteristic, climatic condition, identity, economic consideration and environmental requirements, as well as modern technologies and materials seem to be so much important in order to organizing the historically valuable old texture of Bandar Abbas. Hence, the present study, firstly analyze different aspects of, as mentioned above, Bandar Abbas’s recent status conditions and secondly with the integrated management approach, it suggests strategies to fulfill coastal zone organization. The research method as based on field study and surveys in city of Bandar Abbas. Introducing some patterns and criteria's, thisarticle assess and analyze data according to SWOT table, and after a definition of basic and fundamental strategies, it reveals the large, medium and short term action plans to fulfill them. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مدیریت یکپارچه، بافت فرسوده، بافت ساحلی، سازماندهی ساحل، ساحل بندر عباس.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Integrated Management, old texture, Coastal texture coast Organization, Coastal zone of Bandar Abbas.</keyword>
	<start_page>81</start_page>
	<end_page>92</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-111-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Mehdi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mahmoodi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدمهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>محمودی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mmahmudi@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600212</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600212</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>College of Fine Arts, Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>پردیس هنرهای زیبا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Lida</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Eslami</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>لیدا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>اسلامی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600213</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600213</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>College of Fine Arts, Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>پردیس هنرهای زیبا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
