<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>28</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیل و ارزیابی میزان تاثیر محدودیتهای ترافیکی در کاهش آلاینده های تولیدی وسایل نقلیه؛ نمونه موردی: بزرگراه شهید حکیم</title_fa>
	<title>Evaluation of traffic strategies on pollutant emission of vehicles (Case study: Shahid hakim highway)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;بحران آلودگی هوا در سالهای اخیر به یکی از بحرانهای بزرگ پیش‌روی مسئولین شهری تهران مبدل شده است و استراتژیهای بسیاری در مقابله با آن اتخاذ گردیده است. با توجه به اینکه شبیه سازی نرم‌افزاری ترافیک می‌تواند یکی از بهترین ابزارها در شناخت رفتار رانندگان و وضعیت سرعت و شتاب در شبکه باشد، مدلهای تولید آلاینده در کنار نرم‌افزار شبیه‌ساز می‌توانند ابزاری قدرتمند برای پیش‌بینی آلاینده‌های تولید شده در اختیار مهندسین قرار دهند. در این تحقیق پس از مطالعه نحوه مدلسازی سرعت و شتاب در شبکه و نحوه یافتن میزان آلاینده تولید شده بر اساس جدیدترین مدل تولید آلاینده قرار داده شده در یکی از نرم افزارهای شبیه‌ساز ترافیک، بخشی از شبکه بزرگراهی شهر تهران مورد بررسی قرار گرفت که این بررسی شامل دو استراتژی اصلی اعمال طرح زوج یا فرد و اعمال محدودیت سرعت تردد خودروها می‌باشد. با مقایسه استراتژیهای مذکور با وضعیت عادی شبکه، مشاهده گردید که اعمال طرح زوج یا فرد می‌تواند در شرایط خاص میزان‌آلودگی تولید شده را به نصف کاهش دهد. اما با توجه به موقتی بودن این استراتژی، پیشنهادهایی جهت کاهش آلاینده‌ها به گونه‌ای پایدار ارائه گردید. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Pollution crisis has become one of the most complicated problems which outbreaks the urban management in charge groups of the capital Tehran, and many strategies have been used to control this problem. In this case, using simulation is one of the best tools to predict the driver behavior and also the speed and the acceleration of vehicles in the network. As well as using the pollutant emission models combined with traffic simulation software can provide a suitable prediction tool to predict the pollutants produced by urban transportation network. In this research, after studying the vehicle following models based on acceleration and velocity prediction, and beside some bases of instantaneous emission models, an urban highway in the capital Tehran was investigated. In the investigation both odd and even approach and limitation in speed of vehicles approach were supposed. Comparison the results achieved from both approaches with the ordinary conditions of the network, showed that using the odd and even approach can reduce the pollution to 50% in general. But due to the provisional conditions of this strategy some other suggestions are given in this paper. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شبیه‌ساز ترافیک، آلاینده‌ها، طرح محدودیت سرعت، طرح زوج یا فرد.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Traffic micro simulation, Pollutants, Speed limitation strategy, Odd or even limitation.</keyword>
	<start_page>47</start_page>
	<end_page>60</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-110-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Jamal</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Khodakarami</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>جمال</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خداکرمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600207</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600207</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>School of Engineering, University of Ilam</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده فنی و مهندسی دانشگاه ایلام</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Noori</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علیرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نوری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Alireza.noory@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600208</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600208</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Amirkabir University of Technology</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه صنعتی امیر کبیر</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Saeed</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Toolabi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سعید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>طولابی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600209</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600209</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>School of Engineering, University of Ilam</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده فنی و مهندسی دانشگاه ایلام</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
