<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>28</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>باززنده‌سازی و افزایش کیفیت زندگی در مراکز شهری با رویکرد BID (نمونه موردی: مرکز شهر ارومیه)</title_fa>
	<title>Revitalization and promoting of the quality of life in urban centers with focus on the BID Approach: the Case Study of Uremia City Centre</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;مراکز شهری در طول تاریخ کانون توجهات و محل وقایع خاص شهری بوده و به عنوان مهمترین بخش شهر مورد توجه گرفته است که در حال حاضر با افول کارکردی مواجه اند. برای گذار از این وضعیت، نوسازی و بهسازی این مراکز امری ضروری تلقی می شود. در این میان، روش بهبود نواحی کسب وکار (BID) یکی از استراتژیهای موثر و جدید در ادبیات نوین نوسازی است. هدف تحقیق حاضر، ارزیابی و تبیین میزان انطباق پذیری این روش در مرکز شهر ارومیه و بررسی مولفه های موثر بر افزایش کیفیت زندگی است. روش تحقیق این مقاله، توصیفی- تحلیلی است. روش گردآوری اطلاعات شامل روشهای کتابخانه ای، پرسشنامه و مشاهدات میدانی است. روش نمونه بصورت تصادفی ساده بوده و جامعه هدف ساکنین، اصناف و مراجعین به محدوده انتخاب شده است. حجم نمونه 238 نفر بوده و پایایی پرسشنامه باستفاده از آلفای کرونباخ و روایی آن از طریق آزمون بارتلت و شاخص KMO در سطح بالایی مورد تایید قرار گرفت. علاوه بر این، اطلاعات بدست آمده از پرسشنامه با استفاده از آزمونT ، تحلیل همبستگی، رگرسیون ساده و چند متغیره و تحلیل مسیر تحلیل شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان می دهد که استفاده از این روش، با باززنده سازی مرکز شهر ارومیه همخوانی و سازگاری دارد. تک بعدی نبودن روش BID و ارتقاء شرایط کسب و کار و افزایش کیفیت زندگی در محدوده از دلایل اصلی سازگاری این روش است. نتایج بررسی های آماری در تحقیق نشان داد که عوامل کالبدی بیشترین نقش را در بهبود کیفیت زندگی در مرکز شهر داشته است. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Nowadays, city centers are facing with decline in function, whilst in the past city centers were focal concentration and also a place for special events and always took into consideration as the most important part of city. For passing this situation, renovation and rebuilding of these centers are a required issue. Amongst, Business improvement districts (BID) method is one of the newest effective strategies in modernized renovation that is used for reviving the city centers. Purpose of this article is evaluating and explaining conformity of this method in Uremia city center and examining effective factors for increasing the quality of life. Research method in this article is descriptive-analytic. Method of data gathering includes library studies, questionnaires and field observations. Sampling way is based on simple random sampling method and target community is selected from residents, merchants and travelers to this area. Sample's volume were 238 unit and questionnaires controlled by using Cranach’s Alpha Reliability and validity is confirmed by using Bartlett's test and KMO index. Data obtained from questionnaire were analyzed by using T test, Regression and path analysis. Research results confirm the using of this method for the revitalization of Uremia city. Not being single-dimension of BID method and promoting of business condition through improvement and increasing life quality in the selected domain are the main reason in compatibility with this method. In addition, the findings show that physical factor has the strongest role in improving life quality in the city center. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مراکز شهری، باززنده سازی، کیفیت زندگی، بهبود نواحی کسب و کار، شهر ارومیه.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>City Centers, Revitalization, Quality of Life, Business Improvement District, Uremia City</keyword>
	<start_page>273</start_page>
	<end_page>284</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-124-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Haleh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hosein poor</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>هاله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حسین پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600256</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600256</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Arts University Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده هنر دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hashem</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Dadash Poor</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>هاشم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>داداش پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>h-dadashpoor@modares.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600257</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600257</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Arts University Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده هنر دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mojtaba</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rafiian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مجتبی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رفیعیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600258</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600258</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Arts University Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده هنر دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
