<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>39</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>en</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>Assessing the Sustainability of Urban Neighborhoods in 17 District of Tehran city Using ANP Model</title_fa>
	<title>Assessing the Sustainability of Urban Neighborhoods in 17 District of Tehran city Using ANP Model</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>توسعه محله ای یکی از اهداف برنامه ریزی توسعه پایدار شهری و اقدامی کلیدی در نیل به توسعه پایدار قلمداد می شود. دیدگاه توسعه محله پایدار، رویکرد نوینی است که در آن حل مشکلات شهری را در بازگشت به مفهوم محله جستجومی کند. روش پژوهش توصیفی- تحلیلی و موردکاوی می باشد. همچنین روش یافته اندوزی براساس مطالعات کتابخانه ای، اسنادی و مصاحبه با کارشناسان و مسئولان و با هدف سنجش میزان پایداری در سطح محلات منطقه 17 شهر تهران درصدد بوده تا با استفاده از فرآیند تحلیل شبکه ای و روش دلفی، به بررسی و تحلیل وضعیت 25 شاخص مختلف در ابعاد اجتماعی-فرهنگی، اقتصادی و کالبدی-زیست محیطی برای سنجش پایداری بپردازد. نتایج حاکی از وجود اختلاف قابل توجه بین محلات، از لحاظ ابعاد پایداری بوده و بر این اساس محله یافت آباد بیشترین امتیاز، رتبه اول و محله فلاح کمترین امتیاز را کسب نمود و در رتبه ی آخر به عنوان محرومترین محله ی منطقه به لحاظ شاخص های پایداری قرار گرفته است. نتایج این پژوهش می تواند سیاستگذاران و برنامه ریزان را در تدوین سیاستها و برنامه ریزی مناسب در جهت محرومیت زدایی و برقراری عدالت اجتماعی یاری دهد.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Neighborhood development is considered as one purpose of sustainable urban development (SUD) and a key action to reach the sustainability. This approach (SUN), enhance this new approach that the city's problems can be expected in return to the neighborhood concept. Applied methodology is based on descriptive-analytical, case study and librarian methods. In continuous, it was used of interview with experts and officials for assessing sustainability rates in Neighborhoods of 17 districts in Tehran city using analytic network process and Delphi methods. In this study, 25 different indicators in the size of sociocultural, economical and Physical-environmental dimensions have been studied for measuring sustainability. Results showed that there are significant difference among neighborhoods, in terms of different dimensions of sustainability. Also, the results indicated that Yaft-Abad Neighborhood by achieving the highest score (0.574) had first rank and Fallah Neighborhood with the lowest score (0.719) of the final award and ranked as the most disadvantaged Neighborhood of distinct in accordance with sustainability indicators. Finally, in the end of this presented some solve ways.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>واحد همسایگی پایدار, توسعه پایدار شهری, مدل تحلیل شبکه ای, همسایه های شهری.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>SUN, SUD, ANP Model, Urban Neighborhoods </keyword>
	<start_page>147</start_page>
	<end_page>158</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-549-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Zohreh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Fanni</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>زهره</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فنی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>z-fanni@sbu.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846002026</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002026</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Koorosh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Akhavaan Heidari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>کوروش</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>اخوان حیدری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002027</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002027</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Akbar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Heidari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>اکبر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حیدری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002028</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002028</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
