<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2013</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>32</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارزیابی ابعاد اجتماعی محله های شهری در چارچوب دیدگاه سرمایه اجتماعی ؛مورد پژوهی محله های شهر شیراز</title_fa>
	<title>Assess the social dimensions of urban neighborhoods in the context of social capital perspective case study: shiraz</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>گستردگی ابعاد شهرنشینی در طی دهه‌های اخیر موجب بروز چالش‌های نوینی از جمله کاهش حس هویت و تعلق اجتماعی‌، افزایش نابهنجاریهای محیطی‌، عدم تعادل اکولوژیک و در مجموع کاهش کیفیت زندگی در شهرها شده است‌‌. رویکردها و نظریه‌های نوین برنامه ریزی و مدیریت شهری برای چاره جویی این تنگناها، استفاده از راهبردمشارکتی‌، بسیج اجتماعی و برنامه ریزی از پایین به بالا را در کانون توجه خود قرار داده است‌‌. تحقق ‌این راهبرد مستلزم تعریف نظام تقسیمات فضایی‌ جدیدی در چارچوب سلسله مراتب مدیریت و برنامه ریزی‌شهرهاست‌که مبتنی بر تجارب مدیریت سنتی‌، محله می تواند به دلیل دارابودن ارزشهای نظری و کاربردی، عنصر پایه و محور چنین برنامه ریزی تلقی شود‌. برای ارائه چارچوب نظری در گام نخست پارادایم توسعه پایدار به عنوان پایه نظری تعریف و نظریه سرمایه اجتماعی‌ جهت دستیابی به چارچوبی برای ساختار محله پایدار در بعد اجتماعی تعیین و ملاک عمل قرار گرفت‌. برپایه ‌این الگوبعد اجتماعی، بسترساز توسعه اجتماعی عدالت گرا‌، مشارکت پذیر و اعتمادزا‌، در سطح محله های شهری می باشد‌‌.روش شناسی انجام پژوهش در چارچوب دیدگاه قیاسی و استقرایی و رویکرد غالب آن اسنادی ـ پیمایشی است و با کمک های تکنیک های نمونه گیری اجتماعی سعی در تعمیم نتایج حاصل از این تحقیق به محلات شهر شیراز می‌باشد. تحلیل سه سطحی از محله‌های شهر شیراز در قالب 250 نمونه و در 10 محله منتخب صورت گرفت‌‌. بر اساس یافته‌های میدانی ‌این پژوهش سازمان فضایی منتج از شرایط و تحولات تاریخی محله‌های شهری در چارچوب الگوی مورد انتظار از توسعه پایدارمحله‌ای نشان می دهد که در پی تغییرات و شرایط فعلی حاکم بر محله‌های شهری‌، بعد‌اجتماعی به ویژه حس تعلق‌، تعهد اجتماعی‌، مشارکت مدنی و اعتماد اجتماعی دچار واگرایی اساسی شده است‌‌. در نتیجه‌این شرایط دستیابی به الگوی محله پایدار در چشم انداز شهرهای‌ایران و به ویژه کلانشهرها با اولویت تقویت ابعاد و مولفه‌های سرمایه اجتماعی مبتنی بر اعتماد‌، حس تعلق، همبستگی اجتماعی محله‌ای واجتماع محور بودن مدیریت شهری در ایران میسر می باشد‌.
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Expansion of urbanism during late decade causes new challenges such the decrease in the identity feeling and society belonging, increment of environmental discordant, lack of ecologic adjustment and totally reduction of living quality in cities. Programming new approaches and theories and urban management for solving of above problems, usage of cooperative approach, social mobilization and the bottom-top programming have been considered at itself focus. Fulfillment of this approach needs definition of new division system of space on the urban management and programming framework which on the basis of traditional management experiences, neighborhood because of its theoretical values, applicable and programming aspects, it can be considered as the basic element and axis of this programming. necessity of Pay attention to this concept in the urban programming system is justified, for some reason such as establishment of integrated, cooperative and rationalist management, adaptation of cultural and social changes by necessity factors on the dwelling and living in cities especially today metropolis, attempt to the domestic and local values and attitudes, empowering of identity feeling and also social belonging. In this framework, the main purpose of the present thesis is review of historical changes, role and action, space organization of Iranian urban neighborhood during different period and effort for presentation of sustainable pattern of neighborhood living, agreement of socio-economical and cultural requirements of current years for urban development. As a result, these life conditions, values and foundations in urban neighborhood were undergoing and fundamental changes, by locating city and urban neighborhood to modern elements and symbols, establishment of polar structure in the urban neighborhood were accepted principle of that era. Structural elements and new operation in the urban neighborhood which has been outstanding during this period. New structural elements and functions were created in urban neighborhood space that didn’t exist before this experience, and management of neighborhood has been changed by establishment of new bureaucracy as a form of City Council and municipality. In fact, being less important the principles of Iranian native culture and replacing &amp; superiority of western thought in urban neighborhood structure, has played a key role and On the other hand, development with fundamental changes has had particularities of exotic development. Due to these conditions, it is possible to achieve to sustainable neighborhood pattern in the Iran cities perspective and specially metropolis with empowering propriety of social capital and factors on the basis of reliance, belonging, social cohesion of neighborhood, community oriented urban management in Iran and establishment of management system which has power and authority, cooperation, responsible, legitimate and institution oriented.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>محله‌، اجتماع محلی‌، سرمایه اجتماعی‌، حکمروایی محله‌ای‌، شکل محله‌، محله پایدار‌‌.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>neighborhood, local society, social capital, neighborhood governance, shape of neighborhood, sustainable neighborhood.</keyword>
	<start_page>163</start_page>
	<end_page>184</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-90-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Majid</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Abdollahi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مجید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عبداللهی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>abdollahi847@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600148</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600148</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
