<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>30</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>نقش فضاهای عمومی ساختمان‌های مسکونی بلندمرتبه در افزایش تعاملات اجتماعی ساکنین؛ پژوهش موردی: برج بین‌المللی تهران</title_fa>
	<title>The role of public spaces of high-rise residential buildings in increasing the residents’ social interactions (Case study: International Tower of Tehran)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>امروزه با رشد روزافزون جمعیت شهرها از یک سو؛ و افزایش قیمت زمین از سوی دیگر، روی آوردن انسان به ارتفاع در بسیاری از شهرهای پرجمعیت جهان به امری اجتناب‌ناپذیر مبدل گشته است. از این رو بشر همواره به دنبال یافتن راهکارهایی برای کاهش اثرات منفی زندگی در ارتفاع بر سلامت فردی و اجتماعی خویش بوده است. از مهم‌ترین عواملی که می‌توانند در کاهش این اثرات نقشی اساسی ایفا کنند، فضاهای باز و جمعی مجموعه‌های بلندمرتبه هستند. فضاهای جمعی یک مجتمع مسکونی بلندمرتبه، اگر از طراحی مناسب برای تجمع ساکنین برخوردار باشد، می‌تواند به عرصه‌هایی برای تعامل و تبادل نظر ساکنین مبدل گردد. این فضاها را می‌توان به نوعی در امتداد فضاها و عرصه‌های زندگی خصوصی افراد دانست که وجود آن‌ها در یک مجتمع مسکونی حیاتی است. این پژوهش با این فرض پیش رفت که با افزایش تدریجی ارتفاع، میزان تعاملات اجتماعی ساکنین کاهش می‌یابد. برای آزمون فرضیه، برج بین‌المللی تهران به عنوان نمونه موردی انتخاب گردید و تأثیر تدریجی ارتفاع بر روابط و تعاملات ساکنین این مجتمع مسکونی مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. در همین راستا، تعداد 70 پرسشنامه به صورت تصادفی در میان ساکنین برج توزیع گردید. بعد از جمع‌آوری پرسشنامه‌ها، اطلاعات مربوط به هر سوال دسته‌بندی شد و پس از تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها نتایجی به دست آمد که نشان داد افزایش تدریجی ارتفاع با تعاملات اجتماعی ساکنین رابطه‌ای غیرخطی دارد. در نهایت با توجه به این رابطه و به منظور مقابله با کاهش روابط ساکنین، راهکارهایی برای بالا بردن سطح تعاملات اجتماعی ساکنین در مجتمع‌های مسکونی بلندمرتبه مطرح گردید. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Due to the growth of city population and a sharp rise in land cost, families living in high-rise buildings have been on the increase over the last several years. Therefore, people have always looked for the ways to reduce the negative health effects of living in high stories. One of the most important factors that could play a key role in reducing these effects is public open spaces in the residential areas. A well-designed open space can make them appropriate for residents’ social interactions. These spaces can be regarded as the continuation of private lives that their existence is necessary for a residential complex. The hypothesis of this study was that the residents’ social interactions decrease by gradual increase in height. International tower of Tehran was selected as the case study and the impact of increasing height on social interactions was studied. The questionnaires were randomly distributed among 70 residents of the tower. After collecting the questionnaires, the data and information related to each question were categorized. The result of analyzing the data showed that a gradual increase in height has a linear relation with the social interaction of residents. Finally, according to this relation, and also in order to prevent a decline in social interactions between residents, some strategies were suggested to promote the level of social interactions in high-rise residential complexes.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>ارتفاع، ساختمان بلند مرتبه، فضاهای جمعی، تعاملات اجتماعی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Height, High-rise Building, Public Spaces, Social Interactions.</keyword>
	<start_page>7</start_page>
	<end_page>18</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-165-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Kashfi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدعلی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کشفی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>hosseini@iust.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600347</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600347</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Seyed Baqer</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hoseini</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سیدباقر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حسینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600348</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600348</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Saeed</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Noroozian Maleki</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سعید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نوروزیان ملکی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600349</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600349</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
