<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>34</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>رویکردی تحلیلی به تأثیر آیین ها بر جسم و جان شهرها</title_fa>
	<title>Realization of the Customs’ Influences on Urban’ Physique and Soul</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
اجرای آیین ها و مراسم یکی از ارکان اساسی هویت فرهنگی تمامی جوامع بوده است و همواره یکی از شاخصه های تأثیر گذار بر جسم و جان شهرها بوده است در کشور ما، به واسطه پیشینه فرهنگی غنی، آیین ها از جایگاهی ویژه برخوردار است و توانی بالقوه در پیوند ساکنان شهرها با محیط زندگی اشان می باشد. این پژوهش بر آن است که به مطالعه تأثیر آیین ها بر جسم و جان شهرها بپردازد. آیین ها با توجه به ماهیت اشان در چهار دسته قابل بررسی می باشند که عبارتند از: آیین های کهن، آیین های مذهبی، آیین های موردی و آیین های محلی. در این مقاله آیین های محلی به واسطه گستردگی و تنوع اشان مورد بررسی قرار نمی گیرند. با کنکاش در تأثیر هر دسته از آیین ها بر جسم و جان شهرها ابعاد ناشناخته آنها شناسایی  و تأثیر آیین ها بر روحیه و در سه گروه آموزه های معنوی، آموزه های فردی و آموزه های اجتماعی مشخص گردید. در ارتباط با تأثیر آیین ها بر کالبد شهرها سه زمینه عناصر ثابت، عناصر نیمه ثابت و عناصر متحرک مورد پژوهش قرار می گیرد که این تأثیرات علاوه بر این که کالبد شهرها را دگرگون می سازد در روحیه ساکنان شهرها نیز تأثیر بسیار می گذارد و سبب می گردد شهروندان خود را جزئی از محیطی فرهنگی، اجتماعی، کالبدی ادراک و شناسایی نموده و در رابطه با اصلاح آن کوشا باشند. 
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
Due to a rich cultural history, holding of ceremonies and customs have a special position in Iran. Upon passing of time, the people are insisting on performing their ceremonies including males, females, old men, old women and even adolescences. They make ready their living place for holding of ceremonies which are created through a long-term history. Upon starting the time of ceremonies throughout the city and/or different cities, we are witnessing of great changes in the civil environment not only for changing in cities skeleton but also fundamental changes in the mood of residents. It is in a way prior to start up of these ceremonies, we may witness a movement and changing the whole cities with a fresh soul as well. There are some major and minor elements sometimes in fixed and/or semi-fixed and moving of cities which make the cities ready for concerned ceremonies. This paper intends to recognize any effects of different ceremonies on the skeleton of cities. Then the goals of research are presented as follows: How the ceremonies are effective on cities’ skeleton? How the ceremonies are effective on the mood of cities? Firstly in this research we could analyzed relevant discussions about the mode and life of city and then divided them into three groups of elements (fixed, semi-fixed and moving) by the help of field researches and interpretation method. Then it was possible to specify any effects of which on relevant elements. Regarding all mentioned items, the most important consequences of ceremonies in society are: Citizenship feeling, belonging feeling to a place, belonging feeling to social cultural and religious groups, changing of non-active citizens into active ones and upgrading the meaning of citizenship. It may cause also closer connections of a person with civil environment and close contact between environment and citizens. These are important issues as much attractive as possible for urban planning scientists. As it is obvious, both theoretical and practical viewpoints are considered as the important priorities of discussions for upgrading the interactions of citizens with civil environment. Finally we may state that increasing any contacts with citizens and environment is the most important effects of ceremonies on cities’ skeleton. In case the citizens consider themselves as an integrated part of the environment, they will feel more responsibilities against it. Therefore they are not so much indifferent against the environment and they will be changed into social supporters and environment watches. 
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>آیین, جسم شهر, جان شهر, عناصر ثابت, عناصر نیمه ثابت, عناصر متحرک.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Urban’ Physique and Soul, ceremonies, cities’ skeleton, mood of cities </keyword>
	<start_page>41</start_page>
	<end_page>58</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-758-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Farah</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Habib</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>فرح</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حبیب</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002074</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002074</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Naqi Zadeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نقی زاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002075</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002075</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Nooshin</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Karimi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>نوشین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کریمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002076</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002076</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شهر ری</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
