<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>30</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa> بررسی انگیزه های تخلف احداث بنای مازاد بر تراکم ساختمانی در شهر تهران</title_fa>
	<title>An investigation of the motives for FAR contravention in Tehran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>بخش عمده ای از مسائل و ناهنجاری های کلانشهر تهران را می توان به تخلفات ساختمانی نسبت داد که پس از رشد مهاجرت به شهر، رونق ساخت و ساز و رواج فروش تراکم و ضابطه در شهر تهران شدت یافت. پیامدهای وسیع این پدیده و ناکارآمدی شهرداری تهران در کنترل مناسب ساخت و ساز های شهری، پیشگیری از وقوع این تخلف را در شهر تهران، از طریق تعدیل یا حذف علل پیدایش یا گسترش آن ضروری می سازد. در این مقاله با مرور مطالعاتی که تاکنون در زمینه علل وقوع تخلفات ساختمانی انجام شده است، به بررسی علل و انگیزه های اقدام به یکی از انواع مهم تخلف ساختمانی در شهر تهران (تخلف احداث بنای مازاد بر تراکم مجاز) از طریق بررسی ارتباط بین 6 شاخص آگاهی از قوانین و مقررات ساخت و ساز، انگیزه رفع نیاز خانواده از طریق احداث بنای خلاف، انگیزه سود اقتصادی خلاف، سطح درآمد مالکین، تخصص و تجربه سازندگان و کیفیت نظارت بر ساخت و ساز بر یکدیگر و بر تخلف ساختمانی مازاد تراکم پرداخته شد. اطلاعات لازم برای هر شاخص از طریق یک یا چند سوال از 150 نفر از افرادی که برای پرونده تخلف ساختمانی خود به شهرداری مراجعه کرده اند جمع آوری شد و روش همبستگی پیرسون و تحلیل مسیر برای تحلیل اطلاعات استفاده شد. نتیجه نشان داد که مهم ترین عامل موثر بر تخلف ساختمانی مازاد بر تراکم، کم بودن آگاهی سازنده ساختمان از مقررات و استانداردهای ساختمان است (میزان اثر مستقیم و غیر مستقیم بر این تخلف بر اساس ضریب بتا: 0.616). و پس از آن به ترتیب، سطح درآمد (با ضریب 0.14) و انگیزه رفع نیاز خانواده از طریق احداث یا توسعه غیر قانونی بنا (با ضریب 0.119) با وقوع تخلف مازاد تراکم ارتباط دارند. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Non- compliance with building regulations is one of the major abnormalities in Tehran that its effects can be seen in different aspects and levels. There are different kinds of building contraventions in Tehran that FAR contravention is the most numerous among them. This paper aims to find some reasons for FAR contravention in the city through the consideration of the effect of social, economical motivations and the monitoring system about urban constructions on FAR contravention. Therefore, six indicators including level of awareness, violation of regulations with the aim of meeting the minimum needs of housing (housing related motives), violation of regulations with the aim of gaining financial profit (profit making motives), owner's income level, experience and expertise level of developers, and the quality of supervision and monitoring are determined and the information gathered through questionnaires answered by 150 persons whose cases were under investigation in the municipality and the information are analyzed through path analysis. According to the results, the FARTHEST contraventions have been occurred due to the low level of awareness of citizens about building bylaws and the importance of complying with them in Tehran. In addition, meeting the necessity to more covered space and room for housing or working, and the income level are the principal factors affecting on the occurrence of FAR contravention in the city. </abstract>
	<keyword_fa>ضوابط و مقررات ساختمانی، تخلف ساختمانی، تراکم ساختمانی، تهران.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Building regulations, Building bylaws, building contravention, FAR regulation, Tehran.</keyword>
	<start_page>145</start_page>
	<end_page>162</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-227-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Elnaz</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Sarkheili</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>الناز</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سرخیلی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>e.sarkheyli@modares.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600495</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600495</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mojtaba</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rafiian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مجتبی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رفیعیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600496</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600496</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Bemanian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بمانیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600497</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600497</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
