
	<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"	xmlns:cr_unixml="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2020-07-23T07:27:34+04:30</responseDate>
	<request metadataPrefix="cr_unixml" verb="ListRecords" set="10.1002">http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?mag_id=11&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</request>
	<ListRecords>
		
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-449</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Zoning the Potential Areas for Nature-based Tourism Using GIS: A Case Study of Isfahan Province</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>E</given_name>
					<surname>Seydaei Golsefidi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Seyyedeh Somayeh</given_name>
					<surname>Hoseini</surname>
					<email>sshosseini1361@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The present study intended to determine the priority areas for nature-based tourism in Isfahan province, Iran. Considering the components in question, this study was applied-developmental in nature and its methodology was descriptive-survey based on a systematic analysis of the potentials utilization, potential assessment and identification of priority areas and their combination. To carry out the assessment, the natural tourism attractions were ranked in terms of three variables, namely number of attractions, level of performance (national, local and international) and level of access (pedestrian vs. car). As the findings of the study indicated, the Southern and Western regions of Isfahan Province were of the greatest potential for natural tourism. For ranking purpose, Isfahan Province was divided into 5 categories and it was found that Semirom, Chadegan, Fereydunshahr and Fereydan counties scored the highest hence, these counties can be considered as the priority areas for nature-based tourism development. The study on the potential assessment of Isfahan Province in terms of nature-based tourism development revealed that based on the assigned scores, approximately up to %15.18 and %11.78 of the natural tourism attractions existing in this province are located in the Semirom and Fereydunshahr counties, respectively. Accordingly, it can be claimed that these two counties are of paramount significance as the two axial nature-based tourism priority areas in Isfahan Province. As a result, nature-based tourism can be considered as one of the most important development areas for these two counties. 

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>nature-based tourism</keyword>
	<keyword> Geography Information System (GIS)</keyword>
	<keyword> Isfahan province</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>7</first_page>
								  <last_page>14</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-449-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-450</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Recognizing and Analyzing Iranian – Islamic Identity of Shohada square in Mashhad from the path leading to the Holy Shrine of Imam Reza (from the Beginning to modern times)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Mohammad Reza</given_name>
					<surname>Bemanian</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Amir Ehsan</given_name>
					<surname>Pooyan</surname>
					<email>pouyanehsan@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Abbas</given_name>
					<surname>Hosein Zadeh</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			In today's cities, especially metropolises, the issue of identity and its transformation has become one of the most important issues among urban authorities and designers. Mean while, Mashhad as the second religious metropolises in the world has an identity- causing and effective role among Islamic cities of Iran In recent decades, the amount of urban construction, especially in central part of the city, has significantly increased. This trend has involved identity developments, too. Shohada square as a case study is one of the most crowded squares and the connecting point of six major wags linking Mashhad, railway stretch, Kooh Sangi neighborhood, Khaje Rabei, the Holy Shrine, Ferdowsi square, and Shahid Kalantari highway, which is among the main centers affecting the identity of city – center fabric and creating a sense of place. In this regard, we study the interaction between men and place via the environment's psychological leverage so that in addition to achieve a sense of more satisfaction of the residential place, feelings of attachment to the place, security, identity, and originality is reinforced. However, is seems that what is nowadays defined as an Iranian – Islamic model for urban environments is not an appropriate response for the Islamic community and richness of Iranian architecture. Thus, the value of introducing and offering some suggestions in lined with this requirement and analyzing the bases for the formation and organization of Shohada square as an environment with a historical – religious background is not less than investigating the divine affairs. Findings suggest that there is an increasing trend toward diversity in buildings, especially urban squares we are considering culture as a dynamic issue, so that we could provide an appropriate bed for achieving an original identity, an environment to live, and establishing more spatial attachment for people. 
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Identity</keyword>
	<keyword> Iranian- Islamic city</keyword>
	<keyword> Shohada Square</keyword>
	<keyword> Mashhad.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>15</first_page>
								  <last_page>26</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-450-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-452</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Women’s Experience of Cultural Consequences of Internet-Based Marriage in Isfahan</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Maryam</given_name>
					<surname>Allah Dadian</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Faezeh</given_name>
					<surname>Taqipoor</surname>
					<email>faezeh.taghipour@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			One of the changes brought up by the Internet both in Iran and in the other parts of the world is internet-based marriage. The present study aimed to explore Isfahani women experiences of the cultural consequences of internet-based marriage. To this end, a qualitative-phenomenological research design was used. The participants in the research sample were 12 women who became familiar with their husband via the internet and married them. The participants were selected through purposeful sampling using snowball method. Besides, the data were collected through in-depth interviews and were analyzed usingColaizzi method of analysis. Accordingly, a number of 140 significant codes were extracted. Then, a number of themes were elicited and negative and positive cultural consequences were recognized in terms of values, norms, customs, and family. The participants’ experiences of cultural consequences of internet-based marriage included concepts such as mistrust, the reinforcement of emotional relations, reduced biases, the concealment of type of marriage, disbelief in traditional marriage, the lost of family connections and influences, and poor consultation in family. 
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Internet-based marriage</keyword>
	<keyword> Women</keyword>
	<keyword> Cultural Interactions</keyword>
	<keyword> Virtual Relationships</keyword>
	<keyword> Cultural Consequences</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>27</first_page>
								  <last_page>42</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-453</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>A study and an analysis of prevalence of child mortality caused by accidents with an emphasis on solutions and recommendations for prevention the case study: Tehran Metropolis in a 10-year period (2003-2013)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Esmat Alsadat</given_name>
					<surname>Hashemi</surname>
					<email>es.hashemi@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Today a huge amount of children’s death rate is caused by accidents which remind us the necessity of scientific evaluation and scaling to make a basis for practical actions in this field both properly and efficiently. In National Documents and International conventions, children’s rights especially Millennium Development Goals declining the children’s death rate has been given a special attention. On the other hand, although the recognition of the reasons of death rate prevalence among children has not been recognized appropriately and comprehensively, what we can infer from the existing statistics is that one important reason which endangers the children’s healthfulness is the accidents. In fact without comprehensive and official statistics from children’s injuries, the rate of epidemical accidents and also without having enough information about the accidents which don’t lead to death or the conceptual difficulties about defining an accident and consensus about it, in academic discourse we cannot consider any  suitable image from the question and its solution, as well. Therefore for reaching exact statistics and also analyzing statistical data, in this article children’s death rates for children aged 18 and under in Tehran in the first step “Cross-sectional method” and “Meta-analytic methods” and also in the second step “The Survey method” have been employed.  In the first step all the previous studies relating to this field of study has been both conceptually and operationally analyzed and the results have been presented in this study. In the second step, through making a conceptual model, the operational variables have been defined and after analyzing the statistics in SPSS, the children’s death status in the 10-year period between 2003-2013 has been analyzed. At the end there are some solutions noted to reduce the death rate arising from accidents between children.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>prevalence of child mortality</keyword>
	<keyword> recommendations for prevention</keyword>
	<keyword> accidents</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>43</first_page>
								  <last_page>54</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-454</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Area-Specification affected by Industrial-Mineral Pollution in Isfahan Province</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Mohammad</given_name>
					<surname>Emami Amin</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mehran</given_name>
					<surname>Shiravand</surname>
					<email>shiravand2012@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Air pollution is a consequence of human activities, especially in the period after industrial revolution, which has many (direct and indirect) effects on the human and the environment around him. Among different kinds of pollutions, those related to industries and mines are much more dangerous. Therefore, it is necessary to identify these pollutions and specify them so as to reduce the harmful effects of them. In this regard, Isfahan Province is considered one of the industrial and mineral pivots of the country therefore, it is necessary to recognize and define the industrial-mineral pollution in this area. This research examines the industrial and mineral pollution data of the cities located in Isfahan province within a several-year period of time. At first, the data was analyzed by SPSS and then entered into the software Arc GIS, and then the areas were specified. The data of the wind’s direction and speed was also used to determine the relationship between industrial-mineral pollution and the wind. The results showed that as we go from the west and north toward the center of province, the intensity of pollution is increased. The highest amount of industrial pollution belonged to the cities of Isfahan, Borkhar, Kashan, Aran and Bidgol. And regarding mineral pollution, the highest amountsbelonged to Isfahan, falavarjan and Naiin In terms of point, the cities of Khur and Chadegan had the least amount of pollution. The wind's direction in Isfahan province is from the West and in the months of June, July, and August it is from Northwest.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Industrial-Mineral Pollution</keyword>
	<keyword> Area-Specification</keyword>
	<keyword> GIS</keyword>
	<keyword> Isfahan Province.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>55</first_page>
								  <last_page>60</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-472</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Comparative study of the physical and substantive components of the architecture of the mosque, case study: the Mosque – School Aghabozorg in Kashan and Mosque - School Putrajaya Malaysia</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Seyyed Majid</given_name>
					<surname>Mofidi Shemirani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Shahaab</given_name>
					<surname>Ilka</surname>
					<email>shahabilka@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The architecture of the mosque and the mosque of Islam to the present day with the new architecture of the symbols of wisdom are very high. Throughout history, structural and functional changes in the geometry of the mosque can be seen that the former mosque, reflecting the specific changes and is applicable. Designed mosques abroad in terms of structural and physical components, a special division that can be compared to the comparative study of Iranian-Islamic mosques, monitored and evaluated This paper focuses on two areas: First, structural changes, geometric and functional architecture of mosques in Iran is studied and analyzed Second, in a comparative study of comparative analogy of two mosques inside and outside Iran. The research methods and theoretical research in the literature, analytic method from studies and documents library is used. In the expression of the genetic component of the mosque, legal and comparative analysis of the case study is used. Finally, the results on the geometric changes and functional architecture of mosques in different historical periods on the one hand, and the Iranian mosques and Islamic architectural monuments, mosques foreign examples are presented.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>comparative analysis</keyword>
	<keyword> and substantive components of the physical architecture of mosques</keyword>
	<keyword> cultural representations.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>61</first_page>
								  <last_page>82</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-507</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Strategic Planning to Organize the Urban Historic Fabric Emphasizing on The sustainable development case study: Dezful city</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Hosein</given_name>
					<surname>Esmaili Sangari</surname>
					<email>f_esmaeili_s@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Vahid</given_name>
					<surname>Eilaee</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
This long-lasting point in his life due to economic developments, social and cultural development of the Industrial Revolution, the foundation has been transformed. Today, the need for rehabilitation and restoration of these islands what the city increases, the need to develop a coherent and logical connection between the old and new areas to preserve and enhance the integrity and identity of the city. In this paper, a brief review of the literature on rehabilitation of old textures, and the appropriate approach to understanding the evolution of the spatial structure of the historic fabric of Dezful different historical periods up to date, must be taken. Anatomical studies of the topic, the understanding of the basic structure is in place. The purpose of the original structure, which includes a set of core elements and activities regularly and continuously main city squares and streets that make up the urban areas. These elements are classified into two groups: natural elements and artificial elements. Natural elements are: Altitude, rivers, vegetation and built elements include: building and activity center, open green spaces and urban roads. In the access network, linking different parts of the city and outside the city's first and second communications network and internal network access between the main skeletal elements of the historic fabric is implemented. In addition to understanding the functions and activities of the functional characteristics of urban, social - cultural and economic activities are also analyzed. The characteristics of visual, symbolic signs and urban networks will be studied in the city.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Sustainability</keyword>
	<keyword> Historical</keyword>
	<keyword> Urban</keyword>
	<keyword> Fabric</keyword>
	<keyword> Dezful city</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>83</first_page>
								  <last_page>94</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-508</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Identifying effective factors on profit of public equity firms</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Maria</given_name>
					<surname>Ilka</surname>
					<email>mariailka85@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Identification of influential factors of firms has always been one of the main concerns for both academics and practitioners in the realm of finance. The aim of this study is to identify the role of managers of the firms on this issue. Statistical society of this research is all the public equity firms of Tehran which are registered in Tehran Stock Exchange. The sample is 61 of those firms in different industries. Results show that those registered firms who have board of managers with more independency have reported more profit at the end of their financial year. Managerial implications are presented and directions for future studies are shown at the end of this research. 
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>profit management</keyword>
	<keyword> managerial board</keyword>
	<keyword> public equity.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>95</first_page>
								  <last_page>102</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-509</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Risk Management Plan in Large Urban Projects</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Ehsanollah</given_name>
					<surname>Eshtehardian</surname>
					<email>eshtehardian@modares.ac.ir</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Saeed</given_name>
					<surname>Khodaverdi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
One of the risks distinguishes urban projects from other projects is to purchase of property obstacles. The matter is of more significance in large projects. Issues with regard to possessing property obstacles, lack of accurate layout drawings for underground facilities and following probable changes in designs make it vital to have specific studies on risk management of such projects. So this paper investigates the implementation of risk management plan in large urban projects through a case study, namely Imam Ali highway. To do this, first some generic information is discussed in each section and then it is tried to show how incorporate it in the project studied. According to qualitative analysis done, the issues of obstacles, weak feasibility studies, and inadequacies of resources (scaffolding &amp; forming material) were the main risk factors of the project. In another effort, using Monte Carlo Simulation, the quantitative analysis was done on some outputs of qualitative analysis, and numerical probabilities to achieve scheduled finishing date of the project were obtained.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>PROJECT MANAGEMENT</keyword>
	<keyword> URBAN PROJECTS</keyword>
	<keyword> RISK MANAGEMENT</keyword>
	<keyword> QUALITATIVE ANALYSIS</keyword>
	<keyword> QUANTITATIVE ANALYSIS</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>103</first_page>
								  <last_page>114</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-510</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Nature as a Source of Inspiration of Architectural Conceptual Design</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Sarah</given_name>
					<surname>Naseri</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mohammad Mehdi</given_name>
					<surname>Bolandian</surname>
					<email>m.bolandian@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
From the beginning of creation, human being was surrounded by nature. Everything in nature is well organized and in harmony with the other parts of it. Through the history, nature has been always a source of inspiration for the human begin in different aspects of their life. Architecture as one of the remarkable features in every society cannot be separated from nature. In architecture design works even the ones which have been designed so close to nature, still there are some missing parts in one of their forms, function, or structure. Therefore, the best solution for the architects and designers to increase the optimization in their design works is looking at the nature in every aspect deeper and try to apply them as much as they can in their conceptual design of their project which is the heart of the design process, the point at which the actual form, character, and design details of the project are the best established and finalized. Although, there are a wider areas of inspiration from nature studies in architecture like organic architecture, constructive architecture, deconstructive architecture, and etc. but this study is not going through the philosophy of inspiration from nature and it focusing on the more engineering ones like bionic architecture, Bio mimicry and levels of inspiration.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>nature</keyword>
	<keyword> bionic</keyword>
	<keyword> Conceptual Design</keyword>
	<keyword> forms</keyword>
	<keyword> function</keyword>
	<keyword> or structure.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>115</first_page>
								  <last_page>128</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-511</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Defining the Building-Integrated Photovoltaic Designs in architecture and urbanism with Emphasis on Usage in Iran</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Reza</given_name>
					<surname>Keshavarz Norooz Poor</surname>
					<email>rezakeshavarz6@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
Demand of energy is more sensible now because of population growth and economic growth of countries. In order to increase of energy consumption around the world and environment pollution, attention to the renewable energy such as solar energy is inevitable. Building-integrated photovoltaic (BIPV) electric power systems not only produce electricity, they are also part of the building. For example, a BIPV skylight is an integral component of the building envelope as well as a solar electric energy system that generates electricity for the building. These solar systems are thus multifunctional construction materials. The standard element of a BIPV system is the PV module. Individual solar cells are interconnected and encapsulated on various materials to form a module. Modules are strung together in an electrical series with cables and wires to form a PV array. Direct or diffuse light (usually sunlight) shining on the solar cells induces the photovoltaic effect, generating unregulated DC electric power. This DC power can be used, stored in a battery system, or fed into an inverter that transforms and synchronizes the power into AC electricity. The electricity can be used in the building or exported to a utility company through a grid interconnection. The primary intent of this article is to provide architects and designers with useful information on BIPV systems in the enclosed design briefs. Each brief provides specific technical data about the BIPV system used, including the system’s size, weight, and efficiency as well as number of inverters required for it. This is followed by photographs and drawings of the systems along with general system descriptions, special design considerations, and mounting attachment details. The primary intent of this sourcebook is to provide architects and designers with useful information on BIPV systems in the enclosed design briefs. Each brief provides specific technical data about the BIPV system used, including the system’s size, weight, and efficiency as well as number of inverters required for it. This is followed by photographs and drawings of the systems along with general system descriptions, special design considerations, and mounting attachment details. The finding of research shows development strategy is to enhance systems technologies, to work on the architecture of building integrated PV, and to assess and remove non-technical barriers that impede the widespread application of PV in the built environment.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Building-Integrated Photovoltaic</keyword>
	<keyword> Designs of building</keyword>
	<keyword> Suggestions and strategies.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>129</first_page>
								  <last_page>146</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-512</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Interpretive Structural Modeling of Urban Development Empowerment</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Abdolreza</given_name>
					<surname>Rahmani Fazli</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Hamid</given_name>
					<surname>Shaah Bandar Zadeh</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Mehran</given_name>
					<surname>Shiravand</surname>
					<email>shiravand2012@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name>Seyyed Salman</given_name>
					<surname>Samani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
Cities are centers of technology-based transformations and play pivotal role in economic procedures. Moreover, cities are the social, cultural pivots and center for political challenges either in peace or violence and war. Cities possess a distinguishing share in societies’ economic growth and development. Future of the development of the developing countries is concentrated in cities. Therefore, the article aims at empowerment of urban development and also recognition of relations and modeling of the mentioned elements. Empowerment of urban development is recognized through investigation of the literature of the subject and elites’ opinions. Thereafter, using Interpretive Structural Modeling, the relationship between these empowerments is recognized, based on which a structural model of empowerments effective in urban development is constructed. The results show that economic and cultural, technological, environmental, and population factors are among the most important empowerments in the context of urban development. Based on the results, managers are recommended t concentrate more on these radical factors in their urban development-based activities.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Urban Development</keyword>
	<keyword> Interpretive Structural Modeling Approach</keyword>
	<keyword> Bushehr City</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>147</first_page>
								  <last_page>154</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-513</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Urban planning, urban Management &amp; Urban Air Pollution and solutions for solving it </title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Zohreh</given_name>
					<surname>Farshi Haqqi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mohammad</given_name>
					<surname>Zarqani</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Ali Asghar</given_name>
					<surname>Ehsani Fard</surname>
					<email>Aliasghar_ehsanifard@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
In response to the facts that some Asian developing countries were experiencing the fastest rate of industrialisation and urbanisation, several international initiatives called for a better and ‘sustainable’ urban management. Development of management tools including strategic environmental assessment (SEA), life cycle assessment (LCA), cost benefit analysis (CBA), and environmental management system (EMS) had widened a scope of traditional management remarkably. For instance, urban water management that used to deal only with an aspect of ‘urban water’ is nowadays required to consider urban water issues in a larger perspective, namely whole river and catchment’s ecosystem. The management of the latter is called river basin management. Yet still, it is also realised that various managements (e.g. air, poverty, water, socio-economic etc.) were actively inter-linked and influenced each other on the same platform of ‘urban’ and could not be dealt in isolation. As a challenge to respond to these complex urban problems, an ecosystem approach was considered to be a powerful tool to achieve a holistic management. By taking widely known ecosystem approach frameworks into consideration, this paper attempted to discuss on applicability of ecosystem approach to urban air pollution management. The review provided current knowledge on urban air pollution problems and pros and cons of urban and peri-urban agriculture as an example. In discussion, millennium ecosystem framework and human ecosystem frameworks were explored in terms of urban air pollution management. This inspired a process approach and its usefulness was analysed in the light of translating the philosophy of ecosystem approach into practise. In this particular case, ambient urban air pollution and promotion of urban and peri-urban agriculture was discussed as an example. The findings showed that although the process approach could supplement those frameworks in practise to some extent, it had a difficulty in addressing the social system that played a major role in urban ecosystem. It was indicated that the social system was considered to associate closely with spatial and temporal heterogeneity in the target area. And the approach must figure out a way to incorporate them effectively towards successful urban ecosystem approach. The suggestion was made on another approach that could facilitate to bring the philosophy of ecosystem approach into actual urban management.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Urban Air Pollution</keyword>
	<keyword> transport goals</keyword>
	<keyword> process approach</keyword>
	<keyword> Targets</keyword>
	<keyword> emissions and air quality</keyword>
	<keyword> urban management</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>155</first_page>
								  <last_page>166</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-514</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title> Description the Design with Nature in Bio-Architecture and urban design</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Mahmood</given_name>
					<surname>Rezaee</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Shahab</given_name>
					<surname>Ilka</surname>
					<email>shahabilka@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
The relation between nature and human considers different periods. At first it was bio-utilization which degrades the value of nature as a source of energy and material. After revolution in science development and attention to the damages which they made to environment, they tried to change their look to this issue and expand the mean of relation between human and nature. Birth of such word like ignition emphasize on the new point of view at nature. Bionic is the science that is formed from the combination of various natural and engineering science concepts. It is the study of complex vital systems of live organisms and natural forms and maybe a good solution for solving technical and structural issues of engineers. Nowadays when it is talked about technology, different kinds of cars and big buildings are stroked in human mind It is clear that if the technology result which is the answer of fundamental human needs is considered, it almost will be clear the reason of some circumstances, that each industrial or structural phenomena has been inspired from which natural alive pattern, so it has to be a relation with logical and scientific principles between mechanical system and alive constant system. The first zone contains human and nature informant principles and introduces their relation periods. In the second zone it is surveyed nature rule in human life, in third zone the nature is presented as a teacher and a source of human sprite, and the last zone expresses the relation between architecture and nature and the architecture usage way from nature with some real examples and finally the way for reaching a favorite architecture and the advantages of patterning natural forms and the cause of knowing nature order more and more considered at the conclusion.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>nature</keyword>
	<keyword> architecture</keyword>
	<keyword> Bionic science </keyword>
	<keyword> Bionic architecture.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>167</first_page>
								  <last_page>188</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-515</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Assessment and evaluation on Livable city Case study: Tehran, Neighborhood Darake </title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Maryam</given_name>
					<surname>Safavi</surname>
					<email>star_safavi@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mohammad Taqi</given_name>
					<surname>Razavian</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Gholam Reza</given_name>
					<surname>Koohestani Faarooj</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
Following the global trend of economic and social change, urbanization has been increasing. The trend that has dominated in recent decades in developing countries is the outshining of growth over development which has challenged the maintaining and improving the city residents’ quality of life. One of the most recent topics in the theory of urbanism in response to the decline of urban life  has been addressing the concept of &quot;livable city&quot; that includes all aspects of environmental, social, cultural, historical, infrastructure, governance and participation and applies the strategies such as new urbanization, urban smart growth and increasing development by pressing and human scale of city construction and user intermixture to create diverse options of transportation habitat, attractive and walkable neighborhood which improve the life quality and lead us to have a better environment and more sustainable urban development. The Present study examines the livable ranking of Tehran city and since a livable city is composed of strong neighborhoods, we examined livability of Darake by considering the global indicators and its compliance with local standards. The research method is descriptive-analytic and the results indicated that: auto-oriented transportation, non-variety in settlement and shortage of public spaces are three factors of reducing livability of Darake Neighborhood in Tehran and finally, some suggestions are given in order to increase its livability.  

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>livable city</keyword>
	<keyword> Sustainable urban development</keyword>
	<keyword> new urbanization</keyword>
	<keyword> urban smart Growth</keyword>
	<keyword> Quality of Life</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>189</first_page>
								  <last_page>212</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-516</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Evaluation the theories of semiotics approach in the Reading of Architecture and Urbanism</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Alireza</given_name>
					<surname>Jafari</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mohammad Mansoor</given_name>
					<surname>Falamaki</surname>
					<email>mansourfalamaki@hotmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			
This essay is considered an attempt to present how semiotic studies can be used as a perceptional aspect in reading architecture and urbanism. Appearance of each art is similar to creation of a “text” which transfers a set of customs, values and thought together with itself. Production of each “text” is based on its context, culture and intellectual bed of its origin society. Each text is an independent message from its sender, receiver and covers a set of signs. These signs are coded by author and audience (reader) decodes it on the basis of conventions and with the help of media relation, mental impressions, and personal points of view. Semiotics is the philosophical and scientific study of semiotic: the relation of signification with sign, mind and object or more generally, the creation of meaning. Semiotic is divided in two main thought schools of structuralism and post-structuralism. Structuralism semioticians (such as “Saussure”) mostly specialized in linguistic domain, typically consider a direct relationship between the signifier and signified. By contrast, post-structuralism semioticians (such as “Peirce”, “Umberto Eco”) consider the relationship as an indirect one and seek to discover the implicit “signified” hidden in social, logical and aesthetic issues. The architecture and urban spaces has been consisted of different layers of meaning like a text. The analysis of urbanism, architecture and their spatial configuration is always seen between cognition, culture, knowledge, literature and society. These layers would make different meaning and senses for projects to be appeared in the deepest layer of a scheme. This study compares architecture and urbanism reading (like as text) based on the abovementioned perspectives after considering the theories of semioticians.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Semiotic</keyword>
	<keyword> Reading of text</keyword>
	<keyword> Structuralism Semiotics</keyword>
	<keyword> Post structuralism Semiotics</keyword>
	<keyword> Text of architecture</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>213</first_page>
								  <last_page>222</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-557</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Surveying the Spatial Justice and planning theories with emphasis on Iran’s conditions</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Mohammadreza</given_name>
					<surname>Bemanian</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mehdi</given_name>
					<surname>Bahram Poor</surname>
					<email>mehdi.bahrampour@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name>Ali Akbar</given_name>
					<surname>Taqvaee</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Segregation has been widely discussed by social scientists and especially by urban geographers and planners over the past decades. However, regardless of their focus, most of these studies view segregation as an obvious case of spatial injustice. I argue that this implicit relationship between segregation, (in) justice, and space needs to be reexamined. This paper approaches this task by reviewing an interdisciplinary body of literature (including geography, sociology, history, political sciences, and philosophy) that deals with segregation without (explicitly) tackling the issue of justice. It will then question the dominant contemporary discourse that holds that the Just City should be a diverse city at the neighborhood scale.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Justice</keyword>
	<keyword> city</keyword>
	<keyword> diversity</keyword>
	<keyword> social mix</keyword>
	<keyword> discrimination</keyword>
	<keyword> stigmatization</keyword>
	<keyword> identity</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>223</first_page>
								  <last_page>242</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-558</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>This impress of people characters (traditional and civil) in sustainable urban development</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Teimoor</given_name>
					<surname>Heidari</surname>
					<email>tm_heydari@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mehdi</given_name>
					<surname>Ahmadi</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Here in this article, there is an attempt to pay attention to the importance of people characters (traditional and civil) in the improvement of urban management due to the sustainable urban development. The deduction of this article in that people characters can play an important role in the process of developing and improving the operation of urban management by paving the way far participation of citizens in the urban affairs. These characters are of the basic factor of establishing and supporting the local society, social correlation and social capital.  In this article by the means of secondary analysis, we have settled to considering the present statistic data of the state of people- characterized organizations. Local society in our community in the form of councils, local district councils, religious and civil characters with the support of old  customs of religious resources and also relying to legal resources, have achieved proper abilities  and capacities in relation to mobilize the facilities and participation of people due to the aims of the sustainable development. Considering such abilities, the question is that, how can we use these capacities of present characters of desirable goals of sustainable development, as a sensation of the administrators of the urban management? The goal of present article is to reply this question and to provide same strategies for urban management in order to use the potential and capacities.
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword> state development</keyword>
	<keyword> urban management</keyword>
	<keyword> traditional and civil characters</keyword>
	<keyword> local embassy</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>243</first_page>
								  <last_page>252</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-591</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Sound Pollution Due To Industries, Occupations And Municipalities Role In Managing Industries Decreasing It</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Abolfazl</given_name>
					<surname>Moqimi Esfand Abadi</surname>
					<email>moghimi.ab@gmail.com</email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Sound Pollution Due To Industries, Occupations And Municipalities Role In Managing Industries Decreasing It
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Sound Pollution</keyword>
	<keyword> Industries And Occupations</keyword>
	<keyword> Municipalities</keyword>
	<keyword> Tehran.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>253</first_page>
								  <last_page>260</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>11-592</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-23</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2015</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>13</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>37</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Assessment Of Aesthetic Quality Of Urban Green Space From The User’s Perspective In Sustainable Urban Regeneration Approach Of Historic Core Of Tehran: (The Case Of Compare Between Bab Homayon Street And Imam Khomeini Street)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name>Shahrzad</given_name>
					<surname>Zeinali</surname>
					<email>zeinaliy@yahoo.com</email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name>Mehrdad</given_name>
					<surname>Karimi Moshaver</surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Assessment Of Aesthetic Quality Of Urban Green Space From The User’s Perspective In Sustainable Urban Regeneration Approach Of Historic Core Of Tehran: (The Case Of Compare Between Bab Homayon Street And Imam Khomeini Street)
			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Aesthetic</keyword>
	<keyword> Urban Green Space</keyword>
	<keyword> Sustainable Regeneration Approach.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2015</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>261</first_page>
								  <last_page>273</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl></fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
			
		</ListRecords>
		</OAI-PMH>
		 
  
  
  
  
 