<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>48</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی تطبیقی دو الگوی سنتی و غربی خانه در دوره قاجار؛ نمونه موردی: خانه مِشکیان یزد و عمارت ذوالفقاری زنجان</title_fa>
	<title>A Comparative Investigation of Two Traditional and Western Architecture Models of Houses in the Qajar Era (Case Study: Meshkian House in Yazd and Zolfaqari House in Zanjan)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;معماری قاجار فصل دگرگونی آرمان&amp;zwnj;ها و ارزش&amp;zwnj;ها و عرصه تنوع و تضاد در شیوه&amp;zwnj;ها و گرایش&amp;zwnj;های معماری و شهرسازی ایران است. این دگرگونی، همزمان با رنگ باختن تدریجی مبانی هویت اجتماعی گذشته مانند قومیت، مذهب و زبان و نیل آن به سوی مفاهیمی همچون فرادستان (خواص)، و فرودستان (عوام) نمود بسیار برجسته&amp;zwnj;ای در حوزه معماری مسکونی پیدا کرد و ساختار همگون و یکپارچه محلات سنت&amp;zwnj;محور سابق را به عرصه چالش میان سنت و تجدد و ابراز تفاوت&amp;zwnj;ها و تمایزات طبقاتی مبدل نمود. این تحقیق، از طریق بررسی توصیفی و تحلیلی چند نمونه مفروض سنتی و غربی خانه در دوره قاجار، در صدد استخراج و تبیین شاخصه&amp;zwnj;های سنت و تجدد در معماری مسکونی آن دوران دارد. یافته&amp;zwnj;های پژوهش حاکی از آن است که معماری مسکونی قاجار در گذر از جهان سنت به تجدد، صرف نظر از عدم تحول در فن ساختمان، با استقرار برون&amp;zwnj;گرایی به جای درون&amp;zwnj;گرایی، اعمال تغییرات کالبدی و فضایی در نظام گردشی و الگوبرداری مستقیم از عناصر و تزیینات معماری غرب، تحولی بسیار عظیم و پرشتاب را پشت سر نهاد؛ لیکن عدم تکاپو در راستای بهره&amp;zwnj;برداری و تکامل دستاوردهای اصیل و تاریخی معماری سنتی ایران موجب شد که تحول به وجود آمده به عرصه تقابل و تضاد در معماری مسکونی ایران مبدل گردد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Qajar architecture is a turning point in ideals and values as well as the field of diversity and contrasts in Iranian architecture and urban planning methods and tendencies. This turning point, concurrent with the gradual fade of basics of previous social identity such as ethnicity, religion, language, etc. and its movement towards concepts such as the superordinate (elites) and subordinates (people) became an outstanding instance in residential architecture in such a way that it changed the traditional homogenous and monolith structure of neighborhoods with the challenges between tradition and modernity and the use of the instrument of class differences and distinctions. The present study, conducted via a descriptive-analytical method on some case traditional and western mansions of the Qajar era, is to extract and explain characteristics of tradition and modernity in residential architecture of that era. Findings of the study show that the Qajar residential architecture passed a very tremendous and fast transformation in its passage from the traditional to the western world and regardless of no transformation in the building technology, by establishment of extroversion instead of introversion, formal and spatial changes in the circulation system, and direct modeling of elements and decorations of western architecture. However, no significant dynamics in line with utilization and completion of genuine and historical achievements of Iranian traditional architecture caused that that transformation became the field of contradictions and contrasts in Iranian residential architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>معماری قاجار, خانه‌های سنتی, خانه‌های غربی, خانه مشکیان, عمارت ذوالفقاری. </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Qajar architecture, traditional houses, western houses, Meshkian house, Zolfaqari house.</keyword>
	<start_page>333</start_page>
	<end_page>350</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-55&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سعادتی خمسه</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007860</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007860</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
