<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <records>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>7</startPage>
	<endPage>34</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Age-friendly city design criteria centers of social interaction with the concepts of space and culture approach to mental health</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Hooshang Forooghmand Araabi</name>
	<email>h-foroughmand@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Leila Karimi Fard</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
Attention to the role of the elderly in the urban planning and architecture on the one hand and the realization of the age-friendly cities, the main priorities in the process of planning and architecture. Evolutionary social context and changes in age structure of the population changes in the aging urban population, also focuses on this. Meanwhile, addressing the issue of &quot;mental health&quot; of the main psychological needs of the elderly in this study, with an emphasis on mental health theories and theories of urban design and architecture is done. Tries to measures designed to increase the space in the old centers of social interaction social interaction is discussed. The theoretical basis of this study, based on the idea of &quot;y Gasset&quot; and &quot;field theory of Kurt Lewin was&quot;. The method of &quot;descriptive&quot; in the theoretical literature and research methods &quot;meta-analysis&quot; in discussions with the Data theories and studies, including the library and documentary benefited. At the end of several strategies in order to achieve the first stage of age-friendly cities and recommendations on measures designed to improve the mental health of the elderly in the second stage agreement has been mentioned.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-697-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>age-friendly city</keyword>
	<keyword> the center of social interaction</keyword>
	<keyword> social communication theories</keyword>
	<keyword> and theories of mental health.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>35</startPage>
	<endPage>56</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Utopian ideal of utopian Shi\'ite cities</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Hadi Adib Khah</name>
	<email>spranzabianca@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
Utopia and idealism in history have had the importance of learning Utopia in view of the universal manifestation of the wishes and aspirations of human to their aspirations and dreams in the social structure of the city to bring objectivity. Accordingly, each scholar in the field of critical thought, the features and characteristics of Utopia is examined from a particular perspective Thoughtful and critical thinking and the requirements of historical, social and cultural expression and to determine the characteristics and even the type of approach to the concept of the ideal effect And so that different approaches in dealing with this issue has attracted the human mind. The research is descriptive and analytical study of Data library studies and documentary method is used. The results show that the Western utopia Find all aspects of the material world and more fully in a position of &quot;Plato's Cave&quot; are. In this analogy, the emergence of mind from the lower to the higher line, progress is the recognition of pension and mind during the development of the knowledge gained enough knowledge is inadequate The Iranian utopia, a utopia that is dependent on the Shi'i Islamic ideal and utopia Mahdavi that its characteristics are mentioned in detail.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-698-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Vision</keyword>
	<keyword> Utopia</keyword>
	<keyword> utopian theories</keyword>
	<keyword> Shiite utopia</keyword>
	<keyword> utopia Mahdavi.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>57</startPage>
	<endPage>70</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Role of Comprehensive Decentralization in Realization of Efficient Local Government</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Hosein Rahmatollahi</name>
	<email>hrahmat@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ehsan Aqa Mohammad Aqaii</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mehran Shiravand</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
Current study, assuming desirability and forcibility of the policy of maximum decentralization of official-political wills, tries to cultivate the reasons of existence of this thought from general law data. Afterwards, considering the challenges which are in fact obstacles for role-playing of citizens in the context of master political-official policy makings, the article aims at apply the results of the study in realization of an efficient and democratic local government under the policy of complete decentralization of wills considering the forms of governments. Based on this article’s findings, main characteristic of efficient local government is that ensures and empowers the process of encouragement of citizens in general areas, giving them the most possible powers and wills in political and official decision-makings. Therefore, the current study investigates the subject applying a historic-analytical approach to prove the claim.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-699-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Comprehensive Decentralization</keyword>
	<keyword> Centralization</keyword>
	<keyword> Wide Government</keyword>
	<keyword> Compound Government</keyword>
	<keyword> Central Supervision</keyword>
	<keyword> Citizen Supervision</keyword>
	<keyword> Efficient Local Government.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>71</startPage>
	<endPage>86</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Application of Hierarchical Approach to Estimate the Importance of Elements of Urban Development in a Fuzzy Environment</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Alireza Pooya</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ahmad Qorban Poor</name>
	<email>ah.ghorbanpour.62@stu-mail.um.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
Today human is engaged with a great crisis as a result of his unbalancing the life, neglecting indigenous and environmental factors, and hegemonic behavior toward nature. This has ended to creation of an approach called sustainable development whose main aims are to meet the essential needs, improvement of life quality, and better management of ecosystems. Obviously it is meaningless to discuss sustainability and sustainable development in the absence of cities and urban life. Cities are counted for as the main reasons for unsustainability the world over, however urban sustainability and global sustainability are the same concepts.  Therefore, knowing key elements to reach this station is necessary, whereas recognition and prioritization of effective key elements in sustainable development is strategic and entails economic, social, and health-related results in the sequence of time. The current study is descriptive-analytic in which attempts have been made to estimate the importance of main indices of sustainable development based on the opinions of elites using a fuzzy hierarchical analysis process technic. Analysis of the data shows that from among main indices, urban health, desirable governmental system, and sustainable environment are respectively of the highest importance.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-700-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Urban Sustainable Development</keyword>
	<keyword> Bushehr City</keyword>
	<keyword> Fuzzy Logic</keyword>
	<keyword> Fuzzy Hierarchical Analysis Process.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>87</startPage>
	<endPage>98</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">A comparative study of religious architecture and urban planning Byzantine period in Turkish Seljuk period in Iran</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Darya Nosrat Poor</name>
	<email>daryanosratpour@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Saeed Khaqani</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Vadiheh Molla Salehi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
Synchronization period on the one hand and intercultural relations in each historical period, the cultural and artistic interactions, especially in the field of architecture that representations have been specific in each period This is in comparison to the Byzantine period in Turkish and Iranian Seljuk period is more important because it can be traced Seljuk architecture and urban richness. In this paper we compare the analytical and comparative study of Byzantine and Seljuk architecture in Iran In the end, the results in the frame of the possible similarities and differences and effects of the mentioned period of time.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-705-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>architecture religious sites</keyword>
	<keyword> Byzantine</keyword>
	<keyword> Seljuk</keyword>
	<keyword> comparative study.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>99</startPage>
	<endPage>108</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Factors affecting the interest of place in educational open spaces </title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Mehdi Goodarzi Soroosh</name>
	<email>goodarzisoroush@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Vahid Qorbani</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
The human need to interact emotionally with the place where lives and Or in other words, attachment to place among the most important aspects of the relationship between people and places that need the attention of architects, designers and urban planners should be To assess the performance of the schools we see that most of the colleges and classrooms and other spaces are closed. Planners and designers paid attention to the internal spaces. The landscape and open spaces worthy of attention are neglected. Iranian university studies and applied research aimed at improving the quality of open spaces in the service of student learning, except for a few cases have been mild. In this regard, due to the lack of available scientific and professional knowledge of architecture and professional perspective can be a substantial contribution. In this context, this study aims to review and related documents in this area based on the factors involved in it. Methods In this descriptive study. The sample consists of integrated training Azad University of Hamedan, Bu Ali Sina University in Hamedan and Tehran's Imam Sadeq University. Based on the research findings place identity, emotional attachment, the quality of the physical and social links to attachment sites open spaces teaching the students have a significant effect.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-706-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>attachment to place</keyword>
	<keyword> identity</keyword>
	<keyword> location</keyword>
	<keyword> quality of the physical</keyword>
	<keyword> social ties</keyword>
	<keyword> educational open space.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>109</startPage>
	<endPage>134</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Revive and reorganize the urban tissue for citizen empowerment of women Case: Municipality of Tehran</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Maryam Faraj Poor</name>
	<email>farajpoor.m@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Alireza Dodangi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hosein Soltan Zadeh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
The old urban tissue requires more attention in the field of planning and urban management and restoration is to organize the change of use of the space at the same time that the process of reorganization and modernization can help the re-use of these spaces. On the other hand, female-headed households as a social vulnerable groups and areas of urban management should be considered. Meanwhile, the Women's Affairs Center in Tehran in this regard is important. Therefore, in this article in an analytical and rational assessment of the issue of the change of use of old tissues for recreation centers, social and economic had been women. Reference statistical analysis of the Women's Affairs Center of Tehran Municipality in this regard is the analysis of theoretical literature. The results alluding to the services of Tehran and the empowerment of women, including the design and SH series, to provide solutions to the empowerment of women-headed households is growing in Tehran.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-707-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Empowerment</keyword>
	<keyword> worn tissues</keyword>
	<keyword> regulation and rehabilitation</keyword>
	<keyword> women heads of households</keyword>
	<keyword> the center of Tehran women\'s affairs</keyword>
	<keyword> strategies and recommendations.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>135</startPage>
	<endPage>164</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Discourse of utopian future studies in Iran on Mahdism doctrine</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Mehdi Bolandian</name>
	<email>m.bolandian@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
Analysis of future efforts with resources, models and agents of change or stability, to visualize the potential futures and plan for them Future reflects the reality of tomorrow's generation from the change (or stability) today. Accordingly, outlined a comprehensive vision of urban development and the future of cities in the Islamic Republic of Iran, the Iranian-Islamic utopia needs to scrutinize the components approach the future. According to the discourse of Mahdism, are required to comply with city regulations, principles and standards that are designed to prepare the ground for the emergence of Imam Mahdi (aj) and the realization of cities are based on the principles of Islam and cultural criteria. The research paper is descriptive method of reasoning also explains the components of the utopian discourse of Mahdism and futures benefited. The documentary method and reference to library studies and documents have also been considered. In this future approach and by reference to the concept of utopia Iranian Mahdism in a competent dialogue here the idea of Mahdism of Imam Khomeini is used as a theoretical basis. Try to components, standards and solutions for the infrastructure and preparing the groundwork for the emergence of Iranian civilization and the role of urban planning and urban development is addressed in this regard.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-542-3&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>future studies</keyword>
	<keyword> architecture and urban planning discourse Mahdism</keyword>
	<keyword> the Islamic utopia</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>165</startPage>
	<endPage>188</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Phenomenological approach and the concept of living in the cultural paradigm of life</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Shaahin Ilka</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Behrooz Mansoori</name>
	<email>emarate_khorshid@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Seyyed Mohammad Reza Nasir Salaami</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Seyyed Ali Akbar Saremi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
There is no doubt that architecture has boosted the interaction of culture and culture is affected and influenced. Sociology housing issues trying to identify the circle of conceptual and semantic interaction of culture (society) and housing architecture. Thought process to reach a predefined architecture feedback conceptual architecture needs to be discussed in terms of culture and architecture of the house. The previous question is that the only place of residence can live in a space Find it called? The research paper is an analytical and logical reasoning is used by documentary and library studies. In line with the results of the phenomenological concept of residence and the residence life mentioned in the phenomenological approach and the cultural paradigm in the development of complex biological home based on cultural theories have been discussed as follows: Cultural meaning of architectural, cultural and symbolic meaning of architecture, nonverbal approach in the sense of cultural, architectural and cultural references to understand the rules of architecture, and cultural readings architecture and environment rules.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-708-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>housing</keyword>
	<keyword> housing</keyword>
	<keyword> homes and Iranian culture</keyword>
	<keyword> cultural paradigms and phenomenology of residence.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>189</startPage>
	<endPage>200</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Organizational Self-Esteem and Commitment Relationship with Job Satisfaction among Employers Working in the City of Tehran</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mahammad Taqi Haji Amoo Assaar</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Rashen Abdollahi</name>
	<email>rashinabdollahi@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Dariush Rahmati</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Vahideh Sadat Far Khojasteh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
This article aims at investigating the organizational self-esteem and commitment relationship with job satisfaction among employers of an urban service-giving institute working in the City of Tehran among whom 181 persons are selected randomly. For data collection, 3 methods of organizational self-esteem questionnaire by Pierce and Gardener and Caminker, organizational commitment questionnaire by Alen and Mayer (1990), and job satisfaction questionnaire by Candal and Hulin (1974) are applied. For data analysis, some statistical indices are applies such as frequency, percentage, average, deviation, correlation, and regression analysis. The results show that there is a positive correlation between organizational self-esteem and job satisfaction and a meaningful and positive relationship between organizational commitment and job satisfaction, hence organizational self-esteem and organizational commitment can preserve job satisfaction.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-709-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Organizational Self-Esteem</keyword>
	<keyword> Organizational Commitment</keyword>
	<keyword> Job Satisfaction.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>201</startPage>
	<endPage>220</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Spatial analysis of water vapor pressure in south and southwest of Iran using by spatial autocorrelation techniques emphasizing on population centers</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Yoones Khosravi</name>
	<email>younes_kh15@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hasan Lashkari</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Akbar Mottakaan</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hosein Asaakareh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
As the most important greenhouse gas, water vapor plays a significant role in global warming. Therefore understanding this important climate parameter in populated area can play an important role in survey the climatic comfort. So in this research, first the spatial autocorrelation and identify behavioral patterns of water vapor pressure in South and Southwest of Iran with exploratory spatial data analysis (ESDA) and Anselin Local Moran statistic is investigated and then the effects of this important climatic parameter on population centers is discussed. In this context, the WVP data from 46 synoptic stations in South and Southwest of Iran with appropriate length and highest resolution were used. To analyze the spatial autocorrelation, study area due to the optimal spatial resolution were divided to pixels with the dimension of 9×9 km (3,338 pixels). By programming in MATLAB software, the monthly, annual and decadal WVP were extracted for each pixel. Spatial autocorrelation analysis suggested strengthening and weakening the high-high WVP clusters and Low-Low WVP clusters, respectively. So that high-high WVP clusters have extended near the Persian Gulf (Especially in the Bushehr provinces) and Low-Low WVP clusters have disappeared in southern parts of Zagros Survey and comparison of the spatial distribution of WVP clusters with temperature clusters, as one of the most important influential parameters, showed a significant positive autocorrelation in the study areaک Thus, according to the direct and indirect effects of WVP on human activities and natural environment as the basis of human activity, the establishment of population in population centers of studies area will be affected by fluctuations of WVP and this trend will be more pronounced in the future.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-710-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Spatial Statistics</keyword>
	<keyword> Spatial Autocorrelation</keyword>
	<keyword> Temperature</keyword>
	<keyword> Water Vapor Pressure</keyword>
	<keyword> Anselin Local Moran\'s</keyword>
	<keyword> Population.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>221</startPage>
	<endPage>234</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Legal necessities of institutional budget</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Hamid Qahve Chian</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> Seyyed Salmaan Samani</name>
	<email>salman_samani@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
Searches around budget in Iran have an old history. In this research, we will explain components of the outside-systematic approach to the legal budget system with help of institutional analysis and study its correction barriers in Iran. This research’s achievement is principles and strategies for reformation legal budget system in Iran Regardless of the new approach in the field of public finance law. The most important result of this study is that the legal budgets system in Iran is  shaped In the light of informal organizations and although after the constitutional revolution a series of laws and regulations in this field enacted, but procedures of Ruling the government an related organizations, that caused extending the looting system, Threaten private property, inattention to the materials and characteristics of good governance in Iran, therefor without institutional reform and change in the state’s decision making process and Allocating resources, the situation will be perpetuated. Accordingly, legal budget system’s revision depends on constitutional and administrative system’s reform.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-683-2&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>outside-systematic approach</keyword>
	<keyword> budget</keyword>
	<keyword> institutionalism</keyword>
	<keyword> political approach to budget       </keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>235</startPage>
	<endPage>262</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Determine the design criteria of cultural approach to social sustainability and spatial dynamics Case Study: cultural center in Tehran</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Sahar Salmasi</name>
	<email>salmasi_sahar@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Leila Karimi Fard</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
Today explained social sustainability criteria for sustainable living spaces with a view of the most important issues in the field of architecture and city planning that must be considered in the process of architectural design. On the other hand, the objective of cultural centers, create a free, intimate and open space is through a decentralized system is run. Crudely can cultural centers, cultural and social interactions, known as a cultural center, part of the leisure activities covers the architectural design of these spaces for social mobility refers to the need. Accordingly, this paper using the &quot;analytical method&quot; in the conceptual phase &quot;survey&quot; in the analytical and data gathering tools including library and documentary studies to examine the concept of social sustainability in architecture and design, cultural spaces Paid. To analyze the data obtained from research into architecture and design rules, synapses space is used. In the data for gamma curves alignment and then given maps and In the final stage of this analysis and studies on the site according to the standards and physical, cultural, architectural design has been done. Finally, leveraging social sustainability criteria for designing living spaces and spatial dynamics are discussed and a solution to improve the cultural and structural social mobility and the possibility of forming cultural center in Tehran to attend the public arena has been discussed.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-711-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>social sustainability</keyword>
	<keyword> sustainable development</keyword>
	<keyword> cultural and recreational complex</keyword>
	<keyword> and component design criteria.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>263</startPage>
	<endPage>290</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Study on the concept of urban public areas and the Frankfurt School of critical theory in review</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Reza Bander Abad</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Varaz Moradi Masihi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hamed Kavosh Nia</name>
	<email>hamed-kavosh@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hosein Aali</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
Today, the design and expansion of critical theory to the city, including the &quot;public areas of the city&quot; in the efforts of modern man to achieve optimal living conditions as one of the most important goals of social movements as well as the result of &quot;the richness of historical experience and theoretical results the accumulation of knowledge &quot;is. Public domain in normative concept or idea that the general theoretical framework of Habermas's communicative action and ethics of dialogue instead The public sphere of social life in which citizens can discuss important issues related to the public good (public interest) to pay. The result is the formation of public opinion. Democratic philosophers believe that this physical manifestation spaces of the public sphere, sphere of activity, communication and dialogue open and various people as well as the formation of civil life. This paper documents and logical reasoning and analytical method and the method of data collection, including library and documentary studies to examine some of the critical theory of the Frankfurt School in the city (especially Habermas, Arendt and Harvey) were investigated. In the first phase, the research findings indicate that the Frankfurt School theorists because of their similarity in opinions, including criticism of capitalism and Marxism, and criticism of modern and contemporary and positivist concepts of rationality, science and empirical evidence, human object, the loss of freedom and independence of man, which are called scholars of this school. In some of the issues and their proposed ideas such as revolution and social change agents in capitalist society and its practices, and alternative plans for a successor system, the shape of the human future in the cities and urban areas in the cities of the future changes are different. Next, the criteria and elements for the development of public areas in the city have been mentioned.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-712-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>critical theory</keyword>
	<keyword> the Frankfurt School</keyword>
	<keyword> public areas</keyword>
	<keyword> urban public space</keyword>
	<keyword> public sphere appearance criteria.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>291</startPage>
	<endPage>316</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Principles and standards of architectural space perception traditional markets</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Zahra Abbasi</name>
	<email>z_abbasi@srbiau.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Farah Habib</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Seyyed Mostafa Mokhtabad Amrei</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
Traditional markets with its ancient history in the economic, social and religious also have had an active role Market at the same time as a major hub for communication, economic and cultural city and an important role and position in the social life of cities in Iran. On the other hand, citizens of urban areas in general and the markets, in particular, the special relationship established perception that the use of space and also determines its desirability. The space in the city can be desirable in order to respond to the citizens understood to be in the process of problem solving contemporary design, modern markets and conditions used. The paper examines the principles and standards of architecture, spatial perception in Iran's market. The results and findings is in relation to 'functional characteristics of the Iranian market, explaining the conceptual model of the Iranian market physical, perceptual system in the Iranian market, explaining the concept of perceived Iranian market, meaning the Iranian market and explain the meaning of the concept&quot;. Finally, spatial perception model of traditional markets have been mentioned.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-713-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>market</keyword>
	<keyword> cognitive processes</keyword>
	<keyword> principles and standards of perception.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>317</startPage>
	<endPage>345</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Developing the components of the healing garden design in Iran and its application in the design of urban open spaces</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Roksana Abdollahi</name>
	<email>r.abdollahi@sriau.ac.ir</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Behnaz Amin Zadeh</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Azadeh Shah Cheraghi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Iraj Etesaam</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
Given the relationship between landscape and health in a long time in different cultures and societies has been identified. The view leveraging as a healing approach can be useful and effective strategy in this field seem. According to the designer maximum effort in order to create the healing properties of such a perspective in the promotion of peace, contributing to health, prevent disease and also the use of therapies far superior humanistic and natural, and deserves a lot of the methods of modern man favorite is mechanized. Such an approach was made to meet the requirements addressed in the sights of urban open spaces covered in the above and given the lack of research in this area would be useful and effective tool. Therefore, in this article from the perspective of the relationship between these factors and health issues, including that of particular importance is also the lead researcher to approach healing perspective. The results show that the natural approach to health caused by Persian gardens and can be used in designing urban open spaces have the faith that can stabilize qualitative approach to urban landscapes Iran. This tendency for optimal use of nature, although at low levels, but the goal is to reduce stress and increase health and sometimes in preventing the disease on the one hand and on the other hand protect and historical heritage of our country (Garden of the Persia) and revitalization them to fertilize in the community.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-714-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Iranian Paradise Garden</keyword>
	<keyword> healing perspective</keyword>
	<keyword> mental health</keyword>
	<keyword> urban open space.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>347</startPage>
	<endPage>368</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Operational Budget Planning an Answer to Modern Governmental Management Requirements (An Introduction to Legal System of Operational Budget Planning in USA)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Benyamin Shokoohfar</name>
	<email>b_shokouhfar@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Hadi Rahmani</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
There have been recent fundamental transformations in budget planning in different (specifically developed) countries due to their management style changes. In these countries there is a growing emphasis on budget-oriented performance and emphasizing on the best performance based on the ratified regulations, the executive power is obliged to present the previous performance data and also the prediction of its future performance framed with the annual budget to the parliament and request the budget managers to report the budget performance to the parliament after it is implemented. The concept of observation of the parliament has also changed. Currently such a performance does not necessarily mean the adaptation of budget performance with the budget law but its alignment and adaptation with the decided targets and plans. These countries, through a process of improvement or change, are trying to make the budget planning come closer to a performance-oriented order or some operation in which the budget credit and administrative departments relationship is clear and understandable and doing so, provide the government and parliament with a credible and reliable data support. In such a framework, efficiency, effectiveness and economization are introduced as the main targets of budget planning. In this study, the US system of budget planning is investigated as the first system presenting operational budget planning system, including a very comprehensive federal system. In this article, despite considering principals of operational budget planning, budget law and operation of analysis and finally the forthcoming challenges are presented.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-715-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Modern Governmental Management</keyword>
	<keyword> Budget Law</keyword>
	<keyword> Operational Budget Planning</keyword>
	<keyword> Effectiveness</keyword>
	<keyword> Efficiency.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>369</startPage>
	<endPage>392</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Evaluation of urban tourism with an emphasis on tourism infrastructure development and urban competitiveness Case Study: Metropolitan Tehran</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Hamed Famil Nouroozi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Shahram Sharifi</name>
	<email>shahramsharifi1986@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ailin Sheidaee</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
Today, tourism especially “urban tourism” in the world is very important. Unfortunately, despite the ability of Iran in this regard, the industry has found a worthy place. Therefore, tourism issues and the concept of “urban competitiveness” can be very useful in this context. However, what is now considered to be at increased tourism, “the idea of competitiveness of cities” and the feasibility of the creation and formation of global cities in the category of “urban tourism” in the subject. Accordingly, in this paper, the analytical method in the theoretical and secondary analysis of the data is used. The results show that the competitiveness of urban tourism metropolis of Tehran only amusement park in the area of infrastructure and the urgent need to develop residential complexes in this area is necessary. At the same time in the recreational infrastructure, increase the quantity and improve the quality of them, especially in terms of safety an important issue in terms of competitiveness in Tehran. The strategies mentioned in various aspects in detail.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-205-2&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>urban tourism</keyword>
	<keyword> world cities</keyword>
	<keyword> infrastructure</keyword>
	<keyword> tourism</keyword>
	<keyword> strategies and recommendations.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>393</startPage>
	<endPage>406</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Implementation model of professional ethics in organizations</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mehrzad Shahali</name>
	<email>mshahali14@gmail.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Rashid Poor</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Esmail Kavoosi</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Ali Akbar Etebarian</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
This article is based on a field study entitled &quot;Designing a model of implementation of ethics in organizations&quot; has been developed The purpose of the study in terms of application and the descriptive survey method that has been done with regard to the quantitative modeling In the first study of factors affecting professional ethics on the basis of evidence from reliable sources available on the Delphi technique extraction and refining most important factors of the respective experts. Furthermore, the effect and importance and priority of each of the identified factors to determine the pattern is designed based on a systematic approach. The findings suggest that factors affecting the implementation of professional ethics in organizations in three dimensions: individual, organizational and environmental factors can be contemplated.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-717-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>ethics</keyword>
	<keyword> professional ethics</keyword>
	<keyword> implementation pattern.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2015-09</publicationDate>
	<volume>14</volume>
	<issue>39</issue>
	<startPage>407</startPage>
	<endPage>428</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Analysis of the continuity of the masses and public space in the city</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name>Mansoor Yeganeh</name>
	<email>yaghane@yahoo.com</email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name>Mohammad Reza Bemanian</name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">
The objective of this paper is to examine the coherence and consistency of the masses and the public space in urban areas. The continuity and integrity of one of the main criteria is the quality of urban spaces. Mainly indigenous and traditional spaces such quality criteria. The paper claims that now, both practical and theoretical areas of urban and environmental design associated with the main challenges are in the field. The result is that, in theory, theoretical approaches to this issue and no recall was necessary in practice, many urban areas lack the coherence and cohesion is necessary. The present article is a phenomenological approach - psychological, the continuity and coherence of urban public spaces and buildings studied and integration criteria of the urban public spaces is investigated. Phenomenological approach, limited to the study of urban public spaces according to their specific circumstances regardless of causal factors were The psychological approach, the role of public perception and understanding of the continuity of the building and the city's public spaces of the city In this conjunction buildings and public spaces in the city, a function of the continuity of physical space, spatial, social activity, and symbolic introduced.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-348-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>coherence</keyword>
	<keyword> totality</keyword>
	<keyword> of continuity</keyword>
	<keyword> continuity standards</keyword>
	<keyword> the building and the city</keyword>
	<keyword> subjective and objective.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
 </records>
 
  
  
  
  
 