<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>51</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>شناسایی ساختار شکست ریسک پروژه‌های عمرانی شهرداری اصفهان و اولویت‌بندی  با استفاده از تکنیک تاپسیس فازی سلسله مراتبی</title_fa>
	<title>Identify and prioritize risk breakdown structure of municipal construction projects using fuzzy hierarchical TOPSIS</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;هدف پژوهش حاضر، طراحی ساختار شکست ریسک و اولویت بندی سطوح آن در شهرداری اصفهان بوده و در این راستا، ارائه اهداف پروژه های عمرانی در مدیریت ریسک پروژه ها مورد توجه قرار گرفته است. این پژوهش در خصوص تعیین ساختار شکست ریسک از طریق مطالعات تطبیقی، مصاحبه نیمه ساختار یافته و پرسشنامه حاصل شد و در انتهاء اولویت بندی سطوح ساختار شکست ریسک، اهداف پروژه ها توسط تکنیک تاپسیس فازی سلسله مراتبی بهبود یافته انجام گرفت. با توجه به اینکه در تاپسیس کلاسیک مقدار میانگین و انحراف از استاندارد، معیار کاملی برای مقایسه دو عدد فازی نیستند در این راستا جهت رفع این نقیصه از ضریب تغییر استفاده شده است. این پژوهش توصیفی از نوع پیمایشی و با ماهیت کاربردی و از نظر زمان مقطعی است. ابزار گردآوری داده ها شامل مرور مستندات، تکنیک دلفی و پرسشنامه های محقق ساخته از طریق ترسیم نردبان انتزاعی است که روایی صوری و محتوایی آن به روش لاوشه و پایایی آن توسط شیوه تعیین همسانی درونی مورد تایید قرار گرفت و به طور کلی 29 دسته ریسک در سطح سوم شناسایی گردید که در سه سطح طبقه بندی شده و در دو سطح دوم و سوم اولویت بندی گردیده است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this study was to design a risk breakdown structure and prioritize its levels in Isfahan municipality. In this regard, the presentation of the objectives of the construction projects in project risk management has been considered. This research was conducted to determine the risk breakdown structure through comparative studies, semi-structured interviews, and a questionnaire. Finally, prioritizing the levels of risk breakdown structure, the objectives of the projects were accomplished through improved hierarchical fuzzy topology technique. Due to the fact that in classical Tapis, the mean value and standard deviation are not a complete measure for comparison of two fuzzy numbers, in order to eliminate this defect, the coefficient of variation has been used. This descriptive survey is of a survey type of a practical nature and periodic time. The data gathering tool included review of documentation, Delphi technique and researcher-made questionnaires by drawing an abstract ladder, its content and content validity was evaluated by Lavasheh method and its reliability was confirmed by the internal consistency determination method and in general 29 risk categories in The third level was identified and ranked in three levels and ranked in the second and third levels.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>ساختار شکست ریسک, اهداف پروژه ها, اولویت بندی, ریسک پروژه های عمرانی </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>risk breakdown structure, Projects Objectives, Prioritization, Risk of Construction Projects </keyword>
	<start_page>357</start_page>
	<end_page>371</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1816-82&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>امیرحسین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نادعلی جلوخانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008886</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008886</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید رسول</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>آقاداوود</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008887</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008887</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کرباسیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008888</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008888</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>عبدالمجید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عبدالباقی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008889</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008889</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
