<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>35</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی دیدگاه اعضای شورای شهرتبریز در مورد بهسازی و باز سازی بافت محله مقصودیه شهر تبریز بر مبنای روش سروکوال </title_fa>
	<title>Rehabilitation and Reconstruction of Tabriz Alleys in City Council Members Viewpoint with SERVQUAL Method (Case Study: Maghsodie Alley of Tabriz)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
سرعت تغییرات در بافت قدیم شهرها، اهمیت نحوه نگرش و چگونگی برخورد با آنها را آشکار می سازد. بافت تاریخی شهرها در گذشته پاسخگوی بسیاری از نیازهای کالبدی و اجتماعی و روانی ساکنان آنها بوده است. تاثیر چنین مکان های ماندگار در شکل دهی به ارتباطات اجتماعی و مشارکت مردم در احیا و نگهداری این بافتها، در مقطعی از حیات آنها بر اثر تحولات اقتصادی ، اجتماعی و فرهنگی که نتیجه آن خیابان کشی ها و عدم انسجام محلات و در ادامه از بین رفتن مفهوم محله می باشد، اهمیت فراوانی می یابد. جامعه آماری پژوهش حاضر، مشتمل بر بافت شهری محله مقصودیه تبریز و ارائه پرسش نامه به تعداد 11عدد برای اعضاء شورای اسلامی شهر تبریز می باشد. روش تحقیق با استفاده از رویکرد های توصیفی_ پیمایشی و ارائه پرسشنامه صورت گرفته است. نتایج تحقیق بیانگر دیدگاه مثبت مدیران حوزه های شهری به بهسازی بافت محله مقصودیه شهر تبریز می باشد. نتایج حاصل از تحقیق می توان برای ارتقاء زیر سنجه های چک لیست پیشنهادی محقق در امر ارتقاء فضاهای شهری محلات تاریخی بهره جست.   
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
Rapid changes in the texture of the old city reveal the importance of attitude and how to deal with them. Historical textures of the city responded to many physical and psychological and social needs of their residents in the past. The effect of such memorable places in shaping social communication and public participation in regeneration and maintenance of these textures gain importance in part of their life due to economic, social and cultural changes resulted to layout of  the streets and disintegration of the neighborhoods and losing the concept of neighborhood. The statistical population consists of urban texture of Maghsoudieh neighborhood.The study sample included 11 urban neighborhoods questionnaires provided for council members. The research method is descriptive and survey and using questionnaire. The results indicate a positive viewpoint of urban principals in managing of urban areas to improve and regenerate Tabriz Maghsoudieh neighborhood. The results can be used to enhance the proposed list of measures in promoting historic sites in urban spaces.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa> شورای شهر, بهسازی و بازسازی شهری, سرو کوال, محله مقصودیه شهر تبریز.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>city council, urban reconstruction and regeneration, SERVQUAL, Maghsoudieh Tabriz neighborhood.</keyword>
	<start_page>33</start_page>
	<end_page>42</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-626-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ranaa</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Najari Naabi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رعنا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نجاری نابی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ra.najjari@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001667</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001667</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Islamic Azad University of Tabriz</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تبریز</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Baeseh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rezai</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>باعثه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رضایی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001668</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001668</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Islamic Azad University of Tabriz</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تبریز</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
