<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>15</volume>
<number>42</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تعریف قلمرو محلات: تحلیلی مفهومی با تاکید بر ابعاد روانی- ادراکی و ارائه مدل مفهومی</title_fa>
	<title>The definition of local territory: conceptual analysis with an emphasis on psycho-perceptual and conceptual models</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;انسان موجودی اجتماعی است و اجتماعات انسانی نیز در طول تاریخ بشر خود را در قالب سازمانها و مکانهای خاصی از جمله؛ اجتماع شهری، روستایی و شیوه&amp;shy;های مختلف سکونت به منصه ظهور رسانده است. یکی از اجتماعاتی که از دورانهای کهن شهرنشینی وجود داشته محلات شهری می&amp;shy;باشد که با تغییر و تحولاتی که شهرها در طول زمان در ساختار، محتوا و کالبد به خود دیده اند. قلمرو و محدوده های فضایی و اجتماعی محلات شهری نیز در شهرهای امروزی متحول شده اند. از اینرو ادراک و رفتارهای متفاوت انسانها را از قلمرو محله و نسبت به هم محلی&amp;shy;های خویش (اجتماع محله) در پی داشته است. از جمله رویکردهایی که برای بازتعریف قلمرو محلات و تقویت ادراک حس مکان و حس اجتماعی ساکنین نسبت به قلمرهای محله ایشان مطرح گردیده است، نحوه تعریف این قلمروها مبتنی بر ادراک ذهنی و رفتاری ساکنین از آنها می باشد. بدین ترتیب مقاله حاضر با تبیین آناتومی مفهوم قلمرو محله در شهر، ابتدا به بررسی مولفه های موثر و رویکردهای رایج در زمینه تعیین قلمرو محله، پرداخته و با بیان تئوریها و پژوهشهای مختلف صورت گرفته در این زمینه، ملاحظه می&amp;shy;نماید که اغلب پژوهشها بر محدوده&amp;shy;های رسمی و آماری تکیه می کنند که این محدوده ها، محلات واقعی را نشان نمی دهد. تحلیل اسناد مطالعه نیز به شیوه &amp;laquo;تحلیل درونی&amp;raquo; انجام یافته است. بدین ترتیب، محتو ای منابع و اسناد به لحاظ موضوع، معیارهای شناختی، اندیشه&amp;shy;های نظری و فلسفی مورد بررسی و تحلیل قرار گرفته&amp;nbsp; و به نتایج چندی از جمله؛ ماهیت چندسطحی قلمرو محلات، تفاوت محدوده ادراکی ساکنین با محدوده های آماری، پی می برد، در نهایت با ارائه مدل مفهومی مبتنی بر مولفه های عینی و ذهنی، محدوده ای را (لایه دوم فضای محله) بعنوان قلمرو واقعی محلات معرفی و برای توجه بیشتر در پژوهشهای آتی پیشنهاد می نماید.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 1em 0px; text-align: justify; line-height: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;Garamond&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;; font-size: 13pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial; mso-ansi-language: EN;&quot;&gt;We are social beings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;Garamond&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;; font-size: 13pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial; mso-ansi-language: EN;&quot;&gt; and human societies throughout human history in the form of organizations and certain locations such as urban, rural and different ways of living has brought to fruition. One of the communities that existed from ancient times urbanization that has transformed the urban neighborhoods of cities over time in the structure, content and structure have been seen.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot; lang=&quot;EN&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;Arial&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;sans-serif&amp;quot;; font-size: 13pt; mso-ansi-language: EN; mso-ascii-font-family: Garamond; mso-hansi-font-family: Garamond;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;Garamond&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;; font-size: 13pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial; mso-ansi-language: EN;&quot;&gt;The scope and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;Garamond&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;; font-size: 13pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial; mso-ansi-language: EN;&quot;&gt; limits of social space and urban neighborhoods in cities today have changed. The scope and limits of social space and urban neighborhoods in cities today have changed. Thus, perceptions and behaviors of different people to each local territory and its neighborhood (neighborhood community) is followed. Including approaches to redefine the territory of communities and strengthen a sense of place and sense of community perception of the residents of the neighborhood domains has been raised, how to define these territories based on subjective perception and behavior of their residents. This article discusses the anatomy of the territory of the neighborhoods in the city, first the effective components and common approaches in determining the scope of the neighborhood, is discussed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot; lang=&quot;EN&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;Arial&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;sans-serif&amp;quot;; font-size: 13pt; mso-ansi-language: EN; mso-ascii-font-family: Garamond; mso-hansi-font-family: Garamond;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;Garamond&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;; font-size: 13pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial; mso-ansi-language: EN;&quot;&gt;And&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: &amp;quot;Garamond&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;; font-size: 13pt; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial; mso-ansi-language: EN;&quot;&gt; the expression of different theories and research done in this field, we see that most studies rely on a range of official statistics that these limits, does not show actual locations. Analysis study documents the need to practice &amp;quot;internal analysis&amp;quot; was conducted. Thus, the content of the sources and documents, the recognition criteria, theoretical and philosophical ideas were analyzed and several results including multi-domain nature areas, differences in perceptions of people with a range of statistical follows Winning, ultimately providing a conceptual model based on objective and subjective factors, the range (the second layer of the atmosphere of the neighborhood) as the neighborhoods of the territory and to pay more attention in future research suggests.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>قلمرو, قلمرو محله, ادراک ذهنی محله, آشنایی فضایی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>territory, territory, district, neighborhood subjective perception, spatial orientation.</keyword>
	<start_page>313</start_page>
	<end_page>326</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-918-41&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>وحیده </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>برنون</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003267</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003267</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ناصر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>براتی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003268</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003268</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>آزاده</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>شاهچراغی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846003269</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846003269</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
