<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>28</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیل کیفیت زندگی در بافت فرسوده شهر میاندوآب</title_fa>
	<title>Analyzing urban quality of life in old fabric of Miandoaab city</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;شهر به عنوان عالی‌ترین نمود تمدن بشری، نقش بنیادینی در ایجاد زندگی خوب برای تمام شهروندان را دارد. اما در عین حال تاکید بر ابعاد کمی رشد در بسیاری از کشورها بویژه در کشورهای در حال توسعه منجر به دو قطبی شدن شهرها گردیده است. و از این روی برای حل مشکلات بشر شهرنشین و ارتقاء ابعاد کیفی زندگی او مفهومی تحت عنوان کیفیت زندگی مطرح و مورد تحقیق قرار گرفت. در واقع هدف مقاله تبیین سطوح کیفیت زندگی در بافت فرسوده شهر میاندوآب بر مبنای 6 شاخص اقتصادی، اجتماعی، مسکونی، دسترسی به تسهیلات و امکانات شهری، دسترسی به حمل و نقل عمومی و کیفیت بهداشت محیط می باشد. روش به کار گرفته در این مقاله توصیفی تحلیلی می‌باشد. ابتدا مطالعات اکتشافی به صورت کتابخانه‌ای و بازدید مقدماتی صورت گرفته و مطالعه میدانی با استفاده از روش پرسشنامه‌ای انجام شده است. برای تعیین حجم نمونه مورد مطالعه از تکنیک کوکران استفاده شده و در نهایت برای تحلیل و رتبه‌بندی محلات، روش آنتروپی و SAW به کار گرفته شده است. بر مبنای بررسی‌های صورت گرفته شاخص فضای سبز با امتیاز 477/0 و اختلاف چشمگیری نسبت به بقیه شاخص ها از اهمیت بالایی برخوردار بود. در کل میانگین هریک از عامل ها محاسبه شده است که عامل خدمات و تسهیلات شهری با امتیاز 138/0 در رتبه اول قرار گرفت که نشان دهنده عدم رضایت ساکنین بافت فرسوده از این شاخص می باشد که در برنامه ریزی های آینده باید به آن توجه زیادی شود. بر اساس نتایج بدست آمده از تکنیک SAW محلات 21، 19 و 20 از نظر شاخص‌های مورد مطالعه در بهترین شرایط و محلات 11، 10 و 12 در بدترین شرایط و پایین‌ترین رتبه قرار دارند. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;City as highest symbol of human civilization has a fundamental role for all citizens. But concentrating only on the quantitative aspect of cities has created a bio polar character in most of the developing countries. So the concept of quality of life deals with the problems of urban residents and promotion of his qualitative aspect of living. In fact this paper tries to explain the quality of life in the eroded fabric of the Miandoaab city on the base of four socio-economic, physical-environmental and mental-subjective indexes. The methodology of the research is based on descriptive-analytical methods by conducting a field work to complete the given questionnaires. Cochran technique was used to determine the number of samples, then Entropy and SAW techniques were applied to analysis and rank the different neighborhoods. The results revealed that the index of green space with score of 0.477 showed clear difference with other indexes. In general, the mean of each factor was calculated which the factor of urban service and facility scored 0.138 and placed in first rank as residents were dissatisfied regarding to this index. It seems that provision of urban facilities should be considered more seriously in future planning. The findings from SAW technique revealed that neighborhoods of 19, 20 and 21 had an appropriate condition while the neighborhoods of 10, 11 and 12 placed the lowest rank. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>کیفیت زندگی شهری، شاخص، بافت فرسوده، تکنیک SAW، شهر میاندوآب.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>urban quality of life, index, eroded fabric, SAW technique, Miandoaab city</keyword>
	<start_page>223</start_page>
	<end_page>240</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-120-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Taqi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rahnamaii</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدتقی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رهنمایی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600244</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600244</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Geography Faculty of Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده جغرافیا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ayoob</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Manoochehri Miandoab</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ایوب</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>منوچهری میاندوآب</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ayub.manochehri@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600245</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600245</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Geography Faculty of Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده جغرافیا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Amin</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Faraji Mollai</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>امین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فرجی ملایی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600246</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600246</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Geography Faculty of Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده جغرافیا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
