<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>52</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیل نقش فرهنگ‌ سازمانی، فرهنگ ملی و فرهنگ شهروندی در خط‌مشی‌گذاری فرهنگی شهرداری‌ها کلان‌شهرهای جمهوری اسلامی ایران</title_fa>
	<title>Analyzing the Role of Organizational Culture, National Culture and Citizenship Culture in the Cultural Policymaking of the Metropolitan Municipalities of the Islamic Republic of Iran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;هدف از پژوهش حاضر تحلیل نقش فرهنگ&amp;zwnj; سازمانی، فرهنگ ملی و فرهنگ شهروندی درخط مشی&amp;zwnj;گذاری فرهنگی شهرداری&amp;zwnj;ها کلان&amp;zwnj;شهرهای جمهوری اسلامی ایران می باشد. تحقیق حاضر از نظر هدف، از نوع تحقیقات کاربردی است و از نظر نحوه گردآوری دادهها، توصیفی از نوع همبستگی اسـت که در آن از روش مدل&amp;zwnj;سازی معادلات مسیری- ساختاری برای آزمون فرضیات و برازش مـدل اسـتفاده شـده اسـت. جامعه آماری پژوهش شامل کلیه&amp;zwnj;ی برنامه&amp;zwnj;ریزان، کارشناسان و معاونان حوزه فرهنگی و اجتماعی شاغل در شهرداری&amp;zwnj;های کلانشهر (3 کلانشهر، تهران، شیراز، اصفهان) که تعداد آنها 3000 نفر می&amp;zwnj;باشد. با استفاده از قانون 10، 610 نفر به عنوان نمونه و با روش طبقه&amp;zwnj;ای در دسترس انتخاب شده&amp;zwnj;اند. ابزار گردآوری اطلاعات پرسشنامه می&amp;zwnj;باشد که پایایی پرسشنامه با استفاده از ضریب آلفای کرانباخ و روایی پرسشنامه با استفاده از روایی محتوا با استفاده از نظر متخصصان آشنا به موضوع پژوهش مورد تایید قرار گرفت. همچنین برای تعیین همبستگی و تجزیه و تحلیل داده&amp;zwnj;ها از نرم افزار &lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;SPSS22&lt;/span&gt; و &lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;Lisrel 8.80&lt;/span&gt; استفاده شده است. نتایج حاصل از تجزیه و تحلیل داده&amp;zwnj;ها منجر به تایید همه&amp;zwnj;ی فرضیه&amp;zwnj;های پژوهش گردید: فرهنگ سازمانی، فرهنگ شهروندی و فرهنگ ملی بر خط&amp;zwnj;مشی گذاری&amp;zwnj;های فرهنگی تاثیر مثبت و معناداری دارند.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The aim of this research is to analyze the role of organizational culture, national culture and citizenship culture in the Cultural Policymaking of the Metropolitan Municipalities of the Islamic Republic of Iran. The current research, in terms of purpose, is set in the applied research group and in terms of collecting data, is a description of solidarity group in which the modeling of the path-structural equations for hypotheses testing and model fitting is used. The statistical population of the study consists of all the planners, experts, and deputies of the cultural and social field working in the metropolitan municipality (3 metropolises, Tehran, Shiraz, Isfahan) with 3000 people. By using the law of 10, 610 people have been selected as the sample by a stratified sampling method. The data gathering tool was a questionnaire, which its reliability was determined using Cronbach Alpha coefficient and the validity of the questionnaire was confirmed using content validity using the knowledge of experts familiar with the subject of the research. Also, SPSS22 and Lisrel 8.80 software was used to determine the correlation and analysis of the data. The results of the data analysis have confirmed all the research hypotheses: organizational culture, citizenship culture and national culture have a positive and significant impact on cultural policy making.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>فرهنگ سازمانی, فرهنگ شهروندی, فرهنگ ملی, خط‌مشی فرهنگی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Organizational Culture, Citizenship Culture, National Culture, Cultural Policy Making.</keyword>
	<start_page>5</start_page>
	<end_page>20</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1816-83&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>آلما </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فرامرزی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008992</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008992</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سنجر </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سلاجقه</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008993</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008993</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سعید </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صیادی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008994</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008994</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
