<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>37</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>سنجش پایداری اجتماعی محلات بر اساس دیدگاه ساکنان</title_fa>
	<title> Social sustainability measurement based on the residents views</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>تمرکز توسعه در شهر ها و توجه به مفاهیم کالبدی و هندسی و غفلت از اهداف اجتماعی در طرح های توسعه شهری، شهرها را با چرخه نامطلوبی از عدم تعادل اقتصادی- اجتماعی و زیست محیطی روبرو کرده و چالش های زیادی را از نظر فقر، جرم و بزهکاری، تعارضات فرهنگی، نزول کیفیت زندگی، از هم گسیختگی های اجتماعی و غیره به وجود آورده است. رویکرد توسعه پایدار، برنامه ریزی و مدیریت شهری را از خردترین واحد شهر یعنی محله مورد توجه قرار داده و با رویکرد اجتماعی سعی در شناسایی ظرفیت های موجود در محله ها و کاربست آنها به منظور ترمیم و بهبود شرایط موجود و و ایجاد انعطاف لازم برای حل مشکلات آینده دارد. در این میان تلقی شهروندان از محله خود در تحلیل وضع موجود به دلیل انعکاس شرایط عمومی محله و محیط زندگی افراد حائز اهمیت می باشد. همچنین برداشت شهروندان از محله خود بسیاری از واقعیت های محیط را نمایان می سازد که از جنبه های اجتماعی برنامه ریزی درخور اهمیت است. هدف اصلی این تحقیق تعیین میزان پایداری اجتماعی در سطح محله فیض آباد شهر کرمانشاه با استفاد از دیدگاه ساکنین است تا از این طریق بتوان راهکارهایی را برای ترمیم و بازخوانی پایداری اجتماعی استخراج و پیشنهاد نمود. راهبرد اصلی تحقیق کمی است که در آن با بهره گیری از روش توصیفی- تحلیلی، همبستگی معیارهای تدقیق شده شناسایی و میزان پایداری اجتماعی محله بررسی شده است. بر اساس نتایج حاصل از این تحقیق، تمام معیارها تاثیر مستقیمی بر میزان پایداری اجتماعی محله می گذارند اما شدت تاثیر معیارها متفاوت است. از این نظر، معیارهای رضایتمندی، امنیت اجتماعی و ثبات اجتماعی دارای بیشترین همبستگی با مفهوم پایداری اجتماعی در سطح محله بوده و از دیدگاه ساکنان بیشترین تاثیر را بر سطح پایداری اجتماعی محله دارند. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Due to the nature of development which is mainly concentrated on the cities and that more attention paid to physical and geometric aspects than social ones in urban development plans, cities have faced a kind of negative cycle of socio-economic and environmental imbalances. This created many challenges in terms of poverty, crime and delinquency, cultural conflicts, declining quality of life, social disorganization and etc. Sustainable development approach usually considers small unit of urban structure, namely the neighborhood, in planning and urban management of cities and tries to identify existing potentials across the neighborhood regarding its social dimension to restore and improve existing conditions and make it more flexible and resilience to future problems. In this regard, residents' attitudes towards the neighborhood are great important because their views reflect general conditions of the neighborhood and more details of people's living environment. Moreover, people's perception of the neighborhood can clarify the reality of the environment, those aspects which are so important social dimension of planning. The main goal of this research is to examine the level of social sustainability in the neighborhood of Faizabad, Kermanshah based on the residents view of their neighborhood. The results can pave the way for some strategies to restore and refresh social sustainability. The main research strategy is quantitative which utilizes a kind of descriptive – analytical method based on the correlation analysis to identify social sustainability measurements of the neighborhood. Based on the results, all criteria have a direct impact on the neighborhood social sustainability, but the intensity of their impact is different. In this respect, satisfaction, social security and social stability measurements have the highest correlation with the concept of social sustainability in the neighborhood. This means that they were recognized by the residents as the most effective factors affecting the level of social sustainability in Faizabad neighborhood.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>توسعه پایدار, پایداری اجتماعی, پایداری اجتماعی محله, محله فیض آباد, کرمانشاه</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Sustainable development, Social sustainability, Neighborhood social sustainability, Faizabad neighborhood, Kermanshah</keyword>
	<start_page>73</start_page>
	<end_page>92</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-191-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>هوشمند</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>علیزاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>H.Alizadeh@uok.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846001591</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001591</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه کردستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>کیومرث</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ایراندوست</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Kau1348@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001592</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001592</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه کردستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهنا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>برآور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>m.baravar@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001593</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001593</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه کردستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
