<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>15</volume>
<number>45</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارائه مدل بانک سرمایه فکری در سازمان تامین اجتماعی</title_fa>
	<title>Model of Intellectual Capital Bank on Social Security organization</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;تحقیق حاضر باهدف ارائه مدل بانک سرمایه فکری در سازمان تامین اجتماعی انجام گرفت. روش تحقیق حاضر، از حیث هدف کاربردی و از منظر شیوه اجرا توصیفی ـ پیمایشی (بینابینی) است. جامعه آماری در این تحقیق، کلیه&amp;shy; مدیران ارشد سازمان تامین اجتماعی کشور می باشند که تعداد آنها حدودا 500 نفر می باشد. حجم نمونه این تحقیق باتوجه به فرمول نمونه گیری کوکران 217 نفر برآورد گردید. ابزار اندازه&amp;shy;گیری، پرسشنامه محقق ساخته بوده و جهت سنجش روایی پس از تایید روایی محتوا توسط خبرگان میزان روایی سازه محاسبه و ارتباط سوالات و مولفه ها تایید گردید. همچنین برای سنجش پایایی از ضریب آلفای کرونباخ استفاده گردید. نتایج حاصل از بررسی پایایی پرسشنامه نشان داد که ضریب آلفای کل محاسبه&amp;zwnj;شده برابر با 0.881 است و با توجه به اینکه بزرگتر از 7/0 است، می&amp;zwnj;توان نتیجه گرفت که پرسشنامه مورد استفاده از پایایی پژوهشی لازم برخوردار می&amp;zwnj;باشد. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده ها در سطح آمار توصیفی از فراوانی، درصد، درصد تجمعی، میانگین و انحراف معیار و در سطح آمار استنباطی از آزمون&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt; t &lt;/span&gt;مستقل، تحلیل واریانس یک طرفه و معادلات ساختاری استفاده گردید. سرمایه فکری در این تحقیق به سه دسته سرمایه انسانی، سرمایه ساختاری (سازمانی) &amp;nbsp;و سرمایه مشتری&amp;nbsp; قابل تقسیم است. یافته های تحقیق نشان داد که سرمایه انسانی بر بانک سرمایه فکری کارکنان تأثیر مثبت و معنادار دارد. سرمایه ساختاری نیز بر بانک سرمایه فکری کارکنان تأثیر مثبت و معنادار داشته و همچنین سرمایه رابطه ای نیز بر بانک سرمایه فکری کارکنان تأثیر مثبت و معنادار دارد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); line-height: 115%; font-family: &amp;quot;Garamond&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;; font-size: 13pt; mso-fareast-font-family: Calibri; mso-fareast-theme-font: minor-latin; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial; mso-ansi-language: EN; mso-fareast-language: EN-US; mso-bidi-language: AR-SA;&quot;&gt;The present study aimed to provide the intellectual capital of the bank was carried out in Social Security. Research methodology, in terms of practical purpose and from the perspective of descriptive survey method (interstitial) is. The population in this study, all senior managers in social security organizations, which number about 500 people;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot; lang=&quot;EN&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); line-height: 115%; font-family: &amp;quot;Arial&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;sans-serif&amp;quot;; font-size: 13pt; mso-fareast-font-family: Calibri; mso-fareast-theme-font: minor-latin; mso-ansi-language: EN; mso-fareast-language: EN-US; mso-bidi-language: AR-SA; mso-ascii-font-family: Garamond; mso-hansi-font-family: Garamond;&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang=&quot;EN&quot; style=&quot;color: rgb(34, 34, 34); line-height: 115%; font-family: &amp;quot;Garamond&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;; font-size: 13pt; mso-fareast-font-family: Calibri; mso-fareast-theme-font: minor-latin; mso-bidi-font-family: Arial; mso-ansi-language: EN; mso-fareast-language: EN-US; mso-bidi-language: AR-SA;&quot;&gt;The sample size of 217 was calculated according to the formula Cochran. The measurement instrument was a questionnaire to assess the validity and content validity by experts calculate the validity and relevance of the questions and the components were confirmed. The Cronbach's alpha coefficient was used to assess reliability. The result of the study showed that alpha coefficient of reliability is calculated equal to 0.881. And considering that it is larger than 0.7, it can be concluded that the questionnaire of management reliability is necessary. To analyze the data descriptive statistics of frequency, percentage, cumulative percentage, mean and standard deviation and inferential statistics, independent t-test, ANOVA and structural equation modeling was used. In this research, intellectual capital into three categories: human capital, structural capital (organizational) and customer capital is divided. The results showed that human capital and intellectual capital bank employees a significant and positive impact. Structural capital is also positive and significant impact on the Bank's employees, intellectual capital and relational capital is the intellectual capital of the bank staff is positive and significant impact.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>سرمایه فکری, سرمایه انسانی, سرمایه ساختاری, سرمایه رابطه ای, سازمان تامین اجتماعی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>intellectual capital, human capital, structural capital, relational capital, social security organizations.</keyword>
	<start_page>171</start_page>
	<end_page>192</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-11&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمود </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عزیزخانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846005793</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846005793</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
