<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>12</volume>
<number>33</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>طراحی الگوی مفهومی چالش‌های ناشی از اجرای طرح هدف‌مندسازی یارانه‌ها در شهرداری کرمان</title_fa>
	<title>Modeling Challenges Confronting Kerman Municipality caused by Directing Subsidies</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>با اجرای قانون هدف‌مندسازی یارانه‌ها، نهادهای عمومی همچون شهرداری‌های کشور با مسایل و چالش‌های جدیدی رو به رو شدند. به علاوه در اغلب بحث‌های مطرح شده توسط متخصصان و اندیش‌مندان، چالش‌ها و نتایج اجرای هدفمندسازی یارانه‌ها در مورد اقشار عمومی و مردم بررسی شده است و کمتر به این تاثیرات و نتایج در نهادهای عمومی پرداخته شده است. در این مقاله سعی شده است تا چالش‌های ناشی از اجرای هدفمندسازی یارانه‌ها بر یکی از نهادهای عمومی یعنی شهرداری‌ها بررسی شود. شهرداری‌های کشور نهادهایی هستند که خدمات بسیاری را به شهروندان ارایه می‌نمایند و هر گونه تغییر یا چالشی در این نهاد، اثرات خود را در ارایه خدمات و نهایتا رضایت شهروندان منعکس می‌کند. در این پژوهش ابتدا با استفاده از روش گروه کانونی داده‌های لازم از شهرداری کرمان جمع‌آوری شد و سپس با استفاده از نرم‌افزار Atlas.Ti و با روش تحلیل مضمونی مورد پژوهش قرار گرفت. نهایتا الگوی مفهومی چالش‌های ایجاد شده برای شهرداری کرمان بر پایه داده‌های جمع‌آوری شده به دست آمد. در این الگوی مفهومی معلوم شد در نتیجه اجرای قانون هدف‌مندی یارانه‌ها، با توجه به مضمون‌های: تغییر پویایی میان عوامل موثر بر فعالیت شهرداری، تاثیرات اجرای قانون بر فعالیت شهرداری، و تاثیرات نهایی بر جامعه شهری، مخاطره و هزینه عملیات شهرداری افزایش و اطمینان شغلی کارکنان آن کاهش یافته که مآلا به کاهش خدمات‌دهی و رفاه شهروندان کرمانی منجر خواهد شد.
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>After enactment of Directing Subsidies Act, public institutions like municipalities confronted with new challenges and problems. As with the most of the discussions between experts went to evaluation of impacts of this Act on people, there is less attention has drawn to its impact on public institutions. In this article, we studied the challenges confronting municipalities as a public institution aftermath of Directing Subsidies. Municipalities are institutions that serve citizens in different ways and so, any change or challenge there may lead to increase or decrease of citizens' satisfaction. In this research, first, we gathered needed data about Kerman Municipality through focus group, and then, analyzed through thematic analysis by help of Atlas.Ti software solution. Finally, we developed a conceptual model of challenges confronting Kerman Municipality based on gathered data.  Conceptual model shows that, with certain themes in mind such as: change in dynamism of effective elements on municipality functions, effects of enactment on municipality functions, and ultimate effects on citizens risks and costs of municipality operations have increased and occupational certainty of municipality employees has decreased which may finally lead to a decrease in services and welfare of Kerman citizens
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>طرح هدف‌مندسازی یارانه‌ها, شهرداری کرمان, چالش‌های طرح هدف‌مندسازی یارانه‌ها, تحلیل مضمونی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Directing Subsidies Plan, Kerman Municipality, challenges in enactment of Directing Subsidies Plan, Thematic Analysis</keyword>
	<start_page>33</start_page>
	<end_page>44</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-799-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Moslem</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ali Mahdi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مسلم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>علی مهدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>alimahdi63@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002216</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002216</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه امام رضا مشهد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Radadi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ردادی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002217</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002217</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
