<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>36</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>امکان سنجی توسعه اجتماعی و فرهنگی شهر تهران با تاکید بر سیستم های تصمیم گیری چند شاخصه (مطالعه موردی منطقه 20 تهران)</title_fa>
	<title>Social and cultural development feasibility of Tehran With an emphasis on multi-criteria decision systems (Case study: Neighborhoods in District 20)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
فرهنگ، شهر و محله سه پدیده مکمل هستند. به عبارت دیگر هر سه پدیده های انسانی را تکمیل می کنند. شهر و محله صورت است و فرهنگ محتوای آن است. یکی جنبه خارجی و دیگری جنبه داخلی آن است. محله یکی از عناصر اساسی شناخت فضاهای شهری مثل آثار و ابنیه، سینما ها، مساجد و مدارس است. هدف این مقاله ارزیابی شاخص های توسعه فرهنگی - اجتماعی و نشان دادن سطوح توسعه محلات از نظر بهره مندی فضا ها و امکانات است. آمار مورد استفاده در این تحقیق از سازمان شهرداری های استان تهران و سالنامه های آماری در سال 1390 اخذ شده است. نوع تحقیق کاربردی و روش تحلیل مقایسه ای و مدل مورد استفاده مدل الکترا می باشد. نتایج حاصل از تحقیق نشان می دهد که بین محلات منطقه 20 شهرداری تهران، از نظر بهره مندی از فضاها و امکانات فرهنگی تفاوت فاحشی وجود دارد. در این بین محله دیلمان نسبت به سایر محلات از توسعه فرهنگی و اجتماعی بیشتری نسبت به بقیه برخوردار می باشد.
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
Culture, the city and the area are three complementary phenomenon. In other words, all three complete human phenomena. The city's neighborhoods and culture and its content. One external and the other internal aspect of it. The neighborhood is one of the basic elements of cognition of urban spaces, such as buildings and monuments, cinemas, mosques and schools. The purpose of this paper is to assess the social and cultural development indicators show the levels of courses to benefit development of space and facilities. Statistics used in the study of the Organization of the municipality of Tehran province and Statistical Yearbook in the year 2012 is getting. The type r is functional and comparative analysis method and model used to model Electre. The results of the research show that between 20 area neighborhoods of Tehran municipality, in terms of benefit from cultural spaces and facilities there is a huge difference. In this area of development than other localities dolman social and cultural more than the rest
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>زیرساخت فرهنگی, رتبه بندی فرهنگی, شاخص های فرهنگی محلات, مدل الکترا.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Culture Infrastructure, Culture Ranking, Cultural indicators of neighborhood, Electre</keyword>
	<start_page>339</start_page>
	<end_page>350</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-53-5&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Bemanian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بمانیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>bemanian@modares.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846001475</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001475</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tarbiat Modarres University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Khaliji</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خلیجی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001476</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001476</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Islamic Azad University of Tabriz</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تبریز</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
