<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>39</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیلی بر ابعاد پیوستگی توده و فضا در عرصه‌های عمومی شهری</title_fa>
	<title>Analysis of the continuity of the masses and public space in the city</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
موضوع این مقاله، بررسی ابعاد پیوستگی و انسجام توده و فضا در عرصه های عمومی شهری است. داشتن پیوستگی و انسجام یکی از اصلی‌ترین معیارهای کیفیت فضاهای شهری محسوب می‌شود. فضاهای سنتی و بومی عمدتاً واجد چنین کیفیتی بودند. مدعای این مقاله آن است که در حال حاضر، هم از لحاظ عملی و هم از لحاظ نظری فضاهای شهری و علوم مرتبط با طراحی محیطی در این زمینه دچار چالش‌های اساسی هستند. نتیجه آن‌که به لحاظ نظری، رویکردهای نظری نسبت به‌این موضوع فاقد جامعیت لازم بوده و در عمل، اکثر فضاهای شهری فاقد پیوستگی و انسجام لازم می‌باشند. نوشتار حاضر با رویکردی پدیدارشناختی - روان‌شناختی، موضوع پیوستگی و انسجام فضاهای عمومی شهری را مورد مطالعه قرار داده و معیارهای پیوستگی ساختمان و شهر در فضاهای عمومی شهری را بررسی نموده‌است. با رویکرد پدیدارشناختی، مطالعه صرفاً محدود به وضعیت فضاهای عمومی شهری با توجه به شرایط خاص آنها فارغ از عوامل علی گردیده است. با رویکرد روان‌شناختی، نقش مردم در ادراک و شناخت پیوستگی ساختمان و شهر در فضاهای عمومی شهری مطالعه شده‌است. در این مقاله پیوستگی ساختمان و شهر در فضاهای عمومی شهری، تابعی از پیوستگی فضا در ابعاد کالبدی، فضایی، اجتماعی- فعالیتی، و نمادین معرفی شده‌است.
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
The objective of this paper is to examine the coherence and consistency of the masses and the public space in urban areas. The continuity and integrity of one of the main criteria is the quality of urban spaces. Mainly indigenous and traditional spaces such quality criteria. The paper claims that now, both practical and theoretical areas of urban and environmental design associated with the main challenges are in the field. The result is that, in theory, theoretical approaches to this issue and no recall was necessary in practice, many urban areas lack the coherence and cohesion is necessary. The present article is a phenomenological approach - psychological, the continuity and coherence of urban public spaces and buildings studied and integration criteria of the urban public spaces is investigated. Phenomenological approach, limited to the study of urban public spaces according to their specific circumstances regardless of causal factors were The psychological approach, the role of public perception and understanding of the continuity of the building and the city's public spaces of the city In this conjunction buildings and public spaces in the city, a function of the continuity of physical space, spatial, social activity, and symbolic introduced.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>انسجام,کلیت, ابعاد پیوستگی, معیارهای پیوستگی, ساختمان و شهر, عینیت و ذهنیت. </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>coherence, totality, of continuity, continuity standards, the building and the city, subjective and objective.</keyword>
	<start_page>407</start_page>
	<end_page>428</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-348-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mansoor</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Yeganeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>منصور</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>یگانه</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>yaghane@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001925</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001925</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Bemanian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بمانیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001926</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001926</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
