<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>35</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>مشارکت بهره برداران در فرآیند طراحی، زمینه ساز تحقق پایداری اجتماعی مسکن انبوه در ایران نمونه موردی: مسکن شهرک صنعتی پرند</title_fa>
	<title>The Role of Participation of Users in the Design Process in Achieving Social Sustainability in House Industry in Iran Case Study: Parand Town-Tehran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
در اوایل قرن بیستم میلادی، روش های پیش ساخته سازی در خط تولید (مدولار سازی)، در صنعت ساختمان مطرح و به عنوان معماری سریع تر و کم هزینه تر معرفی، اما به علت در نظر نداشتن مسائلی مانند تنوع و رعایت خواست و سلیقه کاربران در طراحی ساختمان، با شکست مواجه شدند. مشارکت کاربران در طراحی با توسعه فناوری های دیجیتال در قرن 21، شکل جدیدی از پیش سازی ساختمان با نام «شخصی سازی انبوه» را مطرح کرد که می توانست مطابق با خواست هر مشتری و با در نظر گرفتن ویژگی های تولید انبوه کارخانه ای، مجموعه وسیع و متنوعی را تولید کند. هدف از انجام این پژوهش، بررسی نقش مشارکت بهره برداران در فرآیند طراحی، به منظور حرکت صنعت ساختمان در ایران به سوی ساخت و ساز پایدار در فضاهای مسکونی انبوه است. روش پژوهشی مورد استفاده، روش تحلیلی توصیفی و مبتنی بر سنجش معیارها به شکل کیفی است. در این راستا پس از تبیین مفاهیم و معیار های پایداری اجتماعی مسکن، شهر پرند به عنوان نمونه موردی مسکن صنعتی ساز در ایران مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. جامعه آماری این پژوهش 50 خانواده ساکن در خانه های صنعتی ساز با سیستم های نوین ساختمانی LSF، ICF و قالب تونلی بوده است. ابزار مطالعه در این پژوهش پرسشنامه بوده که بر اساس مؤلفه های حاصل از مطالعه تنظیم شده و هدف اصلی آن ارزیابی متغیر های پایداری اجتماعی در مسکن های صنعتی ساز است. نتیجه پژوهش از برآیند پرسشنامه ها و مطالب ارائه شده پیرامون راهکار پیشنهادی حاصل شد که شخصی سازی انبوه لازمه اصلی حرکت به سوی ساخت و ساز پایدار در ایران است.
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
Before the invention of computer-aided design, most manufacturing processes were limited to one of two options: mass production or customization. Mass production is the production of large amounts of identical parts. The idea has existed for hundreds of years (the Venetian Arsenal, a shipyard in Venice, employed mass production to produce one ship per day as far back as the 14th or 15th century), but it did not achieve widespread popularity until its adoption by Henry Ford’s Ford Motor Company (Henry Ford’s famous quote: “Any customer can have a car painted any color that he wants — so long as it is black.”). Due to economies of scale, mass production reduces costs significantly, but it prohibits individual choice. The industrialized method of building, which has been in use since World War II for the construction of residential areas, does not leave much room for individual choice. This lack of choice is common when first introducing mass production in car industry. However, other industries have shown that mass production can be combined with individual choice. 
This approach is called mass customization. It is a mix between the two systems that attempts to combine the low cost of mass production with the flexibility of custom work. Giving buyers more freedom of choice when it comes to the design of their new house will require their participation in the design process. This method is called Self-building that users can design their own buildings. Although not inherently required, mass customization is often achieved through computer aided design, which allows for more flexible output with little or no additional variable costs (though at the cost of a higher up-front investment). By making the production process more flexible, designs that are tailored to individuals can still be produced industrially. But this approach faced with a challenge in house industry because of lacking standardized design and technology that were exist in other industries.
In 21th century by introducing new technologies like CAD-CAM and robotic methods of construction, this gap was filled so mass customization could be justified economically in the house construction industry. The main goal of this study was to evaluate the role of participation of users in the design process, in order to move towards sustainable construction in the house industry in Iran. The subpopulation of this research was 50 families living in prefabricated house in Parand town in Tehran. The survey tool is a questionnaire which was set up in the 26 questions in multiple-choice format that evaluates social sustainability attributes in prefabricated houses. The result shows that these houses have serious weakness in social sustainability indicators in a way that users had no role in the design process and 75% of them are believed that it is better to go back to the traditional method of construction instead of new methods. Finding of this study indicate that with rapid population growth and demand for housing in the country, housing industry in Iran should move toward mass customization in order to achieve successful sustainable construction.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مشارکت در طراحی, صنعتی سازی, شخصی سازی انبوه, طراحی پایدار</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Participation in design, Mass production, Mass customization, Sustainable design</keyword>
	<start_page>7</start_page>
	<end_page>24</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-624-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mahmood</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Golabchi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمود</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>گلابچی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001662</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001662</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University College of Fine Arts</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>پردیس هنرهای زیبا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ramtin</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Khalatbari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رامتین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خلعتبری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>khalatbari.ra@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846001663</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001663</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University College of Fine Arts</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>پردیس هنرهای زیبا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Alireza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Fazel</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علیرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فاضل</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001664</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001664</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University College of Fine Arts</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>پردیس هنرهای زیبا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
