<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>36</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی آثار اقتصادی وندالیسم بر هزینه‌های شهرداری و ارتباط آن با سرمایه اجتماعی: مطالعه موردی مشهد</title_fa>
	<title>Economic impacts of vandalism on municipality expenditures and its relationship with social capital: Case study of Mashhad</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>هدف اصلی این مطالعه بررسی تبعات و آثار اقتصادی وندالیسم بر هزینه‌های شهرداری مشهد و تبیین جایگاه سرمایه اجتماعی در آن می‌باشد. آمار و اطلاعات این مطالعه از طریق تکمیل پرسشنامه و جمع‌آوری آمار و طلاعات از سازمان‌های مختلف شهرداری مشهد بدست آمد. برای این منظور از روش معادلات ساختاری جهت بررسی میزان تأثیرگذاری انواع ناهنجاری‌های اجتماعی بر هزینه شهرداری و تبعات اقتصادی آن استفاده شد. نتایج نشان داد که رفتارهای ناصحیح شهروندان و وندالیسم باعث می‌شود سالانه مبلغی به میزان 808 میلیارد و 918 میلیون ریال به شهرداری مشهد وارد شود. در این خصوص بیشترین هزینه‌ها در زیربخش‌های مختلف شهرداری مربوط به معاونت خدمات شهری (بجز سازمان پارک‌ها و فضای سبز، فردوس‌ها و آتش‌نشانی و ایمنی) (56.8 درصد از کل هزینه ها)، سازمان پارک‌ها و فضای سبز (35.8 درصد از کل هزینه ها) و اتوبوسرانی (5.7 درصد از کل هزینه ها) می‌باشد. سازمان حمل و نقل و ترافیک (0.9 درصد)، سازمان فردوس‌ها (0.5درصد) و شرکت قطار شهری (0.3 درصد) و سازمان آتش‌نشانی (0.1 درصد) در رتبه‌های بعدی قرار دارند. میزان سرمایه اجتماعی (با ابعاد مشارکت، اعتماد، منزلت و مشورت) می‌باشد که در شهر مشهد در حد متوسط است که بیشترین سهم را در تشکیل آن، اعتماد دارد. نتایج حاصل نشان داد که افزایش 10 درصدی سرمایه اجتماعی در جامعه شهروندان مشهد باعث کاهش 1.2 درصدی تخریب وسایل و امکانات توسط شهروندان می‌گردد که این میزان معادل کاهش مبلغی در حدود 9 میلیارد و 445 میلیون ریال می‌باشد. در انتها با توجه به نتایج بدست آمده، راهکارهای مناسب اجرایی جهت افزایش سرمایه اجتماعی و کاهش تخریب‌های ناشی از عدم رعایت فرهنگ شهروندی ارائه شد. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>The main objective of this study is to evaluate the consequences and economic impacts of vandalism on the costs of Mashhad municipality and specifying the position of social capital in it. The data of this study gained by questionnaire filling and collected the information from various organizations of Mashhad municipality. To this purpose were used the Structural Equation Model (SEM) to evaluate the effectiveness a variety of social disorders on municipality expenditures and the economic consequences. The results indicated that, the inaccurate behaviors of citizenry and vandalism causes to be entered annually the amount of 808 billion riyals to Mashhad municipality. In this case, the highest costs in the various subsections of Mashhad municipality is pertained to department of civil service (except of parks and greens spaces organization, Ferdus organization and fire fighting and safty organization) (56.8 percent of total costs), parks and greens spaces organization (35.8 percent of total costs) and Bus organization (5.7 percent of total costs). The transportation and traffic organization (0.9 percent), paradise organization (0.5 percent) and railway operation company (0.3 percent) and fire fighting organization (0.1 percent) are in the next following ranks. The amount of social capital (With dimensions of the partnership, confidence, dignity and consultation), that is moderate in Mashhad and trust have the most share in its formation. Also, the results showed that, 10 percent increases in social capital in Mashhad citizens society is caused 1.2 percent reduction the destruction of equipment and facilities by citizens that this amount is equivalent to a reduction of approximately 9 billion rials. Finally, considering to the results, was provided appropriate executive strategies to increases the social capital and reducing the destruction results from non-observant of citizenship culture.  </abstract>
	<keyword_fa>وندالیسم – آثار اقتصادی - سرمایه اجتماعی – شهرداری – مشهد</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Vandalism, Economic impacts, Social capital, Municipality, Mashhad</keyword>
	<start_page>351</start_page>
	<end_page>368</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-80-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>هادی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رفیعی دارانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>hadirafiy@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001477</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001477</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>مشهد-میدان آزادی-پردیس دانشگاه-جهاددانشگاهی-گروه اقتصاد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سارا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>پارساپور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>sh_parsa_a@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001478</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001478</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>مشهد-میدان آزادی-پردیس دانشگاه-جهاددانشگاهی-گروه اقتصاد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مجید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>دانایی سیج</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>majid.danaee@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001479</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001479</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>مشهد-میدان آزادی-پردیس دانشگاه-جهاددانشگاهی- گروه اقتصاد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>افسانه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زارعی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>zareeiafsaneh@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001480</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001480</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>مشهد-میدان آزادی-پردیس دانشگاه-جهاددانشگاهی- گروه اقتصاد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
