<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>37</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی نگرش مردم محلی به سیاست تبدیل روستا به شهر بر حسب محل سکونت (مطالعه موردی: بخش دیلمان، شهرستان سیاهکل)</title_fa>
	<title>An Investigation of Local Residents’ Attitude to the Policy of Transformation of Villages to Towns According to Settlements (case study: Dailaman District, Siahkal Township)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>در اغلب کشورهای در حال توسعه اتخاذ سیاست تبدیل روستا به شهر بر مبنای این فرض است که شهرهای کوچک در فرایند توسعه ملی، منطقه‌ای و محلی نقش دارند. این پژوهش با مطالعه در بخش دیلمان، در پی ارزیابی نگرش مردم به سیاست تبدیل روستا به شهر در توسعه است. نوع پژوهش، کاربردی، روش انجام آن توصیفی- تحلیلی و روش گردآوری اطلاعات به دو صورت کتابخانه‌ای و میدانی است. تمرکز اصلی در بخش مطالعه میدانی بر پرسشنامه است. داده‌های جمع‌آوری شده پس از کدگذاری و انتقال به نرم‌افزار SPSS، تجزیه و تحلیل گردید. برای آزمون فرضیات، از روش‌های آمار توصیفی و استنباطی استفاده شد. اگرچه دیدگاه دو گروه از پاسخگویان بر عدم توفیق سیاست تبدیل روستا به شهر دلالت دارد؛ اما میزان تأثیر آن در سطح منطقه بر حسب محل سکونت متفاوت بوده؛ یعنی میزان این تأثیر در سطح شهر بیش‌تر از روستاهای پسکرانه است. بنابراین، بین نگرش ساکنان منطقۀ مورد مطالعه به سیاست تبدیل روستا به شهر بر حسب محل سکونت (شهر یا روستا)  تفاوت معنی‌داری وجود دارد. میزان تأثیر این سیاست در ابعاد مختلف متفاوت بوده و بیشترین تأثیر آن در ابعاد اجتماعی- فرهنگی و پس از آن ابعاد کالبدی- زیست‌محیطی  و در انتها ابعاد اقتصادی بوده است.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>There is a bias for transformation of villages to towns in the developing countries because it is thought that small towns have roles in the national, regional and local development. This research based on studying in Dailaman district is going to assess local residents’ attitude to transformation of villages to towns in achievement of the development. The type of research is applied and its method is descriptive-analytical. Required information was collected through the library and field studies. The main tool for data collection was a researcher-designed questionnaire.  For analyzing the data, descriptive and inferential statistical methods were used. Although both groups of respondents comment on the failure of the policy of transformation of villages to towns, the extent of its effects in the region has been different according to the settlements. It means the extent of its effects in the town, is more than the villages. Thus, there is a meaningful difference between two groups' attitude about the policy of the transformation of villages to towns in the development according to the settlements (villages or towns). The extent of its effects has been varied in different dimensions. The greatest impact has been on the social- cultural dimensions and then physical- environmental dimensions and in the end, economical dimensions. </abstract>
	<keyword_fa>نگرش, توسعه روستایی, شهر کوچک, تبدیل روستا به ‌شهر, بخش دیلمان.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Attitude, Rural Development, Town, Transformation of Villages to Towns, Dailaman District </keyword>
	<start_page>193</start_page>
	<end_page>212</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-283-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Bahram</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Karimi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>بهرام</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کریمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>b_karimi9@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001572</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001572</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran - Mohammad Ali Jinnah Boulward- Bayndryha Street - Amrollah Avenue - Second Street - No. 18 - Unit 15 - code: 1459744458</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>تهران- بلوار محمدعلی جناح- خیابان بایندری‌ها- خیابان امرالهی- کوچه دوم-پلاک 18- واحد 15- کد پستی:  1459744458 </affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Badri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بدری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>sabadri@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846001573</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001573</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran - Tehran University -Faculty of Geography</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>تهران- دانشگاه تهران- دانشکده جغرافیا</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Salmani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سلمانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>salmanim@voila.fr</email>
	<code>10031947532846001574</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001574</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran - Tehran University -Faculty of Geography</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>تهران- دانشگاه تهران- دانشکده جغرافیا</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
