<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>29</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارزیابی علل عدم استفاده از فناوری‎های نوین ساختمانی در نوسازی بافت‎های فرسوده شهر تهران</title_fa>
	<title>Evaluation of the use of new technologies in renovation of deteriorated urban areas in Tehran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>صنعت ساختمان و پروژه های عمرانی به گواهی آمار و ارقام، از لحاظ سرمایه و حجم نیروی انسانی درگیر، بزرگ‎ترین صنعت در کشور می‎باشد. رشد سریع جمعیت و افزایش تقاضا، نیاز به کاهش زمان تحویل پروژه های عمرانی و کاهش زمان برگشت سرمایه سرمایه گذاران و عواملی از این قبیل باعث شده اند تا ضرورت ایجاد تحول در شیوه‎های سنتی صنعت ساختمان روزبه‎روز بیشتر شود. نیاز به بهره‎گیری از تکنولوژی‎های ساخت متناسب با رشد هر جامعه و بهره‎گیری از فناوری در سایر صنایع و توانایی‎های اجرای آن جامعه متغیر است. چنین نیازهایی است که بعضاً به نوآوری‎ها و یا انتقال فناوری می‎انجامد. وسعت عظیم بافت‎های فرسوده با معضلات فراوان و نبود استراتژی‎های روشن درخصوص برنامه‎ریزی و مدیریت طرح و اجرا در نوسازی این‎گونه بافت‎ها، سبب شده تازمینه‎های تحقق قوانین و مصوبات هر چند اندک موجود نیز فراهم نشود و بافت‎های فرسوده شهری با روندی افزایشی به مهم‎ترین چالش شهر تهران تبدیل شود. مباحث مربوط به زلزله و مدیریت بحران در وهلۀ نخست و ابعاد اجتماعی، اقتصادی و کیفیت‎های قابل ارتقا کالبدی و کارکردی – فضایی این بافت‎ها در مراتب بعدی، نیاز به رویکردهای ویژه جهت نوسازی آنها را اجتناب‎ناپذیر می‎نماید. در این مقاله سعی شده است تا ضمن تعریف دقیقی از تکنولوژی‎های نوین ساختمانی، به اهمیت علل عدم گسترش فناوری‎های نوین در صنعت ساخت و ساز و شناسایی ریسک‎های ناشی از استفاده از این فناوری‎ها در پروژه‎های نوسازی بافت‎های فرسوده پرداخته شود و در ادامه ضمن دسته بندی و مشخص نمودن هریک از این عدم قطعیت‎ها به ریشه‎یابی علل بروز مهم‎ترین این عوامل پرداخته خواهد شد.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Construction and development projects to certified figures, the volume of capital and human resources involved the largestindustry in Iran. Rapid population growth and increasing demand, reducing the time needed to deliver development projects and reduce capital investment and time to have been caused by factors such as the necessity to change traditional practices in the construction industry. By taking advantage of the technologies needed to build community and develop appropriate technology and skills in other industries, it is changing society. Such demands, which sometimes leads to innovation and technology transfer. Great extent with the problem of worn out tissues and the lack of clear strategies on planning and project management and implementation of the modernization of these tissues, caused by the existing laws and regulations also provide a small and not old urban tissue with increasing trend to become the most important challenges in Tehran. Topics related to earthquake and disaster management and primarily social, economic and scalable physical and functional qualities, especially the need to modernize their approach to the inevitable. This article has attempted to define the precise construction of the new technologies, the importance of developing new technologies in the construction industry and identify the risks arising from use of these technologies in the context of renovation projects should beworn and in the category and clarify any uncertainties to the roots causes of the most important of these factors will be addressed.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>فناوری‎های نوین، بافت فرسوده، نوسازی، انتقال تکنولوژی، تکنولوژی ساخت.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>New Technology, fabric wear, modernization, Technology transfer, technology</keyword>
	<start_page>213</start_page>
	<end_page>234</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-144-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Katayoon</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Taqizadeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>کتایون</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>تقی زاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>ktaghizad@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600308</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600308</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>university of tehran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ehsan</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Soltan Panah</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>احسان</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سلطان پناه</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600309</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600309</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>university of tehran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
