<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>52</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیلی بر تغییرات کاربری اراضی و تاثیرات آن بر منطقه 3 کلان شهر تهران  </title_fa>
	<title>An Analysis of Land Use Change and Its Impact on the 3rd Metropolitan Area of Tehran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;سازمان فضایی زیست&amp;shy;گاه&amp;shy;های شهری، نتیجه مستقیم فرآیندهای اجتماعی، اقتصادی، سیاسی می باشد. این سازمان یابی از محل استقرار اجزاء داخلی یک پراکندگی فضایی تاثیر می پذیرد. محل استقرار هر جزئی نسبت به هر یک از اجزاء دیگر با هم و توأم سازمان یابی فضایی را شکل می دهند. کارکردهای اصلی انسان بویژه کارکردهای اقتصادی، اجتماعی، تجاری و خدماتی و بواسطه انجام آنهاست که چشم انداز محیط شکل، فرم و نظام مختص به خود را می گیرد. به دنبال رواج اندیشه های زیست بوم گرایی و توسعه پایدار در جهان به تدریج این نگرش در اذهان عمومی و برنامه ریزی رسوخ کرد که زمین یک کالای خصوصی نیست. بلکه مهم ترین ثروت همگانی و بستر اصلی تمام فعالیت های شهروندان و ابزار لازم برای تحقیق خواسته ها و آرزوهای انسانی در حال و آینده است در این راستا هدف از پژوهش حاضر تحلیل و ارزیابی کاربری اراضی شهری منطقه براساس تقسیمات کالبدی شهر و تعیین میزان سازگاری کاربریها است و روش تحقیق از نوع کاربردی توصیفی- تحلیلی می باشد. و با استفاده از روش اسنادی و کتابخانه&amp;shy;ای به جمع آوری اطلاعات پرداخته شده و در نهایت با استفاده از تکنیک مدل های چند معیاره اطلاعات را تجزیه و تحلیل نموده&amp;nbsp; که معیار سهم نسبی زیاد فعالیت های ساخت و ساز ناشی از تخریب و نوسازی در کل ساخت و ساز منطقه و پیامدهای ناشی از آن با کسب امتیاز (0.4270) توانسته رتبه اول را به خود اختصاص دهد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The spatial organization of urban habitats is a direct result of social, economic, and political processes. The organization of the internal component of a spatial dispersal can be affected. The location of each component is shaped together with each other in conjunction with spatial organization. The main functions of man, especially the economic, social, commercial, and service functions, are through their activities, the vision of the environment takes shape, form and system of its own. Following the prevalence of the ideas of ecosystemism and sustainable development in the world, this attitude gradually penetrated into public opinion and planning that land is not a private commodity. It is also the most important commonwealth and the mainstay of all the activities of citizens and the means necessary to research the aspirations and aspirations of humanity in the present and future. In this regard, the purpose of this research is to analyze and evaluate the utilization of urban lands of the region based on the city's physical divisions and to determine the degree of adaptation of applications. The research methodology is descriptive-analytical And using the documentary and library method to collect information Finally, using multi-criteria modeling techniques, the information is analyzedThe criterion of the relative relative contribution of construction activities due to the destruction and renovation in the whole construction area and the consequences of it with a score of 0.4270 can be ranked first.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>کاربری اراضی شهری, تغییرات, منطقه 3 شهر تهران, تکنیک مدل های چند معیاره</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Urban land use, Changes, District 3 of Tehran, Multi-criteria model technique</keyword>
	<start_page>127</start_page>
	<end_page>144</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1816-91&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>جعفر </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>پرج</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846009009</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846009009</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ناصر </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>اقبالی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846009010</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846009010</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
