<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>38</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>امکان سنجی مشارکت شهروندان در مدیریت و توسعه پارک های محله ای شهر تهران</title_fa>
	<title>Feasibility study Citizen participation in the management and development of neighborhood parks in Tehran.</title>
	<subject_fa>عمومى</subject_fa>
	<subject>General</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>هدف اصلی این مقاله، امکان سنجی مشارکت شهروندان در مدیریت و توسعه پارک‌های محله‌ای، از طریق سنجش میزان تمایل آنان و عوامل موثر بر آن در سطح شهر تهران است.جهت بررسی موضوع پژوهش از نظریات رابرت دال و نظریه کنش مستدل آیزن و فیش باین استفاده شده است.برای پاسخ گویی به سوال اصلی پژوهش، یعنی میزان تمایل به مشارکت و عوامل موثر بر آن، پیمایشی با استفاده از ابزار پرسش‌نامه بر روی 400 نفر از مراجعه‌کنندگان به پارک‌های محله‌ای، که با روش نمونه‌گیری خوشه‌ای و تصادفی ساده انتخاب شده‌اند، انجام گرفته است.
در این پژوهش، رابطه متغیرهای گرایش به رفتار مشارکتی، هنجار ذهنی، تصور فرد از اهمیت مشارکتش، تصور فرد از مهارت‌ها و تخصص‌هایش، میزان زمان اختصاصی، مشوق مالی، میزان اعتماد به کارائی و عملکرد شهرداری با متغیر وابسته میزان تمایل به مشارکت مورد سنجش قرار گرفته است که مهم‌ترین نتایج مبین آن است که میزان تمایل به مشارکت بر اساس طیف لیکرت(در بازه 1 تا 5) 35/3 و درحد متوسط به بالا است.از میان عوامل موثر بر تمایل به مشارکت، عواملی چون گرایش به رفتار مشارکتی، تصور فرد از مهارت و تخصصش، میزان زمان اختصاصی و مشارکت در قبال مشوق مالی بیشترین تأثیر را بر متغیر تمایل به مشارکت داشته‌اند.این متغیرها توانسته‌اند 1/40 درصد از تغییرات متغیر وابسته تمایل به مشارکت را تبیین کنند. 
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Abstract

This research attempts to investigate the level of willingness to participation in  management and development of a neighborhood park among visitors of  neighborhood parks of urban areas in Tehran .To study this issue, Robert Dahl's theory and the theory of reasoned action has been used. To response the main question of the study, namely the willingness to participation and factors affecting it, this study used a questionnaire on 400 visitors of neighborhood parks by the cluster sampling and simple random sampling in 2013.
In this research we examined the relationship of variables attitude toward participatory behavior, subjective norms, the imagination of a person of the importance of participation, his imagination of  his skills and expertise, the amount of time dedicated, financial incentives, confidence to the performance of municipal with dependent variable of willingness to participation. The results demonstrated the level of willingness to participation (in the range 15 to 75) is 50/29 and that is moderate to high. Among the factors that influence the willingness to participation, Factors such as attitude toward participatory behavior, imagination of a person of his skills and expertise, the amount of time dedicated and financial incentives have the greatest impact on willingness to participation.


</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مشارکت شهروندی , پارک محله ای , فضای سبز , کنش مستدل</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Citizen Participation , Neighborhood Park , Landscape , Reasoned action</keyword>
	<start_page>425</start_page>
	<end_page>448</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-79-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>bahram</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>rasouli</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>بهرام</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رسولی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>rasouli.b@alumni.ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846001852</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001852</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>abdolhosein</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>kalantari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>عبدالحسین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کلانتری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>abkalantari@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846001853</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001853</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
