<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>48</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>عوامل فرهنگی موثر برتوسعه ارتباطات مجازی در روابط عمومی شهرداری منطقه 1 تهران</title_fa>
	<title>Cultural Effective Factors on the Development of Virtual Communication in the Public Relations of Municipality of District 1 in Tehran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;دراین تحقیق در راستای بررسی عوامل فرهنگی موثر بر توسعه ارتباطات مجازی در روابط عمومی شهرداری منطقه 1 تهران، رویکردها و مدلهای مختلف مطرح گردیده و سپس ضمن بررسی نظرات کارکنان شهرداری منطقه 1 تهران، از دیدگاه های ارائه شده از سوی آنها، استفاده شده است. روش تحقیق به کار گرفته شده در این پژوهش از نظر&amp;nbsp; هدف کاربردی، از نظر نوع داده ها کمی&amp;nbsp; و از نظر نحوه گردآوری داده ها، توصیفی و از نوع همبستگی است. جامعه آماری این پژوهش کلیه کارکنان&amp;nbsp; شهرداری منطقه 1 تهران هستند که تعداد آنها حدود 1500 نفر می&amp;zwnj;باشد که با توجه به ضوابط نمونه&amp;zwnj;گیری (بر اساس شیوه نمونه&amp;zwnj;گیری مندرج در جدول مورگان) تعداد 384 نفر به عنوان نمونه تحقیق انتخاب می شوند. 400 پرسشنامه بین این افراد توزیع شده و 384 پرسشنامه برگشت داده شده است. در مرحله بعد بر اساس مدل مفهومی پژوهش، سوالات و فرضیه&amp;shy;های پژوهش، با استفاده از پرسشنامه محقق&amp;shy;ساخته، گویه&amp;shy;های مستخرجه در نمونه آماری تحقیق مورد پرسش قرار گرفته است. در بخش آمار توصیفی، توصیف داده&amp;shy;ها در دو بخش متغیر های زمینه&amp;shy;ای و متغیرهای اصلی با استفاده از شاخص های فراوانی مطلق، فراوانی نسبی، میانگین، انحراف معیار و واریانس در جداول ارائه گردیده و در بخش استنباطی، جهت بررسی فرضیه&amp;shy;ها از آزمون ضریب همبستگی پیرسون و رگرسیون خطی چندگانه استفاده شده است. با توجه به داده های تحقیق می توان گفت عوامل فرهنگی بر توسعه ارتباطات مجازی در روابط عمومی شهرداری منطقه 1 تهران موثر می باشند&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;In this research, in order to study the cultural factors affecting the development of virtual communication in the public relations of the municipality of district 1 in Tehran, various approaches and models have been introduced. Then, after considering the opinions of the employees of the municipality of district 1 in Tehran, the views provided by them have been used. . The research method used in this research is applied in terms of purpose, in terms of data type, quantitative and in terms of data collection method, descriptive and correlational. The statistical population of this research is all employees of the municipality of district 1 of Tehran, whose number is about 1500 people. According to the sampling criteria (based on the Morgan table sampling method), 384 people are selected as the sample of the study. 400 questionnaires were distributed among these people and 384 questionnaires were returned. In the next stage, based on the conceptual model of the research, the research questions and hypotheses, using the researcher-made questionnaire, have been questioned in the statistical sample of the research. In the descriptive section, descriptive data in two parts of the underlying variables and main variables are presented using absolute frequency, relative frequency, mean, standard deviation, and variance in the tables. In the inferential part, for testing the hypotheses, the test Pearson correlation coefficient and multiple linear regression have been used. According to the research data, it can be said that cultural factors affect the development of virtual communication in the public relations of the municipality of district 1 of Tehran.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>عوامل فرهنگی, توسعه ارتباطات مجازی, روابط عمومی, کارکنان شهرداری منطقه 1 تهران.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Cultural factors, development of virtual communication, public relations, municipal employees</keyword>
	<start_page>203</start_page>
	<end_page>224</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-15&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رحمان زاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007902</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007902</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>معصومه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حیدری پارسا</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007903</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007903</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
