<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2013</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>32</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>به کارگیری خوشه‎بندی خاکستری و توابع پایه شعاعی در پهنه‌بندی اقتصادی کلانشهر تهران با تمرکز بر استقرار مؤسسات مالی و اعتباری</title_fa>
	<title>Application of Grey Clustering and Radial Basic Functions in economical zoning of Tehran Megalopolis concentrating on Credit and Financial Institutes installation</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;اهمیت تصمیمات مکانی و تأثیرات آن بر عملکرد سازمان‌ها و شرکت‌های مختلف بر کسی پوشیده نیست. مکان مناسب باعث می‌شود تا سازمان به مشتریان بیشتری دست پیدا کند و مؤسسات مالی و اعتباری همواره در جستجوی بهترین مکان برای فعالیت‎های خود هستند. تحقق این هدف به شناسایی عوامل و معیارهای مؤثر در این زمینه و شناسایی میزان تأثیر‎گذاری هر یک از این عوامل بستگی دارد. این تحقیق به دنبال ارائه مدلی در راستای شناسایی پهنه‎های بهینه در استقرار شعب بانک‎ها و مؤسسات مالی و اعتباری به وسیله روش‎های ذهنی و عینی می‎باشد. در ابتدا پس از شناسایی معیار‌های و عوامل مؤثر اقتصادی بر اساس الگو رفتار فضایی مشتریان و مدیران، داده‌های مکانی متناسب با معیارها جمع‎آوری شد. در روش ذهنی، وزن هر کدام از معیارها پس از تکمیل پرسشنامه مقایسه زوجی از سوی کارشناسان به وسیله مدل فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی(Fuzzy AHP) مشخص گردید و در مدل‌سازی فضایی و پهنه‌بندی منطقه از آنالیز خوشه‎بندی خاکستری(GCA)‎ استفاده شد. همچنین در روش عینی از شبکه‎ عصبی RBFLN جهت مدل‌سازی فضایی و پهنه‌بندی استفاده شد و به منظور ترکیب نتایج این دو روش از عملگر تلفیق AND مدل بولین استفاده گردید. نتایج ترکیب کلاس‎های بهینه هر کدام از این تکنیک‎های پهنه‎های پیشنهادی اولیه را تشکیل می‎دهند. این فرایند در شهر تهران و بر روی هر 22 منطقه این شهر اجرا شد. مدل مورد نظر بر اساس تراکم فعلی بانک‎ها و مؤسسات مالی و اعتباری شهر تهران برای هر دو روش عینی و ذهنی ارزیابی گردید که نتایج حاصل از کارایی مدل حکایت می‌کند. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;The importance of local decisions and their effects on different corporations and services is best known. Selection of suitable places makes it easier for the corporations to find and catch more customers, and hence, credit and financial institutes are always seeking the most proper locations for their activity centers. Achieving this goal depends mainly on identifying the effective criteria and effectiveness of each of the mentioned factors. This research is up to introduce a model in order to identify the optimum zones for installation of banks and credit and financial institutes' branches using objective and subjective methods. In the first step, after identifying effective criteria and economical factors based on the pattern of customers and managers spatial behavior, spatial data were collected. In the subjective method, weight of each criterion was calculated using the Analytical Hierarchy Process (AHP) after fulfillment of a paired comparative questionnaire by the expert. For spatial modeling and zoning the Grey Clustering Analysis (GCA) was used. Also, in the objective method the RBFLN neural network was used for spatial modeling. The Boolean combination function &quot;AND&quot; was used to combine the results of the two former methods. The results of combining the optimum classes constitutes of primary proposed zones. This process was conducted on each of the 22 regions of Tehran. Finally the model was evaluated for both objective and subjective methods, which suggest the significant performance of the model. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>آنالیز خوشه‌بندی خاکستری(GCA)، فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی(Fuzzy AHP)، شبکه عصبی RBFLN، پهنه‎بندی، مؤسسه مالی و اعتباری.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Gray Cluster Analysis (GCA), Fuzzy Analytic Hierarchy Process (Fuzzy AHP), RBFLN neural network, Zoning, credit and financial institute.</keyword>
	<start_page>227</start_page>
	<end_page>244</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-99-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ghadir</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ashoor Nejad</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>غدیر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عشورنژاد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600167</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600167</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Rahilali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Abbaspoor</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رحیم علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عباسپور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>abaspour@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600168</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600168</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Technical Faculty of Tehran University campus</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>پردیس دانشکده های فنی دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
