<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>48</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی جایگاه حیاط در معماری اقلیمی بناهای مسکونی شهری با تاکید بر اقلیم سرد و خشک ایران</title_fa>
	<title>Investigating the position of the courtyard in the climatic architecture of urban residential buildings with an emphasis on the cold and dry climate of Iran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin-right:4.75pt;&quot;&gt;عناصر معماری بومی، بیش از هر عامل دیگری، تحت&amp;shy;تاثیر عوامل محیطی و اقلیمی شکل گرفته&amp;shy;اند. اقلیم به عنوان یک عامل تعیین کننده موجب پدید آمدن گونه های متفاوت معماری در مناطق اقلیمی مختلف شده است. &amp;laquo;حیاط&amp;raquo; یکی از عناصر معماری مسکونی بومی است که نقشی اساسی در حیات بشری خاصه در ایران و معماری ایرانی داشته است؛ چنانچه در مناطق مختلف و تحت&amp;shy;تاثیر شرایط محیطی، ساختار اقلیمی متفاوتی به&amp;shy;خود گرفته است. اهمیت این عنصر از آن&amp;shy;جهت است که به عنوان یک فضای معمارانه، می&amp;shy;تواند رابط میان فضاهای زیستی و فضای خارج بوده و با تاثیر در شرایط محیطی، خود به&amp;shy;عنوان یک خرده&amp;shy;اقلیم عمل نماید. بر این اساس، در این مقاله با روش &amp;laquo;توصیفی- تحلیلی&amp;raquo; و روش &amp;laquo;تحلیل محتوای کالبدی&amp;raquo; به بررسی جایگاه و نقش حیاط در معماری اقلیمی ایران خاصه در بناهای مسکونی پرداخته شده و در اقلیم سرد و خشک نتایج مربوط به جایگاه آن در طراحی همساز با اقلیم مورد اشاره قرار گرفته است و در پایان نیز نتایج مربوط به این بررسی به تفصیل مورد تبیین کیفی و مفهومی قرار گرفته است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Indigenous architectural elements are shaped more than any other factor influenced by environmental and climatic factors. Climate as a determinant factor has led to the emergence of different types of architectures in different climates. The courtyard is one of the elements of indigenous residential architecture, which has played a major role in human life especially in Iran and Iranian architecture, as various climatic conditions have occurred in different areas under the influence of environmental conditions. The significance of this element is that, as an architectural space, it can be the interface between the biological spaces and the outer space and act with its impact on environmental conditions itself as a subtlety. Accordingly, in this article, through descriptive-analytical method and content analysis method, the position and role of the courtyard in the climatic architecture of Iran especially in residential buildings has been investigated. In cold and dry climate, the result related to its position in designing Concordance with the climate has been mentioned. At the end, the results of this study have been described in detail both qualitatively and conceptually.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>معماری همساز با اقلیم, اقلیم, دسته‌بندی اقلیمی, حیاط.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Architecture compatible with climates, climates, cluster classification, courtyard

</keyword>
	<start_page>223</start_page>
	<end_page>244</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-49&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>افشین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رئیسی دهکردی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007846</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007846</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
