<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>39</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تبیین معیارهای طراحی فضاهای فرهنگی با رویکرد پایداری اجتماعی و پویایی فضایی؛ موردپژوهی: فرهنگسراهای شهر تهران</title_fa>
	<title>Determine the design criteria of cultural approach to social sustainability and spatial dynamics Case Study: cultural center in Tehran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
امروزه تبیین معیارهای پایداری فضاهای زیستی با رویکرد پایداری اجتماعی از مهمترین موضوعات در حوزه برنامه‌ریزی معماری و شهر است که باید در فرآیند طراحی معماری موردنظر قرار گیرد. از سویی دیگر، هدف از فرهنگسراها، ایجاد محیطی آزاد، صمیمی و دارای فضایی باز است که از طریق یک سیستم غیرمتمرکز اداره می‌شود. به بیان عامیانه می‌توان فرهنگسراها را پاتوق‌هایی فرهنگی با تعاملات اجتماعی دانست که به‌عنوان یک مرکز فرهنگی، بخشی از فعالیت‌های فراغتی را پوشش می‌دهد که به ضرورت طراحی معمارانه این فضاها برای پویایی اجتماعی اشاره دارد. بر این اساس، مقاله حاضر با بهره‌گیری از «روش توصیفی- تحلیلی» در مرحله نظری و «روش پیمایشی» در مرحله تحلیلی و با ابزار گردآوری داده مشتمل بر مطالعات کتابخانه‌ای و اسنادی به بررسی مفهوم پایداری اجتماعی در معماری و طراحی فضاهای فرهنگی پرداخته است و برای تحلیل داده‌های حاصل از پژوهش و تبدیل آن به احکام معماری و سپس طراحی، از روش چیدمان فضا استفاده شده است. در ادامه این داده‌ها به صورت نمودارهای هم‌ترازی و سپس به صورت نقشه‌های گاما آورده شده است و در مرحله‌ی نهایی با استفاده از این تحلیل‌ها و مطالعات صورت‌گرفته بر روی سایت و با توجه به استانداردها و برنامه‌ی فیزیکی، طراحی معماری فرهنگسرا صورت گرفته است. در پایان نیز به معیارهای طراحی فضاهای زیستی با درنظرگیری پایداری اجتماعی و پویایی فضایی اشاره شده و راهکارهایی در راستای بهبود وضعیت ساختاری و فرهنگی فرهنگسراهای شهر تهران برای پویایی اجتماعی و امکان‌دهی حضور در عرصه‌های جمعی مورد اشاره قرار گرفته است.
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
Today explained social sustainability criteria for sustainable living spaces with a view of the most important issues in the field of architecture and city planning that must be considered in the process of architectural design. On the other hand, the objective of cultural centers, create a free, intimate and open space is through a decentralized system is run. Crudely can cultural centers, cultural and social interactions, known as a cultural center, part of the leisure activities covers the architectural design of these spaces for social mobility refers to the need. Accordingly, this paper using the &quot;analytical method&quot; in the conceptual phase &quot;survey&quot; in the analytical and data gathering tools including library and documentary studies to examine the concept of social sustainability in architecture and design, cultural spaces Paid. To analyze the data obtained from research into architecture and design rules, synapses space is used. In the data for gamma curves alignment and then given maps and In the final stage of this analysis and studies on the site according to the standards and physical, cultural, architectural design has been done. Finally, leveraging social sustainability criteria for designing living spaces and spatial dynamics are discussed and a solution to improve the cultural and structural social mobility and the possibility of forming cultural center in Tehran to attend the public arena has been discussed.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>پایداری اجتماعی, توسعه پایدار, مجتمع‌های فرهنگی- تفریحی, معیارها و مولفه‌های طراحی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>social sustainability, sustainable development, cultural and recreational complex, and component design criteria.</keyword>
	<start_page>235</start_page>
	<end_page>262</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-711-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Sahar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Salmasi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سحر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سلماسی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>salmasi_sahar@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001903</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001903</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران جنوب</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Leila</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Karimi Fard</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>لیلا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کریمی فرد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001904</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001904</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران جنوب</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
