<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>48</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>برآورد نیاز مسکن اقشار کم درآمد در 25 سال آینده</title_fa>
	<title>Estimated need for housing for low-income groups in the next 25 years</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;تعالی هر جامعه در گرو رفع نیازهای اولیه افراد آن جامعه می باشد. چنانچه هر فرد در زندگی خود از شغل و مسکن مناسب برخوردار باشد، در کنار یک ساختار تأمین اجتماعی کارآمد و فراگیر و امنیت کافی و جامعه قانون مدار احساس آرامش خواهد نمود. افراد چنین جامعه ای ظرفیت قابل توجهی برای تعالی و پیشرفت پیدا می نمایند و در صورت وجود برنامه ریزی صحیح در این جوامع، پیشرفت علمی، توسعه یافتگی، تولید ثروت و پیشتازی در اقتصاد و از همه مهمتر تامین کرامت انسانی قطعی خواهد بود. در تمامی جوامع تنوع درآمد در بین افراد جامعه اجتناب ناپذیر است و طبیعتاً افراد با درآمد مناسب قادر به تأمین نیازهای مختلف خود می باشند، لیکن اقشار کم درآمد بدون حمایت دولت&amp;zwnj;ها قادر به رفع نیازهای اساسی خود از جمله تامین مسکن، نخواهند بود. از این رو برنامه ریزی برای حمایت از این گروه پیش نیاز برقراری عدالت اجتماعی و در عین حال لازمه شکل گیری یک جامعه مترقی و متوازن است. بنابراین برای تحقق این موضوع، این مقاله، به برآورد نیاز مسکن اقشار کم&amp;zwnj;درآمد در طول 25 سال آینده پرداخته است. بدین منظور، ابتدا تمامی مشخصات گروه هدف تعیین شده و سپس تعداد مسکن مورد نیاز تا پایان سال هدف برآورد شده است. اهمیت برآورد تعداد واحد مسکونی مورد نیاز برای آینده در برآورد منابع مالی مورد نیاز برای ساخت این واحدهای مسکونی و همچنین جهت مدیریت صحیح و تامین هزینه&amp;zwnj;ها، بسیار حائز اهمیت بوده و از طرفی موجب تامین مسکن مورد نیاز و از سوی دیگر موجب رشد و رونق بازار مسکن خواهد شد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The excellence of each society depends on meeting the basic needs of those people. If any person has a decent job and housing in his life, he will feel comfortable with an efficient and comprehensive social security structure and adequate security and the law-enforcement community. The people of such a community will have considerable potential for excellence and, if there is proper planning in these societies, scientific progress, development, wealth generation, and the pioneering economy and, most importantly, human dignity will be decisive. In all societies, income diversification is inevitable among people, and naturally, people with appropriate income are able to meet their different needs, but low-income groups without the support of governments will not be able to meet their basic needs, including housing. Therefore, planning to support this group is a prerequisite for social justice and, at the same time, necessary for the development of a progressive and balanced society. So, in order to realize this, this paper has addressed the need for housing for low-income groups over the next 25 years. To do this, first all the characteristics of the target group are determined and then the number of required housing is estimated by the end of the year. The importance of estimating the number of residential units needed for the future is very important in estimating the funds needed to build these residential units, as well as for proper management and financing, and, on the other hand, provides the necessary housing and, on the other hand, promotes market growth and prosperity. Housing will be.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>برآورد نیاز مسکن, اقشار کم درآمد, مردان و زنان, ازدواج و طلاق, موالید و اموات</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Estimated housing needs, low income groups, men and women, marriage and divorce, births and wives</keyword>
	<start_page>315</start_page>
	<end_page>326</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-21&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نیکزاد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007918</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007918</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
