<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>30</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارزیابی و سنجش شاخص‌های ذهنی کیفیت زندگی شهری؛ مطالعه موردی: شهر کاشان</title_fa>
	<title>Evaluation and Analysis of Mental Indicators of Urban Quality of Life (Case Study: Kashan City)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>کیفیت زندگی از جمله مسائل مهمی است که ابتدا با گسترش همه جانبه فناوری و فرایند صنعتی شدن در کشورهای غربی مورد توجه اندیشمندان قرار گرفت و روز به روز بر مطالعات در این زمینه افزوده شده و این مهم به دلیل اهمیت روز افزون مطالعات کیفیت زندگی در پایش سیاست های عمومی و نقش آن به عنوان ابزاری کارآمد در مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی شهری است. یکی از ابعاد مطالعات کیفیت زندگی مربوط به شاخص های ذهنی آن می باشد که در این بعد از مطالعات کیفیت زندگی می تواند میزان تجمعی از سطح رضایت در قلمروهای مختلف زندگی باشد. هدف مطالعه حاضر سنجش کیفیت زندگی در شهر کاشان با استفاده از شاخص های ذهنی می باشد که این شاخص ها در قالب سه قلمرو اقتصادی، کالبدی – زیست محیطی و فرهنگی – اجتماعی تدوین و مورد ارزیابی قرار می گیرند. روش تحقیق به صورت توصیفی – تحلیلی و پیمایشی می باشد. همچنین جامعه آماری در این پژوهش ساکنان شهر کاشان می باشند که به صورت تصادفی و با استفاده از جدول کرجی و مورگان 300 نمونه انتخاب و پرسش نامه بین آنها توزیع شده است. به همین جهت در این پژوهش جهت دستیابی به قضاوتی صحیح، از 19 شاخص در سه قلمرو اقتصاد، کالبدی – زیست محیطی و فرهنگی – اجتماعی استفاده شده است. نتایج حاصل از تحقیق حاکی از آنست که اکثر مولفه های ذهنی تا سطح 99% رابطه معناداری را نشان می دهد در واقع بیشتر ساکنان شهر کاشان تا حد نسبتا زیادی از کیفیت زندگی خود رضایت دارند. برای بررسی رابطه بین وضعیت اجتماعی – اقتصادی شهروندان و میزان رضایتمندی از مولفه‌های ذهنی کیفیت زندگی، از آزمون رگرسیون چندمتغیره استفاده شده است که نتایج بدست آمده نشان دهنده رابطه معنادار بین وضعیت اقتصادی - اجتماعی شهروندان (به عنوان متغیر مستقل) و میزان رضایتمندی آنها از مولفه های ذهنی زندگی (به عنوان متغیر وابسته) می باشد. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Quality of life is among the significant issues that was first paid attention to by the scholars with the widespread development of technology and industrialization process in Western countries and the studies in this regard has been increased and this significant issues is due to increasing importance of the studies performed in the field of quality of life in the monitoring of general policy and its role as an efficient tool in urban planning and management. One of the dimensions of the studies in the field of quality of life is related to its mental indicator, considering this dimension of the studies in quality of life, it can be accumulation of satisfaction in various areas of life. This study aims to evaluate quality of life in Kashan city using mental indicators which these indicators have been developed and analyzed in the framework of three economic, physical-environmental and social-cultural realms. The research method is a descriptive-analytical and survey one. Also, the statistical community in this study is Kashan city residents who 300 samples have been selected at random using Kerji and Mourgan Table and a questionnaire has been scattered among them. Therefore, to achieve a correct judgment, 19 indicators in three economic, physical-environmental and social-cultural realms have been used in this study. The results obtained from this study indicate that mental components show a significant relationship up to 99% level which most residents of Kashan city have a relative satisfaction about their quality of life. To examine the relationship between resident's economic-social conditions and their satisfaction of mental component of quality of life, multivariate regression test has been used, by which the obtained results showed a significant relationship between citizen's economic-social conditions (as the independent variable) and their satisfaction with the mental life components (as the independent variable). </abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شاخص‌های ذهنی، کیفیت زندگی، شهر کاشان.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>mental indicators, quality of life, Kashan city.</keyword>
	<start_page>285</start_page>
	<end_page>296</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-238-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ali Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Khajeh Shahkoohi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علیرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خواجه شاهکوهی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600551</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600551</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Golestan University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه گلستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>shahraam</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mahdavi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>شهرام</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مهدوی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Mahdavishahram@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600552</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600552</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Golestan University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه گلستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Farshad</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Soori</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>فرشاد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سوری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600553</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600553</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Esfahan</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه اصفهان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Samadi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صمدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600554</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600554</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Golestan University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه گلستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
