<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>28</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>نقش نهادهای مدیریت شهری در مدیریت پایدار شهر با تاکید بر جایگاه کمیسیون ماده پنج شهر تهران</title_fa>
	<title>The Role of Institutions in Sustainable Urban Management with an Emphasis on the Five Commissions Position in Tehran Metropolitan</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;توسعه پایدار، مشتمل بر رشد و توسعه موزون اقتصاد، محیط زیست و جامعه انسانی و فرهنگ، وظیفه‌ی پیچیده‌ای است و حصول به آن اهمیت نهادهای دولتی را به واسطه‌ی در اختیار داشتن قدرت‌های قانونی و وظیفه‌ی صیانت از آن چه متعلق به عموم، مورد تاکید قرار می‌دهد. از جمله نهادهای تصمیم‌گیر و اثرگذار در امر توسعه پایدار شهری کمیسون ماده پنج وزارت مسکن و شهرسازی می‌باشد که بر اساس قانون تنها مرجع تغییر در طرح جامع و تفصیلی مصوب شهر و تعیین کاربری‌های مورد نظر مالک است. هدف از این پژوهش بررسی کمیسیون ماده پنج تهران به عنوان نهادی میان بخش در مدیریت شهری در تحقق توسعه پایدار شهر تهران می باشد. روش مورد استفاده در این پژوهش تحلیلی- تبیینی بوده و جمع آوری اطلاعات با استفاده از پرسشنامه، در دو سطح مختلف شامل مدیران، متخصصصان مرتبط با مدیریت شهری و فعال در کمیسیون ماده‌ پنج تهران و متخصصین و صاحب نظران دانشگاهی صورت گرفت. یافته ها نشان می‌دهد که در گروه نقاط قوت ابلاغ مصوبات به ادارات و مناطق شهرداری در مدت زمان مقرر، در گروه نقاط ضعف کمبود نیروی متخصص و فنی جدید، در زمینه عوامل فرصت‌ها وجود فارغ التحصیلان دوره‌های تحصیلات تکمیلی مرتبط با مدیریت شهری و در زمینه تهدیدها، رانت زمین و دلالی زمین با بالاترین وزن نسبی در اولویت قرار گرفته‌اند. بر اساس نتایج سهم عوامل تهدیدها از مجموع وزن نسبی بین گروهی برجسته تر می‌باشد. در انتها، پژوهش حاضر بر لزوم مشارکت مردم در اعمال هر نوع تغییری تاکید می‌کند. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Sustainable development, including harmonious growth and development of economy, environment and society, is complex task and achieving it highlights the importance of governmental institutions due to having the legal power and having task preserve public property. An effective decision-maker institution in urban sustainable development is Commission of Article five in Housing and Urban Development ministry which is only one to change an approved detailed plan of city. This research aimed at recognition study of commission of article five as mediator and coordinator institute in urban sustainable development in Tehran metropolis. In order to this, in this investigation, analytical-explanatory Method was used. Data were gathered by questionnaire in two different levels: urban managers in Commissions of article five and specialists in university. The results show that in time impart of approvals to municipal offices in strength variables, shortages in technical personnel in weakness variables, high number of undergraduates related to urban management in opportunity variables, and land rent and land dealers in threat group have highest relative weight among other variables. Corresponding to results, total relative weight of the threat factors shares the most prominent weight of all groups. Finally, research emphasizes the necessity of public participation in decision-making process for any change. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>کمیسیون ماده‌ پنج، مدیریت شهری، برنامه ریزی راهبردی، تهران.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Commission of Article Five, Urban Management, Strategic Planning, Tehran.</keyword>
	<start_page>27</start_page>
	<end_page>46</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-109-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hoseini</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حسینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>a.hosseini@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600203</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600203</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Geography Faculty of Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده جغرافیا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ahmad</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Poor Ahmad</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>احمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>پور احمد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600204</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600204</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Geography Faculty of Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده جغرافیا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Moosa</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Pajoohaan</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>موسی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>پژوهان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600205</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600205</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Geography Faculty of Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده جغرافیا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hojjat allah</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rahimi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حجت الله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رحیمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600206</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600206</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
