<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>48</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>آسیب شناسی مشارکت شهروندان در احساس و ادراک مسائل عمومی در جوامع شهری</title_fa>
	<title>Pathology of citizen participation in feeling and  perception of public issues</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;ﻣﻬﻢ ﺗﺮﻳﻦ و ﻋﻈﻴﻢ ﺗﺮﻳﻦ ﺳﺮﻣﺎیه ﻫﺮﺟﺎمعه ای ﻣﻨﺎﺑﻊ اﻧﺴﺎﻧﻲ آن جامعه است. مشارکت یکی از ارکان نظام&amp;nbsp; های مردم سالارانه و دموکراتیک محسوب می شود که &amp;nbsp;باعث اﻓﺰاﻳﺶ درک و آﮔﺎﻫﻲ ﺷﻬﺮوﻧﺪان از ﻣﺴﺎﺋﻞ ﻣﺮﺑﻮط ﺑﻪ آﻧﻬﺎ شده، و به اثربخشی سیاست ها و برنامه های بخش عمومی منجر می شود. مشارکت شهروندان می&amp;shy;تواند در تامین منابع اقتصادی، کاهش هزینه خدمات، افزایش انسجام اجتماعی، کاهش آسیبها و تنش&amp;shy;های ناشی از زندگی و رضایت شهروندان موثر باشد. هدف اصلی این پژوهش اسیب شناسی مشارکت شهروندان در احساس و ادراک مسائل عمومی به منظور ارائه راهکارهایی مناسب جهت مشارکت شهروندان می باشد. ابزار گردآوری داده ها در این پژوهش&amp;nbsp; پرسشنامه محقق ساخته 69 سؤالی است که بر اساس مبانی نظری تحقیق، تنظیم و روایی پرسشنامه از طریق ارائه &amp;nbsp;نظر خبرگان &amp;nbsp;تائید و ضریب آلفای کرونباخ آن برای &lt;a name=&quot;_Hlk492040724&quot;&gt;جامعه خبرگان 823/0 و برای &amp;nbsp;جامعه مردم عادی 834/0 محاسبه گردیده که بیان گر پایایی و همسانی مؤلفه های درونی&lt;/a&gt; پرسشنامه می باشد. جهت &amp;nbsp;تعیین حجم نمونه در جامعه آماری تحقیق که مراجعین به مجلس شورای اسلامی ایران بودند، از روش نمونه گیری تصادفی بر اساس جدول مورگان تعداد نمونه 384 نفر مشخص شد&amp;nbsp; و در جامعه آماری خبرگان (نمایندگان مجلس شورای اسلامی ایران) از نمونه گیری غیر تصادفی تعداد نمونه 290 نفر مشخص گردید. با توجه به وجود دو جامعه متفاوت برای بررسی مقایسه نظرات&amp;nbsp; دو گروه در&amp;nbsp; وضعیت موجود (جامعه) و وضعیت مطلوب (خبرگان) از آزمون تی مستقل و همچنین اهمیت عملکرد استفاده گردید. نتایج تجزیه و تحلیل اطلاعات نشان داد که درتمامی مولفه ها شکاف میان وضع موجود و مطلوب مشاهده میگردد. بیشترین شکاف مشاهده شده مربوط به شاخص سیاسی ازمولفه اختیار شهروندی و کمترین شکاف مربوط به شاخص غیرحضوری ازمولفه اطلاع رسانی می&amp;zwnj;باشد. لذا برای کاهش شکاف بین وضع موجود ومطلوب مولفه ها، و کمک به ارتقاء مشارکت، در حوزه مولفه ها و شاخصها&amp;nbsp; آسیبها شناسایی و راهکارهایی پیشنهاد&amp;nbsp; شده است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The most important and the main capital of every society is the human resource of that society. Participation is one of the elements of democratic systems, which could enhance the awareness and perception of citizens about relevant issues and could lead to effectiveness of policies and plans of public sector. Participation of citizens could affect supply of economic resources, reduction of service costs, increase in social integration, reduction of damages and stresses caused by life and satisfaction of citizens. The main objective of this study is path0ology of citizen participation in&amp;nbsp; feeling and perception of public issues to pr5ovide some solutions for citizen participation. Data collection instrument in this study is researcher-made questionnaire containing 69 items. According to the theoretical framework of research, the questionnaire was made and its validity was confirmed through survey of experts and the Cronbach's alpha was obtained to 0.823 for the expert population and was obtained to 0.834 for the population of ordinary people and this shows reliability and consistency of internal components of the questionnaire. To determine sample size in the population (clients of Islamic Consultative Assembly of Iran), random sampling was used based on Morgan table and the sample size was determined to 384 people. In the statistical population of experts (representatives of Islamic Consultative Assembly of Iran), nonrandom sampling was used and 290 people were selected as sample. According to existence of 2 different populations, to compare the opinions of two groups under existing status (population) and desired status (experts), independent t-test and significance-performance were used. The results obtained from data analysis showed that in all components, the gap between existing and desired status is evident. The highest gap observed is related to the political index of citizen's discretion and the lowest gap is related to inaccessible indicator of information components. Hence, to decrease the gap between existing and desired status of components and to help enhancement of participation, some suggestions and solutions are provided in field of components and indices and damages.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>آسیب شناسی, مشارکت, احساس مشکل, ادراک مشکل, مسائل عمومی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>pathology, participation, feel the problem, perception of problem, public issues</keyword>
	<start_page>129</start_page>
	<end_page>142</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-42&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حمیده</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عباسی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007831</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007831</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>کرم الله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>دانش‌فرد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007832</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007832</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهربان</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>هادی پیکانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007833</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007833</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
