<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>39</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>en</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>Evaluation Indicators of Good Urban Governance Case Study: The Central Area of Region 10of Tehran Metropolitan</title_fa>
	<title>Evaluation Indicators of Good Urban Governance Case Study: The Central Area of Region 10of Tehran Metropolitan</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>كاربردي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Applicable</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>با پیش بینی استقرار بیش از 66 درصد جمعیت جهان در شهرها در طی 10 سال آینده، جهان در حال تبدیل به جهان شهری است. از این رو مدیریت شهری در آینده درگیر مشکلات فراوانی خواهد بود. محققان و اندیشمندان حکمرانی خوب را بهترین راه برون رفت کلانشهرها از مشکلات مدیریتی خود می دانند، لذا مدیریت شهری با لحاظ نمودن مؤلفه های نظریه  حکمرانی خوب شهری در برنامه ریزی ها از آن بهره مند می  شود. هدف از این نوشتار، ارزیابی شاخص های حکمروایی خوب شهری در محدوده بافت مرکزی منطقه 10 تهران می باشد که به منظور دستیابی به این هدف درابتدا با روش مطالعه اسنادی، مفاهیم نظری، نظریه ها، الگوها، دستورالعمل ها و توصیه ها و معیارهای مختلف در رابطه حکمروایی خوب شهری و مؤلفه های آن در محیط شهری مورد بررسی قرار گرفته اند و با استفاده از مفاهیم و تعاریف، چارچوب اولیه تدوین شده است. برای سنجش حکمروایی هشت عامل اصلی: جامعیت و مشارکت، رضایتمندی، تحقق پذیری، آموزش و افزایش کارآیی، کنترل و نظارت، پاسخگویی و مشارکت، شفافیت، کیفیت و مطلوبیت محیطی در نظر گرفته شده و برای هر کدام زیرمعیارهایی تدوین شده است. در ادامه و به روش پیمایش، اطلاعات محدوده مورد مطالعه با استفاده از پرسشنامه جمع آوری گردید و در پی آن با تهیه ی بانک اطلاعاتی و استفاده از تحلیل عاملی در نرم افزار SPSS معیارها طبقه بندی شدند. و با استفاده از روش تحلیل رگرسیون خطی رابطه عوامل  با رضایتمندی کلی مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفته است و برای ارتقا و بهبود حکمروایی در منطقه 10 شهر تهران به اولویت بندی و رتبه بندی معیارها و زیر معیارها برای ساماندهی محدوده مورد مطالعه پرداخته شده است.</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>With forecasting the settlement of more than 66 percent of  the population of the world in cities over the next 10 years, the world is becoming a global city. So many problems would be involved in the future of urban management. Researchers presume good governance as the best solution for their management problems of metropolitans Therefore, considering the components of the theory of good governance, urban management will benefit from it in the planning. The goal of this article is evaluating the indicators of good urban governance in the central area of region 10 of Tehran metropolitan. In order to achieve this goal, we’ve used theoretical concepts, theories, frameworks, guidelines, recommendations, and different indicators related to good urban governance and its components in the urban environment that have been studied in the beginning. To evaluate the urban governance, eight primary factors including integrity participation, satisfaction, training and high efficiency, control and monitoring, accountability, participation, clarity, actualize,feasibility, quality and desirability of environment have been considered, and sub-criteria have been developed for each factor. data were collected using a questionnaire. Afterwards, by the preparation of the database and making use of factor analysis in SPSS, indicators were classified. Using linear regression analysis, the relation between factors with overall satisfaction was assessed. Furthermore, to improve governance in the central area of region 10 of Tehran, prioritizing and ranking indicators for organizing the study area have been investigated.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>ارزیابی, معیار, حکمروایی خوب شهری, منطقه 10 کلان شهر تهران</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Evaluation, Indicators, Good urban governance, Region 10 of Tehran</keyword>
	<start_page>171</start_page>
	<end_page>182</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-445-1&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Esmaeil</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Shieh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>اسماعیل</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>شیعه</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>es_shieh@iust.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846002172</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002172</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Professor of urbanism, University of Science and Technology, Email: es_shieh@iust.ac.ir, Phone: 09123271494</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>- استاد گروه شهرسازی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، پست الکترونیکی : es_shieh@iust.ac.ir ، تلفن: 09123271494</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Sadaf</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Tabatabaee</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>صدف</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>طباطبایی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>sadaf_tabatabaee78@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002173</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002173</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Master student of urbanism, University of Science and Technology, E-mail: sadaf_tabatabaee78@yahoo.com , Phone: 09128837522</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد رشته شهرسازی، دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، پست الکترونیکی: Sadaf_tabatabaee78@yahoo.com ، تلفن: 09128337522</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mehid</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Saidi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سعیدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mehdi.saidi87@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002174</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002174</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Master student of urbanism, University of Science and Technology, E-mail: mehdi.saidi87@yahoo.com , Phone: 09187741405</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد رشته شهرسازی، دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، پست الکترونیکی: mehdi.saidi87@yahoo.com ، تلفن: 09187741405</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
