<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>51</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>دگردیسی فضایی روستاهای ناحیه پیراشهری؛ مورد پژوهی: نایسر، شهر سنندج</title_fa>
	<title>Spatial Metamorphosis of Peri-Urban; the Case of: Naysar, Sanandaj </title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;بیش از نیمی از جمعیت جهان در نواحی شهری زندگی می&amp;shy;کنند. در صد سال اخیر روند روبه افزایش آن سکونتگاه&amp;shy;های همجوار شهرها را نیز تحت تاثیر قرار داده است. نواحی همجوار شهرها عموماً به صورت خودرو توسط مهاجرین و ساکنین کم&amp;shy;درآمد شکل می گیرند. نایسر نیز سکونتگاه کوچک مجاور شهر سنندج&amp;nbsp; که کمتر از دو دهه با انفجار جمعیتی شدید مواجه و به شهر سنندج ملحق گردید. تحقیق حاضر به بررسی دگردیسی فضایی ناحیه پیراشهری از دیدگاه سه گروه اجتماع حرفه ای، دانشگاهی، ساکنین نایسر پرداخته است، که دگردیسی فضایی و عوامل اثرگذار بر آن را در ابعاد اجتماعی، اقتصادی، محیطی و مدیریتی نهادی را مورد تحلیل قرار داده است. یافته&amp;shy;های تحقیق نشان می&amp;shy;دهد عوامل فقر شهری، مجاورت، دسترسی، عدم نظارت مدیریت شهری بر معاملات زمین و تغییر کاربری اراضی واقع در حریم شهر را بر افزایش جمعیت محدوده مورد مطالعه موثر تشخیص داده&amp;zwnj;اند. مهاجرین وارد شده به نایسر به دلیل شرایط نامتعادل اقتصادی، نایسر را انتخاب نموده اند، انتخابی از سر اجبار و نه اختیار، نایسر با تغییر ویژگی های جمعیتی، تغییر کاربری اراضی به ساخت وسازهای غالب مسکونی به سرعت در حال تغییر بوده است و می توان گفت از لحاظ اقتصادی، اجتماعی و کالبدی به تدریج ویژگی های شهری را بدست آورده است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;More than half of world's population lives in urban areas. Permanent increasing population has also affected peri-urban areas during this 100 years. Peri-urban areas are formed in an organic and without planning sense by new comers who belong to the lower middle class and low-income urban residents. Naysar was formerly a small settlement placed in the east of Sanandaj, but during two very recent decades it has experienced a tremendous increasing amount of settlers then merged into Sanandaj City immediately. The purpose of this study is to investigate the metamorphosis of peri-urban areas emphasizing on Naysar according to the view three different groups of community including: specialists, academics, and settlers of Naysar. The analysis has been done by considering social, economic, environmental, and institutional management approaches. The findings of the research show several factors influencing on spatial metamorphosis: urban poverty, neighboring and accessibility, The lack of supervision of urban management on land transactions and the change in the use of land located in the city on the increase in the population identified the effective study area. Economic problems lead the lower middle class community to settle in Naysar and land use of Naysar has been changed in parallel with changing characteristics of population. Through the findings, we can observe that Naysar has been gradually gaining economically, socially and physically gained urban characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>عوامل موثر بیرونی و درونی, پیراشهری, دگردیسی فضایی, نایسر.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>External and internal Effective Factors, Peri-Urban Spatial metamorphosis, Naysar</keyword>
	<start_page>279</start_page>
	<end_page>296</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1816-77&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مظفر </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صرافی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008766</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008766</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ژیلا </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سجادی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008767</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008767</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسن </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>محمدیان‌مصمم</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008768</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008768</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>شیدا </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>آزادی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008769</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008769</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
