<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>48</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی رابطه بین مدیریت منابع انسانی الکترونیکی با بهره وری در سازمان</title_fa>
	<title>Investigating the relationship between electronic human resource management and productivity in the organization</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;امروزه محدودیت منابع در دسترس لزوم استفاده مفید و کارا و ثمربخش را می&amp;shy;طلبد و افزایش جمعیت و رشد نیازها و خواسته&amp;zwnj;های شهری و کمیابی منابع&amp;nbsp; باعث شده که متصدیان عرصه شهری، سیاست و مدیریت جامعه و سازمان&amp;zwnj;ها، ارتقای بهره&amp;zwnj;وری سازمانهای دولتی را درصدر برنامه&amp;zwnj;های خود قرار دهند. مدیریت منابع انسانی الکترونیک توانایی بالقوه&amp;shy;ای در هر دو حوزه کار آیی و اثربخشی ودرنتیجه بهره وری سازمان دارد. از این رو در تحقیق حاضر به بررسی تأثیر&amp;nbsp; استقرار مدیریت منابع انسانی الکترونیک بر بهره وری در سازمان دارائی بیرجند پرداخته است. تحقیق حاضر کاربردی و از لحاظ روش، توصیفی- پیمایشی می&amp;shy;باشد. جامعه آماری شامل&amp;nbsp; تمامی کارمندان دارائی شهرستان بیرجند می&amp;shy;باشد که نرخ پاسخگویی به پرسشنامه 65 درصد بوده است. به&amp;shy;منظور گردآوری اطلاعات از پرسشنامه شاخصهای الگوی استقرار مدیریت منابع انسانی الکترونیک در سازمانهای دولتی &amp;laquo;خان&amp;shy;زاده و همکاران&amp;raquo; و &amp;laquo;پرسش&amp;shy;نامه بهره&amp;shy;وری شریفی&amp;raquo; استفاده شده است. مسیرهای فرض شده از مدیریت منابع انسانی الکترونیکی بر بهره وری در سازمان&amp;nbsp; معنی دار بوده و از نظر کارکنان کسب بهره&amp;shy;وری ازطریق &amp;nbsp;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;EHRM&lt;/span&gt; درگرو عوامل متعددی از جمله استقرار منابع انسانی الکترونیک به لحاظ بعد ساختاری، بعد فرهنگی، بعد استراتژیک، بعد تکنولوژیک و سایر عوامل می باشد. همه فرضیه متناظر با مسیرهای مورد نظر نیز با 95 درصد اطمینان مورد تأیید قرار گرفت به جز مسیر استقرار منابع انسانی الکترونیک به لحاظ بعد فرهنگی بر بهره وری سازمان که رد شد&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Today, the limited availability of available resources requires useful, efficient and fruitful utilization. Population growth and the growth of urban needs and demands, and the scarcity of resources have caused urban planners, policy and management of society and organizations to increase the productivity of government agencies in their programs. Give Electronic HR management is a potential capability in both areas of work and effectiveness and as a result of organizational efficiency. Therefore, in the present study, the effect of establishment of EHR on productivity in Birjand property organization has been studied. The present research is applied and is descriptive-survey method. The statistical population consisted of all finance staff in Birjand, with a response rate of 65%. In order to collect information, a questionnaire on indicators of the model of establishment of human resources management in the government organizations of Khanzadeh and colleagues in 1395 and Sharifi productivity questionnaire have been used. The hypothesized paths of electronic HR management on productivity in the organization are meaningful and in terms of EHRM productivity gains, various factors including the deployment of electronic human resources in terms of structural dimension, cultural dimension, strategic dimension, technological dimension and other factors is. All hypotheses corresponding to the desired paths were confirmed with 95% confidence, except for the path of deployment of electronic human resources in terms of cultural dimension on the organization's efficiency, which was rejected.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>منابع انسانی الکترونیک, بهره وری سازمان</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Electronic Human Resources, Organizational Productivity</keyword>
	<start_page>411</start_page>
	<end_page>420</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-27&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>زهرا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رجائی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007932</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007932</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ارغوانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007933</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007933</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>زهرا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مهمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007934</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007934</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
