<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>46</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>واکاوی درآمد پایدار شهرداری ها با رویکرد توسعه پایدار شهری؛ مطالعه موردی در شهر بندرعباس</title_fa>
	<title>Analysis of stable income urban municipalities with a sustainable development approach Case Study in Bandar Abbas</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>كاربردي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Applicable</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;شهرداری ها به عنوان بالاترین مقام برنامه ریزی و مدیریت شهری در شهرها شناخته شده اند. این نهاد که وظیفه خدمات رسانی به شهروندان را دارد جهت ایجاد محیط قابل قبول برای شهروندان دارای هزینه هایی جهت اجرای پروژه ها و برنامه های خود می باشد که به نام درآمد شهرداری ها شناخته می شود. این درآمدها گاه به صورت مستقیم وگاه در شرایطی غیر مستقیم می باشند. بررسی و واکاوی این درآمدها می تواند راهگشا و یاری رسان مسوولان جهت برنامه ریزی بهتر در شهرها باشد. بدین منظور در پژوهش حاضر به بررسی درآمد پایدار شهرداری ها با رویکرد توسعه پایدار شهری در شهر بندر عباس پرداخته خواهد شد. جامعه آماری پژوهش، ساکنان شهر بندرعباس و مسئولان مدیریت شهری می باشند. بر این اساس از آزمون تی استیودنت جهت سنجش وضعیت پایداری کلی منابع مالی و درآمدی مورد بررسی استفاده شده و همچنین تحلیل واریانس رگرسیون تأثیر افزایش درآمد پایدار و توسعه اجتماعی، فرهنگی و عمران شهر&amp;shy;ی شهرداری بندرعباس مورد سنجش قرار گرفته و در نهایت منابع درآمدی شهرداری از طریق مدل &lt;/span&gt;VIKOR&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt; مورد سنجش و رتبه بندی قرار گرفته اند. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;As head of the municipal planning and urban management in cities are known; It is the duty of service to the citizens. In order to create an acceptable environment for citizens to implement projects and programs, their costs are known by the name of municipal revenue. These revenues are sometimes directly and sometimes indirectly in the circumstances. Review and analysis of these revenues can be useful and helpful for planning better in cities. Therefore, in this study, stable income urban municipalities with a sustainable development approach will be discussed in Bandar Abbas. The research populations are residents of Bandar Abbas and officials of the civil administration. The Student t-test to measure used to evaluate the stability of financial resources and income. As well as regression analysis the effect of increasing revenue and developing sustainable social, cultural and development of Bandar Abbas municipal evaluated. And finally municipal revenue sources through VIKOR models were evaluated and ranked.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>درآمد پایدار, شهرداری, توسعه پایدارشهری, بندرعباس.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>stable income, municipalities, sustainable development, Bandar Abbas.</keyword>
	<start_page>97</start_page>
	<end_page>112</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-776-8&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>احمدعلی </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>اسدپور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846006123</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846006123</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
