<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>15</volume>
<number>45</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ضرورت آموزش کارگاهی در توانمندسازی دانشجویان شهرسازی در کاربرد دانش از منظر مدل‌های یادگیری سازنده‌گرا</title_fa>
	<title>The Necessity of Studio Education in Empowering the Urban Planning Students for Applying the Knowledge through Constructivism Learning Models</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;کاربردی نبودن دانش آموخته شده در محیط دانشگاه عامل اصلی خلأ بین حرفه و آموزش در بسیاری از رشته ها است. در رشته شهرسازی با توجه به تلفیق دو حوزه نظر و عمل ضمن آموزش دانشجویان شهرسازی این فرصت فراهم است تا دانشجویان بتوانند دانش آموخته شده در کلاس های نظری را مورد تجریه، تحلیل و ارزیابی قرار داده و آن را بصورت ساخت های ذهنی انسجام دهند و سپس در موقعیتی شبه واقعی در کارگاه های عملی به کار برند. بنابراین می توان ریشه ضعف دانش آموختگان شهرسازی در انتقال دانش به حرفه را در فرایند آموزش آنها جستجو نمود. با توجه به رقابتی شدن محیط های حرفه ای و خواست کارفرمایان برای بکارگیری نیروهای حرفه ای، توانمند سازی دانشجویان در امر انتقال آموخته هایشان ضرورتی جدی دارد. مزیت ها، ضرورت و اهمیت وجود آموزش های عملی در برنامه درسی شهرسازی و همچنین کیفیت های مورد انتظار از کارگاه های عملی شهرسازی ابتدا در آثار نظریه پردازان آموزش شهرسازی و سپس از منظر مدل های یادگیری سازنده گرا مورد مطالعه قرار گرفته است و راهبردهای اصلی در این باره براساس مدل های یادگیری سازنده گرا پیشنهاد گردیده است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The gap between profession and education in many courses of study is due the fact that the learned knowledge in the universities is not practical. Considering the collation of theory and practice in teaching the students, the urban planning has provided the opportunity for the students to evaluate and analyze their acquired knowledge in the theoretical classes and organize them as mental constructs and then apply them in practical studios, as semi-real situations. Therefore, the main shortcoming of urban planning students in their professions is the knowledge transfer in the process of education. Empowering the students regarding transferring their knowledge is highly essential because the profession environments have been very competitive and the employers aim to employ professional work force. The benefits, necessity, and the importance of having practical education in urban planning curricula and the expected qualities from urban planning practical studios were examined first by urban planning teaching theoreticians and then were studied through constructivism learning models and finally the main strategies were proposed from constructivism learning models.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>آموزش شهرسازی, کارگاه عملی, یادگیری سازنده گرا, انتقال دانش</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Urban Planning Education, Studio, Constructivism Learning Model, Transfer of Knowledge</keyword>
	<start_page>57</start_page>
	<end_page>72</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-5&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>زینب</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>طالبی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008243</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008243</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>فرح</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حبیب</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008244</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008244</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ایرج</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>اعتصام</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008245</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008245</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
