<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>47</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی تأثیر ارائه خدمات الکترونیکی بر بهبود خدمات شهری؛ نمونه موردی شهرداری ساوه</title_fa>
	<title>The survey of electronic services influence on urban service improvement (Case study: Saveh Municipality)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;منافع حاصل از به&amp;zwnj;کارگیری فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات باعث شده است که در اغلب&amp;nbsp; شهرها و شهرداری&amp;zwnj;ها تلاش&amp;shy;هایی برای پیاده&amp;zwnj;سازی این فناوری صورت گیرد. اما این تلاش&amp;zwnj;ها، در اغلب کشورها چالش عمده&amp;shy;ای را ایجاد کرده که علی&amp;zwnj;رغم سرمایه&amp;shy;گذاری در این فناوری، گسترش و نفوذ کاربردهای متنوع آن، به&amp;zwnj;کندی صورت می&amp;shy;پذیرد. شهرداری ساوه به علت پایین بودن سطح آمادگی الکترونیکی و کارایی و اثربخشی پایین سیستم&amp;shy;های مورداستفاده، در این زمینه نتوانسته آن&amp;zwnj;چنان&amp;zwnj;که نیاز است مثمر ثمر واقع شود. تحقیق حاضر ازنظر نوع جزء تحقیقات کاربردی و روش انجام آن نیز توصیفی_تحلیلی است. آمار و اطلاعات موردنیاز تحقیق از طریق مطالعات کتابخانه&amp;shy;ای، پیمایش میدانی و توزیع پرسشنامه جمع&amp;shy;آوری گردید، &amp;nbsp;در تجزیه&amp;zwnj;وتحلیل و آزمون فرضیات از آزمون کای اسکوئر و برای رتبه&amp;zwnj;بندی گویه&amp;shy;های تحقیق نیز از آزمون فریدمن استفاده گردید، نتایج تحقیق نشان می&amp;shy;دهد هرچند ارائه خدمات الکترونیکی توسط شهرداری ساوه بهبود و ارتقاء سطح خدمات&amp;zwnj;رسانی شهرداری را به همراه داشته است؛ اما این مساله افزایش مشارکت و کاهش هزینه&amp;shy;ها را به همراه نداشته است. بنابراین بهره&amp;shy;گیری بیشتر از امکانات موجود؛ و امکاناتی نظیر آموزش الکترونیک، سیستم مکاتبات بدون کاغذ، کنفرانس راه دور، پایگاه&amp;shy;های داده تحت &lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;Excel&lt;/span&gt;، &lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;Access&lt;/span&gt; و ... پیشنهاد می&amp;shy;گردد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;This concept posed and investigates in relation with theories like electronic government and virtual-electronic cities but when representation of urban services electronic regard by municipality. As present research also is centralized on this aspect&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;٬&lt;/span&gt;as it municipality electronic services mentioned in the form of special concepts pose&amp;nbsp; like electronic municipality and local electronic government. Urban electronic services be interactive Present research is regarding that by the use of available theoretical supporter&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;٬&lt;/span&gt; cover the topic of research and investigated strategies and guidelines based on information technology for increase and improvement of presented services in Saveh municipality by the use of&amp;nbsp; menstruation&amp;nbsp; method and questionnaire&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; The present research in terms of type is part of practical researches that has done by descriptive and analytic method. The research statistical community is consist of municipality employees and Saveh citizenry.(About inhabitant people in city 100 people as sample the minimum quorum is in the descriptive researches)&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &amp;nbsp;Of all employees and Saveh municipality staff 80 people are in touch with related topics to information technology&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;٬&lt;/span&gt;among them&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 40 people&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; completed the questionnaires for distribution of sample number in among all member of statistical community is used by classified sampler. Research stability and validity index by equal to .0725 calculated that it showed good quality of questionnaire in answering to research question.For analytic and hypothesis test are&amp;nbsp;used by Spps and Friedman statistical test&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; The result of index and component of research from citizenry point of view&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; Index and component of research in 3 axis evaluation of municipality operation in electronic services representations amount of citizenry satisfaction in presented services and economies due to electronic services representation considered. In index evaluation of municipality operation 24 hour access to services and presented facility via municipality with 30.08 averages has the highest average and increase of accuracy in directory services with 2.32 average have the lowest average. In satisfaction index of better affairs prosecution with 3.78 averages have the highest average and in the first rank between components allocate to itself. lack of necessity to personal recourse with %2.82 average have been in the lowest rank of this index. Component of awareness level increase and prevention from human error&amp;nbsp;have been respectively 3.08 and 3.04 average. Between economy index components also component of prevention from human errors with 3.67 averages has the highest average between components of this index and has been in the first rank. Component decentralization of&amp;nbsp; the city with2.12 average has been in the lowest rank of this index&lt;span dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>فناوری اطلاعات, خدمات الکترونیکی, خدمات شهری, شهرداری ساوه   </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Information technology, electronic services, utilities, municipalities Saveh</keyword>
	<start_page>545</start_page>
	<end_page>556</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1966-64&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد رضا </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مردانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007953</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007953</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>فاطمه السادات </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>التجا</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846007954</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846007954</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
