<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>12</volume>
<number>33</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تالار شهر؛ فضایی مطلوب در افزایش میزان مشارکت شهروندان</title_fa>
	<title>City Hall, a Desirable Arena to Increase Citizen Participation</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
به نظر می رسد که با توجه به رشد و توسعۀ شهرگرایی و شهرنشینی، مشارکت شهروندان در ادارۀ شهرها ضرورتی انکارناپذیر است. به ویژه در کشورهای در حال توسعه که شهرنشینان با انبوهی از مشکلات و مسائل پیچیدۀ مربوط به برنامه ریزی و اجرای طرح ها روبرو هستند مشارکت شهروندان می تواند تا حدود زیادی راهگشای موانع موجود باشد. مشارکت و یا ضعف مشارکت شهروندان، دارای ابعاد مختلفی است که با در نظر گرفتن ویژگی های اقتصادی، اجتماعی، فرهنگی، کالبدی و تاریخی شهرها و کشورهای مختلف، پیچیدگی های آن عیان تر می شود. هدف از این نوشتار، بررسی و ارائۀ راه حل برای تمامی موانع پیش روی مشارکت شهروندان در ایران نیست؛ بلکه در نظر دارد با تأکید بر مفهوم و کارکرد تالار شهر، به عنوان یک عنصر کالبدی- اجتماعی ویژه و ارتباط آن با موضوعاتی نظیر مشارکت شهروندی و فضای عمومی، بستری فیزیکی را معرفی کند که در آن رویدادهای مهم اجتماعی و فرهنگی شهر با حضور شهروندان معنا می یابد. برای این منظور، با بررسی مفاهیم ذکر شده و معرفی دو نمونه از تالار شهرهای موجود در جهان و همچنین اشارۀ مختصری به شرایط این فضاها در تهران معاصر و ارتباط بین شهروندان و مدیران شهری در تهران امروز، راهکارهایی برای خلق چنین فضاهایی می تواند مناسب و ضروری تشخیص داده شود.
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
Today, the necessity of citizen participation is an undeniable fact in management of cities. Especially in developing countries which are facing with many problems related to planning and implementing of projects, citizen participation can solve many of these difficulties. Participation or non-participation of citizens has several dimensions. Considering the social, cultural and historic features of cities in different countries (and in this perspective, Iran), its complexity becomes more explicit. The purpose of this paper is not review and providing solutions for all the hurdles involved in Iran's citizen non-participation, But intends to introduce a physical context which hosting social and cultural events and increase citizen participation by emphasizing on the meaning and function of City Hall, as a socio-physical element, and also its relationship with social issues such as participation and public space. For this purpose, after reviewing the listed concepts (and their relationship with City Hall) and introduction of two city halls in the world and also a brief mention of the conditions of these spaces in contemporary Tehran and the relationship between citizens and urban management in Tehran, solutions in order to create such atmosphere, but not necessarily as city Hall, will be presented.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شهر, شهروندان, مشارکت شهروندان, فضای شهری, تالار شهر</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>City, Citizen, Citizen Participation, Urban Space, City Hall</keyword>
	<start_page>185</start_page>
	<end_page>200</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-809-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Gholamreza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Latifi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>غلامرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>لطیفی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002244</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002244</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hamed</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Gohari Poor</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حامد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>گوهری پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>hamed1908@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002245</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002245</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
