<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2017</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>46</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>وظایف دولت در طراحی شهری با توجه به نظریه توسعه انسانی آمارتیاسن </title_fa>
	<title>According to the theory of human development in urban planning administration tasks Amartya Sen</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>كاربردي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Applicable</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;توسعه انسانی حلقه پایانی زنجیره&amp;shy;ی نظریات ابراز شده در دانش اقتصاد توسعه است که بنابر رای بنیادگذارانش، تحقق آن منوط بر تحقق توسعه در چهار بعد سیاسی، فرهنگی، اقتصادی و اجتماعی بطور همزمان خواهد بود. آمارتیا سن، اقتصاد دان نامدار هندی که از مهمترین مروجان این نظریه است، معتقد است که برای تحقق توسعه در تمامی این ابعاد، آزادی ابزاری باید تامین و تضمین شوند. یکی از آنها آزادی دسترسی به فرصتهای اجتماعی است. این آزادی نقش بی&amp;shy;بدیل و بسیار مهمی در تحقق توسعه انسانی دارد. یکی از عوامل مهم در دسترسی به فرصتهای اجتماعی، پراکندگی متناسب آنهاست که با مقوله&amp;shy; طراحی شهری نسبت تام و تمام دارد. دولت بمثابه نخستین مسئول تحقق فرآیند توسعه موظف است که فضاهای زیست شهری و پراکندگی امکانات را بنحوی طراحی نماید که هیچ شهروندی بجهت صعوبت دسترسی، از فرصتهای اجتماعی محروم نشود.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The opinions expressed in the knowledge economy, human development the final ring of the vote, its realization depends on the development in four dimensions: political, cultural, economic and social will be at the same time. Amartya Sen, the renowned economist Hindi is the most important promoters of this theory, believes that to achieve development in all these dimensions, freedom means must be secured. One of them is freedom of access to social opportunities. This freedom is unmatched and very important role in the realization of human development. One of the most important factors in access to social opportunities, their propor&lt;a name=&quot;_GoBack&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;tionate distribution that deal with urban design is complete. The state as the first responsible for the implementation of urban development process is responsible for living spaces and distribution facilities are designed in such a way that no citizen because of difficulty of access, deprived of social opportunities.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>توسعه انسانی, طراحی شهری, آمارتیاسن, فرصت‌های اجتماعی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>human development, urban design, Amartya Sen, social opportunities</keyword>
	<start_page>131</start_page>
	<end_page>140</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-776-10&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>یاسر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>روستایی حسین آبادی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846006127</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846006127</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی اکبر </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>گرجی ازندریانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846006128</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846006128</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
