<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>29</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تبیین عوامل موثر بر حکمروایی روستایی در حکومت‌های محلی؛ مطالعه موردی: شهرستان قزوین</title_fa>
	<title>Explain the factors affecting rural governance in local government (Case Study: Qazvin Township)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>طی سال‌های اخیر، عمده تلاش صاحبنظران و پژوهشگران بر تعریف ابعاد و شاخص‌های حکمروایی به منظور سنجش وضع موجود، معطوف بوده است و کمتر عوامل موثر بر حکمروایی و تبیین عِلّی این عوامل در راستای تحقق حکمروایی محلی و روستایی مورد توجه قرار گرفته است. در این راستا مطالعه حاضر با هدف تبیین عوامل موثر بر حکمروایی روستایی دهیاران و شوراهای اسلامی روستایی شهرستان قزوین با استفاده از رویکرد پیمایشی و اسنادی  انجام گرفت. داده‌های مورد نیاز با استفاده از پرسشنامه از 450 نفر از سرپرستان خانواده‌های روستایی، 47 دهیار، 47 رئیس شورای اسلامی روستا، 47 فرم مربوط به بخشداران شهرستان قزوین که با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری طبقه بندی شده با انتساب اپتیمم انتخاب شده‌ بودند، گردآوری شد. برای ارزیابی روایی مقیاس‌های رضایت شغلی، سبک مدیریت و سرمایه اجتماعی از آماره آلفای کرونباخ استفاده شد که به ترتیب ضرایب 69/0، 76/0و 95/0حاکی از همسانی درونی قابل قبول گویه‌های مورد استفاده می‌باشد. برای ارزیابی اعتبار مقیاس‌ها، از نظرات گروهی از متخصصان استفاده شد و با استفاده از همبستگی‌های دوگانه و تحلیل مسیر، داده‌ها مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفت. نتایج تحقیق نشان ‌داد، میانگین نمایه حکمروایی روستایی در 50 درصد از حکومت‌های محلی (دهیاری‌ها و شوراهای اسلامی) در وضعیت نامناسب، 40 درصد در وضعیت متوسط و تنها  10 درصد حکومت‌های محلی دارای حکمروایی روستایی مناسبی می‌باشند. همچنینمتغیرهای درجه دهیاری، جمعیت روستا، رضایت شغلی و سطح تحصیلات دهیار، سبک مدیریت، انسجام اجتماعی، تعامل موثر با دهیاری‌های مجاور و تجربه دهیار، مهمترین عوامل موثر بر حکمروایی روستایی محسوب می‌شوند. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Investigation theoretical concept of governance indicated that although this concept is more important in recent years, but in fact it has historical root, and its nature is in Interaction between actors in rural community life including government, civil society and people. It’s a model through which the participation and cooperation at all functional Forces and at all levels Geographical can provide sustainable development in rural areas. In this regard in recent years, leading experts and researchers working on defining the Governance dimensions and indicators to measure status quo has been focused and less attention has been Factors affecting Governance and causal explanation of these factors. This study aimed at explaining the factors affecting rural governance in local government of Qazvin Township. The research approach is survey methods and required data is gathered using the stratified sampling and completing questionnaire from 450 persons of head of rural households, 47 Rural Municipalities, Rural Islamic Councils and all of District Administrations (DAs) in the township. People were selected using multistage stratified sampling with optimal allocation method. Cronbach alpha coefficient was calculated equal to %69, %76 and %95 indicating the reliability appropriateness of the questionnaire. Data was evaluated by correlation coefficients and path analysis. The results indicate that the rural governance index in 50 percent of local governances is undesirable, 40 percent average and only 10 percent is desirable. Also RM’s degrees, rural population, job satisfaction and education and management style Village administrators (VA), social cohesion, and effective interaction with neighboring RMs and VA’s experience variables are the most important factors affecting rural Governance.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>حکمروایی روستایی، حکومت محلی، شهرستان قزوین، تحلیل مسیر، دهیار، شورای اسلامی روستایی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Rural governance, Local government, path analysis, Qazvin Township, Rural Municipality (Dehyari)</keyword>
	<start_page>179</start_page>
	<end_page>198</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-142-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ali Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Darban Astaneh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علیرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>دربان آستانه</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>astaneali@ut.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600303</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600303</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rezvani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رضوانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600304</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600304</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
