<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2013</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>31</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>مطالعه و شناخت منابع مالی و ارائه راهکارهایی برای بهبود پایداری درآمد شهرداری‌ها؛ مورد پژوهش؛ شهرداری شهر مهاباد</title_fa>
	<title>Study and identifying of financial resources and strategies for sustainable income for municipalities A case study municipality of Mahabad city</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;امروزه اولین و مهم‌ترین محدودیت برای حل مسائل روز افزون شهری و ناکارآمدی خدمات‌رسانی بویژه در شهرهای ملل درحال توسعه از جمله ایران، فقدان منابع مالی پایدار و مستمر، نظام ناکارآمد مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی هزینه است که در نهایت به عدم موفقیت چشم‌اندازهای پیش‌بینی شده شهری و نارضایتی شهروندان منتهی می‌شود. بنابراین ضرورت مطالعات بیشتر در این زمینه از اهمیت بالایی جهت پایداری درآمد و ایجاد کیفیت مناسب زندگی برای شهروندان برخوردار است که در این مسیر، نگاه نو به منابع درآمدی پایدار در شهرداریها، متضمن آینده روشن برای شهر‌ها جهت توسعه و تحقق شهر ایده‌آل می-باشد. درهمین ارتباط مقاله حاضر در نظر دارد به مطالعه و شناخت منابع مالی و راهکار‌های درآمدزایی پایدار برای شهرداری شهر مهاباد به عنوان یکی از شهرهای مهم استان آذربایجان غربی بپردازد. نوع تحقیق در پژوهش حاضر کاربردی و روش بررسی آن توصیفی- تحلیلی و پیمایشی می‌باشد و نتایج آن نشان می‌دهد که شهرداری مهاباد در بسیاری از جنبه‌ها با مشکلاتی مواجه می‌باشدکه ریشه آن به عدم وجود مکانیسم و راهبردهای درآمدزایی پایدار باز ‌می‌گردد. در نهایت با توجه به مشکلات و مسائل موجود شهرداری، راهکارهایی جهت درآمدزایی پایدار شهرداری پیشنهاد شده است. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Today, due to extensive urbanization and physical development of cities, urban management and administration is to become a hard work to do for most municipalities that are located particularly in city management. In this regard, the first and most important  limitations to solve the growing problems of urban and inefficient services in many developing cities of nations  such as Iran is lack of Sustained and continuous financial resources, , inefficient management and cost planning  system which ultimately lead to urban predict landscapes and dissatisfaction of citizens. Thus the need for further studies in the context is very importance for the stability of income and creating a suitable quality of citizen life. In this way, a new point of view to a sustainable income sources in the municipal, will ensures a bright future for cities to develop a comprehensive ideal city. So, the present article intends to study and identify the resources and strategies for sustainable income for Mahabad city as one of the major cities of west Azarbaijan province. Type of research is applied and the survey method is descriptive-analytical.  The results show that the city of Mahabad has many problems in many aspects which have roots in lack of mechanisms and strategies for sustainable income. Finally, with regard to the problems of the municipality, strategies have been suggested to sustainable income.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شهرداری، درآمد پایدار، مدیریت شهری، شهر مهاباد.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>municipality, sustainable income, urban management, Mahabad city</keyword>
	<start_page>107</start_page>
	<end_page>124</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-62-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Keramat Allah</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Zyari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>کرامت الله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زیاری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460059</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460059</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Geography Faculty of Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده جغرافیا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mahdi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مهدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Ali_mas7@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>100319475328460060</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460060</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Geography Faculty of Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده جغرافیا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Masoomeh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mahdian Bahnamiri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>معصومه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مهدیان بهنمیری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460061</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460061</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Golestan University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه گلستان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
