<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>49</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>مطالعه مسکن برای گروه‌های کم درآمد شهری با تاکید بر پایداری اجتماعی؛ نمونه موردی شهر ایلام</title_fa>
	<title>The study of housing for small urban groups with emphasis on social sustainability ( the city 's case of Ilam )</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;پایداری اجتماعی و بهبود رفاه نسل های آینده و کنونی بر می گردد و امروزه در طراحی معماری روند استفاده چشمگیری داشته است. با وجود نگاه های مختلف به مفهوم توسعه پایدار و برداشت های متفاوت از آن، اصل تعادل میان سه بعد زیست محیطی، اجتماعی و اقتصادی مورد توافق همگان است. رویکرد پایداری اجتماعی به جهت در نظر داشتن نیازهای اساسی مردم، عدالت&amp;shy;خواه بودن و رفاه فیزیکی و اجتماعی، ارتقاء خلاقیت و توسعه توان انسانی، حفظ میراث فرهنگی و زیستی، تقویت احساس ارتباط با تاریخ و محیط زیست و مردم سالارانه بودن و نیز بهبود شرایط زندگی رفاه&amp;nbsp; اجتماعی، کالبدی و شور و هیجان ساکنان را به ارمغان می&amp;shy;آورد. باید در نظر داشت در بسیاری از موارد مهمترین عامل تأثیرگذار بر میزان رضایت فرد از سکونت در محله، مسکن و شرایط محیطی آن است لذا در مطالعه مسکن با در نظر گرفتن اصول پایداری اجتماعی امری شایان توجه بنظر می&amp;shy;رسد. اقشار کم&amp;shy;درآمد جامعه همواره به سبب عدم برخورداری از امکانات مناسب مسکونی و اجتماعی مورد غفلت قرار گرفته&amp;shy;اند. مطالعه مسکن بر مبنای الگوهای پایداری اجتماعی با توجه به فاکتورهای اساسی پایداری اجتماعی می&amp;shy;تواند در مطالعه مسکن اقشار کم&amp;shy;درآمد نقش داشته باشد. حال این پرسش مطرح می&amp;shy;گردد که نقش پایداری اجتماعی در مسکن اقشار کم&amp;shy;درآمد چیست و چگونه می&amp;shy;توان از این رویکرد در مطالعه مسکن استفاده نمود. برای پاسخگویی به این پرسش ابتدا موضوع مسکن و شناخت توسعه پایدار، اصول، راهکارها و نیز پایداری اجتماعی مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. در نهایت با بررسی نمونه&amp;shy;های خارجی و منابع مطالعاتی مشخص گردید رویکرد پایداری اجتماعی به جهت دربر داشتن فاکتورهایی مناسب نظیر عدالت اجتماعی، ارتقاء آموزش و رفاه فیزیکی برای مسکن قشر کم&amp;shy;درآمد به عنوان الگویی برای در نظر گرفتن مسکن قشر کم درآمد در نظر گرفته شود.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Social sustainability and the welfare of future generations, and today's trend has been dramatically used in architecture design. Despite the different perspectives of sustainable development and its different perceptions, the principle of balance between the three dimensions of environmental, social and economic consensus is agreeable to everyone. Social sustainability approach to address the basic needs of people, equity and physical and social wellbeing, promotion of creativity and development of human capacity, the preservation of cultural and biological heritage, the sense of association with history and the environment, and being democratic as well as improving the living conditions of social welfare, body and passion bring residents. It should be considered that in many cases, the most important factor affecting the level of satisfaction of a person from residence in the neighborhood, housing and its environmental conditions, therefore, in the study of housing, it is worth considering the principles of social sustainability. Low-income groups in the community have always been neglected due to lack of proper residential and social facilities. Housing studies based on social sustainability patterns, with regard to the basic factors of social sustainability, can play a role in the low-income housing population. The question now is what the role of social sustainability in low-income housing is and how this approach can be used in housing studies. To answer this question, the issue of housing and the recognition of sustainable development, principles, strategies and social sustainability have been investigated first. Finally, by examining external samples and literature sources, the social sustainability approach was considered as a model for considering low-income housing in order to include appropriate factors such as social justice, education promotion and physical well-being for low income families. &lt;a name=&quot;_GoBack&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>گروه‌های کم درآمد شهری, مسکن, پایداری اجتماعی, ایلام.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Low - income urban groups, housing, social sustainability, Ilam.</keyword>
	<start_page>67</start_page>
	<end_page>76</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-49&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد جواد </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ایران نژاد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008274</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008274</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
