<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>30</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بازنگری راهبردی حوزه خدمات شهری مدیریت محلی ایران با تاکید بر پسماند شهری؛ مطالعه موردی: کلانشهر مشهد </title_fa>
	<title>Assessment of Types of Residential High Rise Buildings through their Impacts on Urban Image and Escape</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>نگاه راهبردی در مدیریت یک انتخاب نیست که یک ضرورت است. لازمه این نگاه، داشتن دانش، ژرف اندیشی، همه جانبه نگری، واقع بینی و بلوغ مدیریتی است. مدیریت پروسه ای است که پروژه هایی با مختصّات علمی، واقع گرا و همه جانبه نگر مقوّم آن هستند. در مدیریت شهری، نگاه سیستمی اصلی اجتناب ناپذیر است. اداره مطلوب شهرها و مخصوصاً کلان شهرها بدون مدیریت یکپارچه شهری امکان پذیر نمی باشد و مدیریت یکپارچه شهری همان نگاه سیستمی است که مولود نگاه استراتژیک می باشد. نگاه سیستمی و مدیریت یکپارچه شهری تکلیفی است که واقعیت موجود کلان شهری مثل مشهد در ابعاد گوناگون برگردن متولیان امور و مشخصاً مدیریت محلی مشهد می گذارد یکی از مسائل اساسی در حوزۀ مدیریت شهری مشهد؛ حوزه خدمات شهری و محیط زیست شهری با گستردگی محدوده کلانشهری مشهد است. برای استفاده بهینه از منابع محدود موجود و دستیابی به اهداف مدیریت شهری، این مدیریت محلی طبیعتاً باید بتواند استراتژیهای خاص خود را انتخاب نماید. استراتژیهایی که از یک سو در راستای چشم انداز مدیریت محلی مشهد بوده و از سوی دیگر منبعث از ماموریتهای مدیریت محلی خواهد بود. این پژوهش از حیث نظری و روش‌شناسی بر ساختار‌گرایی و تحلیل تاریخی- تکوینی در سطح کلان و راهبردی استوار است که به روش مطالعات اسنادی-کتابخانه‌ای و تحلیل کیفی در چند محور و با هدف دستیابی به متدولوژی برنامه ریزی راهبردی در مدیریت پسماند شهری مشهد انجام شده است. بر اساس یافته های این پژوهش شناخت نیازها و اولویتهای شهروندان مشهدی (شهروند مداری) و ایجاد محیط زیست سالم و پایدار می‌بایست مبنا و ملاک تصمیم‌سازیها و تصمیم‌گیریها در سیاست-گذاری و برنامه ریزی برای کلان شهر مشهد باشد که بدون نگاه راهبردی و استراتژیک ممکن نمی باشد. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Today, the growth of high rise buildings in most of metropolitans is visible and also has left many impacts. The vast impacts of these buildings on the town’s physic and space have been criticized by many scholars and specialists. Herewith, impacts on the town’s physic and space is one of the main ones left, as their construction may lead to the rise or plunge of the quality of the town. In this regard, attention to the location, planning and design base on the rules and principles, coordination with neighboring and their fabric, creation of urban space in neighboring via combination of identity and active environment, and providing desirable image and escape, are among the remarkable issues in high rise buildings from the perspective of the quality of urban image and escape. This article, despite identifying different aspects of impacts of residential high rise buildings on urban image and escape, and introduction of criteria and sub criteria, studies the types of residential high rise buildings in the new fabric of City of Mashhad (using analysis method of AHP). The results of the study are clarifying the different impacts of samples of residential high rise buildings on urban escape and image of Mashhad and negligence of different dimensions of urban image and escape in location finding, planning, construction and maintenance of them. Although it is determined that type of partial and diversified high rise buildings (Half High Rise) in comparison to the coherent and intense high rise buildings (Half High Rise) are of better contexts to leave positive impacts on urban image and escape. At the end, and according to the findings of the study, holistic principles and rules of programming, planning and construction of high rise buildings so as to the uplift of urban escape and image are proposed. </abstract>
	<keyword_fa>برنامه ریزی راهبردی، مدیریت پسماند شهری، رویکرد راهبردی، مدیریت محلی، روش شناسی راهبردی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Types of High Rise Buildings, Urban Escape and Image, Assessment, AHP Method</keyword>
	<start_page>307</start_page>
	<end_page>319</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-242-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Rahim</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rahnama</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدرحیم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رهنما</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600557</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600557</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Khalil Allah</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Kazemi Khabiri</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>خلیل الله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کاظمی خبیری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Kazemi.manager1@Gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600558</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600558</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad International Unit</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد واحد بین الملل</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
