<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>34</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارائه مدل ارزیابی شهر اسلامی با رویکردی بر شاخص‌های بارز شهر اسلامی در قرآن کریم</title_fa>
	<title>Model of the Islamic city with the approach of the main indicators of the Quran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>هر چند واژه‌ی شهر و شهرنشینی، تاریخی به درازای عمر بشر دارد، اما هیچ شهری در گذر زمان توانِ ماندگاری را نداشته، مگر این‌که دارای هویت فرهنگی مشخص بوده باشد. دین اسلام با توجه به صبغه‌ی فرهنگی برجسته‌ای که دارد؛ از همان آغاز تأثیرگذاری خویش، هویت‌یابی اسلامی را بر پایه مؤلفه‌های اجتماعی بالاخص مؤلفه‌های شهری آغاز نمود. در این پژوهش ابتدا با روش کتابخانه‌ای - اسنادی، مبانی نظری پژوهش که شامل هشت شاخص مهم شهر اسلامی است، بدست آورده و با نگاهی همه‌جانبه بر داشتن هویت اسلامی، شاخص‌ها را با نگاه درون دینی مورد تحلیل قرار داده و در ادامه با روش میدانی و با استفاده از نظر سنجی از خبرگان میزان وزن هر شاخص بدست آمده و سپس با استفاده از روش ساده وزنی (SAW)  مدل  نظام‌‌مندی جهت ارزیابی شهرها بر اساس شاخص‌های اسلامی ارائه شده است. نتایجی که از پرسش نامه‌ها به دست آمد، حاکی از این بود که هیچ‌کدام از شاخص‌ها از نظر شهرسازان و کارشناسان علوم قرآنی بی‌اهمیت و یا کم‌اهمیت نبودند؛ ولی با این وجود بیشتر توجه شهرسازان معطوف به ظواهر شهری بوده و کارشناسان علوم قرآنی به روح معنوی حاکم بر شهر تأکید بیشتری دارند. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Although, cities and urbanization, has a history as long as human life, no city has ever been permanent in the history, unless it have had a specific cultural identity. Islam is the highlight of the cultural overlay, and from the beginning of its influence, it based the Islamic identity on social factors especially in urban components. In the first study using a library–documentation method, the theoretical framework of the study was obtained including the eight important indexes of Islamic cities. With considering the Islamic identity, the indexes were investigated from a religious point of view. In the next step, using the field method and a survey of scholars in the field, the weight of every index was determined. Using the simple weighting method of SAW a systematic method was developed to assess the cities based on the presented Islamic indexes. The results of the survey indicated that none of the indexes was insignificant in the view of the architects and the Quran Sciences scholars, rather architects paid more attention to the urban appearance, and the Quran Sciences scholars focused more on the spirituality prevailing in the city. </abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شاخص‌های شهر, هویت اسلامی, شهر نظام‌مند, ارزیابی, روش ساده وزنی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Urban Indexes, the Islamic identity, systematic city evaluation of simple weighting methods. </keyword>
	<start_page>153</start_page>
	<end_page>169</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-765-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Sohraab</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Morovvati</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سهراب</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مروتی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002094</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002094</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه ایلام</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Fereshteh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Darabi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>فرشته</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>دارابی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>fereshteh_darabi81@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002095</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002095</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه ایلام</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
