<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>15</volume>
<number>44</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>نمایش تبادلات معماری و شهرسازی ایران و غرب در سفرنامه های ایرانیان به فرنگ در دوره قاجار</title_fa>
	<title>The appearance of architectural and Urbanism Interaction between Iran and the Western Urban Planning through the Iranian Travel literatures during the Qajar Period</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;رویارویی با تمدن غرب و تاثیرش بر شهرسازی و معماری از مهم&amp;shy;ترین موضوعات برای طراحان در عرصه&amp;shy;های ملی&amp;nbsp; و بین المللی است. نخستین برخوردهای تاثیرگذار در فضاها و سیمای شهری و خیابان&amp;shy;کشی&amp;shy;ها در ایران به دوره قاجار باز می گردد. همزمانی تحولات در شهر قاجاری با تحولات صنعتی و تغیرات کالبدی شهرهای اروپایی و بازدید ایرانیان از آنجا موجب تغییر در آرمان ها و ذهنیت ایرانیان گردید. از میان مسیرهایی که محقق را در جریان این تبادل قرار می دهد سفرنامه های ایرانیان به فرنگ جایگاه ویژه ای دارند. این پژوهش به تحلیل سفرنامه ها از زاویه تحولات معماری و شهرسازی می پردازد. حدود سی گزارش سفر در بازۀ زمانی ابتدای قاجار تا جنبش مشروطه در محدودۀ مطالعاتی قرار گرفته است. سپس تاثیر این سفرنامه&amp;shy;ها بر فرم و هندسه معماری&amp;nbsp; و تحولات خیابان بندی تهران در دوره قاجار&amp;nbsp; مشاهده گردیده و اطلاعات بدست آمده در سفرنامه ها را در آنها مورد ارزیابی قرار می دهد. روش این پژوهش از نوع &lt;em&gt;روش محتوای تحقیق کیفی از متون تاریخی &lt;/em&gt;است. در نتایج پژوهشگر به تبیین نقش محوری سفرنامه ها و بالخصوص سفرهای سه گانه ناصرالدین شاه در تحولات شهری تهران قاجاری می پردازد.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Confrontation with the West culture and its impact on urbanism and architecture are the most important issues for designers in national and international areas. The first viewpoints in spaces and urban landscapes and street systems in Iran dates back to Qajar era. Simultaneity of developments in Qajar city with industrial transformation and structural changes of the European cities and Iranian visit from there resulted in changing in the attitudes of Iranians. Among the routes that inform the researcher from this exchange, Iranian travel literatures to Europe have a special place. This study discusses on analyzing travel literatures from diverse perspectives. About thirty trip reports in early Qajar period have been studied within the confines of the constitutional movement. Then, the impact of these travels literatures on urban developments and Tehran's streets and the formation of palaces during the Qajar period; the research method is based on qualitative research methods from the content of historical texts. In the results, the researcher deals with explaining the central role of the travel literatures and in particular triple trips of Nasereddin shah in Tehran urban developments and architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مدرنیسم, شهرسازی, عصر قاجاریه, تهران, سفرنامه ها.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Modernism, Urbanism, Architecture, QAJAR’s Architecture, Iranian Travel Lituraters</keyword>
	<start_page>517</start_page>
	<end_page>534</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-918-51&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ایمان</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>تازیکه لمسکی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004772</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004772</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>وحید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>قبادیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004773</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004773</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سلطان زاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004774</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004774</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>بهنام</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>قلیج خانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004775</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004775</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
