<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2013</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>31</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>شناسایی عوامل موثر در شکل گیری شهر یادگیرنده در منطقه 6 شهرداری تهران</title_fa>
	<title>Factors Affecting the Incidence of Learning City in the 6th District of Tehran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;مقاله حاضر با هدف بررسی مفهوم شهر یادگیرنده و شناسایی عوامل موثر در شکل گیری این مفهوم در منطقه 6 شهرداری تهران انجام گرفته است. به این منظور، ابتدا مفاهیم یادگیری سازمانی و سازمان یادگیرنده بررسی شده و سپس چارچوب نظری تحقیق بر مبنای ادبیات پیشین مشخص گشته است. این چارچوب شامل پنج متغیر اصلیمأموریت و استراتژی، آموزش خلاقیت و یادگیری، رهبری و توانمندسازی (مشارکت)، توسعه ارتباطات و همچنین نیروی کار دانشی است. همچنین بررسی ادبیات نشان می‌دهد که برای ایجاد و استمرار شهر یادگیرنده بایستی چند نهاد اصلی در شهر به عنوان نهادهای یادگیرنده فعالیت نمایند که عبارتند از: شهرداری، مدارس، مراکز آموزش علمی و کاربردی بزرگسالان، دانشگاه‌ها و سازمان‌های خصوصی متوسط و کوچک. در ادامه با استفاده از چارچوب نظری تحقیق پرسشنامه ای شامل 92 سئوال برای سنجش متغیرهای شهر یادگیرنده در هر کدام از نهادهای شهری در منطقه 6 شهرداری تهران طراحی و بین 100 پرسشگر توزیع گردید. در مقاله حاضر، داده های حاصل از پرسش نامه های توزیع شده با استفاده از آزمون کولموگروف- اسمیرنوف، t تک نمونه ای برای توزیع‌های نرمال و آزمون علامت برای توزیع‌های غیر نرمال و تحلیل واریانس (ANOVA) تجزیه و تحلیل گردید. یافته های تحقیق نشان دهنده جایگاه منطقه 6 شهرداری تهران بر مبنای ابعاد شهر یادگیرنده از نظر کارشناسان است. در انتهای مقاله، به بحث در مورد اهمیت مفهوم یادگیرندگی در شهر پرداخته شده و راهکارهایی جهت توسعه مفهوم شهر یادگیرنده ارائه می‌شود. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Present study aims to investigate the concept of learning city and to identify affecting factors on building this concept in Tehran Municipality, borough 6. To this end, organizational learning and learning organization concepts are initially investigated and then a conceptual framework is devised based on previous literature. It includes five major variables including mission and strategy, creativity training and learning, leadership and empowerment (contribution), communication development and knowledge workers. Literature studying indicates that some main entities should act as learning organs to establish and keep on learning city including municipality, schools, adults’ applied and scientific training centers, universities and SMEs. Then, a 92 – item questionnaire was devised to measure learning city variables in each urban organ in Tehran Municipality, borough 6 and it was distributed among 100 interviewers. In present paper, gathered data was analyzed by Kolmogrov – Smirnov test, single-sample t test for normal distributions and ANOVA. Research findings show scholars’ opinions on the status of Tehran Municipality, borough 6, in terms of the aspects of a learning city. Finally, the importance of learning in city concept is discussed and guidelines are provided to develop learning city concept.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>یادگیری مادام‌العمر، یادگیری سازمانی، سازمان یادگیرنده، اجتماع یادگیرنده، شهر یادگیرنده.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Lifelong Learning, Organizational Learning, Learning Organization, Learning Community and Learning City.</keyword>
	<start_page>139</start_page>
	<end_page>156</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-64-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Soodeh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Bayat</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سوده</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بیات</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>soudeh.bayat@gmail.com</email>
	<code>100319475328460063</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460063</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University School of Management</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Arian</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Qoli poor</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>آرین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>قلی پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460064</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460064</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University School of Management</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali Asghar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Poor Ezzat</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی اصغر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>پور عزت</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460065</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460065</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tehran University School of Management</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
