<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>36</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیل ابعاد مختلف حقوق شهروندی از دیدگاه شهروندان بررسی میدانی: محدوده پیرامونی خیابان کارگر شمالی و مرکز قلب تهران</title_fa>
	<title>Analysis of Various Aspects of Civil (Citizenship) Rights from the Viewpoint of Citizens (Field Study: The Surrounding of Kargar Shomali Avenue and Tehran Heart Center)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
اساساًحقوقشهروندیبرسهاصلحقوقمدنی،حقوقسیاسیوحقوقاجتماعیبنیاننهادهشدهوازارکاناصلیحقوقبشرمحسوبمی-شود. موارد بسیاری در عدم رعایت حقوق شهروندی دخیل هستند اما به نظر می‌رسد یکی از اصلی‌ترین موارد، نارضایتی شهروندان از فضای جاری حاکم بر زندگی شخصی و تعمیم آن به فضای عمومی و شهری است. هدف از انجام این تحقیق، استخراج تعاریف &quot;حقوق شهروندی&quot; از دیدگاه خود شهروندان است.برای  رسیدن به این هدف، در بخش اول از روش ضریب همبستگی پیرسون به منظور تبیین میزان همبستگی میان متغیر &quot;عدم رعایت قوانین&quot; با سایر متغیرهای تعریف شده و در بخش دوم از روش تحلیل محتوای کیفی، به منظور استخراج نکات اصلی پیرامون ابعاد حقوق مختلف شهروندیاستفاده شده است.مطالعات تحقیق نشان می‌دهد مهمترین عامل موثر در رفتار ناهنجار شهروندان و پیروی نکردن از قانون، نارضایتی از شرایط روحی – روانی حاکم بر فضای ذهنی شهروند است. شرایطی که مربوط به فضای خصوصی فرد است و می‌تواند به فضای عمومی منتقل شود و موجب بروز رفتار نامناسبی از شهروند شود و حق دیگر شهروندان را تضییع کند. از سوی دیگر، در بخش دوم تحقیق یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد تعریف حق شهروندی در میان طیف‌های گوناگون، متفاوت است و در میان هر طیف، منعطف به نیازها و دغدغه های فکری شهروندان است. به نظر می‌رسد ورود فکری ترسیم کنندگان حقوق شهروندی به میان افکار عمومی جامعه و اصلاح یا وضع قوانین جدید مرتبط با حقوق شهروندی، می‌تواند کمک قابل توجهی به جریان آموزش همگانی و درونی سازی قوانین و حقوق شهروندی کند.
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
Citizenship rights are substantially established on the basis of three principles of civil rights, political rights, and social rights and are considered as the main elements of the human rights. Several factors are involved in non-observance of citizenship rights though the main factor is dissatisfaction of citizens with the current atmosphere dominating on the personal life and generalizing the same to the public and urban space. The present research aims at extraction of definitions of “citizenship rights” from the viewpoint of the citizens. To achieve this goal, Pearson correlation coefficient method is used in the first section to clarify the correlation between the variable of “non-observance of regulations” and other defined variables and quality content analysis method is used in the second section to extract the main points in relate to the various aspects of citizenship rights. The research studies indicate that the most effective factor on abnormal behavior of the citizens and non-observance of rules and regulations is dissatisfaction with the mental-psychological conditions dominating on the mental space of citizens the conditions arising from the private space of an individual that will be transferred to the public space and may lead to improper behavior by the citizens and infringe rights of other citizens. On the other hand, the findings in the second section of the research reveal that citizenship right is differently defined among various classes of society and concentrates on the mental needs and concerns of citizens in every class. It seems that inspiring the thoughts of those who define citizenship rights to the public minds and modifying or enactment of new laws on citizenship rights may considerably help the public education and internalization of the citizenship rights and laws. 
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>قانون اساسی, حقوق شهروندی, رضایت از کیفیت زندگی, همبستگی, تحلیل محتوا.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>constitutional law, citizenship rights, satisfaction with life quality, correlation, content analysis. </keyword>
	<start_page>323</start_page>
	<end_page>338</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-434-3&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mojtaba</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Arasteh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مجتبی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>آراسته</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>m.arasteh@modares.ac.ir</email>
	<code>10031947532846001472</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001472</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tarbiat Modarres University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali Akbar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Taqvaee</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی اکبر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>تقوایی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001473</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001473</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tarbiat Modarres University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Maryam</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Kamyar</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مریم</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کامیار</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001474</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001474</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tarbiat Modarres University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
