<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>15</volume>
<number>44</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>مبانی مسئولیت مدنی شهرداریها در رابطه با کارکنان و مستخدمان </title_fa>
	<title>Foundations of municipal civil liability in respect of the staff and employees</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot; style=&quot;margin: 1em 0px; text-align: justify; line-height: normal; unicode-bidi: embed; direction: rtl;&quot;&gt;&lt;span b=&quot;&quot; lang=&quot;FA&quot; style=&quot;font-family:;&quot;&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;شهرداریها از جمله مهمترین نهادهای جامعه مدنی هستند که در قانون اساسی در چهارچوب حاکمیت قرار دارند و در عرصه&amp;shy;های اجتماعی، محلی و شهری جزء ساختارهای مهم مشارکتی و توسعه محسوب می&amp;shy;شوند. شهرداریها از جمله مهمترین ضرورت&amp;shy;های نظام اجتماعی محسوب می&amp;shy;شوند که الزاماً با ساختاری که تنها از طریق مداخله مردم امکان&amp;shy;پذیر است نمایان می گردد و به دلیل وجود این روابط گسترده و نزدیک با جامعه و اشخاص، بستر مناسبی برای ورود خسارات و عدم رعایت توازن قدرتی از یکسو و اخلال در عملکرد شهرداریها از سوی دیگر فراهم می گردد. که باید با تعیین مبنایی حقوقی و متناسب با شرایط و اوضاع و احوال خااص این سازمان، حتی المقدور از ورود خسارات جلوگیری نمود یا تدابیری اندیشید تا در صورت ورود خسارت به بهترین نحو جبران شوند. لذا در این پژوهش با توسل به روش تحلیلی - توصیفی و نظریه پردازی سعی دارد که موضوع مبانی مسئولیت مدنی در موضوع خسارات وارده از سوی شهرداریها و همچنین موضوع مسئول جبران خسارات در روابط میان شهرداریها و کارکنان و مستخدمان را بیان کند.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Municipalities are among the most important institutions of civil society within the framework of the rule of the constitution and in the areas of social, local and municipal participation and development are important components of structures. Municipalities are among the most important needs of society. Not necessarily with a structure that is possible only through the intervention of people is shown. There is an extensive and close tie with the community and suitable persons for damages and failure to observe the balance of power on the one hand and disruption in the functioning of municipalities is provided. Must determine the legal basis and in accordance with the terms and conditions the organization as much as possible be prevented from entering damage. Or measures thought to be compensated for damages to the fullest;&amp;nbsp; this study, analytical - descriptive attempts, The subject matter of the fundamental principles of civil liability in damages from the municipalities and the issue of relations between municipalities and employees' compensation.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مسوولیت مدنی, دولت, شهرداریها, مبنا, تقصیر, خسارت, کارکنان.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>civil liability, government, municipalities, foundations, guilt, loss of employees.</keyword>
	<start_page>459</start_page>
	<end_page>470</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-918-47&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زارع</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460010229</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460010229</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حسین پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460010230</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460010230</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
