<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2013</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>31</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>مشارکت‌پذیری شهروندان تهرانی در حوزه وظایف شهرداری (مطالعه موردی: شهروندان منطقه 4 شهرداری تهران) </title_fa>
	<title>Tendency to participation of Tehran citizens in the activities domain of municipality (case study: citizens of region 4)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;امروزه بیشتر صاحبنظران حوزه مدیریت شهری، تجربه مدیریت متمرکز شهر را شکست خورده دانسته و آن را بدون مشارکت شهروندان ناموفق ارزیابی می کنند. از این رو جلب مشارکت شهروندان یکی از دغدغه‌های اصلی مدیریت‌های نوین شهری محسوب می‌شود. شهرداری تهران یکی از نهادهای مهم مدیریت این کلان شهر با اتخاذ رویکردی اجتماعی، گام‌های اساسی در راستای جلب مشارکت شهروندان برداشته است. نظر به اهمیت مشارکت شهروندان در اداره امور شهری و با توجه به راهبردهای شهرداری تهران در این راستا، مقاله حاضر وضعیت مشارکت‌پذیری شهروندان محلات تهران را با مطالعه موردی شهرداری منطقه چهار بررسی نموده است. چارچوب نظری انتخاب شده به منظور شناخت عوامل تأثیرگذار، چارچوبی ترکیبی مبتنی بر عوامل فردی و اجتماعی است. به منظور بررسی تجربی فرضیات تحقیق از روش پیمایش استفاده شده که در تحلیل داده‌ها از تکنیک‌های آماری میانگین، ضریب همبستگی پیرسون، آزمون T و F و تحلیل رگرسیون چندمتغیره استفاده شده است. نتایج تحقیق بیانگر متوسط بودن سطح مشارکت‌پذیری شهروندان بوده که تغییرات آن با استفاده از عواملی نظیر جنسیت، وضعیت شغلی، آگاهی و اطلاعات درباره امور شهری، انتظار پاداش از مشارکت، عضویت انجمنی، سابقه سکونت در محله و علاقه و تمایل به آن تبیین می شود. شهرداری با انجام اقدامات گوناگون با تکیه بر نتایج این مطالعه می‌تواند تمایلات مشارکتی شهروندان را ارتقاء داده و از ظرفیت‌های آن برای مدیریت بهینه شهر بهره گیرد .&lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>today, most expert believe that the focused urban management experience is failed and it is impossible without citizen participation. So the attraction of citizens’ participation is the main concerns of the urban new managements. Tehran Municipality the one of the major institutions of urban management has adopted the social approach in order to attract the participation of citizens and has taken the basic steps. The present article is aimed to explore the status of Tehran citizens’ tendency to participate in doing activities of municipality (case study region 4). Chosen theoretical framework for understanding the effective factors, a framework based on a combination of individual and social factors.  The survey method was used to examine the hypothesis. The statistical data analysis techniques such as Pearson correlation, t and F tests and multiple regression analysis was used to analyze data. The research results indicate a moderate level of citizens participation tendency that its changes will be explained with factors such as gender, employment status, knowledge and information on urban affairs, expected rewards of participation, association membership, experience and interest in and desire to live in neighborhoods. Municipality with different measures based on results of this study can enhance citizens’ participation willingness, operating these capacities and attract them in doing its activities.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مشارکت، مشارکت‌پذیری، شهرداری، شهروندان منطقه چهار.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>participation, tendency to participation, citizens of region four, municipality</keyword>
	<start_page>157</start_page>
	<end_page>174</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-65-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Jamal</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Abdollah Poor</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>جمال</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عبدالله پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>jamalabdollahpour@gmail.com</email>
	<code>100319475328460066</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460066</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Sociology Faculty of Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده جامعه شناسی دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hasan</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mokhter Poor</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مختار پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460067</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460067</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>School of Environmental Science and Research Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده محیط زیست دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Rajabali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mokhtar Poor</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رجبعلی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مختار پور</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460068</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460068</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Geography Faculty of Tehran University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده جغرافیا دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
