<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>12</volume>
<number>33</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارزشیابی سطح قابلیت زندگی شهری با تأکید بر رویکرد CDS؛ مورد مطالعه: شهر اصفهان</title_fa>
	<title>Evaluation of Urban Livability Level Emphasizing CDS Approach (the Case of Isfahan City)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
افزایش سطح رفاه و خوشبختی، یکی از اهداف دیرینه‏ بشر بوده است. شهرها به‏عنوان سکونت‏گاه‏های انسانی برای رسیدن به این هدف، از ابتدای پیدایش خود انواع مختلفی از الگوهای برنامه‏ریزی شهری را تجربه کرده‏اند. راهبرد توسعه‏ی شهری، یکی از آخرین الگوهای برنامه‏ریزی مطرح شده برای شهرها است. این راهبرد به‏دنبال ایجاد شهرهایی پایدار با چهار رکن قابلیت زندگی، بانک پذیری، رقابت پذیری و حکمرانی خوب است. این مقاله دو هدف عمده را دنبال می‎کند: 1) ارزشیابی سطح قابلیت زندگی شهر اصفهان با کسب نظرات شهروندان، 2) شناسایی قوی‌ترین و ضعیف‌ترین بعد قابلیت زندگی در شهر اصفهان و 3) مقایسه‎ی مناطق چهارده‎گانه‎ی شهر اصفهان از نظر سطح قابلیت زندگی. گردآوری داده‎ها به روش میدانی و با استفاده از ابزار پرسش‎نامه بوده است. نمونه‏ی منتخب، شامل 471 نفر از شهروندان ساکن در مناطق چهارده‎گانه‏ی شهر اصفهان بوده است، که به روش تصادفی طبقه‏بندی شده، انتخاب شد. نتایج پژوهش حاکی از پایین‏تر بودن سطح قابلیت زندگی شهر اصفهان نسبت به متوسط طیف لیکرت و وجود تفاوت معنی‎دار بین مناطق مختلف شهر از نظر این شاخص بود. 
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
Cities have changed a lot over the time. Today, the rapid growth of urban population has made these changes faster and faced cities with opportunities such as increase in economic growth rate, increase in efficiency, and increase in opportunities of scale and with challenges such as increase in urban poverty, deepening of inequality, and lack of infrastructures. Use of these opportunities and encountering the difficulties need to apply proper and effective urban planning methods. City development strategy (CDS( is one of the urban planning methods introduced by Cities Alliance for this purpose. City development strategy is one of the latest urban planning methods. This strategy has four main foundations and livability, as one of its foundations, focuses on increasing citizens' quality of life and access to equal opportunities. In this study the livability level of Isfahan was evaluated using field method and through asking Isfahan citizens' ideas. In order to improve the livability level of Isfahan and decrease the existing difference between its zones in terms of livability, the following suggestions are provided: As “citizen participation in the city affairs” has been the poorest dimension of livability in Isfahan, it is suggested that the municipality of Isfahan should increase its degree of interaction with citizens and through asking their ideas and criticisms should try to improve the livability of the city.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شهرنشینی, برنامه‏ریزی شهری, راهبرد توسعه‎ی شهری, قابلیت زندگی, شهر اصفهان.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>urban planning, city development strategy, Urban Livability, Isfahan City</keyword>
	<start_page>63</start_page>
	<end_page>78</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-800-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Nematollah</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Akbari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>نعمت الله</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>اکبری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002221</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002221</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه اصفهان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Shokoofeh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Farahmand</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>شکوفه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فرهمند</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002222</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002222</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه اصفهان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Monireh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ravan Bakhsh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>منیره</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>روان بخش</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>monire.ral@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002223</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002223</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه اصفهان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
