<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>38</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بنیان‌های نظری حکمروایی خوب در فرایند مدیریت روستایی نوین</title_fa>
	<title>Theoretical basis of good governance in the modern rural management</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
حکمروایی روستایی فرایند نوینی است که با دارا بودن اصول، معیارها و شاخص‌هایی متفاوت از رویکردهای مطرح شده در نظام مدیریت روستایی ماقبل خود باعث توانمندسازی ساکنین نواحی روستایی در زمینه‌های مختلف می شود. مهمترین اصول، معیارها و شاخص‌های حکمروایی خوب روستایی شامل (مشارکت مردمی ساکنین روستایی، پاسخگویی، مسئولیت پذیری، قانون محوری و احترام به قوانین موجود، شفافیت، کارائی و اثربخشی، عدالت و برابری، اجتماع‌گرائی (توافق جمعی) می باشند. این پژوهش از نوع پژوهش‌های کیفی و بنیادی (نظری) و بر مبنای روش اسنادی (کتابخانه‌ای) انجام گرفته است. نتایج حاصل از بررسی های نظری رویکرد حکمروایی خوب روستایی در روند مدیریت توسعه روستایی نشان دهنده این است که این رویکرد با اصول، معیارها و شاخص های ذکر شده می تواند رویکردی مطلوب در ساختار نوین مدیریت روستایی و همچنین نقشی وادارنده در روند توسعه پایدار سیاسی، اقتصادی، اجتماعی، کالبدی، فضایی و مدیریت توسعه روستایی کشور داشته باشد. 
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
Rural governance is Modern process that has principles, criteria and indicators different from the Approaches of their previous rural management Caused In the empowerment of rural areas residents in different field.  The most important Principles, criteria and indicators of good governance, rural Consist of are) Rural residents' popular participation, Accountability, accountability, and respect for the rule of existing laws, transparency, efficiency and effectiveness, fairness and equality, communitarians (collective agreement). This study is a qualitative and fundamental research (Theoretical) and have been conducted based on the documents (Library). The results of reviews Theoretical approach to rural good governance in the rural development of management indicates that This approach with the principles, criteria and indicators are listed could be a good approach in the rural management of modern and essential role in the sustainable development of political, economic, social, physical, spatial and rural development managed.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>حکمروایی, حکمروایی روستایی, مدیریت روستایی, توسعه پایدار روستایی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>governance, good governance, rural management, rural sustainable development</keyword>
	<start_page>43</start_page>
	<end_page>54</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-682-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Abdolreza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rahmani Fazli</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>عبدالرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رحمانی فضلی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001815</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001815</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mozafar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Sadeqi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مظفر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صادقی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001816</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001816</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Jahan Bakhsh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Alipoorian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>جهانبخش</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>علیپوریان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>j.rika62@gmail.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001817</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001817</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
