<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>12</volume>
<number>33</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تدوین معیارهای آسیب پذیری شهرهای کوچک در برابر سوانح طبیعی، مطالعه موردی: شهر گیلانغرب</title_fa>
	<title>Providing vulnerability criteria for small cities against natural disasters, Case study: Gilan-e-Gharb city in west of Iran</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
وقتی یک سانحه طبیعی رخ می‌دهد، شهر به صورت یک‌ مجموعه پیوسته از آن تأثیر می‌پذیرد، به عبارت دیگر عناصر شهری نه تنها خود از آن رخداد تأثیر می‌پذیرند، بلکه در عمل متقابل سیستمی، سایر عناصر شهر را نیز متأثر می‌سازند. هرچه میزان و نحوه تأثیرگذاری یک عنصر شهری و گستره تاثیر آن بیشتر باشد، بر تعداد و انواع بیشتری‌ از سایر عناصر تأثیر خواهد گذاشت، این‌ موضوع در ارزیابی میزان و نحوه آسیب و خسارات که به‌ هر عنصر شهری و در کل به خود شهر وارد می‌آید بسیار اهمیت دارد. در ایران برای شهرهای کوچک (شهرهای با جمعیت تا 20000 نفر) که تعداد قریب به 800 تا900 شهر از 1200 شهر کشور را تشکیل می دهند، هیچ برنامه و قواعدی در خصوص مدیریت بحران برایشان تعریف نشده است. و این موضوع بعنوان یک خلاء در برنامه های مدیریت این گونه شهرها همچنان باقی مانده است و اصول و معیارهای نظام‌مندی در این راستا وجود ندارد. در این پژوهش ابتدا براساس مطالعات اسنادی وکتابخانه ای مروری بر تحقیقات انجام شده در زمینه معیارهای آسیب پذیری شهرهای کوچک در برابر سوانح طبیعی صورت گرفته است و بعد از تعیین معیارهای مرتبط با تهیه پرسشنامه در خصوص تایید و اولویت بندی معیارهای تهیه شده برای شهر گیلانغرب از متخصصین نظرسنجی صورت گرفته است. سپس با روش AHP و استفاده از نرم افزار EXPERTCHOICE نظرات متخصصین اعمال و با تحلیل‌های آماری، ضریب اهمیت معیارها و ضریب وزنی مناطق آسیب پذیر شهر گیلانغرب تعیین و درنهایت نقشه آسیب پذیری شهر تهیه شده است  که می تواند مورد استفاده برنامه ریزی های صحیح شهری قرارگیرد.
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>When a natural disaster occurs, cities are affected series of connected systems. In other words not only the city elements are being affected by disasters but also they influence the other city elements in a systematic interaction. The more the influence and impaction city element, the more the numbers and types of the other elements affected from that. The matter has an extreme importance on the assessment of damage of elements and to city itself, totally. In Iran there are about 873 small cities with the population less than 20000. There is no rule or plan defined for crisis management of small cities and it remains as gap in disaster management programs in such cities and there are no special criteria. Considering the relatively high number of small cities and noting that disaster management programs are established for large cities, this research is conducted on the basis of available documentation, literature review studies and expert opinion in vulnerability assessment and related criteria for small cities against natural disasters. After recognizing the proper criteria, a survey is formed by experts about confirmation and categorizing the criteria for Gilan-e-Gharb city in west of Iran. The research process done based on AHP using EXPERT CHOICE software, expert’s judgment. After statistical data analysis the importance coefficient and weights of criteria of vulnerability for5 city districts are derived and compared so the districts of the city are ranked based on their vulnerability to natural disaster. City fabric, Density, structural robustness, hazards exposure, availability of disaster management measures are some important factors in this regard. The results can be used in a proper risk reduction plan of the city against natural hazards.</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شهرهای کوچک, آسیب پذیری, معیارها, سوانح طبیعی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>small city, vulnerability, criteria, natural disasters, risk reduction measures.</keyword>
	<start_page>19</start_page>
	<end_page>32</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-798-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Behrooz</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Bavand Poori Gilan</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>بهروز</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>باوند پوری گیلان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>b_bavandpor@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846002213</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002213</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Babak</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Omidvaar</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>بابک</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>امیدوار</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002214</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002214</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده محیط زیست دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Esmail</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Salehi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>اسماعیل</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صالحی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846002215</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846002215</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده محیط زیست دانشگاه تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
