<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>28</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی مفهومی باغسازی‌ ایرانی در رویکرد پدیدارشناسی در معماری منظر، تبارشناسی و شاخص‌شناسی</title_fa>
	<title>Conceptual Study of Iranian Garden Design from the Standpoint of Phenomenology in Landscape Architecture, Genealogy and Index logy</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;باغسازی ایرانی به عنوان یکی از اصلی‌ترین پدیده‌ها در ساختار شکل‌دهنده به معماری و ساخت محوطه‌ها و فضاهای باز در تاریخ ایران و تمام سرزمین‌های تحت نفوذ آن حضور داشته است. به واسطه این حضور، ایرانیان در تمام شئون زندگی فردی و جمعی خود، ارتباط نزدیکی با این سنت و پدیده کهن داشته‌اند ازاین‌رو می‌توان باغسازی ایرانی را به عنوان یکی از اصلی‌ترین پدیده‌ها در ساختار شکل‌دهنده به منظر و به‌طور عام طراحی محیط مصنوع در گذشته تاریخی ایران نام برد. در این پژوهش قصد ارزش‌گذاری و برتری بخشیدن به باغسازی ایرانی در معماری منظر را نداریم، بلکه هدف اصلی در پژوهش حاضر بیان احراز هویت در معماری منظر از طریق بررسی مؤلفه‌های فضا در باغسازی ایرانی است. اینکه خوانایی فضا در ساختار کالبدی باغ ایرانی برای مخاطب امروزی چگونه احراز می‌گردد و اینکه آیا ساختار کالبدی این پدیده در خاطره جمعی ایرانیان، هنوز حضوری قابل توجه دارد یا نه، مورد توجه پژوهش حاضر نبوه و هرگونه پرسش در علل پیدایش این تفکرات نیازمند واکاوی در پژوهش‌های دیگر است. روش تحقیق در این پژوهش از نوع توصیفی ـ تحلیلی و جمع‌آوری اطلاعات به شیوه کتابخانه‌ای و میدانی بوده است. نتایج حاصل در این پژوهش بیانگر آن است که باغسازی ایرانی، نظامی از شکل‌گیری مکان در همه ابعاد پدیدارشناسانه این مفهوم بوده است و می‌توان از آن به عنوان یک نظام شایسته در معماری منظر معاصر به عنوان یکی از انتخاب‌های پیشرو در امر طراحی و ساماندهی محیط مصنوع در ارتباط با طبیعت، بدان پرداخت. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Persian garden design is one of the main elements in the architecture and landscaping in Iran and the whole lands influenced by the Iranian culture. This phenomenon has always been present in Iranians' life and they have had a close connection to this ancient tradition. Hence, it can be said that Persian garden design is one of the most crucial features in shaping Landscape, in particular, and creating built environment, in general, throughout the Iranian history. In this research, we don’t intend to valuate the Persian garden design or favor it in Landscape architecture. Our purpose in this study is to seek our identity in Landscape architecture through examining space elements in the Persian garden design. How this space in the physical structure of Persian garden is grasped by viewers or whether the physical structure of this phenomenon still persists in the collective memory of Iranians is not the point to be scrutinized by this research. Any answer to these questions requires probing into other fields. The research methodology in this study was descriptive and analytical and we have collected data in field and bibliographic investigations. This study shows that the Persian garden design is a systematic space shaping with respect to all phenomenological aspects of this concept, and it can be described as a worthy system in Landscape architecture and a pioneering approach in designing and organizing built environment in connection with nature. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa></keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Persian Garden Design, Phenomenology, Landscape Architecture, Space, Identity</keyword>
	<start_page>61</start_page>
	<end_page>80</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-53-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Bemanian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بمانیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>bemanian@modares.ac.ir</email>
	<code>1003194753284600210</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600210</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Arts University Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده هنر دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Elham</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Saleh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>الهام</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صالح</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>elham_saleh1388@yahoo.com </email>
	<code>1003194753284600211</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600211</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Arts University Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده هنر دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
