<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>29</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تلفیق مدل AHP و تحلیل شبکه در محیطGIS جهت مکان گزینی کاربری درمانی (بیمارستان)؛ مطالعه موردی شهر سمنان</title_fa>
	<title>Integrating AHP model and analyze network in GIS Environment for locating of remedial control (hospital) (case study of semnan)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>امروزه جمعیت پذیری شهرها به همراه مسائل اجتماعی- اقتصادی آنها شکل تازه ای از شهر، شهرنشینی و شهرگرایی بوجود آورده است. از آنجایی که بهداشت و درمان از ضرورتهای اولیه زندگی میباشد؛ لذا خدمات رسانی مناسب و پویا به شهرنشینان نیازمند، استقرار مراکز خدمات درمانی در مکان مناسب در سطح شهر می باشد که نقش مهمی در تامین آسایش شهروندان ایفا می کنند. از این رو موضوع مکان یابی، خدمات رسانی، و خدمات‌دهی بهتر این مراکز درسطح شهرمهم است. لذا تحقیق حاضر، بررسی فضاهای بهداشتی- درمانی و دسترسی سریع به آنها، مکانیابی صحیح این فضاها را بعنوان یک پیش فرض می طلبد که ما در این پژوهش جهت مکان یابی مراکز درمانی شهر سمنان، با بررسی کاربری های عمده شهری و بااستفاده از تلفیق سامانه اطلاعات جفرافیاییGIS 1و روش وزندهی تحلیل سلسله مراتبی AHP 2 روش تحلیل شبکه برای تعیین شعاع عملکردی مکان بهینه مراکز درمانی مشخص نموده  و سپس با توجه به تلفیق داده ها علاوه بر 4  بیمارستان موجود در شهر سمنان، 3 بیمارستان جدید پیشنهاد می شود. در واقع این پژوهش، بعنوان تحقیقی بنیادی و کاربردی می تواند مورد استفاده مدیران شهری، برنامه ریزان شهری و دست اندرکاران خدمات در شهر گردد. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Today population reception with their economic and social problems made shape of city, urbanity, and urbanism. Although, remedy and hygiene are primary necessities, so suitable and dynamic servicing to urbanites require establishing remedial services centers in suitable places in city that play the important role in providing comfort of citizens, So better locating and servicing problem of these centers in city is important. So, current study require to consideration of remedial environments and their post access to them. correct locating, that we characterized direction of locating of semnan remedial centers with considering city important control and using integration of geographical information system GIS and the method of scaling of hierarchy analyze AHP for determining action radius of better location of remedial centers in this study and them whit regarding to integrating data rather than 4 hospital in semnan city, the new hospitals have been offered.
Really this study as practical and fundamental study can use by city manager, programmers.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مکان یابی، مراکز درمانی، بیمارستان، تحلیل شبکه، سیستم اطلاعات جغرافیایی، تحلیل سلسله مراتبی، سمنان. </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>locating, remedial center, hospital, network analyze, GIS, AHP, semnan</keyword>
	<start_page>247</start_page>
	<end_page>258</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-146-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Yusefali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ziari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>یوسفعلی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زیاری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Yousef-ziari@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600318</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600318</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Islamic Azad University of Semnan</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد سمنان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Fereshteh</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Khatib Zadeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>فرشته</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خطیب زاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600319</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600319</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Islamic Azad University of Semnan</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد سمنان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
