<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>51</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیل عوامل مؤثر بر بقای عضویت اعضای شورای اجتماعی محلات شهر مشهد به روش تحلیل تاریخچه رویداد</title_fa>
	<title>Analysis of factors affecting the survival of the membership of the Social Council of the city of Mashhad, event history analysis</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;هدف پژوهش حاضر تحلیل عوامل مؤثر بر بقای عضویت اعضای شورای اجتماعی محلات شهر مشهد می&amp;zwnj;باشد. در این پژوهش با استفاده از سامانه جامع اعضای شورای اجتماعی محلات اطلاعات مربوط گردآوری شده است. از سوی دیگر با استفاده از روش تحلیل بقاء به بررسی سه مسئله میزان بقاء، عوامل مؤثر بر بقاء و نمودار بقاء اعضای شورا پرداخته شده است. در بین عوامل بقاء سه حیطه عوامل فردی، شواری و منطقه در نظر گرفته شده است. یافته&amp;shy;ها نشان می&amp;zwnj;دهد که 70 درصد احتمال بقاء در شورای اجتماعی محلات می&amp;zwnj;باشد. از سوی دیگر، شاخص&amp;shy;های مرتبط با عملکرد شورا بیشترین تأثیر را بر بقای اعضا دارد. احتمال ترک عضویت زنان و افراد جوان بیشتر از سایرین است. از سوی دیگر متغیرهای تعداد جلسات، مصوبات و محله افزاینده بقای اعضا و متغیرهای کاهنده تعداد غیبت، تعداد اعضای شورا، رتبه اعتبار مالی، رتبه منزلت اجتماعی، تعداد شورای منطقه، جمعیت محله و مشکلات محله میزان بقای اعضای شورا هستند. در پایان مقاله نیز به ارائه پیشنهادهایی با توجه به یافته های پژوهش همچون تناسب مصوبات و جلسات با توان اعضا، حمایت سازمانی و مدیریت ستادی شوراها همت گمارده شده است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;This study aimed to analyze the factors affecting the survival of the membership of the Social Council of the city of Mashhad. In this study, using a comprehensive system, information is collected about the neighborhood community council members. On the other hand, using survival analysis to has been examine three issues, the survival, factors affecting the survival and the survival graph of Council members. Among the survival factors three areas is considered, individual factors, the council and the region. The findings show that 70 percent chance of survival in the Social Council communities. Indicators related to the performance of the council have the greatest impact on member&amp;rsquo;s survival. Leaving Probability of women and young people are more than others. The variables meetings Number, decisions and community members increase survival and variables that reduce its the number of missing, number of council members, credit rating, ranking social status, number of Council in Regional, local population and local problems are survival of its members. The end of article, regarding the research findings provide recommendations as appropriate approvals and meetings with potential members, organizational support and headquarters management by the council.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شورای اجتماعی محلات, تحلیل تاریخچه رویداد, شهر مشهد, تحلیل بقاء</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Social Council of Neighborhoods, event history analysis, Mashhad, survival analysis</keyword>
	<start_page>225</start_page>
	<end_page>242</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1816-74&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محسن </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نوغانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008760</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008760</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حمید </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مسعودی </last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008761</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008761</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
