<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>39</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تبیین مفهوم مسکن و سکونت در رویکرد پدیدارشناسی و رهیافت پارادایم‌های فرهنگی زیستی</title_fa>
	<title>Phenomenological approach and the concept of living in the cultural paradigm of life</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
شکی نیست که معماری در تعاملی دوسویه «هم بر فرهنگ و هم از فرهنگ تاثیر گذاشته و تاثیر پذیرفته» است، چنانچه مقوله جامعه-شناسی مسکن سعی در شناسایی این حلقه‌های مفهومی و معناییِ تعاملاتِ فرهنگ (جامعه) و معماری مسکن دارد؛ لذا رسیدن به یک فرایند اندیشه ارتباطی خاص بینابینی، به‌عنوان ابزار و داده‌های فرآیند پایدارسازی بستر اجتماعیِ معماری با تکیه بر الگوی فکری خاص و نتایج اجتماعی مشخص به صورت واکنش‌های استاندارد ولی نسبی جامعه و نسبت به معماری با بازخورد ادراکی از معماری، از جمله مفاهیمی است که لازم است تا در رابطه فرهنگ و معماری خانه مورد بحث باشد. پرسش پیشینی مفهوم سکونت این است که آیا صرف جایگیری در یک فضا را می‌توان سکونت یافتن در آن نامید؟ روش تحقیق مقاله، «توصیفی و تحلیلی» و «روش استدلال منطقی» است که از «روش اسنادی» و مطالعات کتابخانه‌ای بهره برده است. در راستای نتایج تحقیق به مفهوم پدیدارشناختی سکونت و مفهوم سکونت زیستی در رویکرد پدیدارشناختی اشاره شده و در پایان پارادایم‌های فرهنگی خانه بر اساس نظریه‌های فرهنگی در پیدایش مجتمع های زیستی مورد اشاره قرار گرفته است که عبارتند از: «مطالعه معنای چندمجرایی فرهنگی معماری، مطالعه معنای نمادین فرهنگی معماری، رویکرد غیرکلامی در درک معنای فرهنگی، معماری قواعد فهم اشاره‌های فرهنگی معماری، و قواعد خوانش فرهنگی معماری و محیط.»
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
There is no doubt that architecture has boosted the interaction of culture and culture is affected and influenced. Sociology housing issues trying to identify the circle of conceptual and semantic interaction of culture (society) and housing architecture. Thought process to reach a predefined architecture feedback conceptual architecture needs to be discussed in terms of culture and architecture of the house. The previous question is that the only place of residence can live in a space Find it called? The research paper is an analytical and logical reasoning is used by documentary and library studies. In line with the results of the phenomenological concept of residence and the residence life mentioned in the phenomenological approach and the cultural paradigm in the development of complex biological home based on cultural theories have been discussed as follows: Cultural meaning of architectural, cultural and symbolic meaning of architecture, nonverbal approach in the sense of cultural, architectural and cultural references to understand the rules of architecture, and cultural readings architecture and environment rules.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>سکونت, مسکن, خانه و فرهنگ ایرانی, پارادایم های فرهنگی و پدیدارشناسی سکونت.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>housing, housing, homes and Iranian culture, cultural paradigms and phenomenology of residence.</keyword>
	<start_page>165</start_page>
	<end_page>188</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-708-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Shaahin</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ilka</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>شاهین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ایلکا</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001889</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001889</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Behrooz</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mansoori</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>بهروز</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>منصوری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>emarate_khorshid@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001890</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001890</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Seyyed Mohammad Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Nasir Salaami</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید محمد رضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نصیر سلامی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001891</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001891</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Seyyed Ali Akbar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Saremi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید علی اکبر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صارمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001892</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001892</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
