<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <ArticleSet>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Spatial analysis on the state of the housing market in Tehran</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>7</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>20</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Like other economic markets, housing market is comprised of supply and demand dimensions and equality of supply and demand makes the housing market balanced. The aim of this paper is to investigate the characteristics of housing market of Tehran city and some deficiencies of this market with fundamental &amp;ndash; applied methodology. The variable studied here is the saleable residential unit with minimum 50m2 area which is obtained after statistical evaluations of housing price for many years and estimation of the loans and deposit of families in different income levels. Results reveal that problems of housing market can be attributed to lack of appropriate planning in housing building and supply (in quantity, area and geographic location), decreasing purchasing power of people various income levels as a result of misfit of increase in income and price of housing, low demand of families and finally, limited income groups for purchasing appropriate housing.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Housing market, Urban housing, Housing supply, Housing demand.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-824-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-824-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Human Functions in Landscape Design Based on human oriented design process</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>21</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>34</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>&lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-family:;&amp;quot; roman&amp;quot;;=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; new=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; &amp;quot;times=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; 13pt;=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; garamond&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;;=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; roman&amp;quot;;&amp;quot;=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&gt;Functions in landscape design include values in design and management process to satisfy moral and environmental needs that current attitudes see that as open space design by natural and man-made elements, while the basic intellectual layers related to human as the principles of environmental design have been forgotten. Human urban knowledge seeks to meet in health, biological, psychological, social and cultural human needs that landscape design also utilizes each of these cases, according to the plan will be considered. The result is moral landscape design is defined as the given Social and moral values in relationship between human and environment and the psychological functioning along environmental issues and performance are discussed. In this process human and environmental functions according to management priorities must be defined, and then the starting point is determined by the planning, that ethical and environmental values, and the executive would not be affected by technical issues.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Landscape design, Human Oriented Design Process, Moral Values, and Social Applications Ecosystem Concepts.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-830-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-830-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Metaphors, an Approach in Creation and Recreation of an Architectural Work (Objective Evidence: Behshahr Industrial Group)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>35</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>48</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Recreation (creativity) is undoubtedly one of the important designing bases and a durable, matchless and unique factor which determines distinction, excellence, and elegance of a building in comparison with other buildings; and architecture as one of the manifestations of human life in a special time and place can be a reflection of thoughts, ideas and living method and also represent identity in shape of thought and creativity which is known as creator of architecture work from viewpoint of architecture. Firstly reflection of architect&amp;rsquo;s character in architecture work, then cultural concept of the work and its belonging to a specific social and ideological movement and besides talent and creativity of the artist, the cultural and artistic movements affect drastically on the result of architect&amp;rsquo;s act who is creator of the art work in form of an architecture event. Therefore it can be mentioned that variables of the present research are nominal and qualitative; the dependent variables are also of the same type. The effects of economic, political, social and cultural movements can also be mentioned which are expressed in form of concepts such as tangible and intangible strategies. The present paper attempted to analyze metaphors used in the major building of Behsharh Industrial Group, which is an objective evidence of Nader Ardalan&amp;rsquo;s work. The analysis was done in a historical-interpretation method and in qualitative form.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>metaphor, recreation, Behshahr Industrial Group, Architects’ approach, architectural work identity</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-831-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-831-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Good Governance Model in Tehran City Islamic Council</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>49</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>68</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>This paper aims at studying governance and distribution of autonomies in Tehran City Islamic Council in the process of performing intra/inter-organizational functions. According to current theories on governance, there are three types of governance according to the kinde of involvement. Authority involvement, interactive involvement and persuasion involvement, in Tehran City Islamic Council in the process of forming and implementing urban regulations. On the other hand, Tehran City Islamic Council could have three kinds of autonomies to be effective: autogeny, heterogeny and discretion. Good governance model for Tehran City Islamic Council is an optimized combination of involvements and autonomies designed by polling the elites a mathematical model analysis. To study the current governance status in Tehran City Islamic Council, a questionnaire is used and the interval is estimated by single T-test. The findings indicate that in terms of involvement and autonomy, Tehran City Islamic Council has a remarkable distance from optimized governance model. 
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>good governance, authority involvement, transactional involvement, persuasion involvement, autonomy,  autogeny,  heterogeny, discretion </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-832-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-832-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Desiging Tabriz Carpet Art Museum Architecture Based on the Blue Mosque Historical Context Identity Potentials</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>69</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>78</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Due to universal importance of Tabriz carpet art and presence of specific indicators and motifs in Tabriz carpet art and its potentials, existence of architectural site for representing this art as carpet art museum in Tabriz is necessary. The site of this project is located adjacent to Tabriz Blue Mosque near the museum historical site. It is essential to consider the historical elements and components of the mentioned district identity in historical sites. This research aims at presenting architectural design of a valuable work of Tabriz carpet art museum besides considering criteria of the historical site adjacent to the Tabriz Blue Mosque. In designing Tabriz carpet art museum, the site potentials, concurrent employment of cultural and historical fabric concepts, adjacency of the Blue Mosque and being in direction of historical bazaar and Silk Road have been considered and used as the key pivots in design. This research is a case study based on observation and using architectural tools. Design limitations have been considered in the architecture of the museum near historical fabrics. The design components consist of Tabriz Bazaar cultural-historical architecture elements, utilization of the spatial connection, semantic continuation, respect to the site, preservation of old historical memory in modern approach. The results of this research can lead to successful architecture design adjacent to historical sites.&amp;nbsp;
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>architecture design, museum, Blue Mosque, cultural historical fabric, Tabriz </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-833-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-833-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Prioritizing the indexes of Discretion, Heterogeny and Autogeny factors in order to analyze and evaluate their readiness for ideal situation of Central bank of the Islamic republic of Iran</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>79</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>90</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>the purpose of this research is to prioritize the indexes of discretion, Heterogeny and Autogeny factors in order to analyze and evaluate their readiness for ideal situation of Central bank of the Islamic Republic of Iran (CBI). This research is an exploratory kind and in terms of method is a survey kind. The data collection tool is questionnaire. After two Delphi cycles, in final questionnaire the detachment variable was eliminated and for Autogeny variable 10 questions, Heterogeny 11 questions and discretion 17 questions were regulated, therefore it can be said the ostensible and content validity of the questionnaire was confirmed. Also since Cronbach's alpha coefficient of the questionnaire was higher than 0.7, it indicates acceptable reliability of the questionnaire. In order to analyze the data, Friedman test with applying SPSS software was used. The results showed, the structural dimension with average grade of 1.83 had higher average than contextual dimension which means in Discretion factor, the structural dimension has more readiness for ideal situation. Also the structural dimension with average grade of 2 had higher average than contextual dimension which means in Heterogeny factor, structural dimension has more readiness for ideal situation. And finally, the contextual tent dimension with average grade of 1.91 had higher average than structural dimension which means in Autogeny factor, the contextual dimension has more readiness for ideal situation.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>central bank, structure, contextual, ideal situation, grading</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-834-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-834-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Explanation of organizational health crisis in the Islamic Azad University Using a modified equilibrium theory; Studied at region six of Azad universities</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>91</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>100</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The aim of this study was to determine the level and analysis of the components of the organizational health at the Islamic Azad University of Region six. The research method is descriptive and population statistical consisted of region six of Islamic Azad university`s units. The subjects include 320 B.A holder individuals of staff who have bachelor`s degree and higher.&amp;nbsp; From among 175 people were selected .benefiting from multistage sampling and Morgan table. Research elements (Lyndon &amp; kingle) was obtained from organizational health questionnaire, Cronbach`s alpha reliability coefficient of 0.90. for analyzing the data mono sample t-test and Friedman have been used .the results revealed that the health status of the academic enterprise of MAHSHAHR and KHORRAMSHAHR is critical and SHOSHTAR`s academic enterprise in emergency and ABADAN AHWAZ and DEZFOUL academic units were normal. also the experimental mean such as: condition of participation`s components, loyalty and commitment, Direction and leadership in all academic units were lower than average (in an emergency) respectively
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>crisis, improved balance, Azad universities, Organizational health</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-835-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-835-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Sustainable Disaster Risk Reduction(SDR)  for Developing Countries with emphasis on land system Resilience (LSR); Case Study: Rural and Urban Settlement</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>101</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>118</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>With increasing frequency, the developing countries and the people living there are being affected by disasters. More and more often, development efforts are being destroyed. The reason for this trend is their growing vulnerability, which in turn is the result of economic and social development processes, such as the expansion of settlements and agricultural land in risk areas. The economic and social consequences of these disasters for the people in our partner countries last for years. To break and, if possible, reverse this trend, international organizations, governments and NGOs in the developing countries are increasingly upgrading the priority of disaster risk management for policy, and taking concrete preventive measures to reduce the risk to the population. This paper examined the concept of disaster and its management in the light of sustainable development with particular reference to Iran. It enumerated the different human and natural phenomena that could be characterized as disasters. It was discovered that, while hazard and/ or disasters possess anthropogenic origins, their consequences are felt on both human and the physical environments. In all cases, the human tolls have been significant. The paper highlighted the important elements of a typical Disaster Management Information System in Iran. After presenting a typology of disasters in Iran, the paper, advocated for a workable disaster management information system.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Disaster Management, Risk, Hazards, Vulnerability.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-836-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-836-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Comparison of Genetic and Hill Climbing Algorithms to Improve an Artificial Neural Networks Model for Water Consumption Prediction</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>119</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>130</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>No unique method has been so far specified for determining the number of neurons in hidden layers of Multi-Layer Perceptron (MLP) neural networks used for prediction. The present research is intended to optimize the number of neurons using two meta-heuristic procedures namely genetic and hill climbing algorithms. The data used in the present research for prediction are consumption data of water subscribers in Fasa City of Fars Province (Iran) between the years 2010 to 2013. Ultimately, using the respective data set, the data of the subsequent year 2014 can be predicted. In the present research it was observed that the mean square errors of per data (MSEPD) for the abovementioned algorithms are less than 0.2, indicating a high performance in the neural networks&amp;rsquo; prediction. Correlation coefficients using genetic and hill climbing algorithms were respectively equal to 0.891 and 0.759. Thus, GA was able to leave a better effect on optimization of neural network. 
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Water Consumption Prediction, Genetic Algorithm, Hill Climbing Algorithm, Artificial Neural Network, Multi-Layer Perceptron, Correlation Coefficient </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-837-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-837-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Determining the dimensions of organizational forgetting management and prioritizing them in university</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>131</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>140</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>This research seeks to determine the dimensions of organizational forgetting management and prioritize them in university. Current research in terms of purpose is applicable. In terms of data, it is quantitative. In terms of method, it is a descriptive-survey research. In this research, for determining the validity of measurement tool, content validity has been used and for calculating the reliability, Cronbach's Alpha method has been used. The population of this research includes the faculty members and employees of Islamic Azad University in region 8. Also the researcher-made questionnaire has been used for information collection. In this research, a framework consisting of quadratic dimensions of the process management, technology, culture and structure for evaluation of organizational forgetting management was considered. With regard to the comparison by using of the mean index, the quadratic dimensions were evaluated in two eligible and available situations. It is determined that with regard to the difference between two available and eligible situations, in fact the level of process dimension is low and it is in available situation, also it can be concluded that culture in available situation is very posterior than ideal and eligible situation. In two technology and structure dimensions, this mean difference is less than two other dimensions. In available situation, the most gaps and deficits at first exist in culture dimension and then in two technology and structure dimensions; and finally there is weakness in the process dimension. Totally in different dimensions, there is a relatively large difference and gap between the mean indexes of two eligible and available situations.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>organizational forgetting,organizational forgetting management,higher education</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-838-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-838-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Optimization Location of  Class Parking, Case Study: Tehran, Iran</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>141</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>148</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Proper siting of a public parking garage increasing efficiency and thus reducing the marginal park and indirectly increase the width of the streets and traffic is mental. At present, the location of public parking with traditional and is performed site visits. In this method, taking into account all factors affecting the location of public parking not possible with regard to the selected sites only a limited number of parameters such as the &amp;ldquo;land price&amp;rdquo; is performed. This would take away parking absorbent centers Travel and parking in the busy streets and increase traffic to the street. &amp;ldquo;Geographical Information Systems&amp;rdquo; (GIS) that science and technology are analyzing spatial data, in order to find the optimum system for the construction of public parking places are considered. The use of GIS in the field of land and increase the accuracy of the work is to reduce the number of hits. In this paper, weighting and combining information from different methods of allocating points such as weight, AHP nine degree and Fuzzy AHP and fuzzy index overlay method and a method using a combination of these methods were compared and the results were presented, and finally the appropriate methods.This article discusses how public parking location using GIS to consider all parameters affecting the positioning simultaneously offers. In this paper, factors affecting the location of public parking from three perspectives, 1. Near the parking lot to the Centers for Trip Attraction, 2. Factors Traffic and 3. The problem, especially in inner-city dumping ground &amp;quot;has been studied and given the location of these views, the conceptual model parking is provided. Below is the perfect place to build parking for the region's seven municipalities in Tehran.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>GIS, multi-criteria decision making, AHP fuzzy, overlapping index, public parking location.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-839-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-839-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Socio-Economic Values and Architectural Features in Traditional Bazaars of Islamic Cites</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>149</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>162</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>One of the most traditional architecture and urban planning patterns is bazaar. The aim of this paper is studying social, economical and architectural features of traditional bazaars. The claim of this study is that they are significant relationship between social and economical values of bazaars with their architectural values. Bazaar usually is located along the main routes of the city and extended to the city center. Most activities and exchanges of city happen in the bazaar. In the past, the bazaar was a place for the transfer of customs, traditions, ideas and practices of social behavior and social life. Bazaar as a social media and social network, bazaar a source of social capital, forming micro funds are the greatest economically and socially achievements in the traditional bazaar. Wakf in addition has socially and economically important functions in day-life and urban activities, also has in physical aspects vital roles in shaping Islamic cities especially Iranian cites and bazaars. One of the most important features of bazaar&amp;rsquo;s set is formation guild organizations, socio-political, and the founder of this organization, which may be composed of civil society. Most of these activities and values are related to architectural and physical features of bazaar.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Social Capital, Social Media, local Fund, Backbone of City Structure, Guilds, Architecture of Bazaar </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-840-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-840-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Evaluating The Creation of Dwelling Space in relation to Place</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>163</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>174</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Primary man in trying to find food went everywhere. But by forming ranching arranged a chain of places and became emigrant. By happening industrial revolution, human life was centralized on one place.&amp;nbsp; Places that base on its advantages make different biologic and behavioral types. Forming cities in seaboard, river shore, boundary of mountains and Champaign cause to make different cultures that shows habitat and continent effects on their inhabitants. This definition of human means native man was removing in industrial revolution because modern life advantages aren't depended on habitat. Loom factories develop in every longitude and latitude and cause to form cities that have sit on beds without native values. In fact dependency on a special place in agriculture ages lost its special value and come off in everywhere. In the other hand, in information and media revolution of globalization life Advantages Sea themselves in communication and virtual space that is quite placeless. In fact if we define habitat as an interacting situation between human and a place, we can survey this concept evolution and change procedure from past to now and study its results and effects on human life space quality. In this study we survey efficacy on and getting effect of habitat by studying cultural and anthropologic evolution and genesis of habitat concept and restudy its relation with human real and virtual residential space.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>place, space, agricultural revolution, industrial revolution, media revolution, globalization</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-841-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-841-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The impact of urban green spaces create a sense of security and promoting mental health in the community </ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>175</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>184</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Plants as the life giving entities have important role in mental and physical health of human. In the modern time with expansion of the cities and increase&amp;nbsp; of industrial centers and living style change and decrease of social negligence about green spaces as the factor for mental diseases, altogether have been propounded for many psychologists and physicians. In this way considering green spaces is necessary to peace of mind. This article intends to study sense and visual capabilities of artificial green spaces using descriptive method and their effects on human. The results show that connection with green space directly or using senses can contribute to reach mental health. It is hoped this research can provide conditions to further researches.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>urban green spaces, architecture, health, mental, vegetation</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-842-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-842-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>A Modern Model for Sustainable Architecture with uses Nanotechnology</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>185</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>202</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The 21st century Nanotechnology has the potential to make a huge impact on sustainability; but to achieve this potential, Nanotechnology is all about getting more function on less space. In other hand, Nanotechnology is one of the most extremely important components in sustainable development. It has the potential to reduce the environmental impact and energy intensity of structures, as well as improve safety and decrease costs associated with civil infrastructure. So, nanotechnology it can one of the most extremely important component for sustainable architecture. In this research we would like to answer below questions: Can nanotechnology be developed in a sustainable manner? How nanotechnology be developed in a sustainable manner? In this Paper, first we brief describe about sustainable architecture and nanotechnology, then we shows nanotechnology it can achieving the goals of sustainable architecture. We propose a new strategy of nanotechnology to achieve sustainable development. Finally, we present a new model for nanotechnology to achieve sustainable development. This work, presents the theory of analytical methods and the analytical approach has explanatory.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Architecture, Nanotechnology, Sustainable Architecture,Environmental Health, Renewable Energy.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-843-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-843-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Comparative Study of Architecture of Mowlawi and Sufism Monasticism; Case study: Sheikh Safi-AldinArdebilli, ChalapiOghlu</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>203</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>218</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Gnosticism and Sufism, investigation of activities of these two schools through times andalso reviewing their different parts have been paid attention by western and eastern researchers across Islamic countries. Islamic Sufism is one major issue in Gnosticism which lasts for twelve centuries since its foundation. This subject has been paid essential attention regarding that an important part of social and religious culture of Muslims is founded on Gnosticism issues. Regard that complete understanding of Islamic culture may not be achieved without recognition of Gnosticism and Sufism and no one can ignore this important phenomena. On the other hand, Sufism is an extended school in Iranian Islamic society and it is an integrated part of religious, literary, and national history of Iran subject to issues of Gnosticism.This paper tends to investigate monastery of Sheikh Safi-AldinArdebili and ChalapiOghlu in Zanjan and monastery of Molana in Qunieh. We tend to compare and contrast similarities and differences of the studied monasteries regarding to Sufism religious ways and spatial hierarchy and form variation in designing monastery spaces. This paper used descriptive-analytical-comparative and contrast method and collected information based on library based studies. Evidences show that monastery of Sheikh Safi-AldinArdebili was founder of Sufism and it includes seven stages of spiritual evolution. Sheikh Safi-AldinArdebili affected on Anatoly and Syria and etc.Monastery of ChalapiOghlu in comparison with Sheikh Safi-AldinArdebili monastery has unique integration in elements and plans and its linear analysis of its plan show an imitation from central idea of Sheikh Safi-AldinArdebili monastery.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>monastery, Sheikh Safi-Adin Ardebili, ChalapiOghlu, Molana</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-844-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-844-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Quality Improving Methods Of Education at  Architecture Conservatories Of  Tehran with Emphasis on Narrative ways of architecture education</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>219</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>234</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Architecture education has social, interpersonal and ethical aspects. The role of narration and storytelling as a pedagogical tool in clarification of academic subjects has been argued by researchers.Architecture is a multidisciplinary field of study that draws on the arts, science and social sciences. The aim in educating architects is seen as developing the imaginative, conceptual and practical skills necessary for students to identify human needs and aspirations, and to be able to meet or express these in space and form. Donald Schon asserts that these defining of abilities can be called &amp;lsquo;thinking like an architect&amp;rsquo;. It would be students&amp;rsquo; capacity to see unfamiliar situations as familiar ones, and bring their past experience to bear on the unique case. In the educational process, the main focus not only on the assessment, but also in the process of learning during the lecture[1]. The importance of this matter is so that it can be observed in families. Changes in technology, human resources, information technology and changes in consumer preferences, has changed perceptions of manpower required education and skills. Due to increasing importance of vocational training school for girls and the need for quality improvement and evaluation, participation and their role in these changes can be very effective but this partnership in comparison with its true position, is still low and negligible. This study examined documentary and scientific aspects of obstacles and strength points and methods of improving quality of teaching in the Conservatories. So we tried to develop a systematic framework for evaluating Conservatory in Tehran, in order to help resolve this need and with its preliminary implementation, while identifying condition of target Conservatory community, will provide condition of comprehensive evaluation for other technical training institutions so that with knowledge of strengths and weaknesses points and obstacles can improve quality of training centers. The present research, is descriptive and functional that evaluate the state through the questionnaire that has been developed with regard to objectives of the Conservatory training of Tehran, identify the current status, obstacles and also utilizes information obtained from interviews of teachers and experts in this sector in four fields educational, personal, social, economic and four levels of &amp;ldquo;high, medium, low and very low&amp;rdquo;. Due to gathered information and analysis by SPSS obstacles have been reported high extent that finally guidelines and recommendations in order to quality improvement of current situation is presented.







</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Obstacles, Strengths, Improving, Quality, Education, Conservatory.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-845-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-845-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>University Good Governance; The study of autonomy and accountability in Islamic Azad University, Qazvin Province</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>235</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>244</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>University autonomy and accountability have been playing such a vital role in all aspects of university governance that their importance cannot be over emphasized. Autonomy can be defined as &amp;ldquo;the right of a group of people to govern itself or to organize its own activities&amp;rdquo; and being autonomous means &amp;ldquo;being independent and having the power to make your own decisions&amp;rdquo;. On the other hand, accountability means being responsible for decisions or actions and being required or expected to justify them. The purpose of this study is to examine and assess the degree and sufficiency of university autonomy in the four area of institutional, financial, staff, and academic and also the degree of accountability of universities to their external stakeholders. The instrument for gathering data was a researcher-made questionnaire with a five- point&amp;nbsp; Likert scale and its calculated Alpha was above ./70. This means that the instrument was reliable. Data were obtained randomly from university managers at Islamic Azad University branches in Qazvin province. The data were analyzed using percentage and five-point Likert scale to objectively determine the degree of accountability and the sufficiency of the university autonomy for good governance of their branches at the four area of autonomy from the view point of university chancellors, vice-chancellors, Dean and Head of the Departments. The analysis of data in relation to research questions were investigated, using one-sample t-test by means of version 18 of SPSS software. The findings indicate that the degree of autonomy in the four area is not sufficient to govern the university well and the University administrators suggest that granting more autonomy from the central administration of Islamic Azad University and Ministry of Science, Technology and Research to the university branches may hold them to be more accountable to internal and external stakeholders.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Islamic Azad University, University good governance, Autonomy, Accountability</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-846-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-846-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Minimalist structures in urban space: a criticism to the works by Sol Lewitt from point of view of Arthur C. Danto with an emphasis on arrangement of works in urban environment </ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>245</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>256</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Urban spaces and in other words urban design and architecture have been found with close linkage with art and beauty especially the arts such as painting and sculpture. Addressing beauty at different areas such as creation of galleries to offer works of art, addressing form of urban spaces and representing works of art in urban environment have improved social life and increased identity, consensus and collective solidarity. On the other hand, it can provide an interesting and calm environment for the citizens and residents. Concurrent with the socio-political developments in the twentieth century and the progress of science and technology, all the areas of the arts were subjected to change. The metamorphosis of the art and stylistic developments took place and a large number of artists tended to innovative phenomena. Since the art at the twentieth century especially the second half of the twentieth century sought to affect the addressee, a group of the contemporary artists including sculptors have not known the tight enclosure of museums and galleries to represent their works and preferred to display their works at open space and wide and large places of cities. Representing works at open space requires largeness of dimensions of works at multiple scale and use of modern materials and techniques. Sol Lewitt (1928 - 2007) has been regarded among the artists at contemporary age at the area of Minimalism and Conceptual Art. American philosopher and theorist and contemporary art critic, Arthur Coleman Danto, has conducted articles in criticism to works by Sol Lewitt and has appeared in exhibition of his works. Lewitt made the earliest structures in 1965 and continued his activity at the 1970s by expansion of plans and planning for the larger projects which have been being made based on morphological&amp;nbsp;and conceptual ideas. Ultimately his arrangements were proposed at huge scale and extended from the space of galleries and museums which tended to conceptual and minimalist art to the urban space. In the present research, works of this artist and ideas of Arthur C.&amp;nbsp;Danto about minimalism and works of Sol Lewitt are analyzed. The main questions are as follow: What outcome representation of these works has in natural environment and urban space? how the border between art has removed the daily life and addressee? 
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Sol Lewitt, minimal structures, urban space, Arthur C. Danto, works of art </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-847-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-847-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>42</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>6</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>A study on dimensions of Fractal geometry in Iranian architecture</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>257</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>267</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The subject of geometry and proportions has been regarded as an issue which has a close relationship with architecture. Since the entire universe, living beings and the human geometry can be seen clearly, that&amp;rsquo;s why our unconscious essence has accustomed to these proportions whereby reflection of this mentality can be seen in the architect&amp;rsquo;s hands and thought in the architecture. It can witness a close linkage between nature and architecture at different levels in Iranian architecture which the linkage at architecture geometry has been regarded as one of these levels. Iranian geometry using plant and geometric forms in Islamic buildings seeks to prove a special continuity in the life to plant and human world. This continuity in the world of geometry has been known with fractal geometry. The present research seeks to examine dimensions of fractal geometry in Iranian architecture and motifs. In following, an attempt is made to examine what the fractal means in Iranian architecture and clarify the motifs and decorations of Iranian architecture after defining the issue of fractal, fractal geometry and fractal in architecture. 
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>geometry, fractal geometry, Iranian architecture, Islamic architecture</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-848-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-848-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
 </ArticleSet>
 
  
  
  
  
 