<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <ArticleSet>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Detecting key success Factor (CSF) employment of decision Making supportive systems (DDS) at urban management area (case study saveh mayoralty).</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>7</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>18</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>decision mating supportive systems help to determiners by the way of direct mutual actin with information and analytic models solve semi-structured issue. Emptical concept in decision making supportive systems is that results should obtain quickly with exports and directly use by politicians or exports researchers. In the present research urban management structure and supportive systems usage of saveh municipality checked present study in terms of essence is in the category of development practical research and in terms of method is member of analytic descriptive research statistic and information of research have don free scaling by library, reading, administrators and saveh mayoralty exports have constituted statistical sociwty of research. Vote and their opinion collected by questionnaire. In the analysis of information spss software and statistical examination chi-square, Friedman and exploratory factor analysis and rotation matrix are used. The result of research show that the main key factor than can increase success; Decision making supportive systems. Include training of participatory urban; Managers, development knowledge division culture and appropriate pragmatics of decision making supportive systems.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Decision making supportive systems (DSS), key success factors (CSF), saveh municipality, urban management</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1174-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1174-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Explaining the Conceptual Model of Interactions among Ports and Their Hinterlands: A Study by Content Analysis Method</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>19</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>40</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Ports are of major gates of spatial flows. These nodes not only guide the distribution of goods within the supply chain, but also play an important role for developing their hinterlands. Lack of attention to these spatial relationships, especially in countries with endogenous development factors, reduces the importance of local hinterlands. This would also shrink the relations among ports and hinterlands at the local and regional scales. In this regard, identifying and highlighting the components of spatial structure lead to strengthen the relations between ports and hinterlands. Up to now, many articles have been written on Ports and Hinterlands that can be generally classified them into five categories: The role of ports and hinterlands within the supply chain and transportation; function and efficiency of ports; port-city relationships; management, policy-making, and governance of port-regions; and the trajectory of spatial structure of ports, hinterlands, and forelands. This study aims at identifying and weighing the factors of spatial structures and proposing an appropriate theoretical framework on the spatial structure of port-hinterland based on content analysis. The findings suggest six components of spatial structure: territory; node; corridor; activity area; interaction; and discipline. Compilation of these components result new dimensions of spatial structure; such as spatial movement, spatial use and spatial form. Furthermore, during the development of port-hinterland relationships logistic spaces come into being, which enrich the flows of production, distribution, and consumption. Spatial movement depends on the relationship between nodes and communities. Also human activities on the land can form spatial use. Spatial form is based on interaction process between spatial movement and spatial use that can be appeared obviously or be hidden. In the regional structure, component of discipline with obvious outward can introduce a new dimension as logistic spaces. In fact, dimension of logistic space makes difference in spatial structure of port-hinterland compared to other spatial structures. Logistic spaces generally export spatial development flows to undeveloped geographical areas and adjust spatial structure of hinterlands. Overall, these dimensions generates a cycle entitled port-hinterland spatial structure, which can influence the entire spatial structure of a country. 
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Port, hinterland, spatial structure, content analysis.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1175-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1175-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Assess the impact of a sense of citizenship of a sense of place by emphasizing its semantic components Case study: The new City Campus</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>41</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>64</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Nowadays, more and more cities into the development process and the physical dimensions of the human desire and her features have faded. The result is fragmentation of man's relationship with his place in particular and the city in general. Thus, the lower part of the city considers its citizens. It does not feel belong; the consequences of which a range of problems such as loss of identity crisis takes responsibility; Aimed to assess the effectiveness of a sense of citizenship with an emphasis on meaning component which has been developed by adopting descriptive and ethnography. This index is based on library studies and documents. In Likert questionnaire was designed using SPSS software test and analysis of different AHP is hierarchical. The results show that social interaction can mean the places affected by the measures in place, individual characteristics, and mental structures; and culture and the formation of a sense of place including indicators, satisfaction and attachment.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>location, location, meaning, sense of place, a place of belonging, social belonging.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1176-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1176-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Child-friendly urban design guideline</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>65</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>90</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Today, attention to socially vulnerable groups, especially children, in the process of designing and planning the city's most important issues and Maximum attention is focused on experts and administrators manage the city. On the other hand, modification of the urban environment for children through urban design solutions, demonstrates a sense of responsibility towards the children of the professional architectural and urban planning. And will be training and responsibility in children and adolescents. Suitable for children and adolescents because the environment did not encompass costs and only requires knowledge, respect and responsibility among authorities and professionals. Accordingly, in this paper, fundamental and problem-based approach, and using the method of &amp;ldquo;analytical&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;logical reasoning&amp;rdquo; and policy research to study the aspects of child-friendly cities studied. And urban design guideline is considered child-friendly cities. Finally, in brief, the principles and design criteria are referred to child-friendly cities.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>children, urban design guidelines, child-friendly city. </Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1177-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1177-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Qualitative Daylight Measurement in the Urban Religious spaces with the Emphasis on Enhancing Spirituality in Place; A case study: SHABESTANI Mosques of Qajar Era in Tabriz Bazar</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>91</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>106</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The effect of light in Islamic architecture is very important. Its importance and spread is undeniable. It is an important factor in making mosque space spirituality heightened. Light is one of the affecting parameters on the value of space as the most non-material sensible element of nature which is always present in Iranian Islamic architecture. It always creates a mystical atmosphere in the place, especially religious places. In the past Iranian architecture, the application of light always comes with special elegance which improves the quality of the atmosphere of the architecture. Today, the attitude of the quantification and semantic aspects being ignored in the design of spaces often has caused to design light to provide the light needed for the reduction of physical activity. The purpose of writing this article is the introduction of quality assessment methods based on the seven principles of the light from the verse of light of the holy QURAN.

The present research methods for logical argument based on analytical descriptive and based on the field observations and library resources; The main findings of the research are as follows: a) introduction of qualitative principles of the light based on the verse of light, b) introduction of qualitative principles of the light in architectural body of religious spaces, c) introduction of objective and qualitative principles of light in religious spaces, d) introduction of the information extraction method for investigation and understanding of strength and weaknesses of the light in creation of spiritual spaces.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Qualitative light, religious space, spiritual space, Tabriz mosque of QAJAR era.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1178-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1178-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Rethinking on the geometric proportions of the creation in the Islamic art and architecture works</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>107</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>124</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The world is a wide book which pages are full of its author's words and just like Quran inspirational text has multiple meaning levels. The basis of this perception from Quran leads to the deepest understanding of the nature of natural faces and the quality of unity dominated on the world. The main issue in this writing is that firstly how the geometric proportions of the creation is form monotheism Quran principle?; And secondly how the geometric proportions of the creation manifested in the Islamic art and architecture works. The methodology of the research is descriptive, analytic and comparative by trend on Quran resources. The method of data analysis is deductive reasoning. The purpose of this writing is to perceive the heavens cosmos life and approach to the by the of Sobhanallah, refers to God's perfect trailts unexampled and rejection of creatures traits from God, operational monotheism by the slogan Alhamdolellah, refers to worshiping God and its importance and action monotheism by the slogan of Allah Akbar, refers to geometric proportions of the creation and unity and coordination in the existence system.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>geometric proportions, art, Islamic architecture, monotheism- creation.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1179-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1179-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Comparative Iranian markets and markets of Islamic Countries (Case Study: Yazd in Iran and Istanbul market in Turkey)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>125</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>138</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The far distant past, as the most active market in Islamic countries is urban and architectural space. Global Islamic countries not only as a space for barter but also as a cultural space, social, religious and the others; The aim of this study was to compare the Iranian markets with other markets of Islamic countries. In order to compare the markets of Yazd and Istanbul; the research was descriptive - analytic case (Yazd in Iran and Istanbul market in Turkey), gathering data, library method has been done. In this study, the concepts of the market, its activities and its features in Islamic countries then introduced Yazd and Istanbul. And have been analyzed. &amp;nbsp; In the end, these two markets in terms of spatial configuration, a variety of spaces, activities, etc. have been compared with each other. In the end, the results of comparative analysis are presented.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Market, Global Islamic countries, Yazd, Istanbul market.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1180-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1180-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Architectural component of the religious monuments of philosophical and phenomenological perspective</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>139</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>154</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Traditionally places of worship, the most ultimate bed and the spiritual evolution of mankind and the spiritual and sacred architecture believers has created a platform for collective worship. In between and among religions and social aspects highlighted that place of worship in Islam are created for the collective worship, is of utmost importance. That's why researchers and experts in Islamic architecture reviews and attitude to religious monuments, numerous methods have been used. So that each of theorists over time with different attitudes have interpreted the phenomenon of Islamic architecture; It is important to note that phenomenology in the process of cognitive reasoning and thinking power is sufficient. In contrast, the scholar of Islamic architecture in addition to enjoying the look of contemplation wisdom and knowledge of Islamic law to become liturgical architecture; this study philosophy and phenomenology, reviews and analysis in this way is recognition of religious monuments. The research method is qualitative and descriptive - analysis. In the case of religious buildings in Iran; and the results of this paper, readings from sacred component in the structure and form of worship as the notion of sacred buildings in the design of places of worship. Thus, the analytical findings of this paper is to identify factors that influence led promoting Iranian mosques architecture and how the presence of these components in the architecture of mosques and archetypes is schematically presented and analyzed; The process leading to the search for quality has been analyzed in this article; that more than anything in the promotion of the fundamental components in different parts of the mosque convenience.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords> places of worship, wisdom, phenomenology, elements of Islamic architecture.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1181-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1181-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Principles of endogenous approach in architecture education </ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>155</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>176</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Nowadays, the physical impact of the environment on human behavioral pattern has been accepted. Given that one of the most influential factors in the quality of the physical environment, architecture, the importance of tutorial system architecture, defined as a system for raising the architects, will be determined. Overcoming the problems of the current system of architectural education in Iran has always been a concern of researchers and scholars. So far different strategies and educational approaches to solve problems of the educational system or parts of it have been proposed. In many cases these strategies defined in the translation of educational approaches abroad. That it does not comply with existing structures architectural education in which part of the issues have been considered. In order to resolve the issues raised and given the multifaceted nature of endogenous development approach; In this paper the possibility of taking advantage of the potential of this development model, to promote and to address issues and problems facing the educational system have been investigated and using simulation and logical argument research method defines conceptual models of the topics discussed and Finally, principles and components of this architectural education approach adopted.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Architecture Education, Academic educational system, Architectural education system. Endogenous n approaches, Principles</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1182-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1182-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Developing a Model Environmental Education to Strengthen Governance Sustainable in Water Resources Management</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>177</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>194</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The aim of this study is to provide educational model to Strengthen sustainable governance in the management of water resources. The tool for evaluation was a questionnaire and the research methodology was of descriptive survey. In this study, the main gaps in water governance with respect to the experiences of past trends and socioeconomic circumstances were completed at national level and&amp;nbsp; the final list of the components of sustainable water resource governance were conducted. After the conclusion and implementation of appropriate governance standards and integration and convergence criteria using experts' opinions, the Delphi method was selected. The validity of the indicators was established by taking into account the views and comments of relevant scholars and experts, and the reliability of the indicators was calculated as 0.94 using the Cronbach&amp;rsquo;s alpha formula. Following interviews with 110 senior water executives, professors of water resources, senior agriculture managers, experts of water in native communities and NGO activists, and by applying the method of complete enumeration, all criteria and indications were graded in the fuzzy decision making. The results of the study show that amongst which the indicator of training obtained the greatest scores. According to the findings, one of the best solutions is to provide educational model.&amp;nbsp; The model has not only a necessity, but it is as a matter of principle for national prosperity. Pattern provided in the form of informal education is, including planning, monitoring and evaluation for all decision-makers and managers of water resources for sustainable governance to 1415.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Sustainable Governance, Water Resources, Environment, Educational Model, Informal</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1183-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1183-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Design and validation tool to assess the two sides can in organizational management</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>195</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>210</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The aim of this study was developing a tool to assess an organization's strategy ambidexterity. To achieve this goal a sample of 173 students of the faculty (academic rank of associate professor with the above) from the University of North Khorasan province in the 94-95 school years were selected using stratified. In this study, the analysis of data from exploratory and confirmatory factor analysis was used. Validity of the questionnaire was confirmed by academic experts. To assess the validity, convergent and divergent validity of the two criteria were used. The results of factor loadings statements of each factor indicated, all items have cause more than 0.4 times the average variance extracted over 0.5, thus confirming convergent validity of the variables. In addition, the square root of the average variance extracted values showed the highest value indicating the validity of the variables. Combining the reliability and validity of the questionnaire for all variables showed high levels of 0.7. The results of confirmatory factor analysis showed that the factors and components of fitness are acceptable And are consistent with the underlying structures. And finally the design of the questionnaire as a valid and reliable instrument can step in to facilitate research in the evaluation of the organization in Iranian organizations is double.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>double the organization, exploration, exploitation, exploratory factor analysis, confirmatory factor analysis.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1184-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1184-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The concept of continuity in the formation and development of architectural design concept Case study: Traditional Iranian Architecture</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>211</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>230</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Iranian architecture, like many other cultural manifestations in the history of its life has been rare continuity. &amp;nbsp;Of course it is not the Iranian people from the beginning of urbanization always quite similar to the structures and foundations have been paid and no change in the plan. It means that the fan when the building after an initial period of its development process went and laid his own way. In this study, a research &amp;ldquo;argument &amp;ndash; conclusion&amp;rdquo; is, the study of literature and examine the history of the concept of architecture in different periods and different climates tried to prove this hypothesis comes as Iran in different periods and architectural design concept in different climates has been a continuity and stability.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>unity, development, design concept, traditional Iranian architecture.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1185-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1185-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Examine the physical structure of the market as a vital element of the old urban fabric; Case Study: Kashan market</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>231</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>252</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Urban commercial spaces have always been and remain an integral component; and market centers example of this is the traditional Iranian architecture. Traditional markets with its ancient history, along with economic aspects also have had an active social role.&amp;nbsp; In many cities of our country can juxtaposition of religious and cultural elements with tissue observe the market? Each building reflects the mind and the mind of its inhabitants is inextricably remains of the building. And &amp;nbsp; Determines the institution where the building emerge. In addition to historical events affected the building of bazaar, according to the geographical conditions - cultural city; and three cultural factors are structural and functional factors are considered influential elements in the formation of the body. The present article tries to explore the concept of the market and its physical features, and then examine the physical structure of the market in terms of Kashan. The research method is descriptive and analytical compilation of qualitative and quantitative methods and practices survey reviews, interviews, and analysis are shooting.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>body market, Kashan, a critical factor in the urban fabric.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1186-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1186-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>A Study of the Involvement of Children in design and urban planning; Challenges and Solutions</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>253</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>278</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Create an urban space for children's welfare requires attention to a variety of planning and design of the city. A guide shows how to redesign the parameters and correct use of child friendly spaces can be created. Guided spaces can be designed in a way that children reduce barriers to independent access. And this is in line with a plan to make the city ideal for children. The participation of children in the planning and urban planning is the most important topics in the field of child-friendly cities. The subject of the present article is formed. Research methodology is descriptive - analytical and meta-analysis method that uses environmental scanning and participation of children and paving the way for its participation model has to offer. For this purpose, using the analytical method - descriptions, definitions of the characteristics child friendly cities and the participation of children in urban affairs with regard to the involvement of children in urban projects, strategies to promote the participation of children and adolescents in the formation of urban spaces provided.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>child friendly city partnership, the cooperation, urban planning</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1187-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1187-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Mutual influences political behavior and professional ethics and organizational commitment (Case Study Bushehr Municipality)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>279</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>288</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Means treating a person's political behavior visible when looking for your goals are. The political practices in the field of management as political strategies, tactics of penetration, political tactics and political maneuvers are also defined. Because few studies have been conducted in this area; the aim of this study was to investigate the role of political behavior in mediating role of organizational commitment and professional ethics. The population of this study municipal employees and managers Bushehr (1,600) that 310 persons were selected based on Morgan table. After gathering information through questionnaires were analyzed. Reliability using Cronbach's alpha coefficient and content validity it is enjoying the views of professors and experts in the field were confirmed. The AMOS structural equation model and research hypotheses with the help of software fitted surveys were analyzed. The results show that the political behavior of managers with professional ethics, organizational commitment has a positive effect. And at the end of the mediating role of professional ethics in the relationship between political behavior and organizational commitment was confirmed.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>political behavior, managers, professional ethics, organizational commitment.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1188-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1188-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Citizen Participation in Urban Environmental Protection in Urban Planning Strategies; Case study: Lavasan</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>289</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>320</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Today, the urban environment due to the major problems of life and increasing amount of pollutants that cause major environmental problems in urban areas are major challenges. &amp;ldquo;Participation and the environment&amp;rdquo; in the last three decades, more and more approaches together in a new approach to environmental protection is taken into consideration; Therefore one of the indicators of the degree of development of a country, the participation and the role of citizens in the country. The projects and programs that the trustee devices such as environmental organizations and municipalities to protect these habitats and reduce degradation of the urban environment and implemented have not had much success. Seems to be the missing link these plans, people often overlooked the importance of their contribution and the absence of people nothing but failure did not result in environmental projects. Therefore, to investigate and suggest solutions to increase the role and participation of citizens in preserving natural areas and the urban environment, including the requirements of any plans for Lavasan city. In this paper survey and field study methods of realization of environmental partnerships citizenship is studied. In the end, a strategic and operational solution for improving the participation of environmental citizens is discussed.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Participation, partnership, environmental, urban planning, policies and strategies.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1189-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1189-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Meta explain the theory, models, methods and techniques of creativity in architecture and design creative cities</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>321</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>350</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>New Urbanism in literature, creative urban space as a place of formation of creativity, knowledge, creative industries and innovation economy in a hybrid approach is considered. If we accept that all the above the axis of creative human capital and Nvavrnd, urban spaces should be eligible so that they can attract and retain these funds Which shows the importance of creativity in design or creative teaching methods in architectural design universities and training centers to train architects and urban designers are creative. In art and architecture, thinking and thinking and is considered an essential part of the process of artistic creativity; as architecture throughout history, a vehicle for expressing ideas and desires of human nature that has tried to crystallize your intellectual and cultural themes drawing close to the physical incarnation. The creativity and innovation of the issues that have a special place in the art of architecture and urban planning, as today the concept of creative and innovative themes of creative urban architecture urban architecture. The analytical method to study the theoretical aspects of creative cities has been discussed and theories, models, methods and techniques of expression and creativity in this regard is summarized. Finally, methodology, models, theories, methods and techniques of creativity in creative cities and architecture and the system architecture planning will be discussed.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>creativity, urban design, architecture, design and training, creative city, theories, models, methods and techniques.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1190-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1190-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of urban parks based on the needs of women citizens, Case Study: Municipality of Kerman</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>351</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>368</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>From the perspective of planning and urban design, landscape spread wider context of the development of vegetation and improve the natural environment of the city and it's actually kind of organizing and regulating the diverse and scattered green spaces. At the same time, having a spatial equity in utilization of urban spaces and parks planning and management of vital matters in today's cities. Accordingly, in this paper, the issue of women needs for parks, green spaces and their assessment of the level of services fitting the needs have been considered. The research is descriptive-analytic and theoretical stage in the evaluation survey. The results shows that in many cases poor design, lack of equipment and for the welfare of consumers, and so exacerbate the performance of many urban parks has provided for women in Kerman. And accordingly equipped, quality improvement and review of design principles and the creation of new green spaces in line with the standards and principles and criteria for sustainable design of the main requirements are considered the current situation in Kerman. Preference social component are different; the area of social services so as to better effectiveness of priority measures is as follows: 1. The need for security; 2. the need for support and advice; 3. need for participation and interaction; 4. the need for knowledge and information. 
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>urban parks, the needs of women, Kerman.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1191-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1191-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The impact of natural geography and climate, urban-oriented short story writers Khuzestan</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>369</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>384</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Climate south of Iran with cultural diversity and the specific nature inspired extraordinary atmosphere in the story. There are palm trees, river and sea, oil and industry, and even the heat coming from the south is the domestic context, have prompted the authors of the territory in which their works benefit from the blessings of God; And by doing this kind of individuation give lightness to his works; In fact, as the most important hub for literature Khuzestan climate of Iran, after the revolution and war and because of the migration of many blows suffered authors. Also, due to the acceleration of developments in social, economic, political and cultural change in recent decades as a result, investigation of these developments, especially in literature, can be felt more than ever. The aim of the present study, an analysis of short stories B. Heidari one of the authors of Khuzestan and the role of geography, climate and environment-oriented urban life in his works.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Southern literature, the authors of Khuzestan, climate-oriented, short stories, B. Heidari.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1192-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1192-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Evaluating of Environmental Culture in the Sustainable Development of the                               National Nuclear Industry</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>385</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>394</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The objective of the current study is to evaluate the environmental culture in nuclear industry in order to achieve sustainable development goals. The methodology of this study was descriptive of survey and the tool for survey consisted of a questionnaire. In this research, the components of environmental culture based on library study, review of documents, official reports, national and international sources as well as interviews with environmental experts was prepared; Statistical group involving 260 managers and experts of nuclear industry in field related to environmental issues. The validity of the questionnaire developed by the researcher was approved by the relevant academicians and its stability was calculated as equivalent to 0.88 using the Cronbach alpha formula. The results of the study showed that the total score of environmental culture in the nuclear industry has been positive and percent of employees with positive environment culture, equivalent to 71.7 and percent of employees with negative environment culture, equivalent to 28.3. This research also indicates that there was no significant difference between environmental culture and gender of employees, but the average environmental culture of employees increased with the increasing level of education, job rating and work experience. Besides, the results taking into account the effects of three parameters level of education, job rating and work experience simultaneously on environmental culture have shown that the impact of work experience and job rating is higher than the impact of level of education. This due to the national nuclear industry interaction with the international atomic energy agency and various training courses held by the international atomic energy agency for managers and experts with higher work experience.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Environmental Culture, Evaluation, Sustainable Development, Safety, Nuclear Industry</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1193-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1193-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Pygmalion effect on organizational citizenship behavior and health in the General Directorate of Technical and Vocational Ardabil</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>395</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>406</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of Pygmalion in organizational citizenship behavior and health in the General Directorate of Technical and Vocational Ardabil. The research was descriptive and correlational in terms of purpose and is conducted in this field. The study population included all employees of the General Department of Vocational province was considered that their number was 284 people. Cochran sampling formula was based on a sample size of 163 people. To collect the data, organizational citizenship behavior questionnaire Oregon and Kanvsky (OCB) (1989) and Organizational Health Inventory (OHI) Hui and colleagues (1996) and Pygmalion effect of self-made questionnaire containing 20 questions was used. To analyze the data, descriptive statistics (frequency tables mean and standard deviation) and inferential statistics (Pearson correlation coefficient and multiple regressions) are used in which the impact of the Pygmalion effect on organizational health and organizational citizenship behavior using SPSS19 software were analyzed. The results showed that the management of funds reasoning based on the Pygmalion effect there is a significant relationship between Ray and organizational citizenship behavior (0.05&gt; P). In the dimensions of organizational citizenship behavior after staff conscience highest correlation (0.408r =) is the Pygmalion effect; Also a significant relationship between organizational health and organizational Pygmalion effect there (0.05&gt; P). The dimensions of organizational health and citizenship behavior is explained by a factor of 77% and 82% could have a role in predicting the Pygmalion effect. Thus organizational citizenship behavior and organizational health in predicting the Pygmalion effect on the efficiency.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Pygmalion effect, citizenship behavior, organizational health, technical and professional.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1194-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1194-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Analyzing the role of neighborhood control abnormal behavior with an emphasis on the concept of citizenship identity Neighborhoods</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>407</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>438</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Contemporary literature, sociology and urban geography are one of the major characteristics of the current metropolises reduced social ties and moral concern of citizens and city views abnormal behavior control. In fact, in addition to numerous criteria to determine the geographic, economic, administrative, technical, network, metropolitan community center - a place in which to fit the increasing population, development of technical work and also raise the expectations of its inhabitants, continuously exposed to various forms of reduced or rupture in the social and moral ties. Accordingly, the concept of neighborhood oriented and analysis of its role in controlling social behavior is an important topic in the field of theoretical is examined. The analytical method and the method of logical reasoning, and the data, including library and documentary studies have examined this issue is. In the end, a central neighborhood and neighborhood planning axis position control unhealthy and abnormal behaviors city will be analyzed.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>community-oriented, abnormal behavior, citizenship, community identity, social control theories and solutions.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1195-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1195-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Johan Pallasmaa reading phenomenological analysis of the differences in the perceptions of architecture and urban and rural area</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>439</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>458</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Built spaces that are less qualified product training mechanisms relaxation, a sense of belonging to the place, the warmth and intimacy and feel Amnytand. If the space is constructed as a multi-faceted phenomenon and have implications, based on the lived experience of people know the truth of subjectivity and the different layers of human, social, cultural, economic and political, then it will be considered phenomenological approach, perhaps more than any other method in recognition of its scientific success is guaranteed. Having fun multi-sensory experience that every human relation with space ways to affect the quality and richness of creative space adds. But what is now being forgotten in contemporary cities is becoming the architecture of the human space to visual space, elegant and eye-catching. In this paper, the phenomenological aspects of architecture and urban spaces from the perspective of Johann Pallasmaa been studied and analyzed to recognize these two different positions in the field of theory.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>perception, feeling, senses, architecture, Johan Pallasmaa.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1196-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1196-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Foundations of municipal civil liability in respect of the staff and employees</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>459</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>470</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Municipalities are among the most important institutions of civil society within the framework of the rule of the constitution and in the areas of social, local and municipal participation and development are important components of structures. Municipalities are among the most important needs of society. Not necessarily with a structure that is possible only through the intervention of people is shown. There is an extensive and close tie with the community and suitable persons for damages and failure to observe the balance of power on the one hand and disruption in the functioning of municipalities is provided. Must determine the legal basis and in accordance with the terms and conditions the organization as much as possible be prevented from entering damage. Or measures thought to be compensated for damages to the fullest;&amp;nbsp; this study, analytical - descriptive attempts, The subject matter of the fundamental principles of civil liability in damages from the municipalities and the issue of relations between municipalities and employees' compensation.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>civil liability, government, municipalities, foundations, guilt, loss of employees.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1198-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1198-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Evaluate the impact of tourism on economic stability and economic growth of cities, case study: the city of Mashhad</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>471</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>480</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Tourism as a commercial activity, and the role of great importance in the economic development of countries, especially developing countries; Several factors such as amenities, facilities, communications, transportation, historical attractions, tours, technical information, and so on tourism activities involved; This indicates that this sector has a close relationship with the country's other economic sectors and intensity of foreign affairs and international relations is affected. On the one hand the development of tourism on national income, foreign exchange, employment and other macroeconomic indicators also impressive. In this paper, view of the economic importance of tourism, to review the status of these activities will be discussed in the national economy. The performance of the tourism sector through their effect on macroeconomic variables during the Third Development Plan will be discussed. Then, a glimpse into the policies of tourism in the Fourth Development Plan and the continuing development of the sector during the review program; At the end of the summary, the position of the sector in the country's economic development will be discussed. Also, the relationship between tourism and economic stability of cities studied and solutions will be mentioned in this connection.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>tourism, economic growth, economic stability.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1199-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1199-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Intimate urban space designed with an emphasis on memorable anthology of Yazd in History</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>481</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>498</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Space intimate space that the individual is resident in that sense that it is also part of your space and your knowledge of space knows; if you feel comfortable and have a man in space, highlighted by his presence in space and the context makes it memorable for him. Anthology pass Yazd is located in the historical context of interventions; part of theirs is being lost. But because of the history still lies in its ability to learn from the teachings of there. This study literature intimate and evocative atmosphere and formulation design principles such space, seeks to restore the familiar and friendly atmosphere in the historical context of the past. Space for users to create more memories. The method used is analytical and applied research. In this context, field observation and interview techniques populations, photography and videography is used. Results indicate that the old user (the old gymnasium, mosques, garages, etc.), although less than in the past, but excuse to attend a gathering and are memorable. There are elements of physical parameters (wind towers lean, domes, porch, etc.),space and the familiar marks of the space in order to help theirs. In addition to the lost and hidden spaces, dilapidated and abandoned buildings of historical value, to undermine intimate space. Open design of this historic transition that led to the loss of such intimate space, with its lessons of tissue, has been resolved. Results of this research in historical context Yazd and the like to create intimate spaces and evocative, it is recommended.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>intimacy, a sense of belonging, collective memory, memorable, historical context.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1200-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1200-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Evaluate the relationship between healing Persian garden landscapes with urban open spaces</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>499</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>516</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Landscape healing as a favorable environment to reduce stress and increasing relaxation and Turbulent dense urban areas today can have an impact on human health. So that these views regarding the features, functionality reduces tension and stress, help you relax and restore their health status. The purpose of this research to know how the Persian Garden and Landscape Healing the Relationship between quality components (utility) and healing urban open spaces to reduce environmental stresses are city dwellers. Both exploratory and correlational research methods and techniques, observation and questionnaires were used to collect field data. The study of users of the urban park built on the principles of garden Iran. And examples of study in these research ten users of the Persian garden Tehran's Vanak park and garden are Gohardasht Iran. Sampling was targeted and the numbers of 110 questionnaires were distributed among the people. The results indicate that the color component with the greatest influence on healing the perspective of the average value of 4.37 in the Iranian garden. As well as fragrance components with an average value of 2.76 is the lowest impact. Results of other studies that some components of fragrances, water, plants and light quality with all the drivers of urban open spaces are connected. All drivers except for color quality components connected to the sense of participation. The music component is associated only with the stimulant quality stimulate the senses.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>healing, healing perspective, Persian gardens, urban open spaces</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1201-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1201-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The appearance of architectural and Urbanism Interaction between Iran and the Western Urban Planning through the Iranian Travel literatures during the Qajar Period</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>517</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>534</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Confrontation with the West culture and its impact on urbanism and architecture are the most important issues for designers in national and international areas. The first viewpoints in spaces and urban landscapes and street systems in Iran dates back to Qajar era. Simultaneity of developments in Qajar city with industrial transformation and structural changes of the European cities and Iranian visit from there resulted in changing in the attitudes of Iranians. Among the routes that inform the researcher from this exchange, Iranian travel literatures to Europe have a special place. This study discusses on analyzing travel literatures from diverse perspectives. About thirty trip reports in early Qajar period have been studied within the confines of the constitutional movement. Then, the impact of these travels literatures on urban developments and Tehran's streets and the formation of palaces during the Qajar period; the research method is based on qualitative research methods from the content of historical texts. In the results, the researcher deals with explaining the central role of the travel literatures and in particular triple trips of Nasereddin shah in Tehran urban developments and architecture.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>Modernism, Urbanism, Architecture, QAJAR’s Architecture, Iranian Travel Lituraters</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1202-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1202-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Clustering and ranking contractors using data mining algorithm and VIKOR (Case study: Mehr housing Hashtgerd New Town)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>535</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>546</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The construction management of Mehr Housing projects, which has an increasing volume and is required to high speed, can be appropriately possible just through receiving and processing the reliable data and information on the right time. Long-term programs, which have been made by managers and can determine the whole levels of Mehr Housing projects, their executive process and the people&amp;rsquo;s operation who are involved in Mehr Housing project, are entirely on the basis of existing data mining. Hashtgerd New Town Development Corporation is one of the most fundamental administrators of Mehr Housing project throughout the country and therefore, an efficient construction management is essential to execute the projects in this town. Considering the fact that more than 80 projects of Mehr Housing project are being executed in Hashtgerd New Town and regarding that the memoranda of understanding have been contracted and operated in a short time, assembling the appropriate information in the field of contractors and projects is fundamental to apply the long-term policies and coherent methods. To cluster the contractors of Mehr Housing projects in this research, firstly the required data has been collected with regard to these contractors and then they have been clustered through cluster analysis method. Correctness of achieved findings has been certified through validation methods. Finally, contractors have been ranked in every cluster by VIKOR as a multiple criteria decision-making method. 
</Abstract>
	<Keywords> Mehr Housing, Clustering, Ranking, Hashtgerd New Town, Contractor Evaluation</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1203-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1203-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>15</Volume>
			<Issue>44</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2016</Year>
				<Month>12</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Investigate the relationship between psychological empowerment and improve performance in District 18</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>549</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>559</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>This study aims to investigate the relationship between psychological empowerment and improve performance in District 18 of Tehran by using descriptive and correlational study was conducted. The population in this study was all employees of District 18 of Tehran in 1395 based on the latest available information and statistics 830 people. The sample size was determined using Cochran formula 263. Simple random sampling is used. To measure the variables used in this research were two questionnaires empowerment and employee performance. Validity of the questionnaire was confirmed by experts. The reliability of questionnaires by Cronbach's alpha coefficient, empowerment questionnaire (81/0), and the staff (83/0) were estimated. For the analysis of descriptive and inferential statistical methods (Pearson correlation) were used. The results showed that a significant feeling of empowerment and all its dimensions, sense of competence, a sense of autonomy, a sense of efficiency, a sense of confidence - there is a significant positive relationship with employee performance.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords>empowerment, employee performance, District 18 of Tehran.</Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1204-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1204-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
 </ArticleSet>
 
  
  
  
  
 