<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <ArticleSet>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The traditional urban areas and its role in the development of cultural heritage tourism 
(Case Study: The historical areas of Sari)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>7</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>26</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>This research is based on library and field study and its main purpose is to assessing the role of Sari historic areas in cultural heritage tourism development. The library studies include the theoretical framework and questionnaire design and field surveys include distributing questionnaires and collecting tourist&amp;rsquo;s opinions. According to Cochran formula, we distributed 410 and gathered 360 questionnaires. The validity of questionnaire is confirmed by academic colleagues and (Cronbach's alpha=0.933) indicates high questionnaire reliability. In order to process data, we used SPSS software. Frequency distribution, averages and percentages were used to describe the data. Also one-sample T-test and Friedman were used for data analysis. Based on the results, architectural and historical monuments in Sari represent a great potential in development of cultural heritage tourism. But statistics show a significant gap between available capacity and level of heritage tourism development. The main reason for this situation is that all available capacity is unused. Therefore, refurbishing and entering valuable historical monuments in tourism cycle, restoring traditional face texture, mounting signposts at the entrance to the old city to guide travelers to review access routes, solving traffic problems, shifting government offices in the texture of measures is necessary.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2369-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2369-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>An Analysis of the Manifestation of Ethical &amp; Legal Ideas in Architectural Design of  Iranian Traditional Houses</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>27</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>44</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The religion of Islam contains many ethical values and principles. These principles have been developed in order to adapt to the life of Muslims and Islam goals. With a view to the evolution of traditional architecture one can see that after accepting Islam, people have attempted to adapt their moralities in life. This is also evident in the works left behind in the area of architecture, such that in addition to involving cultural, social, and historical backgrounds, the founded buildings are the manifestation of ethical virtues and have brought along comfort to the soul and spirit of&amp;nbsp; traditional man by applying some tricks. Architectural design of&amp;nbsp; Iranian traditional houses has been affected by multiple factors such as culture, geographical &amp; social features , etc. From long ago ethics as a socio-cultural factor has had a significant impact on spatial structure of traditional houses. The present study aims at investigating the manifestation of ethical ideas in spatial structure of traditional houses. Accordingly, the research question is as follows: How are moral principles and components as well as adherence to them manifested in spatial structure of traditional houses? The method used herein is descriptive &amp;ndash; analytical based on library and field studies. Thus, first of all, the components of Islamic ethics were extracted from Islamic verses and narratives and ethics books of&amp;nbsp; Islamic scholars; second of all, the study sample was selected and data collection was performed; then by using Factor Analysis, the most important ethical components affecting spatial structure of historical houses (with focus on Tabriz historical houses) were discussed and interpreted. The results of the present study indicate that ethical values and principles derived from the Qur'anic Verses and the Holy Prophet of Islam (peace be upon him) &amp;ndash; who is the great commentator of&amp;nbsp; the concepts in the Quran &amp;ndash; pervades all aspects of life of traditional architectures. Architectures` compliance with ethical values is openly visible and perceptible in architectural design of historical houses. Islamic teachings organize a man`s behavior in relation to God, other men, and nature and it`s components. Examples of such teachings are evident in paying attention to the Quran and truth seeking as God`s rights over the people, dignity, and reverence; respect for the rights of others as people`s rights; and not polluting and do savings in relation to man and nature. Relying on such ethical values, traditional architectures have raised architectural space of traditional houses to a high degree of richness and value. Relying on such moral values as beauty, justice, honoring the guest, respect for privacy, extravagance, edification, and exhortation, etc, the traditional architect has designed the traditional house in a way that the ultimate goal of building a house, that is human peace and dignity in house space, is reached.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2371-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2371-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Investment Management in Urban Health Infrastructure: Designing a Framework </ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>45</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>58</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Domestic and global trends indicate that there is a need for investment in health infrastructure. Although in the recent years, large investments have been made in this area in the country, delay and cost overrun, unfinished projects and in some cases redundant facilities denote a problem. Given the experience in the world and comparative studies and case studies, public-private partnership investment models were considered. The success of these models depend on several factors, among them is a good design.&amp;nbsp; With regard to the conditions and presuppositions, three different models were examined: Model type 1 for situations where it is difficult to detect and monitor the quality of health services provided; model type 2 for situations in which there is a possibility to monitor the quality of the health services; And model type 3 for situations where charitable endowment resources are available. We use Analytic Hierarchical Process (AHP) to prioritize the mentioned models. We use criteria of value for money to benefit from expert judgment which includes: optimal risk transfer, the lifecycle cost, performance and innovation in infrastructure. We have also designed an innovative questionnaire for this purpose. Despite the different criteria in the evaluation, assessment results are very close to each other and no significant differences were evaluated. This conclusion is consistent with our hypothesis: according to the conditions and the importance of criteria to evaluate, we should decide which of models is more fitted and therefore different results can be considered.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2370-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2370-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle></ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>59</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>76</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract></Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2372-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2372-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Analysis The Population Spatial Structure of Tabriz Metropolitan Region (TMR)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>77</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>92</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Regional imbalance is one of the significant features of spatial development in Iran. Changing the type of activity in the metropolitan region of Tabriz causes a concentration of population in Tabriz metropolis, which altered the distribution and pattern of the spatial structure of the population and thus caused a disturbance of the equilibrium of the metropolitan region. The purpose of this research is to analyze the distribution and spatial structure of the population and provide suitable strategies for balanced development of the metropolitan region. The methodology of research is quantitative and the paradigm of research is proof-based. In essence, the research is descriptive-analytic. Demographic data including the population of the metropolitan region of Tabriz for the years 1966 to 2011 have been obtained. For analyzing the population, analytical methods of the basic attribute approach have been used. The results indicate that population deployment in urban centers has not been distributed equilibrium and population distribution is clustered. On the other hand, the pattern of the spatial structure of the city is concentrated in the metropolitan region of Tabriz, It means overcoming the forces of the center. The Hillhorst spatial development model is a suitable model for determining future development strategies for balancing the metropolitan region of Tabriz.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2373-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2373-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Review and evaluate the views of citizens and professionals about the priorities of desirable urban management in Tehran</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>93</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>120</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Establish a common language and understanding between professionals and citizens about nature and how to achieve the desired city, an important first step to realize this numerous. In this research that classified as a basic and applied research used a survey (questionnaire and interview) from citizens as well as the Delphi method to obtain opinions of experts.
The results of this research indicated that tehranian citizens are aware of the necessity and importance of cooperation in city management and believe that the citizens or their representatives should take the responsibility of the city management. However, they are reluctant to participate in city management due to various reasons including: costly cooperation compared to its advantages, reluctancy of authorities, confliction with the numerous problems of life, not having enough time and the emergence of ideological, political and religious orientations. Finally, although experts consider citizen cooperation as the most important of public demands, we found in this research that, from viewpoint of tehranian citizens, responsibility, accountability and justice are the most important characteristics of preferable city management.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2374-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2374-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The Situation of Social Factors in the Forming of Iranian Cities Structure\'s</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>121</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>140</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The structure is one of the words that used in various fields of knowledge. This concept has also been introduced in the field of urbanism and has created an important topic called urban structure. Urban structure can be one of the targeted tools to recognize the city. Factors, elements and social features have been integral to human communities and consequently, it has had many effects on the city's formation. In this research, the explanation and clarification of the status of social factors in shaping the structure of Iranian cities has been studied. In this regard, the terminology and evaluation of the structure, urban structure, and further the recognition of social factors in the urban structure is presented. One of the important points in this research is the study of the roots and the origin of the occurrence of social factors in urban communities which is more important than the components of this important. The research method is analytical-documentary that the qualitative content analysis method was used to define concepts and formulate a conceptual framework. The method for collecting information is also libraries and documents. What is mentioned in the present study as a general result is that social factors play a significant role in the formation, evolution and especially the urban structure excellence and there is a two-way relation between the urban structure and social factors. Social factors in the form of physical representations have added spaces to the structure of Iranian cities, which is a valuable show of authenticity. The existence of this relation in addition to the evolution of urban structure, also promotes the promotion of social factors.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2375-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2375-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle></ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>141</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>158</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract></Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2376-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2376-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Inter-Organizational relationships (IOR) pathology of the urban management organizations in Mashhad metropolitan development plans (Case studies: Roads and Urban Development Office, City Council of Mashhad and Mashhad Municipality)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>159</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>176</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Urban management is the urban development framework, along with a set of tasks, roles and functions, in the form of compile (or codified) programs and its results in urban spaces. Despite the differences in structures and functions, Organizations and institutions involved in urban management processes inevitably interact with each other. It is clear that in order to prevent and overcome the various problems of urban environments and improve conditions, they prepare and formulate urban development plans and programs; in many cases the common theme is one of the fields of communication between urban management organizations it sometimes causes some conflicts and inter-organizational tensions. The purpose of this research is to investigate the pathology of interactions between urban management organizations in Mashhad metropolitan development plans. This research is based on nature and objectives of the analytical-descriptive survey and applied research. The statistical population of the study consisted of 66 members of the organizations studied: Islamic City Council of Mashhad, Organization of Urban Development and Architecture of Khorasan Razavi Road and Urban Development Department, Management of Urban development plans and Management of Planning and Development of Mashhad City at the Department of Urban Planning and Architecture of Mashhad Municipality, in the process of preparing, approving and implementing development plans. In addition to the library method, the research data have been collected using a researcher-made questionnaire, including five main dimensions, and 65 indicators of the statistical population) community) and analyzed by using SPSS and Excel software.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2377-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2377-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Investigation of the Pattern of Improvement of the Performance of Interior Ministry Staff</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>177</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>194</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Improvement of qualified staff and improvement of labor force performance is a necessary issue for organizations in the country, and selection, education and maintenance of them require specific criteria and indicators. The main objective of this research is to investigate the model of localization of the performance of staff in the Ministry of the Interior. The research method is applied in a practical way, and according to the information gathering, it is quantitative and has been done using the structural equation method. Sampling method was Morgan table. For distribution of the questionnaire, 274 persons were considered as a sample of research. The research is conducted in a survey method. A researcher-made questionnaire was used to collect the data. Using statistical software Amos, the statistical test was calculated and analyzed. The results indicate that all components of the employee performance improvement model were confirmed and it was proposed to consider the knowledge and business process of talent management in the Ministry of Interior to implement the model at the Ministry of the Interior.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2388-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2388-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Presenting a Framework (Process Model) For Integrated Management of Urban Projects Based on Project Portfolio Management Approach</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>195</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>220</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Urban programs and projects are the latest chain in urban development plans. Integrated and systematic management of urban programs and projects sets, while improving the efficiency of urban resources also results in the effectiveness and efficiency of urban development plans. Studying on policy, planning, implementation and monitoring urban programs and projects and presenting an appropriate pattern is the requirements of urban management. Project portfolio management is a new approach based on the knowledge of project management that emphasizes for the better efficiency of programs and projects in project-based organizations. The main components of project portfolio management include a process framework, decision criteria, methods and models of choosing the project portfolio that deciding on definition of&amp;nbsp; project portfolio management framework (process model) and categorizing effective indexes and sub-indexes in selecting portfolios are its main and influential stages. This study in terms of objective, is an applied research, and in terms of data collection is a descriptive - scrolling one. According to the article findings a framework (process model) for integrated management of urban projects is consisted of a three &amp;ndash;section: Strategic recognition, Urban project portfolio management and Essential and complementary infrastructure for project portfolio management.&amp;nbsp; In order to select urban projects portfolio, decision criteria separately were recognized and classified into eight groups which include technical, financial, social, economic, environmental, risk, organizational and competitiveness.


</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2378-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2378-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle></ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>221</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>234</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract></Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2379-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2379-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Geometrical principles of Streets in Safavid cities Case study: Isfahan, Qazvin and Mashhad
</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>235</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>250</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Pathways, like alleys and passages, had an important and significant role in the spatial organization and development of cities, during the history. In the Safavid era, &amp;ldquo;street&amp;rdquo; as a functional element, was derived particularly from the Persian gardens&amp;rsquo; pattern, and was used in the urban spaces as a spatial ordering and organizing element. In this era, Safavied sultans&amp;rsquo; interests in showing authority and magnificent of their reign, on one hand, and concentrates on designing with nature in urban development, on the other hand, led to design and utilization of different types of street in the main cities of this period, like &amp;ldquo;Qazvin&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Isfahan&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mashhad&amp;rdquo;, so that the street had a wide and extended impact on urban development processes. In the meanwhile, the significant and important point is that; the design was the way of conserving olden historical zones of city, in this era.

So this article tries to distinguish the influential geometric dimensions of street in arranging and ordering of the city form, by analytical- descriptive method. Therefore, the first part of this paper explains the values and importance of geometrical order, and different aspects of the concept. This research uses descriptions of travelers who observed and wrote events during traveling to Iran in this period. The method of study is based on studies and highlights, mentioned in travelers&amp;rsquo; itineraries, and analysis of their contents as the most important historical sources about &amp;quot;Safavied Street&amp;quot;. Second part of the study as an analytical divide, expand illustrations in case studies.

As conclusion shows, the special geometric order of Safavied's street, had reasoned to the creation of meaningful wholeness and regularity in urban structure. This significant wholeness has diverse dimensions which have impact on foundation of its quality and also it's ordering role. To the extent of this proposition, different implications like: joints, direct, axis, voids, positive spaces, gradient and hierarchy, incorporation, ::union:: and others had been considered and straight streets and streetscape in Qazvin (khiaban), Isfahan (Char Bagh) and Mashhad (kheiyaban) had these features of geometry and order. This idea influenced on urban design and was important in creating continuity of historical and prebuild urban spaces and new ones as correlation and unity in urban components.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2380-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2380-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Ranking the types of NGOs to improve the effectiveness of urban management with the public participation approach</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>251</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>268</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The aim of present study is to prioritize the different types of NGOs in promoting the effectiveness of urban management with a public participation approach. To identify the most important criteria influencing on the effectiveness of urban management as well as the types of active NGOs in the urban area, library research has been used and the AHP has been used to determine the priority of the research criteria. Participators included the experts and senior experts in the field of urban management and NGOs. For this purpose, sixteen experts were selected as sample, and at the final stage based on Paired comparison matrix. Data was mainly gathered by questionnaire. The weight of the criteria identified by using the AHP method is as the follows: The criterion for improving life and reducing urban poverty is the highest priority. The criteria for providing urban services, the transparency of the performance of urban management, social capital, and citizen participation and local culture management are in the next order, respectively. The selection of the best non-governmental organizations based on the main criteria identified using the AHP technique can be concluded that the best option is health, treatment, sports and general health, and the welfare and sustainable development, education and cultural and social activities, citizenship rights and minorities and NGOs in the international arena were in the next rank, respectively.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2381-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2381-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>The Role of Lighting Architecture in Nocturnal City Branding and Management </ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>269</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>290</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>City branding is one of the important issues in the field of urban management that has been studied extensively in recent years. Branding of cities requires coordinated and coherent efforts to draw a unique city image that is accorded to the expectations of citizens and tourists, which ultimately forms their mental image of the city or place. City managers need to create visual attractions, in the process of brand construction and drawing of the city's image, they need to draw a unique character for the city. In the other hand, City life is divided into two parts daily and night section, and this issue has the importance of creating the city's nightlife along the city's image on the day, so in this area, the lighting of city's components is of particular importance. In this research, by analytical-descriptive method, after reviewing the topic literature in the field of urban branding in order to determine priorities and relationships between indicators, as well as to determine the effect of lighting of each types of buildings in creating city branding, semi-structured interview with a sample of 23 persons that is consisted of experts in this field, it examines different aspects of the subject. In order to answer the question, which of the types of buildings has a more effective role in nocturnal city branding, eight types of buildings have been investigated separately to examine the impact of lighting. The Kendall&amp;rsquo;s tau-b test has also been used to analyze the relationship between variables. The analysis suggests that traditional and old buildings, recreational facilities, commercial buildings, and parks have the most impact on urban night-time branding.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2382-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2382-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Feasibility study for the production of bio gas as a clean energy from animal waste in Iran\'s villages for livestock experts</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>291</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>304</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The limitation of fossil resources and the rapid growth of energy consumption in the world are among the factors that encourage researchers to access new and renewable energy sources. Biogas is one of the most renewable resources that can be used in farms for ranchers. The purpose of this study is to determine the feasibility of producing clean energy from biogas from animal waste in Iranian villages for livestock experts. Fingerprinting has been used in this research. The statistical population of the livestock experts was four provinces of Iran (337 people), who&amp;rsquo;s sample was 181 according to Morgan table and stratified random sampling. Based on the findings, eight criteria for the feasibility of biogas production were extracted from animal waste, including socio-cultural, economic, technical, skill, environmental, climatic, infrastructure, information, promotion and education. Also, the significance of each criterion in experts in the provinces revealed that in the province of Fars socio-cultural criteria, in Khorasan Razavi province, infrastructure indicators, in Golestan province, economic and in Kermanshah province, the criteria of infrastructure and climate were more important. It is recommended that groups and organizations of livestock breeders be formed in Iran to make biogas available, provide facilities and provide financial resources. Centers to support and train skilled specialists in the field of installation, maintenance and repair of the biogas plant. Also, given the importance of biogas as a clean energy, it is recommended that future research be focused on the social dimension affecting the implementation of biogas. The conditions for the adaptation and development of biogas in different regions should be examined and the assessment of the social impacts of the implementation of biogas, like all development projects, should be carried out.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2383-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2383-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>An analysis of the Architectural Plan-Checking Reports as a Reflection of the Architectural Design Services Condition in Rasht </ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>305</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>326</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Architectural plan-checking reports which are produced and archived day by day in the broad range of local offices of the Iran Construction Engineering Organization (IRCEO) throughout the country, can provide a reliable picture of the general condition of architectural design services in each office&amp;rsquo;s territory and the whole country in general. However, there have been no proper attention given to these reports as a resource to extract indicators relating to the quality of building design services provided by the relevant architectural firms. The current research is an attempt to fill this gap through which a method is suggested to analyze and interpret the plan-checking reports. To this purpose, as a case study, the method is applied to the plan-checking reports produced in the Rasht office of the IRCEO during March 2017 to December 2017. Meanwhile, 1821 files have undergone the plan checking process among which 954 ones (52%) were rejected by the architectural control officials in their first checking of the documents. Among these rejected files as the total population 419 ones were selected as the sample according to the Cochran formula. In order to achieve an analysis of the content of the reports, the control officials&amp;rsquo; rejection comments on each project were categorized into four main categories including comments related to in-complete application file, improper drafting properties, inner incompatibility of the project plans, and non-conformance to technical requirements which were subdivided into sub-categories in turn.

Based on this the most frequent rejection comments were as follows: drafting-related defects 49.5%, non-compliance with the Iranian national building codes 15%, discrepancy between architectural and structural plans 10%, non-compliance with the extra technical requirements of the local office of the IRCEO 7% and the defects based on the architectural control official&amp;rsquo;s discretion 6.5%. In the next step, some statistical patterns were extracted from the reports, which comprised seven patterns. In order to analyze the statistical findings and achieve a reliable interpretation of the patterns, interviews were conducted with eight principals of architectural firms in Rasht. Finally, the patterns observed in architectural control reports were interpreted and their causes and suggested solutions were discussed. Each provincial office of the IRCEO can target specific indicators according to its architectural firms&amp;rsquo; conditions and, over time, improve its architectural design services standards. This paper ends up with a critique of the idea of abandoning the plan checking from the new suggested building control bylaw.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2384-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2384-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Comparative-Deductive analysis of location of construction of health tourism complex based on SOWT strategic model and AHP analytic hierarchy process (A case study Qom city)
</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>327</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>350</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Since the construction of the Health Tourism Complex is convenient for providing patients and companions for treatment, rest and recreation, it is very important in the tourism issue and it can be effective in raising the status of Iran among the countries of the region, and also if such plans are implemented. In the country, there will be significant foreign exchange earnings; on the other hand, the city of Qom, a city on the margin of the desert, and the host of countless pilgrims, has a lot of potential in this area, which is felt to be highly sought after. The question now is what are the criteria and criteria for locating health tourism complexes? How to get the optimal site for construction of health tourism complex in Qom? This article is aimed at establishing a health tourism complex in Qom metropolitan area. The research methodology is applied in terms of the descriptive-analytical and deductive-comparative nature which uses the SOWT strategy and the AHP hierarchy process to reach the optimal site, and the most suitable site is selected from the three suggested sites. In this way, designing, discovering and extracting ideas has been used and information resources and resource selection methods have been used through library, field visits, and Internet search, and Persian databases have been used to perform the search.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2385-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2385-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Investigation and modeling of land use changes in Khorramabad city by 1404 using MLP, MARKOV and CA-MARCOV models</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>351</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>368</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>The purpose of this study was to survey and model the land use change in Khorramabad city. For this purpose, using three Landsat satellite images of years 1986, 2001 and 2016, the cover and land cover classes have been extracted from Khorramabad city and around it. Overall classification accuracy for image corresponding to the year 1365, 93/89, 1380, and 34/91 of 1395, 62/95 percent is obtained. In order to model the land use changes in Khorramabad, the input layers of elevation, slope, shadow, distance from the road, distance from the built area, distance from the agricultural land, distance from the forestland and the distance from the mountainous terrain were used. In the following, neural network models and CA-MARKOV are used to model and predict land use changes by the year 1404. The results show a high accuracy of 65% for modeling land use change in Khorramabad city. It should be noted that this precision is reasonable for predicting and modeling land-use changes that is dynamic, because in addition to the variables considered in this research and other studies, other factors such as municipal regulations, The land stock exchange, state-owned large-scale housing policies, and so on, will have an impact on land use change.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2386-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2386-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
	
		<Article>
		<Journal>
			<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
			<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
			<PISSN>1607-2227</PISSN>
			<EISSN></EISSN>
			<Volume>17</Volume>
			<Issue>53</Issue>
			<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
				<Year>2019</Year>
				<Month>3</Month>
				<Day>1</Day>
			</PubDate>
		</Journal>
			
		<ArticleTitle>Investigation of Reverse Logistics Management Dimensions in Urban Construction Projects (Multiple Case Study)</ArticleTitle>
		<FirstPage>369</FirstPage>
		<LastPage>386</LastPage>
		<Language>FA</Language>
		

	<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<MiddleName></MiddleName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	<AuthorEmails></AuthorEmails>
	 </Author>
	</AuthorList>
	<DOI></DOI>
	<Abstract>Proper resource management and recycling of debris are principles of the concept of sustainable development. The construction industry recognized as one of the most important aspects of damage to the environment and society. This situation is due to the lack of attention and deficiency in waste management and the lack of proper management of materials. Reverse Logistics (RL) is a concept that has been considered to solve this problem in recent decades. But evidence is that, this important concept of management is not sufficiently understood in Iran, and its benefits are not sufficiently used in construction projects.

In this study, using a multiple case study strategy level of familiarity of experts from RL was examined through in-depth interviews with stakeholders in case studies, and the extent of implementation of this concept was examined in the projects, the most important managerial deficiencies are also identified. The results indicate that industry stakeholders have not had a clear understanding of the concepts and methods of implementing RL in projects. However, they are unknowingly implementing some aspects of it during the construction process. This lack of awareness along with the lack of proper infrastructure and other factors presented in this study has made the RL's effectiveness is insignificant in the construction projects of the country.
</Abstract>
	<Keywords></Keywords>

			<URLs>
				<abstract>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2387-en.html</abstract>
				<Fulltext>
					<pdf>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-2387-en.pdf</pdf>
				</Fulltext>
			</URLs>
			
			
	</Article>
 </ArticleSet>
 
  
  
  
  
 