<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>52</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تبیین نقش طرحواره‌های ذهنی مکانی- اجتماعی در احساس آرامش ساکنین حاشیه سبز بزرگراه‌های درون‌شهری (نمونه موردی: بزرگراه مدرس)</title_fa>
	<title>Relationship between Social-Spatial Mental Schema and Observers' Tranquility in Urban Green Highways (Case Study: Modarres Highways)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;آرامش روانی از جمله عواملی مهم در برنامه&amp;shy;ریزی&amp;shy;های یک طراحی مطلوب می&amp;shy;باشد. توجه به مولفه&amp;shy;های تاثیرگذار در آرامش روانی بزرگراه شهری مانند ایجاد عواملی چون وجود جداره سبز، میزان بالا بودن امنیت در محل، میزان اعتماد به همسایگان و .... می تواند از اهمیت بالایی برخوردار باشد. شکل&amp;shy;گیری طرحواره&amp;shy;های مکانی و اجتماعی همگرا در ذهن شهروندان یکی از اصلی&amp;shy;ترین عوامل ایجاد آرامش روانی ساکنین حاشیه بزرگراه می باشد. هدف این مقاله بررسی عوامل و مولفه&amp;shy;های موثر بر ایجاد آرامش روانی از طریق همگرا ساختن طرحواره&amp;shy;های مکانی و اجتماعی است. روش تحقیق پژوهش شامل روش&amp;shy;های توصیفی- تحلیلی و&amp;nbsp; پیمایشی است. جامعه اماری ساکنین محلات متصل به حاشیه بزرگراه مدرس می&amp;shy;باشد. تکنیک&amp;shy;های تحلیل شامل تحلیل آماری توصیفی و استنباطی است. یافته&amp;shy;های پژوهش نشان می&amp;shy;دهد، در طرحی بزرگراه&amp;shy;های درون شهری توجه به طرحواره های مکانی- اجتماعی یکی از اصلی ترین مولفه های برای ایجاد محیط هایی ارامش بخش برای ساکنین بافت ها و محلات متصل به بزرگراه است. ولی آرامش الزما منجر به تشکیل طرحواره های همگرا و تقویت کننده در ذهن و روان ساکنین نمی&amp;shy;گردد. سن و جنسیت تاثیر آنچنانی بر نحوه و نوع طرحواره&amp;shy;های ذهنی مکانی- اجتماعی در طراحی بزرگراه&amp;shy;های درون شهری ندارند و افرادی که دارای تحصیلات بالاتری هستند می توانند بهتر محیط را درک کنند.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;The aim of this article is to investigate the relationship between the observers&amp;rsquo; tranquility and creating mental schemas in the corridor of the green urban highway. Tranquility is the one that can cause memories and sense of belonging by locating in mind. Being unique and criterion cause quick images to remain in minds and these elements cause the space to become an indicator of spatial identity. To become a tranquiller and memorable space and to remain in minds some schemes should be created in minds and this is the fundamental condition. Furthermore, the space should have a definite and unique identity. Statistical analysis included descriptive and inferential techniques. The findings show that, in designing the urban highways paying attention to spatial-social schemas is one of the main components for generating tranquil of highway margin by criteria. According to the results of the analysis of experimental findings, it seems that considering spatial-social schemes are one of the main components of creating a reliable and tranquil environment for bystanders who visit routes such as highways. According to the results of this study, there is a linear relationship and a high correlation between tranquility and creating mental spatial and social schemes. It means to make a space tranquil and memorable some schemes should be created in minds to make the space effective and persistent. Several sequences and focus points in the special parts can lead us to have a convergence mental schema.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>آرامش روانی, طرحواره‌های ذهنی, حاشیه سبز, بزرگراه درون شهری, یکپارچگی  </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Tranquility for Observers, Mental Schema, Green Corridors, Green Urban Highway</keyword>
	<start_page>49</start_page>
	<end_page>63</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1816-86&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>نگین سادات </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مقدسی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008999</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008999</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
