<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.0//EN" "http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov:80/entrez/query/static/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Effect of Thermal Hydrolysis on Anaerobic Digester Performance</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>7</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>13</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad Ali</FirstName>
	<LastName>Abdoli</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Leila</FirstName>
	<LastName>Amiri</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Naser</FirstName>
	<LastName>Mehrdadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Zohreh</FirstName>
	<LastName>Tarahomi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Anaerobic digestion (AD) has been recently introduced as a promising technology for producing bioenergy around the world. Due to its especial characteristics, solid waste could be considered as a proper feedstock in the digester. Retention time (RT) and rate of biogas production are two major parameters affecting the efficiency of the process. The AD procedure of biogas production consists of hydrolysis, acid genesis, acetogenesis, and methanogens such that feeding materials would be processed inside the digester. The experiments have been carried out using two bioreactors with volume of 5 liters in mesopihilic conditions at 35 ± 1°C. The purpose of this study is to accelerate the hydrolysis step. Pretreatment of the waste is accomplished using thermal hydrolysis in conditions of 155°C and 5 atm. The results of this research indicated 33.33% decrease in RT and 154.87% increase in amount of biogas production using pretreatment process in comparison without considering it.</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Revisiting Missing Identity Ring of Iranian cities (A spatial Temporal Analysis of square Elements in Islamic Architecture and urbanism)</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>15</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>29</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammadreza</FirstName>
	<LastName>Bemanian</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Abbas</FirstName>
	<LastName>Hoseinzadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Amir Ehsan</FirstName>
	<LastName>Pooyan</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>
From long ago, square has been considered as a space for performing area of cities, and it has been a factor determining the identity of cities through its design and structures. However, with the growth of cities and arrival of modernity management challenges are facing cities. Accordingly, cities have gradually changed into a place for predicting different types of technological, conceptual, and social solutions. These factors have embedded their objective manifestation in the body of Iranian cities along with Persian – Islamic architect and urbanism and put in place a new form of urban spaces. In the meantime we are witnessing that past function of spaces such as squares previously used to be considered as an open space and an element indication the spatial – physical coordination of activities, has changed and gained new appearances. The present paper seeks to investigate the factors such as changes in visual and motor space, new civil relations and stimuli speed in three steps. Including: 1- ideal space, 2- movement space, and 3- visual space in forms of square as an element for gathering, square as an element for passage and square as a missing ring, Moreover, factors affecting the survival or destruction of this missing ring of Islamic architecture and urbanism will be analyzed. Also identify – causing factors in spatial analysis of square and the role of theoretical knowledge in understanding instances of Identity will be making clear. 
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Effect of social traffic behavior on traffic violation the case study of Tehran </ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>31</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>43</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mehdi</FirstName>
	<LastName>Ameri</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>
Current standards in microscopic modeling lack the ability to address certain traffic scenarios, the ability to capture discrete differences in driver behavior that exist between various driving populations, and are structured in such a fashion that various vehicle movements are predicted and modeled separately. In this study, effect of social traffic behavior on rate of traffic violation of Tehran citizens becomes a model from the viewpoint of Sociology. Creation of model in this study has been done by questionnaire from 415 persons who refer the Police+10 (the organization of local police) to obtain their vehicle violation ticket. In this study, social traffic behavior defined as drivers' obligation measure to traffic laws that includes social and cultural aspects. Social Anomie, social capital and social assurance are social index aspect. Model shaping effect of mass media and social-cultural station of persons considered as cultural aspects. Conceptual model shows that elements, which studied in research as one part of elements, which is related to humans, are only 42 percent effective in traffic violation. Results of research shows elements like sexuality and education are main elements, inefficient laws component and lack of social justice are elements of social Anomie in social aspect, social-cultural station index and component of primary groups affected by model shaping in cultural aspect index have a great connection with traffic violation in Tehran city.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Value-Oriented Policy Taking and Contextual Architecture in Historical Context</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>45</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>63</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Maryam</FirstName>
	<LastName>Esmaeel Dokht</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohsen</FirstName>
	<LastName>Feizi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>
Today, the field-oriented architecture of the historical context of the most important topics in the field of architecture Because of the inherent value and practical concepts and is directly related to the knowledge, awareness and decision-making at the individual or individuals. No matter how much knowledge is more valuable than the deeper, more complete and more accurate will be extracted and derived values. Changing attitudes regarding the social and historical monuments for survival is necessary. Lack of understanding of the sport's interventions in some cases, not only does not represent the values, but many of the values of cultural monuments were removed. This is discussed in relation to the value of the intervention is necessary. This paper is an analytical technique that is used by documents. This paper seeks to find a connection with the application architecture in historical works and cultural values may be field-oriented evaluation. The first step is to identify record and determine the value of monuments begins Understanding and recognition of the value of the direct relationship with the identification of and intervention practices.   In the end the field orientation and policy recommendations in relation to the values and areas for intervention in historical contexts of reference have been discussed.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Contemporery Urban Development and Sustainable Urban Form </ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>65</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>73</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<LastName>Safavi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Sustainable settlement is one of the key constituents of sustainable development, and sustainable urban development can be defined in this framework. Emergence of sustainable development as a commonly-used phrase has caused several controversies about urban forms. Today’s urban form is known as a source of environmental problems. Undoubtedly, this phrase has persuaded many of researchers to search for several forms of human’s settlement forms which provide sustainable conditions and enable the environments built to play their role in a more constructive manner than the past. This article defines a general framework to reach a sustainable urban form after discussing the main constituents of sustainable urban development and its relation to urban form, and finally, determines 7 design aspects in relation to sustainable urban forms compactness, sustainable transportation, density, usage combination,  variety, form of residential area, and green space.</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Introduction to Roof garden Strategy in Architectural Design and City</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>75</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>88</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ferial</FirstName>
	<LastName>Sadat Siadati</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyyed Mostafa</FirstName>
	<LastName>Mokhtabad Amrei</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>
The roof garden has great functioning of smoothing the shortage of land resource in the city and making use of the land resource diversity and efficiently. The modern era, following the fast development of economic and society, people have a high claim to green roof or roof garden. It is an efficient and reasonable way to exploit the open space the roof of the building. From the classic roof garden of the world, we can find out that roof garden has close relationship with the building. Roof garden is different with other kind landscape in the city it needed cooperation of landscape architect and architect from at the stages of design, construction, upholding and management. We should attach importance to roof garden in the construction of building. But the research works, policies and laws about the green roof and roof garden were not developed so fast to catch up with the development of economic and society. So many contradictions have appeared. In this paper, all the contradictions were picked and dissected, and the ways to solve them were given: 1. The technique and design ways of the working team should be trained, 2. The whole process of a roof green's construction should be supervised by the government, 3. Laws and policies guide should be given, 4. Much more research work on roof green or roof garden should be done
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Phenomenological approach to the design process based on perceptions (Case Study Shiraz School for the Blind)</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>89</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>102</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Najmeh</FirstName>
	<LastName>Zebardastan</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Khosro</FirstName>
	<LastName>Movahed</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>
Researches and evaluation of the different ideas on the subject of design, the complexity of this field of science and providing perspective theories in this regard lead the experts to look deeper into the subject, thus creating descriptive opinions in this regard. Taking another look at this issue will lead the designers and architects to consider a targeted effort based on the knowledge as the practice criteria in their design process, by choosing an appropriate method to achieve the ultimate goal. In recent years, extensive research has been conducted on the theory of architecture and design methods. In this context, little research has also been done on sensory experiences of architectural environment which is driven from a kind of interdisciplinary approach, relying on the theory of architecture in the form of philosophical research, known as phenomenology. In order to achieve the goal of investigating the phenomenological paradigm and its impact on the design process and choosing the method of concretizing the space through design, this study has addressed the sensory perception by the phenomenological approach. Finally, investigating the effective turning points of this point of view in the chosen method of designers in the design process in the presented model is considered. This study was conducted in the form of field research and with regard to the selected sample, and the results of quantitative and qualitative data were formed and environmental qualities such as: analysis of favorable and unfavorable winds, the level of noise pollution in the environment, the effectiveness of good smell of plants and the unfavorable smell of the environment in the desired site were measured and the desired and undesired qualitative and quantitative factors of the environment were analyzed and IDW method was used to analyze them and they were integrated with each other using fuzzy logic. The results have been chosen as the standard practice in the design of Shiraz school for the Blind site.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Future study of Description System Architecture Approaches with Emphasis on Strategic Management </ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>103</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>124</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad Mehdi</FirstName>
	<LastName>Bolandian</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Sarah</FirstName>
	<LastName>Naseri</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>
Systems Architecture is a generic discipline to handle objects (existing or to be created) called systems, in a way that supports reasoning about the structural properties of these objects. Systems Architecture is a response to the conceptual and practical difficulties of the description and the design of complex systems. Systems Architecture is a generic discipline to handle objects (existing or to be created) called systems, in a way that supports reasoning about the structural properties of these objects. System architecting has been around since the Egyptians built the pyramids.  The pyramids presented an enormous number of problems for its designers due to the size of the structure, the lack of proper tools, and the need to make it a tomb fit for a god-king.  Now we are faced with similar problems of system complexity that has outstripped our system building techniques in the area of embedded computer systems.   Heuristics, models, and metaphors help architects abstract away complexity, but much of the difficulty in architecting lies in maintaining a unified vision of the system.  Having a unified vision makes it much easier to create safe, dependable, or fast systems.  Unfortunately, not everyone is a great system architect, and it may never be possible to teach someone all of the necessary skills.  This poses some fundamental limitations on the systems we can create.  
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Description Theory and Approach about Space Syntax Methodology in Urban Design Process</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>125</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>139</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyyad Manaaf</FirstName>
	<LastName>Hashemi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>
Nowadays space is considered to be a net of connections between different areas. The questions how to delineate its character and how it is possible to objectively compare two spaces is a matter under consideration. This was the reason for creating new theories about the structure of space. Space syntax analysis (SSA) or simply Space Syntax defines a number of theories and research areas devoted to the analysis of space configuration. One of the most important goals of Urban Design is to promote the quality of citizens' biological environment and their positive interaction with physical space of city. To achieve such a goal in urban design, a scenario is defined that that physically represents improvement of people's relationship toward each other and with urban spaces. To be sure about the performance of such a scenario is one of the decision – makers and designers main concerns. To achieve such a certainty, various methods such as artistic methods, social sciences and environmental psychology are used. Space syntax methodology is one of the methods that have been invented and completed during the recent decades. This method analyzes the configurative and syntactic relations between all the urban spaces and presents specifications of urban spaces graphically and by the mathematical parameters. Ongoing research and observations of the configuration of spatial settlements and human behavior within in the past years has shown a close relationship between the physical structure of space and the quality of life of its inhabitants. SSA is used as an academic and commercial tool to analyze projects on an urban and building scale. Based on the theory of space syntax, the standing order of spaces next to each other has a direct effect on the way of using the spaces. The analysis of urban space configuration, using the space syntax method and technique, enables urban design experts to make a model to predict behavior in urban spaces. We can make use of this model in urban design process and make an interactive relation with it. It is a tool of sustainable development used to study movement of space users, crime in the city, anti-social behavior, and economics. 
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Environment Security and Decrease of Crimes with CPTED Approach Critical and Analytical Discussion</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>141</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>163</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mehdi</FirstName>
	<LastName>Ameri</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>
Crime and the fear of crime are pervasive and endemic concerns in modern post-industrial society and criminal justice systems are clearly failing to tackle both issues. In this research after mentioning the abstract for motivation and the vital opinion in the security public, the role of city framework (programming the environmental design) in the decrease and prediction of crimes in the city in the function of CPTED. The meaning, principle, paradigms and the strategy function is mentioned. This issue is important in this way that today in the process of open space design in the city and potential of city buildings in decreasing or preventing crimes. The recent function can be designed in a suitable and proper way in a residential location in decreasing crimes the aim is to improve the quality of life and increase of citizen's support.  The recent survey is analyzed by documents and evidence. The use of this project is utilized to make a better residential location for the citizens. The result of this recent survey is analyzed by evidence and the experience of utilize and it can be attested that the city design from the average crime and crimes have been decrease, the use of this project is mentioned.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Using Solar Spatial Analyst to Calculate Global Solar Radiation, 22th Region of Tehran as the Case Study</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>179</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>188</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hoda sadat</FirstName>
	<LastName>Seyedrezaei</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Branch- Islamic Azad University</Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali Reza</FirstName>
	<LastName>Vafaeinezhad</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Branch- Islamic Azad University</Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Hamid Reza</FirstName>
	<LastName>Saremi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mohammad Ali</FirstName>
	<LastName>Nezam Mahaleh</LastName>
	<Affiliation>Tehran University</Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Solar Radiation is considered as an important parameter in modeling environmental, hydrologic and biophysical processes. One of the reasons that solar radiations are not extensively used in models is the problem of its measurement in different points. Solar Analyst Viewshed Algorithm makes possible calculation of the topographic effects on solar radiation at local and landscape scales. With respect to lack of LIDAR data and accurate and updated information, this article studies a modeled solar radiation and rate of radiation using GIS Solar Analyst Viewshed Algorithm and regarding DEM and metrological parameters regionally (District 22 of Tehran). Summary of the radiation statistics for July (maximum, minimum, and mean) for six sets of slopes and landscape in District 22 were analyzed. The results indicate that the southward slopes receive further radiation values than the northward ones during July. This will have a crucial role in architecture, urban development model, and photovoltaic installations.</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Iran National Identity in Malak –o – Shoara Bahar`s poetry</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>189</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>194</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Yoosef Aali</FirstName>
	<LastName>Abbas Abad</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>
Mohammad – Taqi Bahar had been living in a historical period of Iran in which religious, geographical boundaries, culture and Iran`s sovereignty were exposed to numerous threats. Indeed, he, as a pious patriot, had a complete knowledge about these issues and attentively took into consideration the national identity phenomenon in his books and poets.  They mostly consists the historical and political events of around a century ago, thoroughly depicts the attitudes, traditions and culture of the people who were living in that period of time. In this paper and survey of Divan the writer`s definition and his point of view about the national identity have been discussed. This article mainly focuses on those aspects of national identity that the author has put forward as one of the fundamental elements of identity.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Development and Assessing Life Quality Indices from the View points of zahedan Citizens</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>195</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>207</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali</FirstName>
	<LastName>Shoa Bar Abadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Jamal</FirstName>
	<LastName>Mohammadi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>

 From the birth of geography, life quality domain has been gained
attention by geographers and it has been emphasized by geographers like Smith
and Harvey and this issue has got so much significance recently.Present paper
is descriptive-analytical and it is aimed at assessing life quality indices in
thirteen districts of zahedan by examining 25 factors in three groups. The most
part of this research has been done in the form of survey through field studies
and questionnaire. The research population consists of all residents of
thirteen districts of zahedan. To analyze data, SPSS, EXCEL as well as Morris
Model, Lord Index and Cost Index have been employed. Findings indicate that
there is strong inequality in different districts of zahedan in terms of life
quality indices.  
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Exploring the infrastructures for establishment of electronic municipality (e-municipality) in metropolis city of Tabriz</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>209</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>221</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Reza</FirstName>
	<LastName>Rasooli</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Fatemeh</FirstName>
	<LastName>Mehdi Poor</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>
The purpose of this study is to explore infrastructures for establishment of electronic municipality in metropolis city of Tabriz. Thisis a descriptive survey and it is an applied one in terms of goal .Total sample consisted of total number of 120 employees in Statistics and Information Technology Department of municipality as well as those working in related sections to information technology in regional offices of municipality in 2014. Data were collected through researcher-made questionnaire according to Strategic Document of 2025 for municipality of Tabriz. This 51-question questionnaire is graded based on Likert spectrum from 1 to 5. Research findings show that infrastructures of strategic management, human resource training and service have not yet been provided for establishment of electronic municipality in Tabriz however, technical infrastructures (network and communication), hardware and support, software, applied systems, and information security are available for establishment of electronic municipality in Tabriz. Also, infrastructures of strategic management, human resource training, service and applications, network and communication, software and applied systems, hardware and support and network security were found to have a significant relationship with condition of electronic municipality establishment.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Representation of Tehran during Qajar reign (Naseri period) in French travelers’ travel journals</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>223</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>231</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Roohollah</FirstName>
	<LastName>Hoseini</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Asadollah</FirstName>
	<LastName>Mohammad Zadeh</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mehran</FirstName>
	<LastName>Shiravand</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>
Travel journals from different historical periods contain valuable insights that could be analyzed from different aspects and through that we can understand other people’s points of view about us. Description of different cities in travel literature represents French travelers’ views about these cities besides informing us about the quality and quantity of those cities at the times. “Representation of  Tehran during Qajar Dynasty’s reign in French travelers’ travel literature books” based on the three theories of Stuart Hall’s representation gives us insights into what is interesting in a traveler’s mind and also what “Tehran” looked like at the time, how it got improved and developed. This article is focused on how the original nucleus of “Tehran” was formed, its appearances, geography, weather historical buildings and how the cultural heritage has been represented in these travel literature books.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Assessment criteria and factors affecting the success of Public-Private Partnership (PPPs) in urban construction projects with an emphasis on Factor analysis and Pareto analysis</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>233</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>247</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyed Hassan</FirstName>
	<LastName>Parhizkar</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Vahid</FirstName>
	<LastName>Afshinmehr</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>In the present study, criteria and factors affecting the success of public-private partnership in urban construction projects was examined relying on the combined method (analytical and correlation). In the method, based on the literature and document review and subsequent utilizes a field study (case study, interviews with experts and distributed questionnaires) was an attempt to explore the research variables, their relationships are examined. In this way, with the help of descriptive and inferential statistics (parametric and nonparametric) and analysis of the &quot;correlation factor&quot; and &quot;Pareto&quot;, the research hypotheses through the software &quot;SPSS&quot; were tested and analyzed. In total, 48 factors were extracted from library studies and field surveys, but due to limitations of the survey (time, cost and measurement's quality) with comments the experts, 17 of the top factors influencing the success of public-private partnership has been selected and analyzed. 17 factors on the basis of descriptive, Inferential and Pareto tests were analyzed and have led to the ranking factors and identify critical factors (Pareto). Accordingly, the factors of &quot;fair distribution of risks between the project partners,&quot; &quot;spirit and sense of win-win among partners &quot;, &quot;long-term Cooperation and alliance between partners&quot; and &quot;Select the appropriate project finance and delivery system&quot; as Pareto factors were determined. The following, factors influencing the success of public-private partnership, based on the Pare factors to and factor correlations Analysis were analyzed. Accordingly, of the 17 persons in 4 criterion: &quot;risk&quot;, &quot;enterprise&quot;, &quot;process&quot; and &quot;contract&quot; were classified and mapping them with Pareto analysis, criterions of &quot;risk&quot; and &quot;contract&quot; as the basic criteria (Pareto) affecting the success of public-private partnership were determined. </Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Teaching Information literacy Skills for Training Programs to Higher Education with Emphasis on urban studies</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>249</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>255</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyyed Ali</FirstName>
	<LastName>Hoseini</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Shaahin</FirstName>
	<LastName>Hafezi Nejad</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>
This study aims to determine the need for teaching information literacy skills in the curriculum of higher education. From MA and doctoral students in urban studies, 380 samples were selected using stratified random sampling. In the process of gathering data translated Information Literacy Competency Standard Questionnaire for Higher Education by the American Library Association in 2000 approved, used and to analyze the results descriptive statistics were used. The results showed that there is a significant difference between the mean scores of T (inferential statistics ) MA and PhD student’s view test on the literacy information, but between the mean scores of two educational groups (humanities, in urban studies and technical).   There is not a significant difference between the mean scores of male and female students. Based on the findings facilities, educational content, quantity and quality are factors in self-learning and factors that caused differences or lack of differences and recommended that the curricula in higher education, most students considered information literacy capabilities.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Scrutiny the Qualitative and quantitative characteristics of Islamic Councils members in rurals of Bushehr County</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>257</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>267</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>hassan </FirstName>
	<LastName>heidari</LastName>
	<Affiliation>ostandari bushehr</Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>masoud</FirstName>
	<LastName>mahdavi</LastName>
	<Affiliation>university</Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>patviz</FirstName>
	<LastName>kardavani</LastName>
	<Affiliation>university</Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>   Local affairs and ensuring the welfare of the village as a desirable habitat for most people is a task The charge is based Dhyarys and according to law, public affairs, directly involved and of course Dhyarys legal entity, financial and administrative autonomy and property, funds and revenues, rights and specific duties and honors of the state. In this context, the role of village councils no secret . In this study, we have investigated the characteristics of Islamic Councils in the rural city of Bushehr, with a descriptive approach . This study aimed to identify qualitative and quantitative trends Council last three periods (second, third and fourth respectively). The findings show Decreasing age, increasing the role of women in village councils, more specialized work by increasing the number of people with higher education, higher education, council members and increase the average number of Islamic Councils has 5 members . The study was presented Proposals such as increasing the powers of councils, creating a bridge between city and rural Councils considering the findings in order to share experiences and Rural Management Training Program for Rural Councils . </Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>An Overview of the Civil Liability of the Modern State (Concept, Resources, Foundations)</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>269</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>288</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mehdi</FirstName>
	<LastName>Baalavi</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Mahnaz</FirstName>
	<LastName>Bayat Komitaki</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName>Seyyed Salman</FirstName>
	<LastName>Samani</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Modern state is conceptually and subjectively complicated as per the wide range of concepts and subjects related to it, therefore the context is provided to present the viewpoints on its identity and nature. Based on this, human sciences Scientifics investigate it from different perspectives. Complexity of the nature of modern State, arises the various theories around it, despite bring serious challenges to the argument of knowing it. Moreover, emergence of outstanding changes in the area of law and politics, specifically human rights dialogue in modern political philosophy, and thereto formation of political order based on the rightful person, has changed the Westphalia nature of State to a responsible and committed State giving role and orientation to the rightful person. Therefore, the specific Function of the State is to protect people&amp;rsquo;s basic rights and freedoms, which based on the responsibility of that State is defined. In this article, after short analysis of the concept of State in the shadow of the changes of the contemporary age, nature and principals of civil responsibility of the State is studied.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>14</Volume>
<Issue>38</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2015</Year>
<Month>6</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Theoretical review and Planning process of the Relation between Environment, Spatial Justice and Urban Governance</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>290</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>303</LastPage>
	<Language>EN</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName>Ali Akbar</FirstName>
	<LastName>Taqvaee</LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>The concept of spatial justice has been widely employed in the recent literature that attempts to deal with concepts and practices of justice from a geographical perspective. However, the concept of spatial justice needs to be recast. Spatial justice could be the most radical offspring of law&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;spatial turn&amp;rsquo;. Spatial justice is arguably the most promising platform on which to redefine, not only the connection between law and geography but, more importantly, the conceptual foundations of both law and space. The current literature has defined spatial justice as simply a geographically informed version of social justice. Law&amp;rsquo;s spatial turn presents two opportunities: first, to rethink of the law&amp;rsquo;s spatiality, namely the novel unpredictability of geographical space that has now flowed into law. And second, to reclaim the concept of spatial justice from a socially diffusing, geographically applied concept of regionalism, while also making a case for it from within the law. This is a radical and novel research area which will be expected to address issues such as: What is the connection between law and justice from a geographical perspective? Is spatial justice merely a version of social/distributive justice? By theorizing spatial justice, I hope to develop an analytical framework that is gaining ground in urban planning and geography, yet remains theoretically undeveloped. I hope to extend an insight at the heart of environmental justice the places we live, work, and play have a profound effect on the social relations among us, and hence the justice relations among us. By extending this analysis to space more generally, I hope to give a new language to theorists of environment, justice, and contemporary political conflicts.
</Abstract>


</Article>
</ArticleSet>
