<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.0//EN" "http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov:80/entrez/query/static/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Determining Iranian Islamic Influential Factors and Indicators in the balanced Development of Khorasan Razavi Province using Mic Mac Software</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>7</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>30</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Basic attention to ecological, economical, physical, social, and cultural justice in programming and its adjustment in the Islamic justice framework leads to building a fair society and the advancement and the balanced development in all aspects, areas, groups and different geographical regions of the country. The present study aims to explain and to identify the Iranian Islamic influential factors and indicators in the balanced development of Khorasan Razavi province. The type of the research is practical and developmental and its method of investigation is descriptive- analytic and survey. The statistical population involves geographical, economical and social experts. The sample size includes 120 questionnaires that are gathered based on random sampling technique. Methods of data collection are library based and field based (questionnaire). To analyze the data, structural analysis method and MICMAC software were used. Balanced distribution of population indicator in the spatial organization (ecological justice component) with the direct impact rate of (250) and indirect impact rate of (247) and appropriate and equal access indicator of the residents of urban and rural settlements to roads, hospitals, schools and ... (physical justice component) with the direct impact rate of (241) and indirect impact rate of (239) are considered as effective key factors and indicators in balanced development of Khorasan Razavi province. As can be inferred from the results cultural promotion indicator based on genuine Islamic-Iranian identity and avoiding the acceptance of foreign patterns (cultural justice component) with very high influence from other indicators and very low impact on other indicators was known as the richest Iranian Islamic indicator. The results indicate that most of the Iranian Islamic indicators are influential in the balanced development of the Khorasan Razavi province and if they are considered and implemented in the plans, they can influence resources allocation with the aim of eliminating regional inequalities and creating a more balanced development.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Urban management model in the fight against urban vandalism; Case district 20 in Tehran</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>31</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>56</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>All societies with different extents in some way involved with aspects of urban vandalism and negative consequences of this damage. Daily life of every citizen in dealing with behavioral manifestations associated Vandalistic. To understand the causes of these behaviors can be partially affirmative action to prevent or control of it. It may be another parallel social behavior under the effects of abuse and injustice felt that sense of deprivation is linked to the issue. In this article is to answer the following questions: How well-designed urban landscape and social ills in the region 20 Vandal presence in urban space control? The relationship between the urban landscape and vandalism in the area under study is how? Urban landscape management system and its related institutions and organizations how they can reduce these behaviors affect in the study area and to reduce it? In the end, a strategy for urban management model in the fight against urban vandalism is mentioned.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>The Necessity of Studio Education in Empowering the Urban Planning Students for Applying the Knowledge through Constructivism Learning Models</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>57</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>72</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>The gap between profession and education in many courses of study is due the fact that the learned knowledge in the universities is not practical. Considering the collation of theory and practice in teaching the students, the urban planning has provided the opportunity for the students to evaluate and analyze their acquired knowledge in the theoretical classes and organize them as mental constructs and then apply them in practical studios, as semi-real situations. Therefore, the main shortcoming of urban planning students in their professions is the knowledge transfer in the process of education. Empowering the students regarding transferring their knowledge is highly essential because the profession environments have been very competitive and the employers aim to employ professional work force. The benefits, necessity, and the importance of having practical education in urban planning curricula and the expected qualities from urban planning practical studios were examined first by urban planning teaching theoreticians and then were studied through constructivism learning models and finally the main strategies were proposed from constructivism learning models.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Explain the theory of “citizen dialogue” and “communicative action” in recognition of the “public space” based on the ideas of Habermas</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>73</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>94</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>The public sphere is based on the analysis of the relationship between the three key categories of citizenship Habermasian the done through text-based approach to hermeneutics way (Ricoeur) and Development - disclosed (Heidegger) and critical (Habermas) has been made. This article elaborates on the political philosophy of Habermas's theory of citizenship interview. The research method is descriptive - analytical and logical reasoning. Which is the tool library studies and documents; The ability to explain the theory of communicative action concept of citizen dialogue and provide it in. A central role in identifying public areas in the city. The findings indicate that, Habermas social action task for internal communication through dialogue and not by factors external to the formal understanding of the agreement. As a result, actors, dialogue, both morally obliged to fulfill the duties of citizens are. And ensure the realizations of the right of other citizens are.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>The role of vegetation in the quality of life of citizens (Case study: Gorgan)</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>95</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>118</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Evaluate vegetation is the most fundamental problems in cities for future planning and urban management is done on project implementation. The aim of this study was to analyze the role of urban green space to improve the quality of life of the citizens of the city of Gorgan. Methodology in two phase&amp;rsquo;s field observation method is descriptive-analytic. And went on to collect the data required by the questionnaire have been used. The study population is all citizens of Gorgan Cochrane sampling using a sample size of 328 were determined. To enhance the accuracy of the sample rose to 330 people. Furthermore in order to indicate the level of access and distribution of urban green spaces and ranking of the factors studied TOPSIS model was used.&amp;nbsp; As well as to generate maps to assess the level and quality of life of citizens of the relationship between vegetation and geographic information systems (GIS), is used. Continue to assess the relationship between effective factors on quality of life and vegetation help of SPSS statistical test was taken. The results indicate that the individual elements in the access to and quality of life there is significant relationship vegetation. It was found that in all urban areas with a level of enjoyment and desirability of Gorgan in terms of access to and quality of life are vegetation. At the end of the map to show the level of enjoyment and utility of the city of Gorgan is drawn.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Review and prioritize the barriers of knowledge management in the company holding the country Airports with AHP process</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>119</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>134</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Successful implementation of knowledge management in an organization requires that various organizational factors, certain features of coherence and coordination are necessary. And there are gaps and inconsistencies between these factors hinder the successful implementation of knowledge management, will be. &amp;nbsp;Thus, for successful implementation of knowledge management, organization as a whole needs to be looked at and considered all these factors and their status in the organization are identified and analyzed. This paper explores the barriers to knowledge management, Airports Holding Country in country, paid, and then will be prioritized. After evaluation techniques available to achieve a response, Analytic Hierarchy Process as the most suitable method was selected. To determine the priority of hierarchical analysis, comparison matrix formed and compared to determine their compatibility using the formula rate adaptation, adjustment range, all comparisons were calculated. The results confirmed that the pair comparison is carried out, the adjustment was appropriate. The final results of the main obstacles to prioritize proves that in order to measure cultural factors, human factors, technical factors, external factors and structural factors are the degree of priority. Five obstacles in order of preference, lack of planning and implementing activities in the field of culture and exchange of knowledge, lack of confidence based on knowledge sharing environment, lack of adequate support for the activities of the organizational culture creation and transfer of knowledge, lack of senior management support knowledge management and lack of access to information and knowledge, organizations are required by the national and international level.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Survey on Tehran subway company communication network and review of topology structure of metropolitan network</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>135</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>146</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>The structure of communication network systems for public transport and fixing it can always help to improve municipal services. One of the most widely used means of public transport in the city of Tehran subway lines. In this study, to verify the correct way subway network, standards of service and increased stability Networking with other organizations promoting stability and security and increased bandwidth and upgrade monitoring and control service is intended. Using the above criteria, two approaches &amp;ldquo;by increasing the active equipment optimization&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;increase passive products&amp;rdquo; have been examined and compared. A questionnaire was used to collect data. After distributing questionnaires among experts subways, using statistical analysis, the effect of each of the criteria listed in the two methods have been investigated&amp;nbsp;and finally the results and recommendations are provided.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Intertextual relationship of sence of place with an emphasis on originality cities urban restoration and valuation tissue</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>147</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>170</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>texture of the cities is a meaning and a special meaning which does change and social and cultural representations of its inhabitants. On the other hand, textures and buildings of ancient architecture in historic cities seen what they are but what they experience. In other words originality tissue and restoration are received in the sense that transcends architectural appearance and texture of dimensions Conscious and unconscious behavior is hidden dimensions and involves humans. The analytical method and the method of logical reasoning to the authenticity of the tissue cities will be discussed. And the associated restoration of architectural monuments and values of tissue especially like to emphasize the conceptual values. The need for urban restoration period, the sense of place and belonging to a place of meaningful aspects of historical context and its impact on the authenticity of valuation to weave through restoration and approaches are discussed. And Operational and strategic solutions in this field are discussed, which can provide authenticity tissues during restoration interventions.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Model of Intellectual Capital Bank on Social Security organization</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>171</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>192</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>The present study aimed to provide the intellectual capital of the bank was carried out in Social Security. Research methodology, in terms of practical purpose and from the perspective of descriptive survey method (interstitial) is. The population in this study, all senior managers in social security organizations, which number about 500 people; The sample size of 217 was calculated according to the formula Cochran. The measurement instrument was a questionnaire to assess the validity and content validity by experts calculate the validity and relevance of the questions and the components were confirmed. The Cronbach's alpha coefficient was used to assess reliability. The result of the study showed that alpha coefficient of reliability is calculated equal to 0.881. And considering that it is larger than 0.7, it can be concluded that the questionnaire of management reliability is necessary. To analyze the data descriptive statistics of frequency, percentage, cumulative percentage, mean and standard deviation and inferential statistics, independent t-test, ANOVA and structural equation modeling was used. In this research, intellectual capital into three categories: human capital, structural capital (organizational) and customer capital is divided. The results showed that human capital and intellectual capital bank employees a significant and positive impact. Structural capital is also positive and significant impact on the Bank's employees, intellectual capital and relational capital is the intellectual capital of the bank staff is positive and significant impact.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Measurement and prioritization of social capital in city district by utilization of Multi criteria decision models, TOPSIS and GIS, case study: Sari</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>193</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>208</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Social capital as a social merit has an important role in mobility and growth of urban places by considering urban di strict and study of existing capacities in order to reinforce and revive of important applications of social capital elements. We can provide a point support for social-base development. In this study we analyses space distribution of social capital in urban districts of sari and evaluate impressive indices in identify of public places of sari. Study method is descriptive action analytical which its data are collected by questionnaire. Statistical population consists of 383 families from 20 districts of Sari. TOPSIS models were used for ranking and valuation of district enjoyment amount (score) Hierarchical &amp;ndash; cluster end analysis model with ward algorithm were used for scrutiny of findings. Used models were weigh teal by Shannon entropy and map of urban districts ranking was drawn by ARC GIS software. Results show that there is a difference among sari districts in terms of social capital in dices enjoyment. TOPSIS method show that district 9 has the most and district 11 has the least one located in homophonous clusters that 11 districts are in first, second and third, cluster and 9 districts are in second and third cluster. Also among social capital indices, citizen satisfaction (23.95) has the most and feeling of security index (51/15) has the least amount in urban districts.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Check the rule of law, justice and civil justice in its relationship with citizen participation for women</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>209</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>224</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>It seems at the moment to achieve the modern definition of the concept of civil justice and citizenship; women need new approaches to have some legal conceptions of justice. On the issue of civil justice and citizenship is very important due to several factors: characteristics of rights, non-discrimination, balance, moderation, respect for competencies and entitlements. In addition to these measures focus on education as a means to empower civil justice is very important human development on a massive scale. This means that the quality of education and the distribution of and access to free education in the country is planned and implemented. And yet awareness is also high.&amp;nbsp; Therefore, this article discusses the rule of law, justice and social justice criteria, application and its role in civil justice are women. Has a clearer sense of justice for women to obtain citizenship; and the necessary solutions to achieve this kind of justice to be considered.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Troubleshooting form-rise buildings using parametric design process and compare the output optimized form in terms of radiation exposure</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>225</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>238</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Historically, has always been dependent on technological advances is the development of high-rise buildings; One of the remarkable technologies, use of computers for analysis of complex structural systems and its ability to produce construction documents. However, digital tools to help in the design of innovative forms of tall buildings comparable to the achievements. In this paper consists of two parts. First produced in the form of high-rise buildings and innovative design process using digital tools based on parametric design approach will be discussed. That purpose is to determine the variable and function.&amp;nbsp; And then taking advantage of genetic algorithm and programming environment Grasshopper trying to write a program to create optimal form in terms of direct solar light. To confirm the results, the optimum forms of various parameters are compared with each other using extensions Ladybug. The purpose of this article is merged with digital architecture to achieve optimal forms.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Explaining indices of flexible urban space design using Delphi model</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>239</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>264</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Today knowledge of urban spaces and suitable urban design of them is a way to meet the diverse needs of citizens. In the meantime, consideration of the principle of flexibility as one of the factors creating quality urban space enables space to provide the numerous options to citizens. However, in this study, which has an exploratory nature, attempted to explain the concept of flexibility and ways of its realization in the urban space, and also a model is presented in order to achieve flexibility in the urban space. The attainment of this space, with the flexibility indices first need preconditions, which include permeability, diversity, and readability. For this purpose, first qualitative data was collected using library studies and a review of the literature, the most important elements involved in the flexible design of urban space were identified; then by Delphi method, and by means of a questionnaire, and based on the snowball method, components were measured. The results indicate the more effective roles of 17 indices in the formation of flexible urban space. According to the ranking table, indices of compatibility of performances, flexibility, and more choice and greater attention to human relationships and access were more important.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Review implementation of urban development plans in the spatial organization (Case study: coastal city of Babolsar)</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>265</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>276</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>This study examines the implementation of urban development projects on the spatial organization of the coastal city of Babolsar. Therefore, in terms of analytical and descriptive research method in terms of purpose is applied. To collect data from studies library-documents through the analysis of Article 5 of Commission reports and 100 in an 11-year period (1384 to 1394) as well as field surveys, interviews have taken place. The findings indicate that the total area of 1652 hectares Babolsar, a coastal city about 60 hectares through unauthorized density, land use changes and separation, has undergone major changes. City plans conflict with the principles of the people. The results confirm the hypothesis presented, showed that the three main elements (public sector, private sector and the public sector) as operator of the space agency directly and indirectly influenced the changes in Babolsar. Given the dependence of Babolsar city management revenue increased density, this trend has continued from 1385 to 1393; But in 1394 declined and is oriented towards the resolution of land. The increased density in the neighborhood of 16 Babolsar not the same and most of the neighborhood was the prime minister.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Study cultural factors - social impact on the use of social networks (users aged 18 to 30 years in Varamin)</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>277</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>290</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Researcher at the research efforts that cultural-social factors influencing the use of social network users aged 18 to 30 Varamin telegram to the measure; The theoretical basis of social network sites (Giddens, McLuhan's theory, theory of public sphere, the Internet and social networks as public domain, uses and gratifications theory, theory of scarcity, a virtual social theory and the theory of Howard Glock and Stark's religiosity) and research, social and cultural factors affecting usage were identified. These factors include ethnicity, religion, socioeconomic status, religion and education. After developing a theoretical model of a sample of 385 members in the town of Varamin was purposive sampling. It was found that among the variables of ethnicity, socioeconomic status, religion and education a person with the use of cable networks there is a significant relationship; And no significant relationship between religion and usage.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Modeling the spatial decision support systems to manage the crisis before the earthquake, with a view to achieving sustainable development; Case Study: Zanjan City</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>291</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>304</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Earthquake is one of the most important natural phenomena which we face it in Iran considering our situation with regard to faults. Planning for readiness to confront Consequences of earthquake is in work instruction of urban planners.to control crisis and decrease damages, crisis management are executed. Crisis management is one of the approaches of sustainable urban management.in crisis management and critical sustainable, decision making is very important. Therefore in this article with using of spatial decision support system (SDSS) vulnerability of Zanjan city to earthquake for executing crisis management before earthquake has being studied. Zanjan is one of the northern province of Iran which regard to geology maps, is one of the earthquake regions in our country. Components of using system in this project include: data base, (geographical information system), spatial analysis model (vulnerability model) and decision making quantities strategic planning matrix (Q.S.P.M). Effective variables in physical pathology in this study include: vulnerability of availability of open space, buildings density, the average components area and grading, buildings materials, buildings antiquity, physical structure and land using. At the end each of these variables based on their importance factors in GIS will be overlapping and final pathology map will be provided. Results shows regard to pathology over than 55 percent of Zangan s area is highly vulnerable to earthquake and the highest vulnerability relates to mineral fabrics that include district 1 and 2 and part of district 3 and 5 of zanjan. Eventually with regard to final goal of (SDSS) which is decision making, we use quantities strategic planning matrix (Q.S.P.M) to prioritize strategies for executing in highly vulnerable regions to earthquake.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>The relationship between good governance and client satisfaction with the state of South Khorasan province</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>305</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>320</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>In public administration, principles of good governance as one of the aspects of the new paradigm are the special emphasis on the role of government in providing and delivering high quality services to the client and the various groups and satisfy them. Given the importance of client satisfaction and the implementation of the characteristics of good governance in government agencies, the aim of this study was to investigate the relationship between good governance and state agencies to determine the client's satisfaction. These research methods, descriptive and correlational; Managers and experts from government agencies (310) and their client were considered as population. Multi-stage cluster sampling, 172 experts and managers and to random sampling, 384 clients, formed the sample. For data collection, the researcher client questionnaire (18 questions) and good governance standard questionnaire (35 items); the information gathered by descriptive and inferential statistics (correlation coefficient and Friedman) were analyzed by statistical software spss20. The results showed that in total there was a significant correlation between good governance and client satisfaction. In evaluating the measures of good governance, transparency only between the client satisfactions a significant inverse relation was observed. In the rest of the subscales of good governance (result-oriented roles effectiveness, enhance the value, capacity building and accountability) There was no significant relationship with client satisfaction.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>A revision at tourism impression on Qum cultural and social evolutions</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>321</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>338</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Tourism as a profitable and the most important of all as a means of international communication among different nations and races in the world and also people familiarization with each other has always been noted by all countries. Tourism is considered as economic and cultural strategy in postmodern and civility time and leaves a great impression on society cultural and social environment and depends on the situation,&amp;nbsp; in return each society and can affect or be affected by tourism. In the recent years and being located in center of Iran and tourism growth due to holding holy shrine of here excellency Masoomeh (peace be upon her and her family) and also Jamkaran Mosque,&amp;nbsp; Qum city&amp;nbsp; has attracted 18 -20 million tourists from Iran and all over the world. The presented research has noted tourism impression on Qum people&amp;lsquo;s culture and society. This research has been conducted based on questionnaires whish were randomly&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; distributed among different cultural groups and the data gained from questionnaires were analyzed using SPSS software. After analyzing the data it was determined that Qum has been affected by tourists&amp;rsquo; relationship, outfit and communications and there is a meaningful relationship between these tourists&amp;rsquo; features and Qum&amp;rsquo;s people&amp;rsquo;s hospitality morale and city hygiene.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Semiotic theories of architecture and city reflected in readings</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>339</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>350</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>What we know today as architectural semiotics sub-field of semiotics and art in its shadow, no independent representation. Based on the theoretical concepts of architecture and alignment with the ideology of linguistic and semiotic need to explain the evident architectural semiotics explains. In this paper we analyzed the relationship between architecture and semiotics. Each social context (such as architecture), which carries a set of messages and relationships within the text by codes transmitted to the audience. These symptoms are encoded by the creator and reader (audience) on the basis of the social contract, subjective perception and point of view to decode the meaning of the text (Architecture) tries. Structuralist and post-structuralist semiotics provides two views. Signs to direct structural relationship between text and meaning are known. In contrast, post-structuralist semioticians, indirect relationship between text and knowledge and to explore the implication of their relations; in this paper, theories of semiotics, reading Architecture (text) from two perspectives about the analogy has been mentioned. The main focus of research on the meaning of architectural representation, which is composed of multiple layers of meaning, is. Meaning layers of float design and metaphorically, ironically, reflections and so on are intimate. Semiotic reading of architecture, to reproduce plan is based on the relationship between film and audience perceptions are based.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Explain and vulnerability mapping of six area of Tehran during and after a flood</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>351</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>368</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>The overall goal of research is to explain the factors influencing vulnerability zoning district 6 of Tehran and vulnerability in the face of natural disaster flooding. According to the study, the criteria for the vulnerability of cities through previous studies, library studies and Delphi method, interviews of experts will be identified. And then fits the criteria, through the digitization process navigation data to the appropriate format to be imported into GIS. To identify relationships between the standards and the structure of the techniques used DEMATEL. The structure can be obtained through questionnaires completed by experts. Because of the importance of parity is not the way to gain weight ANP criteria will be used. In this study, the MATLAB software for the calculation of the benchmark (DEMATEL techniques) and the application of the criteria used to calculate the weight Super decision. For spatial modeling and vulnerability mapping in Tehran from model-based sorting option is based on profiles that it has removed some restrictions on former methods. This model through the design and incorporation of an extension (extension) using the Python programming language to ArcGis software will be operational. At the end of the six different areas of Tehran in terms of vulnerability to natural disaster will flood zoning. The results showed that a sector with high vulnerability in areas with population density and urban fabric, with an area in the South East is on. Without access to areas after flooding in the vulnerable urban fabric is very important.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>بررسی گفتمان قدرت در نگارش تاریخ هنر و معماری و شهرسازی ایران در عصر ساسانی و ورود اسلام</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>369</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>388</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>ساسانیان خود را جانشینان برحق هخامنشیان می&amp;shy;دانستند. فرهنگ و تمدن و هنر در این دوره از تاریخ ایران به اوج خود می رسد. تاریخ نگاران ایرانی و غیر ایرانی بر این باورند که با سرنگونی دولت ساسانی، ایران هرگز روی تمدن و پیشرفت به خود ندیده است. نظریه گفتمان قدرت و دانش میشل فوکو به تحلیل و واسازی این باورها می پردازد. تحلیل گفتمان اهداف پشت این باورها را نشان می دهد. از نظر فوکو قدرت گزینه هایی را به عنوان دانش انتخاب می کند. این دانش هم مولد و هم سرکوبگراست. شکلهایی از مبارزه با این قدرت- دانش وجود دارد. این پژوهش به کمک روش اسنادی و کتابخانه ای با تحلیل نظریه ی گفتمان قدرت- دانش میشل فوکو در عصر ساسانی می پردازد. هدف این پژوهش نشان دادن تفاوت دو دید گاه متفاوت مولد و مبارز برای تاریخنگاران ایرانی و غیر ایرانی است. بسیاری ازتاریخ نگاران ایرانی، اطلاعات خود را مدیون باستان شناسان و شرق شناسان غربی می دانند. از این رو این تاریخنگاران اغلب باستان گرا هستند. تحلیل گفتمان دانش و قدرت جایگاه متفاوت و متضاد این دو گروه را برما آشکار می سازد.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Fellowship future approach to strategic human resource planning by using meta-synthesis</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>389</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>416</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Explore the relationships between human resources strategic planning and future potential opportunities for increased efficiency provides both areas. This study aims to provide a model for future human resource strategy planning grant in government agencies and meta-synthesis method using the Shannon entropy is done. Thus the scope of Article 314 futures human resources and strategic planning, assessment and content analysis to extract dimensions and their respective codes and the priority of each Shannon entropy was determined using quantitative methods. Based on the findings of six and seventeen step-by-step fellowship for future strategic planning of human resources in government agencies was presented. It was also found that the correct understanding, explaining, explicating the goals to top management, operations managers and users in order to enlist their support among the 110 most important factor code is detected. By identification of each of the stages and steps as well as the relevant codes and consequently the future strategic human resource planning models fellowship in government agencies, map methodological model was introduced. And a range of methods for each step was found to meet today's changing environment of uncertainty and organizations.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>The Identification of Effective Native Architectural Climatic Solutions on Climatic Comfort Conditions of Arak’s Schools</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>417</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>434</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>The architecture is influenced by climate and using climatic solutions &amp;lrm;can help provide comfort conditions of space. Efficiency could be promoted by creating comfort conditions in schools as one of the educational spaces. One of the problems of schools is lack of comfort conditions in them. This means that pay attention to climatic solutions in the design of schools have been neglected. The aim of this study is to identify effective native architectural climatic solutions on climatic comfort conditions with focus on schools in Arak and determine the effectiveness of them. The research has been done by survey method and Delphi technique. For this purpose, first, open-ended questionnaire was distributed among specialists and experts, then responses were checked and the initial list of climatic solutions was extracted. In the next step, the effectiveness of solutions was studied, and then data was analyzed by SPSS software. Finally, specialists stated their final comments, considering to statistical results. The results showed that climatic solutions include: building orientation, building placement, details and building architectural. Among factors, building orientation due to the angel of sunshine to get maximum of solar energy, use of solar energy in sunny times in the winter and building orientation due to the wind flow in the winter, have the most impact.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Studying the taste and preference of domestic tourists in shopping Handicrafts; case study: Gilan Kilim</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>435</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>448</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>There crafts in rural areas can attract tourists to the region and pave the way to prosper addition, the growth of the tourism industry. In the meantime, the widespread presence of crafts in rural areas requires that its marketing activities designed so that they can respond appropriately to the needs of tourists. Due to this, the aim of this study was to investigate the tastes and preferences of tourists in the area of marketing conglomerates crafts. To conduct this study, Gilan products were selected as a case study sample consisted of 120 tourists who visit the handicraft markets had been studied. The results show that in the field of product design, tourists are more willing to buy private plans and traditional decorated with abstract motifs, and choose their favorite color range depends on the space. In addition, the purchase of permanent shops and family via handicraft exhibitions and promotion practices those are friendly to a greater extent. In terms of pricing as well as providing a quality product with good design and packaging are willing to pay more.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Effective Factors on Quality of Urban Public Realms in Mashhad</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>449</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>464</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Urban public realms are as the spaces for presence of people and places for citizens' interaction and urban activities; so occurs many urban functions in them. Therefore, citizens' health depends on the quality and efficiency of urban public realms. A good urban public realm, where users prefer and use it persists. People prefer to reduce their presence in the public realms or change them, if they don't compatible with the needs of users or they don't understand quality of them. Understanding the quality of public realm is a purposeful process in which environmental data is received by the people. So it is dependent on environmental conditions and characteristics of individual perception. The aim of this article is to study quality of urban public realms and facilitate social relations in them. So, it has relied on the phenomenological approach of human and environment interaction in understanding urban public realms quality and utilized to Grounded theory to study the behavioral pattern of Mashhad metropolitan public realms. Spearman correlation test results show that there is a significant correlation between user desires and perceived environment meaning. People's desires and expectations of urban public realms and Discover the meaning of environment are created on the basis of individual and social characteristics. As well, the perceived quality is affected by age, gender and level of individual awareness of the environment and also the purpose of visiting public realms.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Marketing mix factors influencing satisfaction of female citizens of the city of Tabriz pools</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>465</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>474</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>The aim of this study was to investigate the role of customer satisfaction in the managed pool of Tabriz. The research method was descriptive and was performed as a field. The study consisted of all female clients were 11760 Tabriz pools and sample according to the sample volume determination 380 were selected for random cluster sampling. The data collection tool was questionnaire the validity and reliability of the sample, were collected and distributed. For data analysis, descriptive statistics (frequency, percentage, mean, standard deviation, minimum and maximum) and Friedman and binomial test was used. The results showed that elements of satisfaction (service, price, place, promotion, people, physical assets and processes) on female customer satisfaction pools northwestern city of Tabriz, was positive and significant.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Social network analysis lifestyle Iranian family (With emphasis on the risks and damage to social networks)</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>475</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>488</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Undoubtedly, globalization and development of information technology, technology penetration into various communities across national boundaries, borders today and Today, all societies, with extensive communications networks are to deal with Who, along with individual style and character of the new social relations and family have brought. In other words, widespread use of these networks as an inevitable need in the age of communication has different functions Br⁯ family structure (relations between spouses, family members' relationship with each other) to haven increasing or decreasing the rate of security in their organization. The research was descriptive study is to answer questions and related documents in this area and are analyzed using qualitative methods. Therefore, in order to avoid surprises in dealing with new risks of social networks is necessary to identify the network and affect their growth and development, tangible and intangible effects on the family Finally, the proposed revisions suitable for social networks among Iranian families citizens by promoting literacy and attention to acquire the necessary skills to live in electronics.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Evaluation of Optimal Greenhouse in Residential Buildings in Moderate and Mountainous Climate of Iran (Case Study: City of Kermanshah)</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>489</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>504</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>&amp;nbsp;Solar greenhouse from the perspective of energy, including the construction ways disabled by using solar radiation,absorb the solar energy to heating side space in this study using five variable orientation, the angle slope and aspect, light conductor&amp;nbsp; materials, heat transfer and energy conservation and using climate data within the study period (2005-2015) of synoptic meteorological&amp;nbsp; station of&amp;nbsp; Kermanshah airport has been collecting to help optimize solar greenhouse the software simulation and evaluation of energy is analyzed. Based on the results of this study during the warmer months of the year (first six months) the direction which has the greater angle from the south have more energy in this respect the most efficient solar greenhouses during the most optimal formula for calculating depth of 6 meters (width) of the relationship COS (50) = W / h is calculated.We can also improve the performance of&amp;nbsp; windows heating greenhouses with double glazing and low-emission windows with shading with internal&amp;nbsp; movable&amp;nbsp; insulation, which reduces heat transfer coefficient and thus in window reduce energy waste placed&amp;nbsp; in the greenhouse.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>A Novel Method for establishing quality of service in the management of the various branches of commerce using network-based software</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>505</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>516</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>The extent and complexity of urban problems and the growth and development of cities, the management of the city has become a difficult task. In the past two decades, the term ICT as a new phenomenon and powerful, has found their niche. And the use of ICT in administration, especially in managing cities, urban management is an effective step towards sustainable development. So that can improve management practices and urban life and it's much easier. Commerce, organization and management of ICT for better and faster your referrals use. One of the most important infrastructures for the commerce, infrastructure and telecommunications network that is used to control the different branches requires fast and stable connection. Therefore, investigating and resolving this issue is essential and in this article we have tried to solve these problems. In this article, contact the service quality issue as a problem of linear programming model. &amp;nbsp; And then to solve the problem of bee colony meta-heuristic algorithm is used. &amp;nbsp;And finally the result of the proposed method is expressed. Simulation results show that the proposed method for communication service quality assurance branch with the control center, has been effective. And can not be used.
</Abstract>


</Article>
<Article>
<Journal>
<PublisherName> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</PublisherName>
<JournalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</JournalTitle>
<Issn>1607-2227</Issn>
<Volume>15</Volume>
<Issue>45</Issue>
<PubDate PubStatus = "ppublish">
<Year>2017</Year>
<Month>3</Month>
<Day>1</Day>
</PubDate>
</Journal>


	<ArticleTitle>Analysis of the necessity of hospital design green approach to sustainable architecture</ArticleTitle>
	<FirstPage>517</FirstPage>
	<LastPage>532</LastPage>
	<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


	<Author>
	<FirstName></FirstName>
	<LastName></LastName>
	<Affiliation></Affiliation>
	 </Author>


</AuthorList>
<Abstract>Among the variety of architectural spaces, no space, such as health centers at the confluence of the two issues are not medical science and the arts. And in between architecture, design no space is not as important medical centers. Such therapeutic areas, including areas that affect people's moods. And poor design of the environment can cause behavioral disorders and anxiety in them. Today, in hospital design, functionalism account for the bulk of the design thinking. So that attention to environmental qualification dramatic impact on the treatment of patients, and reduce their anxiety plays a lesser role. The purpose of this change design perspective in the design and strategies in the treatment centers is the design of green space; To be effective in improving the quality of hospital environment And thus accelerating healing and reducing anxiety in the lead. These studies is a comprehensive review and search the corporate sites and reputable domestic and foreign electronic databases was conducted in order to identify patterns Green Hospital. It seems that in our country a comprehensive plan of action to improve weaknesses in achieving the standards required hospital is green. And inadequate attention to environmental protection strategies, lack of adequate training in the field of environmental green hospital of the main obstacles to achieving the benchmarks.
</Abstract>


</Article>
</ArticleSet>
