<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>30</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>مدیریت یکپارچه شهری در ساماندهی سکونتگاههای غیررسمی شهرهای میانی ایران؛ مورد پژوهی: زنجان و همدان</title_fa>
	<title>Urban integrated management in arranging of Informal settlement in Iran moderate cities (Zanjan and Hamadan)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>مدیریت یکپارچه شهری مدیریتی است هم افزا،با حضور تمامی ذی‌نفعان و ذی‌نفوذان شهری در چارچوب نهادی، سازمانی و قانونی مشخص به منظور ارتقاء سطح مدیریت شهری و پایدار نمودن زیست پذیری شهر. این مقاله سعی بر آن داشته است با بررسی ساختار مدیریت شهری شهرهای میانی ایران (زنجان و همدان) در ساماندهی سکونتگاه های غیررسمی با نگرش مدیریت یکپارچه بپردازد. روش تحقیق پژوهش از نوع پیمایشی- کمی بوده که با استفاده از روش اسنادی و میدانی گردآوری داده ها صورت پذیرفته است. جامعه آماری پژوهش شامل اعضای ستاد توانمند سازی اسکان غیررسمی، (بخش دولتی و عمومی) نهادهای مردمی و مردم ساکن در بافتهای اسکان غیر رسمی و فعالان اقتصادی (بخش خصوصی) مستقر در این بافتها می باشد. حجم نمونه برآورد شده برای بخش دولتی و عمومی 18 سازمان، برای بخش مردمی 620 نمونه و برای بخش خصوصی510 نمونه بوده است که با استفاده از روش آزمون میانگین و مدل تحلیل مسیر تجزیه و تحلیل داده ها صورت پذیرفت. نتایج حاصل از پژوهش نشان می دهد در شهرهای میانی ایران مدیریت یکپارچه شهری عملکرد نیافته و مدیریت شهری دارای نگرش و کارکرد سنتی است و نتیجه این نوع نگرش ناکارمدی طرح های ساماندهی و گسترش مسائل شهری در بافتهای اسکان غیررسمی است. از طرف دیگر تشریک مساعی نهادی (هم افزایی نهادی) بعنوان پیش شرط پیاده سازی مدیریت یکپارچه در حال حاضر در این شهرها نامناسب و در پایه چرخه حیات مدیریت یکپارچه شهری واقع شده است. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Integrated management of urban management is also Synergic, with the participation of all stakeholders and influential city in the institutional framework, institutional and legal order to determine the steady level of urban management for city livability. This article is intended to scrutiny the management structure of the metropolitan cities of Iran (Zanjan and Hamedan) in arranging informal settlements with an integrated management approach.research method is survey- quantity method that achieves documents and field data collection has been done. Society statistical is members of the informal settlement enabling head quarters,(public and state sectors), community institutes people that living in informal settlements and economic actors (private sector) based in the tissues. Sample size estimates for the public sector and 18 public organizations for public and state sectors and samples for private sector and 620 samples for people that using the depletion method and the average test data analysis were performed. Results of the study show that in the middle of Iran's cities, urban integrated management has been the traditional function of attitude. This type of attitude and organization design and development urban issues in the tissues is an informal settlement. From the collaborating institution (institutional synergy) as a precondition for implementation of integrated management is now integrated in the urban poor and urban-based lifecycle management is situated. </abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مدیریت شهری، مدیریت یکپارچه، شهرمیانی، اسکان غیر رسمی، ایران.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Urban management, integration, Moderate city, Iran</keyword>
	<start_page>53</start_page>
	<end_page>68</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-217-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Esmail</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Daviran</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>اسماعیل</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>دویران</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Socialcapita2007@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600469</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600469</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Gholamreza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Kazemian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>غلامرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کاظمیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600470</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600470</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Tabatabai University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Abolfazl</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Meshkini</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>ابوالفضل</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مشکینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600471</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600471</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Abdolreza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rokn Al Din Eftekhari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>عبدالرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رکن الدین افتخاری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600472</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600472</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Bijan</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Kalhornia</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>بیژن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کلهرنیا</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600473</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600473</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Kermanshah University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
