<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>29</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa> بافت شناسی بافت کالبد تاریخی شهر یزد با نگرش سیستمی</title_fa>
	<title>Histology of urban historical textures</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;مباحث زیادی درباره بافت کالبد تاریخی شهر با نگرش‌های مختلف در ادبیات شهرسازی و معماری جهانی مطرح شده است. در ایران، بررسی‌های عمومی و پراکنده‌ای از آن‌ها تاکنون ارائه شده است. گونه‌گونی و پیچیدگی بافت‌ها سبب شده، تا دستیابی به بافت‌شناسی آن‌ها، به عنوان هدف اصلی این مقاله مطرح باشد. به این منظور، مطالعاتی در حوزه‌های علمی مختلف انجام گرفت. نظریه‌ها، نگرش ها و چارچوب مفهومی «بافت» مورد توجه قرار گرفت. مشاهدات، پیمایش‌ها و برداشت‌های متعددی از بافت‌های کالبد تاریخی شهرهای ایران، به ویژه شهر یزد انجام شد. اجزای بافت‌ها شناسائی شدند. با استفاده از روش پژوهش توصیفی- تحلیلی، مباحث مربوطه تألیف شدند. از فرآیند رفت و برگشت جزء به کل و بر عکس در این پژوهش استفاده شد. بررسی و مطالعه، موجب شناسائی و معرفی اجزا در قالب مدل‌های مراتبی شد. پی‌گیری متناظر اجزای مطرح در مدل‌های مراتبی ارائه شده با نظریه سیستم‌ها، شناسائی زیرسیستم‌های سیستم بافت کالبد تاریخی شهر یزد را به دنبال داشت. به نظر می‌رسد مدل‌های ارائه شده، قابلیت‌های تئوریک عمده‌ای دارند. از این‌رو، استفاده از مطالب مقاله در مطالعه و مداخله‌ در بافت‌های کالبد تاریخی شهرهای کشور توصیه‌ می‌شود. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;A lot of different arguments have been done about urban historical texture in the literature of architecture and urbanism. Some considerations are done about urban historical texture in architecture and urbanism literature of IRAN up to now. However, they are scattered. Extent, variety and complexity of them have caused many difficulties in the Histology of the urban historic texture.For this purpose many studies in texture ground in different scientific. Theories, outlooks and conceptual framework of texture concept are considered. Many different observation and considerations were done from urban historical texture of Iran specific YAZD city. The elements, relationships, intermediates and etc, are explicated. These cases are collected and edited by descriptive-analytical method. Hierarchy model are made from them. Equivalent Counterpart elements and containing Counterpart elements are considered so that system and subsystem of the urban historical textures were explicated. In system theory base, the urban historical textures system was definite and was presented in model framework. It was used from induction and reduction cycle process and reverse. IT was edited detail to total after it was districted confidence results. Consequently this model can be highly recommended to use in Urbans historical texture. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>بافت شناسی، بافت کالبد تاریخی شهر یزد، پود، تار، بند، شبکه، ماده زمینه‌ای.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Histology, urban historical texture, Connection, Woof, Wrap, Web, knot, Matrix.</keyword>
	<start_page>23</start_page>
	<end_page>48</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-129-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mostafa</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Behzadfar</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مصطفی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بهزادفر</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600271</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600271</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hosein</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Noor Mohammad Zaad</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>نور محمد زاد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>nourm2003@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600272</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600272</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Yazd University School of Art and Architecture</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده هنر و معماری دانشگاه یزد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
