<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1396</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2018</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>16</volume>
<number>49</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی تاثیر کیفیت نظام ارتباطی پروژه بر میزان احساس مشارکت تیم پروژه</title_fa>
	<title>Influence of project communication system quality on participation sense of project team</title>
	<subject_fa></subject_fa>
	<subject></subject>
	<content_type_fa></content_type_fa>
	<content_type></content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;مشارکت به عنوان یک راهکار کارآمد در سطوح مختلف و در حوزه&amp;zwnj;های متعدد مدیریت، به ویژه مدیریت پروژه توانسته است پاسخ جامعی را در برابر انتقادهای جریان پست مدرنیسم از مدیریت مدرن فراهم نماید. اما آنچه کمتر به آن توجه شده است موضوع زیربناها و عوامل تاثیر&amp;zwnj;گذار بر بهبود مشارکت است. عواملی که شناسایی آنها می تواند تاثیر چشمگیری بر امکان ارائه راهکارهای عملیاتی و اثربخش در جهت بهبود پدیده مشارکت داشته باشد. این تحقیق با هدف پر&amp;zwnj;کردن این شکاف در ادبیات موضوع بر نقش تعیین کننده کیفیت نظام ارتباطی پروژه بر بهبود احساس مشارکت تیم پروژه به عنوان یک عامل مهم و تقویت کننده مشارکت متمرکز شده است&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; برای این منظور با رویکرد کمی و با استفاده از روش تحقیق توصیفی- تحلیلی داده های میدانی گرد آورده شده&amp;zwnj;اند و از آزمون عاملی به منظور شناسایی عوامل شکل دهنده دو مفهوم کیفیت نظام ارتباطی و همچنین احساس مشارکت تیم پروژه استفاده شده است. بر مبنای نتایج حاصل از آزمون عاملی زمینه برای ارائه راهکارهای عملی و آزمون فرض تحقیق فراهم شده است. در نهایت آزمون فرض تحقیق با استفاده از ضریب هبستگی پیرسون نشان&amp;zwnj;دهنده همبستگی مثبت بین کیفیت نظام ارتباطی پروژه و احساس مشارکت تیم پروژه است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Participation as an effective approach has provided a comprehensive response in different level and areas of management, especially project management in deal with postmodern criticisms which have been mentioned against modern management. But what have been neglected are foundations and influential factors on participation improvement. It is important because identification of these factors can have significant influence on our ability to offer effective and practical solution to improve participation phenomenon. This research with the aim of covering this gap in literature has been concentrated on the decisive role of project communication system quality in the improvement of project team participation sense as an important factor and amplifier of participation phenomenon. For this reason, with quantitative approach and by using descriptive-analytical research method, field data have been gathered and factor test has been used in order to diagnosing factors for both communication quality system and participation sense of project team. Result of factor analysis provides the condition in a way that research hypothesis be testable and practical solution be presentable. In final, the test of research hypothesis by using Pearson correlation coefficient, showed positive correlation between project communication system quality and project team participation sense.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>نظام ارتباطی پروژه, احساس مشارکت, آزمون عاملی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>communication system of project, participation sense, factor test.</keyword>
	<start_page>499</start_page>
	<end_page>509</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-73&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسن </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ریحانی همدانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008328</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008328</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهرداد </first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سرهادی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846008329</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846008329</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
