<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>30</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>طبقه بندی شاخص های کلیدی در تبیین الگوی منشور پروژه برای مدیریت پروژه های شهری</title_fa>
	<title>Categorizing The Key Indices For Establishing A Project Charter For Urban Project Management</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>اجرای پروژه‌های شهری نیازمند بررسی شرایط و الزامات برگرفته از معیارها و شاخص های موثر بر منشور و قوانین رسمی و ملی است و در مقایسه با ضوابط بین المللی، پیرو کمترین خطای معیار استاندارد است. در پروژه های شهری، همچون سایر پروژه ها، موفقیت پروژه و رضایتمندی کلیه عوامل آن را می توان مهم ترین امر در مدیریت پروژه دانست. بر طبق تحقیقات صورت گرفته چنین موفقیتی محصول عوامل مختلفی است؛ از مهمترین این عوامل، مستند سازی دلایل وجودی پروژه، اهداف، نقش ها و مسئولیت ها، وظایف و اختیارات ذینفعان پروژه در مرحله آغازین پروژه می باشد که حاصل آن سندی به نام منشور پروژه است. در این مقاله تحقیقی که با روش اکتشافی انجام شده است، ابتدا به معرفی منشور به عنوان ابزاری تحلیلی، تفهیمی و ارتباطی و نیز ابزاری برای تصمیم گیری پرداخته شده و با بررسی و تحقیق روی نمونه های مختلف منشورها در 42 پروژه مختلف جهانی، مراحل تدوین آن قدم به قدم طرح و معیارهای ضروری بدین منظور ارائه گردیده است. نتایج تحقیق، الگویی مناسب برای تهیه منشور پروژه شهری بدست می دهد. برای رسیدن به این الگو، با برداشت از اطلاعات شرکت های بزرگ و معتبر دنیا، موجه ترین عناوین مورد پذیرش ذینفعان استخراج و در یک طرح جامع خاص شامل: اطلاعات عمومی پروژه، الزامات حوزه های نه گانه مدیریت پروژه مورد نظر، مشارکت‌ها، حمایت‌ها و همچنین تصویب نامه‌ها گنجانده شده است. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Investigating the requirements adopted from effective criteria and indices for national laws and regulations is needed for urban projects execution and these projects are followed by the least standard deviation. Project success and all staffs satisfaction are in fact the most important issues in urban projects as well as all kinds of projects. The most important factor is documentation of project existance reasons, goals, roles and responsibilities, stakeholders duties and authorities in the early stages of the project which is called project charter. In this article, which has used explorative method, after reviewing the project charter literature, various templates in 42 different projects in the world are investigated. Then we design the preparation step by step and derive the needed criteria and the result of the research is a suitable pattern for project charter preparation. Regarded that most of the projects in Iran have not included a project charter, the researchers of the paper have investigated the current effective factors used to prepare four big project charters by reviewing their documents and comparing them to designed model. </abstract>
	<keyword_fa>مدیریت پروژه، پروژه های شهری، منشورپروژه، اهداف پروژه، موفقیت پروژه.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>project management, urban projects, project charter ,project goals, project team</keyword>
	<start_page>223</start_page>
	<end_page>238</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-228-4&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Reza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Falsafi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>رضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فلسفی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>r_falsafi@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600519</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600519</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ahmadali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Yazdanpanah</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>احمد علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>یزدان پناه</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600520</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600520</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Seyyed Badr Aldin</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ahmadi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید بدرالدین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>احمدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600521</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600521</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Loza</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Ahmadi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>لوزا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>احمدی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600522</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600522</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>University of Tarbiat Modares</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
