<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>29</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>کاربرد چیدمان فضایی در خیابان ولیعصر شهر باشت</title_fa>
	<title>The application of the space syntax of the Valiasr St Basht city</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;شهرها به عنوان بزرگترین محل تجمع انسانی هم از رفتار و عملکرد انسان های ساکن، تأثیر پذیرفته و شهر را بر اساس نیازها و خواسته های خودشان شکل داده اند و هم شهرها و چگونگی قرار گیری فضاها در کل سیستم شهر بر نوع رفتارها و عملکرد انسان ها تأثیر گذاشته است. که با مطالعه و شناخت این روابط می توان هر فضایی یا هر نوع کاربری را در جای خود استقرار نمود. در این بین نظریه چیدمان فضایی، نظریه نسبتاً جدیدی است که ریشه در علم ریاضیات گسسته (نظریه گراف ها) دارد و از دهه 1980 وارد مباحث شهرسازی و معماری شده است. این نظریه به بررسی روابط بین چیدمان فضاها و رفتار افراد در این فضاها با استفاده از عامل های وضوح، اتصال، هم پیوندی، عمق و نقشه هم پیوندی می پردازد. با استفاده از این نظریه و تحلیل عاملها در نرم افزارهای Arcgis, Arc view در شهر باشت به بررسی علت تجمع کاربری های تجاری در خیابان ولیعصر و به تبع آن تراکم رفت آمدهای سواره و پیاده در این خیابان بپردازد. در نهایت با این پژوهش مشخص می گردد که علت تجمع کاربری ها و به تبع آن تراکم رفت و آمدها بالا بودن وضوح، اتصال، هم پیوندی و پایین بودن عمق در خیابان ولیعصر شهر باشت است. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;While the Cities are the largest human gathering place for people living influenced in the behavior and performance, and formed the city based on their needs and desires and cities and how layout of spaces the whole city system has affected the On the type of human behavior and functions. The study and understanding of these relationships can be located in place of any space or any type of uses. Among this, space syntax theory is relatively a new theory that rooted in discrete mathematics science (theory of graphs), since the 1980s this theory has entered in the urban and architectural issues. This theory examines the relationship between syntax of spaces and focuses on individual behavior in these spaces with using the definition of intelligibility, connectivity, integration, depth and axial map. Using this theory and factor analysis in Arcgis, Arc view software in Basht city to pay of review this accumulation commercial uses in the Valiasr Street and result in the riding and pedestrian trips density in the streets. Finally this research will determine the cause of this accumulation and its subsequent trips density is elevated intelligibility, connectivity, integration and low depth in the Valiasr Street Basht city. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>چیدمان فضایی، شهر باشت ، تراکم رفت و آمد و Arcgis,Arcview</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>space syntax, Basht city, traffic density, Arcgis, Arc view</keyword>
	<start_page>81</start_page>
	<end_page>90</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-131-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Abbas</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Molla Zadeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>عباس</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>ملازاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Abbasm89@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600278</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600278</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch of Tehran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Vahid</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Barani Pesian</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>وحید</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>بارانی پسیان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600279</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600279</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch of Tehran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Khosro Zadeh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خسرو زاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600280</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600280</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch of Tehran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
