<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>2015</YEAR>
<VOL>14</VOL>
<NO>39</NO>
<MOSALSAL>0</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>428</PAGE_NO>


<ARTICLES>

	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>شهر دوستدار سالمند و معیارهای طراحی مراکز تعاملات اجتماعیِ سالمندی با رویکرد سلامت‌روان</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Age-friendly city design criteria centers of social interaction with the concepts of space and culture approach to mental health</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
امروزه توجه به جایگاه و نقش سالمندان در نظام برنامه‌ریزی شهری و معماری از یک‌طرف و تحقق-پذیری شهرهای دوستدار سالمند، از اولویتهای اساسی در فرآیند برنامه‌ریزی شهر و معماری است که تطورات بافت اجتماعی و تغییر ساختار سنی کشور و تحولات جمعیتی موجود که به پیر شدن جمعیت شهری می‌پردازد، نیز بر این امر تاکید دارد. در این میان، پرداختن به مقوله «سلامت روان» از اصلی-ترین نیازهای روان‌شناختی سالمندان است که در این پژوهش با تاکید بر نظریه‌های سلامت روان و نظریه‌های طراحی فضاهای شهری و معماری، تلاش شده است تا معیارهایی در طراحی مراکز تعاملات اجتماعی سالمندی در قالب فضای افزایش تعاملات اجتماعی مورد اشاره قرار گیرد. مبنای نظری این تحقیق، بر اساس نظریه فعالیتِ «گاست» و «نظریه میدانی کورت لوین» بوده که از روش تحقیق «توصیفی- تحلیلی» در مرحله ادبیات نظری و روش تحقیق «فراتحلیل» در جمعبندی نظریه-ها و راهکارسنجی با ابزار گرداوری داده مشتمل بر مطالعات کتابخانه‌ای و اسنادی بهره برده است. در پایان راهکارهایی چند در راستای تحقق‌پذیری شهرهای دوستدار سالمند در مرحله اول و پیشنهاداتی در حوزه معیارهای طراحی برای ارتقاء سلامت روان‌شناختی سالمندان در مرحله دوم مورد اشاره قرار گرفته است.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
Attention to the role of the elderly in the urban planning and architecture on the one hand and the realization of the age-friendly cities, the main priorities in the process of planning and architecture. Evolutionary social context and changes in age structure of the population changes in the aging urban population, also focuses on this. Meanwhile, addressing the issue of &quot;mental health&quot; of the main psychological needs of the elderly in this study, with an emphasis on mental health theories and theories of urban design and architecture is done. Tries to measures designed to increase the space in the old centers of social interaction social interaction is discussed. The theoretical basis of this study, based on the idea of &quot;y Gasset&quot; and &quot;field theory of Kurt Lewin was&quot;. The method of &quot;descriptive&quot; in the theoretical literature and research methods &quot;meta-analysis&quot; in discussions with the Data theories and studies, including the library and documentary benefited. At the end of several strategies in order to achieve the first stage of age-friendly cities and recommendations on measures designed to improve the mental health of the elderly in the second stage agreement has been mentioned.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>7</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>34</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>هوشنگ</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>فروغمند اعرابی</Family>
				<NameE>Hooshang</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Forooghmand Araabi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران جنوب</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>h-foroughmand@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>لیلا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کریمی فرد</Family>
				<NameE>Leila</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Karimi Fard</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران جنوب</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>age-friendly city</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>the center of social interaction</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>social communication theories</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>and theories of mental health.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهر دوستدار سالمند</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مرکز تعاملات اجتماعی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نظریه‌های تعاملات اجتماعی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نظریه سلامت روان.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>آرمان آرمانشهری در شهرهای آرمانی شیعی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Utopian ideal of utopian Shi'ite cities</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
آرمانشهرها و آرمان‌گرایی در طول تاریخ از اهمیت فراگیری برخوردار بوده اند؛ چنانچه آرمانشهر در دیدگاهی جهان‌شمول، جلوه‌ای از خواستها و آرمانهای بشری است تا بتواند تمنیّات و رویاهای خویش را در ساختار اجتماعی و کالبدی شهر به عینیّت برساند. بر همین اساس است که هر اندیشمند بر حسب حوزه اندیشه انتقادی خود، ویژگیها و شاخصه‌های آرمانشهر را از دیدگاهی خاص مورد ارزیابی قرار داده است. راست است که اندیشه متفکّر و نقّاد، و شرایط و مقتضیّات تاریخی، اجتماعی و فرهنگی، در بیان و تعیین ویژگیها و حتی نوع رویکرد به مفاهیم شهر آرمانی تاثیر دارد؛ و این چنین است که رویکردهای متفاوتی در برخورد با این مقوله ذهن بشر را به‌خود معطوف داشته است. روش تحقیق پژوهش حاضر توصیفی و تحلیلی است که از ابزار گرداوری داده شامل مطالعات کتابخانه ای و روش اسنادی بهره برده است. نتایج تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که آرمانشهر غربی در جستجوی همه ابعاد در عالم مادی و بطور کامل‌تر در مقام مصداق «غار افلاطونی» است. در این تمثیل، عروج ذهن از بخش‌های پایین خط به بخش‌های بالاتر، پیشرفتی شناخت‌شناسی است و ذهن در جریان مستمری از تکامل، از حالت شناخت نابسنده به شناخت کافی دست می‌یابد. همچنین آرمانشهر ایرانی، یک آرمانشهر شیعی است که وابسته به جامعه آرمانی اسلامی و مدینه فاضله مهدوی دارد که خصوصیات آن به تفصیل اشاره شده است.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
Utopia and idealism in history have had the importance of learning Utopia in view of the universal manifestation of the wishes and aspirations of human to their aspirations and dreams in the social structure of the city to bring objectivity. Accordingly, each scholar in the field of critical thought, the features and characteristics of Utopia is examined from a particular perspective Thoughtful and critical thinking and the requirements of historical, social and cultural expression and to determine the characteristics and even the type of approach to the concept of the ideal effect And so that different approaches in dealing with this issue has attracted the human mind. The research is descriptive and analytical study of Data library studies and documentary method is used. The results show that the Western utopia Find all aspects of the material world and more fully in a position of &quot;Plato's Cave&quot; are. In this analogy, the emergence of mind from the lower to the higher line, progress is the recognition of pension and mind during the development of the knowledge gained enough knowledge is inadequate The Iranian utopia, a utopia that is dependent on the Shi'i Islamic ideal and utopia Mahdavi that its characteristics are mentioned in detail.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>35</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>56</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد هادی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ادیب خواه</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Hadi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Adib Khah</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>spranzabianca@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Vision</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Utopia</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>utopian theories</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Shiite utopia</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>utopia Mahdavi.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آرمان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آرمانشهر</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نظریه های آرمانشهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آرمانشهر شیعی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدینه فاضله مهدوی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>نقش تمرکززدایی کامل در تحقق دولت محلی کارآمد</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Role of Comprehensive Decentralization in Realization of Efficient Local Government</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
مقاله پیش‌رو با فرض مطلوبیت و بایستگیِ سیاست عدم تمرکز حداکثری اختیارات اداری- سیاسی، می‌کوشد تا نخست علّت وجودی و غایی این تفکر را با بهره‌گیری از داده‌های حقوق عمومی واکاود؛ سپس با نظر به چالش‌هایی که در عمل مانع تحقق حق تعیین‌کنندگی و نقش‌آفرینی شهروندان در عرصه سیاست‌گذاری‌های کلان اداری- سیاسی می‌شود، درصدد است تا در پرتوی سیاست تمرکززدایی کامل اختیارات و با توجه به شکل دولت‌ها: دولت بسیط و انواع آن، دولت مرکب و انواع آن و نحوه نظارت قدرت مرکزی بر آن‌ها، یافته‌های تحقیق را در جهتِ تحقق و استقرار دولت محلی کارآمد و دموکراتیک به کار گیرد. به باور این نوشتار، مشخصه اصلی دولت محلی کارآمد آن است که فرآیند تقویت کردن شهروندان را در حوزه عمومی، با واگذاری بیشترین میزان اختیارات تصمیم‌گیری در امور اداری و سیاسی به شهروندان، تثبیت و تحکیم می‌نماید. از این رو مقاله حاضر در جهت اثبات مدعای پیش گفته، با رویکردی تاریخی- تحلیلی به موضوع مورد بحث می‌پردازد.   
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
Current study, assuming desirability and forcibility of the policy of maximum decentralization of official-political wills, tries to cultivate the reasons of existence of this thought from general law data. Afterwards, considering the challenges which are in fact obstacles for role-playing of citizens in the context of master political-official policy makings, the article aims at apply the results of the study in realization of an efficient and democratic local government under the policy of complete decentralization of wills considering the forms of governments. Based on this article’s findings, main characteristic of efficient local government is that ensures and empowers the process of encouragement of citizens in general areas, giving them the most possible powers and wills in political and official decision-makings. Therefore, the current study investigates the subject applying a historic-analytical approach to prove the claim.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>57</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>70</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رحمت اللهی</Family>
				<NameE>Hosein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rahmatollahi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hrahmat@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>احسان</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>آقا محمد آقایی</Family>
				<NameE>Ehsan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Aqa Mohammad Aqaii</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهران</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شیراوند</Family>
				<NameE>Mehran</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shiravand</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Comprehensive Decentralization</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Centralization</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Wide Government</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Compound Government</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Central Supervision</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Citizen Supervision</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Efficient Local Government.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تمرکززدایی کامل</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تمرکز‌گرایی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دولت بسیط</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دولت مرکب</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نظارت مرکزی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نظارت شهروندی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دولت محلی کارآمد.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>خوشه‌بندی صنایع در محیط فازی از لحاظ توجه به میزان سبزیت زنجیره تامین جهت مدیریت زیست محیطی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Application of Hierarchical Approach to Estimate the Importance of Elements of Urban Development in a Fuzzy Environment</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
در دهه‌های اخیر به دلیل پیدایش توسعه پایدار، مردم جهان توجه بیشتری به حفاظت از محیط زیست و منابع زیستی دارند. این نگرش مثبت باعث گردیده که مدیران صنایع مختلف در پی رویکرهای عملیاتی جهت ارتقاء عملکرد سازمانی خود با رعایت نکات زیست محیطی به عنوان یک مزیت رقابتی باشند. بدین منظور، هدف این مقاله، ارائه الگویی ترکیبی جهت خوشه‌بندی صنایع استان بوشهر از لحاظ توجه به میزان سبزیت در زنجیره تامین می‌باشد. برای این کار، شاخص مؤثر با مطالعه ادبیات موضوعی و مصاحبه با متخصصین شناسایی و سپس با بکارگیری رویکرد فرایند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی، میزان اهمیت هر یک از شاخص‌های مؤثر بر میزان سبز بودن مدیریت زنجیره تأمین محاسبه گردیدند. سپس با بکارگیری رویکرد فازی سی مینز صنایع موجود در قلمرو مکانی تحقیق خوشه بندی ‌گردیدند. لازم به ذکر است که جامعه آماری این پژوهش را مدیران،کارشناسان صنایع منطقه ویژه پارس جنوبی و نیز اساتید دانشگاهی تشکیل داده‌اند. جهت اکتساب داده‌های لازم از روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی ساده استفاده گردید. یافته‌های تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که بسیاری از صنایع بدلیل درجه عضویت بسیار نزدیک هم در خوشه‌ اول و هم در خوشه‌ دوم قرار گرفتند. سپس به منظور تعیین میزان توجه به سبزیت صنایع هر خوشه، آزمون آماری تی استیودنت(t) در سطح معنی‌داری 0.05 انجام گرفت. نتایج تحلیل بیان می‌دارد که توجه صنایع عضو خوشه اول به محیط زیست بالاو در خوشه دو متوسط است. لذا، به مدیران صنایع عضو خوشه دو توصیه می‌گردد که جهت افزایش سطح توجه به محیط زیست، بر شاخص‌های آموزش و پژوهش، توجه به محیط و هزینه تمرکز بیشتری داشته باشند تا بتوانند علاوه بر افزایش عملکرد، معضلات زیست محیطی را نیز پیشگیری نمایند.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
Today human is engaged with a great crisis as a result of his unbalancing the life, neglecting indigenous and environmental factors, and hegemonic behavior toward nature. This has ended to creation of an approach called sustainable development whose main aims are to meet the essential needs, improvement of life quality, and better management of ecosystems. Obviously it is meaningless to discuss sustainability and sustainable development in the absence of cities and urban life. Cities are counted for as the main reasons for unsustainability the world over, however urban sustainability and global sustainability are the same concepts.  Therefore, knowing key elements to reach this station is necessary, whereas recognition and prioritization of effective key elements in sustainable development is strategic and entails economic, social, and health-related results in the sequence of time. The current study is descriptive-analytic in which attempts have been made to estimate the importance of main indices of sustainable development based on the opinions of elites using a fuzzy hierarchical analysis process technic. Analysis of the data shows that from among main indices, urban health, desirable governmental system, and sustainable environment are respectively of the highest importance.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>71</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>86</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علیرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>پویا</Family>
				<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Pooya</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>فردوسی مشهد</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>احمد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قربان پور</Family>
				<NameE>Ahmad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Qorban Poor</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>فردوسی مشهد</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>ah.ghorbanpour.62@stu-mail.um.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Urban Sustainable Development</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Bushehr City</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Fuzzy Logic</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Fuzzy Hierarchical Analysis Process.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زنجیره تأمین سبز</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>منطق فازی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فرایند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>الگوریتم سی‌مینز</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>خوشه‌بندی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی تطبیقی معماری اماکن مذهبی و شهرسازی دوره بیزانس در ترکیه با دوره سلجوقی در ایران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>A comparative study of religious architecture and urban planning Byzantine period in Turkish Seljuk period in Iran</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
همزمانی دوره‌های تاریخی از یک طرف و مناسبات بین فرهنگی در هر دوره تاریخی، باعث تاثیر و تاثرات فرهنگی و هنری و بالاخص در حوزه معماری می‌شود که بازنمودهای ویژه‌ای در هر مقطع زمانی داشته است. این امر در مقایسه تطبیقی دوره بیزانس در ترکیه و دوره سلجوقی ایران دارای اهمیت بیشتری است که دلیل آن را می‌توان در غنای معماری و شهرسازی دوره سلجوقی جستجو کرد. در این مقاله با روش تحلیلی و مقایسه‌ای به بررسی تطبیقی معماری دوره بیزانس با دوره سلجوقی در ایران پرداخته شود. در این مقاله در یک دیدگاه تطبیقی مقایسه‌ای بین معماری ابنیه دوره سلجوقی و بیزانس ترکیه صورت گرفته و نتایجی چند در این رابطه مورد اشاره قرار می‌گیرد. در پایان به نتایج تحقیق در قالب بیان تفاوتها و شباهتهای احتمالی و تاثیر و تاثر این دوره های زمانی اشاره شده است.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
Synchronization period on the one hand and intercultural relations in each historical period, the cultural and artistic interactions, especially in the field of architecture that representations have been specific in each period This is in comparison to the Byzantine period in Turkish and Iranian Seljuk period is more important because it can be traced Seljuk architecture and urban richness. In this paper we compare the analytical and comparative study of Byzantine and Seljuk architecture in Iran In the end, the results in the frame of the possible similarities and differences and effects of the mentioned period of time.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>87</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>98</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>دریا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>نصرت پور</Family>
				<NameE>Darya</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Nosrat Poor</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>daryanosratpour@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سعید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>خاقانی</Family>
				<NameE>Saeed</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Khaqani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شاهرود</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>ودیهه</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ملاصالحی</Family>
				<NameE>Vadiheh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Molla Salehi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد سمنان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>architecture religious sites</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Byzantine</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Seljuk</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>comparative study.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>معماری اماکن مذهبی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دوره بیزانس</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دوره سلجوقی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مقایسه تطبیقی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بررسی عوامل موثر بر دلبستگی مکان در فضاهای باز آموزشی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Factors affecting the interest of place in educational open spaces </TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
نیاز انسان به تعامل عاطفی با مکانی که در آن زندگی می‌کند و یا به‌عبارتی دلبستگی به مکان از جمله مهم‌ترین ابعاد رابطه انسان و مکان است که باید مورد توجه معماران، طراحان و برنامه‌ریزان شهری قرار گیرد. با ارزیابی به‌عمل‌آمده از دانشگاه‌ها ملاحظه می گردد که بخش اعظم آن را دانشکده‌ها و کلاس‌های درس و سایر فضاهای بسته تشکیل می‌دهند و تمام توجهات برنامه‌ریزان و طراحان معطوف به فضاهای درونی است. در این میان منظر و فضاهای باز از توجه شایسته مغفول مانده‌اند. در دانشگاه های ایران مطالعات و تحقیقات کاربردی با هدف ارتقا کیفیت فضاهای باز دانشگاه‌ها در خدمت یادگیری دانشجویان، به جز چند مورد جزئی انجام نشده است. در این راستا با توجه به خلاء علمی و حرفه‌ای موجود می‌توان از دانش معماری و حرفه منظر کمک قابل توجهی گرفت. در این راستا پژوهش حاضر سعی دارد بر پایه مرور متون و اسناد مرتبط در این حوزه ضمن ارائه تعاریف دلبستگی به مکان به بررسی علل و عوامل دخیل در آن بپردازد. روش تحقیق در این پژوهش از نوع توصیفی- پیمایشی است. نمونه آماری شامل مجتمع های آموزشی دانشگاه آزاد همدان، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان و دانشگاه امام صادق تهران می‌باشد. بر اساس نتایج یافته‌های پژوهش هویت مکان، دلبستگی عاطفی، افزایش کیفیت فضای کالبدی و پیوند اجتماعی بر دلبستگی مکان فضاهای باز آموزشی دانشگاه‌ها از سوی دانشجویان اثر معناداری دارند.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
The human need to interact emotionally with the place where lives and Or in other words, attachment to place among the most important aspects of the relationship between people and places that need the attention of architects, designers and urban planners should be To assess the performance of the schools we see that most of the colleges and classrooms and other spaces are closed. Planners and designers paid attention to the internal spaces. The landscape and open spaces worthy of attention are neglected. Iranian university studies and applied research aimed at improving the quality of open spaces in the service of student learning, except for a few cases have been mild. In this regard, due to the lack of available scientific and professional knowledge of architecture and professional perspective can be a substantial contribution. In this context, this study aims to review and related documents in this area based on the factors involved in it. Methods In this descriptive study. The sample consists of integrated training Azad University of Hamedan, Bu Ali Sina University in Hamedan and Tehran's Imam Sadeq University. Based on the research findings place identity, emotional attachment, the quality of the physical and social links to attachment sites open spaces teaching the students have a significant effect.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>99</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>108</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>گودرزی سروش</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Mehdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Goodarzi Soroosh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد همدان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>goodarzisoroush@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>وحید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قربانی</Family>
				<NameE>Vahid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Qorbani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد همدان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>attachment to place</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>identity</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>location</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>quality of the physical</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>social ties</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>educational open space.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دلبستگی به مکان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>هویت مکان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کیفیت فضای کالبدی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پیوند اجتماعی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فضای باز آموزشی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>احیاء و ساماندهی بافتهای فرسوده شهری در راستای توانمندسازی زنان شهروند؛ موردپژوهی: اقدامات شهرداری تهران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Revive and reorganize the urban tissue for citizen empowerment of women Case: Municipality of Tehran</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
امروزه بافتهای فرسوده شهرها، نیازمند توجه بیشتری در حوزه برنامه ریزی و مدیریت شهری برای ساماندهی و احیاء می باشد که در این میان تغییر کاربری این فضاها همزمان با فرایند ساماندهی و نوسازی می تواند راهگشای استفاده مجدد از این فضاها باشد. از سویی دیگر، زنان سرپرست خانوار به عنوان یکی از اقشار آسیب‌پذیر اجتماعی لازم است مورد توجه مدیریت شهری و شهرداریها قرار گیرند که در این میان اقدامات مرکز امور بانوان شهرداری تهران در این رابطه حائز اهمیت است. بر این اساس، در این مقاله در روش توصیفی و تحلیلی و ارزیابی استدلالی به موضوع تغییر کاربری بافتهای فرسوده برای مراکز تفریحی، اجتماعی و اقتصادی بانوان منجمله مراکز شهربانو پرداخته شده است. مرجع تحلیل آمار مرکز امور زنان شهرداری تهران و تحلیل ادبیات نظری در این رابطه بوده است. نتایج تحقیق نیز ضمن اشاره به میزان خدمات رسانی شهرداری تهران و امور زنان منجمله در طرح های توانمندسازی و مجموعه های شهربانو، به ارائه راهکارهایی در راستای توانمندسازی زنان سرپرست خانوار شهر تهران در حوزه وظایف شهرداری و مدیریت شهری تهران معطوف شده و پیشنهاداتی را در این رابطه مورد اشاره قرار داده است.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
The old urban tissue requires more attention in the field of planning and urban management and restoration is to organize the change of use of the space at the same time that the process of reorganization and modernization can help the re-use of these spaces. On the other hand, female-headed households as a social vulnerable groups and areas of urban management should be considered. Meanwhile, the Women's Affairs Center in Tehran in this regard is important. Therefore, in this article in an analytical and rational assessment of the issue of the change of use of old tissues for recreation centers, social and economic had been women. Reference statistical analysis of the Women's Affairs Center of Tehran Municipality in this regard is the analysis of theoretical literature. The results alluding to the services of Tehran and the empowerment of women, including the design and SH series, to provide solutions to the empowerment of women-headed households is growing in Tehran.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>109</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>134</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مریم</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>فرج پور</Family>
				<NameE>Maryam</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Faraj Poor</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>farajpoor.m@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علیرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>دودانگی</Family>
				<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Dodangi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تربيت دبير شهيد رجايی تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سلطان زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Hosein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Soltan Zadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Empowerment</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>worn tissues</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>regulation and rehabilitation</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>women heads of households</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>the center of Tehran women\'s affairs</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>strategies and recommendations.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>توانمندسازی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بافتهای فرسوده</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ساماندهی و احیاء</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زنان سرپرست خانوار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مرکز امور زنان شهرداری تهران</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>راهکارها و پیشنهادات.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>گفتمان آینده‌پژوهیِ آرمانشهری در شهرهای امن اسلامی در بستر دُکترین مهدویت</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Discourse of utopian future studies in Iran on Mahdism doctrine</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
آینده‌پژوهی مجموعه تلاش‌هایی است که با واکاوی منابع، الگوها، و عوامل تغییر یا ثبات، به تجسّم آینده‌های بالقوّه و برنامه‌ریزی برای آنها می‌پردازد. آینده‌پژوهی بازتاب‌دهنده چگونگی زایش واقعیّت «فردا» از دل تغییر (یا ثبات) «امروز»، است. بر این اساس، ترسیم چشم‌اندازی جامع در حوزه شهرسازی و آینده شهرها در ایران اسلامی، نیازمند تدقیق در مولفه‌های آرمانشهر ایرانی- اسلامی آنهم شهرهای امن با رویکرد آینده‌پژوهی است که با توجه به گفتمان مهدویت، لازم است تا شهرها مطابق با ضوابط، اصول و معیارهای طراحی و آماده سازی شوند که زمینه‌ساز ظهور امام عصر (عج) و تحقق شهرهای مبتنی بر اصول و معیارهای فرهنگی دین مبین اسلام باشند. روش تحقیق مقاله، روشی توصیفی- تحلیلی است که از روش استدلالی نیز در تبیین مولفه‌های آرمانشهری، گفتمان مهدویت و فرآیند آینده‌پژوهی بهره برده است. در ضمن روش اسنادی و رجوع به مطالعات کتابخانه‌ای و اسناد موجود نیز مورد توجه بوده است. در این پژوهش در رویکرد آینده‌پژوهی و با رجوع به مفاهیم آرمانشهر ایرانی، و در قالب گفتمان صالحه مهدویت که در اینجا از اندیشه مهدویت امام خمینی (ره) به عنوان مبنای نظری استفاده کرده است، تلاش شده است تا مولفه‌ها، معیارها و راهکارهایی برای بسترسازی و آماده‌سازی شهر و تمدن ایرانی برای مقدمات ظهور و جایگاه و نقش برنامه‌ریزی شهری و شهرسازی در این رابطه پرداخته شود که به اختصار مورد اشاره قرار گرفته است.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
Analysis of future efforts with resources, models and agents of change or stability, to visualize the potential futures and plan for them Future reflects the reality of tomorrow's generation from the change (or stability) today. Accordingly, outlined a comprehensive vision of urban development and the future of cities in the Islamic Republic of Iran, the Iranian-Islamic utopia needs to scrutinize the components approach the future. According to the discourse of Mahdism, are required to comply with city regulations, principles and standards that are designed to prepare the ground for the emergence of Imam Mahdi (aj) and the realization of cities are based on the principles of Islam and cultural criteria. The research paper is descriptive method of reasoning also explains the components of the utopian discourse of Mahdism and futures benefited. The documentary method and reference to library studies and documents have also been considered. In this future approach and by reference to the concept of utopia Iranian Mahdism in a competent dialogue here the idea of Mahdism of Imam Khomeini is used as a theoretical basis. Try to components, standards and solutions for the infrastructure and preparing the groundwork for the emergence of Iranian civilization and the role of urban planning and urban development is addressed in this regard.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>135</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>164</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد مهدی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بلندیان</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Mehdi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Bolandian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>m.bolandian@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>future studies</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>architecture and urban planning discourse Mahdism</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>the Islamic utopia</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ژوهی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهر امن</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>گُفتمان مهدویت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آرمانشهر اسلامی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تبیین مفهوم مسکن و سکونت در رویکرد پدیدارشناسی و رهیافت پارادایم‌های فرهنگی زیستی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Phenomenological approach and the concept of living in the cultural paradigm of life</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
شکی نیست که معماری در تعاملی دوسویه «هم بر فرهنگ و هم از فرهنگ تاثیر گذاشته و تاثیر پذیرفته» است، چنانچه مقوله جامعه-شناسی مسکن سعی در شناسایی این حلقه‌های مفهومی و معناییِ تعاملاتِ فرهنگ (جامعه) و معماری مسکن دارد؛ لذا رسیدن به یک فرایند اندیشه ارتباطی خاص بینابینی، به‌عنوان ابزار و داده‌های فرآیند پایدارسازی بستر اجتماعیِ معماری با تکیه بر الگوی فکری خاص و نتایج اجتماعی مشخص به صورت واکنش‌های استاندارد ولی نسبی جامعه و نسبت به معماری با بازخورد ادراکی از معماری، از جمله مفاهیمی است که لازم است تا در رابطه فرهنگ و معماری خانه مورد بحث باشد. پرسش پیشینی مفهوم سکونت این است که آیا صرف جایگیری در یک فضا را می‌توان سکونت یافتن در آن نامید؟ روش تحقیق مقاله، «توصیفی و تحلیلی» و «روش استدلال منطقی» است که از «روش اسنادی» و مطالعات کتابخانه‌ای بهره برده است. در راستای نتایج تحقیق به مفهوم پدیدارشناختی سکونت و مفهوم سکونت زیستی در رویکرد پدیدارشناختی اشاره شده و در پایان پارادایم‌های فرهنگی خانه بر اساس نظریه‌های فرهنگی در پیدایش مجتمع های زیستی مورد اشاره قرار گرفته است که عبارتند از: «مطالعه معنای چندمجرایی فرهنگی معماری، مطالعه معنای نمادین فرهنگی معماری، رویکرد غیرکلامی در درک معنای فرهنگی، معماری قواعد فهم اشاره‌های فرهنگی معماری، و قواعد خوانش فرهنگی معماری و محیط.»
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
There is no doubt that architecture has boosted the interaction of culture and culture is affected and influenced. Sociology housing issues trying to identify the circle of conceptual and semantic interaction of culture (society) and housing architecture. Thought process to reach a predefined architecture feedback conceptual architecture needs to be discussed in terms of culture and architecture of the house. The previous question is that the only place of residence can live in a space Find it called? The research paper is an analytical and logical reasoning is used by documentary and library studies. In line with the results of the phenomenological concept of residence and the residence life mentioned in the phenomenological approach and the cultural paradigm in the development of complex biological home based on cultural theories have been discussed as follows: Cultural meaning of architectural, cultural and symbolic meaning of architecture, nonverbal approach in the sense of cultural, architectural and cultural references to understand the rules of architecture, and cultural readings architecture and environment rules.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>165</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>188</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>شاهین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>ایلکا</Family>
				<NameE>Shaahin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Ilka</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>بهروز</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>منصوری</Family>
				<NameE>Behrooz</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mansoori</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>emarate_khorshid@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید محمد رضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>نصیر سلامی</Family>
				<NameE>Seyyed Mohammad Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Nasir Salaami</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید علی اکبر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>صارمی</Family>
				<NameE>Seyyed Ali Akbar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Saremi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>housing</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>housing</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>homes and Iranian culture</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>cultural paradigms and phenomenology of residence.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سکونت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مسکن</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>خانه و فرهنگ ایرانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پارادایم های فرهنگی و پدیدارشناسی سکونت.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>رابطه عزت نفس سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی با رضایت شغلی در کارکنان شاغل شهر تهران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>The Organizational Self-Esteem and Commitment Relationship with Job Satisfaction among Employers Working in the City of Tehran</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی رابطه عزت‌نفس سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی بر رضایت شغل کارکنان شاغل یکی از موسسات خدماتی شهر تهران می‌باشد که از بین افراد شاغل این ارگان تعداد 181 نفر با روش تصادفی انتخاب شدند. برای جمع‌آوری اطلاعات از سه پرسشنامه عزت نفس سازمانی پیرس و گاردنر، کامینکر پرسشنامه تعهد سازمانی آلن و مایر (1990) و پرسشنامه رضایت شغلی JDI کندال و هیولین (1947) استفاده شد. برای تحلیل داده‌های پژوهشی از شاخص‌ها و روش‌های آماری شامل فراوانی و درصد و میانگین، انحراف معیار و ضریب همبستگی و تحلیل رگرسیون استفده شد. نتایج پژوهش نشان داد که بین عزت نفس سازمانی و رضایت شغلی همبستگی مثبت وجود دارد و بین تعهد سازمانی و رضایت شغلی رابطه مثبت و معنی‌داری وجود دارد و عزت نفس سازمانی و تعهد سازمانی می‌تواند پیش‌بینی‌کننده رضایت شغلی باشد.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
This article aims at investigating the organizational self-esteem and commitment relationship with job satisfaction among employers of an urban service-giving institute working in the City of Tehran among whom 181 persons are selected randomly. For data collection, 3 methods of organizational self-esteem questionnaire by Pierce and Gardener and Caminker, organizational commitment questionnaire by Alen and Mayer (1990), and job satisfaction questionnaire by Candal and Hulin (1974) are applied. For data analysis, some statistical indices are applies such as frequency, percentage, average, deviation, correlation, and regression analysis. The results show that there is a positive correlation between organizational self-esteem and job satisfaction and a meaningful and positive relationship between organizational commitment and job satisfaction, hence organizational self-esteem and organizational commitment can preserve job satisfaction.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>189</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>200</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمد تقی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حاجی عمو عصار</Family>
				<NameE>Mahammad Taqi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Haji Amoo Assaar</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>علوم انتظامی امين</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>راشن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عبداللهی</Family>
				<NameE>Rashen</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Abdollahi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>علامه طباطبايی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>rashinabdollahi@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>داریوش</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رحمتی</Family>
				<NameE>Dariush</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rahmati</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>علوم انتظامی امين</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>وحیده</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سادات فر  خجسته</Family>
				<NameE>Vahideh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sadat Far Khojasteh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تربيت مدرس</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational Self-Esteem</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Organizational Commitment</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Job Satisfaction.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عزت نفس سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>تعهد سازمانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رضایت شغلی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تحلیل فضایی فشار بخار آب در جنوب و جنوب‌‌ غرب ایران با استفاده از تکنیک-های‌ خودهمبستگی فضایی با تآکید بر مراکز و کانون‌های جمعیتی</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Spatial analysis of water vapor pressure in south and southwest of Iran using by spatial autocorrelation techniques emphasizing on population centers</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
بخار آب به عنوان مهم‌ترین گاز گلخانه‌ای نقش مؤثری در گرمایش زمین ایفاء می‌کند. از این رو شناخت وضعیت این عنصر اقلیمی در مناطق جمعیتی می‌تواند نقش مهمی در بررسی آسایش اقلیمی یک منطقه داشته باشد. لذا در این پژوهش ابتدا به بررسی خودهمبستگی فضایی و شناسایی الگوی رفتاری مقادیر فشار بخار آب در جنوب و جنوب‌غرب ایران با استفاده از تکنیک تحلیل اکتشافی داده‌های فضایی (ESDA) و آماره موران محلی پرداخته شده است و سپس تأثیرات این عنصر مهم اقلیمی در کانون‌های جمعیتی مورد بحث قرار گرفته است. در این راستا از داده‌های فشار بخار آب 78 ایستگاه سینوپتیک موجود در پهنه جغرافیایی جنوب و جنوب‌غرب ایران با طول دوره آماری مناسب و بالاترین درجه تفکیک زمانی بهره گرفته شد. برای انجام تحلیل‌های خودهمبستگی ابتدا محدوده مطالعاتی با توجه به بهینه‌ترین تفکیک مکانی، به یاخته‌های 9×9 کیلومتر (3338 یاخته) تقسیم‌ گردید. سپس مقادیر فشار بخار آب به صورت میانگین ماهانه، سالانه و دهه‌ای برای هر یاخته و با استفاده از نرم‌افزار MATLAB استخراج شد. نتایج تحلیل خودهمبستگی فضایی طی سه دهه گذشته (2010-1981) حاکی از تقویت خوشه‌های فشار بخار آب زیاد (بالا- بالا) و تضعیف خوشه‌هایی با مقادیر پایین (پایین- پایین) است. ایجاد خوشه‌های بالا-بالا فشار بخار آب در حاشیه خلیج‌فارس (به‌خصوص در استان بوشهر) و از بین رفتن مقادیر پایین- پایین در بخش‌های جنوبی زاگرس قابل مشاهده است. بررسی و مقایسه پراکندگی فضایی خوشه‌های بخار آب با خوشه‌های دمایی به عنوان یکی از مهم‌ترین پارامترهای تأثیرگذار بر روی فشار بخار آب، حاکی از خودهمبستگی مثبت و معنی‌دار در دوره مورد مطالعه بود. بنابراین، با توجه به اثر گذاری مستقیم و غیر مستقیم فشار بخار آب بر فعالیت های انسان و همچنین محیط طبیعی به عنوان بستر فعالیت های انسانی، استقرار جمعیت در کانون‌ها و مراکز جمعیتی مناطق مورد مطالعه، متأثر از نوسانات فشار بخار آب خواهد بود و این روند در آینده مشهودتر خواهد بود.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
As the most important greenhouse gas, water vapor plays a significant role in global warming. Therefore understanding this important climate parameter in populated area can play an important role in survey the climatic comfort. So in this research, first the spatial autocorrelation and identify behavioral patterns of water vapor pressure in South and Southwest of Iran with exploratory spatial data analysis (ESDA) and Anselin Local Moran statistic is investigated and then the effects of this important climatic parameter on population centers is discussed. In this context, the WVP data from 46 synoptic stations in South and Southwest of Iran with appropriate length and highest resolution were used. To analyze the spatial autocorrelation, study area due to the optimal spatial resolution were divided to pixels with the dimension of 9×9 km (3,338 pixels). By programming in MATLAB software, the monthly, annual and decadal WVP were extracted for each pixel. Spatial autocorrelation analysis suggested strengthening and weakening the high-high WVP clusters and Low-Low WVP clusters, respectively. So that high-high WVP clusters have extended near the Persian Gulf (Especially in the Bushehr provinces) and Low-Low WVP clusters have disappeared in southern parts of Zagros Survey and comparison of the spatial distribution of WVP clusters with temperature clusters, as one of the most important influential parameters, showed a significant positive autocorrelation in the study areaک Thus, according to the direct and indirect effects of WVP on human activities and natural environment as the basis of human activity, the establishment of population in population centers of studies area will be affected by fluctuations of WVP and this trend will be more pronounced in the future.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>201</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>220</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>یونس</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>خسروی</Family>
				<NameE>Yoones</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Khosravi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شهيد بهشتی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>younes_kh15@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسن</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>لشکری</Family>
				<NameE>Hasan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Lashkari</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شهيد بهشتی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی اکبر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>متکان</Family>
				<NameE>Ali Akbar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mottakaan</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شهيد بهشتی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عساکره</Family>
				<NameE>Hosein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Asaakareh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>زنجان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Spatial Statistics</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Spatial Autocorrelation</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Temperature</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Water Vapor Pressure</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Anselin Local Moran\'s</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Population.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>آمار مکانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>خودهمبستگی فضایی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>دما</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فشار بخار آب</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>موران محلی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>جمعیت.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بایسته‌های حقوقی بودجه نهادگرا</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Legal necessities of institutional budget</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
پژوهش پیرامون بودجه در ایران دارای پیشینه‌ای طولانی می باشد. در این تحقیق، مولفه‌های رویکرد برون‌سیستمی نظام حقوقی بودجه با عنایت به تحلیل نهادگرا تبیین و موانع اصلاح آن در ایران بررسی شده است. دستاورد این تحقیق، صرفنظر از طرح رویکرد جدیدی در رشته حقوق مالیه عمومی، بیان ضرورت‌ها، مبانی و راهکارهای اصلاح نظام حقوقی حاکم بر بودجه در ایران می باشد. مهم‌ترین دستاورد این تحقیق آن است که نظام حقوقی بودجه در ایران، بیشتر در پرتو نهادهای غیررسمی شکل گرفته و اگر چه بعد از انقلاب مشروطه، مجموعه قوانین و مقرراتی در این زمینه وضع گردید اما رویه‌های مربوط به حکمرانی، سازمان دولت و نهادهای‌ مرتبط با آن که موجب بسط نظام غارتی، تهدید مالکیت خصوصی، کم‌توجهی به لوازم توسعه و شاخصه‌های حکمرانی خوب در ایران بوده‌، لذا بدون اصلاح نهادِ دولت و ایجاد تحول در تصمیم‌گیری‌ها و تخصیص منابع، وضعیت نامطلوب گذشته استمرار خواهد داشت. بر این اساس بازنگری نظام حقوقی بودجه در گرو اصلاح حقوق اساسی و نظام اداری است.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
Searches around budget in Iran have an old history. In this research, we will explain components of the outside-systematic approach to the legal budget system with help of institutional analysis and study its correction barriers in Iran. This research’s achievement is principles and strategies for reformation legal budget system in Iran Regardless of the new approach in the field of public finance law. The most important result of this study is that the legal budgets system in Iran is  shaped In the light of informal organizations and although after the constitutional revolution a series of laws and regulations in this field enacted, but procedures of Ruling the government an related organizations, that caused extending the looting system, Threaten private property, inattention to the materials and characteristics of good governance in Iran, therefor without institutional reform and change in the state’s decision making process and Allocating resources, the situation will be perpetuated. Accordingly, legal budget system’s revision depends on constitutional and administrative system’s reform.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>221</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>234</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حمید</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>قهوه چیان</Family>
				<NameE>Hamid</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Qahve Chian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید سلمان</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سامانی</Family>
				<NameE>Seyyed Salmaan</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Samani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>هتران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>salman_samani@ut.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>outside-systematic approach</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>budget</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>institutionalism</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>political approach to budget</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نگاه برون سیستمی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بودجه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نهادگرایی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>رویکرد سیاسی بودجه.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تبیین معیارهای طراحی فضاهای فرهنگی با رویکرد پایداری اجتماعی و پویایی فضایی؛ موردپژوهی: فرهنگسراهای شهر تهران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Determine the design criteria of cultural approach to social sustainability and spatial dynamics Case Study: cultural center in Tehran</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
امروزه تبیین معیارهای پایداری فضاهای زیستی با رویکرد پایداری اجتماعی از مهمترین موضوعات در حوزه برنامه‌ریزی معماری و شهر است که باید در فرآیند طراحی معماری موردنظر قرار گیرد. از سویی دیگر، هدف از فرهنگسراها، ایجاد محیطی آزاد، صمیمی و دارای فضایی باز است که از طریق یک سیستم غیرمتمرکز اداره می‌شود. به بیان عامیانه می‌توان فرهنگسراها را پاتوق‌هایی فرهنگی با تعاملات اجتماعی دانست که به‌عنوان یک مرکز فرهنگی، بخشی از فعالیت‌های فراغتی را پوشش می‌دهد که به ضرورت طراحی معمارانه این فضاها برای پویایی اجتماعی اشاره دارد. بر این اساس، مقاله حاضر با بهره‌گیری از «روش توصیفی- تحلیلی» در مرحله نظری و «روش پیمایشی» در مرحله تحلیلی و با ابزار گردآوری داده مشتمل بر مطالعات کتابخانه‌ای و اسنادی به بررسی مفهوم پایداری اجتماعی در معماری و طراحی فضاهای فرهنگی پرداخته است و برای تحلیل داده‌های حاصل از پژوهش و تبدیل آن به احکام معماری و سپس طراحی، از روش چیدمان فضا استفاده شده است. در ادامه این داده‌ها به صورت نمودارهای هم‌ترازی و سپس به صورت نقشه‌های گاما آورده شده است و در مرحله‌ی نهایی با استفاده از این تحلیل‌ها و مطالعات صورت‌گرفته بر روی سایت و با توجه به استانداردها و برنامه‌ی فیزیکی، طراحی معماری فرهنگسرا صورت گرفته است. در پایان نیز به معیارهای طراحی فضاهای زیستی با درنظرگیری پایداری اجتماعی و پویایی فضایی اشاره شده و راهکارهایی در راستای بهبود وضعیت ساختاری و فرهنگی فرهنگسراهای شهر تهران برای پویایی اجتماعی و امکان‌دهی حضور در عرصه‌های جمعی مورد اشاره قرار گرفته است.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
Today explained social sustainability criteria for sustainable living spaces with a view of the most important issues in the field of architecture and city planning that must be considered in the process of architectural design. On the other hand, the objective of cultural centers, create a free, intimate and open space is through a decentralized system is run. Crudely can cultural centers, cultural and social interactions, known as a cultural center, part of the leisure activities covers the architectural design of these spaces for social mobility refers to the need. Accordingly, this paper using the &quot;analytical method&quot; in the conceptual phase &quot;survey&quot; in the analytical and data gathering tools including library and documentary studies to examine the concept of social sustainability in architecture and design, cultural spaces Paid. To analyze the data obtained from research into architecture and design rules, synapses space is used. In the data for gamma curves alignment and then given maps and In the final stage of this analysis and studies on the site according to the standards and physical, cultural, architectural design has been done. Finally, leveraging social sustainability criteria for designing living spaces and spatial dynamics are discussed and a solution to improve the cultural and structural social mobility and the possibility of forming cultural center in Tehran to attend the public arena has been discussed.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>235</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>262</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سحر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>سلماسی</Family>
				<NameE>Sahar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Salmasi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران جنوب</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>salmasi_sahar@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>لیلا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کریمی فرد</Family>
				<NameE>Leila</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Karimi Fard</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران جنوب</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>social sustainability</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>sustainable development</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>cultural and recreational complex</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>and component design criteria.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پایداری اجتماعی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>توسعه پایدار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مجتمع‌های فرهنگی- تفریحی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>معیارها و مولفه‌های طراحی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>جستاری بر مفهوم‌شناسی عرصه‌های عمومی شهری در بازخوانی نظریه‌ انتقادی و مکتب فرانکفورت</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Study on the concept of urban public areas and the Frankfurt School of critical theory in review</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
امروزه طرح و تعمیم نظریه های انتقادی به شهر و منجمله «عرصه های عمومی شهری» در ادامه تلاشهای انسان معاصر برای دست‌یابی به شرایط زیستی مطلوب به عنوان یکی از مهم‌ترین آرمانهای جنبش‌های اجتماعی و همچنین حاصل «غنای تجربه‌های تاریخی و ثمره نظری انباشتگی معرفتها» است. حوزه عمومی در واقع ایده یا مفهومی هنجاری است که در چارچوب کلی نظریات کلی هابرماس درباره کنش ارتباطی و اخلاق گفتگو جای دارد. حوزه عمومی بخشی از حیات اجتماعی است که در آن شهروندان می توانند به تبادل نظر درباره موضوعات و مسایل مهم مربوط به خیر عمومی (مصالح عامه) بپردازند. نتیجه این امر شکل گیری افکار عمومی است. فیلسوفان دموکراتیک نیز بر این باورند که این فضاها تجلی کالبدی حوزه عمومی، عرصه فعالیت، ارتباط و گفتگوی انسانهای آزاد و گروه های مختلف و همچنین محل شکلگیری حیات مدنی است. این مقاله با روش توصیفی- تحلیلی و روش اسنادی و استدلال منطقی و با ابزار گردآوری داده مشتمل بر مطالعات کتابخانه ای و اسنادی به بررسی برخی نظریه‌های انتقادی به شهر و مکتب فرانکفورت (بالاخص هابرماس، آرنت و هاروی) پرداخته است. در مرحله اول یافته‌های تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که نظریه‌پردازان مکتب فرانکفورت به دلیل تشابه در نظریه‌ها و آراء‌شان منجمله در انتقاد از نظام سرمایه‌داری متاخر و معاصر و پوزیتیویسم و مارکسیسم و انتقاد از مفاهیمی چون عقلانیت‌ابزاری، علم‌اثباتی و تجربی، شیء گشتگی انسان، از بین رفتن آزادی و استقلال انسان، که تحت نام اندیشمندان این مکتب قرار گرفته‌اند و در بعضی از مباحث و اندیشه‌های مطرح‌شان منجمله انقلاب و تغییر اجتماعی و کارگزاران آن در جامعه سرمایه‌داری و شیوه های آن، طرح یک نظام جانشین و آلترناتیو، شکل حکومت آینده بشر در شهرها و تغییرات عرصه های عمومی شهری در شهرهای آینده و غیره، با یکدیگر تفاوت دارند. در مرحله بعد نیز معیارها و مولفه هایی برای شکلگیری عرصه های عمومی در شهر مورد اشاره قرار گرفته است.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
Today, the design and expansion of critical theory to the city, including the &quot;public areas of the city&quot; in the efforts of modern man to achieve optimal living conditions as one of the most important goals of social movements as well as the result of &quot;the richness of historical experience and theoretical results the accumulation of knowledge &quot;is. Public domain in normative concept or idea that the general theoretical framework of Habermas's communicative action and ethics of dialogue instead The public sphere of social life in which citizens can discuss important issues related to the public good (public interest) to pay. The result is the formation of public opinion. Democratic philosophers believe that this physical manifestation spaces of the public sphere, sphere of activity, communication and dialogue open and various people as well as the formation of civil life. This paper documents and logical reasoning and analytical method and the method of data collection, including library and documentary studies to examine some of the critical theory of the Frankfurt School in the city (especially Habermas, Arendt and Harvey) were investigated. In the first phase, the research findings indicate that the Frankfurt School theorists because of their similarity in opinions, including criticism of capitalism and Marxism, and criticism of modern and contemporary and positivist concepts of rationality, science and empirical evidence, human object, the loss of freedom and independence of man, which are called scholars of this school. In some of the issues and their proposed ideas such as revolution and social change agents in capitalist society and its practices, and alternative plans for a successor system, the shape of the human future in the cities and urban areas in the cities of the future changes are different. Next, the criteria and elements for the development of public areas in the city have been mentioned.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>263</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>290</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی رضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بندر آباد</Family>
				<NameE>Ali Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Bander Abad</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>واراز</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مرادی مسیحی</Family>
				<NameE>Varaz</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Moradi Masihi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حامد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کاوش نیا</Family>
				<NameE>Hamed</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Kavosh Nia</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>hamed-kavosh@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حسین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عالی</Family>
				<NameE>Hosein</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Aali</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University></University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country></Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>critical theory</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>the Frankfurt School</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>public areas</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>urban public space</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>public sphere appearance criteria.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>نظریه انتقادی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مکتب فرانکفورت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>حوزه عمومی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فضای عمومی شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>معیارهای پدیداری حوزه عمومی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تدوین اصول و معیارهای ادراک فضایی در معماری بازارهای سنتی ایران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Principles and standards of architectural space perception traditional markets</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
بازارهای سنتی ایران با سابقه کهن خود در کنار جنبه اقتصادی، از نقش فعال اجتماعی و مذهبی نیز برخوردار بوده‌اند؛ به این صورت که بازار به‌صورت همزمان یک محور مهم ارتباطی، اقتصادی و فرهنگی شهر بوده و نقش و منزلت مهمی در حیات اجتماعی شهرهای ایران داشته است. از سویی دیگر، شهروندان با فضاهای شهری به طور اعم و بازارها بطور اخص، ارتباط ادراکی خاصی برقرار می‌کنند که نحوه کاربست فضا و مطلوبیت از آن را نیز تعیین می‌کند. در واقع فضایی در شهر می‌تواند در راستای پاسخ‌دهی محیطی مطلوب باشد که از نظر شهروندان نیز قابل درک باشد که باید در فرآیند مساله‌گشایی طراحی شهری و بازارهای مدرن در شرایط معاصر نیز مورد استفاده قرار گیرد. بر این اساس مقاله حاضر به تدوین اصول و معیارهای ادراک فضایی در معماری بازارهای ایرانی پرداخته است. نتایج و یافته‌های تحقیق، در رابطه با «ویژگی‌های نظام کارکردی بازار ایرانی، تبیین مدل مفهومی نظام کالبدی بازار ایرانی، نظام ادراکی در بازار ایرانی، تبیین مدل مفهومی نظام ادراکی بازار ایرانی، نظام معنایی بازار ایرانی و تبیین مدل مفهومی نظام معنایی» بوده است و در پایان نیز مدل جامع مفهومی ادراک فضایی بازارهای سنتی ایران مورد اشاره قرار گرفته است.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
Traditional markets with its ancient history in the economic, social and religious also have had an active role Market at the same time as a major hub for communication, economic and cultural city and an important role and position in the social life of cities in Iran. On the other hand, citizens of urban areas in general and the markets, in particular, the special relationship established perception that the use of space and also determines its desirability. The space in the city can be desirable in order to respond to the citizens understood to be in the process of problem solving contemporary design, modern markets and conditions used. The paper examines the principles and standards of architecture, spatial perception in Iran's market. The results and findings is in relation to 'functional characteristics of the Iranian market, explaining the conceptual model of the Iranian market physical, perceptual system in the Iranian market, explaining the concept of perceived Iranian market, meaning the Iranian market and explain the meaning of the concept&quot;. Finally, spatial perception model of traditional markets have been mentioned.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>291</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>316</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>زهرا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عباسی</Family>
				<NameE>Zahra</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Abbasi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقيقات</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>z_abbasi@srbiau.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>فرح</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>حبیب</Family>
				<NameE>Farah</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Habib</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقيقات</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>سید مصطفی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>مختاباد امرئی</Family>
				<NameE>Seyyed Mostafa</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Mokhtabad Amrei</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تربيت مدرس</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>market</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>cognitive processes</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>principles and standards of perception.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بازار</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فرآیندهای ادراکی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اصول و معیارهای ادراکی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تدوین مؤلفه‌های شفابخشی منظر در باغ‌های ایرانی و کاربرد آن در طراحی فضاهای باز شهری </TitleF>
		<TitleE>Developing the components of the healing garden design in Iran and its application in the design of urban open spaces</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
توجه به ارتباط میان منظر و سلامت در مدت زمان طولانی در فرهنگ‌ها و جوامع مختلف عیان گردیده است؛ لذا درنظرگیری رویکرد منظر تحت عنوان منظر شفابخش می‌تواند راهکاری موثر و سودمند در زمینه شفابخشی فضا به نظر رسد؛ چراکه با توجه به تلاش بیشینه طراحان منظر در جهت ایجاد خصوصیات شفابخشی در فضای چنین منظری، ارتقاء آسایش، کمک به سلامت، جلوگیری از ایجاد بیماری در مراتب عالی‌تر و در ضمن استفاده از روشهای درمانی انسانگرا و طبیعی تاحد زیادی مورد علاقه بشر امروزی به جای روشهای مکانیزه می‌باشد. لحاظ چنین رویکردی در مناظر فضاهای  باز شهری به منظور تحقق انجام ضرورتهای مدنظر مطرح شده و با توجه به فقدان پژوهشهایی در این حیطه، ابزاری کارساز و مفید خواهد بود که در این مقاله از میان مضامین دربرگیرنده رابطه منظر و سلامت که از اهمیت خاصی نیز برخوردار است، پژوهشگر را به رویکرد منظر شفابخش رهنمون نموده است. نتایج این تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که رویکرد طبیعی درمانگر ناشی از باغ‌های ایرانی و قابل استفاده در طراحی فضاهای باز شهری دارای این حسن است که می‌تواند رویکرد ارتقاء کیفی و زیست‌پذیری را در مناظر شهری ایران تثبیت کند و این گرایش را برای استفاده بهینه از طبیعت هرچند در سطح کم ولی با هدف وجود سطوحی در شهر برای کاهش تنش و افزایش سلامت و بعضاً ممانعت از بیماری از یکسو و از سوی دیگر حفاظت از میراث ارزشمند و تاریخی کشور (باغ‌های ایرانی) و باززنده سازی آنها تا حدممکن را در جامعه بارور کند؛ مزید بر این مطلب که تئوری‌های مربوط به منظر شفابخش عمدتاً در مورد فضاهای عمومی خاص و برای افراد ویژه‌ای مطرح شده‌اند.   
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
Given the relationship between landscape and health in a long time in different cultures and societies has been identified. The view leveraging as a healing approach can be useful and effective strategy in this field seem. According to the designer maximum effort in order to create the healing properties of such a perspective in the promotion of peace, contributing to health, prevent disease and also the use of therapies far superior humanistic and natural, and deserves a lot of the methods of modern man favorite is mechanized. Such an approach was made to meet the requirements addressed in the sights of urban open spaces covered in the above and given the lack of research in this area would be useful and effective tool. Therefore, in this article from the perspective of the relationship between these factors and health issues, including that of particular importance is also the lead researcher to approach healing perspective. The results show that the natural approach to health caused by Persian gardens and can be used in designing urban open spaces have the faith that can stabilize qualitative approach to urban landscapes Iran. This tendency for optimal use of nature, although at low levels, but the goal is to reduce stress and increase health and sometimes in preventing the disease on the one hand and on the other hand protect and historical heritage of our country (Garden of the Persia) and revitalization them to fertilize in the community.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>317</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>345</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>رکسانا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>عبداللهی</Family>
				<NameE>Roksana</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Abdollahi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقيقات تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>r.abdollahi@sriau.ac.ir</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>بهناز</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>امین زاده</Family>
				<NameE>Behnaz</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Amin Zadeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>آزاده</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شاه چراغی</Family>
				<NameE>Azadeh</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shah Cheraghi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقيقات تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>ایرج</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>اعتصام</Family>
				<NameE>Iraj</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Etesaam</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقيقات تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Iranian Paradise Garden</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>healing perspective</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>mental health</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>urban open space.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>باغ و پردیس ایرانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شفابخشی منظر</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>سلامت روان</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>فضای باز شهری.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>بودجه‌ریزی عملیاتی پاسخی به نیازهای مدیریت نوین دولتی (درآمدی بر نظام حقوقی بودجه ریزی عملیاتی ایالات متحده آمریکا) </TitleF>
		<TitleE>Operational Budget Planning an Answer to Modern Governmental Management Requirements (An Introduction to Legal System of Operational Budget Planning in USA)</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
امروزه تحولات بنیادینی در نظام بودجه‌ریزی کشورهای مختلف (بویژه کشورهای توسعه یافته) به دنبال تحول در سبک مدیریت دولتی آنها بوجود آمده است. در این کشورها به طور روزافزون بر عملکرد بودجه‌ای تاکید می‌شود و ضمن تاکید بر بهترین عملکرد، براساس قوانین مصوب، قوه مجریه موظف است که اطلاعات عملکرد گذشته و همچنین پیش بینی عملکرد آتی خود را در چهارچوب بودجه سالیانه به قوه مقننه ارائه دهد و همچنین از مدیران بودجه بخواهد که پس از اجرای بودجه، گزارش عملکرد بودجه را به قوه مقننه ارائه دهند. مفهوم نظارت قوه مقننه نیز متحول شده است. این نظارت هم اکنون لزوماً به معنای تطابق کارکردهای بودجه‌ای با قانون بودجه‌ نیست، بلکه همسو بودن و انطباق با هدف‌ها و برنامه‌های تعیین شده می‌باشد. این کشورها در تلاشند نظام بودجه ریزی خود را در یک فرایند بهبود یا تغییر به یک نظام عملکرد محور یا عملیاتی که در آن ارتباط بین اعتبارات بودجه‌ای و عملکرد دستگاه‌های اجرایی شفاف و قابل درک است، نزدیک‌تر سازند و از این طریق پشتوانه اطلاعاتی معتبر و قابل اطمینانی برای تصمیمات بودجه‌ای دولت و مجلس فراهم آورند. در چنین چارچوبی کارآیی، اثر بخشی و صرفه‌جویی به‌عنوان هدف اصلی بودجه‌‌ریزی مطرح می‌شود. در این پژوهش، نظام حقوقی (بودجه‌ریزی) دولت ایالات متحده آمریکا به عنوان اولین نظامی که مبدع و مجری بودجه ریزی عملیاتی بوده است مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. در حال حاضر چارچوب‌های قانونی ایالات متحده آمریکا در خصوص بودجه‌های فدرال بسیار جامع می‌باشد. قانونگذار با تصویب قانون عملکرد و نتایج فعالیت‌های دولت در سال 1993 ضمن جلوگیری از تکرار چالش‌ها گذشته، زمینه‌های قانونی استقرار بودجه ریزی عملیاتی را فراهم نمود. در این مقاله ضمن اشاره به مبانی بودجه ریزی عملیاتی، قانون بودجه و عملکرد تحلیل و در پایان چالش‌های پیش روی مجریان این شیوه از بودجه ریزی بیان شده است. 
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
There have been recent fundamental transformations in budget planning in different (specifically developed) countries due to their management style changes. In these countries there is a growing emphasis on budget-oriented performance and emphasizing on the best performance based on the ratified regulations, the executive power is obliged to present the previous performance data and also the prediction of its future performance framed with the annual budget to the parliament and request the budget managers to report the budget performance to the parliament after it is implemented. The concept of observation of the parliament has also changed. Currently such a performance does not necessarily mean the adaptation of budget performance with the budget law but its alignment and adaptation with the decided targets and plans. These countries, through a process of improvement or change, are trying to make the budget planning come closer to a performance-oriented order or some operation in which the budget credit and administrative departments relationship is clear and understandable and doing so, provide the government and parliament with a credible and reliable data support. In such a framework, efficiency, effectiveness and economization are introduced as the main targets of budget planning. In this study, the US system of budget planning is investigated as the first system presenting operational budget planning system, including a very comprehensive federal system. In this article, despite considering principals of operational budget planning, budget law and operation of analysis and finally the forthcoming challenges are presented.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>347</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>368</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>بنیامین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شکوه فر</Family>
				<NameE>Benyamin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shokoohfar</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>علامه طباطبايی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>b_shokouhfar@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>هادی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رحمانی</Family>
				<NameE>Hadi</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rahmani</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>شهيد بهشتی</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Modern Governmental Management</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Budget Law</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Operational Budget Planning</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Effectiveness</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>Efficiency.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>مدیریت نوین دولتی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>حقوق بودجه</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>بودجه‌ریزی عملیاتی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>پاسخگویی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اثربخشی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کارایی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>ارزیابی گردشگری شهری با تاکید بر توسعه زیرساختهای گردشگری و رقابت‌پذیری شهری؛ موردپژوهی: کلانشهر تهران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Evaluation of urban tourism with an emphasis on tourism infrastructure development and urban competitiveness Case Study: Metropolitan Tehran</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
امروزه «صنعت گردشگری» به‌ویژه «گردشگری شهری» در جهان از اهمیت خاصی برخوردار شده است و متأسفانه علی‌رغم توانمندی بالای ایران در این زمینه، جایگاه شایسته‌ای را در این صنعت پیدا نکرده است، لذا توجه به مسائل گردشگری و مقوله «رقابت‌پذیری شهرها»، می‌تواند در این زمینه بسیار مفید، واقع شود. با این‌حال آنچه که امروزه باید بیش از گذشته در گردشگری مورد توجه قرار گیرد، «ایده رقابت‌پذیری شهرها» و امکان‌سنجی ایجاد و شکل‌گیری شهرهای جهانی در مقوله «گردشگری شهری» در این موضوع می باشد. بر این اساس در این مقاله در روش توصیفی- تحلیلی در مرحله مبانی نظری و روش تحلیل ثانویه در مرحله تحلیل داده‌ها استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که رقابت‌پذیری گردشگری شهری کلانشهر تهران تنها در حوزه زیرساختهای شهربازی و مجتمع‌های اقامتی نیاز شدید به توسعه در این زمینه را لازم می کند. در عین حال در بعد زیرساختهای تفریحی، ازدیاد میزان کمی آنها و ارتقاء میزان کیفی آنها بالاخص در ابعاد ایمنی از موضوعات مهم در بعد رقابت پذیری شهر تهران است. در پایان راهکارهایی در ابعاد مختلف به تفصیل اشاره شده است.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
Today, tourism especially “urban tourism” in the world is very important. Unfortunately, despite the ability of Iran in this regard, the industry has found a worthy place. Therefore, tourism issues and the concept of “urban competitiveness” can be very useful in this context. However, what is now considered to be at increased tourism, “the idea of competitiveness of cities” and the feasibility of the creation and formation of global cities in the category of “urban tourism” in the subject. Accordingly, in this paper, the analytical method in the theoretical and secondary analysis of the data is used. The results show that the competitiveness of urban tourism metropolis of Tehran only amusement park in the area of infrastructure and the urgent need to develop residential complexes in this area is necessary. At the same time in the recreational infrastructure, increase the quantity and improve the quality of them, especially in terms of safety an important issue in terms of competitiveness in Tehran. The strategies mentioned in various aspects in detail.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>369</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>392</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>حامد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>فامیل نوروزی</Family>
				<NameE>Hamed</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Famil Nouroozi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد همدان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>شهرام</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شریفی</Family>
				<NameE>Shahram</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sharifi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد همدان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>shahramsharifi1986@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>آیلین</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شیدایی</Family>
				<NameE>Ailin</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Sheidaee</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تهران</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>urban tourism</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>world cities</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>infrastructure</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>tourism</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>strategies and recommendations.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>گردشگری شهری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>شهرهای جهانی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>زیرساختهای گردشگری</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>راهکارها و پیشنهادات.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>الگوی پیاده‌سازی اخلاق حرفه‌ای در سازمان‌های ایران</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Implementation model of professional ethics in organizations</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
مقاله حاضر براساس یک مطالعه میدانی تحت عنوان «طراحی الگوی پیاده‌سازی اخلاق حرفه‌ای در سازمان‌های ایران» تدوین گردیده است. پژوهش مزبور به لحاظ هدف؛ کاربردی و از نظر روش اجرا؛ توصیفی ـ پیمایشی است که با توجه به مراحل مدل‌سازی کمّی انجام شده است. در تحقیق مذکور ابتدا عوامل مؤثر بر اخلاق حرفه‌ای براساس روش اسنادی از منابع معتبر موجود، استخراج و سپس بر اساس تکنیک دلفی مهم‌ترین عوامل تأثیرگذار از نظر متخصصین مربوطه پالایش گردیده‌است. در ادامه نیز میزان تأثیر و اهمیت و اولویت هر یک از عوامل شناسایی شده، تعیین و الگوی مربوطه مبتنی بر یک رویکرد سیستمی طراحی شده است. یافته‌های تحقیق حاکی از آن است که عوامل مؤثر بر پیاده‌سازی اخلاق حرفه‌ای در سازمان‌ها در سه بُعد فردی، سازمانی و محیطی قابل مداقه می‌باشد. 
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
This article is based on a field study entitled &quot;Designing a model of implementation of ethics in organizations&quot; has been developed The purpose of the study in terms of application and the descriptive survey method that has been done with regard to the quantitative modeling In the first study of factors affecting professional ethics on the basis of evidence from reliable sources available on the Delphi technique extraction and refining most important factors of the respective experts. Furthermore, the effect and importance and priority of each of the identified factors to determine the pattern is designed based on a systematic approach. The findings suggest that factors affecting the implementation of professional ethics in organizations in three dimensions: individual, organizational and environmental factors can be contemplated.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>393</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>406</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>مهرزاد</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>شاه علی</Family>
				<NameE>Mehrzad</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Shahali</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان خوراسگان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>mshahali14@gmail.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>رشید پور</Family>
				<NameE>Ali</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Rashid Poor</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان خوراسگان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>اسماعیل</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>کاوسی</Family>
				<NameE>Esmail</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Kavoosi</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران شمال</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>علی اکبر</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>اعتباریان</Family>
				<NameE>Ali Akbar</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Etebarian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>آزاد اسلامی واحد اصفهان خوراسگان</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ethics</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>professional ethics</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>implementation pattern.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اخلاق</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>اخلاق حرفه‌ای</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>الگوی پیاده‌سازی.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>


	<ARTICLE> 
		<TitleF>تحلیلی بر ابعاد پیوستگی توده و فضا در عرصه‌های عمومی شهری</TitleF>
		<TitleE>Analysis of the continuity of the masses and public space in the city</TitleE>
		<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
		<ABSTRACTS>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
موضوع این مقاله، بررسی ابعاد پیوستگی و انسجام توده و فضا در عرصه های عمومی شهری است. داشتن پیوستگی و انسجام یکی از اصلی‌ترین معیارهای کیفیت فضاهای شهری محسوب می‌شود. فضاهای سنتی و بومی عمدتاً واجد چنین کیفیتی بودند. مدعای این مقاله آن است که در حال حاضر، هم از لحاظ عملی و هم از لحاظ نظری فضاهای شهری و علوم مرتبط با طراحی محیطی در این زمینه دچار چالش‌های اساسی هستند. نتیجه آن‌که به لحاظ نظری، رویکردهای نظری نسبت به‌این موضوع فاقد جامعیت لازم بوده و در عمل، اکثر فضاهای شهری فاقد پیوستگی و انسجام لازم می‌باشند. نوشتار حاضر با رویکردی پدیدارشناختی - روان‌شناختی، موضوع پیوستگی و انسجام فضاهای عمومی شهری را مورد مطالعه قرار داده و معیارهای پیوستگی ساختمان و شهر در فضاهای عمومی شهری را بررسی نموده‌است. با رویکرد پدیدارشناختی، مطالعه صرفاً محدود به وضعیت فضاهای عمومی شهری با توجه به شرایط خاص آنها فارغ از عوامل علی گردیده است. با رویکرد روان‌شناختی، نقش مردم در ادراک و شناخت پیوستگی ساختمان و شهر در فضاهای عمومی شهری مطالعه شده‌است. در این مقاله پیوستگی ساختمان و شهر در فضاهای عمومی شهری، تابعی از پیوستگی فضا در ابعاد کالبدی، فضایی، اجتماعی- فعالیتی، و نمادین معرفی شده‌است.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
			<ABSTRACT>
			<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
			<CONTENT>
The objective of this paper is to examine the coherence and consistency of the masses and the public space in urban areas. The continuity and integrity of one of the main criteria is the quality of urban spaces. Mainly indigenous and traditional spaces such quality criteria. The paper claims that now, both practical and theoretical areas of urban and environmental design associated with the main challenges are in the field. The result is that, in theory, theoretical approaches to this issue and no recall was necessary in practice, many urban areas lack the coherence and cohesion is necessary. The present article is a phenomenological approach - psychological, the continuity and coherence of urban public spaces and buildings studied and integration criteria of the urban public spaces is investigated. Phenomenological approach, limited to the study of urban public spaces according to their specific circumstances regardless of causal factors were The psychological approach, the role of public perception and understanding of the continuity of the building and the city's public spaces of the city In this conjunction buildings and public spaces in the city, a function of the continuity of physical space, spatial, social activity, and symbolic introduced.
</CONTENT>
			</ABSTRACT>
		</ABSTRACTS>

		<PAGES>
			<PAGE>
			<FPAGE>407</FPAGE>
			<TPAGE>428</TPAGE>
			</PAGE>
		</PAGES>

		<AUTHORS>
			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>منصور</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>یگانه</Family>
				<NameE>Mansoor</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Yeganeh</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تربيت مدرس</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email>yaghane@yahoo.com</Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>

			<AUTHOR>
				<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
				<MidName></MidName>
				<Family>بمانیان</Family>
				<NameE>Mohammad Reza</NameE>
				<MidNameE></MidNameE>
				<FamilyE>Bemanian</FamilyE>
				<Organizations>
				<Organization></Organization>
				</Organizations>
				<Universities>
				<University>تربيت مدرس</University>
				</Universities>
				<Countries>
				<Country>ايران</Country>
				</Countries>
				<EMAILS>
				<Email></Email>
				</EMAILS>
			</AUTHOR>
		</AUTHORS>


		<KEYWORDS>
			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>coherence</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>totality</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>of continuity</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>continuity standards</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>the building and the city</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>subjective and objective.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>انسجام</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>کلیت</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ابعاد پیوستگی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>معیارهای پیوستگی</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>ساختمان و شهر</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>

			<KEYWORD>
				<KeyText>عینیت و ذهنیت.</KeyText>
			</KEYWORD>
		</KEYWORDS>

		<REFRENCES>
			<REFRENCE>
				<REF>## ##</REF>
			</REFRENCE>
		</REFRENCES>

	</ARTICLE>

</ARTICLES>

</JOURNAL>
</XML>
