<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" 

"journalpublishing3.dtd">

<article 
article-type="research-article"
dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en" 
xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
>

<front>

<journal-meta>

  <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">1</journal-id>
  <issn>1607-2227</issn>

  <publisher>

	<publisher-name> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher-name>
  </publisher>

</journal-meta>



<article-meta>

  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">804</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Factors affecting the feeling of security with an emphasis on social factors (Case study: the villages of south of Tehran province)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>7</fpage>

  <lpage>22</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The Feeling of security is an important issue that is necessary for to continue the growth and development, and Increase work and activities incentives in the community. This issue in rural areas Because of the nature of the activity and production in wide and spread land in the territory, has a double significance. Tehran Province is one of the central provinces of the country. The literal definition of the security, is protection against risk (objective security), the feeling of safety (subjective security) and freedom from doubt (confidence in personal receipts). The feeling of social security, is a positive mental mindset and orientation of citizens (convincing, relaxing) about the presence and influence of anti-security events and incidents (threats) in current and future conditions in the community. The feeling of financial security is to ensure people's assets and wealth against theft and robbery. The feeling of financial security is an assurance that can be achieved from providing material and financial needs. The feeling of financial security is established when a person feels that his property is inviolable and protected. On the other hand, 877 thousand people in this province are living in 757 rural settlements. Therefore, Aim of this study is investigate the Feeling of security of villagers and factors affecting it, in south of Tehran province. This research based on the objective is an Applied Research. This study, according to analysis of the current situation and assess the relationship between the variables is a descriptive- analytical research. The statistical population, is all heads of households in rural areas in south Tehran province. According to the 1390 census, the statistical population is 105,963 people. To calculate the sample size, the Cochran formula was used and 380 people were estimated. In order to select respondents, multi-stage sampling was used. Initially, in the first stage of sampling, three county of Varamin, Ray and shareyar were selected. An in the second stage, 24 villages were randomly selected, and were interviewed. The results show that all the variables including fighting in the village, The number of deaths in the village, number of arrests in the village and the number of suicides in the village there was a negative significant relationship with the feeling of security.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">805</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Investigating the Effect of Size of Entrepreneurial Marketing Strategy on Innovative Performance of Small and Medium (SMES) Company</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>23</fpage>

  <lpage>34</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Mixed marketing consisted of two distinct disciplines, to describe the marketing processes that companies looking for opportunities in uncertain market conditions and often are under conditions of limited resources. The aim of this study is to identify the impact of entrepreneurial marketing on the innovative performance of small and medium-sized company of Khorasan province. Hypothesized relationships between entrepreneurial marketing dimensions and the innovative performance of small and medium sized companies, with data through a structured questionnaire in person the manager and owner of 360 small and medium companies in Khorasan province have been selected to sampling, the collected and tested. &amp;nbsp;Methods in this study consisted of the nature, applied and descriptive - correlation dimension. For validity of questionnaire, content validity and reliability of Cronbach's alpha, its results for the questionnaire was 97.25%, , for data analysis, structural equation modeling with Partial Least Squares approach of Smart PLS software has been used. Results of the analysis showed that there is a positive relationship between the dimensions of entrepreneurial marketing; predictor measures, opportunity-oriented, risk-taking and leverage resources with innovative performance.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">806</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Identifying and Evaluating the Importance of ethical Criteria in Service organizations in order to formulating the Ethical charter (Case Study: Mashhad Municipality)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>35</fpage>

  <lpage>56</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>


Nowadays, massive improvements in management science, Pay attention to ethical principles and human individualities, are Inevitable for managers. It is clear that lack of respect for ethical principles in dealing with interests, Create problems for organizations and Challenges about legitimacy of the organization and its actions, and affected Profitability, success and effectiveness of the organization. The purpose of this study is Identification of ethical responsibilities of Mashhad municipality as an example of a large service organization in return of internal and external stakeholders and also Identification of their importance and priority and Finally Formulate organizational Code of Ethics. For this purpose first Reviewed Literature and identified ethical codes. Then with Using the questionnaire, was taken viewpoints of expert municipal managers regarding the importance above-mentioned Indicators and determinate level of importance and priority of these indexes by using different statistical tests. Finally prepared the draft of the ethical charter and provided senior managers and was applied the reform and Released final document.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">807</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Shiie ideal atmosphere and environment compatibility analysis of theoretical approaches against Islam and the West</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>57</fpage>

  <lpage>86</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Despite the fact that since the concept of development in its broadest sense, a fundamental role in the development of its natural resources and the environment, until recent decades of neglect was paying serious attention to it. The economic growth brought the consequences of technological progress in the field of environment and natural resources and As concern for ecological economists and scientists upset. Look especially Shiite Islam and the concept of urban adaptation to the environment and nature can be at odds with the West theoretical approaches is considered essential in the planning of urban spaces. However, in this paper, the concept of an ideal space Shiite and environmental compatibility of Islam and the West is opposed to theoretical approaches The analytical method and benefited method of logical reasoning. Finally, the themes and contrasting examples of theoretical approaches mentioned Islam and the West And an ideal place for nature and the environment in the Shiite cities were explained as a model that can interact with the city's comprehensive and considered urban environment.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">808</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Semantic analysis of the visual effects of light in the Iranian architecture case Iranian houses</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>87</fpage>

  <lpage>106</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

We live in a visual age where image is part of its architecture. The symbolic nature of light and imaginative mind of man comes. There is a clear preference of light over darkness. Existence, is pure light, and not darkness, and darkness. When darkness and brightness to their maximum intensity and penumbra remove or trivial, the positive and negative space created. During the day, natural light physical characteristics of areas inside the shape and form of identity is created. In this paper, semantic analysis of the visual effects of light in architecture (houses in Iran) were studied. Qualitative research methods were used in an interpretive approach Azjlvh visual elements for the operation were light, and values, meanings were analyzing light. Results, light control elements in Iranian homes, visual analysis of Iranian architecture is light.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">809</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Budgeting is an opportunity for democratic management of public spending (Case United States of America)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>107</fpage>

  <lpage>124</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

However, in all countries with democratic political system of absolute supremacy of Parliament in matters relating to the &amp;quot;budget&amp;quot; included in their legislation. But the role of the legislature in the budget process in all systems are not equal. In a general classification, the country's legislature in budgeting reflects the fact that countries do not have similar legal systems, each based on the particular circumstances and political, social and economic, are a particular system. We concluded that the legal system is based on three types of funding constitutes the legislative authority noted: First, the legal system in England that has very little to delegate legislative body, to the extent that the budget proposed by the government, is actually rarely changed and improved. Second, the military, the first system in the opposite direction, and this institution has wide powers to the parliament of the autonomous government bill makes the system, the legal system governing the process of preparing and approving the budget in the United States. (Also, according to the powers that the French parliament, the Philippines, Nigeria, and to some extent the South Korean parliament is expected to consider and approve the budget, the two countries can be considered one of the countries rely on the legal system of the second type). Third, much of the legal system in countries such as Sweden are valid, based on the methods of advertising between the two systems is mentioned. This means that the correction to the legislature granted this authority is limited in practice marginal reforms. In this study, the United States of America considered the state budget. Assess the developments in the US financial rights and property rights system budget has been different dimensions in this regard, the role of the Congress in determining the country's fiscal policy has changed.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">810</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Analysis of factors affecting the performance marketing with an emphasis on marketing capabilities of firms and services Case Study: Company Sinjergaz</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>125</fpage>

  <lpage>152</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

With the increased competition, into local markets to international markets and diversity and cultural diversity and social needs and demands of customers in different markets, the growing need for market orientation is felt. Successful managers are the ones who make your organization keep pace with the day. This synchronization is when employees and managers tend to accept the market as a culture and vision. The ability to rapidly introduce new products and adopt new processes are also an aspect of competition. Special assets and implicit and unchanging innovation capability of a company is closely connected with inner experiences and empirical studies. The analysis of the factors affecting the performance of marketing services firms, with emphasis on marketing capabilities in important cases that can affect the orientation. The development of applied knowledge and practical application of research to identify the most important factors affecting the company's marketing function, is an applied research. Considering the discussions and the very strong marketing capabilities with the company's marketing performance, brand equity, the effect of marketing capabilities and brand value of the company's marketing performance is evaluated Sinjergaz.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">811</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Application of science in architecture and urban design, environmental psychology with an emphasis on the principles and criteria Design of residential complexes</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>153</fpage>

  <lpage>178</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Today, the status of the behavioral sciences in urban design and architecture and how the space on the incidence of human behavior, including conceptual and operational issues that need to review that illustrates the real position is in architectural design, environmental psychology. In fact, knowledge of urban design and environmental psychology knowledge such as behavioral science can provide the opportunity for designers to meet the needs and culture of users, to design spaces and The conditions favorable for life for urban spaces to be provided. Due to population growth and urbanization, and the research on the psychological aspects and behaviors associated with this approach has been paid, so in this study, we link between psychology and architectural areas, especially urban design with the base the psychology environmental and architectural importance of the relationship between environment and design (especially urban design) should be considered. The methodology of this paper is to describe - analytical methods for the analysis and content analysis has been used to study the researches related to this issue. In the end, the important design principles and standards of residential complexes and a few points in this regard is mentioned.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">812</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Accountability-based management: Introduction to financial management based on the performance of the Government of Canada</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>179</fpage>

  <lpage>192</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Budgeting In The Public Sector Relating To Anticipated Sources And Uses Of Funds For The Missions And Tasks Of The State. In This Definition, Budgetary Information Reflects Financial And Administrative Decisions In Accordance With The Framework Of The Budget Synonymous Or Activities Of The Government. Overall, The Budget Is The Most Important Tool For Development Programs And Policies. متن یا آدرس وب سایت را تایپ کنید یا سندی را ترجمه کنید.

The Specific Objectives May Be Called Resources, Economic Stability And Social Justice Was Mentioned. The Basic Changes In The Budgeting System Of Different Countries (Especially Developed Countries) Are Looking For A Change In Management Style They Have Been Made Public. In These Countries Increasingly On Performance Budgeting Is Emphasized And Emphasized The Best Performance, According To The Statutes, The Executive Is Obliged To Historical Performance Data And Predict Future Performance In The Framework Of The Annual Budget To The Legislature Offer The Fund Managers Seek After The Implementation Of The Budget, Budget Performance Reports Presented To The Legislature. The Legislature Has Changed The Concept Of Supervision. The Monitoring Functions Of The Budget Now Does Not Necessarily Mean Compliance With The Budget Law (Rules And Regulations Governing), But Is Determined In Accordance And Compliance With The Goals And Programs. In This Article We Have Tried Budgeting Impact On The Development Of The Executive Branch Accountability In The Use Of Public Funds In Canada To Be Checked.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">813</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Presentation of economic performance improvement model based on green marketing strategies with environment protection role; Case study of Tehran municipality</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>193</fpage>

  <lpage>208</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The destruction of environment and social concerns for continual development has changed competitive scenarios and has confronted organizations with new challenges. This research by presenting a model of economic performance improvement has analyzed the impact of green marketing strategies on performance. The research population in this study consists of municipal staff of Tehran. Data collection was done by implementing probable sampling method with a sample mass of 192 and the data analysis and study was carried out by means of structural equation test with the least square method by the use of (PLS) software. The findings show that implementing a single green marketing strategy along with service and product quality development, corporate image and environmental protection directly and indirectly facilitate economic performance aspects as well as reducing the expenses and increasing the efficiency. Similarly, environmental protection and service and product quality improvement has a positive impact on corporate image.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">814</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title></article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>209</fpage>

  <lpage>226</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>


</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">815</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Examine ways to increase the efficiency of urban parks and green spaces; Case: urban parks Arak</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>227</fpage>

  <lpage>248</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Urban parks in terms of its functional capabilities as the possibilities for improving the quality of the world's cities. Urban Parks has two major functional aspects: first, the effect of green spaces and parks in promoting environmental conditions as lung of the city, and secondly, the role of urban land uses in a variety of leisure citizens by providing leisure individual and collective. With such a background, this paper aims to provide solutions and guidelines to improve the efficiency of urban public parks with an emphasis on the city, based on the results of theoretical studies, surveys and polls of people and experts to identify and analyze the barriers inhibiting or reducing the overall productivity of urban parks to be explored. The solutions to remove or reduce these barriers and increase the attractiveness and public reception of the urban public spaces is presented. Physical and functional characteristics of all the parks in the city and study the strengths and weaknesses of the park were evaluated in relation to citizens. We provide a functional hierarchy of the city park based on existing conditions and constraints and possibilities of each park inspired by the experiences we have in the planning and urban parks. In addition, some parks that have been in place special conditions or specific proposals have been presented.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">816</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Critical discourse analysis models and theories of cognitive symptoms in Architecture and Urban Design</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>249</fpage>

  <lpage>272</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Semiotics is the science that explores a variety of symptoms, their interpretation, and rules governing pay symptoms. And how to communicate and meaning in things and different sign systems studies. Semiotics with check sign helps people understand the world around them through signs. And helps to encrypt and decrypt become symbolic systems and enables people to communicate through these symptoms can interact with the world around them. The method of this paper analysis and analytical reasoning is in line with semiotic analysis, critical discourse on architecture and urban planning is concerned. The findings of this study and the genealogy of the models and theories of architecture and urban design is semiotic analysis. Finally, semiotic analysis model applicable to all views presented semiotic experts. Which can be used as an example of superior sound and semiotic analysis used.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">817</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>The role of ecology in the environmental quality culture model (the study of Islamic Azad University of Tehran Province)</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>273</fpage>

  <lpage>292</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The title of the study, the environmental - ecological model of quality culture. Daniel Ehlers cultural aspects - psychological and structures - manage the introduction and the study on the environmental study - Ecology has added to it. The research was descriptive and statistical population includes both the community. The first experts to plan and adjust the components and second experts to confirm the factor loadings component and a visiting faculty members of Islamic Azad University in Tehran were selected. Measurement tools, self-designed questionnaire environmental dimension - Ecology 10 components and 33 questions and 5-point Likert scale was used to assess the validity and content validity by experts calculate the validity and relevance of the questions was confirmed and components . The Cronbach's alpha coefficient was used to test its validity in this study environmental value - Ecology 0.907 respectively. The results showed that loadings and environmental significance level calculated - Ecology 10 components, component loadings associated with the administration of 10.00, the social environment component with factor loadings of 9.97 and 9.39 component factor loadings customers with the highest factor loadings between 10 factors respectively.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">818</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Behavior model design canvas - Iran offered to public organizations</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>293</fpage>

  <lpage>312</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The purpose of this paper model design canvas - the action for public organizations of Iran. Ecological behavior - before doing the action in protected environments helps identify the behaviors in this article are three levels of individual, institutional, and environmental factors associated with the components and it is intended. The method is based on the purpose, nature descriptive, cross-sectional view and in terms of the type of data is qualitative. Statistical research, public managers and deputy director of Tehran province through the sample of 255 people, 720 of which were considered as examples. Questionnaire consisted of 90 questions that confirm its validity and its reliability by using Cronbach's alpha with the 924/0 has been approved. Using descriptive and inferential statistics (confirmatory factor analysis) were analyzed research data. The results showed that ecological behavior before action at all three levels studied, along with the components and indicators is approved.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">819</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>The definition of local territory: conceptual analysis with an emphasis on psycho-perceptual and conceptual models</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>313</fpage>

  <lpage>326</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

We are social beings and human societies throughout human history in the form of organizations and certain locations such as urban, rural and different ways of living has brought to fruition. One of the communities that existed from ancient times urbanization that has transformed the urban neighborhoods of cities over time in the structure, content and structure have been seen. The scope and limits of social space and urban neighborhoods in cities today have changed. The scope and limits of social space and urban neighborhoods in cities today have changed. Thus, perceptions and behaviors of different people to each local territory and its neighborhood (neighborhood community) is followed. Including approaches to redefine the territory of communities and strengthen a sense of place and sense of community perception of the residents of the neighborhood domains has been raised, how to define these territories based on subjective perception and behavior of their residents. This article discusses the anatomy of the territory of the neighborhoods in the city, first the effective components and common approaches in determining the scope of the neighborhood, is discussed. And the expression of different theories and research done in this field, we see that most studies rely on a range of official statistics that these limits, does not show actual locations. Analysis study documents the need to practice &amp;quot;internal analysis&amp;quot; was conducted. Thus, the content of the sources and documents, the recognition criteria, theoretical and philosophical ideas were analyzed and several results including multi-domain nature areas, differences in perceptions of people with a range of statistical follows Winning, ultimately providing a conceptual model based on objective and subjective factors, the range (the second layer of the atmosphere of the neighborhood) as the neighborhoods of the territory and to pay more attention in future research suggests.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">820</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Management of the Shiie Islamic cities</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>327</fpage>

  <lpage>354</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Discussion on the Islamic city is: What characteristics and components of the important issues that need to be studied in the field of urban management in Islamic cities. Therefore, it seems necessary to answer such questions and to Islamic utopia recognition and its management by identifying and recognized components, the possibilities and provide recreation Shiite Muslim city. The Islamic utopia features and characteristics that will distinguish it from other cities and other countries. These features, in fact, refers to the approach to phenomena such as believer and Muslim world, the hereafter, man and the universe and God. In this article, descriptive - analytical and managerial qualities in Islamic cities in Shiite cities studied, with emphasis on theoretical and conceptual aspects of the analysis. At the end of the characteristics mentioned in detail theoretical and practical principles is phenomenal.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">821</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>The Effects of Brand Experiences, Trust and Satisfaction on Building Brand Loyalty, Case study: KALLEH dairy products</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>355</fpage>

  <lpage>368</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

The purpose of this study has been the brand experience on satisfaction، Trust and loyalty of KALEH dairy productions. To this aim،using questionnaire of statistical population was the consumers in HYPERMI and HYPERSTAR stores who were exposed by sampling in KALEH dairy products and the statistical sample has selected randomly available the number of 384 people and using factor analyzing as well as structured equation modeling to analyze data. As a result of this study, brand experiences, satisfaction, trust have positively effects brand loyalty. 

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">822</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Analysis of the concept of living and housing in theory culturalism reviewed with emphasis on the views of Amos Rapoport</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>369</fpage>

  <lpage>402</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Rappaport including anthropology pioneer in the field of space and architectural know, who knows both the body and the culture and trying to connect the two analyzes together. Therefore the authenticity of any of these two elements and not to a reciprocating relationship between them believes. In other words, it is true that human beings shape the environment but as soon as it was built environment can organize and control human behavior. So he rejected the man's passive position and instead suggests an interaction between him and the environment. In this article, descriptive - analytical and analytical reasoning Rappaport in shaping the view of the environment is complex. Finally, sum up and draw the necessary conclusions in this regard are provided. The results indicate that the formation of his life and the concept of housing complexes to purely cultural dimension knows that divides them: 1. theories that consider space determines human relations. 2. Comments that human relationships are forming space. And (3) theories that consider space and human interaction.

</body>

</article>


  <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">823</article-id>

  <article-categories>
	<subj-group>
	  <subject>Special</subject>

	</subj-group>
  </article-categories>

  <title-group>
	<article-title>Investigation and analysis of biological anthropology with an emphasis on areas of domestic spaces</article-title>

  </title-group>

  


  <contrib-group>

  
	<contrib contrib-type="author">

	  <name>

		<surname></surname>
		<given-names></given-names>
	  </name> 
	</contrib> 
	

  </contrib-group>

  
			<aff>

			
	</aff>
 
 
  


  <pub-date pub-type="pub">

	<day>1</day>
	<month>6</month>

	<year>2016</year>

  </pub-date>

  <volume>15</volume>

  <issue>42</issue>

  <fpage>415</fpage>

  <lpage>427</lpage>

  
			  <history>

				<date date-type="received">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
			  <history>

				<date date-type="accepted">

				  <day>12</day>
				  <month>03</month>
				  <year>2016</year>
				</date>

			  </history>

		
</article-meta>

</front>



<body>

Home From an economic standpoint a &amp;ldquo;product&amp;rdquo;, from an artistic perspective &amp;ldquo;symbolic&amp;rdquo;, from a sociological point of view &amp;ldquo;institution&amp;rdquo; from the viewpoint of Engineering and Architecture by or building, Urban &amp;ldquo;space&amp;rdquo; and the anthropological vision of a &amp;ldquo;culture&amp;rdquo; is that all those aspects. Leave the house and its place in the system of social relations of people and society by considering all aspects of the symbolic, institutional, material and aesthetic home or &amp;ldquo;house of culture&amp;rdquo; is possible. In anthropology comprehensive or holistic way of looking at the human and social affairs &amp;ldquo;holistic approach&amp;rdquo; call. In the &amp;ldquo;Culture House: Origins, functions and templates&amp;rdquo; these concepts as the theoretical framework of the study. This article examines the anthropological aspects of home living spaces and homes in approach and understanding of cultural spaces housing will be discussed.

</body>

</article>

