<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>39</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تحلیل فضایی فشار بخار آب در جنوب و جنوب‌‌ غرب ایران با استفاده از تکنیک-های‌ خودهمبستگی فضایی با تآکید بر مراکز و کانون‌های جمعیتی</title_fa>
	<title>Spatial analysis of water vapor pressure in south and southwest of Iran using by spatial autocorrelation techniques emphasizing on population centers</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
بخار آب به عنوان مهم‌ترین گاز گلخانه‌ای نقش مؤثری در گرمایش زمین ایفاء می‌کند. از این رو شناخت وضعیت این عنصر اقلیمی در مناطق جمعیتی می‌تواند نقش مهمی در بررسی آسایش اقلیمی یک منطقه داشته باشد. لذا در این پژوهش ابتدا به بررسی خودهمبستگی فضایی و شناسایی الگوی رفتاری مقادیر فشار بخار آب در جنوب و جنوب‌غرب ایران با استفاده از تکنیک تحلیل اکتشافی داده‌های فضایی (ESDA) و آماره موران محلی پرداخته شده است و سپس تأثیرات این عنصر مهم اقلیمی در کانون‌های جمعیتی مورد بحث قرار گرفته است. در این راستا از داده‌های فشار بخار آب 78 ایستگاه سینوپتیک موجود در پهنه جغرافیایی جنوب و جنوب‌غرب ایران با طول دوره آماری مناسب و بالاترین درجه تفکیک زمانی بهره گرفته شد. برای انجام تحلیل‌های خودهمبستگی ابتدا محدوده مطالعاتی با توجه به بهینه‌ترین تفکیک مکانی، به یاخته‌های 9×9 کیلومتر (3338 یاخته) تقسیم‌ گردید. سپس مقادیر فشار بخار آب به صورت میانگین ماهانه، سالانه و دهه‌ای برای هر یاخته و با استفاده از نرم‌افزار MATLAB استخراج شد. نتایج تحلیل خودهمبستگی فضایی طی سه دهه گذشته (2010-1981) حاکی از تقویت خوشه‌های فشار بخار آب زیاد (بالا- بالا) و تضعیف خوشه‌هایی با مقادیر پایین (پایین- پایین) است. ایجاد خوشه‌های بالا-بالا فشار بخار آب در حاشیه خلیج‌فارس (به‌خصوص در استان بوشهر) و از بین رفتن مقادیر پایین- پایین در بخش‌های جنوبی زاگرس قابل مشاهده است. بررسی و مقایسه پراکندگی فضایی خوشه‌های بخار آب با خوشه‌های دمایی به عنوان یکی از مهم‌ترین پارامترهای تأثیرگذار بر روی فشار بخار آب، حاکی از خودهمبستگی مثبت و معنی‌دار در دوره مورد مطالعه بود. بنابراین، با توجه به اثر گذاری مستقیم و غیر مستقیم فشار بخار آب بر فعالیت های انسان و همچنین محیط طبیعی به عنوان بستر فعالیت های انسانی، استقرار جمعیت در کانون‌ها و مراکز جمعیتی مناطق مورد مطالعه، متأثر از نوسانات فشار بخار آب خواهد بود و این روند در آینده مشهودتر خواهد بود.
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
As the most important greenhouse gas, water vapor plays a significant role in global warming. Therefore understanding this important climate parameter in populated area can play an important role in survey the climatic comfort. So in this research, first the spatial autocorrelation and identify behavioral patterns of water vapor pressure in South and Southwest of Iran with exploratory spatial data analysis (ESDA) and Anselin Local Moran statistic is investigated and then the effects of this important climatic parameter on population centers is discussed. In this context, the WVP data from 46 synoptic stations in South and Southwest of Iran with appropriate length and highest resolution were used. To analyze the spatial autocorrelation, study area due to the optimal spatial resolution were divided to pixels with the dimension of 9×9 km (3,338 pixels). By programming in MATLAB software, the monthly, annual and decadal WVP were extracted for each pixel. Spatial autocorrelation analysis suggested strengthening and weakening the high-high WVP clusters and Low-Low WVP clusters, respectively. So that high-high WVP clusters have extended near the Persian Gulf (Especially in the Bushehr provinces) and Low-Low WVP clusters have disappeared in southern parts of Zagros Survey and comparison of the spatial distribution of WVP clusters with temperature clusters, as one of the most important influential parameters, showed a significant positive autocorrelation in the study areaک Thus, according to the direct and indirect effects of WVP on human activities and natural environment as the basis of human activity, the establishment of population in population centers of studies area will be affected by fluctuations of WVP and this trend will be more pronounced in the future.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>آمار مکانی, خودهمبستگی فضایی, دما, فشار بخار آب, موران محلی, جمعیت. </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Spatial Statistics, Spatial Autocorrelation, Temperature, Water Vapor Pressure, Anselin Local Moran\'s, Population.</keyword>
	<start_page>201</start_page>
	<end_page>220</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-710-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Yoones</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Khosravi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>یونس</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>خسروی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>younes_kh15@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001897</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001897</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hasan</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Lashkari</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>لشکری</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001898</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001898</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Ali Akbar</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Mottakaan</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی اکبر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>متکان</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001899</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001899</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hosein</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Asaakareh</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>عساکره</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001900</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001900</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه زنجان</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
