<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1397</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2019</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>17</volume>
<number>53</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تبیین اصول هندسی حاکم بر خیابان در شهرهای دوره صفوی مطالعه موردی: اصفهان، قزوین و مشهد
</title_fa>
	<title>Geometrical principles of Streets in Safavid cities Case study: Isfahan, Qazvin and Mashhad
</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;شریان &lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&amp;shy;&lt;/span&gt;ها و مسیرهای رفت &lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&amp;shy;&lt;/span&gt;و&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&amp;shy;&lt;/span&gt; آمد با نام &amp;shy;های مختلفی مانند شارع و گذر، همواره به عنوان ساختاری مهم در سازماندهی و توسعه شهرها، مطرح بوده &amp;shy;است. در دوره&amp;shy; صفوی این کارکرد با عنوان &amp;laquo;خیابان&amp;raquo; به&amp;shy; صورت یک الگوی انتظام &amp;zwnj;&amp;shy;بخش فضایی، از ساختار باغ&amp;shy; ایرانی وارد فضاهای شهری شد و تأثیرات هندسی وسیعی در توسعه یکپارچه شهر گذاشت. خیابانِ&amp;shy; صفوی به &amp;shy;عنوان عنصری انعطاف&amp;shy; پذیر از نظر عملکرد، با مداخله در بافت پیشین شهر، اتصال بین اجزاء ارزشمند پیرامونی را برقرار می&amp;shy;کرد. درحالیکه بیشتر خیابان&amp;shy;کشی&amp;shy;های کنونی در مداخلات شهری ایران، با کم توجهی به این اصول، موجب کم ارزشی بافت&amp;shy; های پیرامونی شده &amp;shy;است. این مقاله درصدد است تا با تحقیق در مؤلفه&amp;shy; های هندسی خیابان، &amp;shy;مهمترین اصول انتظام &amp;shy;بخش فضایی را تبیین نماید و نشان دهد که هر&amp;shy;یک از ویژگی &amp;shy;&amp;shy;های این مؤلفه &amp;shy;ها، چه اصول اساسی را به &amp;shy;وجود آورده&amp;shy; است.پژوهش حاضر به روش توصیفی- تحلیلی و با استفاده از منابع کتابخانه&amp;shy;&amp;zwnj;ای شامل متون و اسناد تاریخی، انجام گرفته &amp;shy;است.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;نتایج نشان می &amp;shy;دهد؛ نظام هندسی حاکم بر خیابان صفوی، سبب پیدایش نظم و کلیتی معنادار در ساختار شهری شده &amp;shy;&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;&amp;shy;&lt;/span&gt;است. این کلیت معنادار، واجد مؤلفه &amp;zwnj;ها و عوامل متعددی است که در ایجاد کیفیت و نقش انتظام &amp;shy;بخش آن تأثیرگذار بوده &amp;shy;است، مفاهیمی چون مفصل&amp;zwnj; ها، جهت&amp;zwnj; ها و محورها، ارزش&amp;zwnj; گذاری، مرتبت و منزلت، تعیّن فضایی و به&amp;zwnj; هم پیوستگی، در ایجاد اصولِ اساسی نظیر؛ &amp;laquo;سلسله&amp;zwnj; مراتب&amp;raquo;، &amp;laquo;اتصال&amp;raquo;، &amp;laquo;محور&amp;raquo; و &amp;laquo;حرکت و جهت&amp;raquo; در چارچوب کلی نظام هندسی خیابان صفوی، نقش داشته و همین امر سبب شده &amp;shy;است تا شهر اتصال و پیوستگی خود را با بافت پیشین به طور کامل حفظ نماید.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;Pathways, like alleys and passages, had an important and significant role in the spatial organization and development of cities, during the history. In the Safavid era, &amp;ldquo;street&amp;rdquo; as a functional element, was derived particularly from the Persian gardens&amp;rsquo; pattern, and was used in the urban spaces as a spatial ordering and organizing element. In this era, Safavied sultans&amp;rsquo; interests in showing authority and magnificent of their reign, on one hand, and concentrates on designing with nature in urban development, on the other hand, led to design and utilization of different types of street in the main cities of this period, like &amp;ldquo;Qazvin&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Isfahan&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mashhad&amp;rdquo;, so that the street had a wide and extended impact on urban development processes. In the meanwhile, the significant and important point is that; the design was the way of conserving olden historical zones of city, in this era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this article tries to distinguish the influential geometric dimensions of street in arranging and ordering of the city form, by analytical- descriptive method. Therefore, the first part of this paper explains the values and importance of geometrical order, and different aspects of the concept. This research uses descriptions of travelers who observed and wrote events during traveling to Iran in this period. The method of study is based on studies and highlights, mentioned in travelers&amp;rsquo; itineraries, and analysis of their contents as the most important historical sources about &amp;quot;Safavied Street&amp;quot;. Second part of the study as an analytical divide, expand illustrations in case studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As conclusion shows, the special geometric order of Safavied's street, had reasoned to the creation of meaningful wholeness and regularity in urban structure. This significant wholeness has diverse dimensions which have impact on foundation of its quality and also it's ordering role. To the extent of this proposition, different implications like: joints, direct, axis, voids, positive spaces, gradient and hierarchy, incorporation, ::union:: and others had been considered and straight streets and streetscape in Qazvin (khiaban), Isfahan (Char Bagh) and Mashhad (kheiyaban) had these features of geometry and order. This idea influenced on urban design and was important in creating continuity of historical and prebuild urban spaces and new ones as correlation and unity in urban components.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa></keyword_fa>
	<keyword></keyword>
	<start_page>235</start_page>
	<end_page>250</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-2473-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>لیلا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>مدقالچی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846009283</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846009283</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سمیه</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صدری کیا</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846009284</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846009284</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
