<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>3</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>38</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>مدیریت نوین مالی ضرورتی مغفول در پاسخگویی مدیریت شهری (تاملی در چالش‌های حقوقی بودجه‌ریزی عملیاتی در نظام حقوقی ایران)</title_fa>
	<title>Modern Financial Management, a Forgotten Necessity in Urban Management Responsiveness (A Consideration into Legal Challenges of Administrative Budget Planning in Iran’s Legal Order)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>مفهوم پاسخگویی در طول زمان تکامل یافته است و از حفاظت از دارایی‌ها به مدیریت و سپس به پاسخگویی در برابر اقدامات و نتایج به دست‌آمده تبدیل شده است. از طرفی نیز تحوّلات به وجود آمده در نقش و مأموریت های دولت در اداره امور جامعه، نظام های بودجه ریزی و مدیریت مالی دولت‌ها را نیز متحوّل ساخته است. افزایش «صرفه اقتصادی»، «کارایی» و «اثربخشی» بودجه، نحوه تخصیص منابع از طریق تاکید بر اهداف سنجش‌پذیر، افزایش پاسخگویی مسوولان امر در قبال اعطای آزادی عمل بیشتر از جمله ویژگی های خاص بودجه‌ریزی عملیاتی نسبت به سایر شیوه های بودجه ریزی می باشند که دولتها را جهت استقرار چنین شیوه ای اقناع نموده است. وجود قانون بودجه ای جامع، تعریف وتصویب اهداف و فعالیت‌های دستگاه های اجرایی توسط قانونگذار با لحاظ اصل حاکمیت قانون، اعمال نظام حسابرسی مبتنی بر عملکرد به وسیله مراجع نظارتی، وجود اختیارات لازم برای قوّه مقننه و پاسخگویی دولت از جمله بسترهای حقوقی لازم جهت استقرار بودجه‌ریزی عملیاتی می‌باشد که با وجود مشکلات ساختاری و قانونی موجود در کشور هیچ یک از عناصر مذکور به طور کامل تأمین نشده اند که در این پژوهش به بررسی اساسی ترین الزامات حقوقی استقرار بودجه ریزی مزبور پرداخته می شود. 
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Concept of responsiveness is gradually undergoing evolution, changing from protection of wealth to management and then responsiveness in response to the outcomes gained. Also transformations in the governments role in management of societies’ affairs, has given rise to the budget planning and financial management alterations. Increase in “economic efficiency”, “efficiency”, and “effectiveness” of budget, increases responsible persons’ responsiveness versus their more power in decision-making, leading governments to be convinced to implement such an order. Existence of  a master budget law, defining and ratification of aims and activities of different organs if the government by the law-makers considering the rule of law, implementing auditing order based on performance, giving enough power to the legislative assembly, and government’s reciprocity, are all legal bases for to implement administrative budget planning, which are studied in this article while they are not completely met in the country’s provisions because of structural and legal problems.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>بودجه ریزی عملیاتی, صرفه اقتصادی, کارایی, اثربخشی, قانون بودجه جامع و پاسخ گویی مالی دولت.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Administrative Budget Planning, Economic efficiency, Efficiency, Effectiveness, Budget Master Law, Government’s Financial Responsiveness.</keyword>
	<start_page>55</start_page>
	<end_page>74</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-683-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mehdi</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rezaee</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مهدی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رضایی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001818</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001818</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Seyyed Salman</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Samani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سید سلمان</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>سامانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>salman_samani@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001819</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001819</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Hasan</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Sayyad</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>صیاد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001820</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001820</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
