<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1390</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2011</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>9</volume>
<number>28</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بررسی عوامل موثر بر تمایل به پرداخت شهروندان برای کاهش آلودگی هوا در شهر مشهد؛ کاربرد الگوی دو مرحله ای هکمن</title_fa>
	<title>Investigation of Citizens' WTP for Mashhad Air Pollution Reduction (Applying two stage Heckman model) </title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;مطالعه حاضر با هدف تعیین ارزش اقتصادی بهبود کیفیت هوای شهر مشهد و عوامل موثر بر آن، روش ارزش-گذاری مشروط و الگوی دو مرحله ای هکمن را در مورد داده های جمع آوری شده به شیوه پیمایش میدانی در دو منطقه پرآلوده و متوسط‌آلوده این شهر بکارگرفته است. بر اساس نتایج روش ارزش گذاری مشروط می توان نتیجه گرفت که ارزش کل 30 درصد بهبود وضعیت آلودگی هوا در منطقه پرآلوده مشهد برابر 7134146560 ریال در ماه و در منطقه متوسط‌آلوده برابر 5242428950 ریال در ماه است. بنابراین در مجموع 30 درصد بهبود وضعیت آلودگی هوای مشهد از دیدگاه شهروندان ارزشی معادل 12376575510 ریال در ماه دارد. همچنین بر اساس نتایج این مطالعه متغیرهای تحصیلات، سن، نوع منطقه محل سکونت افراد، جنسیت و داشتن فرزند متغیرهای موثر بر تصمـیم افراد به تمایـل به پرداخــت برای کاهـش آلودگــی هوا می باشند. علاوه بر این متغیرهای تحصیلات، جنسیت، سن، درآمد خانوار، داشتن فرزند و داشتن خودرو متغیرهای موثر بر تمایل به پرداخت افراد در مرحله عمل ـ بعد از مرحله تصمیم ـ می باشند. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;In order to value Mashhad air quality improvement and determine its effective factors, current study has applied contingent valuation method and two stage Heckman model on gathered data of high-polluted and medium-polluted regions of Mashhad which are gathered through field survey method. Based on results of contingent valuation method it can be say that 30 percent improvement of air quality total value in high-polluted region equals 7134146560 Rials per month and in medium-polluted region equals 5242428950 Rials per month. Therefore according to citizens’ mentality, value of 30 percent improvement of Mashhad air pollution state equals 12376575510 Rials per month. Based on results of this study, in decision-making stage, education level, age, kind of settlement region, sex and having child are significant variables on citizens' WTP for air pollution reduction. In addition education level, sex, age, household income, having child and having car are effective factors on people willingness to pay in administrating stage. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>آلودگی هوا، تمایل به پرداخت، ارزش گذاری مشروط، الگوی دو مرحله ای هکمن، شهر مشهد. </keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Air Pollution, Willingness to Pay, Contingent Valuation, Two-Stage Heckman Model, Mashhad city.</keyword>
	<start_page>7</start_page>
	<end_page>26</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-107-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Ali</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Firooz zare</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فیروز زارع</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>: alifiroozzarea@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600190</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600190</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Qorbani</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>قربانی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600191</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600191</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
