<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <records>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>5</startPage>
	<endPage>25</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Applying the Management Model (CIPP) to Assess the Iranian Urban Education System </title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Today collegiate education in all majors is considered as inevitable necessities for countries development. Establishing and developing of each major has a tight relation with educating persons who can be trained. Interdisciplinary nature of urbanism has made it face serious challenges so that educational content of urbanism should differ according to time and place. Considering the fact that urbanism is a novel major and educational system plays an effective role in this major especially in our country, evaluating urbanism educational system is an inevitable necessity. Accordingly, it is necessary to extract urbanism educational system indicators in the form of evaluation model and assess this model in sample. On the basis of this approach, the research type is developmental- practical and from content point of view is descriptive- analytical. For compiling data, desk study, interview and questionnaire were applied. Analyzing the compiled data was done by content analysis, swinging weighting and Multi Criteria Decision Making in SPSS software. In order to determine research validity, professors and elites judgments were used and questionnaire reliability was assessed through Cronbach's alpha. Iran is in a lower level than average and this shows the necessity of big changes in urbanism educational system.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-46&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Evaluation</keyword>
	<keyword> Education</keyword>
	<keyword> Urbanism education</keyword>
	<keyword> Urbanism</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>27</startPage>
	<endPage>48</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Conceptual investigation of discovering the relation between the extern attribute and the latent meaning in the Holy Shrine of IMAM REZA (peace be upon him)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Permanent memorials in fields of culture, religion and history of nations depend on the social background and depth of musing in every tribe. These precious remnants are linked to wide comprehension, exalted philosophy, ordinary ceremonies of the time, religious and national morality and culture, and the consistent output is ornamented by artifice and technique. Shrine, as a masterpiece among art, artifice, industry and combination of industrial arts, is used to preserve and protect the chaste mausoleums of the descendants of Prophet MUHAMMED (peace be upon him), and holds an ancient past. Meanwhile, the Holy mausoleum of IMAM REZA(p. b. u. h.) and his Shrine have attracted great attention since a&amp;nbsp; long time ago, especially during the Safavieh Reign, and many Persian and Shia artists have performed crafts and presented practical sincere in the Holy mausoleum. The article is codified in analysis and descriptive manner with the purpose of imparting the context and theosophy that has been transferred orally from the artists of Islamic arts, designers, illustrators, traditional pattern designers and shrine manufacturers to the author. Due to researches on the Razavi Shrine, also known as the Golden and Silver Shrine, which is done by the author, no script has been found which may contain conceptual studies of structure and tropical patterns so far. The general results are presented by the usage of library sources, concepts included in the Holy Qur`an, the history and behavior of Imams and the Hadith quoted by them, extracted theosophy from the Persian and Shia literature and achievements reached by investigators of Islamic arts, and scrutiny in the whole Golden and Silver Shrine including the details.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-47&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Golden and Silver Shrine</keyword>
	<keyword> Shia theosophy</keyword>
	<keyword> Imam Reza</keyword>
	<keyword> Symbology</keyword>
	<keyword> Islamic arts</keyword>
	<keyword> Patterns and designs.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>49</startPage>
	<endPage>65</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Recognition of the Concept of the Interaction between Safavid Square and Royal Gardens “Investigating the Mutual Relationship between Public Space and Centralized Power </title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Formation of the Safavid Empire can be regarded as a milestone in the relationship between power and space production in Iranian cities. Since, for the first time, we can see the appearance of public spaces in Iranian cities where the main elements of the city were located in their neighborhood and provided a center with political, religious and economic power respectively. At this time, square played a significant role as a gateway to the royal garden; The present research aims at investigating the recognition of the interaction between Square and Royal Gardens (Safavid Royal Court) or rather, recognition of the role of the public space of square in relation to the discourse of centralized power. To find this relationship, it is necessary to analyze and interpret the first rate resources and documents written simultaneously with the formulation of such buildings. Hence, this study is a qualitative and historical research that, using analytical-descriptive method, attempts to finds the symbolic function of urban elements in the course of social and political changes of that era. The analytical approach used in this essay for the interpretation of the role of squares is influenced by the arguments of Foucault and Bourdieu as well as Henri Lefebvre's social ideas. Using this approach, we came to know that according to Safavid royal courts, square has conceptually differed from what has been the place of public gathering and people interaction, and has been instead a center for the display of central power and the use of economic and religious powers to strengthen the Safavid dynasty.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-48&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>square</keyword>
	<keyword> Royal Gardens (Safavid Royal Court)</keyword>
	<keyword> power</keyword>
	<keyword> public place</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>67</startPage>
	<endPage>76</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The study of housing for small urban groups with emphasis on social sustainability ( the city \'s case of Ilam )</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Social sustainability and the welfare of future generations, and today's trend has been dramatically used in architecture design. Despite the different perspectives of sustainable development and its different perceptions, the principle of balance between the three dimensions of environmental, social and economic consensus is agreeable to everyone. Social sustainability approach to address the basic needs of people, equity and physical and social wellbeing, promotion of creativity and development of human capacity, the preservation of cultural and biological heritage, the sense of association with history and the environment, and being democratic as well as improving the living conditions of social welfare, body and passion bring residents. It should be considered that in many cases, the most important factor affecting the level of satisfaction of a person from residence in the neighborhood, housing and its environmental conditions, therefore, in the study of housing, it is worth considering the principles of social sustainability. Low-income groups in the community have always been neglected due to lack of proper residential and social facilities. Housing studies based on social sustainability patterns, with regard to the basic factors of social sustainability, can play a role in the low-income housing population. The question now is what the role of social sustainability in low-income housing is and how this approach can be used in housing studies. To answer this question, the issue of housing and the recognition of sustainable development, principles, strategies and social sustainability have been investigated first. Finally, by examining external samples and literature sources, the social sustainability approach was considered as a model for considering low-income housing in order to include appropriate factors such as social justice, education promotion and physical well-being for low income families. 
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-49&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Low - income urban groups</keyword>
	<keyword> housing</keyword>
	<keyword> social sustainability</keyword>
	<keyword> Ilam.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>77</startPage>
	<endPage>97</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Investigating the Influencing Factors in the Conversion of Social Space to Element and Urban Symbol from the perspective of identity and collective memories in Shiraz</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The city is a memory less city that faces the phenomenon of identity crisis. Events in the city make memories and they need space to create them. The memorabilia spaces already existed in our cities have been degraded. Hence, there are fewer areas for the formation of collective memories in today's cities and there are few spaces from the past that have become urban signs by changing their usage over time. Therefore, the present research seeks to prove that urban elements can become urban signs by using effective design factors. This research, using available resources, explores several examples of urban space in Shiraz, which have become good urban symbols with a memorable approach. It also shows the spaces that help the city's identity, and, despite their various uses, have become a good city element and symbol of urban memories.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-50&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Social Space</keyword>
	<keyword> Identity</keyword>
	<keyword> Collective memories</keyword>
	<keyword> Urban Element</keyword>
	<keyword> Shiraz city</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>99</startPage>
	<endPage>116</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Electronic readiness assessment municipalities taken action In order to fulfill the electronic municipal</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">A mayor with electronic readiness has high speed in access to information and full satisfaction from FAVA applications in areas, and service centers. For effective use of ICT, a country should have widespread access to ICT, population access to ICT and regulatory and regulatory requirements. Developing countries can be able to evaluate electronic readiness to facilitate the size and design of integrated ICT programs. This helps them to focus and determine areas that require foreign help. A range of measurement tools for the size of electronic preparedness is a country or an economy created. These tools make a wide use of the different definitions and definitions of e - test testing and the assessments are significantly different in the goals and outcomes. Research findings show that the evaluation of the status quo in the municipality will be ideal for planning and indigo. If we consider the progress of IT progress in the city in three phases: identification of the status quo, the position of the ideal and the transition from the status quo to the desired position, we can identify the mayor's position in terms of readiness and review the strengths and weaknesses of the four axes. To determine the extent of municipal progress in electronic, it should be used in a number of consecutive years. The action that comes after evaluation is precisely dependent on the future goal of the municipality, (considering the current state of the city) evaluation of the electronic readiness of how to achieve future goals.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-51&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>municipal electronic preparedness assessment</keyword>
	<keyword> electronic readiness</keyword>
	<keyword> electronic municipality.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>117</startPage>
	<endPage>132</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Analysing &amp; cheking the role Of Communicative planning in the upgrade of urban development az novel approach in Iran. Case sample: Sohrabiye neighbourhood in Karaj</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Urban planning began in Iran in the mid-40s. But from the same time, in a way that was more advanced in the world, the inefficiency of those practices was proven, and new ways were replaced. The first program for cities was developed with a simple, comprehensive approach called the &amp;quot;Comprehensive plan&amp;quot; in 1345. It coincided with the time when this approach in Europe was replaced by new approaches such as comprehensive rational and cyclic systems. After about twenty years, Iranian experts acknowledged the inefficiencies of using those practices, and an attempt was made to overcome the defects of those programs or to replace them with newer methods. Understanding this has led to an attempt to improve the urban planning system in Iran. It was based on the fact that there were attempts to apply programs with various titles in Iran. On the other hand, the system of localities in Iran has undergone fundamental changes over the past 100 years. The traditional system of weak neighborhoods and the replacement of the new system are also ineffective. Among these, new approaches such as communication planning can be used to improve the quality of the current situation in neighborhoods. This kind of planning, incidentally, with the use of social, psychological and political theories, set foot on the ground and directly concerned the existence of conflict and contradiction among all the subsumed of space. This theory and its approaches seek to spread the power by studying how to distribute power in favor of disadvantaged groups of society. The research method is qualitative and descriptive-analytic. The purpose of this study is to examine the capacity and benefits of using communication planning approach in neighborhood scale programs. The main result of this research is paying attention to the role of urban planners in improving the quality of urban development. Communicative planning as a new approach to the participation of all stakeholders and stakeholders in the city is a major contributor to the creation of community participation. This is not necessarily a top-notch issue under the authority of state institutions and laws, but also as much as the needs of the community and, in the meantime, the city and the urban environment that can be urgently needed. To do such planning, it is necessary to know the needs of the local community, to redefine the problem and the problem for them, so that the need for cooperation and participation can be established. In this way, planning should focus its attention and energy more on the community and take action with the use of process and content strategies. Urban planners and specialists should not be seen as partnerships as an auxiliary tool, but as a goal.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-52&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Communication activities</keyword>
	<keyword> communication planning</keyword>
	<keyword> role of urban planners</keyword>
	<keyword> participation</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>133</startPage>
	<endPage>149</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Analysis of Geometry of the Housing Initiative at the Beginning of the Contemporary Period in Isfahan Based on Spatial Organization</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Over time, geometric and cultural factors have led to the creation of spaces in a different structure. The spatial organization analysis can reveal the structural structure of the building in a different timeframe. These organizations are directly affected by the geometric features, the external and internal features, as well as the visual and objective structure of the building. Other scholars have studied the formation of the building based on the spatial organization of inter-house houses, palaces and other buildings. This paper examines the new spatial organization approach on the geometry of the extraterritorial and semi-extraterrestrial planes of the beginning of the contemporary era of Isfahan. The research method is qualitative with purposeful application and its data is collected by library and field method. This essay aims to analyze the impact of the geometry of the housing plan on spatial organization. In this study, first, the structure of the out-of-date plan of the beginning of the present century, the physical structure of space and spatial relationships, and then analyzed its existence or its absence on the study samples. Surveys conducted revealing the geometric properties of houses in this period have led to the same organization in the field of outsourcing and semi-outsourcing residential plans.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-53&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Geometry of the Housing Plan</keyword>
	<keyword> Housing of the Contemporary Age</keyword>
	<keyword> Spatial Organization</keyword>
	<keyword> Spatial Relations</keyword>
	<keyword> Isfahan Houses.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>151</startPage>
	<endPage>170</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Dialectical arenas (components and indicators of place formation in urban areas from the perspective of critical theory) </title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The public sphere is in fact a normative concept or concept in the general context of Habermas's general theories of communicative action and the ethics of dialogue. The public sphere is part of a social life in which citizens can exchange views on important issues related to public good (public interest). The result is the formation of public opinion. Democratic philosophers also believe that these spaces are the physical manifestation of the public domain, the field of activity, the communication of free people and groups, and the place of the formation of civil life.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-54&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Place</keyword>
	<keyword> public sphere</keyword>
	<keyword> critical theory</keyword>
	<keyword> factor analysis.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>189</startPage>
	<endPage>216</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Explanation of the principles of architecture of nature architecture in architecture and urbanism based on research models</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Today, education has found a role in the learning process those changes in the education system across the world. This is in the context of today's change of practice in models and methods, especially in relation to the structure of research and its position, and has highlighted the need for a view of common perspectives and access to research patterns in architecture and urbanism. In this paper, while referring to the concept of education, the interdependent categories with the class of education in general and the training of architectural education in particular, and then in an analytical approach, models and model research models in the urbanism and architecture. Finally, to provide some educational solutions in the context of practice and practice, which is based on the basis for studies and studies of architectural education and by generalizing them to the architecture of architecture, the process of design and education in architecture; Also, on the basis of studies and studies of architectural education and by generalizing them to the architecture of nature architecture, some proposed methods of education are dynamic education - based education; education - based education; education - based education; education - based education; education - based education; education - based education; education - based education; education - based education.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-56&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Research - oriented training</keyword>
	<keyword> templates</keyword>
	<keyword> and architecture of architecture and urbanism</keyword>
	<keyword> models of nature. </keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>217</startPage>
	<endPage>231</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">New urbanism and management of urban defenseless spaces to control criminal behavior</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Big cities have a lot of crime at its heart. State crime statistics indicate that Tehran metropolis due to the special circumstances of the geographical space and the highest crime statistics between the cities of the country. The incidence of these crimes, issues and has created many challenges for citizens and city managers. The most important theoretical approaches to the interpretation of the formation of centers of crime is crime prevention through environmental design. This article is extracted from a doctoral thesis titled as New Urbanism and management of urban defenseless spaces to control criminal behavior; case study Tehran. This study seeks to discover which factors and environmental conditions help to facilitate crimes such as theft in the city? The research method is descriptive. After theoretical studies, through sub-GIS software, and then observation centers have been identified robbery, factors and conditions facilitating the study was to explore the relationship between the two. The results indicate that the major centers of mass in the regions 6 and 7. Observing weak territoriality, little oversight residents by design poor, the poor people in places due to lack of planning, lack of standards urbanism, walls and windows dirty and run-down of the major factors and conditions that are rule in hot spots of Tehran.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-57&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>crime</keyword>
	<keyword> Tehran</keyword>
	<keyword> urban planning</keyword>
	<keyword> crime prevention</keyword>
	<keyword> environmental design</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>233</startPage>
	<endPage>243</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">How to create tissues and architecture spaces Bronze Age (3000 - 1500 A.H. M) in north - east plateau Iran</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The Bronze Age of Iran from historical relative to the early millennium of the third millennium to the mid - second millennium of the second millennium, about 1500 years ago; This growing culture is achieved in the field of developing the wheel of pottery, the innovation of metal, the formation of the ILAM lines, and the creation of urbanization structures. Due to the advent of the bronze in this period, the formation of a metal is a form of texture architecture. The rise in trade between the region and is a sign of the creation of human communities that require residential architectural spaces, and at the end of the change of burial pattern in this period, which has been shifted from the burial state of the dead, and that may indicate the creation of religious structures. According to broadening areas under influence Bronze Age culture in Iran, in this paper area northeastern portion due to Iran include ancient areas at the time. Were on the territory of Iran and now from its territory have partitioned and several ancient compound including hill barrier and generally tissue architecture can be to three categories: First - residential buildings, the second - and third - industrial buildings religious buildings.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-58&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>architecture</keyword>
	<keyword> tissues</keyword>
	<keyword> spaces</keyword>
	<keyword> area northeastern portion due to Iran </keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>245</startPage>
	<endPage>262</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Analysis of the geometry of bricks behind the vaults of the Hakim Mosque in Isfahan on the emergence of visual techniques</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">People are always receiving information from their surroundings. In architecture, much of these messages are delivered through decorations. These decorations have valuable geometries, each of which has different characteristics, and the analysis of these techniques and features makes it easier to read and understand the causes of different visual perceptions. In fact, visual techniques directly affect how bricks are stacked, how bricks and tiles are combined, and how the colors are distributed in the design as well as the type of knot. Other researchers have examined visual techniques from the point of view of the physical structure and composition of the paintings. This article examines for the first time visual techniques from the perspective of the geometry of bricks behind the courtyards of the Hakim Mosque of Isfahan. The methodology of the research is qualitative, in terms of purpose, applied. The data of this research have been compiled by library and field method. The aim of this study is to analyze the impact of brickwork geometry on visual techniques. This research first explores the modeling of the samples and extracts the visual techniques required and then decomposes the designs to represent the features of the visual techniques in two general forms of equilibrium and order. The investigations revealed that various shapes (size and angle of the bricks), the combination of different colors and the integration of bricks and tiles created various visual techniques in the framework of balance and order.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-59&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Geometry of brickwork - visual techniques - balance - order - porch of Hakim mosque</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>263</startPage>
	<endPage>286</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Representation the concept of housing in social and economic factors</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The concept of dwelling is one of the most complicated and historical issues for the human kind.&amp;nbsp; The questions of whom and what are always considerable for the concept of dwelling and philosophy. In fact, the concept of dwelling is one of the main principles for nations and religions. Although there is no solid definition between thinkers and philosophers for the concept of dwelling, almost all of them have an agreement on its essence. Transitions have been occurred recently in human's life, changed the approach toward dwelling and came up with new ideas about it.&amp;nbsp; The most part of these changes can be reachable in postmodern era. &amp;nbsp;So, for knowing this concept precisely, we should analyze its transition from different viewpoints and periods. Then we will be able to release appropriate definition. Comprehending this concept and explaining all of its aspects precisely, is the first step to achieve this goal.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-60&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>concept of housing</keyword>
	<keyword> architecture</keyword>
	<keyword> social and economic factors</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>287</startPage>
	<endPage>296</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Legal analysis of the role of the environment in the life of the disabled and veterans and civil responsibility</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The realm of civil responsibility in today's world is so widespread that it must be certain that no damage should be left. On the other hand, they are at the level of society, where they are willing to seek the aid of the legal community when they are threatened by society. One of the groups, who need these legal supporting, are disabled people who have fallen at birth at birth, for genetic reasons, or at the moment of a completely healthy birth, and have had a disability in our country, as well as a crime or something that has to be seen in our country. One of the most important causes of physical damage to the disabled and veterans is due to the imposition of discrimination and subsequent rights to the civil lawsuit, which has not been discussed so far, due to the lack of adequate environment surrounding the disabled. For years, in this land, persons with disabilities are particularly vulnerable to dangers in public and private places. From time to time we shall know, through the papers, that a blind or disabled person, a person who is blind or disabled, has suffered tragic accidents in the streets or in other places or if he is safely home. Thus, the community is aware of its responsibility for the dangerous environment and the proper protection of the environment that threatens some of the veterans and veterans seriously. In this study, we discussed how veterans and veterans could use the organs of civic responsibility for the lawsuit. As for the appropriateness of the environment, we will look at the comparative rights to the best of the weaknesses of the internal law.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-61&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Civil Responsibility</keyword>
	<keyword> Disabled</keyword>
	<keyword> disability</keyword>
	<keyword> Rights</keyword>
	<keyword> Damages. </keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>297</startPage>
	<endPage>308</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">The Social Role of Religious Places in the Society; Case Study: Shrine shrines and Emamzade Saleh in Tehran City</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Religion is an important component of the culture of civilization and any nation. The Dean of Danes society is always seeking to strengthen the component that is religious. There are many in Iran, but some of them are considered to be a specific state and centre, and they can be used in shaping and continuity of some theories of society and some of them such as the King of Light, King Abdel Azim Hosni Hosni and the Emamzade Saleh. In this study, the quality and role of the King Abd al - Azim Al - Faysal City of Rey and Emamzade Saleh are analyzed.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-62&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Religion</keyword>
	<keyword> society</keyword>
	<keyword> community</keyword>
	<keyword> Shah Abdel - Azim</keyword>
	<keyword> Emamzade Saleh</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>309</startPage>
	<endPage>329</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Theoretical Measurement of Residential Satisfaction Measures with Psychology of Religion Approach from   Recognition approach</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The thought, wisdom and creativity of the driving force on micro - scale and macro - scale activities for human and communities - and make sense of human activity, and it becomes important that the citizens choose or take advantage of their needs. The lack of sufficient attention from the architects of the designer to the residential set as a focal point in the accelerated growth of urbanization problems will have problems such as social conflict, urban conditions, and increase of psychological pressures, social and environmental, social and environmental implications. Therefore, in the architecture of the architecture, and the concepts of residential satisfaction in particular, the need for infrastructure thinking with the merger of other sciences, including psychology for the theory and theory of human being in dealing with the world 's environment for happiness and earthly happiness and making sense of the life we enjoy. One of these deep - rooted approaches is the psyche of behavioral science. His present research is aimed at exploring the influence of Dean's spirit on residential content and tries to determine what components of residential satisfaction can relate to the cognitive component of religion and provide the rise of increased content satisfaction in residential spaces. First, discussion of the basics and origins of the psychology of religion and the satisfaction - e - residential content are discussed and the opinions of some effective thinkers have been addressed, and ultimately the underlying components are considered.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-63&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Residential Satisfaction</keyword>
	<keyword> Quality of Residential Spaces</keyword>
	<keyword> Psychology of Religion</keyword>
	<keyword> Satisfaction</keyword>
	<keyword> Housing</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>331</startPage>
	<endPage>349</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Biophilic attitude toward improving the quality of the living environment of residential residences</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The strong connection of human life and the nature of nature as an inherent element, this human imagination to escape under the domination of the life system by the development of humanity and the modern of the natural ecosystem surrounding the ecosystem and the natural processes surrounding the ecosystem and its natural processes and processes. In the current world, the rise of the population of cities from one side and the development of the criteria on the other hand, and such an industry regardless of the comfort and health of individuals in residential spaces have exposed human societies to the crisis. Housing is one of the real phenomena that human beings are always trying to change. It is not meant to create only production, but is considered to be a user, and quality has an important role in satisfying housing applicants. Improving the quality of residential complex, one of the factors influencing environmental desirability is considered to affect the quality of life and the satisfaction of residents in residential residences. The fundamental belief in this research is that human beings, as a biological species, have always a natural instinct between human beings and other living systems, recognizing human nature to communicate with nature and global strategy. The method used in terms of goal, applied research method and study in terms of the method and nature, descriptive - analytical research and the compilation of its information based on the study of the library resources, is the result of the fact that with the creation of the relationship between human nature and its users' environment, the results of the empirical research are to the users of its users.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-64&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Residential Architecture</keyword>
	<keyword> Biophilic</keyword>
	<keyword> Nature</keyword>
	<keyword> Human.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>351</startPage>
	<endPage>365</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Investigating and Assessing the Role of Agricultural Economics in the Development of the City of Maidovud (Case Study of Rice Culture)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The physical development of cities is a dynamic process in which the physical and physical limits of cities in vertical and horizontal directions increase quantitatively and qualitatively, and if this is a fast and unplanned process, urban systems will have many problems in the future. Given the ever-increasing migration of people from rural areas around cities and elsewhere, which has increased their demand for urban land for living, and if such structures are not monitored, in addition to the disappearance of high-quality agricultural land, the city Faces economic, social and environmental crises. The purpose of this study is to analyze the economic-based economic map with sustainable development approach. Considering the rate of immigration in recent years and environmental damage, the goal is to scientifically and precisely explain the role of the agricultural economy in the development and development of the city. In evaluating the economic growth of rice and its effect on physical growth of the city of Meydwond, a questionnaire was prepared and after completion of the questionnaire by residents of the study area, based on scientific methods, was analyzed. The results of the analysis of the questionnaire show that the economic growth caused by rice cultivation was significant due to the change in the type of agriculture and the production efficiency has increased significantly and this economic growth has affected the population's survival and physical development of the city
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-65&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>rice</keyword>
	<keyword> development</keyword>
	<keyword> city</keyword>
	<keyword> economy</keyword>
	<keyword> Maidovud.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>367</startPage>
	<endPage>385</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Security sense Measurement of Citizens in Hashtgerd New Town </title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Security is the sense of relief and confidence from no violation to life, property and other human rights. Social disorganization in cities has increased exponentially due to population growth, rapid expansion of urbanization and social, economic, political and cultural changes arising from it. The aim of this study is analysis of the resident's security sense in Hashtgerd New Town to safety evaluation and awareness of policy makers and decision-makers from this issue. Research method is analytical and applied. Sample size has been calculated through Cochran formula and it is estimated 567 people. In this study, sampling method was cluster random. The data collection tool has been done through a questionnaire. The results indicate that there is a significant correlation between two variable gender and sense of security. So that women than men are lower sense of security in Hashtgerd New Town. There are Significant differences between age groups and a sense of security and the level of family income and feel secure in Hashtgerd New Town. Thus, sense of security is lower in neighborhoods with low economic and social status as well as vulnerable groups such as women and children in Hashtgerd.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-66&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>poverty</keyword>
	<keyword> women</keyword>
	<keyword> Security sense</keyword>
	<keyword> Hashtgerd New Town</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>387</startPage>
	<endPage>407</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Analyze the ranking of the urban locatinal competitiveness of the centers of the provinces of Iran based on the Principal Component Analysis (PCA)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">In spite of the complexity of the concept of competitiveness, its goal is, to some extent clear to be able to outperform other competitors. The four components of urban competitiveness are economic, socio-cultural, environmental and locational. The general objective of this research is to identify the factors influencing the promotion of urban locational competitiveness. From the UN perspective, there are three different ways of identifying the real factors of urban competitiveness. With regard to the research paradigm, which is positivist, a quantitative/statistical method was chosen among the three methods proposed. Urban competitiveness locational indicators are Hypsography, Location Conditions, Accessibility, and Spatial Data Infrastructure. The main component analysis is the data analysis method using SPSS and Minitab software and XLSTAT. The first five main components explain 0.87 variance; therefore, the examination of the five main components is sufficient, and the ranking is performed based on the first component. Among the suggestions of this research for future researchers is that due to the difference in the urban management model at different levels of the cities in the country, their criteria get prepared and set with regard to their demographic, climatic, cultural and political conditions.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-67&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Urban Locational Competitiveness</keyword>
	<keyword> Iran</keyword>
	<keyword> Principal Component Analysis</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>409</startPage>
	<endPage>429</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Protecting the urban population against enemy threats case study: Tehran metropolitan</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Protecting human capital in urban management will preserve human or spiritual assets, and the resistance and sustainability of people to the threats will enhance the ability to stand, sustain and sustain people s ability to believe in their abilities and ultimately rely on self - reliance. The main question of research is to protect the urban population vs. Enemy threats with the Passive defense approach? It is. The type of research is a useful application. The method of conducting this research from the mixed approach involves the two approaches based on the Delphi method , plus the study of documents and the library and the quantitative approach focusing on the descriptive - survey method . The statistical community consisted of scholars, experts, and members of the country, and members of the country. The volume of statistical community of 15 people is chosen based on the formula kocran.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-68&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Passive defense</keyword>
	<keyword> urban population</keyword>
	<keyword> enemy threats</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>431</startPage>
	<endPage>451</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng"> Review of the Iranian house on the basis of cultural ecologic theory</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>4</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="4">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The study of contemporary architectural research begins with the arrival of the East Asian land, including Iran. In studies, indigenous researchers are also seen. It can be considered as a product of modern science. In post - theories, it has been attempted to look at the relationship between the sciences and the cultural ecology of such a view of the researchers, especially ecologists and sociologists. Data analysis method is qualitative analysis and data collection method is documented. The communication pattern and consequently the architecture with the canvas and the human being demonstrate the ability to enter the culture of culture in architectural research, particularly in sustainable architectural research. The present study, introducing cultural ecology of environmental and cultural factors, serves as a model for the residence model and its body products, which are the Iranian home yard, and introduces them to the environmental factors such as the topology, climate, and geography of the Iranian house.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-69&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Cultural ecology</keyword>
	<keyword> Settlement</keyword>
	<keyword> Environment</keyword>
	<keyword> livelihood.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>453</startPage>
	<endPage>467</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Influence of effective factors (Culture, Human resources) 0n performance of municipality personal of Ahvaz</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The main purpose of this article is examining impact of effective factors, namely human resources and organizational culture on personnel performance. Statistical population of this study consist of 1500 Ahvaz municipality staffs (having bachelor of art degree or higher) that 305 Participant by using Karjesi and Morgan table, simple random sampling method have been used as sample. The present research method based on applied purpose and in terms of collecting data is a descriptive study and in respect of relationship between variables is a causal one and is based on constructional equations modeling. In this research, questionnaire is an instrument of collecting data. The used questionnaire in this study is: Organizational cultures: Denison 2000, Human Resources: Ango &amp; et al 2008, Personnel performance: designing with idea of experts. The Validity of research instrument obtained with consulting with experts and reliability of questionnaire have obtained with help of Cronbach Alpha. In order to assessing research variables in addition to questionnaire and statistical analysis. We used SPPS, LISREL software. The results of questionnaire analysis have shown that human resources and organizational culture (their dimensions) have significance and positive influence on personal performance and therefore providing necessary training in order to conduct and apply performance management in an organization ,accepting continual improvement as a principle by managers and institutionalization of improvement in an organization and that managers should have more focus on development and training organizational culture values in change programs, improving and reconstructing organization has been suggested.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-70&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Human Resources Factors</keyword>
	<keyword> Organizational Cultures</keyword>
	<keyword> Staffs Performance</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>469</startPage>
	<endPage>487</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Space atmosphere in phenomenology as a space without surface</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">The space that is the main part of architecture has been criticized for the length of history and in various time periods from various philosophical angles from a body to meaning, from the form of Fermi aesthetics to linguistics and typology. But, always, the important question that comes in front of these views is whether the understanding of space has a sense of how it comes from space. If the meaning of space is understood from the point of view, is a suitable space for human biology? In this study, with the emphasis on the consumer of space, human beings and his abilities in receiving environmental data and its energies to theories that are discussed in this context in the history of thought, it is analyzed that the foundation of phenomenology is the foundation of the sciences. The radical vote in architecture calls for a creative science and the structure and paradigms of the human mind that make up the idea of the idea of progress and development that makes the structure of the surfaces in the space of decorative act. In this opportunity, the transformation and transformation of how life and its nature are transformed into the nature of the house and housing in Iran , the most tangible and widely used space among human biology. In this study, we investigate qualitative methods for understanding and evaluating perceptions in space by describing space such as and in more modern houses. For this, it is used to take advantage of the cells that do not possess the characteristics or characteristics of a particular architecture; By choosing five houses from three Qajar (beheshti home, arazi home), side of the first (shelviri house in Qazvin) and two houses from the second side in the Narmak residential complex at the Narmak residential complex.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-71&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Space with surface</keyword>
	<keyword> space without surface</keyword>
	<keyword> phenomenology. </keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>489</startPage>
	<endPage>497</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Examination of the restrictions of equity law in the municipalities\' law</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Equity law has been one of the most important issues of challenge between individuals and governments in the general sense of the word. In different times, private ownership of individuals has been deprived by government's intervention and in cases such interference is considered as one of the undeniable hazards in private life. This study examines the concept of equity law in law and law and its place against public interest in the introduction of restrictions of private property in the municipality's law, and by referring to the examples of restrictions, rules of verdicts and the binding principles of liability has been investigated in the municipality's law. The study of the legal sources and sources shows the inefficiency and of urban management rules that regulate these rules to regulate part of the problems in this area. Also training and acquainting the citizens with the culture of urbanization and regulations of this field can help governments to apply and enforce laws. Recognizing that the limitation of equity law, to provide safety, health and comfort of urban life and the equal status of public utilities and public services, is inevitable; the results of this study can be applied applied to planners in urban management area planners.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-72&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>equity law</keyword>
	<keyword> private property</keyword>
	<keyword> public interest</keyword>
	<keyword> municipality's law</keyword>
	<keyword> urban culture.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>499</startPage>
	<endPage>509</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Influence of project communication system quality on participation sense of project team</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Participation as an effective approach has provided a comprehensive response in different level and areas of management, especially project management in deal with postmodern criticisms which have been mentioned against modern management. But what have been neglected are foundations and influential factors on participation improvement. It is important because identification of these factors can have significant influence on our ability to offer effective and practical solution to improve participation phenomenon. This research with the aim of covering this gap in literature has been concentrated on the decisive role of project communication system quality in the improvement of project team participation sense as an important factor and amplifier of participation phenomenon. For this reason, with quantitative approach and by using descriptive-analytical research method, field data have been gathered and factor test has been used in order to diagnosing factors for both communication quality system and participation sense of project team. Result of factor analysis provides the condition in a way that research hypothesis be testable and practical solution be presentable. In final, the test of research hypothesis by using Pearson correlation coefficient, showed positive correlation between project communication system quality and project team participation sense.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-73&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>communication system of project</keyword>
	<keyword> participation sense</keyword>
	<keyword> factor test.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>511</startPage>
	<endPage>533</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Development and accreditation of rural good governance indicators </title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>3</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="3">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Good governance in rural areas, through comparative approach and behavior regularity and institutionalization of accountability, public participation, transparency, rule of law, accountability, consensus oriented, and so it can be done. Accordingly, it can be good governance of rural interaction between officials and planners at macro and micro levels for local communities with people who defined development plans would be affected. Of course, the importance of rural governance analysis without identification, formulation and validation of indicators of domestic and influence will not be realized; The purpose and nature of the study and application of correlation method. The population consisted of 35 experts to study the 9 main index and 48 items. To validate and obtain expert consensus criteria for prioritizing methods positive ratings, rankings, reverse of the rank statistics mean and standard deviation were used. The two methods for determining the quality of the items of content validity ratio (CVR) and content validity index (CVI) was used. The results showed that the indices 9 of the standard values ​​of these methods for prioritizing indicators; participation (0.42) consensus oriented (0.28) justice (0.21) responsibility (0.19) transparency (0.33) accountability (0.25) lawful (0.20) legitimacy (0.24) efficiency and effectiveness (0.20) obtained from experts. In the study, the quality of the items from total of 48 items, 42 items were identified as items of for good governance in rural areas, out of which 8 items index participation, consensus oriented 4 items index, the index justice 4 items, 4 items index responsibility, 7 items to transparency, accountability 3 items index, the index of rule 6 items, 4 items 8 items index legitimacy and effectiveness indicator belong to.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-74&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>accreditation</keyword>
	<keyword> indicate</keyword>
	<keyword> planning</keyword>
	<keyword> governance</keyword>
	<keyword> rural governance</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>535</startPage>
	<endPage>549</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Evaluating the Effectiveness of Traffic Routing Techniques in Tehran Metropolis and Providing Appropriate Strategies for Reducing Traffic (Case Study of Tehran Region 2)</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Today, with the growth of cars and the growth of intra-city travel, traffic management and management has become one of the most important requirements of urban management. Traffic is an unpleasant phenomenon that is the cause of growing urbanization and urbanization. On the other hand, the increasing growth of automobile production and the lack of necessary cameras in creating appropriate streets and roads have resulted in such results as Creating traffic congestion, reducing transportation efficiency, increasing travel time, pollution and excessive consumption of fossil fuels. To this end, the relevant experts are trying to efficiently plan, use existing capacities and increase system efficiency; reduce traffic in cities. The purpose of this study was to investigate the effectiveness of traffic reduction strategies in Tehran's 2nd district. The research is descriptive-analytic and the information is collected using the documentary and library method. The statistical population of this research includes experts Due to the impossibility of conducting research on the whole society, a multi-stage random sampling method has been used. And the data is analyzed using the Delphi method and the technique of multi-criteria decision-making methods of Tapsis. And the results indicate that education standards, awareness raising, strengthening legal tools and promoting the use of public transport By gaining points (0.735193), (0.688986), (066447) ، have ranked first, second, and third, respectively.
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-75&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>Urbanization Growth</keyword>
	<keyword> Traffic Crisis</keyword>
	<keyword> Tehran 2nd District</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
	<record>
	<language>per</language>
	<publisher> سازمان شهرداريها و دهياريهاي كشور</publisher>
	<journalTitle>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</journalTitle>
	<issn>1607-2227</issn>
	<publicationDate>2018-03</publicationDate>
	<volume>16</volume>
	<issue>49</issue>
	<startPage>550</startPage>
	<endPage>567</endPage>
	<documentType>article</documentType>
	<title language="eng">Explain urban parks and urban parks design criteria for adaptation to women\'s needs</title>


	<authors>
	<author>
	<name> </name>
	<email></email>
	<affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
	 </author>
	</authors>
	 <affiliationsList>
	      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
                 
	      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>


	<abstract language="eng">Urban sprawl design is now one of the most important urban planning and management priorities, as today's cities have been criticized for confronting problems like crowds, congestion, high traffic density and traffic congestion. In this context, green spaces, campuses and parks of cities are important areas that provide a place for relaxation and recreation, and their design is considered for women; therefore, it is necessary to generalize the principles and criteria that must be met. Urban parks should be considered as a kind of open and public spaces for women in the city, and planning should be made to create attractive and suitable spaces for female citizens. The research method is a descriptive-analytical and meta-analysis that examines the criteria for designing urban space for women
</abstract>
	<fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1432-55&amp;slc_lang=en&amp;sid=1</fullTextUrl>
	<keywords>
	<keyword>green space</keyword>
	<keyword> park and campus</keyword>
	<keyword> city femininity</keyword>
	<keyword> design criteria.</keyword>
	</keywords>


	</record>
 </records>
 
  
  
  
  
 