<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1391</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2012</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>10</volume>
<number>30</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>بازشناخت جنبش پیاده مداری در پایداری فضاهای متراکم شهری </title_fa>
	<title>Recognition of pedestrian-oriented movement for sustainability of dense urban zones</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>امروزه جنبش پیاده مداری که هدف آن بازیابی و توسعه فضاهای پیاده در سطح شهرها و به رسمیت شناختن و اولویت قائل شدن برای عابرین پیاده بعنوان عناصر درجه اول شهری؛ به یکی از محورهای برنامه ریزی و طراحی شهری بدل گردیده است. به ویژه با آغاز هزاره سوم ضرورت رویکرد مجدد به حرکت پیاده بعنوان سالم ترین، اقتصادی ترین و پویاترین روش جابجایی و حمل و نقل درون شهری مورد توجه جدی کارشناسان و مدیران امور شهری قرار گرفته است. عواملی چون افزایش قابل توجه زمان جابجایی، افزایش تصادفات، آلودگی های صوتی، بصری و نزدیک شدن میزان آلودگی هوا به مرزهای تهدید سلامت انسانی، از تبعات سیستم حمل و نقل ناپایدار در شهرها می باشد. همچنین، موانعی از قبیل کمبود اعتبار مالی برای زیرساخت ها، فقدان ایمنی و امنیت، موقعیت نامناسب فضاها و ساختمان ها، موانع قانونی و حقوقی و در نهایت فقدان اعتبار و منزلت اجتماعی، بر سر راه توسعه شبکه حمل و نقل غیر موتوری وجود دارد. نتایج تجربیات سایر کشورها حاکی از آن است که پایداری تنها با ایجاد تغییرات در طراحی، الگوهای استفاده و مدیریت وسایل نقلیه حاصل نمی‌شود، بلکه باید تغییراتی در نحوه تفکر نسبت به شناخت و ارزشیابی راهکارهای ممکن برای حل مشکلات حمل و نقل ایجاد گردد. از اینرو در این پژوهش ابتدا نگاهی اجمالی بر مفاهیم حمل و نقل پایدار شهری صورت می گیرد، سپس ضمن بررسی پیاده روی و دوچرخه سواری و اثرات آنها به عنوان شیوه ای مؤثر از حمل و نقل غیر موتوری، راهبردهای رسیدن به توسعه پایدار در فرم مطلوب شهری، در محدوده ی فلکه دوم صادقیه (واقع در شهرداری منطقه 2 تهران) با استفاده از مدل ترکیبی SWOT و Likert مورد تحلیل و ارزیابی قرار گرفته، تا با بکارگیری این راهکارها و گسترش آن در کشور از مزایای آن بهره مند گردیم. این پژوهش، با حمایت پژوهشکده سازمان شهرداری ها و دهیاری های کشور انجام شده است. </abstract_fa>
	<abstract>Today, the pedestrian oriented movement, whose goal is to retrieve and expand pedestrian spaces on the face of the city, and to recognize and give priority to pedestrians as first rate elements of the city, has turned into one of the axes of programming and urban design. Especially with the beginning of the third millennium, renewed necessity of pedestrian movement as the most healthy, economic and dynamic method of movement and inner city transportation has attracted experts and leaders of urban affairs. Factors such as significant increase in movement time, increase in accidents, increase in sound and visual pollution and air pollution which is getting close to the borders of creating health threats for humans, are the consequences of the unstable urban transportation system. In addition, obstacles such as lack of funding for infrastructure, lack of safety and security, improper positioning of spaces and buildings, legal and regulatory obstacles and finally, lack of credibility and social status exist in the path of development of the non-motorized transportation network. The results of the experiences of other countries indicate that stability cannot be reached only with changes in design, models of utilization and management of transportation systems, but with changes in mentality and way of thinking towards identification and evaluation of possible solutions for solving the problems of transportation. Therefore in this research we first have a brief overview of the concepts of sustainable urban transport, then we study walking and cycling and their effect as effective methods of non-motorized transportation, along with strategies for reaching sustainable development in desirable urban form, in the area of 2nd Sadeqieh square ( located in zone 2 of the municipality of Tehran) which have been analyzed and evaluated using a mixed model of SWOT and Likert, in order to use benefits of applying these strategies and developing them in the country. This research has been done with the support of the Institute of municipalities and village council of the country. </abstract>
	<keyword_fa>پیاده مداری، حمل و نقل غیر موتوری، فضاهای متراکم شهری، توسعه پایدار.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Pedestrian-oriented, non-motorized transportation, Dense urban areas, sustainable development.</keyword>
	<start_page>179</start_page>
	<end_page>194</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-230-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Mohammad Javad</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Feizi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمدجواد</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فیضی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>joefeizi@gmail.com</email>
	<code>1003194753284600509</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600509</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Shahr-e Rey</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شهر ری</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Azita</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Rajabi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>آزیتا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>رجبی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600510</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600510</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Islamic Azad University of Tehran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکز</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Yasaman</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hoseini</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>یاسمن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حسینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>1003194753284600511</code>
	<orcid>1003194753284600511</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Science and Research Branch, Islamic Azad University, Alborz</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات البرز</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
