<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1395</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2016</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>15</volume>
<number>43</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>ارائه مدل نگهداشت کارکنان سازمانهای دولتی ایران</title_fa>
	<title>The model retention of employees of public organizations </title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p dir=&quot;RTL&quot;&gt;یکی از وظایف اساسی مدیریت منابع انسانی سازمانها، نگهداشت کارکنان می&amp;shy;باشد&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt; .&lt;/span&gt;از آنجا که نگهداشت، مکملی بر سایر اقدامات و فرایندهای مدیریت منابع انسانی است؛ حتی اگر عملیات کارمندیابی، انتخاب، انتصاب و بهسازی به&amp;shy;نحو شایسته&amp;shy;ای انجام شود، بدون توجه کافی به نگهداشت، نتایج حاصل از اعمال مدیریت چندان چشمگیر نخواهد بود. هدف این پژوهش، ارائه مدل نگهداشت کارکنان سازمانهای دولتی ایران است. بدین منظور پس از مروری بر ادبیات موضوع و بهره گیری از نظرات خبرگان، مدل اولیه تحقیق تنظیم گشت. سپس با استفاده از نظرات خبرگان، مدل نهایی تحقیق آماده گردید. روش پژوهش، توصیفی کاربردی است.جامعه آماری این پژوهش را کارکنان اداره کل آموزش و پرورش استان خوزستان تشکیل داده اند. روش نمونه گیری تصادفی طبقه ای بوده و بر اساس جدول مورگان نمونه آماری 217 نفر بوده است. در این تحقیق عوامل نگهداشت کارکنان شامل: عوامل فرهنگی، عوامل سازمانی، عوامل دولتی بود. نتایج تحلیل معادلات ساختاری نشان می&amp;shy;دهد که&amp;shy;میزان ضریب مسیر عوامل فرهنگی 0.29، عوامل دولتی 0.27، عوامل سازمانی0.31 بوده است. نتایج نشان می&amp;shy;دهد عوامل سازمانی بیشترین تاثیر را در نگهداشت کارکنان داشته است&lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; عوامل سازمانی در این تحقیق شامل پنج مولفه: ماهیت شغل، ارتقاء شغلی، نظام پرداخت، سبک رهبری، حمایت اجتماعی است. بر اساس نتایج بدست آمده از تحلیل عاملی، سبک رهبری با عدد معنی داری از آزمون &lt;span dir=&quot;LTR&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt; به دست آمده برابر 18.21و ضریب مسیر 0.965 بیشترین سهم ونقش را در بین عوامل سازمانی به خود اختصاص داده است.&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p&gt;One of the basic tasks of human resources management, staff retention is maintenance. With the complement to other measures and human resources management processes, even if the operation of the recruitment, selection, appointment and renewal to be done properly without giving due consideration to maintenance, results management will be modest. The aim of this study was the model retention of employees of public organizations.. Therefore, after reviewing the literature and the use of expert opinions, the original investigation was set. Then, using expert opinions, the final research model was ready. The research method used descriptive statistical population of the research staff of the Department of Education have formed the province. Stratified random sampling method and based on Morgan table sample of 217 people. In this study, staff retention factors including cultural factors, organizational factors, government agencies. The results of structural equation shows that the path coefficient cultural factors, 00:29, 00:27 governmental factors, organizational factors was 0.31. The results suggest that organizational factors have the greatest impact on employee retention. Organizational factors in this study consists of five components: job content, promotions, payment systems, leadership style, social support. Based on the results of the factor analysis, leadership style t-test with a significant number obtained 18.21 against 0.965 path coefficient between organizational factors accounted for the largest share in the role.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>نگهداشت, عوامل فرهنگی, عوامل سازمانی, عوامل دولتی, عوامل فردی, عوامل محیطی.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>retention, cultural factors, organizational factors, government factors, personal factors, Environmental factors</keyword>
	<start_page>291</start_page>
	<end_page>304</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-1145-19&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>حسن</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>توکلی نژاد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004987</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004987</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>نسرین</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>جزنی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004988</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004988</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>غلامرضا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>معمارزاده</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004989</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004989</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name></first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name></last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>محمد علی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>افشار کاظمی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846004990</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846004990</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa></affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
