<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1394</year>
	<month>6</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2015</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>14</volume>
<number>39</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>شهر دوستدار سالمند و معیارهای طراحی مراکز تعاملات اجتماعیِ سالمندی با رویکرد سلامت‌روان</title_fa>
	<title>Age-friendly city design criteria centers of social interaction with the concepts of space and culture approach to mental health</title>
	<subject_fa>عمومى</subject_fa>
	<subject>General</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
امروزه توجه به جایگاه و نقش سالمندان در نظام برنامه‌ریزی شهری و معماری از یک‌طرف و تحقق-پذیری شهرهای دوستدار سالمند، از اولویتهای اساسی در فرآیند برنامه‌ریزی شهر و معماری است که تطورات بافت اجتماعی و تغییر ساختار سنی کشور و تحولات جمعیتی موجود که به پیر شدن جمعیت شهری می‌پردازد، نیز بر این امر تاکید دارد. در این میان، پرداختن به مقوله «سلامت روان» از اصلی-ترین نیازهای روان‌شناختی سالمندان است که در این پژوهش با تاکید بر نظریه‌های سلامت روان و نظریه‌های طراحی فضاهای شهری و معماری، تلاش شده است تا معیارهایی در طراحی مراکز تعاملات اجتماعی سالمندی در قالب فضای افزایش تعاملات اجتماعی مورد اشاره قرار گیرد. مبنای نظری این تحقیق، بر اساس نظریه فعالیتِ «گاست» و «نظریه میدانی کورت لوین» بوده که از روش تحقیق «توصیفی- تحلیلی» در مرحله ادبیات نظری و روش تحقیق «فراتحلیل» در جمعبندی نظریه-ها و راهکارسنجی با ابزار گرداوری داده مشتمل بر مطالعات کتابخانه‌ای و اسنادی بهره برده است. در پایان راهکارهایی چند در راستای تحقق‌پذیری شهرهای دوستدار سالمند در مرحله اول و پیشنهاداتی در حوزه معیارهای طراحی برای ارتقاء سلامت روان‌شناختی سالمندان در مرحله دوم مورد اشاره قرار گرفته است.
</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
Attention to the role of the elderly in the urban planning and architecture on the one hand and the realization of the age-friendly cities, the main priorities in the process of planning and architecture. Evolutionary social context and changes in age structure of the population changes in the aging urban population, also focuses on this. Meanwhile, addressing the issue of &quot;mental health&quot; of the main psychological needs of the elderly in this study, with an emphasis on mental health theories and theories of urban design and architecture is done. Tries to measures designed to increase the space in the old centers of social interaction social interaction is discussed. The theoretical basis of this study, based on the idea of &quot;y Gasset&quot; and &quot;field theory of Kurt Lewin was&quot;. The method of &quot;descriptive&quot; in the theoretical literature and research methods &quot;meta-analysis&quot; in discussions with the Data theories and studies, including the library and documentary benefited. At the end of several strategies in order to achieve the first stage of age-friendly cities and recommendations on measures designed to improve the mental health of the elderly in the second stage agreement has been mentioned.
</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>شهر دوستدار سالمند, مرکز تعاملات اجتماعی, نظریه‌های تعاملات اجتماعی, نظریه سلامت روان.</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>age-friendly city, the center of social interaction, social communication theories, and theories of mental health.</keyword>
	<start_page>7</start_page>
	<end_page>34</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-697-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Hooshang</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Forooghmand Araabi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>هوشنگ</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>فروغمند اعرابی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>h-foroughmand@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001856</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001856</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران جنوب</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Leila</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Karimi Fard</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>لیلا</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>کریمی فرد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>10031947532846001857</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001857</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation></affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران جنوب</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
