<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1393</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2014</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>13</volume>
<number>36</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>تعیین عوامل انگیزشی ساکنین بافت فرسوده شهر شیراز برای مشارکت دربهسازی و نوسازی آن</title_fa>
	<title>Factors motivating residents of Shiraz distressed areas to participate in improving and renovating programAbstract</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>
امروزه مشارکت مردم در نوسازی بافت فرسوده شهرها به عنوان مهم‌ترین عامل موفقیت درمدیریت شهری محسوب می‌شود. بدیهی است که مشارکت مردم در نوسازی بافت فرسوده، نیازمند وجود انگیزه‌های لازم ساکنین است و وجود انگیزه‌های لازم مستلزم متقاعد‌شدن آنها در این کار می‌باشد. متقاعد‌شدن نیز نیازمند گفتگو و انعطاف‌پذیری ساکنین می‌باشد و طبیعتاً گفتگو و انعطاف‌پذیری مستلزم شناخت عوامل انگیزشی مردم در مشارکت می‌باشد.
مقاله حاضر حاصل پژوهشی است که در خصوص تعیین عوامل انگیزشی مشارکت مردم در بهسازی و نوسازی بافت‌های فرسوده شهرشیراز انجام شده است. این پژوهش از لحاظ هدف کاربردی و به‌لحاظ روش از نوع توصیفی- تحلیلی بوده و گردآوری داده‏ها به شیوه پیمایش صورت گرفته است. ابزار سنجش این پژوهش پرسشنامه ای بود که روایی آن توسط صاحب‏ نظران مدیریت شهری مورد تأیید قرار گرفت. نمونه آماری تحقیق شامل 400 نفر از ساکنین محله‌های مختلف منطقه تاریخی و فرهنگی شهر شیراز است. 
پرسش اصلی این پژوهش عبارت بود از این که مهمترین عامل انگیزشی مردم برای مشارکت در بهسازی و نوسازی بافت چیست؟ یافته‏های پژوهش نشان می دهد که از بین عوامل انگیزشی،  عامل محله به خصوص علاقه به بهتر شدن محله و بالا رفتن امنیت آن از سایر انگیزه‏ها تاثیر بیشتری بر مشارکت داشته است. با بررسی عوامل فردی مشخص شد که سن و نوع جنسیت فرد بر بالا رفتن مشارکت تاثیر دارد.

</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>
Urban distressed area has been a serious problem in many cities in Iran for decades. One of the fundamental trends in Iranian government has been the implementation of consistent strategies for overcoming problems of urban distressed area. Old historical zone of Shiraz city is among the distressed area with different cultural, social and physical problems. Amongst the improvement and renovation policies for dealing with distressed areas is the concept of the people participation. 
Partnership is part of the social responsibility to overcome the urban problems. ‘People Participation’ is a very commonly used term in the urban development literature as well as in policy making and implementation by both governments and non-governmental bodies. It can be defined as an interventionist process leading to a sustainable improvement in the standard of living and welfare of the people living in the distressed areas.  
What people say is also what they believe as well as what they need. When investigating about the population structure of Shiraz distressed area, what the residents believe about their living area and their partnership in improvement and renovation is very important.
The current study investigated what factors motivate people to participate in improving and renovating their living areas. For this purpose, answering the following questions was conducted:
1) What ate the residents’ views concerning their willingness to cooperate with the government for improving and renovating Shiraz distress areas. 
2) What are the factors that motivate residents to participate in improvement and renovation?
3) What are the barriers that interfere with people’ participation?
In this study, the technique of the questionnaire is used and the statistical analysis of the questionnaire is carried out using the SPSS program. By using the questionnaire data, the population structure of Shiraz distressed area and their willingness to participate in improving and renovating program were identified. The questionnaire carried out in this study consisted of 21 questions. The questions were presented in either a short answer or multiple-choice format. The questionnaire survey carried out from July 2012 until November 2012. 400 residents of the entire population of old historical zone of Shiraz city were asked to answer the survey questionnaire. 
In order to analysis the questionnaire. The questionnaire was assessed to see what will encourage people to participate in improving and renovating program. This is assessed by asking respondents to judge the partnership. The respondents were asked to rate the agreement of each item. It refers to the degree to which an individual approve the benefit of participation in improving and renovating program. 
There are different motivations affecting the people participation in improving and renovating program. For finding the motivations affecting the people participation, Kendall’s tau correlation coefficient was calculated for bivariate comparisons between partnership and different items. Strong association was found for age and gender of the respondent. Also, the respondents who like to have relation with their neighbors and those have participated for regeneration and revitalization of urban distressed areas have more tendencies in participation. 
The most important reasons for participating in improving and renovating program identified through this study were security progress of districts, the houses firmness and district cleanness. Survey respondents also indicated that encouragement of others, significantly contributed to the participating in improving and renovating program.

</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>بافت‌های فرسوده, شیراز, بهسازی و نو سازی, مشارکت, عوامل انگیزشی</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Distressed Area, Improvement and Renovation, Shiraz, Motivation Factors,</keyword>
	<start_page>223</start_page>
	<end_page>232</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-244-2&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Khosro</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Movahed</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>خسرو</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>موحد</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>Khmovahed1@yahoo.com</email>
	<code>10031947532846001409</code>
	<orcid>10031947532846001409</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>Faculty of Arts and Architecture, Islamic Azad University of Shiraz</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده هنر و معماری دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد شیراز</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
