<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<journal>
<title>urban and rural management</title>
<title_fa>مديريت شهري و روستايي</title_fa>
<short_title>مديريت</short_title>
<subject>Art &amp; Architecture</subject>
<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir</web_url>
<journal_hbi_system_id>1</journal_hbi_system_id>
<journal_hbi_system_user>admin</journal_hbi_system_user>
<journal_id_issn>1607-2227</journal_id_issn>
<journal_id_issn_online></journal_id_issn_online>
<journal_id_pii>8</journal_id_pii>
<journal_id_doi>7</journal_id_doi>
<journal_id_iranmedex></journal_id_iranmedex>
<journal_id_magiran></journal_id_magiran>
<journal_id_sid>14</journal_id_sid>
<journal_id_nlai>8888</journal_id_nlai>
<journal_id_science>13</journal_id_science>
<language>fa</language>
<pubdate>
	<type>jalali</type>
	<year>1392</year>
	<month>9</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<pubdate>
	<type>gregorian</type>
	<year>2013</year>
	<month>12</month>
	<day>1</day>
</pubdate>
<volume>11</volume>
<number>32</number>
<publish_type>online</publish_type>
<publish_edition>1</publish_edition>
<article_type>fulltext</article_type>
<articleset>
	<article>


	<language>fa</language>
	<article_id_doi></article_id_doi>
	<title_fa>کیفیت فضاهای عمومی و افزایش تعاملات اجتماعی( مطالعه موردی: مجتمع مسکونی کوثر و فاز دو مجتمع مسکونی اکباتان )</title_fa>
	<title>Public spaces and social interactions enhancement (Case study: Kosar residential complex and Ekbatan residential complex-phase 2)</title>
	<subject_fa>تخصصي</subject_fa>
	<subject>Special</subject>
	<content_type_fa>پژوهشي</content_type_fa>
	<content_type>Research</content_type>
	<abstract_fa>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;براساس مدلهایی که برای تعریف نیازهای انسانی ارائه شده‌اند، تعاملات اجتماعی، یکی از موارد ضروری می‌باشد. جدا از مسایل مربوط به باورها، نگرش‌ها، ترجیحات و دیگر جنبه های شخصیتی ویژه افراد که در نظریه‌های مربوط به علوم رفتاری به عنوان مهمترین عوامل کنترل کننده رفتار انسان مطرح شده‌اند، محیط کالبدی نیز در ارتباط با رفتارهای انسان امکانات بالقوه‌ای دارد. در این راستا، فضاهای عمومی مجتمع‌های مسکونی بعنوان محیطی که امکان حضور ساکنان درکنار یکدیگر را فراهم می‌کند، می‌تواند زمینه ساز ایجاد تعامل بین آنها شود. عدم توجه به این نیاز افراد و عدم قابلیت محیط در تامین آن، موجب می-شود تا محیط کالبدی بسیاری از مجتمع های مسکونی به مجموعه‌ای از احجام و فضای خالی بین آنها تبدیل گردد. این مسئله می‌تواند باعث نارضایتی ساکنان از محیط زندگی و متعاقب آن عدم حضور در فضاهای عمومی مجتمع‌، بعنوان لازمه‌ی بروز فعالیت‌های بعدی، شود. این مقاله به بررسی این مسئله در دو مجتمع مسکونی به عنوان نمونه، ازطریق مشاهده میدانی و مصاحبه و طرح پرسشنامه می‌پردازد. در پایان با روش تحلیل همبستگی داده‌ها جمع بندی و نتیجه ارائه شده است. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract_fa>
	<abstract>&lt;p align=&quot;justify&quot;&gt;Based on the models which are presented in order to define the human needs, social interactions is one of the necessary issues. Disregarding the notions, beliefs, preferences and other aspect of different personalities which are thought to be the most important human behavior controllers in behavioral science theories, physical environment also has a potential impact related to the human behavior. In according to this, public spaces in residential areas, as the places that provide residents with the possibility of gathering together, could establish the social interactions among them. Ignoring this need of residents and also the environment’s capability for supporting this issue, may change physical environment into useless and empty spaces. This could cause dissatisfaction of the environment among inhabitants and consequently, would result to their absence in public spaces. The present study, investigated this issue in two residential complexes by using field survey, interviews, and questionnaire. Finally the data were analyzed by correlation coefficient and then the result presented. &lt;/p&gt;</abstract>
	<keyword_fa>فضای عمومی ،  فعالیت جمعی ، تعامل اجتماعی ، قابلیت محیط</keyword_fa>
	<keyword>Public space, communal activity, social  interaction, environmental affordance</keyword>
	<start_page>7</start_page>
	<end_page>22</end_page>
	<web_url>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?a_code=A-10-76-1&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=fa</web_url>


<author_list>
	<author>
	<first_name>Abbas</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Yazdanfar</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سیدعباس</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>یزدانفر</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460097</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460097</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Baqer</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Hoseini</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>سیدباقر</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>حسینی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email></email>
	<code>100319475328460098</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460098</orcid>
	<coreauthor>No</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


	<author>
	<first_name>Mostafa</first_name>
	<middle_name></middle_name>
	<last_name>Zaroodi</last_name>
	<suffix></suffix>
	<first_name_fa>مصطفی</first_name_fa>
	<middle_name_fa></middle_name_fa>
	<last_name_fa>زرودی</last_name_fa>
	<suffix_fa></suffix_fa>
	<email>mostafa_zaroudi@arch.iust.ac.ir</email>
	<code>100319475328460099</code>
	<orcid>100319475328460099</orcid>
	<coreauthor>Yes
</coreauthor>
	<affiliation>School of Architecture University of Science and Technology, Iran</affiliation>
	<affiliation_fa>دانشکده معماری و شهرسازی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</affiliation_fa>
	 </author>


</author_list>


	</article>
</articleset>
</journal>
