
	<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"	xmlns:cr_unixml="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
	<responseDate>2020-07-22T09:12:36+04:30</responseDate>
	<request metadataPrefix="cr_unixml" verb="ListRecords" set="10.1002">http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/browse.php?mag_id=28&amp;slc_lang=fa&amp;sid=1</request>
	<ListRecords>
		
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1445</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Investigation the financing strategies of improvement and renovation projects of urban distressed areas</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The vast expanse of the urban distressed areas in the country and multiple damages that their inhabitants face on economic, social and cultural aspects remind the need for higher attention to these constructions. Meanwhile, Tehran's distressed areas with more than 3268 hectares (5.3% of the area of ​​Tehran) has a population of one million and three hundred thousand people in it, is one of the priorities of the improvement and renovations in the country. According to what most experts and researchers say one of the main obstacles to the process of improvement and renovation of the urban distressed areas, is the selection and use of appropriate methods of financing. Several methods of financing that have been raised to be used in the process of improvement and renovation,&amp;nbsp;on one hand due to the variety they provide are an opportunity, and on the other hand face the managers and city decision-makers with some problems in the process of selection and utilization, because using any of the methods depends on several regional and local factors. In this regard and in order to facilitate the process of decision-making in the process of improvement and renovation of urban distressed areas, this research used a cross-sectional study and also investigated the evaluation criteria and different methods of financing the distressed areas and &amp;nbsp;using the obtained field data from questionnaires distributed in two stages using ANOVA test, tested the research hypothesis in order to determine the best financing method according to the improvement and renovation process from the perspective of the tested criteria and in this way tried to compare the various methods of financing in order to take advantage of the process of improving and renovation of urban distressed areas in Tehran. In this regard and based on the obtained results three methods of repayment from the operation of the project, civic engagement (contract) -guaranteed and selling shares were identified as ways with the highest priority to utilize in the process of improvement and renovation of the urban distressed areas of Tehran.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>urban distressed areas</keyword>
	<keyword> financing methods</keyword>
	<keyword> the process of improvement and renovation</keyword>
	<keyword> Tehran city.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>9</first_page>
								  <last_page>18</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1445-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1446</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Assistant professor, Architectural department, Payame Noor University</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			University students are exposed to stress because of their age and their particular situation. Stress can cause serious problems to the health and academic performance of students. One of the factors affecting stress is the environment. Therefore, finding ways to reduce stress in universities is important and needs to be investigated. Unfortunately, one of the fundamental problems of universities is the lack of features and qualities of a space that reduces the stress of students. This means that university spaces are not designed and constructed for reducing the stress of students and enough attention was not paid to this issue. The relative lack of research in this field makes necessary to pay attention to this issue and carry out studies in this regard. The purpose of this study is to provide effective spatial features to reduce the stress of university students and to determine the effectiveness of each of these features. The research is conducted by survey method and Delphi technique was carried out in three rounds. For this purpose, firstly open-ended questionnaires were distributed among the experts. Then the answers were investigated and the lists of features were extracted. In the next step, based on the information obtained, close-ended questionnaires were made and the importance levels of features were put into question among the experts and then data were analyzed using SPSS software. In the final stage, experts expressed their final opinions considering the statistical results of the previous stage. The results of this study showed that effective spatial features on stress reduction of students are classified by influencing level into four categories of environmental conditions, natural factors, environmental comfort and physical aspects. And among the details of these features, adequate and proper light for spaces&amp;rdquo;, connecting with outdoor and semi-outdoor spaces and desirable sound in spaces, are of utmost importance.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Effective spatial features on stress reduction</keyword>
	<keyword> university</keyword>
	<keyword> students.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>19</first_page>
								  <last_page>34</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1446-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1447</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Comparative Analysis of Urban Construction Patterns in Historical district and Spontaneous Settlements (Case Studies: Historical District in Yazd and Baghshater District in Tehran)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Investigation on modern history of urban planning in Iran shows that there are three approaches in the subject under discussion: &amp;ldquo;Modernism and Westernism&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Traditionalism and anti-Westernism&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Adopt and Adapt&amp;rdquo;. Proponents of the first approach believe in encouraging methods to use the external concepts. The second, is the idea about ​​cultural and religious values, ​​thereby everything with nontraditional orientation is rejected. In the third approach the thinkers believe that if the parts of tradition are synthesized by modernity, culture and religion can adapt themselves with the development. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the adaptation of traditional urban design patterns of Islamic-Iranian cities in incompatible district of new Iranian cities (spontaneous settlements) and to focus on the application of the third approach in the current situation of Iranian cities. On this basis, the method of comparative analysis has been applied to survey the differences and similarities between historical districts and spontaneous settlements. Studies show that there are rather similarities among physical - spatial parameters (such as structural and environmental criteria) between the two types of districts; because both of these residential districts formed as organic structures that are unstable against unexpected risks and earthquake. However, there are the differences between these two types of districts in organized and formed periods. Despite historical districts that have been consolidated and organized during hundreds of years, spontaneous urban textures formed quickly and without any plan and planning. Meanwhile, the historical districts have usually integrated townscapes and unique materials such as clay, bricks or stone, while this character (integrated townscape and unique materials) never have been seen in the spontaneous settlements. There are similarities in economic and socio- cultural characteristics between residents in the two the types of districts. The residents living in poor economic condition, but under a very strong socio-capital and traditional beliefs; There can be seen several socio-cultural and particularly religious characteristics in people of historical residential districts that are similar with the spontaneous residential places, such as &amp;ldquo;strong relationship among families, friends&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;hospitality&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;mutual relationship among family members&amp;rdquo;, strong religious beliefs and the needs for privacy and security. However, these communities are different in some principles such as quality of life and spatial and physical qualities especially in favorable and beautiful urban landscapes. So it can be extracted and adopted excellent principles from traditional and historical districts and adapt them to the inappropriate modern urban districts. With regard to the existence of these similarities, we explain applicable principles of the spatial characteristics and designing quality in the historical district of Yazd to apply in Baghshater District in Tehran as a spontaneous settlement. Findings show that we can use several solutions to reconstruct this zone included: 1) land readjustment as the suitable solution in Baghshater District with regard to the familial residential pattern in historical zone of Yazd such as Fahadan District. 2) Focusing on the traditional concept of mutual relationship in residential houses. 3) Emphasizing on the hierarchy of The entrances and exits of the residential units.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Tradition</keyword>
	<keyword> modernity</keyword>
	<keyword> adopt</keyword>
	<keyword> historical zone of Yazd</keyword>
	<keyword> familial residential pattern</keyword>
	<keyword> Baghshater spontaneous settlement.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>35</first_page>
								  <last_page>50</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1447-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1448</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title> Bio-urban design and the Hidden Rules of Nature</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			There was a turning point in each period of time which human has discovered a new sight about the world and nature order in a way, and then has presented this relation by numeral, artful and industrial language. Biourbanism focuses on the urban organism, considering it as a hyper complex system, according to its internal and external dynamics and their mutual interactions. Nowadays when it is talked about technology, different kinds of cars and big buildings are stroked in human mind؛ It is clear that if the technology result which is the answer of fundamental human needs is considered, it almost will be clear the reason of some circumstances, that each industrial or structural phenomena has been inspired from which natural alive pattern, so it has to be a relation with logical and scientific principles between mechanical system and alive constant system. The main aim of using important nature achievements is that instead of recreating from alive fauna , study nature principles and their consistency because all things in nature are powers balance , so that world has structure , therefore architectures and experts commissions and trainings to find better solution for symbiosis with nature serves as today world need. Bio urbanism endorses principles of geometrical coherence, Biophilic design, Bio Architecture, Bio mimesis, etc. in practices of design and also new urban policies and, especially Bio politics, to promote urban revitalization by ensuring that man-made changes do not have harmful effects to humans.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Bio-urban</keyword>
	<keyword> Nature</keyword>
	<keyword> Hidden Rules</keyword>
	<keyword> Bio urbanism.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>51</first_page>
								  <last_page>64</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1448-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1449</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Reflecting the symbolic meanings of Islamic mysticism in design of Mosque in Hermeneutic and Semiotic as research methodology</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Mosques, as symbol of Islamic architecture must play an important role in reflecting the superiority of Allah the Almighty. There are many ways in making it successful and one of them is through the high quality of aesthetic value. Aesthetic value in Islamic art and architecture is normally portrayed by the highest degree of motifs and ornamentation. Contemporary mosque designers normally focused on the majestic looks of the exterior part of the mosques and leave the manipulation of the interior space to the users. This research method is descriptive - analytic gathering tool: library studies and documents referring to the theories of thinkers has benefited the field. So, this paper explain Reflecting the symbolic meanings of Islamic mysticism in design of Mosque in Hermeneutic and Semiotic as research methodology. At the end of some of the concepts related to reread the configuration mystical concepts discussed in the relevant analysis is presented.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>mysticism</keyword>
	<keyword> Utopia</keyword>
	<keyword> narrative structure</keyword>
	<keyword> architecture and urban fabric of the city.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>65</first_page>
								  <last_page>78</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1449-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1450</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Evaluation of urban management and political Scandinavian economy (case study: Sweden and Norway)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Study on international political economy of two countries, Sweden and Norway, in international interactions allows us to examine political economy of these two countries as the case study for further understanding of macro patterns of international political economy.&amp;nbsp; Thus, understanding the power of influence of international developments in two economic and political areas in internal relations of countries refers to one of the necessities in this research. The present research displays how a constant pattern such as the welfare state pattern can change under influence of global relations or loses its some principles, i.e. the vice versa of this rule is true. In other words, we face impact and effectiveness of the two sides of the exchange. Without doubt, movement toward pattern of welfare state generates behaviors, patterns and considerations at the area of foreign policy of Sweden and Norway, which we will examine them in this research. However this multi-variable equation has not yet on the stage of final settlement and in some cases the relation between Norway and Sweden has not yet defined with the developments in the new world at the area of international political economy, definition for what going on is required to understand this complexity and the reason for creation of some ambiguities. Definition for political economy of Norway and Sweden as two countries with the most welfare worldwide reveals the necessity to conduct this research.&amp;nbsp; Since Norway and Sweden have a distinctive pattern in their welfare services, measurement of the relation between these distinctive patterns and common patterns which have conventionalized at the international economy is considered a major concern. Ultimately, this research is the necessity for our country to use the interactive pattern existing in Scandinavian&amp;nbsp;countries at the area of international political economy. however, there are huge differences between our country and Scandinavian&amp;nbsp; countries in terms of geographical position, population size and financial facilities, it can use some of the patterns of welfare state in our country and some of the behavioral patterns of Norway and Sweden in international relations to progress the political and economic relations of our country in international system.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>political economy</keyword>
	<keyword> Scandinavian</keyword>
	<keyword> Sweden</keyword>
	<keyword> Norway </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>79</first_page>
								  <last_page>92</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1450-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1451</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Identify enablers of agility and agile modeling strategy with neural network approach</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The electronic industry suffers a rapid changing and highly rival environment. Thus, firms have an essential need to strive for acquiring the competitive advantage. Strategy Organizational Agility (SOA) is a tool which enables to assist firms to attain the competitive advantage. Therefore, this study benchmarks the core competencies from a case study within the supply chain network and establishes a set of attributes for augmenting SOA. A novel multi-criteria decision-making structure is proposed to deal with the complex interrelationships among the aspects and attributes. Radial basis function (RBF) neural network can use linear learning algorithm to complete the work formerly handled by nonlinear learning algorithm, and maintain the high precision of the nonlinear algorithm. However, the results of RBF would be slightly unsatisfactory when dealing with small sample which has higher feature dimension and fewer numbers. Higher feature dimension will influence the design of neural network, and fewer numbers of samples will cause network training incomplete or over-fitted, both of which restrict the recognition precision of the neural network. The competence and accountability indicators can the continuously increasing level of agility to be effective. According to the analysis chart production and product design performance indicators alone cannot level a considerable amount of agility to change. But reducing the level of the index level of agility is reduced. Flexibility indices speed and agility level changes can also affect the organization. But with increased levels of these two indicators increased agility rate change indicators will be more flexibility. The results showed that customer knowledge management impact on organizational agility and organizational effectiveness and customer knowledge management through organizational agility has significant positive impact on organizational effectiveness. Finally, some practical suggestions, future research suggestions and research limitations are presented.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Organization Agility</keyword>
	<keyword> enablers</keyword>
	<keyword> Neural Network</keyword>
	<keyword> strategy</keyword>
	<keyword> approach.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>93</first_page>
								  <last_page>120</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1451-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1452</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Identification and evaluation of factors affecting the adoption of e-banking in the customers of country\'s banking system (Case Study: Post Bank)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Today's world has been built on the basis of competition and uncertainty, thus the role of facilitators, such as technology and information technology is undeniable. In this research developed Technology Acceptance Model to identify and prioritizing the factors affecting was used on formation of decision and behavior of customers in adoption of Internet banking of Post Bank. The statistical population consisted of all consumers of Post Bank in Tehran. Total of 400 questionnaires was distributed among community members; ultimately 384 usable questionnaires were coded and were entered into SPSS and LISREL software up to use the analysis of data. Results of factor analysis indicated proper fitting of the model and compliance of extracted factors with designed questions and explained variables in the model of the research. At the inferential statistics level also the results of using single sample T-test and ANOVA Friedman tests often were confirmed research hypotheses. Furthermore were showed the ease of application variable has the most influence on Internet banking adoption and next variables had been in order being applied, the security of private information, being pleasure existence of appropriate hardware and familiarity with Internet banking.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Internet-banking</keyword>
	<keyword> technology adoption model</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>121</first_page>
								  <last_page>132</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1452-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1453</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Evaluate the relationship between intellectual capital and the performance of employees of Ports and Maritime Organization</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The present research has been done with the aim of determine the relationship between intellectual capital and employee performance of Ports and Maritime Organization. Statistical population of the present study includes head office employees of Tehran Ports and Maritime Organization. The statistical population is 140 people, 103 samples were selected according to Morgan table. In this research, field study and the standard questionnaire of intellectual capital of Bontis (1998) and employee performance of Hersey and Goldsmith (1980) have been used as data collection tools, In order to describe the data, descriptive statistics to analyze the data and Kolmogorov Smirnov test and Pearson's correlation coefficient have been used to evaluate the research hypotheses .Statistical analysis has been done by using SPSS software. According to the results of this research there is a significant relationship between the dimensions of intellectual capital (human capital, structural capital, relational capital)&amp;nbsp; with the performance of Ports and Maritime Organization, and intellectual capital and its dimensions was not assessed at desirable level in the Ports and Maritime Organization with an average rate of 3.224 as well as the performance of employees was not assessed at desirable level in the Ports and Maritime Organization with the Average Rate of 3.468 .

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>intellectual capital</keyword>
	<keyword> human capital</keyword>
	<keyword> relational capital</keyword>
	<keyword> structural capital</keyword>
	<keyword> employee performance</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>133</first_page>
								  <last_page>142</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1453-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1454</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>The challenges in Cyberspace Mate Selection among the young people of Jahrom in 1395</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The Internet along with many advantages has some disadvantages, and the lack of a complete understanding of cyberspace can cause damage in terms of mate selection method. This article attempts to address some of the disadvantages and threats that virtual spaces create in mate selection method and tries to introduce some strategies to prevent and reduce these emerging injuries. This study was conducted using a questionnaire survey and the reference method. The population of this research is all youth between 20 to 34 years old who live in Jahrom in 1395. The sampling methods used here is the cluster sampling method. The sample size has been calculated by the Cochran formula, and 320 people were selected. The questionnaire was 0.77 alpha general questionnaire and statistical analysis was performed by SPSS software in the form of analyzing the correlation coefficient and regression.&amp;nbsp;In this research, after describing the stages of major indicators of family position as the most important unit of society, and after declaring the ideas about mate selection and cyberspace relationships, and mentioning them as opportunities and threats, emerging injuries following by cyberspace relationships and their influence on the mate selection methods are discussed.&amp;nbsp; In this study, family attachment, traditional values and the level of religiosity are effective in young people attitudes to cyberspace mate selection, as well as effective variables have an impact on mate selection method with a coefficient of 0.611% were able to predict changes. In other words, effective independent variables have been able to define 0.611% of changes in mate selection methods, and the rest of the effects are due to some variables that are not included in this study.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Cyberspace Mate Selection young people </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>143</first_page>
								  <last_page>152</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1454-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1455</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Reviewing causative &amp; effect relationships of budget deficit, money offering &amp; inflation rate in Iran</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The main goal of this research is studying the causative &amp; effect of deficit budget, money offering and inflation rate in Iran during 1360-1390. The results in long time indicates that the bulk of money has had positive effect &amp; meaning on inflation rate during that time and alteration of budget deficit of the government has also positive effect on inflation but by meaningless impress, in other words this alteration has no independent impress from other alterations and specially form the bulk of money on inflation. Also on the basis of the results of Grenjer causative test, there is a direct relationship or indirect among all the alterations in the model. In regard with the results, money offering is one impressive alteration on inflation and continued increasing in offering the money leads to increasing of inflation. In other hand there is a causative relationship between budget deficit and inflation. Increasing the inflation causes increasing the expenditures and decreasing the revenues therefore by considering that high percentage of budget deficit in Iran to be supplied by central bank that has expansible effect on the total demand &amp; price levels. It is necessary that budget deficit to be supplied from other ways except receiving the loan from bank system such as getting loan from people and selling governmental valuable papers. 

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Deficit</keyword>
	<keyword> Inflation</keyword>
	<keyword> Money Supply</keyword>
	<keyword> Causality</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>153</first_page>
								  <last_page>160</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1455-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1456</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Impact of social capital on employees\' job performance of Forensic Medicine Organization</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The aim of this study is to investigate the relationship between social capital among employees with their job performance in Tehran's Forensic Medicine Organization. The study population consisted of all the employees of Tehran's Forensic Medicine Organization in 2015 that based on available statistics are 120 employees that because of limited statistical population, sampling has not been done. To collect data, two instruments were used to measure including social capital questionnaire of Nahapiet and Ghoshal (1998), with average reliability coefficient of 93% and job performance questionnaire of Hersey and Goldsmith Achiu model with average reliability coefficient of 88%. Descriptive statistics were used to describe the data and to analyze and evaluate the research hypotheses; test of inferential statistics including univariate regression analysis was used. While confirming the research hypotheses, results showed: Structural, cognitive and communicative dimensions of social capital of employees have an increasing and positive impact on their job performance and this effect is statistically significant. 

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>social capital</keyword>
	<keyword> job performance</keyword>
	<keyword> Tehran's Forensic Medicine Organization</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>161</first_page>
								  <last_page>172</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1456-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1457</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Consideration of satisfaction factors of electronic management of relationship with customers in factories</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Widespread usage of web technology provides an opportunity for business in order to use internet as the tool for management of electronic relationship with costumers. Organizations that undertake expense of investment in this field, one of their primary purposes is improvement of satisfaction of costumers. For this reason, in most of organizations which use the system of electronic relationship with costumers, there is this question that does this action affects customer satisfaction or not? Therefore, it is determined that this question and dimensions of customer satisfaction are considered in research project. The present research is functional in terms of the purpose. The results of research, after collection of data and analysis by using LISREL software shows that electronic management in factories affects satisfaction dimensions of after-sale services, product and sales process.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword> electronic management of relationship with customer</keyword>
	<keyword> customer satisfaction</keyword>
	<keyword> structural equations</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>173</first_page>
								  <last_page>186</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1457-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1458</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Mediating effect of Knowledge management mediating effect on relationship between organizational culture and entrepreneurial orientation (Case study: employees of Qazvin’s municipalities of districts one and two)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The aim of the present research was to study the impact of organizational culture on entrepreneurial orientation given the mediating role of knowledge management. The statistical population consisted of the employees of district 1 and 2 municipalities of Qazvin who were about 200 in number, of whom 130 people were selected based on stratified random sampling method and Cochran formula. Data analysis was done using structural equation modeling with the help of LISREL 8.8 software and Smart PLS 2 in two parts: measurement model and structural part. In the former, technical characteristics of questionnaire were evaluated and the necessary amendments were made; and in the second part, the coefficients of structural model were used to test the hypothesis of the research. The results indicate a significant and positive impact on the entrepreneurial orientation of organizational culture and knowledge management on the one hand and on the other hand a significant impact on the relationship between the two of the mediator of knowledge management.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>knowledge management</keyword>
	<keyword> organizational culture</keyword>
	<keyword> entrepreneurial orientation</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>187</first_page>
								  <last_page>198</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1458-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1459</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Investigation of Rural Area and Development Strategies; Case Study of Central District of Semnan County</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Generally, studied villages as regard to the Socioeconomic structure have not considerable development in comparison with their around structure due to functional area.&amp;nbsp; Nowadays, regarding rural development, proceeding with economical analysis of geographical areas has a great position. Considering the applied investigations, upon increasing the knowledge and literacy and scientific and practical skills, tendency for employment in the traditional areas has been decreased and interest for employment in modern and service departments has been increased as you may see in the Iran&amp;rsquo;s villages. We may say there are new and not discovered opportunities in these areas. Timely discovering and operating these opportunities, and constituting new and competitive businesses and works can provide salient socioeconomic privileges for the villagers. The results of this research indicates that the most proper rural development strategy in the region, environmental development and planning which is the optimum and sufficient pattern towards achieving the rural sustainable development in the region.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>rural development</keyword>
	<keyword> rural environment</keyword>
	<keyword> sustainable development </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>199</first_page>
								  <last_page>210</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1459-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1460</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Determine school performance evaluation model based on data envelopment analysis and TOPSIS (Case Study: urban High Schools in Qazvin)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Performance evaluation is one of the most important management agendas as key to achieving continuous improvement in the ability to evaluate the ongoing performance of the organization. Many organizations have realized the importance of ongoing evaluation of performance and performance appraisal systems employ a variety of organizations. In this regard between 1850 and 1975, only on the basis of financial measures to assess the performance of the organizations involved, for reasons such as: encouraging short-term view of the lack of strategic focus and inability to provide data about the quality, responsiveness and flexibility, encouraging an optimistic view, the failure to provide information about what customers want and how competitors were criticized. Methods: This study intends to evaluate the model ordinary native city through the provision of integrated model questionnaire and analyze the results it provides. The proposed model schools ranked theoretical and mathematical description is composed of two parts. This model utilizes the model of the Balanced Scorecard, developed its shape or conceptual cross section of the rating model, the recall is complete. All the research community to the city of Qazvin is no ordinary high school. A total of 177 patients were collected points. For the analysis of data obtained from the decision matrix with TOPSIS technique and Excel software to compare the two choice expert significant part of this research is 5%.packaging determined. The results of the ranking of schools with units 2 TOPSIS indicate that the school is the top priority compared to other options. Conclusion: All the components of the index and rank high schools in the city of Qazvin no effective diagnostic data obtained for decision criteria are less than 0.05. So all indicators can be used to evaluate the performance of ordinary high schools, theoretically, contribute to the city of Qazvin. 

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>fusion model</keyword>
	<keyword> TOPSIS</keyword>
	<keyword> school performance</keyword>
	<keyword> performance evaluation </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>211</first_page>
								  <last_page>224</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1460-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1461</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>The right of citizens in social Justice in the International Documents of Human Rights and the Constitution law of the Islamic Republic of Iran </title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The rights of citizens to provide Social justice, due to emphasis on the basic needs of human beings, known as one of the most fundamental principles in international documents of human rights and civil rights. It's indicators include the right to a fair life, right to health, right to education, right to social security, and right to work and employment, which in human rights documents, particularly in the International Covenant on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights, regarded as the second generation of human rights. Social justice, who has been noted specifically in the first, third and fourth chapters of Constitution of the Islamic Republic of Iran, are the same components that have been identified in international documents of human rights. These indicators will realize when all citizens have equal opportunity to take advantage of it. The government's obligation to support these rights is positive, and an obligation to urgent results and in some indicators the obligation of result, is increasing.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>citizens</keyword>
	<keyword> justice</keyword>
	<keyword> social justice</keyword>
	<keyword> human rights</keyword>
	<keyword> constitutional law</keyword>
	<keyword> constitution </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>225</first_page>
								  <last_page>238</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1461-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1462</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Comparison of parametric and fuzzy analytic hierarchy process in land evaluation (Case study: Varamin region)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			In last decades, the skillful planning of land resources has become a major issue for rural development. The development of cultivated areas becomes gradually impossible due to ever increasing population growth and urban development. Fuzzy logic is preferred to Boolean logic for land evaluation, because fuzzy techniques lead to estimate for land use suitability on a continuous scale and can therefore, be more informative than the Boolean technique. The objective of this study is to apply fuzzy set methodology in the context of a decision making process known as the Analytic Hierarchy Process (AHP) to land evaluation for irrigated wheat. The results revealed that the results obtained with fuzzy AHP method are in better agreement (R2=0.911) with the observed yield as compared to those obtained with parametric method (R2=0.804). Although, the fuzzy AHP provided more efficient and accurate results than parametric method, the choice of membership functions, width of the transition zones and weight values are determinant to achieve its realistic results in land suitability assessment.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Multi-criteria decision making</keyword>
	<keyword> Fuzzy set theory</keyword>
	<keyword> Land suitability evaluation</keyword>
	<keyword> parametric method </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>239</first_page>
								  <last_page>248</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1462-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1463</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>The effectiveness of three-dimensional urban advertising from the perspective of iconology</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			In today's communities achieving to effectiveness of urban advertising is one of troubles of advertisement industry. This research is trying to answer this question that using three-dimensional design in urban advertising has what place in urban field? This query has been conducted in the method of iconological analysis on chosen urban advertising works of last 15 years in the world with the goal of achieve to volume effect on effectiveness of public advertisement. Results show that reason of effectiveness of chosen urban advertising (billboard) of last 15 years in the world (2000-2015) is -due to public audience of commercial advertisement and services- using volume display in the amount of 86.7% which among this number 83.3% of them have interacted with around environment space.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>creativity- three-dimensional design- urban advertising- effectiveness of advertisement </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>249</first_page>
								  <last_page>258</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1463-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1464</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>A Study on Organizational Factors Contributing to Reduce Work-related Accidents in Zamyad Co., an Iranian Commercial Vehicle Manufacturing Company</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			One of the increasingly important organizational considerations involves occupational health and staff safety. Hence, it is crucial for the managers to identify the key organizational factors contributing to reduce work-related accidents. This study was conducted on 340 workers, employees, experts, supervisors, directors, and managers. The data evaluation involved a questionnaire while the analysis involved SPSS. Additionally, the Kolmogorov-Smirnov test, Pearson correlation, and Kruskal-Wallis test were employed. With regard to the main criteria, the HR training procedure had the highest effect while the HR hiring procedure had the lowest effect on work-related accidents. Considering that HR training procedure has the greatest effect on reducing work-related accidents, it is critical to continuously optimize the training courses; There by to curb the major work-related accidents.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>organizational factors</keyword>
	<keyword> work-related accidents</keyword>
	<keyword> Zamyad Co.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>259</first_page>
								  <last_page>268</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1464-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1465</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>  Model to evaluate faculty competence in higher education of educational city    </title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Today country success in economic, social, political , cultural and tendencies are the hostages and pawns of coherent and dynamic didactic system and approved; The education and didactic programs for qualification improvement and dynamism need to evaluate and scrutiny quantitatively and qualitatively. Current study started with the goal of presenting faculty competency evaluation for the reason of qualitative improvement of Islamic Azad University. Research in term of how to collect and compilation the data is descriptive- survey and in term of goal and target type is practical that by doing general scrutiny in literature and subject history and past, we drawled the theoretical frame and conceptual model in this study. Nominee educational members opinions (faculty members (self- assessment), supervisors (superiors), students (clients) of Fars stat Islamic Azad different universities, are the research society. In this research with researcher evaluation in 24 active units in Fars state, approximately 125000 persons examined. That sample volume selected by the clustered random sampling method (kerjesi and Morgan formula), 380 persons, for the reason of collecting dates we used a researcher questionnaire that its validity confirmed by the specialists and its stability calculated by using the Kronbakh&amp;rsquo;s Alfa method 0.84.Researche questionnaire includes effective component in competency in five general axis, collects the data. Then with using 360 degree evaluation method, executed. For the data analysis me used descriptive statistic method and elicitation statistic (fact oral analysis, vilkakson and Friedman) that the results of the study as follows: 1.drawing the model of competency evaluation of faculty (main dimension of evaluation indexes of faculty competency&amp;rsquo;s).2.in the field of evaluation of current situation from the dimensions and competence skill parameters, ethical values, role, personal, favorable status exists. But in the performance and functional dimension and its subcomponents unfavorable status and lower than average level evaluated and the results of ranking of evaluation of dimensions of competency&amp;rsquo;s of faculty in order the most priority is related to skill dimension and the least priority is related functional and performance dimension.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>competency</keyword>
	<keyword> faculty</keyword>
	<keyword> evaluation</keyword>
	<keyword> educational city    </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>269</first_page>
								  <last_page>282</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1465-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1466</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>A comparative study of Factors influencing moral actions in Iran and Blasi’s viewpoint</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			One of the significant dimensions of human&amp;rsquo;s social growth is his moral development. The human being not only is a rational and intellectual being, but also is a moral being. His morality has its origin in his sociability. The human being not only is self-centered and concerned about his own interests and well-being, but also is concerned about others&amp;rsquo; interests and their judgment of his actions and behavior. In addition, emotional perception of moral and ethics is also concerned about the importance of emotion in a moral approach; therefore, when we, as human beings, draw a line between emotion and intellect, and consider them as totally unrelated, we are actually heading in the wrong path. The results of this study revealed that the main categories of moral action consist of: knowledge management, decision making, individual&amp;rsquo;s will, coherency of moral perception. In addition, the main theme which was derived is culture. The culture theme was the most important theme derived from this study. This study tried to investigate Blasi&amp;rsquo;s moral action theory in the context of Iran.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>moral actions</keyword>
	<keyword> Blasi’s viewpoint</keyword>
	<keyword> significant dimensions</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>283</first_page>
								  <last_page>290</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1466-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1467</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>The principles of traditional designing dominant on carpet and tile designing and Islamic architecture</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The feature of decorating curves in Iranian arts, paintings, illumination, cover decorating, Engraving Carving Sudoriferous Cloth carpet and several decorations related to architecture including tile, stucco have principles and features of traditional designing. Several types of figures of Khatayi and Ieslimi and their roles in combination and space besides having principles in proportion to ground have certain features. This article has been formulated by the aim of reading Khatayi and eslimi figures in both carpet and tile arts and its main issue is how to draw these figures and their system of combination in both of these arts. The methodology is descriptive. The statistical population includes architectural works of several Islamic periods and carpet works in contemporary period. All the designs presented in this article are drawn by the author and it has been attempted to be able to explain features of traditional design system exactly.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>traditional design</keyword>
	<keyword> tile</keyword>
	<keyword> Khatayi and Ieslimi figures</keyword>
	<keyword> Islamic Architecture</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>291</first_page>
								  <last_page>304</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1467-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1468</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Effects of Willful Misconduct and Equivalent Fault (or Gross Negligence) of Carrier and its Servants in International Transport Conventions: CMR, CVR, CIM, CIV</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Although liability under general tort and contract law principles is not limited to a certain amount, liability arising under a carriage contract is limited by the majority of international transport conventions and national legislatures and, there are certain reasons given to justify the &amp;ldquo;essential departure from the current rules of civil law&amp;rdquo; and it is common for the liability of the carrier to be limited under the international regimes regarding transportation. The limitation of liability, which is nowadays considered to be a basic right rather than a privilege, is not a matter of justice, but merely a matter of public policy. Naturally, under modern transport law regimes, willful misconduct is not the only situation whereby the carrier or ship-owner loses his right to limit. Conventions regarding means of transportation, particularly road carriage, also employ provisions for breaking the limits. The aim of this paper is to investigate the effects of willful misconduct and gross negligence of road carrier in CMR, CVR, and COTIF 1999 (CIM and CIV) conventions and for this purpose admitted solutions in said convention is discussed.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>limitation of liability</keyword>
	<keyword> carrier</keyword>
	<keyword> willful misconduct</keyword>
	<keyword> gross negligence</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>305</first_page>
								  <last_page>318</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1468-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1469</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>A study of the relationship between the exploitation and subsidence of Salmas </title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Salmas plain is located at the west of Uremia lake and at the 75 km of north of Uremia city. The main river of the plain, called Zulachai, is drained into Uremia Lake. Salmas aquifer is one of the coastal aquifers of Uremia Lake and has hydraulic connection with the lake. The recent draught occurrences and increased water consumption in agriculture and drinking sections water have not only caused regression of lake water, but also effected on coastal aquifer, such as Salmas plain aquifer. Over the long-term, average groundwater level in the Salmas aquifer has dropped sharply to 18/05 meters (averaging about 0/44 meters per year) and there has been 241 million cubic meters of reservoir capacity reduction. Salmas plain has two confined and unconfined Aquifers. Salmas annual depletion of groundwater resources in the study area during the water years of 2014-15 has been equal to 146 million cubic meters. The effects of land subsidence have been observed in some output areas (Kalshan and Qareh Qeshlaq areas).

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Salmas</keyword>
	<keyword> water substrate subsidence</keyword>
	<keyword> water storage deficit</keyword>
	<keyword> the groundwater hydrograph</keyword>
	<keyword> ground subsidence</keyword>
	<keyword> coastal aquifer.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>319</first_page>
								  <last_page>326</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1469-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1470</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Emanation of Chivalry ethics in Iranian Islamic Architectures </title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Chivalry mores and etiquettes have never been limited to a specific time, place, or tradition, but the topic of discussion in this research holds some symbols of Chivalry mores in Iranian architecture in Islamic period. Chivalry principles, in Islamic period, are based on the pure nature of manliness and its origin and orientation goes back to Imams and prophets. By obeying and adherence to these principles, which have been called as Chivalry principles, people were categorized as the Chivalry. These mores have also been common in other countries such as Iraq, Anatoly, and todays&amp;rsquo; Syria. In early Islamic period, Chivalry mores was only peculiar to some specific people, but as the time passed guilds also founded some rules based on Chivalry, which must have been obeyed by volunteers willing to join that guild. The place and footprint of mores and etiquettes of chivalrous people in Islamic architecture works were studied in this research. To do this, Chivalry appearances in the architecture of Islamic period buildings investigated. Relying on the comparative and analytical reasoning between the moral principles of the Chivalry and the Islamic architectural works, some results were gained. Some of them are the existence of internal spaces, taken from the idea of confidentiality of the Chivalry and leaving the doors shorter in Islamic architecture of some structures like Zurkhaneh (gymnasium), to illustrate the humility and modesty while entering into such places. 

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>chivalrous</keyword>
	<keyword> Islamic architecture</keyword>
	<keyword> moral principles</keyword>
	<keyword> Chivalry mores</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>327</first_page>
								  <last_page>336</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1470-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1472</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Surveying the Impact of New Information Technologies on Improving Customer Relation Management considering Organizational Innovation as intervening variable (Case study: Bank Mellat of West Azerbaijan)</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The aim of the present study is to Surveying the Impact of New Information Technologies on Improving Customer Relation Management considering Organizational Innovation as intervening variable (Case study: Bank Mellat of West Azerbaijan). The study is applied and descriptive in nature. All of the employee in Bank Mellat of West Azerbaijan branches were candidiate to participate in the study but using Cochran formula and stratified random sampling method, the sample size was determined as 236. To collect the data standard questionnaire were used. Using Cronbach alpha coefficient, the reliability was calculated as 0.902 which shows the good reliability. For statistical analysis purpose, SPSS and Smart Pls softwares were used. The results indicated that New Information Technologies Effected on Improving Customer Relation Management considering Organizational Innovation as intervening variable.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>New Information Technologies</keyword>
	<keyword> Customer Relation Management</keyword>
	<keyword> Organizational Innovation.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>337</first_page>
								  <last_page>346</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1472-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1473</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Explanation and presentation of professional ethics criteria and indicators for the promotion of Social Accountability within Iranian’s government organizations using structural equation modeling</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Concurrently, organizations must respond effectively to social expectations and moral law and to achieve success in all areas and by respecting professional ethics adopt an appropriate procedure to achieve these expectations align with organizational goals to facilitates promotion of social accountability and realization of higher goals. In this study, we have formulated a framework by reviewing the literature and related researches so that with application of quality and quantitative combinatory approch as well as utilization of Delphi and judgmental sampling and chain and professional acceptance of scientific and organizational model (32 members), a comporehensive model was instituted in the form of a standard model (individual, organizational and cross- organizational) and 23 indicators of professional ethics to promote social accountability. Then, realized model structures in the studied organizations has been tested through structural equation modeling (confirmatory factor analysis) using smart PLS software. Meanwhile, Cronbach's alpha (0.965) is used to measure questionnaire&amp;rsquo;s reliability in addition to evaluation of validity. Moreover, among national executive accountability, 124 members are selected for this study through Morgan table and stratified random sampling method so that the situation of each dimensions such as individual (3.56), organizational (3.50) and cross-organizational (3:06) were obtained unfavorably. Overall, this study defines a new method to analyze and measurements of enhance public accountability and professional ethics under Iranian&amp;rsquo;s government agencies.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Ethical Accountability</keyword>
	<keyword> Social Accountability</keyword>
	<keyword> Individual Ethical Accountability</keyword>
	<keyword> Organizational professional Ethics Ethical Accountability</keyword>
	<keyword> Environmental professional ethics Ethical Accountability. </keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>347</first_page>
								  <last_page>358</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1473-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1474</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>Investigating the Influence of Emotional-Social Competencies on the Mental Health of the Staff; Case study: Iran’s Dairy Industry</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="2">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="3">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
					
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="4">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			Background and purpose: Managers&amp;rsquo; competencies leave a decisive effect on the mental health of staff. The present research intends to investigate the influence of emotional-social competencies on the mental health of the staff. Method: the current research is practical in its purpose and correlative regarding data gathering. The statistical community included all the staff of Pegah Company in District 3, which were 221 persons selected through simple random sampling. The assessment tools of this study were standard Boyatzis questionnaire for emotional-social competencies of managers from the staff&amp;rsquo;s point of view and Goldberg general health questionnaire for the mental health of the staff. The validity (content, convergent, divergent) and reliability (load factor, composite reliability, and Cronbach&amp;rsquo;s alpha coefficient) were employed which indicated that assessment tools have acceptable validity and reliability; and the gathered data were analyzed by SMART-PLS2 and descriptive statistics with SPSS21. Findings: the outcomes of this study indicate that t coefficient ranges between emotional-social competency, emotional competency and social competency with the mental health which were respectively 7.46, 5.21, and 10.46. Also, the values of R2 coefficient of determination were 0.71, 0.67, and 0.54 respectively which are desired results. It shows that emotional-social competency, emotional competency and social competency leave positive and significant impacts on mental health. Conclusion: the results of this study attests to the importance of managers&amp;rsquo; emotional-social competency for mental health of staff. Thus, the organizations should employ some strategies for the managers to acquire emotional-social competencies and accordingly improve mental health of staff and attain organizational goals.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>emotional-social competency</keyword>
	<keyword> emotional competency</keyword>
	<keyword> social competency</keyword>
	<keyword> mental health</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>359</first_page>
								  <last_page>365</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1474-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
				
			
				<record>
					<header>
						<identifier>28-1475</identifier>
						<datestamp>2020-07-22</datestamp>
						<setSpec>10.1002</setSpec>
					</header>
					<metadata>
						<cr_unixml:crossref xmlns="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0"
							xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.crossref.org/xschema/1.0 http://www.crossref.org/schema/unixref1.0.xsd">
							<journal>
								<journal_metadata language="en">
									<full_title>Intenational Journal of Urban and Rural Management</full_title>
									<abbrev_title>مديريت</abbrev_title>
									<issn media_type="print">1607-2227</issn>
									<issn media_type="electronic"></issn>
									<doi_data>
										<doi>7</doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_metadata>
								<journal_issue>
									<publication_date media_type="print">
										<year>2017</year>
									</publication_date>
									<journal_volume>
										<volume>15</volume>
									</journal_volume>
									<issue>45</issue>
									<doi_data>
										<doi></doi>
										<resource></resource>
									</doi_data>
								</journal_issue>
								<journal_article publication_type="full_text">
									<titles>
										<title>An Analytical Study of the Evolution of Qajar Palaces</title>
									</titles>

				<contributors>
				
				<person_name contributor_role="author" sequence="1">
					<given_name></given_name>
					<surname></surname>
					<email></email>
				</person_name>
				
				</contributors>
			
			<abstract>
			The political and social system involved in the limbo between tradition and modernity of the Qajar Era caused widespread and quick developments in Iranian culture, art, and architecture as well as a challenge between tradition and modernity. Relatively numerous palaces built in this era were signs of greatness and distinction-seeking of the Qajar kings and aristocrats, who embraced all transformations of architecture in their era and played a significant role in changing Iranian architectural values. Therefore the purpose of the present study is to investigate developments in architecture of the Qajar Era and their effects on the evolution of palaces in this era. Using case studies methodology and referring to historical sources, contemporary studies on Qajar architecture and field studies conducted on outstanding palaces of this era, it can be concluded that the continuation of Safavid architecture early in this period, Qajar kings' tendency to Iranian ancient architecture, and the culmination of the architectural influence of the West in the Nasserid Era were the main factors effective on the formation of Qajar palaces. Moreover, the evolution of these buildings has occurred in three pre, early and late Nasserid Eras with various traditional, eclectic and European characteristics regarding the construction period and the effects of the above factors on the evolution of plans and circulation systems, facades and sections, materials, decorations, and architectural elements. In addition to shedding more light on common features of architecture and decoration of Qajar palaces, the study tried to determine their general and specific differences.

			</abstract>
				<keywords>
	<keyword>Qajar palaces</keyword>
	<keyword> evolution</keyword>
	<keyword> tradition and modernity</keyword>
	<keyword> Iranian architecture</keyword>
	<keyword> European architecture.</keyword>
	</keywords>

							  <publication_date media_type="print">
								  <year>2017</year>
								  <month>3</month>
								  <day>01</day>
							  </publication_date>
							  <pages>
								  <first_page>366</first_page>
								  <last_page>389</last_page>
							  </pages>
								  <fullTextUrl>http://ijurm.imo.org.ir/article-1-1475-en.pdf</fullTextUrl>
							  <doi_data>
								  <doi></doi>
								  <resource></resource>
							  </doi_data>
							  <citation_list>
							  </citation_list>
						  </journal_article>
					  </journal>
				  </cr_unixml:crossref>
			  </metadata>
			</record>
			
		</ListRecords>
		</OAI-PMH>
		 
  
  
  
  
 