<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Microfoundations of Dynamic Capabilities in Service Innovation of Manufacturing Firms (Studied Case: SAIPA Automotive Company)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mahdavi Mazdeh, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Jafari, Mostafa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Kahrizi, Abdolmadjid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hosseini Khamseh Motlagh, Atefeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Servitization]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Service Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dynamic Capabilities]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Microfoundations]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Manufacturing Firm]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Along the change of world economic vision to service-based economy, service innovation is considered as a significant factor in achieving and maintaining firm’s competitive advantage. In this situation, manufacturing firms are also required to adopt a strategy to develop services to their portfolio and consider service innovation (in addition to product innovation). The main challenge of manufacturing firms involved in shifting from "product orientation" to "product and service orientation", is management of dynamic capabilities for creating service innovation. Dynamic capabilities facilitate the transformation and renewal of firms’ current processes and enable all types of innovation to create a better fit with the environment. The purpose of this study is to identify microfoundations of dynamic capabilities in service innovation and explanation the interactions between these microfoundations in an Iranian manufacturing firm (SAIPA Automotive Company). Therefore, 14 microfoundations were identified in three dynamic capability categories through deep literature reviewing. Then, the opinion of the academic and executive experts was collected using a questionnaire about the necessity and importance of each microfoundations in service innovation. Based on the opinion of the executives, the intensity and interconnectivity between these microfoundations in the context of SAIPA Automotive Company as a manufacturing firm were studied through FUZZY DEMATEL technique.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_102630_ac05a50226cf5448db5470bdc0867d16.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Presenting Conceptual Framework for Formation of University-based Entrepreneurial Ecosystem in Tehran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohaghar, َAli]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohammadi, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mokhtarzadeh, Nima]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[shahidipour, Roohollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[University-based Entrepreneurial Ecosystems]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Conceptual Framework]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[life cycle]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Thematic Analysis]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[comparative analysis]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Thematic Network]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Delphi]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This paper presents a Conceptual Framework for formation of university-based Entrepreneurial Ecosystems in Tehran and its indicators using a qualitative method. The conceptual Framework of the research includes a 3×4 matrix whose rows show the position of the ecosystem in life cycle (i.e. the 4 stages of emergence, Activation, Integration andMaturity) and the columns indicate the ecosystem formation model (i.e. the 3 states of organic and community-oriented, systematic and university-based, and a combination of both). Further in the qualitative section, the suggested indicators of the conceptual Framework were determined through thematic analysis and thematic network.In the quantitative section, the conceptual Framework and its dimensions were verified using the Delphi method. The following Four life cycle indicators were then identified: the level of development of entrepreneurship infrastructures, strength of the communication network between ecosystem actors, Culcural &amp; Manegerial Infrastructures and the resources available in the ecosystem.The following six indicators were also identified for the ecosystem formation: the extent of Student and Alumni intervention, andNon Academic Factors.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_102632_b472787dcce9278c425444c11ffc372a.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Impact of entrepreneurship on inequality of income distribution
  (Between provinces of the country)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[najafi, zahra]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[sameti, majid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[jamali, somayeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Entrepreneurship]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Income distribution inequality]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[panel- Data]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Over the recent years, the importance of entrepreneurship has contributed to the advancement of countries' economic growth and development and the elimination of income distribution inequalities. So that entrepreneurs have played a central role in developing economies in developed countries. While this importance has been neglected in developing countries. Therefore, considering the importance of the role of entrepreneurship, this study examines the relationship between entrepreneurship and income inequality in Iranian provinces during the years 1395-1959. The results confirm the reverse U-relationship between these two variables, and the results also showed that most of the countries surveyed are in the downward curve, that is, with increasing levels of entrepreneurship, income distribution inequality is reduced. Other variables affecting inequality of income distribution, urbanization rate and population density have positive and negative effects on inequality, respectively.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_102633_042a8ba670dafd3feae4566a43b3dee3.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Diagnosis of Science and Technology Budget in Iran Using Meta-synthesis Method]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Behrooz, Amirhesam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Pourezzat, Ali Asghar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Dezhpasand, farhad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Amiri, Mojtaba]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Budgeting]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Meta-Synthesis]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Science and Technology budget]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[research budget]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[financing of Research and technology]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The present paper is a meta-synthesis study on the research and technology budget areas in Iran with the aim of comprehensive and holistic diagnosis. The statistic of the present paper consists of 96 documents, including research papers, review papers, reports and research projects which have been published in Persian during the years 2002-2019. In this study, Sandlowski and Barroso's seven-step method was used, and after screening by helping the COREQ 32-item index, 69 documents were identified as high-quality and medium-quality research for deeper analysis, and they have been reviewed in the two sections of descriptive and qualitative. The themes were analyzed and extracted from the articles and final findings using the theme analysis method. The results showed that the barriers to implementation of research and technology budgeting consisted of 139 main factors and obstacles in 19 components (sub themes) in 5 dimensions (Main theme) includes science and technology policy making, budget planning, budget approval, budget execution and budget monitoring.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_102634_3ff094bd73e286bc919c13c1ceb1567b.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Identifying the waves of military innovation in the Islamic Republic of Iran based on the ideas of the Supreme Leader]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Noruzi, khalil]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[zahedi khozani, karim]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[alavian, mojtaba]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation Industries]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Military Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Defense Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Iran's supreme leader]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The need for military innovation for defense industries in countries is increasingly felt today. Military innovation as a nascent field has special theoretical foundations. This study examines the foundations, goals, and requirements of realizing military innovation based on the ideas of the Supreme Leader Supreme Leader. The third wave refers to the institutional innovations that led to the establishment of revolutionary institutions in defense and military. The fourth wave is devoted to outlining their expectations of excellence in military and defense sciences during the current revolution. The Fifth Wave, one of the findings of the great think-tank's research process, is called Fundamental Knowledge Innovation, which addresses the concept of the fundamental sciences that can launch a new design in the military. Since then, the system of explicit expectations has been extracted from military organizations, military and defense commanders and commanders, and ultimately documented scholars in their field.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_102635_408685297503e0e09162251e3a52c3fd.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Effect of Innovation on Market Share of Selected Countries from Non-Oil Exports of the World]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khoshtinat, Behnaz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shahabadi, Abolfazl]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shojaei Shad, Mostafa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Moradi, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2020]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Non-Oil Exports]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Global Innovation Index]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation Input]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation output]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The development of non-oil exports can regulate the employment situation and help to the provide of necessary foreign exchange resources for imports. It can also increase the resilience of the economy by cutting off dependence on foreign exchange earnings from oil exports. But to achieve this, in today's competitive world, It needs to support creative ideas, build new products and services, based on the needs and preferences of foreign customers using their new tools and methods of production and commercialization, referred to as innovation. Therefore, the present study attempted to examine the effect of inputs and outputs of innovation on the market share of two oil exporting selected countries (sample group) and Innovation -Driven Stage selected countries (control group) from non-oil global exports during the period 2007-2017. For this purpose, the research model was estimated using panel data and generalized method of moments in two groups of countries. The results showed that the effect of inputs and outputs of innovation on the market share of both groups of selected countries from non-oil world exports was positive and significant. Of course, the estimated coefficient of these variables is higher in oil-exporting countries.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_107464_4b374f20911555144726618e5f836dce.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>