<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Identification and Prioritization of Motivational Factors Affecting Knowledge-sharing in an Industrial-Research Organization</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و رتبه بندی عوامل انگیزشی موثر بر اشتراک دانش در یک سازمان پژوهشی-صنعتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>107</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>135</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14605</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پیمان</FirstName>
					<LastName>اخوان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اکبر</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحیمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه ازاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In today&#039;s competitive environment, gaining competitive advantage is one of the most fundamental challenges for managers. Nowadays, &quot;human resources&quot; are among the most important resources for creating competitive advantages, and those employees viewed as sources of knowledge will gain more value in organization. The importance and value the knowledge workers receive in an organization lead to a strategy known as knowledge preservation. Researchers have found that what leads to the creation of competitive advantage is employees&#039; knowledge and the process of sharing it. Managers try to promote knowledge-sharing, while employees tend to keep their knowledge secret. This paradox leads to different approaches taken by human resources and managers in hoarding or sharing knowledge. The solution proposed in this paper for aligning these two different approaches is using factors that cause human resources to share their knowledge with others voluntarily. In this study, motivations are introduced as factors that lead to human resources knowledge-sharing on a voluntary basis. After reviewing the literature and theories of motivation, and by using the questionnaire survey method, effective motivational factors in knowledge-sharing are identified in an industrial-research organization in Tehran, then ranked by Friedman method. The results show that in knowledge-sharing, intrinsic motivational factors have higher priorities than extrinsic ones. The results also demonstrate that &quot;friendly and sincere relations&quot; and &quot;job promotion&quot; are the most important intrinsic and extrinsic motivational factors affecting knowledge-sharing.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در محیط رقابتی دنیای امروز، کسب مزیت رقابتی یکی از چالش های اساسی مدیران است. منابع انسانی به عنوان یکی از مهم ترین منابع جهت ایجاد مزیت رقابتی شناخته می شود و کارکنانی که از منبع دانش بهره لازم را برده باشند دارای ارزش بیشتری در سازمان هستند. اهمیت بیشتر سازمان به دانشکاران، موجب به کارگیری راهبرد حفظ دانش توسط آنها می شود. محققان دریافته اند که آنچه به ایجاد مزیت رقابتی منجر می شود، دانش کارکنان و به اشتراک گذاری آن با دیگران است. تلاش مدیران جهت اشتراک دانش کارکنان از یک سو و به کارگیری راهبرد حفظ دانش توسط کارکنان از سوی دیگر، باعث ایجاد دو رویکرد متفاوت بین منابع انسانی سازمان و مدیران در احتکار یا اشتراک دانش شده است. راه حل پیشنهادی این مقاله برای همسوسازی این دو رویکرد متفاوت، به کارگیری عواملی است که موجب شود منابع انسانی به صورت داوطلبانه دانش خود را در اختیار دیگران قرار دهند. در این تحقیق انگیزه ها به عنوان عواملی معرفی می گردند که باعث می شوند منابع انسانی از روی تمایل دانش خود را در اختیار دیگران قراردهند. پس از بررسی تحقیقات پیشین و نظریه های مختلف انگیزشی، با استفاده از پرسشنامه و به شیوه پیمایشی، عوامل انگیزشی موثر بر اشتراک دانش در یک سازمان پژوهشی-صنعتی در شهر تهران شناسایی شده و با استفاده از آزمون فریدمن رتبه بندی گردیدند. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد که برای اشتراک دانش، عوامل انگیزشی درونی نسبت به عوامل انگیزشی بیرونی از اولویت بالاتری نزد کارکنان برخوردار بوده و عوامل انگیزشی &quot;ارتباط دوستانه و صمیمی&quot; و &quot;ترفیع شغلی&quot; به ترتیب به عنوان مهم ترین عوامل انگیزشی درونی و بیرونی موثر بر اشتراک دانش شناخته شدند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتراک دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل انگیزشی درونی موثر بر اشتراک دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل انگیزشی بیرونی موثر بر اشتراک دانش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14605_b3484e8c527c72f8bea134ce217afb35.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
