<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Factors affecting of the growth of agricultural startups]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Yousefi, Zahra]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[naderi, nader]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[rezaei, bijan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[key words: startup]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[growth]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[technology]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In this study, researcher were looking for Factors affecting of the growth of agricultural startups that conducted as a qualitative and Grounded theory. Participants were 15 executives of agricultural startups in 1395 that Their companies were in the growth stage or growth. And were engaged supported by the Science and Technology Park and through interviews with 11 of them reached theoretical saturation. In order to collect data, in-depth interviews with open-ended questions that the main research question were: “What the barriers were for growth their agricultural start-up,s?” and data analysis was performed based on Seven analytical methods grounded theory and Finally, another interview was conducted to check the validity of research results. The research findings in the form of 5 major themes and 5 sub themes which the main themes are: The low share of government funds for agricultural based idea activities, Weakness notification system in introducing based idea products to farmers, Uncertainty in the market agricultural based ideas products, The consequences of the long process of obtaining the necessary permits, Attention of farmers to impact of new start-up product or service on the personal interests and not the public aspects of it.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_46949_3a9881b59478e7417e0e0bfa9725c094.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Meta-synthesis of success factors for commercialize of products with advanced technology]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hajipour, Bahman]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Motameni, Alireza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tayebi Abolhasani, Amirhossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Commercialization]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[technology]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Success]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Meta-Synthesis]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[One of the main reasons for the rapid development of technology in developed countries is attention to commercialization process of research and technological ideas that countries. Aim of this research according to important role of commercialization in the advancement of Industrial and economic any society, is quality combining in the area of commercialization from previous studies have been carried out. For this purpose, with utilize meta-synthesis approach in this study is to analyze the results and findings of other researchers. With comprehensive studies have been done about success factors for commercialize of products with advanced in scientific databases of Internal and foreign, eventually, 118 articles were identified. Results classified on 3 dimensions (individual, organizational and environmental factors), 19 components (individual manager's mind, individual manager's character, manager's inter-personal abilities, general conditions, experience, human resources, financial resources, technical ability, production ability, marketing and sales abilities, ability of absorption and project management, strategic abilities, organizational absorption capacity, competitors, supporting institutions, infrastructure, social factors, legal factors, political, economic and technological factors) and 99 indices.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_46945_696969ee9c576d783010eb363673b747.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Identify gaps and opportunities for Photovoltaic technologies using content analysis of patent documents]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bayanloo, Zohreh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[zare ahmadabadi, habib]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technology Opportunities]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Patent document]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Photovoltaic]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[K-means Clustering]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Identify gaps and opportunities in various fields of technology has special place. The process on issues such as global energy crisis and exist environmental problems, such as global warming , greenhouse gases, air pollution , etc... will be more important. It is felt, the use of renewable energy source such as photovoltaic system as an alternative of fossil fuels due to lower maintenance costs, no need for fuel and no dependence on AC power. Looking specifically to photovoltaic technology as a new technology and its important in recent research , need that could justify future study innovations this technology. In this study all international patent of United state Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) as largest patent database during 1985 to 2016 were identified in the field of photovoltaic. With the use of expert in this field, text mining and clustering analysis of these patents, were identify invertor considered research areas , research gaps and innovational research opportunities. The result of this study will be useful to identify opportunities for investment in research and development in photovoltaic technology.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_46946_0f77c688411c7e250745ca3c493ba2e7.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Nucleus and Network Policy, from Dream to Reality: Analyzing Outward-looking Policies of Defense Industries in Recent Decade]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Booshehri, Alireza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Policy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[nucleus and network]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Defense Industries]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[performance]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In the late 1370s, Iran Defense firms confronted the reality that they cannot answer all their customers’ needs with their then-existing capacities. As a result, policy makers changed the inward-looking policies by adopting a new policy called “nucleus and network”. Now, after more than a decade, the question is whether this policy has been successful in increasing innovation performance and whether factors like history of firms before Islamic revolution has influenced this performance. To answer these questions, orientation toward the nucleus and network policy, openness, absorptive capacity, history of cooperation with foreign firms, size, and innovation performance of 114 defense firms were analyzed using multiple regression Technic. Results showed that history and size had no effect and openness and absorptive capacity had significant positive effect on innovation performance of the firms. Based on these results, combining the nucleus and network policy with policies for strengthening absorptive capacity of firms, a significant change in firms’ performance will be achieved.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_46944_fded88c24021a3e276eac9f02c981945.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Designing and Devising a Suitable Innovation Sample for I.R.I Army According to Supreme Leaders Statements]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ardalan, Omid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[alvani, mahdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[shahlaie, naser]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[creativity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[scientific innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[model innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Iran army]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The aim of this study was derived from a project that was in the army, define and design a suitable model for innovation in the army of the Islamic Republic is based on the supreme leader. This research is based on the purpose and nature of the exploratory study based on applied research achievements.A survey, documents related to the speech of the Leader of the Revolution and the number 106 Commanders and deputies education, research and university faculty members are military officers.109 lectures, the numbers of holiness, through content analysis, 67 items were extracted. Using factor analysis, finally presented in the form of 12. In this study, data collection tools for documents and questionnaires were used The use of library and field required data have been collected.The results show that the appropriate model based on innovation and creativity in the military commands of the supreme leader is a model that contains Individual aspects (scientific power, scientific courage, motivation), organizational aspects (goals and strategies based on science, organizational structure, organizational culture and climate, technology, equipment, systems, human resources, education and research system) And dimensions bureau (Basiji spirit and thinking, knowledge and faith) is.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_46947_525b5268e002746cfc03391ad0cbda65.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Firm Future Readiness: Concept Presentation and Composite Index]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghadiri, amir]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tabatabaeian, Seyed Habibolah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohmmadi, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Zolfagharzadeh, Mohammad Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nazemi, Amir]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Futures Studies]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Company]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Company Future Readiness Composite Indicator]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Factor analysis]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Companies are the motor of growth and development in all countries and they have special importance in all planning and policy making activities. Every decision in almost all companies is based on knowledge and future information of managers and experts inside the company who often makes their decisions based on looking to the future. Today, in an increasingly changing world, there are more necessary to focus on the future and identify future events and occurrences and managers and experts in a company should, having a good knowledge on these changes, increase their readiness for encountering to them and avoid from “strategic surprises”. In this research, tried to introduce a new concept in the field of futures studies i.e. “Company Future Readiness” in a composite indicator, so that companies using that can evaluate and promote their future readiness in encountering to future and its changes. For this, methodology of developing composite indicators was used and basic conceptual framework was developed based on literature review. Then by a survey on large knowledge based companies, data was gathered so that the basic framework was analyzed by using factor analysis method. By doing this research, a company future readiness composite indicator was developed which consists of 17 variables and 120 questions.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_46948_98497ba2b669a2e8e807a2d4e24a01ac.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>