<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Corporate Governance on the Innovative Efforts of Companies in the Tehran Stock Exchange</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تاثیر حاکمیت شرکتی بر تلاشهای نوآورانه شرکت‌های فعال در بازار بورس و اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>99</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>126</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">96996</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>الیاسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرزایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت تکنولوژی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید یحیی</FirstName>
					<LastName>حساس یگانه</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید سروش</FirstName>
					<LastName>قاضی نوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>After corporate financial scandals such as Enron, Vantel and ... corporate governance matters, and attracted the attention of the researchers. In this study, the relationship between corporate governance and innovation Efforts in the companies active in the Tehran Stock Exchange (304 companies) has been investigated. This paper attempts to identify the dimensions and indicators of corporate governance, and then the most important factors affecting enterprise innovation are extracted, and indicators such as reliance on disclosed reports and the timeliness of reported disclosures, in other Studies have not been observed. The audited financial statements from 1391 to 1396 analyzed using the data panel method. The results show that the board of directors&#039; education, choice of CEO from within or outside the company and the premium of the board of directors have a positive and significant effect on firm innovation, but the amount of payment for the right of the board of directors, the ability to rely on disclosed reports and the number of years of activity of the firm has a negative effect on the firm&#039;s innovation. CEO&#039;s education, the outsider board of directors, the ownership concentration and the timeliness of the disclosures by the company have no significant effect on the firm&#039;s innovation</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA"> پس از رسوایی‌های مالی شرکت‌هایی مانند انرون، وان‌تل و ... موضوع حاکمیت شرکتی اهمیت یافت و نظر محققان را به خود جلب نمود. یکی از موضوعات مطالعاتی در زمینه حاکمیت شرکتی، تأثیر آن بر نوآوری بنگاه می‌باشد. در این مطالعه ارتباط حاکمیت شرکتی و تلاش‌های نوآوری در 304 شرکت‌ فعال در بازار بورس تهران بررسی شده است. در این نوشته سعی شده است ابعاد و شاخص‌های کلان حاکمیت شرکتی شناسایی و سپس مهم‌ترین عوامل تأثیرگذار بر نوآوری بنگاه استخراج شود و شاخص‌هایی مانند قابلیت اتکای در گزارشات افشاشده و به‌موقع بودن گزارشات افشاشده، در سایر مطالعات مشاهده نشده است. صورت‌های مالی حسابرسی شده مربوط به ساله‌ای 1391 تا 1395 بوده و با استفاده از روش پنل دیتا تجزیه‌وتحلیل گردیده است. نتایج برآورد مدل نشان می‌دهد که تحصیلات هیئت‌مدیره، انتخاب مدیرعامل از داخل یا خارج شرکت و پرداخت پاداش هیئت‌مدیره اثر مثبت و معنادار، اما میزان پرداختی بابت حق حضور هیئت‌مدیره، قابلیت اتکای گزارش‌های افشاشده و تعداد سنوات فعالیت بنگاه اثر منفی بر میزان نوآوری بنگاه دارد. تحصیلات مدیرعامل، غیرموظف بودن اعضای هیئت‌مدیره، تمرکز مالکیت و به‌موقع بودن گزارش‌های افشاشده توسط شرکت اثر معناداری بر نوآوری بنگاه ندارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حاکمیت شرکتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تلاش های نوآورانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_96996_b5bec6e77887c04207d924150fd5a24e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
