<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2023</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Impacts of Work Engagement on Innovative Behavior with an Emphasis on the Mediatory Role of Sharing Mistakes</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر تعلق خاطر کاری بر رفتار نوآورانه با نقش میانجی به اشتراک گذاری خطاها</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>29</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>52</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">33015</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>جهانگیر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت رفتاری، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>خوراکیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>لگزیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today, organizations need innovations in order to grow and survive. Organizations that cannot deliver innovative products and services to market continually are doomed to fail. But the key of innovation is in the innovative behavior of employees. Various factors affect the innovative behavior of employees. The work engagement of employees is one of the factors which can affect this behavior. Despite this fact, the way it affects is one of the major issues in IT community. The aim of this study is to investigate the mediatory role of sharing mistakes in the way work engagement affect innovative behavior of IT experts. The statistical population of this study includes IT experts in IT companies, who are members of the Computer Union Organization of Khorasan Razavi province, Iran. In this study, stratified sampling is employed. In order to evaluate the research variables, a questionnaire is used with 26 questions. The questionnaire is distributed among 120 IT experts in Mashhad, Khorasan Razavi province. To analyze the data, structural equation modeling is used. The results of the study show that work engagement has a positive impact on sharing mistakes and idea generation. In addition, sharing mistakes mediates the impact of work engagement on generating and promoting ideas.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر به بررسی نقش میانجی به‌اشتراک‌گذاری خطاها در تأثیر تعلق‌خاطر کاری بر رفتار نوآورانة کارشناسان فناوری اطلاعات می‌پردازد. امروزه، سازمان‌ها برای رشد و حتی بقا به نوآوری‌ نیاز دارند. سازمانی که نتواند به‌طور مداوم محصولات و خدمات نوآورانه به بازار عرضه کند، با شکست روبه‌رو می‌شود. از سویی، رفتار نوآورانة کارکنان نیز تحت تأثیر عوامل مختلفی است. تعلق‌خاطر کاری کارکنان یکی از عواملی است که می‌تواند بر این رفتار تأثیر بگذارد. با وجود این، نحوة تأثیرگذاری تعلق‌خاطر کاری کارکنان یکی از بحث‌های مهم در جامعة کارشناسان فناوری اطلاعات است. جامعة آماری این پژوهش، کارشناسان فناوری اطلاعات در شرکت‌های فناوری اطلاعات عضو سازمان نظام صنفی رایانه‌ای خراسان رضوی در شهر مشهد است. در این پژوهش از روش نمونه‌گیری طبقه‌ای و برای سنجش متغیرهای پژوهش از پرسش‌نامه‌ای شامل 26 سؤال، استفاده شد. این پرسش‌نامه، میان 210 نفر از کارشناسان فناوری اطلاعات در شهر مشهد توزیع گردید. برای تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌ها، روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری به‌کار گرفته شد. نتایج، نشان داد تعلق‌خاطر کاری، بر به‌اشتراک‌گذاری خطاها و تولید ایده‌ها تأثیر مثبت و معنی‌دار دارد. همچنین به‌اشتراک‌گذاری خطاها بر تولید و ترویج ایده‌ها تأثیرگذار است. به‌اشتراک‌گذاری خطاها، تأثیر تعلق‌خاطر کاری بر تولید و ترویج ایده‌ها را میانجی‌گری می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">به اشتراک گذاری خطاها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار نوآورانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارشناسان فناوری اطلاعات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعلق خاطر کاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_33015_95c884120aa5f9c6d6a0b777c170b4b8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
