<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Editorial: Structuring a Scientific-Research Paper for Publishing]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tabaian, Seyed Kamal]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Gharakhani, Masoud]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2022]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[highly cited papers]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[structuring scientific-research paper]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In this study, we compare and analyze 10 highly cited papers and 50 papers rejected before entering the review process to indentify pattern of structuring highly cited scientific-research papers. We found empirical evidence that highly cited papers are different from unsuccessful ones not only in content, but also in structure. As good content in necessary for the success of a paper, appropriate structure matters too. Deciding on an appropriate structure is the first and simplest step to writing a good paper. This study aims to help authors understand this important step and pass it.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_34014_5afb07b5ba4690669b8074603c36edc7.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Effect of Companies' Participation or Non-Participation in the Creation of Industrial Clusters on Their Innovation Performance with an Emphasis on the Mediatory Role of Knowledge Management]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Moradi, Morteza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Zandi paak, Rabe]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2023]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[clusters]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Knowledge Management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation Performance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cluster]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Industrial clustering approach is a way to increase cooperation and the use of knowledge and innovation among competing small and medium firms. The aim of this study is to investigate innovation performance of companies having formed industrial clusters in comparison with those not having formed industrial clusters, with an emphasis on the mediating role of knowledge management. The companies selected are rubber parts producers of Hamedan province, Iran. This study is practical in purpose and descriptive-survey of correlational type in methodology and nature. Data gathering tool used in this study is a standard questionnaire based on Likert scale. Its reliability is tested and confirmed by Cronbach's alpha, and its validity by confirmatory factor analysis. The statistical population includes the employees of Rosen rubber parts industrial cluster (430) and the employees of 16 rubber parts producers (287) not having formed industrial clusters. Based on Morgan table, the size of the sample is 205 individuals in the first group of companies and 165 in the second. Structural equations modeling, two-sample test and Levene's test are used for analyzing the findings. The results show that companies having formed clusters are in better positions in terms of innovation performance and knowledge management than those not having formed clusters.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_15341_109753eec13c59deb9708166ca2dd897.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Impacts of Work Engagement on Innovative Behavior with an Emphasis on the Mediatory Role of Sharing Mistakes]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Jahangir, Mostafa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khorakian, Alireza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Lagzian, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2023]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sharing Mistakes]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovative behavior]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[work engagement]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[IT experts]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Today, organizations need innovations in order to grow and survive. Organizations that cannot deliver innovative products and services to market continually are doomed to fail. But the key of innovation is in the innovative behavior of employees. Various factors affect the innovative behavior of employees. The work engagement of employees is one of the factors which can affect this behavior. Despite this fact, the way it affects is one of the major issues in IT community. The aim of this study is to investigate the mediatory role of sharing mistakes in the way work engagement affect innovative behavior of IT experts. The statistical population of this study includes IT experts in IT companies, who are members of the Computer Union Organization of Khorasan Razavi province, Iran. In this study, stratified sampling is employed. In order to evaluate the research variables, a questionnaire is used with 26 questions. The questionnaire is distributed among 120 IT experts in Mashhad, Khorasan Razavi province. To analyze the data, structural equation modeling is used. The results of the study show that work engagement has a positive impact on sharing mistakes and idea generation. In addition, sharing mistakes mediates the impact of work engagement on generating and promoting ideas.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_33015_95c884120aa5f9c6d6a0b777c170b4b8.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Technology Management: The Emergence and Evolution of an Academic Discipline]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Salami, Sayyed Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shojaei, Mohammad Hosain]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tabatabaeian, Sayyed Habibollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bamdad Soofi, Jahanyar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2022]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technology Management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[(Academic) Discipline]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Education]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Research]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Scientific Community]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Body of Knowledge]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Over about four decades, ​​technology management field of study has become an independent (academic) discipline with an impressive growth rate. This rapid growth, alongside the scientific community's desire to evaluate their discipline, has drawn some researcher's attention to study the technology management discipline "itself". This paper aims to examine the evolution of the discipline and to shed light on its unknown or little-known aspect through introducing a framework for the "comprehensive" study of a discipline and systematically reviewing of researches on technology management discipline.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_32913_27871183cdcc794852f93747251bc64d.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Prioritizing the Development and Success Challenges of Biotechnology Spin-Off Companies]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Naghi zadeh, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ojani, Mahdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[AghaZadeh, Sohrab]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[safardoust, Atiyeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghaffarian, Kamyar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2023]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Development and success challenges]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[spin-off companies]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Biotechnology]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[One of the main solutions to commercializing intellectual assets of universities and research centers is developing spin-off firms. The main objective of this paper to identify and prioritize the challenges these firms confront with to be successful. In this study, we use exploratory mixed method. After reviewing the related literature, we conduct eleven interviews with biotechnology commercialization experts, and extract some key challenges by using thematic analysis. In the quantitative section of the study, we prioritize these challenges using confirmatory factor analysis, t-test and Friedman test. Finally, 41 challenges are identified and classified into six dimensions. The most important challenges include: a) lack of information about and precise understanding of market and customer needs; b) lack of supportive pricing mechanisms; and c) cultural gap between research centers and industrial firms.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_33007_0428a44bcb678891571008e524d1ce8a.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Proposing a Framework for Managing Technology Development Projects in Iran's Oil and Gas Industry]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Azizi, Mojtaba]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Moghadam, Adele]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2023]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technology Development Projects]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[project management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Program Management]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[project success]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Iran's oil and gas industry]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Technology development projects, unlike many other kinds of projects, do not have pre-defined goals or clear implementation methods from the outset. Besides common uncertainties any project may face, technology development projects have a high degree of uncertainty in project definition. For this reason, conventional project management methods, such as those provided in the PMBoK, have little use in these projects. This paper describes the characteristics of a technology development project and processes proposed in the literature to manage such projects, studies two technology development projects of Iran's oil and gas industry in-depth, and identifies and analyzes their management challenges. In order to solve the problems found in the field studies, a management model for technology development projects is designed and validated using the strengths of models like the new stage/gate, spiral development model and DoD Extension to the PMBoK. Some features of the proposed model include: considering the iterative management cycles rather than linear management; using program management principals rather than project management; determining flexible time and budget within acceptable limits rather than determining the exact time and cost of the project, etc.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_33419_b2d3e040a4074699e972038c21207f73.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Model for Classification and Study of Success Factors in International Collaborative Networks]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Asadifard, Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Chookhachi Zadeh Moghadam, Amin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Goodarzi, Mahdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2023]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Science & technology (S&T)]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Collaborative networks]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[regional and international network]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Islamic countries]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Success Factors]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Collaborative networking has been considered as a key policy tool in the last decades in the field of science and technology (S&amp;T). Therefore, S&amp;T policymakers and managers needed to know the measures affecting the success and failure of these networks. Four S&amp;T networks of Islamic countries — created under the supervision of Organization of Islamic Cooperation's (OIC) Standing Committee on Scientific and Technological Cooperation (COMSTECH) — are the cases of this study. Using a qualitative survey and multiple case study method, we collect relevant data through in-depth interviews with key informants, observation, and review of archived documents. In this study, 24 success factors of regional/international S&amp;T collaborative networks are identified and categorized by developing a conceptual model. These factors are divided to two main endogenous and exogenous groups. The results reveal that besides the general success factors of all networks, there are some specific factors playing important roles in each network that need to be addressed.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_33420_8264cc7c1a59f973e42fe224f5e68cad.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>