<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Three waves of Transition in Iran&#039;s Defense Industries: With an Emphasis on Anti-Armor Missile</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>موج های سه گانه گذار در صنعت دفاعی ایران با نگاهی خاص به صنعت ضد زره</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>34</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14769</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>وزیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدسپهر</FirstName>
					<LastName>قاضی نوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدمحمدامین</FirstName>
					<LastName>قانعی راد</LastName>
<Affiliation>مرکز تحقیقات سیاست علمی کشور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرتوک زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This paper tries to provide a socio-technical explanation of the formation and transition of Iran&#039;s defense Industries in the past 50 years. The main framework using a combination of technical and social elements to make such explanation is the multi-level perspective (MLP). This framework describes transition through interaction of different landscape, regime and niches levels in socio- technical systems, such as defense industry, but in the developing world transition is the path of formation of these levels. In this paper, Bourdieu&#039;s field theory is applied to understand regime and niche formation. According to Bourdieu&#039;s field theory, we narrate how niche and regime positions are produced as two cores of socio-technical field in Iran defense industries. Focusing on anti-armor industries, we elaborate the three periods of transition in Iran&#039;s defense industries to &quot;Dual Core Field&quot; by means of Bourdieu&#039;s triple levels of inquiry. In each of these periods — named as &quot;the waves&quot; —defense field and its habitus has certain conditions. In the first wave, the exploitation of &quot;Turn-Key&quot; plants in a hierarchal structure occurs. In the second, the hierarchical is broken, bottom-up forces become active and technological learning accelerates. Industrial regimes grow in greenhouses. In the third wave, the niche cores are formed in the industry.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این مقاله سعی دارد تفسیری اجتماعی- تکنیکی از شکل گیری و گذار صنعت دفاعی ایران در طول چند دهه اخیر را ارائه نماید. برای این منظور، ابتدا با الهام از نظریه میدان بوردیو، چارچوبی برای تحلیل گذار ارائه شده است. در ادامه با ترکیبی از روش شناسی سه مرحله ای بوردیو و روش نظریه پردازی زمینه محور تلاش شده است فرآیند گذار با تاکید بر صنعت ضد زره تحلیل گردد و ایده های نظری جدیدی پیرامون تحول اجتماعی- تکنیکی در صنعت دفاع ارائه شود. بر اساس چارچوب و ایده های ارائه شده در این پژوهش، برای فهم نوآوری و تغییرات فنی در صنعت دفاعی باید به بررسی تحولاتی که در کنش و قشربندی مهندسان و عادت واره، سبک و ارزش های مهندسی رخ می دهد، پرداخت. تجربه صنعت دفاعی نشان می دهد که توازن و هماهنگی بین سرمایه تکنیکی و سرمایه نمادین مهندسان، مهم ترین عامل در توسعه فناورانه و پایداری میدان صنعت دفاعی است. این توازن باعث ایجاد یک قشربندی اجتماعی و روابط کاری مولد بین نیروهای صنعت م یشود. در صورتی که این توازن وجود نداشته باشد، روابط کاری مولد به وجود نمی آید و در نتیجه انباشت سرمایه ممکن نمیشود. میدان سیاست با مداخله در میدان صنعت تاثیر به سزایی بر این توازن و هماهنگی دارد. توجه به این تاثیرگذاری برای سیاست گذاری علم وفناوری در ایران از ضرورت مضاعف برخوردار است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">میدان صنعت دفاعی ایران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صنعت ضد زره</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عادت واره مهندسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گذار اجتماعی- تکنیکی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دیدگاه چندسطحی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14769_a1dc47c8c69e7822fd45ea994602cf76.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
