<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identification and Prioritization of Commercialization Services needed for Technology Units Located at Science and Technology Park of University of Tehran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و اولویت بندی خدمات تجاری سازی مورد نیاز واحدهای فناور مستقر در پارک علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>137</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>161</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">70596</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هاشم</FirstName>
					<LastName>آقازاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار مدیریت بازرگانی دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد رحیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسفیدانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میثم</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>زادبر</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس واحد تجاری سازی پارک علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Science and technology parks are designed to facilitate the development of technology and commercialization of new technology based products and services. The present study aimed at identifying the commercialization services of science and technology parks and prioritizing these services based on the actual needs of the established companies. This applied research was carried out at the University of Tehran’s Science and Technology Park with the help of 227 employees of 93 companies based in aforementioned park and also the park’s commercialization staff. The data gathering method were using questionnaire tool and conducting interview. Categorizing commercialization services using exploratory factor analysis led to identification of 10 factors. Subsequently, these categories and services were ranked by grading weighting analysis (SWARA) method. The results showed that services: marketing, financing and investment, contracts and guarantees, training and counselling respectively, have the highest priority for companies based in Tehran University of Science and Technology Park; therefore providing such services can be helpful in their success and development.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پارک‌های علم و فناوری با هدف تسهیل توسعه فناوری و تجاری‌سازی محصولات و خدمات جدید فناوری‌محور شکل گرفته‌اند. پژوهش حاضر با هدف شناسایی خدمات تجاری‌سازی پارک‌های علم و فناوری و اولویت‌بندی این خدمات بر اساس نیاز واقعی شرکت‌های مستقر انجام شده است. این مطالعه کاربردی در پارک علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران با کمک 227 نفر از کارکنان 93 شرکت مستقر در پارک و کارمندان واحد تجاری‌سازی پارک و با ابزار پرسشنامه و مصاحبه صورت گرفته است. دسته‌بندی خدمات تجاری‌سازی پارک با تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی در این مطالعه منجر به شناسایی 10 عامل گردید. همچنین رتبه‌بندی این دسته‌ها و خدمات، با استفاده از روش تحلیل ارزیابی وزن‌دهی تدریجی انجام شده است. نتایج این پژوهش نشان می‌دهد بازاریابی، تأمین مالی و سرمایه‌گذاری، امور قراردادها و ضمانت‌نامه‌ها، آموزش و مشاوره به ترتیب بیشترین اولویت را برای شرکت‌های مستقر در پارک علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران دارند؛ بنابراین ارائه این‌گونه خدمات می‌تواند در موفقیت و توسعه آن‌ها راه گشا باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تجاری‌سازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرکت های دانش بنیان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پارک علم و فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرکت های کوچک و متوسط</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_70596_fa82dbcbe0f85c228a183594c1ca9d5e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
