<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2023</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Proposing a Framework for Managing Technology Development Projects in Iran&#039;s Oil and Gas Industry</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائه الگویی برای مدیریت پروژه‌های ‌توسعه فناوری در صنعت نفت و گاز ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>103</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>128</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">33419</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>عزیزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیأت علمی/ دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عادله</FirstName>
					<LastName>مقدم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد/ دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Technology development projects, unlike many other kinds of projects, do not have pre-defined goals or clear implementation methods from the outset. Besides common uncertainties any project may face, technology development projects have a high degree of uncertainty in project definition. For this reason, conventional project management methods, such as those provided in the PMBoK, have little use in these projects. This paper describes the characteristics of a technology development project and processes proposed in the literature to manage such projects, studies two technology development projects of Iran&#039;s oil and gas industry in-depth, and identifies and analyzes their management challenges. In order to solve the problems found in the field studies, a management model for technology development projects is designed and validated using the strengths of models like the new stage/gate, spiral development model and DoD Extension to the PMBoK. Some features of the proposed model include: considering the iterative management cycles rather than linear management; using program management principals rather than project management; determining flexible time and budget within acceptable limits rather than determining the exact time and cost of the project, etc.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پروژه‌های توسعه فناوری بر خلاف بسیاری از پروژه‌های دیگر، دارای هدف و یا روش دستیابی از قبل تعریف‌شده نیستند. در کنار عدم قطعیت‌هایی که هر پروژه می‌تواند داشته باشد، پروژه‌های توسعه فناوری با درجة بالایی از عدم قطعیت در بخش تعریف پروژه همراه هستند. به‌همین‌دلیل روش‌های معمول مدیریت‌ پروژه مانند موارد ارائه شده در استاندارد PMBoK کاربرد چندانی در این پروژه‌ها ندارند. در این مقاله، ضمن تشریح ویژگی‌های یک پروژه توسعه فناوری و روش‌هایی که در ادبیات موضوع برای مدیریت این‌گونه پروژه‌ها ارائه شده است، دو پروژه توسعه فناوری از صنعت نفت و گاز ایران، به‌صورت عمیق مطالعه و چالش‌های مدیریتی آنها شناسایی و تحلیل شده است. به‌منظور رفع مشکلات مشاهده‌ شده در مطالعات میدانی و با استفاده از نقاط قوت مدل‌هایی مانند مدل مرحله/دروازه جدید، مدل توسعة مارپیچ و الحاقیه DoDاز استاندارد PMBoK، یک الگوی مدیریتی برای پروژه‌های توسعه فناوری طراحی و پس از طی مراحل اعتبارسنجی، به‌عنوان مدل پیشنهادی پژوهش، ارائه شده است. در نظر گرفتن چرخه‌های مدیریتی تکرارشونده به‌جای مدیریت خطی، استفاده از منطق مدیریت طرح به‌جای منطق مدیریت پروژه، بودجه‌بندی و زمان‌بندی متغیر با حد بالا و پایین به‌جای مشخص نمودن زمان و هزینه قطعی برای پروژه نمونه‌هایی از ویژگی‌های الگوی پیشنهادی هستند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پروژه های توسعه فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت پروژه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت طرح</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">موفقیت پروژه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صنعت نفت و گاز ایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_33419_b2d3e040a4074699e972038c21207f73.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
