<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Configuration of Control Mechanisms in Innovative Corporations</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Mahmoud</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hosseini</namePart>
				<affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rezaeian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Manijeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghareche</namePart>
				<affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Isa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Parizadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>According to traditional management theories, control and innovation are two opposite ends of a continuum. These theories argue that control systems create serious obstacles for creativity and innovation, and in principle, organization&#039;s degree of formality is in inverse relation with innovation. But the new proposed approaches in control literature and experimental researches show that control is not only a rigid and static concept concentrated on standardization and minimizing the diversity and novelty, but formal control systems could also positively affect innovation management process. This paper tries to develop a new framework for making innovation compatible with control in organizations by configuration approach, presenting four conceptually organizational configurations. Two of the configurations provide the necessary context for innovation. In other words, organizations can use these two configurations to make the emergence of innovation possible.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>32</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14722_ec30d914c2613fc2eb7dcaa48f087954.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating the Relationship between Organizational Climate and Perceived Organizational Innovation in Khorasan Regional Electricity Company</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Saeed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mortazavi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khorakian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Elahe</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nasserinejad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Memari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabatabai University Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The concept of perceived organizational innovation refers to employees&#039; perception of organization&#039;s support for innovation, leading to an increase in their sense of satisfaction and commitment. Many studies have examined the effect of organizational factors on perceived organizational innovation. The aim of this paper is to study the relationship between organizational climate and the perception of organizational innovation in regards to the role of gender as a moderating variable. The subjects of the study include 150 experts from Khorasan Regional Electricity Company, Khorasan province, Iran. Questionnaire is used to collect data and its validity is confirmed by content and factorial analysis using SPSS and AMOS statistical software. The findings of the model test show that only 3 aspects of organizational climate, including autonomy, cohesion and trust, have positive effects on the perception of organizational innovation, and there is a strong relationship between organizational climate and perceived innovation. Moreover, the hypothesis concerning the moderating role of employees&#039; gender in the relationship between organizational climate and organizational perceived innovation is not confirmed.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>33</start>
					<end>52</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14723_0878fbc84a1fd8c17ad4326b69ed8a34.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating the Impacts of Knowledge Network on Product Innovation Performance Using Structural Equation Modeling: A Case Study of E-Commerce Companies in Isfahan Province</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shohre</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nasrabadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Elham</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fallah</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Samaneh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shirani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Science and Research Branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2024</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Acquiring new knowledge enables organizations to gain competitive advantage and improves their organizational performance. Knowledge networks are among the main sources of knowledge. The purpose of this study is to investigate the relationship between knowledge management and product innovation performance. To do so, a conceptual framework of product innovation performance is proposed with respect to the factors of knowledge management and product development strategies. Next, the impact of strategic focus on new product development and product innovation performance is empirically studied from the perspective of technical knowledge, customer&#039;s knowledge and competitive knowledge. The statistical population is selected from IT experts in the field of knowledge management and innovation, working for e-commerce companies in Esfahan province, Iran, and academics of the field. In this study, structural equation modeling and AMOS software are used to examine and test the conceptual model, and exploratory factor analysis is used to confirm the validity of the research criteria and structural validity. The results show that product innovation performance is created by knowledge management systems. The findings also reveal that some product development strategies have significant impacts on product innovation performance and knowledge networks. Among product development strategies, incremental strategy has no significant impacts on product innovation performance. Also, knowledge networks have a significantly positive effect on product innovation performance.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2024</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>53</start>
					<end>75</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14724_78115de430cb6624b1bc833db38564f2.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A New Product Diffusion Model: A System Dynamics Approach</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Hashem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mousavi Haghighi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty Member of Fars Research Center for Agriculture and Natural Resources,Shiraz,iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tajik</namePart>
				<affiliation>Shiraz University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Innovation diffusion is a complex and dynamic process affected by various variables, such as quality, competition, the time of market entry, advertising and customer&#039;s satisfaction. Traditional innovation diffusion models, like Bass model, ignore the dynamics of diffusion process and simplify the assumptions based on which the diffusion process is analyzed. Therefore, this paper seeks to propose a developed and dynamic innovation diffusion model through the application of system dynamics methodology. This methodology has found advocates in various fields as an effective approach in studying dynamic and complex behaviors of economic and social systems. The proposed model is simulated by Vensim DSS software and its validity is verified by statistical and systemic tests. Moreover, the model is applied to a new product of B. A. Foodstuff Company. After ensuring the reproduction of real behavior, some scenarios are performed in order to improve the process. The results of the scenarios indicate that the &quot;word-of-mouth&quot; factor has a greater effect on accelerating the diffusion process than &quot;advertising&quot; factor. Also, factors such as the satisfaction of primary consumers, affecting the advertisement procedure through the &quot;word-of-mouth&quot;, plays a major role in innovation diffusion.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>77</start>
					<end>99</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14725_5891c3c0fdd5ca41fda2f15f04290403.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Proposing a Conceptual Model for Making Knowledge Broker Effective in the Process of Knowledge-sharing</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ehsan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Vazirri Goudarzi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Islamic Azad University,Science and Research Branch,Tehran,Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Farzad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Movahedi Sobhani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Islamic Azad University,Science and Research Branch,Tehran,Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Knowledge broker is a simple-looking concept. It looks easy, because the task of knowledge broker is to facilitate communications between the one in need of knowledge and the one in possession of the knowledge. We say it just looks easy, because knowledge transfer without knowledge internalization is not effective. The main goal of this study is to identify the characteristics of knowledge broker for making knowledge-sharing process effective. Qualitative research method with data-based approach is used here. Therefore, the duties and characteristics of knowledge brokers are investigated in the context of a domestic knowledge-based organization, and structural connections between these duties and characteristics are explained for making knowledge-sharing process effective. The data of this study is collected through a series of semi-structured interviews with the managers and experts of the organization, and then analyzed by utilizing open, center-based and selective coding method. The findings reveal four characteristics for knowledge brokers, including extroversion, charisma, position, and organizational authorities and ability. Also, according to the conceptual model proposed in this study, knowledge brokers, besides developing communication capacity, improve change capacity in organization and thereby make knowledge-sharing process effective.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>101</start>
					<end>120</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14734_35a829be158fd12c23ca9777acfc2bd5.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Designing Products by Integrating Kano and QFD Models Using TOPSIS: A Case Study of Cell-Phone</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tabatabaeenasab</namePart>
				<affiliation>Yazd University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahsa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ebrahimpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Yazd University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Various methods have been devised and tested to develop new products or services. But, nowadays considering advantages and disadvantages of each, hybrid methods seem more appealing. In this paper, QFD and Kano methods are combined. The resulting hybrid method is a new product covering both competitive and innovative characteristics. At the first step, the needs of customers are identified through interviews with the focus group and classified by Kano method through surveying 282 users. Then, the correlation between each characteristic and the related requirements are identified by experts and considered in the final QFD matrix. Simultaneously, 18 characteristics ranked by TOPSIS reach the final matrix. In the QFD matrix, goals are determined by various analyses, and the cell-phone meeting the competitive and creative requirements is introduced. Finally, those attributes leading to satisfaction and competitive advantages remain in the QFD matrix and considered in the final product design. The design procedure in this method can reduce the risk of new product introduction and accordingly increase the competitiveness of enterprises.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>121</start>
					<end>144</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14735_24902358206bde3de7ae00d881d7bc29.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>