<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Relationship between Emotional Intelligence Capabilities and Organizational Entrepreneurship: A Case Study of Iran&#039;s Commercial Automotive Industry</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی و مطالعه ارتباط قابلیت های هوش هیجانی با کارآفرینی سازمانی؛ مطالعه موردی صنعت خودروی های تجاری در ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>39</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>64</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14602</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوروزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اصغر</FirstName>
					<LastName>مشبکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید حمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>خداداد حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اسدالله</FirstName>
					<LastName>کردنائیج</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Rapid changes, increased competition, reduced product life-cycles and rapid advance of technology are considered as unavoidable features of the current business environment. Creative and innovative entrepreneurs are necessary for organizations to survive. The particular interest of organizations and institutions in recent years reveals the importance of entrepreneurship in business environment. The present study aims to evaluate the effects of emotional intelligence capabilities on organizational entrepreneurship. The population studied in this study includes the commercial and cargo automotive industry of Iran. The study is based on a descriptive survey. In order to measure the emotional intelligence of managers and employees, the Afzalur &amp; Minors standard questionnaire is used to evaluate self-awareness, self-regulation, self-motivation, social awareness and social skills, while a researcher-made questionnaire is used to measure organizational entrepreneurship. The validity and reliability of the questionnaire are determined by experts and Cronbach&#039;s alpha. The data are analyzed using statistical methods, including Spearman correlation matrix, Friedman test and stepwise regression. The results show a significant positive relationship between the emotional intelligence of employees and organizational entrepreneurship. Also, confirmatory factor analysis is used to measure the total fitness of the model</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">    تغییرات سریع، رقابت فزاینده، کاهش طول عمر محصولات و سرعت زیاد پیشرفت فناوری از ویژگی های غیر قابل اجتناب محیط کسب و کار کنونی است. وجود افراد خلاق، نوآور و کار آفرین از الزامات اساسی تداوم حیات سازمان ها می باشد. این پژوهش به منظور بررسی تاثیر ابعاد هوش هیجانی کارکنان در دو بعد شایستگی هایی فردی (خودآگاهی، خودانگیزشی، خود تنظیمی) و شایستگی های اجتماعی ( آگاهی اجتماعی، مهارت های اجتماعی) برمیزان کارآفرینی سازمانی انجام شده است. در این مقاله، کارآفرینی سازمانی  به عنوان متغیر وابسته و ابعاد هوش هیجانی کارکنان سازمان، به عنوان متغیر مستقل درنظر گرفته شده است. جامعه آماری تحقیق صنعت تولید خودروهای تجاری و باری در ایران می باشد. روش پژوهش توصیفی و از نوع پیمایشی است. برای سنجش هوش هیجانی کارکنان و مدیران، از پرسشنامه استاندارد افزلور و ماینورس استفاده گردید و برای سنجش کارآفرینی سازمانی پرسشنامه محقق ساخته مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. روایی پرسشنامه با استفاده از نظر خبرگان و پایایی آن با آلفای کرونباخ تعیین شد. داده ها با استفاده از روش های آماری ماتریس همبستگی اسپیرمن و آزمون فریدمن و روش رگرسیون گام به گام، مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. نتایج حاصل رابطه ای مثبت و معنی دار میان هوش هیجانی کارکنان و کارآفرینی سازمانی را نشان داد. برای سنجش برازش کلی مدل تحقیق از تحلیل عاملی تاییدی استفاده گردید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوش هیجانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قابلیت های شخصی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قابلیت های اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14602_a8580e1d5da23c3aa04089a2d3285641.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
