<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identifying, Analyzing and Categorizing Factors Affecting the Formation of Innovation Networks in Knowledge-Based Firms: A Case Study of the University of Tehran Science and Technology Park</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشکده علوم و فنون نوین، دانشگاه تهران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hamidi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Behrooz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mahmoudi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sepideh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Javadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Nowadays, considering complex technologies, companies are no longer capable of developing innovative products and services by themselves. Thus, cooperation among companies in products and technology innovation has become important. Accordingly, organizations and corporations pay more attention to networking with the aim of innovation, as a form of collaboration. However, the formation of these networks requires factors that pave the way for the formation of this mode of cooperation. This study aims to identify factors affecting the formation of innovation networks in knowledge-based firms, and investigate their effectiveness. The methodology of this study includes field study and correlation. The results are analyzed by SPSS software and exploratory factor analysis. The study classifies factors affecting the formation of innovation networks in four categories: communication, cooperation development, internal capabilities, and facilitators. The results also show the significance of the role of variables, such as specialists, regulations and their appropriate implementation, companies&#039; familiarity with each other&#039;s activities, the existence of knowledge base, and trust.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>24</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14736_ec7ff952110a3302100d8f1271957071.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Meta-Synthesis of Regional Innovation Models: A Review of 1990–2013</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Naghizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shaban</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Elahi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Manoochehr</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Manteghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malek-Ashtar University of Technology  </affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Sepehr</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghazinoory</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malek-Ashtar University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In recent decades, different studies have been conducted on regional innovation development, most of which have been case studies using qualitative research methodologies. Thus, this paper tries to investigate the findings of the related qualitative studies systematically based on the identified themes, and analyze the reasons and contexts of regional innovation models. No similar study has been done so far on regional innovation models. In this study, we investigate 300 papers from Sage and Scopus databases dated from 1990 to 2013, and finally after two stages of screening, 48 papers are identified as high and average quality papers for deep analysis. Then, three themes, and their related sub-themes, are identified based on the findings from meta-synthesis method using open coding method for analyzing the papers. The main themes are: 1) the level of regional development, especially in institutional section; 2) the decrease of governmental intervention in industries and firms; and 3) globalization and the increase of international relations. Also, each theme has several sub-themes used for the analysis. Based on the analysis, the regions are categorized in three clusters with respect to their innovation levels. Early innovators, transitional innovators and advanced innovators are three regional model categories useful for policy-makers to make better decisions. Finally, some suggestions are offered based on the results for innovation development in the region of Iran.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>25</start>
					<end>56</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14737_b8784b94c69b2ac01dd34e3957b3dbb3.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Analyzing the Effects of Three-Dimensional Model on Social Innovation: A Case Study of a Company in Iran's Automotive Industry</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mobini Dehkordi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran  </affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehran</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Keshtkar Haranaki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Supreme National Defense University  </affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In an era characterized by uncertainty, globalization and ever-increasing changes in technology, the success of organizations are dependent upon innovative measures, including employing new social patterns in employees&#039; interactions. This issue known as social innovation leads to finding new solutions for needs, requirements and eventually fulfilling organizational goals. Analyzing social innovation can promote the awareness and recognition of organizational factors by deepening the understanding of social innovation. Therefore, the present study aims to examine the role of co-structural, contextual and content factors — in the form of a three-dimensional model — in social innovation in a company related to Iran&#039;s automotive industry. The statistical sample of the study consists of 130 managers, deputies and heads of various sectors of industry, selected by Chochran&#039;s formula. The results illustrate three points. First, there is a positive and meaningful relationship among the main variables of the study. Second, by comparing the three-dimensional factors, it turns out that co-structural, content and contextual factors respectively have the highest impacts on the social innovation of the organization. Finally, the effects of these factors on social innovation processes are different in the five stages. Co-structural factors have respectively the highest and lowest impacts on big-scale execution and creating a common sense; context factors have respectively the highest and lowest impacts on big-scale execution and sampling; and content factors have respectively the highest and lowest impacts on creating a common sense and big-scale execution. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>57</start>
					<end>75</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14738_eaf649262b1c8d191dff76961b9be38b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Effects of Psychological Capital on Organizational Performance with an Emphasis on the Mediatory Role of Innovation in Information Technology: A Case Study of the Branches of Agriculture Bank in Tehran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Babak</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ziyae</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran  </affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mobaraki</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran  </affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mozhgan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Saeediyoun</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran  </affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In the past two decades, organizational performance has become one of the most attractive topics of interest, resulting in various innovations in research and applied fields. This paper seeks to investigate the effects of psychological capital on organizational performance, focusing on the mediating role of innovation in information technology among the branches of Agriculture bank in Tehran, Iran. This study is empirical with descriptive-correlative methodology. The research population includes 135 managers and employees working for Agriculture bank in Tehran. A sample of 100 is selected from them for the experiment, using Kerjeici and Morgan table and random sampling. Data gathering tool in this study is a standard questionnaire, while structural equation modeling (SEM) and SmartPLS 2 software are used for data analysis. The results show that innovation in IT mediates the relationship between psychological capital and organizational performance, and there is a significant and positive relationship between psychological capital and innovation in IT. At the end, some suggestions are made to increase innovation in IT and to improve organizational performance.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>77</start>
					<end>100</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14739_415843535f2c4162424409e2b882c3c7.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating Graduate Programs in Technology Management: A Comparative Study</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Hosain</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shojaei</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University  </affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Hamed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mazarei</namePart>
				<affiliation>پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Investigating and studying educational programs is one of the main activities of any academic discipline for self-evaluation. This paper reviews previous studies about educational programs of technology management (and related fields) to find their shortcomings, and then tries to answer four questions about technology management graduate programs in a different way: 1) How are these programs geographically distributed worldwide and which schools/faculties offer them? 2) How do the program themes relate to regions and schools/faculties? 3) What courses have the highest frequencies? 4) How do the courses relate to themes and schools/faculties? An initial list of educational programs is prepared by keywords searching on the Internet. The list is then finalized by searching information technology management (educational) programs in 100 top universities worldwide along with other educational institutes ranked as &quot;very good&quot; by the Iranian Ministry of Science, Research and Technology. After extracting the needed data about the programs, we use thematic method for analyzing the titles of programs and courses based on the initial data for answering the research questions. The results are useful for policy-makers, the scientific community of technology management, and whoever interested in learning technology management. Also, the Iranian IT educational programs are compared with the results.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>101</start>
					<end>130</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14740_e3d7ad58548d8c932b3172e86c7dc0cd.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Prioritization of Criteria Affecting the Evaluation of Venture Capital Projects</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shahrzad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Derakhshan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University  </affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parastoo</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University  </affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The evaluation of new idea projects is one of the most challenging issues in the relationship between entrepreneurs and venture capitalists. The aim of this paper is to identify and rank important criteria used by venture capitalists in the evaluation of new idea projects. To do so, the required data is gathered by a questionnaire. The data analysis is performed using partial least squares method, a subsidiary to structural equations modeling. The results show that the financial considerations of product have the highest priority and personality traits and the ability of entrepreneur respectively rank the next. Also, 24 of 46 basic criteria have reached the final stage of analysis and are recommended to be used in the screening phase. The results are validated for 4 new ideas projects. The accuracy of ranking these projects is 83 percent based on the results of this study.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>131</start>
					<end>152</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14741_4d68710abb85f6a948e9b9e99420bd7d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>