<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An analysis of a Model for External Organizational Factors Influencing Innovation Development in Industrial-Research Organizations</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mansur</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sadeghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Imam Hussein University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sadeghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Imam Hussein University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This study intends to identify the constituent elements of &quot;a model for external factors influencing innovation development&quot;, to identify relations among the main elements, and lastly to design a comprehensive structure of a model for external factors influencing innovation development in research organizations. To design a theoretical framework for the model, using the relevant literature and library research, and conducting exploratory interviews, we extract the factors effective on innovation development in research organizations, and then evaluate them by survey research methodology and questionnaires. The data of the study are collected by using questionnaires distributed among 300 subjects, and then each major component of the conceptual model is analyzed. The structural equation model and LISREL software are used to evaluate the causal relations between the components of the conceptual model. Based on the findings, &quot;competitive intelligence&quot; is the most influential factor (through dominating emerging technologies space, absorbing and transferring knowledge from organization&#039;s external environment elements, forecasting before competitors, reaching future before customers, and predicting market changes). The next important influential factors include taking advantage of &quot;science &amp; research centers&quot; (through benchmarking, outsourcing, and idea absorption); and considering the &quot;customers&quot; (through investigations based on customer needs and their participation in all design processes and innovation, and getting customers&#039; satisfaction).</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>20</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14616_f23b1edbb43a3367f4497bccd630edd7.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Developing a Framework for Aligning Adaptive Foresight with Science, Technology and Innovation Evidence-Based Policy-Making</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Leila</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Namdarian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hasanzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares
University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sha&rsquo;ban</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Elahi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Majidpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Amirkabir University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>A foresight activity can be assumed effective when its consequences are reflected in the policy-making process. This notion emphasizes the concept of foresight as a policy intelligence tool. No framework has yet been presented to show that foresight influences policy-making process. Therefore, the present study tries to provide a framework for aligning technology foresight with policy-making. This study mainly develops the proposed framework by integrating the concepts of evidence-based policy-making and adaptive foresight with the help of a mixed method. The &quot;mixed method&quot; approach used in this study has a sequential exploratory design characterized by the collection and analysis of qualitative data followed by the collection and analysis of quantitative data. First, a conceptual framework is developed in the qualitative part of the study by meta-synthesis and constant comparative method of analysis (CCM); second, in the quantitative part, the quantitative tests are done to evaluate the factors, dimensions, and components of the developed theoretical framework. To test the proposed model, questionnaires are distributed as the data collection tool among a sample of 15 experts active in the field of foresight and policy-making. The results confirm the hypotheses of the study and the validity of the proposed framework.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>21</start>
					<end>50</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14626_711f766c0e4d867bf624c14f20a53997.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Designing a Model for Leadership Evaluation Based on Complexity Theory</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Afshar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bazyar</namePart>
				<affiliation>هیئت علمی دانشگاه</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fesharaki</namePart>
				<affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The current age is characterized by competitiveness and complexity as the age of knowledge and information. Knowledge age organizations inevitably take collaborating and networking approaches. Networking approaches have raised new issues in organizations, and to confront these issues requires revisiting the presumptions of management, leadership, and organization sciences. The main purpose of this study is to investigate these issues analytically and to present a model for leadership evaluation based on the complexity theory. In order to build the model, it is supposed that the primary aim of a complex organization is to enhance the adaptability and response speed to achieve the results. For this purpose of the study, the main networks interpreting theories — i.e. complexity theory and complexity leadership theory — are used. The concept of super-structure is used to explain organizing in network and the main processes of the net centric warfare is used to explain the main process of network. In order to conclude and integrate the ingredients of the model, organizational excellence approach is utilized. Finally, a conceptual, testable, and operational model is introduced.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>51</start>
					<end>70</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14627_5a3bb595783a4a2d28f84a8f22f84830.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Presenting a Strategic Model of Organizational Performance Assessment based on a Logic Model</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zamani Mazdeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Payame Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mahmudi Meimand</namePart>
				<affiliation>Payame Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Karimi Govareshaki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Payame Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mojtaba</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sarvar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Amirkabir University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Performance is compared to an umbrella that covers all the concepts important for the success and doing activities in an organization; that is why its evaluation is important. Several models have been proposed so far, yet a comprehensive model is lacking, which focuses on strategic goals, covers all key issues needed for managers, and has the ability to evaluate strategic innovation. The aim of this study is to present such a model based on a qualitative research. First, conceptual and philosophical analyses are performed; then, the most important features of an ideal model from the literature are extracted and classified into five general groups; after that, a strategic model for assessing the organizational performance with four layers (1. Input, 2. Process, 3.Output, 4.Outcomes) is designed by studying 30 models of performance evaluation and using a comparative analysis (in systemic perspective). Since the emphasis of the systemic perspective is on the coordination and communication of components, a logic model is used to highlight the integrity and hierarchical features of the model (4 layers). For validation purpose, first the structured method and a judgment based on knowledge and expertise is used, then the modified model is evaluated operationally in 21 strategic classes of organization. The questionnaires are distributed among 3 organizational groups in order to test the validity. The average scores of the questionnaire show the 78 percent acceptability by managers and experts in the whole organization.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>71</start>
					<end>100</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14628_8e670b7cebf4a3690ef3780f1727e704.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Identification and Evaluation of Criteria for Choosing High-Tech Industries in Technology Parks in Iran: A Case Study of Sheikh-Baha'i Science &amp; Technology Park</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Naser</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nouruzi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Narimani</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Policy-making, or task prioritization, in different research and industrial fields is among the most important factors in increasing efficiency of resource allocation. Since the concept of science and technology park is new in Iran and has great potential for facilitating the move toward development, prioritizing activities of these centers seems very important. In this study, in addition to library studies and surveys on national documents — including the Fifth Development Plan, the 20-Year Perspective Document of Iran, the National Integrated Scientific Scheme and the Strategic Document of Transformation for Iran Science and Technology — seventeen criteria are chosen for selecting high-tech industries to enter technology parks. Based on these criteria, a questionnaire is developed and distributed among three influential actors, namely policy-makers at the Ministry of Science, Research and Technology, the firms located inside the parks and the absorption committees of the parks. Data gathered through the questionnaires are analyzed using SPSS software and the statistical method of factor analysis in order to classify the seventeen criteria in four general factors. After reviewing the related literature, the titles Economic &amp; Technical, Strategic, Infrastructures and Environmental are suggested for these factors. Finally, a framework is introduced for prioritizing high-tech industries to enter Sheikh-Baha&#039;i Science &amp; Technology Park, Esfahan, Iran.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>101</start>
					<end>112</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14629_64911e2b48b7d2df20d10c1ae79db6fa.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Modeling Factors Affecting Technological Collaboration Achievements: A Case Study of Technological Collaboration in the Field of Nanotechnology in Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abolfazl</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bagheri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba’i
University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bushehri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malekashtar University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Many studies have been carried out on technological collaboration achievements in the field of science and technology policy. Some focus on the effectiveness of science and technology policies. Iran&#039;s science and technology policies support technological collaboration by providing many incentives, especially for emerging technologies like nanotechnology. There are still some debates about whether these policies are effective or not. This study is conducted to investigate the factors affecting achievements of technological collaborations. Based on the related literature, the factors affecting technological collaborations are classified into four groups: individual, institutional, organizational, and interactional. The model is verified by interviewing 20 experts active in the field of science and technology policy and nanotechnology sector in Iran. After that, the model is examined by structural equations modeling and path analysis methods. All the 72 researchers participated in the survey are randomly selected from nanotechnology experts&#039; database. The results show that the interactional factors, including social networks, individual interactions, organizational interactions and technological networks, directly and positively affect collaboration achievements.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>113</start>
					<end>140</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14630_45fb4082cb96aa1cf905c965e2bf54c8.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>