<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying and prioritizing Critical Success Factors of product design in IT industry with Crowdsourcing Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>عوامل کلیدی موفقیت پروژه‌های طراحی‌محصول با رویکرد جمع‌سپاری در صنعت فناوری اطلاعات</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>51</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>84</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">88595</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>سلطانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میثم</FirstName>
					<LastName>شفیعی رودپشتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیت علمی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید جاوید</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش آموخته مدیریت بازرگانی دانشگاه تهران پردیس فارابی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Crowdsourcing is one of the new cooperative strategiesin open innovation that Using Information Technology (IT) facilities, provides a platform for active online crowds in various activities of companies such as product design. However, in this area, there were not too many projects which have achieved acceptable results. Therefore, this research attempts to identify and prioritize success factors of crowdsourcing in product design and improvement. the type of research is mixed method. The method of analysis for qualitative section is based on content analysis and for quantitative part is based on descriptive survey. Data were collected from experts and specialists in the field of crowdsourcing. Hence, several factors has been extracted from previous studies, then 36 main success factors has been recognized through interviewing approximately ten managers who are experienced in crowdsourcing for product design. The factors were assayed by Delphi method and final dimensions and factors were weighed by experts using best worth method. The study prioritized the quadruple dimensions of crowdsourcing as follows: contributors, IT system, organization management and employees. Among the factors of mentioned dimensions, “contributors operation quality”, “quality of IT System”, “control and supervision process” and “employees efficiency” are the most important ones, respectively.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">جمع‌سپاری یکی از راهبردهای همکاری در نوآوری باز است که با بهره‌گیری از امکانات فناوری اطلاعات (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Calibri;&quot;&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt;) بستری را برای حضور فعال جمعیت‌های آنلاین در فعالیت‌های مختلف شرکت‌ها نظیر طراحی‌محصول فراهم کرده‌است. با این حال تعداد پروژه‌هایی که در این حوزه به نتایج قابل قبول نرسیده و کارایی لازم را نداشته‌اند نیز کم نبوده‌است. این پژوهش درصدد شناسایی و تعیین اولویت برای شاخص‌های موفقیت در جمع‌سپاریطراحی‌محصول و بهبود آن بوده‌است. این تحقیق از نوع تحقیقات آمیخته است که در قسمت کیفی، تحلیل مضمون و در قسمت کمی با روش توصیفی پیمایشی صورت گرفته‌است. جامعه تحقیق شامل تمام کارشناسان،نخبگان و متخصصان حوزه جمع‌سپاری بود، در همین راستا ابتدا با استفاده از ادبیات پیشین تعدادی عوامل استخراج شد سپس به کمک مصاحبه با ۱۰ نفر از کارشناسان،مدیران سازمان‌هایی که تجربه استفاده از جمع‌سپاری را در طراحی‌محصول داشته‌اند، در مجموع ۳۶ عامل حیاتی برای موفقیت جمع‌سپاری مورد شناسایی قرار گرفت که با روش دلفی غربالسازی شدند و  به کمک روش بهترین-بدترین (&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Calibri;&quot;&gt;BWM&lt;/span&gt;) اولویت‌بندی شدند. از میان ابعاد چهارگانه جمع‌سپاری به ترتیب «مشارکت‌کنندگان»، «سیستم &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Calibri;&quot;&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt;»، «مدیریت سازمان» و «کارمندان» و نیز در میان عوامل این ابعاد، «کیفیت عملکرد مشارکت‌کنندگان»، «کیفیت سیستم &lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Calibri;&quot;&gt;IT&lt;/span&gt;»، «فرآیند کنترل و نظارت» و «کارآیی کارمندان» به ترتیب دارای بیشترین اهمیت بودند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جمع‌سپاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طراحی‌محصول</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صنعت it</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل کلیدی موفقیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش دلفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تکنیک BWM</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_88595_262a63e44f8bf824357e25fa56580b70.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
