<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating the Effects of Company Resources and Environmental Variables on the Commercialization of New Product at the Iranian National Laser Center</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nabavi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Officer of Iranian National Center for Laser Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sabetifard</namePart>
				<affiliation>مرکز ملی علوم و فنون لیزر ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Davoud</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghiyasvand</namePart>
				<affiliation>مرکز ملی علوم و فنون لیزر ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shadi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghoreishi</namePart>
				<affiliation>مرکز ملی علوم و فنون لیزر ایران</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Clearly one of the main reasons for fast growth of technology development in developed countries is paying attention to commercialization process of internal researches&#039; results. It can be concluded that the basis of commercialization process is the cooperation of research and industrial sectors in conversion of research results into innovations and the development of new products. In this survey, we try to study the impact of resources and environmental variables on the commercialization of new product development, especially variables like &quot;dominant design&quot;, &quot;increase in market heterogeneity&quot; and &quot;network side-effects&quot; in Iranian National Laser Center (INLC). This study is applied in objective and descriptive-survey in nature. After reviewing the literature through library studies, a researcher-made questionnaire is applied to test the research hypotheses. The validity and reliability of the questionnaire are tested respectively by content and construct related validities, and &quot;Cronbach&#039;s alpha&quot;. Bivariate linear regression and structural equation modeling are used as inferential statistics methodology. Findings imply that &quot;dominant design&quot;, &quot;technology acquisition attitude&quot; and &quot;increase in market heterogeneity&quot; have significant effects on the commercialization of new product in INLC; whereas &quot;company&#039;s resources&quot; and &quot;network side-effect&quot; do not have any significant effects on the commercialization of new product in the center.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>24</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14759_dbb14cb771b3fc235f6d54faa7549413.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identifying the Critical Success Factors of Research Collaborations between Universities and Defense Industries in Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Abbas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Dadvar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Maleke-ashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Manoochehr</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Manteghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Maleke-ashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abolfazl</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bagheri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Maleke-ashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>There is an institutionalized connection between industry and university in developed countries. However, in Iran, despite a great emphasis on establishing and strengthening connections between defense industries and universities, there is no specific process to build an effective collaboration and the current policies are not highly sufficient for existing needs. The main reason is lack of proper identification of critical success factors in industry-university collaboration. So, the main purpose of this study is to identify the critical success factors of defense industries and university collaboration. To do so, 19 critical success factors are identified in four dimensions of interactions design, knowledge, social, and collaboration success through the literature review, then the research model and hypotheses are proposed consequently. A questionnaire is designed to collect experts&#039; opinions. The four dimensions and their factors are measured by frequency tables, mean and standard deviation. In addition, the effect of each factor on collaboration is determined through one sample test. Also, another questionnaire (including 36 items) is designed and distributed among users. Its questions are assessed and confirmed by conformity factor analysis. After that, the effects of all success factors are verified by path analysis, and the research model and hypothesis are confirmed by the findings resulted from structural equation modeling. Finally, some solutions and practical suggestions are made to improve and enhance the collaborations between university and defense industries.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>25</start>
					<end>52</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14764_eed34a4df3eafdc817f0b05cc8c8193b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Model for Product Technology Strategizing in a Firm Based on its Suppliers' Technological Capabilities</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Karimpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Payam-e-Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Arasti</namePart>
				<affiliation>Sharif University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Akbari Jokar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Sharif University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sheikhzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Sharif University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>With the increasing complexity of products and necessity for development, today&#039;s products, processes and the relevant technologies are planned, designed and finally manufactured with the participation of suppliers in the wide range of the corporation&#039;s supply chain. Lack of attention of corporations to the technological capabilities of supply chains has made them experience different problems in implementing product and process development strategies. This paper tries to design an integrated model for product technology strategizing in the supply chain of a firm based on the technological capabilities of its suppliers. This study is conducted with qualitative approach in two stages. First, after reviewing the literature and studying the documents of automotive companies, the preliminary data is gathered through in-depth interviews with a group of experts of Iranian automotive industry, and then the collected data is analyzed by theme methodology. After that, based on the identified themes and exploring the relations between them, a conceptual model is designed. At the second phase, the validity and reliability of the designed model are tested and confirmed using the methodology of focus group with another group of experts of the industry. The designed model makes it possible for corporations to develop a strategy of technology with the participation of supply chain.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>53</start>
					<end>85</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14765_cf353041b8069c7a95da5b1009ce5afc.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Organizational Preparedness for the Successful Implementation of Technology Development Strategies</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hessam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">ZandHessami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Qazvin Islamic Azad University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Zeinab</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ashtianipour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Qazvin Islamic Azad University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Soraya</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Pourabdolah</namePart>
				<affiliation>Shahre-e-Qods, Islamic Azad University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Competition and maintaining competitive position in the current complex market situation require the selection of an appropriate strategy to gain the goals and knowledge of the capabilities and capacities within the organization. The evaluation of organizational preparedness is a good measure to look into the current level of organization&#039;s capabilities of designing and implementing strategies. Technology and technology development strategies are important factors for gaining organization&#039;s goals. To implement technology development strategies successfully, being aware of organization&#039;s internal capabilities helps managers better identify technology development opportunities and leads to growth and achieving competitive advantage. This study is of descriptive-analytical and functional type. Data collection is done by reviewing the literature, interviews with experts and scholars, and questionnaires. The data is analyzed through interpretive-structural modeling (ISM) technique and DEMATEL, and then the relation and sequence of dimensions and criteria are determined. Finally, the integrated model of ISM-DEMATEL is presented.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>87</start>
					<end>107</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14766_d0395148f8e491fa9d00f076cbb1e248.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Effects of Organizational Structure and Culture on Innovation: A Comparative Study of the Central Organizations of the Islamic Azad University, Payame Noor University, the University of Applied Science and Technology, and the University of Tehran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mirkamali</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty of Education and Psychology, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sahba</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rezaeian</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Nowadays, innovation is regarded as one of the main merits for the liveliness of educational organizations, especially universities. This study aims to examine the differences between various universities of Iran in terms of organizational innovation and the impact of structure and culture. To do so, Iran&#039;s universities are categorized into four main groups: Islamic Azad University, Payame Noor University (PNU), the University of Applied Science and Technology (UAST), and public universities. The statistical population of the study is comprised of managers and employees of the central organization of these universities. The conceptual model and research hypotheses are developed based on the related literature. Data collection, and hypotheses and model testing are done through questionnaire tool and structural equation model. In the UAST, a meaningful relationship is revealed between innovation-culture and innovation-structure; in the University of Tehran, there is a positive and meaningful relationship between culture and innovation; and In the Islamic Azad University, a meaningful relationship exist only between culture and innovation. By structural equations modeling, the impacts of latent variables (structure) on endogenous latent variables (culture and innovation) are examined, and the results show that the structure does not affect innovation in central organization of these universities directly. But the meaningful impact of structure on culture and very meaningful impact of culture on organizational innovation lead to the conclusion that organizational structure can be influential via affecting the culture.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>109</start>
					<end>131</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14767_03338f7d8faaea16ce51551b34ec988d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Designing a Model for Technology Transfer from R&amp;D to Industry in Defense Industries</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Forozandeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghanadian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Islamic Azad University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammadreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hooshmand</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The transfer of technology makes possible the access to and acquisition of technology to be used effectively for economical and technological growth of industry and the improvement of quality. It is achieved in an organization when there is an integrated and systematic model for it based on technology maturity levels and nature, so that the right technology can be identified, transferred and applied. The purpose of this study is identifying factors affecting the transfer of technology from research and development (R&amp;D) sector to industry in Iranian defense industries and providing a local model for it. For this purpose, after reviewing the literature of the subject and the current models of technology transfer, and interviewing industry experts, the factors affecting technology transfer are categorized in six dimensions of strategy, transferor, technology, transferee, results and achievements and, the method of the transfer. Then, by interviewing and surveying 10 experts, distributing a questionnaire among 40 experts and by using T-test, the effects of these factors on technology transfer are examined in defense industries. Finally, based on the known factors and the interviews, the final and local model of the study is designed. The results show that technology transfer must be taken into account from the beginning of a project feasibility phase. Moreover, cooperation between transferor and transferee has to be maintained in order to promote the level of the transferred elements. The opposed model can contribute to the success of technology transfer projects.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>133</start>
					<end>160</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14768_048d6a3567c3a6a99b8ee4321e71462e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>