<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The emergence of dynamic capabilities in a knowledge -based SME for Fintech</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ظهور قابلیت‌های پویا در یک شرکت کوچک و متوسط دانش بنیان حوزه فین تک</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>101</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>138</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">102631</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سروش</FirstName>
					<LastName>قاضی نوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نیما</FirstName>
					<LastName>مختارزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>ابویی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>متین</FirstName>
					<LastName>رشیدی آستانه</LastName>
<Affiliation>تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Iran&#039;s business environment is a vibrant and unpredictable environment and operating in this situation requires special capabilities.Constant changes in this environment have made it difficult for companies to simply compete with existing capabilities and resource. The purpose of this article is to examine how a company (knowledge-based) can perform well in a turbulent environment by relying on its capabilities. Accordingly, theories of competitive advantage were examined and finally the theory of dynamic capabilities was selected as the appropriate theory. This article is assumed that the emergence of dynamic capabilities depends on the microfoundations formed in the company and these foundations could were embedded in three layers (human, social, organizational). We were extracted related variables in each layer based on the research literature an after interviewing with the company executives and staff, we were coded and placed them in their related layers. The results showed that human and social layers are very important in a FinTech and knowledge-based enterprise.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">محیط کسب و کار ایران، محیطی پرنوسان و غیرقابل پیش بینی است و فعالیت در آن، نیازمند قابلیت‌های منحصر به فردی است. تغییرات مستمر این محیط باعث شده تا شرکت‌ها صرفا با اکتفا به قابلیت‌ها و منابع موجود نتوانند به رقابت بپردازند و در این مسیر موفق شوند. هدف مقاله، بررسی این فرضیه است که چگونه یک شرکت (دانش بنیان) در چنین محیط پرتلاطمی با اکتفا به قابلیت‌های خود توانسته عملکرد مناسبی داشته باشد. بر این اساس، تئوری‌های حوزه مزیت رقابتی مورد بررسی قرار گرفت و در نهایت تئوری قابلیت‌های پویا به عنوان تئوری مناسب انتخاب شد. در این مقاله فرض شد که ظهور قابلیت‌های پویا منوط به بنیان‌های خردی است که در شرکت شکل گرفته‌اند و این بنیان‌ها می‌توانند در سه لایه (فردی، اجتماعی، سازمانی) گنجانده شوند. ما متغیرهای مرتبط با هر لایه را براساس ادبیات تحقیق استخراج کردیم و پس از مصاحبه با مدیران و کارکنان تخصصی شرکت، آن‌ها را کدگذاری و در لایه‌های مرتبط با خود قرار دادیم. نتایج نشان داد که در این شرکت دانش بنیان فین تک، لایه‌های فردی و میانی از اهمیت بسیاری برخوردار هستند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قابلیت های پویا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درک کردن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهره برداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازپیکربندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فین تک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرکت دانش بنیان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_102631_df8f17ca3f27b4bbad22fb46be866dba.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
