<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Comparative Study of Innovation Modes and HR Configurations in Knowledge-Based Firms in Science and Technology Parks</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی انطباقی سبک نوآوری و سبک مدیریت منابع انسانی در شرکت های دانش بنیان مستقر در پارک های علم و فناوری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>22</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14844</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>وجه الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>قربانی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>راحله</FirstName>
					<LastName>منتظر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میرعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>سیدنقوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داوود</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسین پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Human capital is one of the most important factors for innovation in companies. In this paper, we focus on two characteristics of human capital, i.e. uniqueness and value creation, to conduct a comparative study on the modes of innovation and human resource (HR) configurations in knowledge-based firms located in Pardis Technology Park and the University of Tehran Science and Technology Park. Managing human capital in innovative companies needs a set of HR practices suitable for work force characteristics and special aims of firm. In this study, we try to answer the question: Do knowledge-based firms choose their HR configuration according to their human capital characteristics and innovation mode? This study is a descriptive survey, with questionnaire as data collecting tool. We perform confirmatory factor analysis to assess the construct validity and model verification, and use binominal test to assess the level of coordination between the modes. In the first stage, the maximum level of coordination is identified between productivity-based HR system and market-oriented innovation, and in the next stage, the maximum coordination is between collaborative HR system and science-based innovation mode. Also, the average of value creation scores higher than uniqueness.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سرمایه انسانی یک شرکت از مهمترین عوامل نوآوری محسوب می‌شود. در این پژوهش با تمرکز بر‌ دو ویژگی منحصر‌به‌فردی و ارزش‌آفرینی سرمایه انسانی،‌ به بررسی انطباقی ‌سبک نوآوری با سبک کارکردهای منابع انسانی در شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان مستقر در دو پارک علم وفناوری پردیس و دانشگاه تهران پرداخته شد. مدیریت سرمایه‌های انسانی شرکت‌های نوآور، نیازمند بکارگیری مجموعه‌ای از کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی متناسب با ویژگی‌های کارکنان و اهداف ویژه شرکت می‌باشد. پژوهش حاضر بدنبال پاسخ به این سوال است که آیا شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان بر مبنای نوع و ویژگی‌های سرمایه انسانی ‌و منطبق با سبک نوآوری خود، سبک کارکردهای منابع انسانی خود را انتخاب می‌نمایند؟ برای این منظور پس از مرور ادبیات، 46 شرکت مستقر در دو پارک فناوری پردیس و دانشگاه تهران، مورد بررسی قرار گرفتند. برای گردآوری داده‌ها از ابزار پرسش‌نامه استفاده شد. در ادامه، پس از تحلیل داده‌ها با روش تحلیل عاملی تاییدی و تایید مدل، میزان هماهنگی میان سبک‌ها با استفاده از آزمون دو جمله‌ای مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. بیشترین میزان انطباق، میان سبک نوآوری ‌بازارمحور و سبک مدیریت منابع انسانی بهره‌وری و پس از آن میان سبک نوآوری علم‌محور و سبک‌مدیریت منابع انسانی همکاری مشاهده شد. ویژگی ارزش‌آفرینی سرمایه انسانی در شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان دارای میانگین بالاتری نسبت به ویژگی منحصربه‌فردی بود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منحصر به فردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش راهبردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سبک نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سبک مدیریت منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هماهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل عاملی تاییدی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14844_050f4482bacd27960386681baec0bc9a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
