<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An investigation of the challenges of industry-university cooperation: A case of Tehran’s Power Distribution Company</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی چالش‌های همکاری دانشگاه-صنعت (مورد مطالعه: شرکت توزیع نیروی برق تهران بزرگ)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>89</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>106</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">91154</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مارال</FirstName>
					<LastName>مقدس نوده</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت تکنولوژی، گرایش تحقیق و توسعه، شرکت توزیع نیروی برق تهران بزرگ، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Although Industry-university cooperation has a long history, it has not a desirable status, in particular in under development and developing countries. In the literature, there are several studies focused on investigating the challenges of industry-university cooperation but there is a scant research to scrutinize the interrelationships among the challenges and “how to” solutions for overcoming them. Therefore, this paper has two contributions to fill in the literature gaps. First, it summarizes various variables and parameters influencing the industry-university cooperation in a conceptual framework. Second, this study proposes an integrative framework by using fuzzy Delphi method (FDM) anf interpretive structural modeling (ISM). In order to validate the proposed frameworks, they was employed in a real case study of Tehran’s Power Distribution Company. Findings show that the root challenge of the university-industry cooperation in power industry is the beurucratic processes of university-related projects in the company and it leads to other challenges such as low motivation of researchers to cooperation with industry. According to the experts of this study, the proposed framework is significantly useful in investigating the cause and effect, and structural hierarchical</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">همکاری دانشگاه و صنعت، اگرچه دارای سبقه‌ای طولانی است، همچنان، به‌ویژه در کشورهای در حال توسعه و توسعه‌نیافته، از وضعیت مطلوبی برخوردار نیست. در ادبیات پژوهش، مطالعات متعددی به بررسی چالش‌ها و مشکلات همکاری دانشگاه و صنعت پرداخت‌اند، با این حال، کمتر مطالعه‌ای به چشم می‌خورد که به تحلیل علی معلولی چالش‌های همکاری صنعت و دانشگاه پرداخته باشد. بدین منظور، در این پژوهش علاوه بر ارائه مدلی مفهومی به منظور جمع بندی نظرات قبلی در خصوص فرایند همکاری صنعت و دانشگاه، تحلیل ساختاری سلسله مراتبی از چالش‌های همکاری صنعت و دانشگاه با استفاده از روش‌های دلفی فازی و مدلسازی ساختاری تفسیری (ISM)، در مورد مطالعه شرکت توزیع نیروی برق تهران بزرگ، پیشنهاد گردید. نتایج تحقیق نشان می‌دهد، چالش ریشه‌ای و کلیدی در همکاری صنعت برق و دانشگاه، وجود فرایندهای بوروکراتیک و دیوانسالار است که منجر بروز چالش‌های دیگری از جمله کاهش انگیزه پژوهشگران به همکاری می‌گردد. بر اساس نظر خبرگان پژوهش، روش پیشنهادی در بررسی علی معلولی و ساختاری چالش‌ها می‌تواند تا حد قابل ملاحظه‌ای مثمر ثمر باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همکاری صنعت و دانشگاه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چالش ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش دلفی فازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدلسازی ساختاری تفسیری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_91154_c258620b66de8b702b8983d6f8275ba0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
