<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Presenting a Strategic Model of Organizational Performance Assessment based on a Logic Model</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائه الگوی راهبردی ارزیابی عملکرد سازمانی مبتنی بر الگوی منطق</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>71</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>100</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14628</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>زمانی‏ مزده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمودی‏ میمند</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدحسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمی‏ گوارشکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>سرور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Performance is compared to an umbrella that covers all the concepts important for the success and doing activities in an organization; that is why its evaluation is important. Several models have been proposed so far, yet a comprehensive model is lacking, which focuses on strategic goals, covers all key issues needed for managers, and has the ability to evaluate strategic innovation. The aim of this study is to present such a model based on a qualitative research. First, conceptual and philosophical analyses are performed; then, the most important features of an ideal model from the literature are extracted and classified into five general groups; after that, a strategic model for assessing the organizational performance with four layers (1. Input, 2. Process, 3.Output, 4.Outcomes) is designed by studying 30 models of performance evaluation and using a comparative analysis (in systemic perspective). Since the emphasis of the systemic perspective is on the coordination and communication of components, a logic model is used to highlight the integrity and hierarchical features of the model (4 layers). For validation purpose, first the structured method and a judgment based on knowledge and expertise is used, then the modified model is evaluated operationally in 21 strategic classes of organization. The questionnaires are distributed among 3 organizational groups in order to test the validity. The average scores of the questionnaire show the 78 percent acceptability by managers and experts in the whole organization.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">عملکرد به چتری تشبیه می‌شود، که تمامی مفاهیم حائز اهمیت برای دستیابی به موفقیت و انجام فعالیت‌ها در سازمان را پوشش می‌دهد؛ بنابراین ارزیابی آن از اهمیت ویژه‌‌ای برخوردار است. با وجود ارائه الگوهای مختلف، هنوز جای خالی الگویی جامع، متمرکز بر اهداف راهبردی، دارای قابلیت پوشش تمام موضوع‌های کلیدی مورد نظر مدیران و همچنین امکان ارزیابی نوآوری‏های راهبردی سازمان، احساس می‌شود. این پژوهش با هدف طراحی الگوی توصیف شده انجام شد. برای این منظور، ابتدا با تحلیل مفهومی و فلسفی، مهمترین ویژگی‏های یک الگوی مطلوب از مطالعات کتابخانه‌ای استخراج گردید و پس از طرح در گروه کانونی در قالب 5 ویژگی کلی دسته‌بندی شد. در ادامه با مطالعه 30 الگوی ارزیابی عملکرد  و با استفاده از روش تحلیل تطبیقی (در دیدگاه سیستمی) الگوی راهبردی ارزیابی عملکرد سازمانی با 4 لایه ورودی، فرایندها، خروجی و پیامدها طراحی گردید. با توجه به اینکه در دیدگاه سیستمی، تاکید بر هماهنگی و ارتباط بین اجزا است، الگوی منطق نیز برای پررنگ‌تر شدن بعد جامعیت و سلسله مراتبی بودن الگو مورد استفاده گرفت. برای اعتبارسنجی در مرحله اول، روش هدفمند و قضاوتی مبتنی بر شناخت و خبرگی استفاده شد. در مرحله دوم الگوی اصلاح شده در 21 رده راهبردی سازمان، ارزشیابی عملیاتی گردید. روایی سوال‌های پرسش‌نامه پس از پیاده‌سازی آزمایشی در 3 رده سازمانی بررسی و تایید شد. میانگین امتیازهای پرسش‌نامه، مقبولیت 78 درصدی مدیران و صاحب‌نظران را در کل سازمان به همراه داشت.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزیابی عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی منطق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انعطاف‌پذیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پایداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پویایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری راهبردی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14628_8e670b7cebf4a3690ef3780f1727e704.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
