<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Developing an assessment scale for Entrepreneurial Orientation of Public Research Institutions in Energy industry of Iran, and investigating its effect on performance by contingency approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ایجاد مقیاس ارزیابی گرایش کارآفرینانه در پژوهشگاه‌های دولتی صنعت انرژی ایران و بررسی تأثیر آن بر عملکرد با رویکرد اقتضایی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>143</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>168</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">44424</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>خان آقا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترا / گروه کارآفرینی فناورانه، دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>مبینی دهکردی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار، ‌گروه کارآفرینی فناورانه، دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>زالی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار،‌گروه کارآفرینی سازمانی، دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حجازی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه کارآفرینی فناورانه، دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This paper links two branches of Knowledge-based entrepreneurship (Academic &amp; Corporate entrepreneurship) by employing the widely-used construct of Entrepreneurial Orientation (EO) from corporate entrepreneurship literature, to indentify the favorable strategic posture for entrepreneurial activities within Public Research &amp; Technology Institutions (RTIs) in Energy Sector of Iran, and to investigate its effect of their performance indices. Due to context-dependent nature of EO construct, an exploratory sequential research design was utilized to first develop a new EO measurement scale in public RTIs and then, investigate its effect on performance indices of 15 research centers within these RTIs from universalistic and contingency perspectives (moderating effect of environmental and internal factors). The results indicated that the Entrepreneurial Orientation of research centers has a positive and substantial effect on their financial performance which is being moderated by environmental factors in a way that EO has the strongest relationship with financial performance under unfavorable environmental conditions.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این پژوهش با برقراری پیوند میان دو شاخه از کارآفرینی دانش‌بنیان (کارآفرینی شرکتی و کارآفرینی دانشگاهی)، از سازۀ گرایش کارآفرینانه متعلق به ادبیات کارآفرینی شرکتی، برای شناسایی وضعیت راهبردی مساعد کارآفرینی و آثار آن در پژوهشگاه‌های دولتی صنعت انرژی ایران بهره می‌گیرد. با توجه به وابستگی ابعاد تشکیل‌دهندۀ گرایش کارآفرینانه به زمینۀ سازمانی، با استفاده از روش تحقیق آمیخته ترتیبی اکتشافی، ابتدا مقیاس جدیدی برای سنجش گرایش کارآفرینانه در زمینۀ سازمانی جدید ایجاد شده و سپس تأثیر آن بر عملکرد مالی 15 پژوهشکده وابسته به این پژوهشگاه‌ها با رویکردی اقتضایی (تحت تأثیر عوامل محیطی و عوامل درون سازمانی) مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. نتایج نشان می‌دهند که گرایش کارآفرینانه پژوهشکده‌ها با عملکرد مالی آنها رابطۀ مثبت و قابل توجهی دارد که توسط عوامل محیطی تعدیل می‌شود، بطوری‌که بیشترین تأثیر گرایش کارآفرینانه بر عملکرد مالی در شرایط نامساعد محیطی بروز می‌کند. این پژوهش ضمن توسعۀ کاربرد سازۀ شناخته ‌شدۀ گرایش کارآفرینانه به یک حوزۀ سازمانی جدید، اشاره‌ های سیاستی قابل توجهی برای تقویت گرایش پژوهشگاه‌های دولتی به مشارکت در کارآفرینی دانشگاهی و دانش‌بنیان در بر دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی دانش‌بنیان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی دانشگاهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گرایش کارآفرینانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زمینۀ سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پژوهشگاه‌های دولتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایجاد مقیاس</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_44424_76031910719a27f8b760a0fd9b5f0504.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
