<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Policy Learning in Iran&#039;s Technology and Innovation Development 
(The Study of Third, Fourth and Fifth Development Plan regulations)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>یادگیری سیاستی در سیاستهای توسعه فناوری و نوآوری ایران (مطالعه قوانین برنامه سوم، چهارم و پنجم توسعه)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>30</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60171</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کیارش</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرتاش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>الیاسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید سروش</FirstName>
					<LastName>قاضی نوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>سازماناستادیار، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید حبیب ا...</FirstName>
					<LastName>طباطبائیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده حسابداری و مدیریت دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Over the time, policy change and learning play a significant role in national decision making and improving transparency of policy situations. On this basis, current paper has concentrated on Iran&#039;s national development plans, as the major national mid-term developmental policies, to investigate policy learning and its mechanisms in the most crucial policy attempts to develop technology and innovation (T&amp;I). Analyzing five past development plans led to selection of third to fifth plans, which have more coherent and integrated approach to T&amp;I development by including a dedicated section in this regard, as suitable case studies for this paper. After content analysis of relevant policy documents in addition to conducting eighteen interviews with key policy actors of development planning process related to T&amp;I articles, sixteen major policy issues were extracted in which direct implications are apparent in at least two investigated plans. Dominant share of policy learning belongs to political and technical learning with eight and seven frequencies respectively. Dominancy of political learning, as the most irrelevant type of policy learning, reflects low maturity of learning in T&amp;I policy actors in Iran. Furthermore, this indicates superficial commitment of high level politicians to the most fundamental T&amp;I policy objectives, which haven&#039;t fulfilled yet without any sign of sufficient attempts to meet defined objectives. Technical and conceptual learning (with seven and five occurrences) refer to relatively successful policy endeavours that are being tried to be improved or continued, usually by low and mid-level policy actors. Two key cases of identified social learning unveil effective role of public media and policy experts to widen and strengthen the discourse on innovation and knowledge-based development. Resulted social learning has brought mentioned discourse to the attention and commitments of high level politicians. Our findings contribute to more detailed recognition of Iran&#039;s T&amp;I policy environment in the past two decades as well as decision making in near future.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقاله حاضر با هدف بررسی یادگیری سیاستی و سازوکار‌های آن در عمده‌ترین تلاش‌های سیاست‌گذاری فناوری و نوآوری ایران، بر برنامه‌های توسعه به عنوان مهم‌ترین سیاست‌های توسعه‌ای میان مدت کشور تمرکز نموده است. با بررسی 5 برنامه‌ توسعه اخیر، برنامه‌های سوم تا پنجم توسعه که دارای نگاهی منسجم‌تر و یکپارچه در قالب یک فصل مجزا به توسعه فناوری و نوآوری هستند به عنوان سه قانون منتخب مورد مطالعه قرار گرفت. پس از بررسی و تحلیل محتوای اسناد سیاستی و مصاحبه با 18 نفر از بازیگران اصلی این فرآیند، 16 مقوله محوری در توسعه فناوری و نوآوری استخراج گردید. سهم غالب یادگیری سیاستی در این 16 مقوله به یادگیری سیاسی و فنی به ترتیب با 8 و 7 تکرار اختصاص یافته است. این سهم بالای یادگیری سیاسی به عنوان نازل‌ترین نوع یادگیری، نشان از بلوغ پایین یادگیری در بدنه سیاست‌گذاری فناوری و نوآوری کشور است. یادگیری فنی و مفهومی (با 7 و 5 وقوع) نشان از تلاش‌های نسبتاً موفق سیاستی است که عموماً بازیگران سیاستی سطح پایین و میانی درصدد بهبود و استمرار روند موفقیت‌های گذشته هستند نتایج این پژوهش می‌تواند در شناخت دقیق‌تر فضای سیاستی توسعه فناوری و نوآوری در دو دهه گذشته و تجارب آتی مفید باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">یادگیری سیاستی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">یادگیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قانون برنامه توسعه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاستهای توسعه فناوری و نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60171_04c1aeac65a26c5420e2c7af5d324c0a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
