<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Fitness of Product Innovation Level and Brand Change: A Survey on Customers of Cleaning and Hygiene Products</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تناسب سطح نوآوری در محصول با میزان تغییر در علامت تجاری: پیمایشی از مشتریان محصولات شوینده و بهداشتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>87</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>108</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60173</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جلیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>غریبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ندا</FirstName>
					<LastName>ناظمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات شاهرود، شاهرود، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Selecting a proper attitude for choosing a trademark is an important factor in succeeding new products. The purpose of this study is to answer this question: What are the costumer&#039;s criteria for choosing new products according to its trademark? In this paper, comments of 385 costumers of washing and hygienic products who usually go to shopping stores of Tehran gathered based on the metrical attitude. Results show that primary acceptors prefer the substantial technical innovations with new trademarks and current products with current trademarks. But about the more gradual innovations (having minor differences with older products), they do not demonstrate a unique pattern. But about other acceptors, current products with their present trademarks are more rational. They also accept the gradual innovation with both introducing new trademarks and current trademarks. But about more substantial innovations, there are rather dispersed patterns around two opposite options of current trademarks and the new one. In this paper, the reasons for these patterns that are concluded from collecting qualitative date and also somewhat could help explain the existing causes of these patterns.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">انتخاب رویکرد مناسب برای علامت تجاری عاملی مهم در تعیین موفقیت محصولات جدید است. هدف از پژوهش حاضر پاسخ به این سوال است که الگوی مشتریان برای انتخاب محصولات نوآورانه با توجه به علامت تجاری همراه با این محصولات چیست؟ در این مقاله با اتکا بر رویکرد پیمایشی ، نظرات 385 نفر از مشتریانِ مراجعه کننده به فروشگاه‌های بزرگ شهر تهران در خصوص خرید و استفاده از مواد شوینده و بهداشتی جمع‌آوری شد. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که پذیرندگان اولیه، نوآوری‌های فنی جهشی‌تر (حاوی تفاوت اساسی با محصولات قبلی) را به‌همراه علائم تجاری جدید و محصولات فعلی را به‌همراه علامت تجاری فعلی می‌پذیرند اما در خصوص نوآوری‌های تدریجی‌تر (حاوی تفاوت جزئی با محصولات قبلی)، الگوی یکسانی را نشان نمی‌دهند. در حالیکه برای سایر پذیرندگان، محصولات فعلی که به‌همراه علامت تجاری فعلی عرضه می‌شوند منطقی‌تر به نظر می‌رسند، نوآوری‌های تدریجی‌تر را نیز معمولا با توسعه علامت تجاری شناخته و قبول می‌کنند اما در خصوص نوآوری‌های جهشی‌تر الگوی نسبتا پراکنده‌ای حول دو انتخاب متضاد علامت تجاری فعلی و علامت تجاری جدید نشان می‌دهند. در این مقاله دلایل این الگوها که از جمع‌آوری داده‌های کیفی حاصل شده است نیز تا حدودی توانسته به تبیین علل بوجود آمدن این الگوها کمک کند</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری محصول</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری جهشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری تدریجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">علامت تجاری جدید</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توسعه علامت تجاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پذیرندگان اولیه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60173_3d463691029462a5d93a813e65a72ac6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
