<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Analysis of Photovoltaic Solar System Technological Innovation System in Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">zohreh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">rahimi rad</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Mazandaran
Department of Business Economics</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mahmood</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">yahyazade far</namePart>
				<affiliation>mazandaran university</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Tahere</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mir emadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>IROST</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mehrdad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">madhoshi</namePart>
				<affiliation>mazandaran university</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This study aims to analyze the historical development of photovoltaic Technological Innovation System (TIS) functions in Iran and extraction of innovation Engine in each step. Origin of TIS framework roots in developed countries, while developing countries generally receive technology, so function indicators such as knowledge creation will be different in each country. In this paper, this framework is divided into R&amp;D-based TIS and diffusion-based TIS and also due to the nature of technological innovation system in Iran which is based on the imports of equipments and then assembling, the concepts of diffusion-based TIS are investigated. To this end, after introducing the structural components of photovoltaic solar system in Iran, conducting expert interviews, analysis of documents and historical data analysis method, the innovation Engine was identified at each stage of development, and finally the innovation Engine in the current stage was examined by designing a questionnaire and validated using structural equation modelling.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>28</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_70595_32425e6bf97d862902b2c5352f6f8d57.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Modeling and Policymaking the Techno-Sectoral Innovation System in Petrochemical Industry using System Dynamics</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sayyed Mohsen</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azad</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Candidate, Industrial Engineering &amp;amp; Management Systems Department, Amirkabir university of technology, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghodsipour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor, Industrial Engineering &amp;amp;amp; Management Systems Department, Amirkabir Universitiy of technology, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Science and technology policymaking refers to policies that facilitate technology progress to the market phase, reaching idea to wealth and technology exploitation. The execution of science and technology development policies in every country has an effective role in increasing entrepreneurship and GDP by reinforcing knowledge-based companies and research institutes. Current paper focuses on innovation systems of petrochemical industry approaches as one of the important pillars of science and technology policymaking. Identifying system dynamics is used to model the techno-sectoral innovation system of petrochemical industry. Trend of motivation motors of petrochemicals based on technology motors is analyzed by causal loops of system dynamics. Also, system dynamics present a model for science and technology policymaking. The results, based on validated proposed model, show the acceptable performance of all innovation system functions (more than 85%). Then, 4 scenarios have been proposed to give each technology, a reward by industry. Finally the results of scenario analysis show that the industry should allocate its rewards to each technology based on their performance in a tuneable way in order to increase industry profits</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>29</start>
					<end>62</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_70594_4c9722a7ec1d92ce52b3ee5f1dee011d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Presenting a Framework for Describing the Technological Transitions Based on the Multilevel Analysis Approach 
(Case Study: The Transition to Renewable Energy in Iran)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Moslem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mousavi Dorcheh</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD student Scientific Policy Research Center, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Amin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">GhaneiRad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty of national Research Institute  for Science Policy, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Karimian Khouzani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Expert, Strategic Assessment and Control, MAPNA Group, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Behrouz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shahmoradi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty member of research institute for science and technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>It is necessary to take new and acceptable policies to develop renewable energy sources and finitude of fossil fuels in Iran. To do so, it is vital to identify and address technological changes. Also, to take advantage from concepts of technological transition literature, we understood that by changing only the technology it is not possible to change technological transition, but it needs some changes in society, acts, industry and economy. The synchronously analysis of all these changes in a social context is called technological transition. Therefore, it is necessary to identify the type of changes before any policymaking in order to take adequate policies for making transition path. Typology of changes is called paths of technological transition. In current research authors tried to identify and investigate the paths of technological transition by assessing the factors for allocating paths. The results indicate that in 4 stages of renewable energy transition in Iran, the transition path in stage 2 and stage 3 are in type of layering while in stage 4 it is changing from layering type to replacing technological path.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>63</start>
					<end>98</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_70599_65b602c49da81e1cbc639e38e79dd39f.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Application of TRIZ Methodology to Detect and prioritize Problems among Iranian Triple Helix Actors using (Case study: at Nanotechnology Sector)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">hamidreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">zarghami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Shahid Sattari Aeronautical University of Science &amp;amp; Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mostafa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">jafari</namePart>
				<affiliation>school of industrial engineering, iran university of science &amp;amp; technology, tehran, iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Peyman</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Akhavan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Iran University of Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The University-industry-government (UIG) interaction is now seen as the nucleus of innovation at the national level. Considering the importance of the nanotechnology in research and attention paid to the upstream documents of the country in this domain, the current study by exploiting the innovative capability of modelling complex social problems in TRIZ methodology, has analyzed the contradictions between interactions of the three pillars in the process of nanotechnology innovation. The research method is qualitative and explanatory; research data were gathered using field observation tools, study documents and conducting interviews with key experts, and the main research strategy was a multidimensional type. The data analyzed using thick description approach based on TRIZ methodology. Thirty seven normal and sixty three innovative issues were identified in current research. Innovative issues were modeled into ninety four physical contradictions (PC) and hundred and thirty technical contradictions (TC). Finally, the study used TRIZ for the explanation of the issues/problems and contradiction among TH actors, for the first time. As this study used an in-depth approach for this purpose, the results shed lighted on many ways for further theoretical and applied studies in the TRIZ and science, technology and innovation (STI) policy fields of study.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>99</start>
					<end>136</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_70598_7d38031cad1d5488e62f734cf259c648.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identification and Prioritization of Commercialization Services needed for Technology Units Located at Science and Technology Park of University of Tehran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hashem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aghazadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Rahim</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Esfidani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Meysam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University Of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">hosein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">zadbar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Expert of Commercialization Department of Science and Technology Park of University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Science and technology parks are designed to facilitate the development of technology and commercialization of new technology based products and services. The present study aimed at identifying the commercialization services of science and technology parks and prioritizing these services based on the actual needs of the established companies. This applied research was carried out at the University of Tehran’s Science and Technology Park with the help of 227 employees of 93 companies based in aforementioned park and also the park’s commercialization staff. The data gathering method were using questionnaire tool and conducting interview. Categorizing commercialization services using exploratory factor analysis led to identification of 10 factors. Subsequently, these categories and services were ranked by grading weighting analysis (SWARA) method. The results showed that services: marketing, financing and investment, contracts and guarantees, training and counselling respectively, have the highest priority for companies based in Tehran University of Science and Technology Park; therefore providing such services can be helpful in their success and development.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>137</start>
					<end>161</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_70596_fa82dbcbe0f85c228a183594c1ca9d5e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Effective Factors on Technology Sourcing Method: Case Study on Strain Technology at Cinnagen Company</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amir</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Albadvi</namePart>
				<affiliation>School of Industrial and Systems Engineering, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sajjad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shekarchian</namePart>
				<affiliation>School of Industrial and Systems Engineering, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Technology sourcing method is one of the most important issues in corporate strategic management which over the past few years has increasingly received attention among researchers. However, these studies do not suffice yet, so it is necessary to conduct more research on identification of effective factors in technology sourcing in Iran. Also, it is necessary to identify and investigate all the factors specifically in each industry.This qualitative research tries to identify factors influencing the choice of technology sourcing method by studying one of the successful Iranian bio-pharmaceutical firms. Research data is collected through conducting interviews with Cinnagen Company and Pasteur Institute staffs and biotechnology policy makers and also investigating archival resources; then the gathered data analyzed using the grounded theory method. The identified factors affecting the strain technology sourcing method are “time to market”, “need to confirm”, “extent of the existence of strain generation infrastructure in the country”, “fear of technological sanctions” and “technological capabilities of the firm” which some assumptions for influencing methods of each factor were developed. In addition, “features of biopharmaceutical industry” is identified as a contextual factor.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>162</start>
					<end>192</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_70597_9f9f8cdc81db85ade755b7c2b79028df.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>