<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying the policies for improving the knowledge absorption  capacity and their effects on organizational performance : A System Dynamics Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی سیاستهای بهبود ظرفیت جذب دانش و تاثیر آنها بر عملکرد سازمانی با رویکرد پویایی شناسی سیستم</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>143</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>168</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">88596</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>جهانیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی گروه مدیریت، دانشکده علوم اداری واقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فائزه</FirstName>
					<LastName>امینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مدیریت، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>شائمی برزکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مدیریت، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this research is to investigate the policies which are most effective on the knowledge absorption capacity and then their effects on organizational performance. In this study we use Balanced Score Card(BSC) as our performance measurement structure. In order to be able to measure the effects of each policy and also their combinations, A system dynamics methodology is applied through which the main variables of the system and its boundaries are identifies. After testing all sections of the model and also the whole model through various validity tests, three separate policies including increased training hours, the competency of interviewers and increased proportion of retired employees been interviewed are performed by a simulation tool by which a stock &amp; Flow model is made during the modeling process. According to the results the best policy for improving absorptive knowledge capacity and hence the organizational performance is a combination of all above mentioned policies. This study leads to a kind of decision support system through which managers in different levels would be able to simulate their potentially effective policies to see if they are actually effective on organizational performance or not. This study is a novel research which combines system dynamics with BSC in the field of knowledge absorption capacity in the organization.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از این پژوهش شناسایی سیاستهای تاثیرگذار بر بهبود ظرفیت جذب دانش در سازمان و سنجش میزان تاثیر آنها بر عملکرد سازمان می باشد. به این منظور با استفاده از روش شناسی پویایی شناسی سیستمها ابتدا متغیرهای مربوطه شناسایی شده و سپس با ساخت مدل حالت-جریان امکان شبیه سازی سیستم برقرار می شود. پژوهش حاضر یک طرح کاربردی برای نظام تصمیم گیری سازمان فراهم می کند که سطح دانش کسب شده، دانش منتشر شده، دانش مورد استفاده و بخشی از دانشی که از سازمان خارج میشود را در گذر زمان اندازه گیری می کند. طبق نتایج مدل حاضر، بهترین سیاست برای افزایش سطح دانش مورد استفاده در سازمان ،ترکیب سه سیاست افزایش ساعات آموزش، آموزش و متخصص کردن مصاحبه کنندگان و افزایش درصد مصاحبه شوندگان بازنشسته است که میتواند سطح دانش مورد استفاده را در حالت بهینه نگه دار. این پژوهش با شبیه سازی سیستم مدیریت دانش سازمان یک سیستم پشتیبان تصمیم گیری در زمینه مدیریت دانش ارائه کرده است به گونه ای که با اعمال سیاستهای مختلف در این سیستم و مقایسه آثار آن بهترین سیاست اتخاذ می گردد. پژوهش حاضر منجر به تولید ابزاری برای نظام تصمیم گیری سازمان شده است که سطح دانش کسب شده، دانش منتشر شده، دانش مورد استفاده و دانشی که از سازمان خارج می شود را در گذر زمان اندازه گیری می کند</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ظرفیت جذب دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارت امتیازی متوازن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پویایی شناسی سیستم</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_88596_15e1cc4847f929a0801ee2f4611c7a6e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
