<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Comparative Study of Development Strategies in A High Tech Industry Through Text Mining of Policy Documents</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مطالعه تطبیقی مسائل و گزینه‌های راهبردی در صنعت هوافضا‌ با استفاده از متن‌کاوی اسناد سیاستی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>57</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>90</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">81031</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>تلافی داریانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدمحمدحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>شجاعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5074-8947</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید امین</FirstName>
					<LastName>طاهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present study seeks to apply Lesson drawing process for analyzing aerospace industry (AI) policies in nine regions/countries and learning from them. This analysis has been carried out by applying the methodology of text mining to policy documents of AI and the two related policy areas, i.e. science, technology and innovation, and defense. The study comprises the regions/countries of the EU,UK,USA,Brazil,Turkey,the Zionist regime,Russia,Japan-Korea,and India-Pakistan. After analyzing the frequency of words, drawing the co-occurrence network of words and clustering this network for all policy documents, the co-occurrence networks for each of the nine countries/regions are separately mapped and analyzed; then the most important policy points are extracted. Finally, the most important lessons learned for AI policy Analysis in the Islamic Republic of Iran are presented. Orientation towards applied research and application of researches; the interaction of government, industry and universities; the integration of policies and programs; the application of science and technology diplomacy capacities; the optimal use of resources; accurate planning for future innovations and technologies; the development of training programs;special attention to space observation services; the creation of aerospace clusters and the use of regional capacities; the diversification of financing sources; the localization of products and systems in developing countries; and a systematic approach to science,Technology and Innovation policy are lessons learned from the analyzed policy documents in this study.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تحقیق حاضر در پی به‌کارگیری فرایند درس‌آموزی برای تحلیل سیاست‌های توسعه صنعت هوافضا در نه منطقه جهان و یادگیری از آن‌ها است. این تحلیل با به‌کارگیری روش متن‌کاوی روی اسناد سیاستی صنعت هوافضا و دو زیرحوزه سیاستی مرتبط یعنی علم، فناوری و نوآوری و دفاع انجام شده است و قلمرو آن مناطق اتحادیه اروپا، انگلستان، امریکا، برزیل، ترکیه، رژیم صهیونیستی، روسیه، ژاپن-کره جنوبی، و هند- پاکستان بوده است. پس از تحلیل فراوانی واژه‌ها، ترسیم شبکه هم‌رخدادی کلمات و خوشه‌بندی این شبکه برای مجموع اسناد سیاستی گردآوری‌شده، شبکه‌های هم‌رخدادی برای هریک از مناطق نه‌گانه به‌طور مجزا ترسیم و تحلیل شده‌اند و مهم‌ترین نکات سیاستی استخراج شده است. در نهایت مهم‌ترین درس‌آموخته‌ها برای سیاست‌گذاری در صنعت هوافضای جمهوری اسلامی ایران ارائه شده است. جهت‌گیری به سمت تحقیقات کاربردی و کاربردی کردن تحقیقات؛ ارتباط دولت، صنعت و دانشگاه؛ یکپارچه‌سازی سیاست‌ها و برنامه‌ها؛ استفاده از ظرفیت‌های دیپلماسی علم و فناوری؛ استفاده بهینه از منابع؛ برنامه‌ریزی دقیق و زمان‌مند برای نوآوری‌ها و فناوری‌های آینده؛ توسعه برنامه‌های مهارت‌آموزی؛ توجه ویژه و فراگیر به کاربردها و خدمات مشاهده زمین؛ ایجاد خوشه‌های تخصصی هوافضا و استفاده از ظرفیت‌های مناطق؛ تنوع‌بخشی به منابع تأمین مالی؛ تلاش برای بومی‌سازی محصولات و سامانه‌های هوافضا در کشورهای در حال توسعه؛ و نگاه سیستمی به سیاست‌گذاری علم، فناوری و نوآوری درس‌هایی هستند که از اسناد سیاستی تحلیل‌شده در این تحقیق می‌توان آموخت.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل سیاست</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">درس‌آموزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">متن‌کاوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل هم‌واژگانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صنعت هوافضا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81031_397c415428d80057dde22db05bb6e790.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
