<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Technology Transfer Challenges in Iran&#039;s International Commercial Contracts based on a thematic Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رویکردی زمینه محور به چالش های انتقال فناوری در قراردادهای بین المللی تجاری در ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>19</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">57421</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>نقی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>امینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سارا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract> Technology is one of the main determinants of international trade. Firms try to acquire beneficial technologies through different ways. One of these ways, regarded by active firms in developing countries, is technology transfer. However, many technology transfer projects have confronted with different serious challenges toward their knowledge goals realization. This research tries to identify and explain these technology transfer challenges in Iran&#039;s important commercial contracts with a thematic analysis approach. regarding the importance of deep understanding of aforementioned  challenges and its dependence on the analyzed field, we used thematic analysis in order to analyze deep interviews of 10 industrial and scientific experts . After coding the results,  18 challenges have been classified into four main groups. The necessity of having comprehensive approach to different aspects of technology transfer and considering the special context and circumstance of Iran are some of the main results. As well, unwillingness to technology transfer due to economic, political, and project based reasons related to the factor of technology transferor factor, low absorptive capacity of Iranian firms related to technology transferee factor, lack of economic sustainability related to context factor and finally different nature of technologies related to content factor were introduced as the main challenges of technology transfer in important commercial projects in Iran. </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">فناوری عاملی کلیدی در تجارت بین­المللی است. بنگاه­های اقتصادی تلاش می­کنند تا از طرق مختلف به فناوری­های مزیت­ساز دست یابند. یکی از راه های مورد توجه شرکت­های فعال در کشورهای درحال توسعه، انتقال فناوری است. بسیاری از پروژه­های انتقال فناوری در جهت تحقق اهداف دانشی مدنظر خود با چالش­های جدی مواجه هستند. این پژوهش تلاش دارد تا با رویکردی زمینه­محور به شناسایی و تبیین چالش­های انتقال فناوری در قراردادهای بزرگ تجاری ایران بپردازد. با توجه به اهمیت درک عمیق چالش­های مذکور و وابستگی آن به بستر و زمینه مورد تحلیل، از روش تحلیل تم به­منظور آنالیز مصاحبه­های عمیق  صورت گرفته با 10 نفر از خبرگان صنعتی و علمی استفاده شد. پس از کدگذاری یافته­های پژوهش 18 چالش در قالب چهار گروه اصلی طبقه­بندی گردیدند. لزوم نگاه جامع به همه ابعاد موثر بر انتقال فناوری و همچنین توجه ویژه به بستر و محیط ایران بخشی از یافته­های اصلی پژوهش بودند. در بعد واگذارنده فناوری، عدم تمایل به دلایل اقتصادی، سیاسی و پروژه­ای، در بعد گیرنده فناوری، ظرفیت جذب پایین شرکت های ایرانی، در بعد محیط و فرآیند انتقال، عدم ثبات اقتصادی و در بعد محتوای مورد انتقال، ماهیت متفاوت فناوری­ها بخشی از مهمترین چالش­های انتقال فناوری در پروژه­های بزرگ تجاری بودند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انتقال فناوری بین المللی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قراردادهای تجاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ظرفیت جذب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویکرد زمینه محور</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_57421_87978100349a7bae44e798dcc7272770.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
