<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" "journalpublishing3.dtd">
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_61839_b5ef8b178282022a6a1a0b9bb4b2e150.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>چارچوب تحلیلی زیست‌بوم همکاری‌های فناورانه بین شرکت‌های بزرگ و شرکت‌های کوچک فناوری‌محور</article-title>
			        <subtitle>چارچوب تحلیلی زیست‌بوم همکاری‌های فناورانه بین شرکت‌های بزرگ و شرکت‌های کوچک فناوری‌محور</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>الهی</surname>
			            <given-names>شعبان</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>خالدی</surname>
			            <given-names>آرمان</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری سیاستگذاری علم و فناوری دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مجیدپور</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>هیات علمی دانشکده مدیریت، علم و فناوری، دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>اسدی فرد</surname>
			            <given-names>رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیات علمی پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2018</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>1</fpage>
			      <lpage>32</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>01</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>17</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_61839.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_61839.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>با توجه به رقابتی شدن محیط کسب‌وکار در طی چند دهه‌ اخیر،شرکت‌های بزرگ با وجود دسترسی به منابع مالی و کانال‌های توزیع با دیوان‌سالاری، لَختی و عدم انعطاف‌پذیری روبرو هستند، در مقابل شرکت‌های کوچک فناوری‌محور با وجود انعطاف‌پذیری و توانمندی نوآوری بالا با کمبود منابع و عدم دسترسی به بازار روبرو هستند.بنابراین هر دو دسته شرکت‌های فوق برای حفظ موقعیت خود در فضای رقابتی و ادامه حیات نیاز دارند که با همدیگر همکاری کنند.با این حال همکاری فناورانه بین شرکت‌ها موضوعی پیچیده است که بررسی جامع آن نیازمند نگرشی نظام‌مند و کل‌نگر است.در این راستا میتوان از رویکرد اکوسیستمی برای تحلیل و تبیین فرآیند همکاری فناورانه بین دو دسته شرکت‌های مذکور استفاده کرد.به همین منظور در راستای تدوین چارچوب مناسب برای تحلیل اکوسیستم همکاری فناورانه از روش مرور نظام‌مند استفاده و با جستجو در پایگاه‌های معتبر تعداد 605 سند استخراج شد که پس از بررسی‌های لازم 63 مورد از آن‌ها به‌عنوان اسناد مرتبط و معتبر شناسایی و در ادامه نیز با استفاده از روش فراترکیب، اسناد منتخب بررسی و کدگذاری شدند.در نهایت کدهای استخراج شده در ذیل 5 مقوله قرار گرفتند که یک مقوله در مورد ویژگی‌های اکوسیستم بود و 4 مورد دیگر به مقوله‌هایی اشاره داشتند که در تحلیل اکوسیستم باید به آن‌ها توجه شود این مقوله‌ها عبارتند: چرخه عمر، ابعاد تحلیل، نقش‌ها و نهادهای حاضر در اکوسیستم همکاری فناورانه.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>زیست‌بوم</kwd>
						<kwd>همکاری فناورانه</kwd>
						<kwd>مرور نظامند</kwd>
						<kwd>فراترکیب</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Adner, R. 2006. Match your innovation strategy to your innovation ecosystem. Harvard business review, 84(4), pp. 98-107.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Adner, R. 2017. Ecosystem as Structure An Actionable Construct for Strategy. Journal of Management, Volume (43), pp. 39-58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Adner, R. &amp; Kapoor, R. 2010.Value creation in innovation ecosystems: How the structure of technological interdependence affects firm performance in new technology generations. Strategic Management Journal, Volume (31), pp. 306-333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Ahmad, N. &amp; Hoffmann, A. 2008. A framework for addressing and measuring entrepreneurship.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Arruda, C. Nogueira, V. S. &amp; Costa, V. 2013. The Brazilian entrepreneurial ecosystem of startups: An analysis of entrepreneurship determinants in Brazil as seen from the OECD pillars. Journal of Entrepreneurship and Innovation Management, Volume (2), pp. 17-57.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Bannerjee, S. Bielli, S. &amp; Haley, C. 2016. Scaling together: Overcoming barriers in corporate-stratup collaboration. London: Nesta.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Barge-Gil, A. 2010.  Cooperation-based innovators and peripheral cooperators: An empirical analysis of their characteristics and behavior. Technovation, Volume (30), pp. 195-206.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Basu, S. Phelps, C. &amp; Kotha, S. 2011. Towards understanding who makes corporate venture capital investments and why. Journal of Business Venturing, Volume (26), pp. 153-171.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Battistella, C. Colucci, K. De Toni, A. F. &amp; Nonino, F. 2013. Methodology of business ecosystems network analysis: A case study in Telecom Italia Future Centre. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Volume (80), pp. 1194-1210.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Bazi, H. R. &amp; Hasanzadeh, A. R. 2017. Proposal the novel cloud computing adoption framework using Meta synthesis approach. Journal of Information Processing and Management, 2(33), pp. 547-584</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Bench, S. &amp; Day, T. 2010. The user experience of critical care discharge: a meta-synthesis of qualitative research. International journal of nursing studies, Volume (47), pp. 487-499.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Berger, E. S. &amp; Kuckertz, A. 2016. Female entrepreneurship in startup ecosystems worldwide. Journal of Business Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Body, J. &amp; Habbal, F. 2016. The Innovation Ecosystem. Creating Innovation Leaders. Springer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Bosch-Sijtsema, P. M. &amp; Bosch, J. Aligning innovation ecosystem strategies with internal R&amp;D. Management of Innovation and Technology (ICMIT), 2014 IEEE International Conference on, 2014. IEEE, pp. 424-430.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Büyüközkan, G. &amp; Arsenyan, J. 2012. Collaborative product development: a literature overview. Production Planning &amp; Control, Volume (23), pp. 47-66.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Carayannis, E. G. &amp; Campbell, D. F. 2009. 'Mode 3'and'Quadruple Helix': toward a 21st century fractal innovation ecosystem. International Journal of Technology Management, Volume (46), pp. 201-234.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Casals, F. E. The SME Co-operation Framework, a Multi-method Secondary Research Approach to SME Collaboration. 2010 International Conference on E-business, Management and Economics. IPEDR, 2011.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Chaharbaghi, K. Adcroft, A. Willis, R. Todeva, E. &amp; Knoke, D. 2005. Strategic alliances and models of collaboration. Management Decision, Volume (43), pp. 123-148.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, D. &amp; Karami, A. 2010. Critical success factors for inter-firm technological cooperation: an empirical study of high-tech SMEs in China. International Journal of Technology Management, Volume (51), 282-299.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, J. Liu, X. &amp; Hu, Y. 2016. Establishing a CoPs-based innovation ecosystem to enhance competence-the case of CGN in China. International Journal of Technology Management, Volume (72), pp. 144-170.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H. W. 2006. Open innovation: The new imperative for creating and profiting from technology, Harvard Business Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Christensen, J. L. Schibany, A. &amp; Vinding, A. L. 2001. Collaboration between manufacturing firms and knowledge institutions on product development: evidence from harmonised surveys in Australia, Austria, Denmark, Norway and Spain. Innovative Networks, Co-Operation in National Innovation Systems, pp. 253-278.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Clarysse, B. Wright, M. Bruneel, J. &amp; Mahajan, A. 2014. Creating value in ecosystems: Crossing the chasm between knowledge and business ecosystems. Research Policy, Volume (43), pp. 1164-1176.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Clegg, B. Minshall, T. Mortara, L. Elia, S. &amp; Probert, D. 2008. Development of practitioner guidelines for partnerships between start-ups and large firms. Journal of Manufacturing Technology Management, Volume (19), pp. 391-406.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Cohen, W. M. &amp; Levinthal, D. A. 1990. Absorptive capacity: A new perspective on learning and innovation. Administrative science quarterly, pp. 128-152.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Comi, A. &amp; Eppler, M. J. 2009. Building and managing strategic alliances in technology-driven start-ups. Università della Svizzera italiana.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Crossan, M. M. &amp; Apaydin, M. 2010. A multi‐dimensional framework of organizational innovation: A systematic review of the literature. Journal of management studies, Volume (47), pp. 1154-1191.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>D'auria, A. Tregua, M. Spena, T. R. &amp; Bifulco, F. 2016. Exploring innovation contexts: system, network and ecosystem innovation. International Journal of Management and Enterprise Development, Volume (15), pp. 127-146.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>De Vasconcelos Gomes, L. A. Facin, A. L. F. Salerno, M. S. &amp; Ikenami, R. K. 2016. Unpacking the innovation ecosystem construct: Evolution, gaps and trends. Technological Forecasting and Social Change.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Dedehayir, O. Mäkinen, S. J. &amp; Ortt, J. R. 2016. Roles during innovation ecosystem genesis: A literature review. Technological Forecasting and Social Change.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Dodgson, M. 1992. Technological collaboration: problems and pitfalls. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, Volume (4), pp. 83-88.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Donnelly, J. P. 2017. A systematic review of concept mapping dissertations. Evaluation and Program Planning, Volume (60), pp. 186-193.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Drexler, M. Eltogby, M. &amp; Foster, G. Entrepreneurial ecosystems around the globe and early-stage company growth dynamics. Geneva: World Economic Forum, 2014.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Dushnitsky, G. &amp; Lenox, M. J. 2005. When do incumbents learn from entrepreneurial ventures? Corporate venture capital and investing firm innovation rates. Research Policy, Volume (34), pp. 615-639.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K. M. &amp; Schoonhoven, C. B. 1996. Resource-based view of strategic alliance formation: Strategic and social effects in entrepreneurial firms. organization Science, Volume (7), pp. 136-150.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Feld, B. 2012. Startup communities: Building an entrepreneurial ecosystem in your city, John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Foster, G. Shimizu, C. Ciesinski, S. Davila, A. Hassan, S. Jia, N. &amp; Morris, R. Entrepreneurial ecosystems around the globe and company growth dynamics. World Economic Forum, 2013.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Franco, M. 2011. Determining factors in the success of strategic alliances: an empirical study performed in Portuguese firms. European Journal of International Management, 5, pp. 608-632.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Freeman, C. 1995. The ‘National System of Innovation’in historical perspective. Cambridge Journal of economics, Volume (19), pp. 5-24.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Frenkel, A. Maital, S. Leck, E. &amp; Israel, E. 2015. Demand-driven innovation: An integrative systems-based review of the literature. International Journal of Innovation and Technology Management, Volume (12), 1550008.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Fuerlinger, G. Fandl, U. &amp; Funke, T. 2015. The role of the state in the entrepreneurship ecosystem: insights from Germany. Triple Helix, 2(1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Garnsey, E. &amp; Leong, Y. Y. 2008. Combining resource based and evolutionary theory to explain the genesis of bionetworks. Industry and Innovation, Volume (15), pp. 669-686.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Gebauer, A. Nam, C. W. &amp; Parsche, R. 2005. Regional technology policy and factors shaping local innovation networks in small German cities 1. European Planning Studies, Volume (13), pp. 661-683.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Gnyawali, D. R. &amp; Fogel, D. S. 1994. Environments for entrepreneurship development: key dimensions and research implications. Entrepreneurship theory and practice, Volume (18), pp. 43-43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Hagedoorn , J. 1993. Understanding the rationale of strategic technology partnering: Nterorganizational modes of cooperation and sectoral differences. Strategic management journal, Volume (14), pp. 371-385.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Hagedoorn, J. 2002. Inter-firm R&amp;D partnerships: an overview of major trends and patterns since 1960. Research policy, Volume (31), pp. 477-492.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Hargadon, A. &amp; Sutton, R. I. 1997. Technology brokering and innovation in a product development firm. Administrative science quarterly, pp. 716-749.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Hartigh, E. D. &amp; Asseldonk, T. V. Business ecosystems: A research framework for investigating the relation between network structure, firm strategy, and the pattern of innovation diffusion. ECCON 2004 Annual Meeting, 2004.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Heimeriks, K. H. Bingham, C. B. &amp; Laamanen, T. 2015. Unveiling the temporally contingent role of codification in alliance success. Strategic Management Journal, Volume (36), pp. 462-473.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Hoffmann, W. H. &amp; Schlosser, R. 2001. Success factors of strategic alliances in small and medium-sized enterprises—An empirical survey. Long range planning, Volume (34), pp. 381-357.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Hogenhuis, B. N. Van Den Hende, E. A. &amp; Hultink, E. J. 2016. When Should Large Firms Collaborate with Young Ventures? Understanding young firms’ strengths can help firms make the right decisions around asymmetric collaborations. Research-Technology Management, Volume (59), pp. 39-47.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Holm, K. &amp; Ankarkrona, G. 2016. The Entrepreneurship Ecosystem and its supports in Nairobi-in Nairobi-A Qualitative study of their relationships.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Iansiti, M. &amp; Levien, R. 2004. Strategy as ecology. Harvard business review, Volume (82), pp. 81-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Isenberg, D. 2011. Introducing the entrepreneurship ecosystem: Four defining characteristics. Forbes, May, 25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Isenberg, D. 2016. Applying the Ecosystem Metaphor to Entrepreneurship: Uses and Abuses.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Jang, H. Lee, K. &amp; Yoon, B. 2017.Development of an open innovation model for R&amp;D collaboration between large firms and small-medium enterprises (smes) in manufacturing industries. international journal of innovation management, Volume (21), 1750002.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Jucevicius, G. Juceviciene, R. Gaidelys, V. &amp; Kalman, A. 2016. The Emerging Innovation Ecosystems and" Valley of Death": Towards the Combination of Entrepreneurial and Institutional Approaches. Engineering Economics, Volume (27), pp. 430-438.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Kapoor, R. 2013. Collaborating with complementors: What do firms do. Advances in strategic management, Volume (30), pp. 3-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Kempner, R. and Levine, B. 2008. Asset Mapping Roadmap: A Guide to Assessing Regional Development Resources.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Khorsheed, M. S. 2016. Learning from Global Pacesetters to Build the Country Innovation Ecosystem. Journal of the Knowledge Economy, pp. 1-20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Kim, S.K. 2015. Building up the startup ecosystem in Korea. International Journal of Teaching and Case Studies, Volume (6), pp. 170-182.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Kogut, B. 1988. Joint ventures: Theoretical and empirical perspectives. Strategic management journal, Volume (9), pp. 319-332.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Koltai, S. 2014. The Six+Six Entrepreneurship Ecosystem Model[Online]. koltai &amp; company. Available: http://koltai.co/home/six-six 2016</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Kon, F. Cukier, D. Melo, C. Hazzan, O. &amp; Yuklea, H. 2014. A panorama of the israeli software startup ecosystem. Available at SSRN 2441157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Kshetri, N. 2014. Developing successful entrepreneurial ecosystems: Lessons from a comparison of an Asian tiger and a Baltic tiger. Baltic Journal of Management, Volume (9), pp. 330-356.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Kumar, R. 2014. Managing ambiguity in strategic alliances. California Management Review, Volume (56), pp. 82-102.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Landis, J. R. &amp; Koch, G. G. 1977. The measurement of observer agreement for categorical data. biometrics, pp. 159-174.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Lash, J. 2002. People and Ecosystems–The Fraying Web of Life. People, 3(2).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Lawshe, C. H. 1975. A quantitative approach to content validity. Personnel psychology, Volume (28), pp. 563-575.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Leten, B. Vanhaverbeke, W. Roijakkers, N. Clerix, A. &amp; Van Helleputte, J. 2013. IP Models to Orchestrate Innovation Ecosystems. California management review, Volume (55), pp. 51-64.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Li, J. F. &amp; Garnsey, E. 2014. Policy-driven ecosystems for new vaccine development. Technovation, Volume (34), pp. 762-772.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Li, X. Zheng, Y. &amp; Wang, C. L. 2016. Inter-firm collaboration in new product development in Chinese pharmaceutical companies. Asia Pacific Journal of Management, Volume (33), pp. 165-193.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Lu, C. Rong, K. You, J. &amp; Shi, Y. 2014. Business ecosystem and stakeholders’ role transformation: Evidence from Chinese emerging electric vehicle industry. Expert Systems with applications, Volume (41), pp. 4579-4595.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Mack, E. &amp; Mayer, H. 2015. The evolutionary dynamics of entrepreneurial ecosystems. Urban Studies, 0042098015586547.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Mack, E. &amp; Mayer, H. 2016. The evolutionary dynamics of entrepreneurial ecosystems. Urban Studies, Volume (53), pp. 2118-2133.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Mäkinen, S. A view on science-based start-ups as innovation ecosystems: Exploring functions of basic mechanisms. Management of Innovation and Technology (ICMIT), 2014 IEEE International Conference on, 2014. IEEE, pp. 223-229.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Mazzarol, T. 2014. Growing and sustaining entrepreneurial ecosystems: What they are and the role of government policy. White Paper WP01-2014, Small Enterprise Association of Australia and New Zealand (SEAANZ).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Mercan, B. &amp; Goktas, D. 2011. Components of innovation ecosystems: a cross-country study. International Research Journal of Finance and Economics, Volume (76), pp. 102-112.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Möller, K. &amp; Rajala, A. 2007. Rise of strategic nets—New modes of value creation. Industrial marketing management, Volume (36), pp. 895-908.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Moore, J. F. 1993. Predators and prey: a new ecology of competition. Harvard business review, Volume (71), pp. 75-83.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Motoyama, Y. &amp; Watkins, K. K. 2014. Examining the connections within the startup ecosystem: A case study of st. louis. Louis (September 1, 2014). Kauffman Foundation Research Series on City, Metro, and Regional Entrepreneurship.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Mueller, C. &amp; Herstatt, C. 2000. Interfirm cooperation: a brief overview of current theoretical findings and issues for future research. International Journal of Human Resources Development and Management, Volume (1), pp. 48-67.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Narula, R. 2004. R&amp;D collaboration by SMEs: new opportunities and limitations in the face of globalisation. Technovation, Volume (24), pp. 153-161.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson, R. R. &amp; Sidney, G. 2005. Winter. 1982. An evolutionary theory of economic change. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Nielsen, B. B. 2007. Determining international strategic alliance performance: A multidimensional approach. International Business Review, Volume (16), pp. 337-361.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Nonino, F. 2013. The network dimensions of intra-organizational social capital. Journal of Management &amp; Organization, Volume (19), pp. 454-477.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Oh, D.S. Phillips, F. Park, S. &amp; Lee, E. 2016. Innovation ecosystems: A critical examination. Technovation, Volume (54), pp. 1-6.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Okamuro, H. 2007. Determinants of successful R&amp;D cooperation in Japanese small businesses: The impact of organizational and contractual characteristics. Research Policy, Volume (36), pp. 1529-1544.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Oughton, D. Mortara, L. &amp; Minshall, T. 2013a. Managing asymmetric relationships in open innovation: lessons from multinational companies and SMEs. Open Innovation in the Food and Beverage Industry. Elsevier.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Oughton, D. Mortara, L. &amp; Minshall, T. 2013b. Managing asymmetric relationships in open innovation: lessons from multinational companies and SMEs.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Overholm, H. 2015. Collectively created opportunities in emerging ecosystems: The case of solar service ventures. Technovation, Volume (39), pp. 14-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Pansiri, J. 2008. The effects of characteristics of partners on strategic alliance performance in the SME dominated travel sector. Tourism Management, Volume (29), pp. 101-115.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Paterson, B. L. 2001. Meta-study of qualitative health research: A practical guide to meta-analysis and meta-synthesis, Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Peltoniemi, M. 2005. Business ecosystem: a conceptual model of an organisation population from the perspectives of complexity and evolution.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Peltoniemi, M. 2006. Preliminary theoretical framework for the study of business ecosystems. Emergence-mahwah-lawrence Erlbaum, 8(1), pp. 10-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Potočnik, J. Innovation and Research: SMEs are the DNA of European economy. How to support them more and better? speech delivered at the conference Union Européenne, Recherche et PME: l'Innovation en Mouvement, Paris, 15th September, 2008.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Rabelo, R. J. &amp; Bernus, P. 2015.A holistic model of building innovation ecosystems. IFAC-PapersOnLine, Volume (48), pp. 2250-2257.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Rahatullah Khan, M. 2013. Mapping entrepreneurship ecosystem of Saudi Arabia. World Journal of Entrepreneurship, Management and Sustainable Development, Volume (9), pp. 28-54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Rinkinen, S. &amp; Harmaakorpi, V. 2017.The business ecosystem concept in innovation policy context: building a conceptual framework. Innovation: The European Journal of Social Science Research, pp. 1-17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. 2011.Nurturing business ecosystems from firm perspectives: lifecycle, nurturing process, construct, configuration pattern. University of Cambridge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. Hou, J. Shi, Y. &amp; Lu, Q. From value chain, supply network, towards business ecosystem (BE): Evaluating the BE concept's implications to emerging industrial demand. Industrial Engineering and Engineering Management (IEEM), 2010 IEEE International Conference on, 2010. IEEE, pp. 2173-2177.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. Hu, G. Hou, J. Ma, R. &amp; Shi, Y. 2013a. Business ecosystem extension: facilitating the technology substitution. International Journal of Technology Management, Volume (63), pp. 268-294.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. Hu, G. Lin, Y. Shi, Y. &amp; Guo, L. 2015a.Understanding business ecosystem using a 6C framework in Internet-of-Things-based sectors. International Journal of Production Economics.Volume (159), pp. 41-55.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. Lin, Y. Shi, Y. &amp; Yu, J. 2013b.Linking business ecosystem lifecycle with platform strategy: a triple view of technology, application and organisation. International journal of technology management, Volume (62), pp. 75-94.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. Shi, Y. &amp; Yu, J. 2013c. Nurturing business ecosystems to deal with industry uncertainties. Industrial management &amp; data systems, Volume (113), pp. 385-402.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. Wu, J. Shi, Y. &amp; Guo, L. 2015b. Nurturing business ecosystems for growth in a foreign market: Incubating, identifying and integrating stakeholders. Journal of International Management, Volume (21), pp. 293-308.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Sandelowski, M. &amp; Barroso, J. 2006.Handbook for synthesizing qualitative research, Springer Publishing Company.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Sawhney, M. &amp; Nambisan, S. 2007.The global brain: Your roadmap for innovating faster and smarter in a networked world, Pearson Prentice Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Schulze, A. &amp; Brojerdi, G. J. C. 2012.The effect of the distance between partners' knowledge components on collaborative innovation. European Management Review, Volume (9), pp. 85-98.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Schwartz, D. and Bar-El, R. 2015.The role of a local industry association as a catalyst for building an innovation ecosystem: An experiment in the State of Ceara in Brazil. Innovation, 17(3), pp. 383-399.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>Segers, J.P. 1993. Strategic partnering between new technology based firms and large established firms in the biotechnology and micro-electronics industries in Belgium. Small Business Economics, Volume (5), pp. 271-281.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>Shaw, D. R. &amp; Allen, T. 2016.Studying innovation ecosystems using ecology theory. Technological Forecasting and Social Change.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Song, J. 2016.Innovation ecosystem: impact of interactive patterns, member location and member heterogeneity on cooperative innovation performance. Innovation: Management, Policy &amp; Practice, pp. 1-17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>Song, J. Sun, Y. &amp; Jin, L. 2017.PESTEL analysis of the development of the waste-to-energy incineration industry in China. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, Volume (80), pp. 276-289.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R115">
			<label>115</label>
			<element-citation>Spender, J.C. Spender, J.C. Corvello, V. Corvello, V. Grimaldi, M. Grimaldi, M. Rippa, P. &amp; Rippa, P. 2017. Startups and open innovation: a review of the literature. European Journal of Innovation Management, Volume (20), pp. 4-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R116">
			<label>116</label>
			<element-citation>Spithoven, A. Vanhaverbeke, W. &amp; Roijakkers, N. 2013.Open innovation practices in SMEs and large enterprises. Small Business Economics, Volume (41), pp. 537-562.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R117">
			<label>117</label>
			<element-citation>St-Pierre, J. Foleu, L. Abdulnour, G. Nomo, S. &amp; Fouda, M. 2015.SME Development Challenges in Cameroon: An Entrepreneurial Ecosystem Perspective. Transnational Corporations Review, Volume (7), pp. 441-462.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R118">
			<label>118</label>
			<element-citation>Stam, E. 2015.Entrepreneurial ecosystems and regional policy: a sympathetic critique. European Planning Studies, Volume (23), pp. 1759-1769.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R119">
			<label>119</label>
			<element-citation>Strauss, A. &amp; Corbin, J. 1994.Grounded theory methodology. Handbook of qualitative research, Volume (17), pp. 273-85.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R120">
			<label>120</label>
			<element-citation>Suominen, A. Seppänen, M. &amp; Dedehayir, O. Innovation Systems and Ecosystems: A Review and Synthesis. ISPIM Conference Proceedings, 2016.The International Society for Professional Innovation Management (ISPIM), pp. 1-14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R121">
			<label>121</label>
			<element-citation>Suresh, J. &amp; Ramraj, R. 2012.Entrepreneurial ecosystem: case study on the influence of environmental factors on entrepreneurial success. European Journal of Business and Management, Volume (4), pp. 95-101.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R122">
			<label>122</label>
			<element-citation>Tansley, A. G. 1935.The use and abuse of vegetational concepts and terms. Ecology, Volume (16), pp. 284-307.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R123">
			<label>123</label>
			<element-citation>Thomas, L. D. &amp; Autio, E. 2014. The processes of ecosystem emergence. Working Paper, Imperial College Business School, University of London, July.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R124">
			<label>124</label>
			<element-citation>Traitler, H. Watzke, H. J. &amp; Saguy, I. S. 2011.Reinventing R&amp;D in an open innovation ecosystem. Journal of food science, 76(2), R62-R68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R125">
			<label>125</label>
			<element-citation>Tsujimoto, M. Kajikawa, Y. Tomita, J. &amp; Matsumoto, Y. 2017.A review of the ecosystem concept—Towards coherent ecosystem design. Technological Forecasting and Social Change.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R126">
			<label>126</label>
			<element-citation>Turner, R. H. 2001. Role theory. Handbook of sociological theory, pp. 233-254.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R127">
			<label>127</label>
			<element-citation>Weiblen, T. &amp; Chesbrough, H. W.2015. Engaging with startups to enhance corporate innovation. California Management Review, Volume (57), pp. 66-90.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R128">
			<label>128</label>
			<element-citation>West, J. &amp; Gallagher, S.2006. Patterns of open innovation in open source software. Open Innovation: researching a new paradigm, 235.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R129">
			<label>129</label>
			<element-citation>Xiaoren, Z. Ling, D. &amp; Xiangdong, C.2014. Interaction of open innovation and business ecosystem. International Journal of u-and e-Service, Science and Technology, Volume (7), pp. 51-64.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R130">
			<label>130</label>
			<element-citation>Yang, E. C. L. Khoo-Lattimore, C. &amp; Arcodia, C.2017. A systematic literature review of risk and gender research in tourism. Tourism Management, Volume (58), pp. 89-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R131">
			<label>131</label>
			<element-citation>Zahra, S. A. &amp; Nambisan, S.2012. Entrepreneurship and strategic thinking in business ecosystems. Business Horizons, Volume (55), pp. 219-229.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R132">
			<label>132</label>
			<element-citation>Zimmer, L. 2006.Qualitative meta synthesis: a question of dialoguing with texts. Journal of advanced nursing, Volume (53), pp. 311-318.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R133">
			<label>133</label>
			<element-citation>جهانی‏راد، ف. مشبکی، ا. کردنائیج، ا. و خدادادحسینی، س. 1394. تبیین مبانی فکری رویکرد زیست‌بوم کسب‏وکار</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R134">
			<label>134</label>
			<element-citation>پژوهش‏های مدیریت در ایران، دوره 19, صص. 160-139.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R135">
			<label>135</label>
			<element-citation>خالدی، آ. 1396. تفاوت زیست‌بوم نوآوری و سیستم نوآوری. فصلنامه سیاست علم و فناوری، شماره 3.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R136">
			<label>136</label>
			<element-citation>خواستار، ح. 1388. ارایه‌ی روشی برای محاسبه‌ی پایایی مرحله‌ی کدگذاری در مصاحبه‌های پژوهشی. مجله روش‏شناسی علوم انسانی، دوره 15, صص. 161-174._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R137">
			<label>137</label>
			<element-citation>Adner, R. 2006. Match your innovation strategy to your innovation ecosystem. Harvard business review, 84(4), pp. 98-107.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R138">
			<label>138</label>
			<element-citation>Adner, R. 2017. Ecosystem as Structure An Actionable Construct for Strategy. Journal of Management, Volume (43), pp. 39-58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R139">
			<label>139</label>
			<element-citation>Adner, R. &amp; Kapoor, R. 2010.Value creation in innovation ecosystems: How the structure of technological interdependence affects firm performance in new technology generations. Strategic Management Journal, Volume (31), pp. 306-333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R140">
			<label>140</label>
			<element-citation>Ahmad, N. &amp; Hoffmann, A. 2008. A framework for addressing and measuring entrepreneurship.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R141">
			<label>141</label>
			<element-citation>Arruda, C. Nogueira, V. S. &amp; Costa, V. 2013. The Brazilian entrepreneurial ecosystem of startups: An analysis of entrepreneurship determinants in Brazil as seen from the OECD pillars. Journal of Entrepreneurship and Innovation Management, Volume (2), pp. 17-57.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R142">
			<label>142</label>
			<element-citation>Bannerjee, S. Bielli, S. &amp; Haley, C. 2016. Scaling together: Overcoming barriers in corporate-stratup collaboration. London: Nesta.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R143">
			<label>143</label>
			<element-citation>Barge-Gil, A. 2010.  Cooperation-based innovators and peripheral cooperators: An empirical analysis of their characteristics and behavior. Technovation, Volume (30), pp. 195-206.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R144">
			<label>144</label>
			<element-citation>Basu, S. Phelps, C. &amp; Kotha, S. 2011. Towards understanding who makes corporate venture capital investments and why. Journal of Business Venturing, Volume (26), pp. 153-171.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R145">
			<label>145</label>
			<element-citation>Battistella, C. Colucci, K. De Toni, A. F. &amp; Nonino, F. 2013. Methodology of business ecosystems network analysis: A case study in Telecom Italia Future Centre. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Volume (80), pp. 1194-1210.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R146">
			<label>146</label>
			<element-citation>Bazi, H. R. &amp; Hasanzadeh, A. R. 2017. Proposal the novel cloud computing adoption framework using Meta synthesis approach. Journal of Information Processing and Management, 2(33), pp. 547-584</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R147">
			<label>147</label>
			<element-citation>Bench, S. &amp; Day, T. 2010. The user experience of critical care discharge: a meta-synthesis of qualitative research. International journal of nursing studies, Volume (47), pp. 487-499.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R148">
			<label>148</label>
			<element-citation>Berger, E. S. &amp; Kuckertz, A. 2016. Female entrepreneurship in startup ecosystems worldwide. Journal of Business Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R149">
			<label>149</label>
			<element-citation>Body, J. &amp; Habbal, F. 2016. The Innovation Ecosystem. Creating Innovation Leaders. Springer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R150">
			<label>150</label>
			<element-citation>Bosch-Sijtsema, P. M. &amp; Bosch, J. Aligning innovation ecosystem strategies with internal R&amp;D. Management of Innovation and Technology (ICMIT), 2014 IEEE International Conference on, 2014. IEEE, pp. 424-430.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R151">
			<label>151</label>
			<element-citation>Büyüközkan, G. &amp; Arsenyan, J. 2012. Collaborative product development: a literature overview. Production Planning &amp; Control, Volume (23), pp. 47-66.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R152">
			<label>152</label>
			<element-citation>Carayannis, E. G. &amp; Campbell, D. F. 2009. 'Mode 3'and'Quadruple Helix': toward a 21st century fractal innovation ecosystem. International Journal of Technology Management, Volume (46), pp. 201-234.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R153">
			<label>153</label>
			<element-citation>Casals, F. E. The SME Co-operation Framework, a Multi-method Secondary Research Approach to SME Collaboration. 2010 International Conference on E-business, Management and Economics. IPEDR, 2011.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R154">
			<label>154</label>
			<element-citation>Chaharbaghi, K. Adcroft, A. Willis, R. Todeva, E. &amp; Knoke, D. 2005. Strategic alliances and models of collaboration. Management Decision, Volume (43), pp. 123-148.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R155">
			<label>155</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, D. &amp; Karami, A. 2010. Critical success factors for inter-firm technological cooperation: an empirical study of high-tech SMEs in China. International Journal of Technology Management, Volume (51), 282-299.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R156">
			<label>156</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, J. Liu, X. &amp; Hu, Y. 2016. Establishing a CoPs-based innovation ecosystem to enhance competence-the case of CGN in China. International Journal of Technology Management, Volume (72), pp. 144-170.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R157">
			<label>157</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H. W. 2006. Open innovation: The new imperative for creating and profiting from technology, Harvard Business Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R158">
			<label>158</label>
			<element-citation>Christensen, J. L. Schibany, A. &amp; Vinding, A. L. 2001. Collaboration between manufacturing firms and knowledge institutions on product development: evidence from harmonised surveys in Australia, Austria, Denmark, Norway and Spain. Innovative Networks, Co-Operation in National Innovation Systems, pp. 253-278.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R159">
			<label>159</label>
			<element-citation>Clarysse, B. Wright, M. Bruneel, J. &amp; Mahajan, A. 2014. Creating value in ecosystems: Crossing the chasm between knowledge and business ecosystems. Research Policy, Volume (43), pp. 1164-1176.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R160">
			<label>160</label>
			<element-citation>Clegg, B. Minshall, T. Mortara, L. Elia, S. &amp; Probert, D. 2008. Development of practitioner guidelines for partnerships between start-ups and large firms. Journal of Manufacturing Technology Management, Volume (19), pp. 391-406.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R161">
			<label>161</label>
			<element-citation>Cohen, W. M. &amp; Levinthal, D. A. 1990. Absorptive capacity: A new perspective on learning and innovation. Administrative science quarterly, pp. 128-152.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R162">
			<label>162</label>
			<element-citation>Comi, A. &amp; Eppler, M. J. 2009. Building and managing strategic alliances in technology-driven start-ups. Università della Svizzera italiana.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R163">
			<label>163</label>
			<element-citation>Crossan, M. M. &amp; Apaydin, M. 2010. A multi‐dimensional framework of organizational innovation: A systematic review of the literature. Journal of management studies, Volume (47), pp. 1154-1191.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R164">
			<label>164</label>
			<element-citation>D'auria, A. Tregua, M. Spena, T. R. &amp; Bifulco, F. 2016. Exploring innovation contexts: system, network and ecosystem innovation. International Journal of Management and Enterprise Development, Volume (15), pp. 127-146.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R165">
			<label>165</label>
			<element-citation>De Vasconcelos Gomes, L. A. Facin, A. L. F. Salerno, M. S. &amp; Ikenami, R. K. 2016. Unpacking the innovation ecosystem construct: Evolution, gaps and trends. Technological Forecasting and Social Change.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R166">
			<label>166</label>
			<element-citation>Dedehayir, O. Mäkinen, S. J. &amp; Ortt, J. R. 2016. Roles during innovation ecosystem genesis: A literature review. Technological Forecasting and Social Change.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R167">
			<label>167</label>
			<element-citation>Dodgson, M. 1992. Technological collaboration: problems and pitfalls. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, Volume (4), pp. 83-88.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R168">
			<label>168</label>
			<element-citation>Donnelly, J. P. 2017. A systematic review of concept mapping dissertations. Evaluation and Program Planning, Volume (60), pp. 186-193.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R169">
			<label>169</label>
			<element-citation>Drexler, M. Eltogby, M. &amp; Foster, G. Entrepreneurial ecosystems around the globe and early-stage company growth dynamics. Geneva: World Economic Forum, 2014.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R170">
			<label>170</label>
			<element-citation>Dushnitsky, G. &amp; Lenox, M. J. 2005. When do incumbents learn from entrepreneurial ventures? Corporate venture capital and investing firm innovation rates. Research Policy, Volume (34), pp. 615-639.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R171">
			<label>171</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K. M. &amp; Schoonhoven, C. B. 1996. Resource-based view of strategic alliance formation: Strategic and social effects in entrepreneurial firms. organization Science, Volume (7), pp. 136-150.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R172">
			<label>172</label>
			<element-citation>Feld, B. 2012. Startup communities: Building an entrepreneurial ecosystem in your city, John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R173">
			<label>173</label>
			<element-citation>Foster, G. Shimizu, C. Ciesinski, S. Davila, A. Hassan, S. Jia, N. &amp; Morris, R. Entrepreneurial ecosystems around the globe and company growth dynamics. World Economic Forum, 2013.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R174">
			<label>174</label>
			<element-citation>Franco, M. 2011. Determining factors in the success of strategic alliances: an empirical study performed in Portuguese firms. European Journal of International Management, 5, pp. 608-632.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R175">
			<label>175</label>
			<element-citation>Freeman, C. 1995. The ‘National System of Innovation’in historical perspective. Cambridge Journal of economics, Volume (19), pp. 5-24.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R176">
			<label>176</label>
			<element-citation>Frenkel, A. Maital, S. Leck, E. &amp; Israel, E. 2015. Demand-driven innovation: An integrative systems-based review of the literature. International Journal of Innovation and Technology Management, Volume (12), 1550008.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R177">
			<label>177</label>
			<element-citation>Fuerlinger, G. Fandl, U. &amp; Funke, T. 2015. The role of the state in the entrepreneurship ecosystem: insights from Germany. Triple Helix, 2(1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R178">
			<label>178</label>
			<element-citation>Garnsey, E. &amp; Leong, Y. Y. 2008. Combining resource based and evolutionary theory to explain the genesis of bionetworks. Industry and Innovation, Volume (15), pp. 669-686.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R179">
			<label>179</label>
			<element-citation>Gebauer, A. Nam, C. W. &amp; Parsche, R. 2005. Regional technology policy and factors shaping local innovation networks in small German cities 1. European Planning Studies, Volume (13), pp. 661-683.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R180">
			<label>180</label>
			<element-citation>Gnyawali, D. R. &amp; Fogel, D. S. 1994. Environments for entrepreneurship development: key dimensions and research implications. Entrepreneurship theory and practice, Volume (18), pp. 43-43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R181">
			<label>181</label>
			<element-citation>Hagedoorn , J. 1993. Understanding the rationale of strategic technology partnering: Nterorganizational modes of cooperation and sectoral differences. Strategic management journal, Volume (14), pp. 371-385.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R182">
			<label>182</label>
			<element-citation>Hagedoorn, J. 2002. Inter-firm R&amp;D partnerships: an overview of major trends and patterns since 1960. Research policy, Volume (31), pp. 477-492.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R183">
			<label>183</label>
			<element-citation>Hargadon, A. &amp; Sutton, R. I. 1997. Technology brokering and innovation in a product development firm. Administrative science quarterly, pp. 716-749.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R184">
			<label>184</label>
			<element-citation>Hartigh, E. D. &amp; Asseldonk, T. V. Business ecosystems: A research framework for investigating the relation between network structure, firm strategy, and the pattern of innovation diffusion. ECCON 2004 Annual Meeting, 2004.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R185">
			<label>185</label>
			<element-citation>Heimeriks, K. H. Bingham, C. B. &amp; Laamanen, T. 2015. Unveiling the temporally contingent role of codification in alliance success. Strategic Management Journal, Volume (36), pp. 462-473.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R186">
			<label>186</label>
			<element-citation>Hoffmann, W. H. &amp; Schlosser, R. 2001. Success factors of strategic alliances in small and medium-sized enterprises—An empirical survey. Long range planning, Volume (34), pp. 381-357.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R187">
			<label>187</label>
			<element-citation>Hogenhuis, B. N. Van Den Hende, E. A. &amp; Hultink, E. J. 2016. When Should Large Firms Collaborate with Young Ventures? Understanding young firms’ strengths can help firms make the right decisions around asymmetric collaborations. Research-Technology Management, Volume (59), pp. 39-47.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R188">
			<label>188</label>
			<element-citation>Holm, K. &amp; Ankarkrona, G. 2016. The Entrepreneurship Ecosystem and its supports in Nairobi-in Nairobi-A Qualitative study of their relationships.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R189">
			<label>189</label>
			<element-citation>Iansiti, M. &amp; Levien, R. 2004. Strategy as ecology. Harvard business review, Volume (82), pp. 81-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R190">
			<label>190</label>
			<element-citation>Isenberg, D. 2011. Introducing the entrepreneurship ecosystem: Four defining characteristics. Forbes, May, 25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R191">
			<label>191</label>
			<element-citation>Isenberg, D. 2016. Applying the Ecosystem Metaphor to Entrepreneurship: Uses and Abuses.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R192">
			<label>192</label>
			<element-citation>Jahanizadeh F, M. A., Kord Naeij A, Khodadad Hosseini S H  (2015). Explaining the Basic Principles of Business Ecosystem Approach. IQBQ, 19(2), pp.139-160.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R193">
			<label>193</label>
			<element-citation>Jang, H. Lee, K. &amp; Yoon, B. 2017.Development of an open innovation model for R&amp;D collaboration between large firms and small-medium enterprises (smes) in manufacturing industries. international journal of innovation management, Volume (21), 1750002.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R194">
			<label>194</label>
			<element-citation>Jucevicius, G. Juceviciene, R. Gaidelys, V. &amp; Kalman, A. 2016. The Emerging Innovation Ecosystems and" Valley of Death": Towards the Combination of Entrepreneurial and Institutional Approaches. Engineering Economics, Volume (27), pp. 430-438.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R195">
			<label>195</label>
			<element-citation>Kapoor, R. 2013. Collaborating with complementors: What do firms do. Advances in strategic management, Volume (30), pp. 3-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R196">
			<label>196</label>
			<element-citation>Kempner, R. and Levine, B. 2008. Asset Mapping Roadmap: A Guide to Assessing Regional Development Resources.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R197">
			<label>197</label>
			<element-citation>Khaledi, A. (2017). Different between Innovation Ecosystem and Innovation System. Journal of Science &amp; Technology Policy, 9(3).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R198">
			<label>198</label>
			<element-citation>Khastar, H. (2009). A Method for Calculating Coding Reliability in Qualitative Research Interviews. Methodology of Socail Science and Humanities Journal, 15(58), pp. 161-174.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R199">
			<label>199</label>
			<element-citation>Khorsheed, M. S. 2016. Learning from Global Pacesetters to Build the Country Innovation Ecosystem. Journal of the Knowledge Economy, pp. 1-20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R200">
			<label>200</label>
			<element-citation>Kim, S.K. 2015. Building up the startup ecosystem in Korea. International Journal of Teaching and Case Studies, Volume (6), pp. 170-182.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R201">
			<label>201</label>
			<element-citation>Kogut, B. 1988. Joint ventures: Theoretical and empirical perspectives. Strategic management journal, Volume (9), pp. 319-332.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R202">
			<label>202</label>
			<element-citation>Koltai, S. 2014. The Six+Six Entrepreneurship Ecosystem Model[Online]. koltai &amp; company. Available: http://koltai.co/home/six-six 2016</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R203">
			<label>203</label>
			<element-citation>Kon, F. Cukier, D. Melo, C. Hazzan, O. &amp; Yuklea, H. 2014. A panorama of the israeli software startup ecosystem. Available at SSRN 2441157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R204">
			<label>204</label>
			<element-citation>Kshetri, N. 2014. Developing successful entrepreneurial ecosystems: Lessons from a comparison of an Asian tiger and a Baltic tiger. Baltic Journal of Management, Volume (9), pp. 330-356.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R205">
			<label>205</label>
			<element-citation>Kumar, R. 2014. Managing ambiguity in strategic alliances. California Management Review, Volume (56), pp. 82-102.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R206">
			<label>206</label>
			<element-citation>Landis, J. R. &amp; Koch, G. G. 1977. The measurement of observer agreement for categorical data. biometrics, pp. 159-174.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R207">
			<label>207</label>
			<element-citation>Lash, J. 2002. People and Ecosystems–The Fraying Web of Life. People, 3(2).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R208">
			<label>208</label>
			<element-citation>Lawshe, C. H. 1975. A quantitative approach to content validity. Personnel psychology, Volume (28), pp. 563-575.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R209">
			<label>209</label>
			<element-citation>Leten, B. Vanhaverbeke, W. Roijakkers, N. Clerix, A. &amp; Van Helleputte, J. 2013. IP Models to Orchestrate Innovation Ecosystems. California management review, Volume (55), pp. 51-64.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R210">
			<label>210</label>
			<element-citation>Li, J. F. &amp; Garnsey, E. 2014. Policy-driven ecosystems for new vaccine development. Technovation, Volume (34), pp. 762-772.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R211">
			<label>211</label>
			<element-citation>Li, X. Zheng, Y. &amp; Wang, C. L. 2016. Inter-firm collaboration in new product development in Chinese pharmaceutical companies. Asia Pacific Journal of Management, Volume (33), pp. 165-193.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R212">
			<label>212</label>
			<element-citation>Lu, C. Rong, K. You, J. &amp; Shi, Y. 2014. Business ecosystem and stakeholders’ role transformation: Evidence from Chinese emerging electric vehicle industry. Expert Systems with applications, Volume (41), pp. 4579-4595.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R213">
			<label>213</label>
			<element-citation>Mack, E. &amp; Mayer, H. 2015. The evolutionary dynamics of entrepreneurial ecosystems. Urban Studies, 0042098015586547.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R214">
			<label>214</label>
			<element-citation>Mack, E. &amp; Mayer, H. 2016. The evolutionary dynamics of entrepreneurial ecosystems. Urban Studies, Volume (53), pp. 2118-2133.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R215">
			<label>215</label>
			<element-citation>Mäkinen, S. A view on science-based start-ups as innovation ecosystems: Exploring functions of basic mechanisms. Management of Innovation and Technology (ICMIT), 2014 IEEE International Conference on, 2014. IEEE, pp. 223-229.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R216">
			<label>216</label>
			<element-citation>Mazzarol, T. 2014. Growing and sustaining entrepreneurial ecosystems: What they are and the role of government policy. White Paper WP01-2014, Small Enterprise Association of Australia and New Zealand (SEAANZ).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R217">
			<label>217</label>
			<element-citation>Mercan, B. &amp; Goktas, D. 2011. Components of innovation ecosystems: a cross-country study. International Research Journal of Finance and Economics, Volume (76), pp. 102-112.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R218">
			<label>218</label>
			<element-citation>Möller, K. &amp; Rajala, A. 2007. Rise of strategic nets—New modes of value creation. Industrial marketing management, Volume (36), pp. 895-908.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R219">
			<label>219</label>
			<element-citation>Moore, J. F. 1993. Predators and prey: a new ecology of competition. Harvard business review, Volume (71), pp. 75-83.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R220">
			<label>220</label>
			<element-citation>Motoyama, Y. &amp; Watkins, K. K. 2014. Examining the connections within the startup ecosystem: A case study of st. louis. Louis (September 1, 2014). Kauffman Foundation Research Series on City, Metro, and Regional Entrepreneurship.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R221">
			<label>221</label>
			<element-citation>Mueller, C. &amp; Herstatt, C. 2000. Interfirm cooperation: a brief overview of current theoretical findings and issues for future research. International Journal of Human Resources Development and Management, Volume (1), pp. 48-67.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R222">
			<label>222</label>
			<element-citation>Narula, R. 2004. R&amp;D collaboration by SMEs: new opportunities and limitations in the face of globalisation. Technovation, Volume (24), pp. 153-161.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R223">
			<label>223</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson, R. R. &amp; Sidney, G. 2005. Winter. 1982. An evolutionary theory of economic change. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R224">
			<label>224</label>
			<element-citation>Nielsen, B. B. 2007. Determining international strategic alliance performance: A multidimensional approach. International Business Review, Volume (16), pp. 337-361.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R225">
			<label>225</label>
			<element-citation>Nonino, F. 2013. The network dimensions of intra-organizational social capital. Journal of Management &amp; Organization, Volume (19), pp. 454-477.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R226">
			<label>226</label>
			<element-citation>Oh, D.S. Phillips, F. Park, S. &amp; Lee, E. 2016. Innovation ecosystems: A critical examination. Technovation, Volume (54), pp. 1-6.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R227">
			<label>227</label>
			<element-citation>Okamuro, H. 2007. Determinants of successful R&amp;D cooperation in Japanese small businesses: The impact of organizational and contractual characteristics. Research Policy, Volume (36), pp. 1529-1544.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R228">
			<label>228</label>
			<element-citation>Oughton, D. Mortara, L. &amp; Minshall, T. 2013a. Managing asymmetric relationships in open innovation: lessons from multinational companies and SMEs. Open Innovation in the Food and Beverage Industry. Elsevier.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R229">
			<label>229</label>
			<element-citation>Oughton, D. Mortara, L. &amp; Minshall, T. 2013b. Managing asymmetric relationships in open innovation: lessons from multinational companies and SMEs.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R230">
			<label>230</label>
			<element-citation>Overholm, H. 2015. Collectively created opportunities in emerging ecosystems: The case of solar service ventures. Technovation, Volume (39), pp. 14-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R231">
			<label>231</label>
			<element-citation>Pansiri, J. 2008. The effects of characteristics of partners on strategic alliance performance in the SME dominated travel sector. Tourism Management, Volume (29), pp. 101-115.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R232">
			<label>232</label>
			<element-citation>Paterson, B. L. 2001. Meta-study of qualitative health research: A practical guide to meta-analysis and meta-synthesis, Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R233">
			<label>233</label>
			<element-citation>Peltoniemi, M. 2005. Business ecosystem: a conceptual model of an organisation population from the perspectives of complexity and evolution.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R234">
			<label>234</label>
			<element-citation>Peltoniemi, M. 2006. Preliminary theoretical framework for the study of business ecosystems. Emergence-mahwah-lawrence Erlbaum, 8(1), pp. 10-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R235">
			<label>235</label>
			<element-citation>Potočnik, J. Innovation and Research: SMEs are the DNA of European economy. How to support them more and better? speech delivered at the conference Union Européenne, Recherche et PME: l'Innovation en Mouvement, Paris, 15th September, 2008.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R236">
			<label>236</label>
			<element-citation>Rabelo, R. J. &amp; Bernus, P. 2015.A holistic model of building innovation ecosystems. IFAC-PapersOnLine, Volume (48), pp. 2250-2257.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R237">
			<label>237</label>
			<element-citation>Rahatullah Khan, M. 2013. Mapping entrepreneurship ecosystem of Saudi Arabia. World Journal of Entrepreneurship, Management and Sustainable Development, Volume (9), pp. 28-54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R238">
			<label>238</label>
			<element-citation>Rinkinen, S. &amp; Harmaakorpi, V. 2017.The business ecosystem concept in innovation policy context: building a conceptual framework. Innovation: The European Journal of Social Science Research, pp. 1-17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R239">
			<label>239</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. 2011.Nurturing business ecosystems from firm perspectives: lifecycle, nurturing process, construct, configuration pattern. University of Cambridge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R240">
			<label>240</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. Hou, J. Shi, Y. &amp; Lu, Q. From value chain, supply network, towards business ecosystem (BE): Evaluating the BE concept's implications to emerging industrial demand. Industrial Engineering and Engineering Management (IEEM), 2010 IEEE International Conference on, 2010. IEEE, pp. 2173-2177.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R241">
			<label>241</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. Hu, G. Hou, J. Ma, R. &amp; Shi, Y. 2013a. Business ecosystem extension: facilitating the technology substitution. International Journal of Technology Management, Volume (63), pp. 268-294.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R242">
			<label>242</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. Hu, G. Lin, Y. Shi, Y. &amp; Guo, L. 2015a.Understanding business ecosystem using a 6C framework in Internet-of-Things-based sectors. International Journal of Production Economics.Volume (159), pp. 41-55.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R243">
			<label>243</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. Lin, Y. Shi, Y. &amp; Yu, J. 2013b.Linking business ecosystem lifecycle with platform strategy: a triple view of technology, application and organisation. International journal of technology management, Volume (62), pp. 75-94.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R244">
			<label>244</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. Shi, Y. &amp; Yu, J. 2013c. Nurturing business ecosystems to deal with industry uncertainties. Industrial management &amp; data systems, Volume (113), pp. 385-402.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R245">
			<label>245</label>
			<element-citation>Rong, K. Wu, J. Shi, Y. &amp; Guo, L. 2015b. Nurturing business ecosystems for growth in a foreign market: Incubating, identifying and integrating stakeholders. Journal of International Management, Volume (21), pp. 293-308.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R246">
			<label>246</label>
			<element-citation>Sandelowski, M. &amp; Barroso, J. 2006.Handbook for synthesizing qualitative research, Springer Publishing Company.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R247">
			<label>247</label>
			<element-citation>Sawhney, M. &amp; Nambisan, S. 2007.The global brain: Your roadmap for innovating faster and smarter in a networked world, Pearson Prentice Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R248">
			<label>248</label>
			<element-citation>Schulze, A. &amp; Brojerdi, G. J. C. 2012.The effect of the distance between partners' knowledge components on collaborative innovation. European Management Review, Volume (9), pp. 85-98.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R249">
			<label>249</label>
			<element-citation>Schwartz, D. and Bar-El, R. 2015.The role of a local industry association as a catalyst for building an innovation ecosystem: An experiment in the State of Ceara in Brazil. Innovation, 17(3), pp. 383-399.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R250">
			<label>250</label>
			<element-citation>Segers, J.P. 1993. Strategic partnering between new technology based firms and large established firms in the biotechnology and micro-electronics industries in Belgium. Small Business Economics, Volume (5), pp. 271-281.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R251">
			<label>251</label>
			<element-citation>Shaw, D. R. &amp; Allen, T. 2016.Studying innovation ecosystems using ecology theory. Technological Forecasting and Social Change.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R252">
			<label>252</label>
			<element-citation>Song, J. 2016.Innovation ecosystem: impact of interactive patterns, member location and member heterogeneity on cooperative innovation performance. Innovation: Management, Policy &amp; Practice, pp. 1-17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R253">
			<label>253</label>
			<element-citation>Song, J. Sun, Y. &amp; Jin, L. 2017.PESTEL analysis of the development of the waste-to-energy incineration industry in China. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, Volume (80), pp. 276-289.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R254">
			<label>254</label>
			<element-citation>Spender, J.C. Spender, J.C. Corvello, V. Corvello, V. Grimaldi, M. Grimaldi, M. Rippa, P. &amp; Rippa, P. 2017. Startups and open innovation: a review of the literature. European Journal of Innovation Management, Volume (20), pp. 4-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R255">
			<label>255</label>
			<element-citation>Spithoven, A. Vanhaverbeke, W. &amp; Roijakkers, N. 2013.Open innovation practices in SMEs and large enterprises. Small Business Economics, Volume (41), pp. 537-562.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R256">
			<label>256</label>
			<element-citation>St-Pierre, J. Foleu, L. Abdulnour, G. Nomo, S. &amp; Fouda, M. 2015.SME Development Challenges in Cameroon: An Entrepreneurial Ecosystem Perspective. Transnational Corporations Review, Volume (7), pp. 441-462.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R257">
			<label>257</label>
			<element-citation>Stam, E. 2015.Entrepreneurial ecosystems and regional policy: a sympathetic critique. European Planning Studies, Volume (23), pp. 1759-1769.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R258">
			<label>258</label>
			<element-citation>Strauss, A. &amp; Corbin, J. 1994.Grounded theory methodology. Handbook of qualitative research, Volume (17), pp. 273-85.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R259">
			<label>259</label>
			<element-citation>Suominen, A. Seppänen, M. &amp; Dedehayir, O. Innovation Systems and Ecosystems: A Review and Synthesis. ISPIM Conference Proceedings, 2016.The International Society for Professional Innovation Management (ISPIM), pp. 1-14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R260">
			<label>260</label>
			<element-citation>Suresh, J. &amp; Ramraj, R. 2012.Entrepreneurial ecosystem: case study on the influence of environmental factors on entrepreneurial success. European Journal of Business and Management, Volume (4), pp. 95-101.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R261">
			<label>261</label>
			<element-citation>Tansley, A. G. 1935.The use and abuse of vegetational concepts and terms. Ecology, Volume (16), pp. 284-307.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R262">
			<label>262</label>
			<element-citation>Thomas, L. D. &amp; Autio, E. 2014. The processes of ecosystem emergence. Working Paper, Imperial College Business School, University of London, July.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R263">
			<label>263</label>
			<element-citation>Traitler, H. Watzke, H. J. &amp; Saguy, I. S. 2011.Reinventing R&amp;D in an open innovation ecosystem. Journal of food science, 76(2), R62-R68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R264">
			<label>264</label>
			<element-citation>Tsujimoto, M. Kajikawa, Y. Tomita, J. &amp; Matsumoto, Y. 2017.A review of the ecosystem concept—Towards coherent ecosystem design. Technological Forecasting and Social Change.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R265">
			<label>265</label>
			<element-citation>Turner, R. H. 2001. Role theory. Handbook of sociological theory, pp. 233-254.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R266">
			<label>266</label>
			<element-citation>Weiblen, T. &amp; Chesbrough, H. W.2015. Engaging with startups to enhance corporate innovation. California Management Review, Volume (57), pp. 66-90.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R267">
			<label>267</label>
			<element-citation>West, J. &amp; Gallagher, S.2006. Patterns of open innovation in open source software. Open Innovation: researching a new paradigm, 235.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R268">
			<label>268</label>
			<element-citation>Xiaoren, Z. Ling, D. &amp; Xiangdong, C.2014. Interaction of open innovation and business ecosystem. International Journal of u-and e-Service, Science and Technology, Volume (7), pp. 51-64.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R269">
			<label>269</label>
			<element-citation>Yang, E. C. L. Khoo-Lattimore, C. &amp; Arcodia, C.2017. A systematic literature review of risk and gender research in tourism. Tourism Management, Volume (58), pp. 89-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R270">
			<label>270</label>
			<element-citation>Zahra, S. A. &amp; Nambisan, S.2012. Entrepreneurship and strategic thinking in business ecosystems. Business Horizons, Volume (55), pp. 219-229.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R271">
			<label>271</label>
			<element-citation>Zimmer, L. 2006.Qualitative meta synthesis: a question of dialoguing with texts. Journal of advanced nursing, Volume (53), pp. 311-318.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81030_221e8a9288bac400f1d3958b084eec87.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>نظام های نوآوری</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تحلیل ساختاری- کارکردی نظام نوآوری فناورانه بالگرد در ایران</article-title>
			        <subtitle>تحلیل ساختاری- کارکردی نظام نوآوری فناورانه بالگرد در ایران</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>میرعمادی</surname>
			            <given-names>طاهره</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>مدیر  گروه سیاستها و راهبردها سازمان پژوهشهای علمی و صنعتی ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بهارلو</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوریهای نوین، سازمان پژوهش‌های علمی و صنعت ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بهزادی‌راد</surname>
			            <given-names>مریم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده اقتصاد، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد فیروزکوه</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2018</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>33</fpage>
			      <lpage>56</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>24</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>08</day>
			          <month>12</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81030.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81030.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>هدف این مقاله تحلیل وضعیت کنونی نظام نوآوری فناورانه بالگرد در ایران و شناسایی نقاط ضعف و مسایل آن است. برای این منظور از رویکرد ساختاری- کارکردی در ارزیابی نظامهای نوآوری، استفاده شده است. پیکره‌بندی ساختاری نظام با مطالعه اسناد و بهره‌گیری از نظر 6 نفر از خبرگان بالگرد، در چهار بعد بازیگران، تعاملات آنها، نهادها و فناوری (زیرساختهای آن) شناسایی و بررسی گردید. وجود شبکه قوی در بخش عرضه و تقاضای دولتی-دفاعی و شبکه ضعیف در تعاملات بخش خصوصی، مبادی سیاست‌گذاری و تسهیل‌گری و تقاضای غیرنظامی از ویژگیهای ساختار نظام نوآوری بالگرد در ایران تشخیص داده شد. برای ارزیابی وضعیت کارکردهای نظام از ابزار پیمایش بهره گرفته شد و مشخص گردید که وضعیت کلی کارکردها در شرایط رو به ضعف قرار دارد و البته کارکردهای «انتشار دانش» و «بسیج منابع» ضعیفترین کارکردهای این نظام هستند. ضعف کارکرد انتشار دانش ناشی از مولفه‌هایی چون سطح مشارکت و رقابت پایین بازیگران و فضای انتشار دانش و فناوری محدود است. درباره بسیج منابع نیز مواردی چون عدم‌کفایت و توزیع نامناسب منابع مالی در تناسب با نیازها و اهداف نظام، به‌عنوان مهمترین علل ضعف این کارکرد، شناسایی شد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>بالگرد</kwd>
						<kwd>نظام نوآوری فناورانه</kwd>
						<kwd>تحلیل ساختاری</kwd>
						<kwd>تحلیل کارکردی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Bell Helicopter. (n.d.). AMCP 706 Series: Engineering Design Handbook. USA: Bell Helicopter Textron.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Bergek, A., Jacobsson, S., Hekkert, M., &amp; Smiths, K. (2007). Functionality of Innovation Systems as a Rationale for, and Guide to Innovation Policy. In R. Smiths, S. Kuhlmann, &amp; P. Shapira, Innovation Policy, Theory and Practice. An International Handbook: Elgar Publishers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Bergek, A.; Jacobsson, et al. (2008). Analyzing the functional dynamics of technological innovation systems: A scheme of analysis. Research Policy,Volume( 37), pp. 407-429.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Blanchard, B. (2004). Systems Engineering Management, 3rd Edition. USA: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Carlsson, B., &amp; Stankiewicz, R. (1991). On the nature, function and composition of technological systems. Journal of evolutionary economics, 1(2), pp. 93-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Hekkert, M., Negro, S., &amp; al, e. (2011). Technological innovation system analysis: A manual for analysts. Utrecht University - Faculty of Geosciences - C&amp;M.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Hekkert, M.P.; Suurs, R.A.; et al. (2007). Functions of innovation systems: A new approach for analysing technological change. Technological forecasting and social change, 74(4),pp.  413-432.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Jacobsson, S., &amp; Bergek, A. (2004). Transforming the energy sector: the evolution of technological systems in renewable energy technology. Industrial and corporate change, 13(5), pp. 815-849.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Markard, J., &amp; Truffer, B. (2008). Technological innovation systems and the multi-level perspective: Towards an integrated framework. Research Policy Volume(37), pp. 596-615.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Musiolik, J., &amp; Markard, J. (2011). Creating and shaping innovation systems: Formal networks in the innovation system for stationary fuel cells in Germany. Energy Policy, 39(4), pp. 1909-1922.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Nooteboom, B. (2000). Learning and innovation in organizations and economies. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Russian Helicopters. (2014). Anuual Report'14, Around The World. Retrieved 2016, from Russian Helicopters: http://www.russianhelicopters.aero/upload/iblock/be2/be2083fffbdc38714b12bc020a046353.pdf</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Smits, R., &amp; Kuhlmann, S. (2004). The rise of systemic instruments in innovation policy. International Journal of Foresight and Innovation Policy,Volume(1), pp. 4–32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Suurs, R., &amp; Hekkert, M. (2009). Motors of sustainable innovation: Towards a theory on the dynamics of technological innovation systems. Utrecht: Utrecht University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Wieczorek, A. J., &amp; Hekkert, M. P. (2012). Systemic instruments for systemic innovation problems: A framework for policy makers and innovation scholars. Science and Public Policy, 39(1), pp. 74-87.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Woolthuis, R. K., Lankhuizen, M., &amp; Gilsing, V. (2005). A system failure framework for innovation policy design. Technovation, 25(6), pp. 609-619.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Yeasmin, S., &amp; Rahman, K. F. (September 2012). 'Triangulation' Research Method as the Tool of Social. BUP JOURNAL, 1(1), pp. 154-163.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>افخم‌نیا, ر., &amp; بهارلو, م. (1394). شناسایی و اولویت بندی عوامل کلیدی موفقیت در مدیریت نوآوری، مطالعه موردی صنایع هوایی ایران. پنجمین کنفرانس بین المللی و نهمین کنفرانس ملی مدیریت فناوری. تهران: انجمن مدیریت فناوری ایران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>برآ, ش. م. (1394). کتاب جامع صنعت هوایی و فضایی ایران. تهران: مرکز همکاریهای فناوری و نوآوری ریاست جمهوری- کارگروه هوافضا.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>بهارلو, م. (1395). پروژه تدوین طرح اجرایی ایجاد، شکل ‌گیری و توسعه شبکه همکاران صنعتی دانش‌بنیان در صنعت بالگرد کشور، گزارش فاز یک: بررسی و تحلیل اجمالی طرح تجاری بالگرد ملی و اولویت‌های سرمایه‌گذاری در صنعت بالگرد ایران. تهران: پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری ریاست جمهوری به سفارش معاونت علمی و فناوری ریاست جمهوری.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>بهارلو, مهدی. (1395). پروژه تدوین طرح اجرایی ایجاد، شکل ‌گیری و توسعه شبکه همکاران صنعتی دانش‌بنیان در صنعت بالگرد کشور، گزارش فاز چهار: تبیین زنجیره ارزش و خوشه‌های صنعتی- فناورانه در صنعت بالگرد ایران. تهران: پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری ریاست جمهوری به سفارش معاونت علمی و فناوری ریاست جمهوری.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>حسینی, س., محمدی, م., &amp; حاجی‌حسینی, ح. (تابستان 1395). عوامل حیاتی موفقیت نوآوری در محصولات و سیستم‌های پیچیده (Cops)؛ مطالعه موردی: پروژه بالگرد ملی سازمان صنایع هوایی. فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه فناوری، 3(5) ،صص.  159-186.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>حیرانی, ح., قدسی‌پور, س., باقری‌مقدم, ن., &amp; کریمیان, ح. (1393). تحلیل پویای کارکردی- ساختاری توسعه فناوری در چارچوب نظام نوآوری فناورانه؛ مورد‌مطالعه: فناوری تولید همزمان برق و حرارت. فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه فناوری، 2(2)، صص. 49-80.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>ستاد توسعه هوافضا، معاونت علمی و فناوری ریاست جمهوری. (1391). سند جامع توسعه هوافضای کشور. تهران: معاونت علمی و فناوری ریاست جمهوری.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>کزازی, ا., طباطباییان, س., امیری, م., &amp; شیرازی‌شایسته, م. (بهار 1393). بررسی عوامل موثر بر شکل‌گیری و توسعه خوشه بالگرد کشور. مدیریت نوآوری، 3(1) ،صص. 23-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>مجلس شورای اسلامی. (1396). قانون برنامه پنجساله ششم توسعه جمهوری اسلامی ایران (مصوب 14/12/1395 مجلس شورای اسلامی). بازیابی در 10 21, 1396، از شناسنامه قانون: https://shenasname.ir/1391-09-30-20-01-30/tosee/plan6/3579</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>محمدی, م., طباطباییان, س. ح., الیاسی, م., &amp; روشنی, س. (1392). تحلیل مدل شکل‌گیری کارکردهای نظام نوآوری فناورانه نوظهور در ایران؛ مطالعه موردی بخش نانوتکنولوژی در ایران. سیاست علم و فناوری، سال 5 (4)، صص. 19-32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>نبوی, ب., ثقفی, ف., &amp; محمدی, م. (زمستان 1396). شناسایی موانع و چالشهای شکل‌گیری نظام نوآوری در بخش هوانوردی عمومی ایران. مدیریت فردا، 16صص.  297-312._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Afkham Nia, R., &amp; Baharloo, M. (2015). Identifying and Prioritizing Key Success Factors in Innovation Management, A Case Study of Iran's Aircraft Industry. IRAMOT2015. Tehran: IRAMOT {in persian}.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Baharloo (a), M. (2016). A review and analysis of the national rotary wing business plan and investment priorities in the rotary wing industry in Iran. Tehran : Technology Studies Institute, Ordered by Vice Presidency for Science and Technology {in persian}.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Baharloo (b), M. (2016). Explaining the value chain and industrial-technological clusters in Iran's National Rotary Wing. Tehran: Technology Studies Institute, Ordered by Vice Presidency for Science and Technology {in persian}.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Bara Aerospace Engineering Co. (2015). Comprehensive Book of Iran's Aviation and Space Industry. Tehran: Center for Innovation and Technology Cooperation-Aerospace Work Group {in persian}.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Bell Helicopter. (n.d.). AMCP 706 Series: Engineering Design Handbook. USA: Bell Helicopter Textron. Bergek, A., Jacobsson, S., Hekkert, M., &amp; Smiths, K. (2007). Functionality of Innovation Systems as a Rationale for, and Guide to Innovation Policy. In R. Smiths, S. Kuhlmann, &amp; P. Shapira, Innovation Policy, Theory and Practice. An International Handbook: Elgar Publishers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Bergek, A.; Jacobsson, et al. (2008). Analyzing the functional dynamics of technological innovation systems: A scheme of analysis. Research Policy,Volume( 37), pp. 407-429.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Blanchard, B. (2004). Systems Engineering Management, 3rd Edition. USA: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Carlsson, B., &amp; Stankiewicz, R. (1991). On the nature, function and composition of technological systems. Journal of evolutionary economics, 1(2), pp. 93-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Hekkert, M., Negro, S., &amp; al, e. (2011). Technological innovation system analysis: A manual for analysts. Utrecht University - Faculty of Geosciences - C&amp;M.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Hekkert, M.P.; Suurs, R.A.; et al. (2007). Functions of innovation systems: A new approach for analysing technological change. Technological forecasting and social change, 74(4),pp.  413-432.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Heirani, H., Bagherimoghaddam, N., &amp; karimian, H. (2014). Dynamic structural-functional analysis of technology development process in the context of Technological innovation system; The case of Iran combined heat and power(CHP) technology. Journal of Technology Development Management, 2(2), 49-80 {in persian}.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Hosseini, S. A., Mohammadi, M., &amp; Hajihoseini, H. (2016). Critical Success Factors of Innovation in Complex Products and Systems; The Case of National Helicopter. Journal of Technology Development Management, 4(1), 159-186 {in persian}.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Jacobsson, S., &amp; Bergek, A. (2004). Transforming the energy sector: the evolution of technological systems in renewable energy technology. Industrial and corporate change, 13(5), pp. 815-849.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Kazazi, A., Tabatabaeian, S. H., Amiri, M., &amp; Shirazi Shayesteh, M. (2014). An Analysis of Factors Affecting the Formation and Development of Innovative Cluster in Iranian Helicopter Industry. Innovation Management Journal, 3(1) , 23-45 {in persian}.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Markard, J., &amp; Truffer, B. (2008). Technological innovation systems and the multi-level perspective: Towards an integrated framework. Research Policy Volume(37), pp.596-615.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammadi, M., Tabatabaeian, S. H., &amp; etal. (2013). Formation of Emerging Technological Innovation System in Iran; Case of Nanotechnology Sector. Journal of Science &amp; Technology Policy, 5 (4) , {in persian}.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Musiolik, J., &amp; Markard, J. (2011). Creating and shaping innovation systems: Formal networks in the innovation system for stationary fuel cells in Germany. Energy Policy, 39(4), pp. 1909-1922.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Nabavi, B., Saghafi, F., Manteghi, M., &amp; Mohammadi, M. (2018). Detecting obstacles and chalenges of formation and development of innovation system in Iran’s General Aviation Sector. Modiriat-E-Farda Journal, 16(53), 297-312 {in persian}.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Nooteboom, B. (2000). Learning and innovation in organizations and economies. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Parliament. (2017). The Law of the Sixth Five-Year Plan of Development of the Islamic Republic of Iran. Retrieved 10 21, 1396, from https://shenasname.ir/1391-09-30-20-01-30/tosee/plan6/3579 {in persian}</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Russian Helicopters. (2014). Anuual Report'14, Around The World. Retrieved 2016, from Russian Helicopters: http://www.russianhelicopters.aero/upload/iblock/be2/be2083fffbdc38714b12bc020a046353.pdf</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Smits, R., &amp; Kuhlmann, S. (2004). The rise of systemic instruments in innovation policy. International Journal of Foresight and Innovation Policy,Volume(1), pp. 4–32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Suurs, R., &amp; Hekkert, M. (2009). Motors of sustainable innovation: Towards a theory on the dynamics of technological innovation systems. Utrecht: Utrecht University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Vice Presidency for Science and Technology. (2013). Comprehensive document on aerospace development. Tehran: Vice Presidency for Science and Technology {in persian}.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Wieczorek, A. J., &amp; Hekkert, M. P. (2012). Systemic instruments for systemic innovation problems: A framework for policy makers and innovation scholars. Science and Public Policy, 39(1), pp. 74-87.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Woolthuis, R. K., Lankhuizen, M., &amp; Gilsing, V. (2005). A system failure framework for innovation policy design. Technovation, 25(6), pp. 609-619.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Yeasmin, S., &amp; Rahman, K. F. (September 2012). 'Triangulation' Research Method as the Tool of Social. BUP JOURNAL, 1(1), pp. 154-163.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81031_397c415428d80057dde22db05bb6e790.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>سیاست گذاری و مدیریت علم، فناوری، نوآوری و کارآفرینی و ارزیابی آن ها</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>مطالعه تطبیقی مسائل و گزینه‌های راهبردی در صنعت هوافضا‌ با استفاده از متن‌کاوی اسناد سیاستی</article-title>
			        <subtitle>مطالعه تطبیقی مسائل و گزینه‌های راهبردی در صنعت هوافضا</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>تلافی داریانی</surname>
			            <given-names>مجتبی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>شجاعی</surname>
			            <given-names>سیدمحمدحسین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>طاهری</surname>
			            <given-names>سید امین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2018</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>57</fpage>
			      <lpage>90</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>15</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>19</day>
			          <month>12</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81031.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81031.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>تحقیق حاضر در پی به‌کارگیری فرایند درس‌آموزی برای تحلیل سیاست‌های توسعه صنعت هوافضا در نه منطقه جهان و یادگیری از آن‌ها است. این تحلیل با به‌کارگیری روش متن‌کاوی روی اسناد سیاستی صنعت هوافضا و دو زیرحوزه سیاستی مرتبط یعنی علم، فناوری و نوآوری و دفاع انجام شده است و قلمرو آن مناطق اتحادیه اروپا، انگلستان، امریکا، برزیل، ترکیه، رژیم صهیونیستی، روسیه، ژاپن-کره جنوبی، و هند- پاکستان بوده است. پس از تحلیل فراوانی واژه‌ها، ترسیم شبکه هم‌رخدادی کلمات و خوشه‌بندی این شبکه برای مجموع اسناد سیاستی گردآوری‌شده، شبکه‌های هم‌رخدادی برای هریک از مناطق نه‌گانه به‌طور مجزا ترسیم و تحلیل شده‌اند و مهم‌ترین نکات سیاستی استخراج شده است. در نهایت مهم‌ترین درس‌آموخته‌ها برای سیاست‌گذاری در صنعت هوافضای جمهوری اسلامی ایران ارائه شده است. جهت‌گیری به سمت تحقیقات کاربردی و کاربردی کردن تحقیقات؛ ارتباط دولت، صنعت و دانشگاه؛ یکپارچه‌سازی سیاست‌ها و برنامه‌ها؛ استفاده از ظرفیت‌های دیپلماسی علم و فناوری؛ استفاده بهینه از منابع؛ برنامه‌ریزی دقیق و زمان‌مند برای نوآوری‌ها و فناوری‌های آینده؛ توسعه برنامه‌های مهارت‌آموزی؛ توجه ویژه و فراگیر به کاربردها و خدمات مشاهده زمین؛ ایجاد خوشه‌های تخصصی هوافضا و استفاده از ظرفیت‌های مناطق؛ تنوع‌بخشی به منابع تأمین مالی؛ تلاش برای بومی‌سازی محصولات و سامانه‌های هوافضا در کشورهای در حال توسعه؛ و نگاه سیستمی به سیاست‌گذاری علم، فناوری و نوآوری درس‌هایی هستند که از اسناد سیاستی تحلیل‌شده در این تحقیق می‌توان آموخت.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>تحلیل سیاست</kwd>
						<kwd>درس‌آموزی</kwd>
						<kwd>متن‌کاوی</kwd>
						<kwd>تحلیل هم‌واژگانی</kwd>
						<kwd>صنعت هوافضا</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Alder, E. and Bernstein, S. 2005. Knowledge in Power: The Epistemic Construction of Global Governance. In M. Barnett and R. Duvall eds. Power in Global Governance. Cambridge, Cambridge University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Altaweel, M. and Bone, C. 2012. Applying content analysis for investigating the reporting of water issues. Computers, Environment and Urban Systems, 36(6), pp. 599-613.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Bailey, C.A. 2007. A guide to qualitative field research: Sage Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Charalabidis, Y. and Loukis, E. 2012. Participative public policy making through multiple social media platforms utilization. International Journal of Electronic Government Research (IJEGR,), 8(3), pp. 78-97.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Cho, J. 2014. Intellectual structure of the institutional repository field: A co-word analysis. Journal of Information Science, 40(3), pp. 386-397.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Choudhary, A.K., Oluikpe, P., Harding, J.A. and Carrillo, P.M. 2009. The needs and benefits of Text Mining applications on Post-Project Reviews. Computers in Industry, 60(9), pp. 728-740.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Common, R. 2001. Public management and policy transfer in Southeast Asia. Aldershot: Ashgate.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Common, R. 2004. Organisational learning in a political environment: Improving policy-making in UK government. Policy studies, 25(1), pp. 35-49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>De Fortuny, E.J., De Smedt, T., Martens, D. and Daelemans, W. 2012. Media coverage in times of political crisis: A text mining approach. Expert Systems with Applications, 39(14), pp. 11616-11622.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Derrick, G., Meijer, I. and Van Wijk, E. 2014. Unwrapping “impact” for evaluation: A co-word analysis of the UK REF2014 policy documents using VOSviewer. Proceedings of the science and technology indicators conference.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Dolowitz, D. and Marsh, D. 1996. Who Learns What from Whom: a Review of the Policy Transfer Literature. Political Studies, 44(2), pp. 343-351.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Dolowitz, D. and Marsh, D. 2000. Learning from Abroad: The Role of Policy Transfer in Contemporary Policy-Making. Governance: An International Journal of Policy and Administration, 3(1),pp. 5- 24.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Dye, T. 2008. Understanding public policy. Pearson: Prentice Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Evans, M. 2004. Policy transfer in global perspective. Aldershot: Ashgate.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Evans, M. 2009. Policy transfer in critical perspective. Policy Studies, 30(3), pp. 243- 268.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Evans, M. and Davies, J. 1999. Understanding policy transfer: A Multi‐level, multi‐disciplinary perspective. Public administration, 77(2), pp. 361-385.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Feng, J., Zhang, Y.Q. and Zhang, H. 2017. Improving the co-word analysis method based on semantic distance. Scientometrics, 111(3), pp. 1521-1531.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Gal-Tzur, A. et al. 2014. The potential of social media in delivering transport policy goals. Transport Policy, Volume (32), pp. 115-123.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Given, L.M. 2008. The Sage encyclopedia of qualitative research methods: Sage Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Haas, P.M. 1989. Do regimes matter? Epistemic communities and Mediterranean pollution control. International organization, 43(3), pp. 377-403.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Hashimi, H., Hafez, A. and Mathkour, H. 2015. Selection criteria for text mining approaches. Computers in Human Behavior, Volume (51), pp. 729-733.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Heclo, H. 2010. Modern social politics in Britain and Sweden: ECPR Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Hulme, R. 2005. Policy Transfer and the Internationalisation of Social Policy. Social Policy &amp; Society, 4(4), pp. 417- 425.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Kang, Y., Shin, J. and Park, C. 2016. Assessing climate change risk and adaptation policy improvements through text-mining. Urban Design, Volume (17), pp.  69-84.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Kantardzic, M. 2011. Data mining: concepts, models, methods, and algorithms: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Kao, A. and Poteet, S.R. 2007. Natural language processing and text mining: Springer Science &amp; Business Media.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Kobayashi, V.B. et al. 2018. Text mining in organizational research. Organizational Research Methods , 21(3), pp. 733-765.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Kraft, M.E. and Furlong, S.R. 2012. Public policy: Politics, analysis, and alternatives: Cq Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Kugo, A., Yoshikawa, H., Shimoda, H. and Wakabayashi, Y. 2005. Text mining analysis of public comments regarding high-level radioactive waste disposal. Journal of Nuclear Science and Technology, 42(9), pp.  755-767.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Ladi, S. 2005. Globalisation, policy transfer and policy research institutes. Cheltenham: Edward.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Li, C. 2017. Market Opportunity and Policy Support for Chinese Old Aging Industry: An Application of Text Mining. SHS Web of Conferences, EDP Sciences.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Lim, E.T. 2002. Five trends in presidential rhetoric: An analysis of rhetoric from George Washington to Bill Clinton. Presidential Studies Quarterly, 32(2), pp.  328-348.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Lincoln, Y.S. and Guba, E.G. 1985. Naturalistic inquiry. Beverly Hills, CA: Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Lourenço, R.P. and Costa, J.P. 2007. Incorporating citizens' views in local policy decision making processes. Decision Support Systems, 43(4), pp.  1499-1511.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Merriam, S.B. and Tisdell, E.J. 2009. Qualitative research: A guide to design and implementation: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Masahiko, O. 2013. Analysis of the Influence on Interregional Migration by the Region's Policy Priority: Measurement of policy priority sensitivities using text mining. Discussion Papers 13072. Research Institute of Economy, Trade and Industry (RIETI).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>May, P.J. 1992. Policy learning and failure. Journal of public policy, 12(4), pp.  331-354.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Meseguer, C. and Yebra, C.M. 2009. Learning, policy making, and market reforms: Cambridge University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Monarch, I.A. 2013. Information science and information systems: converging or diverging? Proceedings of the Annual Conference of CAIS/Actes du congrès annuel de l'ACSI.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Ngai, E. and Lee, P. 2016. A Review of the literature on Applications of Text Mining in Policy Making. PACIS.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Oe, H., Yamaoka, Y. and Hideshima, E. 2016. How to Support Decision Making of Local Government in Prioritising Policy Menu Responding to Citizens’ Views: An Exploratory Study of Text Mining Approach to Attain Cognitive Map Based on Citizen Survey Data. International Conference on Decision Support System Technology, Springer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Park, C. and Yong, T. 2017. Prospect of Korean nuclear policy change through text mining. Energy Procedia, Volume (128), pp. 72-78.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Park, S.J. et al. 2011. Networked politics on Cyworld: The text and sentiment of Korean political profiles. Social Science Computer Review, 29(3), pp. 288-299.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Quinn, K.M. et al. 2010. How to analyze political attention with minimal assumptions and costs. American Journal of Political Science, 54(1), pp.  209-228.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Ravikumar, S., Agrahari, A. and Singh, S. 2015. Mapping the intellectual structure of scientometrics: A co-word analysis of the journal Scientometrics (2005–2010). Scientometrics, 102(1), pp.  929-955.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Rose, R. 1991. What is Lesson-Drawing? Journal of Public Policy, 11(1), pp. 3- 30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Rose, R. 1993. Lesson-Drawing in Public Policy: A Guide to Learning across Time and Space. Chatham, NJ: Chatham House Publishers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Rose, R. 2005. Learning from Comparative Public Policy: A Practical Guide. London: Routledge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Sabatier, P.A. 1988. An advocacy coalition framework of policy change and the role of policy-oriented learning therein. Policy sciences, 21(2-3), pp. 129-168.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Schneider, A. and Ingram, H. 1988. Systematically pinching ideas: A comparative approach to policy design. Journal of public policy, 8(1), pp.  61-80.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, K.B. and Larimer, C.W. 2009. The public policy theory primer: Westview Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Sobkowicz, P., Kaschesky, M. and Bouchard, G. 2012. Opinion mining in social media: Modeling, simulating, and forecasting political opinions in the web. Government Information Quarterly, 29(4), pp.  470-479.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Stiglitz, J. 2000. Scan Globally, Reinvent Locally: Knowledge Infrastructure and the Localization of Knowledge, in: D. Stone (ed.) Banking on Knowledge: The Genesis of the Global Development Network. London: Routledge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Stone, D. 2000. Non-Governmental Policy Transfer: The Strategies of Independent Policy Institutes. Governance: An International Journal of Policy and Administration, 13(1), pp.  45- 62.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Stone, D. 2001. Learning Lessons, Policy Transfer and the International Diffusion of Policy Ideas. University of Warwick.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Stone, D. 2003. Banking on knowledge: the genesis of the Global Development Network: Routledge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Tadashi, M. 2016. Policy Agenda and Local Assembly Reform in the North Kanto Region: Analysis of the Minutes of the Seven Major City Assemblies using Text-mining Approach. Studies of regional policy, 18(2/3), pp. 33-49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Talamini, E. and Dewes, H. 2012. The macro-environment for liquid biofuels in Brazilian science and public policies. Science and Public Policy, 39(1), pp. 13-29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Talamini, E., Wubben, E.F. and Dewes, H. 2013. The Macro-Environment for Liquid Biofuels in German Science, Mass Media and Government. Review of European Studies, 5(2), p. 33.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Thelwall, M., Vann, K. and Fairclough, R. 2006. Web issue analysis: An integrated water resource management case study. Journal of the American Society for information Science and Technology, 57(10), pp.1303-1314.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Velasquez, J.D. and Gonzalez, P. 2010. Expanding the possibilities of deliberation: The use of data mining for strengthening democracy with an application to education reform. The Information Society ,26(1), pp. 1-16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Wen, M. 2018. A Co-Word Analysis on Policy of Business Incubator in Guangdong Province. Open Journal of Business and Management, Volume (6), pp.  214-224.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Whittington, R. 2001. What is strategy-and does it matter? 2 ed: Cengage Learning.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Wolman, H. 1992. Understanding cross national policy transfers: the case of Britain and the US. Governance, 5(1), pp.  27-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Wormell, I. 2000. Critical aspects of the Danish welfare state as revealed by issue tracking. Scientometrics, 48(2), pp.  237-250.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Wu, S. and Chu, S. 2013. The text mining and classification analyses on the relationship of Macau special administrative region's policy addresses from 2012 to 2013. International Conference on Engineering, Management Science and Innovation (ICEMSI), IEEE.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Yan, B.-N., Lee, T.-S. and Lee, T.-P. 2015. Mapping the intellectual structure of the Internet of Things (IoT) field (2000–2014): a co-word analysis. Scientometrics, 105(2), pp. 1285-1300.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>بنیاد توسعه علوم و فناوری‌های هوافضا ۱۳۹۳. روش‌شناسی تدوین اسناد سیاست‌گذاری و ره‌نگاشت با نگاه به بخش هوافضا. تهران: بنیاد توسعه علوم و فناوری‌های هوافضا.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>پورعزت، ع.ا. و سوداگر، ه. 1391. تبیین فراگرد شکل‌گیری استراتژی در سازمان‌های دولتی فعال در عرصه سیاسی ج.ا. ایران. پژوهش‌های مدیریت در ایران 16(2)، صص. 35-56.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>حاجی‌پور، ب. و ناجی، م. 1390. گونه‌شناسی شکل‌گیری استراتژی در سازمان‌های دولتی فعال در عرصه اقتصادی جمهوری اسلامی ایران. اندیشه مدیریت راهبردی 5(1)، صص. 99-124._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Aerospace Science and Technology Development Foundation. 2014. Methodology for policy making and creating technology roadmaps by looking at the aerospace sector. Tehran: Aerospace Science and Technology Development Foundation.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Alder, E. and Bernstein, S. 2005. Knowledge in Power: The Epistemic Construction of Global Governance. In M. Barnett and R. Duvall eds. Power in Global Governance. Cambridge, Cambridge University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Altaweel, M. and Bone, C. 2012. Applying content analysis for investigating the reporting of water issues. Computers, Environment and Urban Systems, 36(6), pp. 599-613.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Bailey, C.A. 2007. A guide to qualitative field research: Sage Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Charalabidis, Y. and Loukis, E. 2012. Participative public policy making through multiple social media platforms utilization. International Journal of Electronic Government Research (IJEGR,), 8(3), pp. 78-97.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Cho, J. 2014. Intellectual structure of the institutional repository field: A co-word analysis. Journal of Information Science, 40(3), pp. 386-397.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Choudhary, A.K., Oluikpe, P., Harding, J.A. and Carrillo, P.M. 2009. The needs and benefits of Text Mining applications on Post-Project Reviews. Computers in Industry, 60(9), pp. 728-740.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Common, R. 2001. Public management and policy transfer in Southeast Asia. Aldershot: Ashgate.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Common, R. 2004. Organisational learning in a political environment: Improving policy-making in UK government. Policy studies, 25(1), pp. 35-49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>De Fortuny, E.J., De Smedt, T., Martens, D. and Daelemans, W. 2012. Media coverage in times of political crisis: A text mining approach. Expert Systems with Applications, 39(14), pp. 11616-11622.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Derrick, G., Meijer, I. and Van Wijk, E. 2014. Unwrapping “impact” for evaluation: A co-word analysis of the UK REF2014 policy documents using VOSviewer. Proceedings of the science and technology indicators conference.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Dolowitz, D. and Marsh, D. 1996. Who Learns What from Whom: a Review of the Policy Transfer Literature. Political Studies, 44(2), pp. 343-351.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Dolowitz, D. and Marsh, D. 2000. Learning from Abroad: The Role of Policy Transfer in Contemporary Policy-Making. Governance: An International Journal of Policy and Administration, 3(1),pp. 5- 24.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Dye, T. 2008. Understanding public policy. Pearson: Prentice Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Evans, M. 2004. Policy transfer in global perspective. Aldershot: Ashgate.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Evans, M. 2009. Policy transfer in critical perspective. Policy Studies, 30(3), pp. 243- 268.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Evans, M. and Davies, J. 1999. Understanding policy transfer: A Multi‐level, multi‐disciplinary perspective. Public administration, 77(2), pp. 361-385.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Feng, J., Zhang, Y.Q. and Zhang, H. 2017. Improving the co-word analysis method based on semantic distance. Scientometrics, 111(3), pp. 1521-1531.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Gal-Tzur, A. et al. 2014. The potential of social media in delivering transport policy goals. Transport Policy, Volume (32), pp. 115-123.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Given, L.M. 2008. The Sage encyclopedia of qualitative research methods: Sage Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Haas, P.M. 1989. Do regimes matter? Epistemic communities and Mediterranean pollution control. International organization, 43(3), pp. 377-403.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Hajipour, B. and Naji, M. 2011. Typology of Strategy Formation in Economic Public Organizations of Iran. Strategic Management Thought 5(1) 99-124.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Hashimi, H., Hafez, A. and Mathkour, H. 2015. Selection criteria for text mining approaches. Computers in Human Behavior, Volume (51), pp. 729-733.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Heclo, H. 2010. Modern social politics in Britain and Sweden: ECPR Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Hulme, R. 2005. Policy Transfer and the Internationalisation of Social Policy. Social Policy &amp; Society, 4(4), pp. 417- 425.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Kang, Y., Shin, J. and Park, C. 2016. Assessing climate change risk and adaptation policy improvements through text-mining. Urban Design, Volume (17), pp.  69-84.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Kantardzic, M. 2011. Data mining: concepts, models, methods, and algorithms: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Kao, A. and Poteet, S.R. 2007. Natural language processing and text mining: Springer Science &amp; Business Media.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Kobayashi, V.B. et al. 2018. Text mining in organizational research. Organizational Research Methods , 21(3), pp. 733-765.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Kraft, M.E. and Furlong, S.R. 2012. Public policy: Politics, analysis, and alternatives: Cq Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Kugo, A., Yoshikawa, H., Shimoda, H. and Wakabayashi, Y. 2005. Text mining analysis of public comments regarding high-level radioactive waste disposal. Journal of Nuclear Science and Technology, 42(9), pp.  755-767.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Ladi, S. 2005. Globalisation, policy transfer and policy research institutes. Cheltenham: Edward.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Li, C. 2017. Market Opportunity and Policy Support for Chinese Old Aging Industry: An Application of Text Mining. SHS Web of Conferences, EDP Sciences.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Lim, E.T. 2002. Five trends in presidential rhetoric: An analysis of rhetoric from George Washington to Bill Clinton. Presidential Studies Quarterly, 32(2), pp.  328-348.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Lincoln, Y.S. and Guba, E.G. 1985. Naturalistic inquiry. Beverly Hills, CA: Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Lourenço, R.P. and Costa, J.P. 2007. Incorporating citizens' views in local policy decision making processes. Decision Support Systems, 43(4), pp.  1499-1511.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Merriam, S.B. and Tisdell, E.J. 2009. Qualitative research: A guide to design and implementation: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Masahiko, O. 2013. Analysis of the Influence on Interregional Migration by the Region's Policy Priority: Measurement of policy priority sensitivities using text mining. Discussion Papers 13072. Research Institute of Economy, Trade and Industry (RIETI).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>May, P.J. 1992. Policy learning and failure. Journal of public policy, 12(4), pp.  331-354.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Meseguer, C. and Yebra, C.M. 2009. Learning, policy making, and market reforms: Cambridge University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>Monarch, I.A. 2013. Information science and information systems: converging or diverging? Proceedings of the Annual Conference of CAIS/Actes du congrès annuel de l'ACSI.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>Ngai, E. and Lee, P. 2016. A Review of the literature on Applications of Text Mining in Policy Making. PACIS.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Oe, H., Yamaoka, Y. and Hideshima, E. 2016. How to Support Decision Making of Local Government in Prioritising Policy Menu Responding to Citizens’ Views: An Exploratory Study of Text Mining Approach to Attain Cognitive Map Based on Citizen Survey Data. International Conference on Decision Support System Technology, Springer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>Park, C. and Yong, T. 2017. Prospect of Korean nuclear policy change through text mining. Energy Procedia, Volume (128), pp. 72-78.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R115">
			<label>115</label>
			<element-citation>Park, S.J. et al. 2011. Networked politics on Cyworld: The text and sentiment of Korean political profiles. Social Science Computer Review, 29(3), pp. 288-299.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R116">
			<label>116</label>
			<element-citation>Pourezzat, A. and Sodagar, H. 2012. Explaining the strategy formation process in governmental organizations in the political arena of the Islamic Republic of Iran. Management Research in Iran 16(2) 35-56.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R117">
			<label>117</label>
			<element-citation>Quinn, K.M. et al. 2010. How to analyze political attention with minimal assumptions and costs. American Journal of Political Science, 54(1), pp.  209-228.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R118">
			<label>118</label>
			<element-citation>Ravikumar, S., Agrahari, A. and Singh, S. 2015. Mapping the intellectual structure of scientometrics: A co-word analysis of the journal Scientometrics (2005–2010). Scientometrics, 102(1), pp.  929-955.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R119">
			<label>119</label>
			<element-citation>Rose, R. 1991. What is Lesson-Drawing? Journal of Public Policy, 11(1), pp. 3- 30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R120">
			<label>120</label>
			<element-citation>Rose, R. 1993. Lesson-Drawing in Public Policy: A Guide to Learning across Time and Space. Chatham, NJ: Chatham House Publishers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R121">
			<label>121</label>
			<element-citation>Rose, R. 2005. Learning from Comparative Public Policy: A Practical Guide. London: Routledge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R122">
			<label>122</label>
			<element-citation>Sabatier, P.A. 1988. An advocacy coalition framework of policy change and the role of policy-oriented learning therein. Policy sciences, 21(2-3), pp. 129-168.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R123">
			<label>123</label>
			<element-citation>Schneider, A. and Ingram, H. 1988. Systematically pinching ideas: A comparative approach to policy design. Journal of public policy, 8(1), pp.  61-80.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R124">
			<label>124</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, K.B. and Larimer, C.W. 2009. The public policy theory primer: Westview Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R125">
			<label>125</label>
			<element-citation>Sobkowicz, P., Kaschesky, M. and Bouchard, G. 2012. Opinion mining in social media: Modeling, simulating, and forecasting political opinions in the web. Government Information Quarterly, 29(4), pp.  470-479.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R126">
			<label>126</label>
			<element-citation>Stiglitz, J. 2000. Scan Globally, Reinvent Locally: Knowledge Infrastructure and the Localization of Knowledge, in: D. Stone (ed.) Banking on Knowledge: The Genesis of the Global Development Network. London: Routledge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R127">
			<label>127</label>
			<element-citation>Stone, D. 2000. Non-Governmental Policy Transfer: The Strategies of Independent Policy Institutes. Governance: An International Journal of Policy and Administration, 13(1), pp.  45- 62.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R128">
			<label>128</label>
			<element-citation>Stone, D. 2001. Learning Lessons, Policy Transfer and the International Diffusion of Policy Ideas. University of Warwick.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R129">
			<label>129</label>
			<element-citation>Stone, D. 2003. Banking on knowledge: the genesis of the Global Development Network: Routledge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R130">
			<label>130</label>
			<element-citation>Tadashi, M. 2016. Policy Agenda and Local Assembly Reform in the North Kanto Region: Analysis of the Minutes of the Seven Major City Assemblies using Text-mining Approach. Studies of regional policy, 18(2/3), pp. 33-49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R131">
			<label>131</label>
			<element-citation>Talamini, E. and Dewes, H. 2012. The macro-environment for liquid biofuels in Brazilian science and public policies. Science and Public Policy, 39(1), pp. 13-29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R132">
			<label>132</label>
			<element-citation>Talamini, E., Wubben, E.F. and Dewes, H. 2013. The Macro-Environment for Liquid Biofuels in German Science, Mass Media and Government. Review of European Studies, 5(2), p. 33.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R133">
			<label>133</label>
			<element-citation>Thelwall, M., Vann, K. and Fairclough, R. 2006. Web issue analysis: An integrated water resource management case study. Journal of the American Society for information Science and Technology, 57(10), pp.1303-1314.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R134">
			<label>134</label>
			<element-citation>Velasquez, J.D. and Gonzalez, P. 2010. Expanding the possibilities of deliberation: The use of data mining for strengthening democracy with an application to education reform. The Information Society ,26(1), pp. 1-16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R135">
			<label>135</label>
			<element-citation>Wen, M. 2018. A Co-Word Analysis on Policy of Business Incubator in Guangdong Province. Open Journal of Business and Management, Volume (6), pp.  214-224.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R136">
			<label>136</label>
			<element-citation>Whittington, R. 2001. What is strategy-and does it matter? 2 ed: Cengage Learning.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R137">
			<label>137</label>
			<element-citation>Wolman, H. 1992. Understanding cross national policy transfers: the case of Britain and the US. Governance, 5(1), pp.  27-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R138">
			<label>138</label>
			<element-citation>Wormell, I. 2000. Critical aspects of the Danish welfare state as revealed by issue tracking. Scientometrics, 48(2), pp.  237-250.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R139">
			<label>139</label>
			<element-citation>Wu, S. and Chu, S. 2013. The text mining and classification analyses on the relationship of Macau special administrative region's policy addresses from 2012 to 2013. International Conference on Engineering, Management Science and Innovation (ICEMSI), IEEE.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R140">
			<label>140</label>
			<element-citation>Yan, B.-N., Lee, T.-S. and Lee, T.-P. 2015. Mapping the intellectual structure of the Internet of Things (IoT) field (2000–2014): a co-word analysis. Scientometrics, 105(2), pp. 1285-1300</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_69190_89c048dea5e60f2c23700a19369246fb.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>ساختارها و فرآیندهای پشتیبان نوآوری</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>خوشه‌بندی و بررسی عملکرد الگوهای یادگیری در صنایع با سطح فناوری بالا و متوسط</article-title>
			        <subtitle>خوشه‌بندی و بررسی عملکرد الگوهای یادگیری در صنایع با سطح فناوری بالا و متوسط</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>سهرابی</surname>
			            <given-names>سمیه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه مدیریت تکنولوژی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران ،ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محمدی</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2018</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>91</fpage>
			      <lpage>118</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>24</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>17</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_69190.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_69190.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>باتوجه به اهمیت نوآوری، امروزه سازمان‌ها در تلاش اند با ارتقای آن به مزیت رقابتی و سهم بیشتر بازار دست پیدا کنند.در چنین شرایطی، افزایش قابلیت‌های یادگیری سازمان می‌تواند بهترین راه برای دستیابی به این موفقیت و همچنین بهره‌برداری از فرصت‌ها و انواع مختلف نوآوری باشد. بدین منظور شناسایی سبک‌های مختلف یادگیری و نوآوری کمک بسزایی در این امر دارد لذا در تحقیقات پیشین دو سبک نوآوری و یادگیری از طریق علم، فناوری و نوآوری (STI)و یادگیری از طریق انجام، استفاده و تعامل (DUI) مورد بررسی قرارگرفته شده اند. در این تحقیق نیز سعی شده است با شناخت الگوهای یادگیری و نوآوری در728 شرکت فعال در دوحوزه با سطح فناوری بالا (صنعت فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات) و متوسط(صنعت نفت و گاز و قطعه سازی خودرو) در ایران به عنوان یک کشوردرحال توسعه زمینه‌ای در راستای اتخاذ سیاست‌های توسعه و ارتقای توانمندی نوآوری را فراهم نماید. لذا با تبیین شاخص‌های مناسب ارزیابی الگوهای یادگیری با روش تحلیل کلاس پنهان، چهار خوشه 1-سبک یادگیری تلفیقیDUI متوسط+ STI خوب، 2-سبک یادگیری DUI،3-سبک یادگیری تلفیقی(STI+DUI) قوی،4-سبک یادگیری STI متوسط شناسایی شده است.در آخر تاثیر الگوهای فوق بر عملکرد شرکت ها با روش رگرسیون لجستیک، مورد آزمون قرار گرفته و مشخص می شود سازمان‌هایی که از سبک یادگیری تلفیقی STI+DUI تبعیت می کنند از موفقیت بیشتری در رشدمالی، گستردگی عرضه کالا و نوآوری برخوردارند.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>DUI</kwd>
						<kwd>STI</kwd>
						<kwd>سبک‌های یادگیری و نوآوری</kwd>
						<kwd>خوشه بندی</kwd>
						<kwd>تحلیل کلاس پنهان</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Amara, N., Landry, R., Becheikh, N. and Ouimet, M., 2008. Learning and novelty of innovation in established manufacturing SMEs. Technovation, 28(7), pp. 450-463.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Apanasovich, N., 2016. Modes of innovation: a grounded meta-analysis. Journal of the Knowledge Economy, 7(3), pp. 720-737.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Apanasovich, N., 2014. The impact of business innovation on innovation performance: the case of Belarus. Doctoral dissertation, Deusto University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Aslesen, H.W., Isaksen, A. and Karlsen, J., 2012. Modes of innovation and differentiated responses to globalisation a case study of innovation modes in the Agder region, Norway. Journal of the Knowledge Economy, 3(4), pp. 389-405.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, J. and Guo, A., 2010. An empirical study on the relationship between the STI/DUI Learning and technological innovation performance in Chinese's industries. In International Schumpeter Society Conference (Vol. 120).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Corricher, N., Cusmano, L. and Morrison, A., 2011. Competitive strategies and innovation modes in KIBS: Evidence from Lombardy. University of Padua, pp. 18-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Fitjar, R.D. and Rodríguez-Pose, A., 2013. Firm collaboration and modes of innovation in Norway. Research Policy, 42(1), pp. 128-138.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Gokhberg, L., Kuznetsova, T. and Roud, V., 2012. Exploring Innovation Modes of Russian Companies: what does the diversity of actors mean for policymaking?. Higher School of Economics Research Paper No. WP BRP 01/STI/2012 . Available at SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=2156347 or http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2156347</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>González-Pernía, J.L., Parrilli, M.D. and Peña-Legazkue, I., 2015. STI–DUI learning modes, firm–university collaboration and innovation. The Journal of Technology Transfer, 40(3), pp. 475-492.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>González-Pernía, J.L., Parrilli, M.D. and Peña, I., 2012. Learning modes, types of innovation and economic performance (No. 2012-R01, pp. 1989-1288). Orkestra Working Paper Series in Territorial Competitiveness.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Isaksen, A. and Karlsen, J., 2010. Different modes of innovation and the challenge of connecting universities and industry: case studies of two regional industries in Norway. European Planning Studies, 18(12), pp. 1993-2008.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Isaksen, A. and Nilsson, M., 2013. Combined innovation policy: Linking scientific and practical knowledge in innovation systems. European Planning Studies, 21(12), pp. 1919-1936.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Jensen, M.B., Johnson, B., Lorenz, E. and Lundvall, B.Å., 2007. Forms of knowledge and modes of innovation. Research Policy, 36(5), pp. 680-693.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Lorenz, E. and Lundvall, B.Å. eds., 2006. How Europe's economies learn: coordinating competing models. Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B.Å., 2007. National innovation systems—analytical concept and development tool. Industry and innovation, 14(1), pp. 95-119.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B.Ä. and Johnson, B., 1994. The learning economy. Journal of industry studies, 1(2), pp. 23-42.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Frenz, M. and Lambert, R., 2009. Exploring non-technological and mixed modes of innovation across countries. Innovation in Firms, pp. 69-110.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>McCutcheon, A.L., 1987. Latent class analysis. SAGE Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Othman Idrissia, M., Amaraa, N. and Landrya, R., 2012. SMEs’ degree of openness: the case of manufacturing industries. Journal of technology management &amp; innovation, 7(1), pp. 186-210.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Parrilli, M.D. and Elola, A., 2012. The strength of science and technology drivers for SME innovation. Small Business Economics, 39(4), pp. 897-907.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Pater, R. and Lewandowska, A., 2015. Human capital and innovativeness of the European Union regions. Innovation: The European Journal of Social Science Research, 28(1), pp. 31-51.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Tödtling, F., Lehner, P. and Kaufmann, A., 2006. Do different types of innovation require different kinds of knowledge interactions. In 46th European Congress of the European Regional Science Association.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Tödtling, F., Lehner, P. and Trippl, M., 2004. Knowledge intensive industries, networks, and collective learning.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Trigo, A. and Vence, X., 2012. Scope and patterns of innovation cooperation in Spanish service enterprises. Research Policy, 41(3), pp. 602-613.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Trigo, A., 2013. The nature of innovation in R&amp;D-and non-R&amp;D-intensive service firms: evidence from firm-level latent class analysis. Industry and Innovation, 20(1), pp. 48-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Parrilli, M.D. and Heras, H.A., 2016. STI and DUI innovation modes: Scientific-technological and context-specific nuances. Research Policy, 45(4), pp. 747-756.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>OECD, 2011, Directorate for Science, Technology and Industry Economic Analysis and Statistics Division.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>شجاعی،آرش. 1394. بررسی سازوکارهای یادگیری در نظام نوآوری فناورانه. پایان­نامه کارشناسی ارشد.دانشکده علوم و فنون نوین دانشگاه تهران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>محمدی، مهدی؛ باقری­مقدم، ناصر؛ شجاعی چرمینه، آرش،1396. "تحلیل سبک‌های یادگیری و نوآوری در کشورهای در حال توسعه(  مطالعه موردی بخش فاوا ایران)"، فصلنامه سیاست علم و فناوری، دوره نهم، شماره 1، صص. 53-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>گزارش پیمایش نوآوری معاونت علمی و فناوری ریاست جمهوری، 1394._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Amara, N., Landry, R., Becheikh, N. and Ouimet, M., 2008. Learning and novelty of innovation in established manufacturing SMEs. Technovation, 28(7), pp. 450-463.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Apanasovich, N., 2016. Modes of innovation: a grounded meta-analysis. Journal of the Knowledge Economy, 7(3), pp. 720-737.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Apanasovich, N., 2014. The impact of business innovation on innovation performance: the case of Belarus. Doctoral dissertation, Deusto University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Aslesen, H.W., Isaksen, A. and Karlsen, J., 2012. Modes of innovation and differentiated responses to globalisation a case study of innovation modes in the Agder region, Norway. Journal of the Knowledge Economy, 3(4), pp. 389-405.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, J. and Guo, A., 2010. An empirical study on the relationship between the STI/DUI Learning and technological innovation performance in Chinese's industries. In International Schumpeter Society Conference (Vol. 120).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Corricher, N., Cusmano, L. and Morrison, A., 2011. Competitive strategies and innovation modes in KIBS: Evidence from Lombardy. University of Padua, pp. 18-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Fitjar, R.D. and Rodríguez-Pose, A., 2013. Firm collaboration and modes of innovation in Norway. Research Policy, 42(1), pp. 128-138.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Gokhberg, L., Kuznetsova, T. and Roud, V., 2012. Exploring Innovation Modes of Russian Companies: what does the diversity of actors mean for policymaking?. Higher School of Economics Research Paper No. WP BRP 01/STI/2012 . Available at SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=2156347 or http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.2156347</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>González-Pernía, J.L., Parrilli, M.D. and Peña-Legazkue, I., 2015. STI–DUI learning modes, firm–university collaboration and innovation. The Journal of Technology Transfer, 40(3), pp. 475-492.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>González-Pernía, J.L., Parrilli, M.D. and Peña, I., 2012. Learning modes, types of innovation and economic performance (No. 2012-R01, pp. 1989-1288). Orkestra Working Paper Series in Territorial Competitiveness.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Isaksen, A. and Karlsen, J., 2010. Different modes of innovation and the challenge of connecting universities and industry: case studies of two regional industries in Norway. European Planning Studies, 18(12), pp. 1993-2008.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Isaksen, A. and Nilsson, M., 2013. Combined innovation policy: Linking scientific and practical knowledge in innovation systems. European Planning Studies, 21(12), pp. 1919-1936.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Jensen, M.B., Johnson, B., Lorenz, E. and Lundvall, B.Å., 2007. Forms of knowledge and modes of innovation. Research Policy, 36(5), pp. 680-693.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Lorenz, E. and Lundvall, B.Å. eds., 2006. How Europe's economies learn: coordinating competing models. Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B.Å., 2007. National innovation systems—analytical concept and development tool. Industry and innovation, 14(1), pp. 95-119.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B.Ä. and Johnson, B., 1994. The learning economy. Journal of industry studies, 1(2), pp. 23-42.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Frenz, M. and Lambert, R., 2009. Exploring non-technological and mixed modes of innovation across countries. Innovation in Firms, pp. 69-110.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>McCutcheon, A.L., 1987. Latent class analysis. SAGE Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammadi, M., Bagheri Moghadam, N., Shojaei, A. 2017. Analysis of Learning and Innovation Modes in Developing Countries; Case study ICT in Iran, Journal of Science &amp; Technology Policy,9(1), pp. 53-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Othman Idrissia, M., Amaraa, N. and Landrya, R., 2012. SMEs’ degree of openness: the case of manufacturing industries. Journal of technology management &amp; innovation, 7(1), pp. 186-210.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>OECD, 2011, Directorate for Science, Technology and Industry Economic Analysis and Statistics Division.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Parrilli, M.D. and Elola, A., 2012. The strength of science and technology drivers for SME innovation. Small Business Economics, 39(4), pp. 897-907.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Parrilli, M.D. and Heras, H.A., 2016. STI and DUI innovation modes: Scientific-technological and context-specific nuances. Research Policy, 45(4), pp. 747-756.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Pater, R. and Lewandowska, A., 2015. Human capital and innovativeness of the European Union regions. Innovation: The European Journal of Social Science Research, 28(1), pp. 31-51.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Reports on Innovation Survey of the Vice President of Science and Technology of the Presidency, 2015.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Shojaei, A. 2015. Study of Learning Mechanisms in the Technology Innovation System. Master's Degree. Faculty of Science and Technology of Tehran University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Tödtling, F., Lehner, P. and Kaufmann, A., 2006. Do different types of innovation require different kinds of knowledge interactions. In 46th European Congress of the European Regional Science Association.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Tödtling, F., Lehner, P. and Trippl, M., 2004. Knowledge intensive industries, networks, and collective learning.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Trigo, A. and Vence, X., 2012. Scope and patterns of innovation cooperation in Spanish service enterprises. Research Policy, 41(3), pp. 602-613.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Trigo, A., 2013. The nature of innovation in R&amp;D-and non-R&amp;D-intensive service firms: evidence from firm-level latent class analysis. Industry and Innovation, 20(1), pp. 48-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81020_9c0a309751b612bd1430b02c068eefb6.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>توسعه محصول، خدمت و فرآیند جدید</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>الگوی توسعه خدمت جدید در اپراتوری تلفن همراه ایران</article-title>
			        <subtitle>الگوی توسعه خدمت جدید در اپراتوری تلفن همراه ایران</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حسنی پارسا</surname>
			            <given-names>مجید</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>مدیر اجرایی پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>الیاسی</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>طباطبائیان</surname>
			            <given-names>سید حبیب ا...</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار دانشکده حسابداری و مدیریت دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حنفی زاده</surname>
			            <given-names>پیام</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار دانشکده حسابداری و مدیریت دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2018</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>119</fpage>
			      <lpage>152</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>14</day>
			          <month>12</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>19</day>
			          <month>11</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81020.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81020.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>در دنیای امروز که سهم خدمات در اقتصاد کشورها همواره در حال افزایش است، نوآوری در خدمات و توسعه خدمت جدید (NSD)، برای بنگاه‌های خدماتی بسیار مهم و حیاتی شده است. اما علی‌رغم این اهمیت، مطالعات کافی در مورد الگوهای توسعه خدمت جدید در برخی از صنایع خدماتی (مانند اپراتوری تلفن همراه) در کشورمان انجام نشده است. پژوهش حاضر با هدف پرکردن این شکاف تحقیقاتی و با رویکردی کیفی مبتنی بر مطالعه موردی (از نوع چندموردی) به بررسی الگوی توسعه خدمت جدید در اپراتوری تلفن همراه ایران پرداخته است. در گام اول این پژوهش، الگوهای توسعه خدمت جدید در ادبیات موضوع بررسی و تحلیل شده و الگوی مفهومی توسعه خدمت جدید استخراج شد. در گام بعدی، از آنجا که الگوی توسعه خدمت جدید در هر بخش و یا کشوری تحت شرایط خاص آن بخش و کشور مورد مطالعه تفاوت می‌کند، مطالعه چندموردی انجام‌شده و الگوی اولیه توسعه خدمت جدید با تحلیل بین موردیِ مطالعات انجام‌شده ارائه شد. در پایان نیز الگوی پیشنهادی توسعه خدمت جدید در اپراتوری تلفن همراه ایران با مقایسه و تحلیل الگوهای مفهومی و اولیه ارائه شده است.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>توسعه خدمت جدید</kwd>
						<kwd>تلفن همراه</kwd>
						<kwd>مطالعه چندموردی</kwd>
						<kwd>الگوی فرآیندی</kwd>
						<kwd>ایران</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Ahn, J.H., Kim, M.S., and Lee, D.J. (2005). Learning from the failure: experiences in the Korean telecommunications market, Technovation, Vol. 25, pp. 69–82.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Alam, I. (2013). Customer interaction in service innovation: evidence from India, International Journal of Emerging Markets, Vol. 8, Iss 1, pp. 41 – 64.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Alam, I. (2010). Does service innovation process differ across cultures? Asia Pacific Journal of Marketing and Logistics, Vol. 22 Iss: 4 pp. 460 – 472</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Alam, I. (2006). Service innovation strategy and process: a cross-national comparative analysis, International Marketing Review, 23(3), pp. 234-254.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Avlonitis, G.J. (2001). An empirically based typology of product innovativeness for new financial services: success and failure scenarios, The Journal of Product Innovation management, 18(5), pp. 324-342.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Bae, D. and Leem, C. (2014). a visual interactive method for service prototyping, Managing Service Quality, Vol. 24, Iss 4, pp. 339 – 362.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Booz, Allen and Hamilton (1982). New Products Management for the 1980s, New York: Booz, Allen and Hamilton Inc.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Boukis, A. (2013). Identifying some internal S/F factors of NSD project performance, International Journal of Retail &amp; Distribution Management, Vol. 41, Iss. 7, pp. 531 – 544.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Bowers, M.R. (1985). An Exploration in to New Service Development; Process, Structure and Organization, A PHD Dissertation by Michael Roy Bowers, Texas A&amp;M University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Burger, T., Ganz1, W., Pezzotta, G., Rapaccini, M. and Saccani, N. (2010). Service development for product services: a maturity model and a field research, Working Paper, European Association for research on services (RESER).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Carbonell, P. and Rodriguez-Escudero, A.I. (2014). Antecedents and consequences of using information from customers involved in new service development, Journal of Business &amp; Industrial Marketing, Vol. 29, Iss 2, pp. 112 – 122.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Carbonell, P., Rodriguez-Escudero, A.I. and Pujari, D. (2012). Performance effects of involving lead users and close customers in new service development, Journal of Services Marketing, Vol. 26, Iss. 7, pp. 497 – 509.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Cheng, C.C., Chen, J.S. and Tsou, H.T. (2012). Market-creating service innovation: verification and its associations with new service development and customer involvement, Journal of Services Marketing, Vol. 26, Iss. 6, pp. 444 – 457.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, R.G. and Edgett, S.J. (2000). Product Development for the Service Sector: Lessons from Market Leaders, Cambridge, MA: Preseus Books.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Cowell, D.W. (1988). New service development, Journal of Marketing Management, 3(3), pp. 296-312.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Dolfsma, W. (2004). THE PROCESS OF NEW SERVICE DEVELOPMENT - ISSUES OF FORMALIZATION AND APPROPRIABILITY, International Journal of Innovation Management, Vol. 8, No. 3, pp. 319–337</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Donnely, J.H., Berry, L.L. and Thompson, T.W. (1985). Marketing Financial Services, Dow Jones-Irwin.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Droege, H., Hildebrand, D. and Heras Forcada, M.A. (2009). Innovation in services: present findings, and future pathways, Journal of Service Management, Vol. 20 Iss: 2.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Edvardsson, B., Meiren, T., Schäfer, A. and Witell, L. (2013). Having a strategy for new service development – does it really matter?, Journal of Service Management, Vol. 24, Iss 1, pp. 25 – 44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Edvardsson, B., Gustafsson, A. and Enquist, B. (2005). Challenges in New Service Development and Value Creation through Service, ISD’2005 conference, 14 - 17 August 2005, Karlstad University, Sweden.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Froehle, C.M. and Roth, A.V. (2007). A Resource-Process Framework of New Service Development, PRODUCTION AND OPERATIONS MANAGEMENT, Vol. 16, No. 2, pp. 169–188</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>GSMA &amp; A.T. Kearney (2013). The Mobile Economy, London, United Kingdom.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Jin, D., Chai, K.H. and Tan, K.C. (2014). new service development maturity model, Managing Service Quality: An International Journal, Vol. 24, Iss. 1, pp. 86 –116.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Johne, A. and Storey, C. (1998). New service development: a review of the literature and annotated bibliography, European Journal of Marketing, Vol. 32 Iss: 3, pp. 184 – 251.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Johnson, E.M., Scheuning, E.E. and Gaida, K.A. (1986). Profitable Service Marketing, Dow Jones-Irwin.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Kekkonnen, K., (2012). User-Centric New Service Development in Telecom Industry, Master’s thesis, School of Science, University of Aalto, Helsinki. Finland.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Kim, C., Choe, S., Choi, C. and Park, Y. (2008). A systematic approach to new mobile service creation, Expert Systems with Applications, Vol. 35 pp. 762–771.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Kwang-Jae, K., Deok-Hwan, K., Kwangsoo, K. and Byung-In, K. (2007). A Model of Rapid New Service Development Process, Department of Industrial and Management Engineering, Pohang University of Science and Technology, Republic of Korea.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Larbig-Wüst, C. (2010). Measuring Customer Involvement in New Service Development Projects, PHD thesis, Faculty of Management, Cass Business School, City University of London.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Lin F.R. and Hsieh P.S. (2011). A SAT View on New Service Development, Journal of Service Science, 3(2), pp. 141-157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Melton, H.L. and Hartline, M.D. (2010). Customer and Frontline Employee Influence on New Service Development Performance, Journal of Service Research, 13(4), pp. 411-425.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Melton, H.L. (2007), A FRAMEWORK FOR EFFECTIVE CUSTOMER AND FRONTLINE EMPLOYEE INVOLVEMENT IN NEW SERVICE DEVELOPMENT, PHD Dissertation, COLLEGE OF BUSINESS, THE FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Menora, L.J., Tatikonda, M.V. and Sampson, S.E. (2002), new service development: areas for exploitation and exploration, Journal of Operations Management, Vol. 20, pp. 135–157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Meyer, C.B. (2001). A case in case study methodology, Filed Methods, 13(4), pp. 329-352.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammed-Salleh, A. and Easingwood, C. (1993). Why European financial institutions do not test-market new consumer products, International Journal of Bank Marketing, 11(3), pp. 23-27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Nijssen, E.J., Hillebrand, B., Vermeulen, P.A.M. and Kemp, R.G.M. (2006). Exploring product and service innovation similarities and differences, International Journal of Research in Marketing, Vol 23: 241–251.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Oduori, F.N. (2010). New service development: strategy and process in the hospitality sector in Kenya, 19th EDAMBA Summer Academy, Soreze, France.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Office of the undersecretary of defense, (2010). Taxonomy for the Acquisition of Service, US Department of Defense, 3000 Defense Pentagon, Washington, USA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD), (2000). The Service Economy, Business and Industry Policy Forum Series.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Posselt, T. and Förstl, K. (2011). Success Factors in New Service Development: a Literature Review, RESER (European Association for Research on Service) Conference Papers, Hamburg, Germany, 7- 10 September 2011.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Riedl, C., Leimeistery, J.M. and Krcmarz, H. (2009). New Service Development for Electronic Services - A Literature Review, Americas Conference on Information Systems (AMCIS).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Sandén, B. (2007). The Customer's Role in New Service Development, PHD thesis, Karlstad University, Sweden.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Santos, J.B. and Spring, M. (2013). New service development: managing the dynamic between services and operations resources, International Journal of Operations &amp; Production Management, Vol. 33, Iss. 7, pp. 800 – 827.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Scheuing, E.E. and Johnson, E.M. (1989). A Proposed Model for New Service Development, The Journal of Services Marketing, Vol3, No2.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Shekar, A. (2007). An Innovative Model of Service Development: A process guide for service managers, The Innovation Journal: The Public Sector Innovation Journal, Volume 12 (1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, A.M., Fischbacher, M. and Wilson, F.A. (2007). New Service Development: From Panoramas to Precision, European Management Journal, Vol. 25, No. 5, pp. 370–383.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Spath, D., Husen, C.V., Meyer, K. and Elze, R. (2007). Integrated Development of Software and Service – The Challenges of IT-Enabled Service Products, In D. Spath and K.P. Fähnrich (Eds.), Advances in Services Innovations, Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg, Germany.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Stevens, E. and Dimitriadis, S. (2005(. managing the new service development process: towards a systemic model, European Journal of Marketing, Vol. 39 Iss: 1 pp. 175 – 198.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Sundbo, J. (2007). Innovation and Learning in Services – The Involvement of Employees, In D. Spath and K.P. Fähnrich (Eds.), Advances in Services Innovations, Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg, Germany.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Tajeddini, K. (2011). CUSTOMER ORIENTATION, LEARNING ORIENTATION, AND NEW SERVICE DEVELOPMENT: AN EMPIRICAL INVESTIGATION OF THE SWISS HOTEL INDUSTRY, Journal of Hospitality &amp; Tourism Research, Vol. 35, No. 4, pp. 437-468.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Tatikonda, M.V. and Zeithaml, V.A. (2002). New Directions in Supply-Chain Management, Technology, Strategy and Implementation, Boone and Ganeshan [eds.], American Management Association, New York, Chapter 10: Managing the New Service Development Process: Multi-Disciplinary Literature Synthesis and Directions for Future Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Tidd, J. and Hull, F.M. (2003). SERVICE INNOVATION: Organizational Responses to Technological Opportunities &amp; Market Imperatives, University of Sussex, UK.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Weerawardena, J. and McColl-Kennedy, J.R. (2002). New Service Development and Competitive Advantage: A Conceptual Model, Australasian Marketing Journal, Vol. 10 (1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Yin, R.K. (2003). Case study research: Design and methods, Sage publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Yoonsoo, O., Eui-ho, S., Jongyi, H. and Hyunseok, H. (2009). A feasibility test model for new telecom service development using MCDM method: A case study of video telephone service in Korea, Expert Systems with Applications, Vol. 36, pp. 6375–6388.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>چسبرو هنری (1391)، نوآوری باز خدماتی، برگردان: سید کامران باقری، نشر رسا.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>مشایخ جواد، طباطبائیان سیدحبیب‌الله، امیری مقصود و شکریه محمود (1395)، تأثیر عوامل زمینه‌ای بیرونی بر اتخاذ نوآوری باز با تأکید بر ویژگیهای بخش: شواهدی از شرکتهای بخش مواد پیشرفته در ایران، مدیریت نوآوری، سال پنجم، شماره 2، تابستان 1395، صفحه 1-31._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Ahn, J.H., Kim, M.S., and Lee, D.J. (2005). Learning from the failure: experiences in the Korean telecommunications market, Technovation, Vol. 25, pp. 69–82.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Alam, I. (2013). Customer interaction in service innovation: evidence from India, International Journal of Emerging Markets, Vol. 8, Iss 1, pp. 41 – 64.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Alam, I. (2010). Does service innovation process differ across cultures? Asia Pacific Journal of Marketing and Logistics, Vol. 22 Iss: 4 pp. 460 – 472</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Alam, I. (2006). Service innovation strategy and process: a cross-national comparative analysis, International Marketing Review, 23(3), pp. 234-254.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Avlonitis, G.J. (2001). An empirically based typology of product innovativeness for new financial services: success and failure scenarios, The Journal of Product Innovation management, 18(5), pp. 324-342.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Bae, D. and Leem, C. (2014). a visual interactive method for service prototyping, Managing Service Quality, Vol. 24, Iss 4, pp. 339 – 362.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Booz, Allen and Hamilton (1982). New Products Management for the 1980s, New York: Booz, Allen and Hamilton Inc.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Boukis, A. (2013). Identifying some internal S/F factors of NSD project performance, International Journal of Retail &amp; Distribution Management, Vol. 41, Iss. 7, pp. 531 – 544.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Bowers, M.R. (1985). An Exploration in to New Service Development; Process, Structure and Organization, A PHD Dissertation by Michael Roy Bowers, Texas A&amp;M University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Burger, T., Ganz1, W., Pezzotta, G., Rapaccini, M. and Saccani, N. (2010). Service development for product services: a maturity model and a field research, Working Paper, European Association for research on services (RESER).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Carbonell, P. and Rodriguez-Escudero, A.I. (2014). Antecedents and consequences of using information from customers involved in new service development, Journal of Business &amp; Industrial Marketing, Vol. 29, Iss 2, pp. 112 – 122.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Carbonell, P., Rodriguez-Escudero, A.I. and Pujari, D. (2012). Performance effects of involving lead users and close customers in new service development, Journal of Services Marketing, Vol. 26, Iss. 7, pp. 497 – 509.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Cheng, C.C., Chen, J.S. and Tsou, H.T. (2012). Market-creating service innovation: verification and its associations with new service development and customer involvement, Journal of Services Marketing, Vol. 26, Iss. 6, pp. 444 – 457.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H. (2011), Open Service Innovation, Rasa Publication, Tehran, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, R.G. and Edgett, S.J. (2000). Product Development for the Service Sector: Lessons from Market Leaders, Cambridge, MA: Preseus Books.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Cowell, D.W. (1988). New service development, Journal of Marketing Management, 3(3), pp. 296-312.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Dolfsma, W. (2004). THE PROCESS OF NEW SERVICE DEVELOPMENT - ISSUES OF FORMALIZATION AND APPROPRIABILITY, International Journal of Innovation Management, Vol. 8, No. 3, pp. 319–337</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Donnely, J.H., Berry, L.L. and Thompson, T.W. (1985). Marketing Financial Services, Dow Jones-Irwin.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Droege, H., Hildebrand, D. and Heras Forcada, M.A. (2009). Innovation in services: present findings, and future pathways, Journal of Service Management, Vol. 20 Iss: 2.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Edvardsson, B., Meiren, T., Schäfer, A. and Witell, L. (2013). Having a strategy for new service development – does it really matter?, Journal of Service Management, Vol. 24, Iss 1, pp. 25 – 44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Edvardsson, B., Gustafsson, A. and Enquist, B. (2005). Challenges in New Service Development and Value Creation through Service, ISD’2005 conference, 14 - 17 August 2005, Karlstad University, Sweden.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Froehle, C.M. and Roth, A.V. (2007). A Resource-Process Framework of New Service Development, PRODUCTION AND OPERATIONS MANAGEMENT, Vol. 16, No. 2, pp. 169–188</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>GSMA &amp; A.T. Kearney (2013). The Mobile Economy, London, United Kingdom.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Jin, D., Chai, K.H. and Tan, K.C. (2014). new service development maturity model, Managing Service Quality: An International Journal, Vol. 24, Iss. 1, pp. 86 –116.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Johne, A. and Storey, C. (1998). New service development: a review of the literature and annotated bibliography, European Journal of Marketing, Vol. 32 Iss: 3, pp. 184 – 251.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Johnson, E.M., Scheuning, E.E. and Gaida, K.A. (1986). Profitable Service Marketing, Dow Jones-Irwin.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Kekkonnen, K., (2012). User-Centric New Service Development in Telecom Industry, Master’s thesis, School of Science, University of Aalto, Helsinki. Finland.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Kim, C., Choe, S., Choi, C. and Park, Y. (2008). A systematic approach to new mobile service creation, Expert Systems with Applications, Vol. 35 pp. 762–771.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Kwang-Jae, K., Deok-Hwan, K., Kwangsoo, K. and Byung-In, K. (2007). A Model of Rapid New Service Development Process, Department of Industrial and Management Engineering, Pohang University of Science and Technology, Republic of Korea.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Larbig-Wüst, C. (2010). Measuring Customer Involvement in New Service Development Projects, PHD thesis, Faculty of Management, Cass Business School, City University of London.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Lin F.R. and Hsieh P.S. (2011). A SAT View on New Service Development, Journal of Service Science, 3(2), pp. 141-157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Mashayekh, J., Tabatabaeian, S., Amiri, M., Shokrieh, M. (2016). The Impact of External Contextual Factors on Open Innovation Adoption with an Emphasis on Sectorial Characteristics: Evidences from Iran's Advanced Materials Firms. Innovation Management Journal, 5(2), 1-31.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Melton, H.L. and Hartline, M.D. (2010). Customer and Frontline Employee Influence on New Service Development Performance, Journal of Service Research, 13(4), pp. 411-425.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Melton, H.L. (2007), A FRAMEWORK FOR EFFECTIVE CUSTOMER AND FRONTLINE EMPLOYEE INVOLVEMENT IN NEW SERVICE DEVELOPMENT, PHD Dissertation, COLLEGE OF BUSINESS, THE FLORIDA STATE UNIVERSITY.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Menora, L.J., Tatikonda, M.V. and Sampson, S.E. (2002), new service development: areas for exploitation and exploration, Journal of Operations Management, Vol. 20, pp. 135–157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Meyer, C.B. (2001). A case in case study methodology, Filed Methods, 13(4), pp. 329-352.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammed-Salleh, A. and Easingwood, C. (1993). Why European financial institutions do not test-market new consumer products, International Journal of Bank Marketing, 11(3), pp. 23-27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Nijssen, E.J., Hillebrand, B., Vermeulen, P.A.M. and Kemp, R.G.M. (2006). Exploring product and service innovation similarities and differences, International Journal of Research in Marketing, Vol 23: 241–251.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Oduori, F.N. (2010). New service development: strategy and process in the hospitality sector in Kenya, 19th EDAMBA Summer Academy, Soreze, France.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Office of the undersecretary of defense, (2010). Taxonomy for the Acquisition of Service, US Department of Defense, 3000 Defense Pentagon, Washington, USA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD), (2000). The Service Economy, Business and Industry Policy Forum Series.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Posselt, T. and Förstl, K. (2011). Success Factors in New Service Development: a Literature Review, RESER (European Association for Research on Service) Conference Papers, Hamburg, Germany, 7- 10 September 2011.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Riedl, C., Leimeistery, J.M. and Krcmarz, H. (2009). New Service Development for Electronic Services - A Literature Review, Americas Conference on Information Systems (AMCIS).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Sandén, B. (2007). The Customer's Role in New Service Development, PHD thesis, Karlstad University, Sweden.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Santos, J.B. and Spring, M. (2013). New service development: managing the dynamic between services and operations resources, International Journal of Operations &amp; Production Management, Vol. 33, Iss. 7, pp. 800 – 827.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Scheuing, E.E. and Johnson, E.M. (1989). A Proposed Model for New Service Development, The Journal of Services Marketing, Vol3, No2.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Shekar, A. (2007). An Innovative Model of Service Development: A process guide for service managers, The Innovation Journal: The Public Sector Innovation Journal, Volume 12 (1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, A.M., Fischbacher, M. and Wilson, F.A. (2007). New Service Development: From Panoramas to Precision, European Management Journal, Vol. 25, No. 5, pp. 370–383.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Spath, D., Husen, C.V., Meyer, K. and Elze, R. (2007). Integrated Development of Software and Service – The Challenges of IT-Enabled Service Products, In D. Spath and K.P. Fähnrich (Eds.), Advances in Services Innovations, Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg, Germany.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Stevens, E. and Dimitriadis, S. (2005(. managing the new service development process: towards a systemic model, European Journal of Marketing, Vol. 39 Iss: 1 pp. 175 – 198.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Sundbo, J. (2007). Innovation and Learning in Services – The Involvement of Employees, In D. Spath and K.P. Fähnrich (Eds.), Advances in Services Innovations, Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg, Germany.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Tajeddini, K. (2011). CUSTOMER ORIENTATION, LEARNING ORIENTATION, AND NEW SERVICE DEVELOPMENT: AN EMPIRICAL INVESTIGATION OF THE SWISS HOTEL INDUSTRY, Journal of Hospitality &amp; Tourism Research, Vol. 35, No. 4, pp. 437-468.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Tatikonda, M.V. and Zeithaml, V.A. (2002). New Directions in Supply-Chain Management, Technology, Strategy and Implementation, Boone and Ganeshan [eds.], American Management Association, New York, Chapter 10: Managing the New Service Development Process: Multi-Disciplinary Literature Synthesis and Directions for Future Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>Tidd, J. and Hull, F.M. (2003). SERVICE INNOVATION: Organizational Responses to Technological Opportunities &amp; Market Imperatives, University of Sussex, UK.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>Weerawardena, J. and McColl-Kennedy, J.R. (2002). New Service Development and Competitive Advantage: A Conceptual Model, Australasian Marketing Journal, Vol. 10 (1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Yin, R.K. (2003). Case study research: Design and methods, Sage publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>Yoonsoo, O., Eui-ho, S., Jongyi, H. and Hyunseok, H. (2009). A feasibility test model for new telecom service development using MCDM method: A case study of video telephone service in Korea, Expert Systems with Applications, Vol. 36, pp. 6375–6388.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81028_70d1ce7e67a5cdbeab075de9fedef68c.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تاثیر ویژگی های صنایع مبتنی بر فناوری برتر بر نوآوری فناورانه و عملکرد محصول در صنعت الکترونیک دفاعی (مطالعه موردی: صنعت الکترونیک دفاعی شیراز)</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محرابی</surname>
			            <given-names>سمیه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی مقطع دکترا - دانشکده مدیریت و مهندسی صنایع- دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محمودزاده</surname>
			            <given-names>ابراهیم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>هیأت علمی دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بوشهری</surname>
			            <given-names>علیرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه مالک اشتر</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رمضان</surname>
			            <given-names>مجید</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیات علمی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>22</day>
			        <month>05</month>
			        <year>2018</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>1</issue>
			      <fpage>153</fpage>
			      <lpage>176</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>27</day>
			          <month>06</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>17</day>
			          <month>12</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81028.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81028.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>سازمان‌های دفاعیِ مبتنی بر فناوری برتر به دلیل ویژگی‌های خاص، نیازمند توجه بیشتر به قابلیت‌های متناسب با شرایط خود، از جمله نوآوری فناورانه (نوآوری محصول و نوآوری فرایند) می‌باشند. به همین دلیل در این پژوهش، به بررسی تاثیر ویژگی‌های صنایع مبتنی بر فناوری برتر بر قابلیت نوآوری محصول و فرایند پرداخته شده است. همچنین با توجه به اهمیت بالای عملکرد محصول در صنعت دفاعی، این متغیر به عنوان متغیر وابسته در مدل لحاظ شده است. روش تحقیق از منظر هدف، اکتشافی و توصیفی و از منظر دستاورد، کاربردی است. به منظور طراحی مدل و استخراج برخی از شاخص‌های ابعاد مدل در سازمان‌های دفاعی مبتنی بر فناوری برتر ایران، از مصاحبه و برای تایید مدل از روش دلفی استفاده شده است. به منظورآزمون مدل، اطلاعات مورد نیاز در قالب پرسشنامه از 58 سازمان صنعت الکترونیک دفاعی در شیراز در سال 1396 جمع‌آوری شده است. تحلیل داده‌های حاصل با کمک مدلسازی معادلات ساختاری مبتنی بر حداقل مربعات جزئی نشان داده که ویژگی‌های این صنایع دارای تاثیر مثبت بر قابلیت نوآوری محصول، نوآوری فرایند و عملکرد محصول دفاعی است. بنابراین یافته‌های تحقیق، به بهره‌مندی از ویژگی‌های این صنعت در دفاع به عنوان یک فرصت و نه یک تهدید، با هدف توانمندسازی سازمان در حوزه نوآوری محصول و فرایند توصیه می‌نماید.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>صنعت مبتنی بر فناوری برتر</kwd>
						<kwd>عملکرد محصول</kwd>
						<kwd>قابلیت نوآوری محصول</kwd>
						<kwd>قابلیت نوآوری فرایند</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Azar, G. Ciabu schi, F. 2017. Organizational innovation, technological innovation, and export performance: The effects of innovation radicalness and extensiveness, International Business Review, 26 (2017), pp. 324-336.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Banerjeea, T. Siebertb, R,2017. Dynamic impact of uncertainty on R&amp;D cooperation formation and research performance: Evidence from the bio-pharmaceutical industry, Research Policy, Volume(46), pp. 1255-1271</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Bauer, J. M., Lang, A., Schneide, V,2011. Innovation Policy and Governance in High-Tech Industries: The Complexity of Coordination</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Bi, K.X., Sun, D.H., Zheng R.F., &amp; Li, B.Z,2006. The construction of synergetic development system of product innovation and process innovation in manufacturing enterprises. Proceedings of the 13th International Conference on Management Science and Engineering (ICMSE), Lille, France, pp. 628–636.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Bunnell, T,2002. Positioning Malaysia: High-tech networks and the multicultural rescripting of national identity. Political Geography, Volume(21), pp. 105-124.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Camisón, C., Villar-López, A, 2014. Organizational innovation as an enabler of technological innovation capabilities and ﬁrm performance. Journal of Business Research, Volume(67), pp. 2891–2902.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Camisón, C., &amp; Villar-López, A, 2010. An examination of the relationship between manufacturing flexibility and firm performance: The mediating role of innovation. International Journal of Operations and Production Management, 30(8).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Chiaroni, D. Chiesa, V. Frattini, F,2011. The Open Innovation Journey: How Firms Dynamically Implement the Emerging Innovation Management Paradigm, Technovation, 31(1), pp. 34-43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Chin, W.W,1998.The Partial Least Squares Approach to Structural Equation Modeling. In ModernMethods for Business Research, Marcoulides, G.A. (ed.), Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, Mahwah, NJ, pp. 1295-1336.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Chorev, S., Anderson, A. R, 2006.  Success in Israeli high-tech start-ups; Critical factors and process. Technovation, 26(2), pp. 162-174.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Crawford,  C. M. Di Benedetto, C. A, 2015.New Products Management, 11 edition</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Damanpour, F, 2010. An integration of research ﬁndings of effects of ﬁrm size and market competition on product and process innovations. British Journal of Management, 21(4), pp. 996–1010.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>De Vol, R,1999. America's High Tech Economy: Growth, Development, and Risks for Metropolitan areas, CA: The Milken Institute.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>DOVLEAC, L,2011. AN ANALISYS OF CONSUMERS’ EXPENDITURES ON HIGH- TECH PRODUCTS. Transilvania University of Braşov, Series V: Economic Sciences, pp. 93-98.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Erensal, Y. C., Oncan, T., Demircan, M. L, 2006. Determining key capabilities in technology management using fuzzy analytic hierarchy process: A case study of Turkey. Information Sciences, Volume(176), pp. 2755-2770.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Etemad H, Lee Y,2001. Technological capabilities and industrial concentration NICs and industrialized countries: Taiwanese SMEs versus Southern Korean chaebols. Int J Entrepr Innov Manage, 1(3), pp 329-55</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Eurostat,2005. what is High-tech Trade? Definition Based on the SITC Nomenclature. EuropeanUnion_Eurostat.March2005. information website: http://europa.eu.int/comm/eurostat/newcronos/ reference/ sdds/ en/ strind/ innore_high_tech_trade.pdf</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Gima, K., Murray, J.Y,2007. Exploratory and exploitative learning in new product development: a social capital perspective on new technology ventures in China. Journal of International Marketing, 15(2), pp. 1-29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Gu, Q, Jiang, W, Wang, G, 2016. Effects of external and internal sources on innovation Performance  in Chinese high-tech SMEs: A resource-based Perspective, J.Eng.Technol.Manage, Volume(40), pp. 76–86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Gunday, G., Ulusoy, G., Kilic, K., &amp; Alpkan, L, 2011. Effects of innovation types on ﬁrm performance. International Journal of Production Economics,Volume(133),pp. 662–676</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Han, Ch, Rhyn, S,  Yang, M, Ieromonachou, M, Zhang, H, 2018. Evaluating R &amp; D investment eﬃciency in China's high-tech Industry, Journal of High Technology Management Research, http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.hitech.2017.04.007</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Hao, Sh. Song, M, 2016. Technology-driven strategy and firm performance: Are strategic capabilities missing links? Journal of Business ResearchVolume(69),pp.  751–759</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Hecker, D. E, 2005. High-technology employment: a NAICS-based update. Monthly Labos Review,Volume(7), pp. 57-72.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Hill, C. Jones, G,1995. Strategic Management: an Integrated Approach, McGraw Hill, Boston, USA</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Hirunyawipada, T, 2006. Consumer innovativeness and perceived risk: implications for high technology product adoption. Journal of Consumer Marketing, 23(4),pp. 182-198.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Kerr, C., Farrukh, C., Phaal, R., Probert. D, 2013. Key principles for developing industrially relevant strategic Technology: management toolkits. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, Volume(80), pp. 1050-1070.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Lio, S., Chang, W., Wu, C. &amp; Katrichis, J.M, 2011. A Survey of Market Orientation Research (1995-2008). Industrial Marketing Management, 40(2), pp. 301-310.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Medcof, J. W,1999. Identifying'super-technology'industries. Research-Technology Management, 42(4), pp. 31-36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Menguc, B., &amp; Auh, S, 2010. Development and return on execution of product innovation capabilities: The role of organizational structure. Industrial Marketing Management, Volume(39), pp. 820-831.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Mishra, S. S., Saji, K. B, 2013. The impact of institutional variables in new high-tech product development processes: The moderating roles of perceived risk and project duration. Marketing Intelligence &amp; Planning, 31(2),pp. 160–178.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Mumford, M. D. Zaccaro, S. J. Connelly, M. S. Marks, M.A, 2000. Leader ship Skills: Conclusions and Future Directions, Leadership Quarterly, 11(1), pp.155–170</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Ortega, M. J, 2009. Competitive strategies and firm performance: Technological capabilities’ moderating role. Journal of Business Research, 63(12), pp. 1273-1281</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Porter, M. E, 2003. Building the Microeconomic Foundations of Competitiveness Report 2002-2003, World Economic Forum, New York, Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Ringle, C. M., Wende, S., &amp; Will, A, 2005. SmartPLS 2.0 [Computer soft­ware]. Retrieved from www.smartpls.de</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Santhapparaj, A.S. Sreenivasan, J.  Loong, J.C.K, 2006. Competitive Factors of Semiconductor Industry in Malaysia: the Managers’ Perspectives, Competitiveness Review, 16( 3&amp;4), pp.197-211.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Schilling, M.A. and Hill, C.W.L, 1998. Managing the new product development process: strategic imperatives, Academy of Management Executive, 12(3), pp. 67-81.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Shenhar, A. J,1993. From low- to high-tech project management. R&amp;D Management, 23(3),pp. 199-214.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Song, M., Noh, J, 2006. Best new product development and management practices in the Korean high-tech industry. Industrial Marketing Management, Volume(35), pp. 262-278</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Swamidass, P.M., Newell, W. T.,1987.Manufacturing Strategy, Environmental Uncertainty and Performance: A Path Analytic Model, management science,pp. 509-524.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Tenenhaus, M., Amato, S., &amp; Esposito Vinzi, V, 2004. A global goodness­of-fit index for PLS structural equation modeling. In Proceedings of the XLII SIS Scientific Meeting Padova, Italy: CLEUP, pp. 739-742.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Tenenhaus, M., Esposito Vinzi, V., Chatelin, Y.-M., &amp; Lauro, C, 2005. PLS path modeling. Computational Statistics &amp; Data Analysis, Volume(48), pp. 159-205.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Tishler, A., Dvir, D., Shenhar, A. Lipovetsky, S,1996. Identifying critical success factors in defense development projects: A multivariate analysis, Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 51(2), pp. 151-171.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Tsai, K. H, 2004. The impact of technological capability on firm performance in Taiwan's electronics industry. Journal of High Technology Management Research, Volume(15), pp. 183–195.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Tuominen, M., &amp; Hyvönen, S, 2004. Organizational innovation capability: A driver for competitive superiority in marketing channels. International Review of Retail, Distribution and Consumer Research, 14(3), pp. 277-293.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Unger JM, Rauch A, Frese M, Rosenbusch N.,2011. Human capital and entrepreneurial success: a meta- analytical review. J Bus Ventur, Volume(26), pp. 341-358</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Viardot, E, 2004. Successful Marketing Strategy for High-Tech Firms (Third edition). Artech House Inc.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Walker, R. M, 2004. Innovation and Organisational Performance: Evidence and a Research  Agenda. Retreived 01.07.15, [from] http://www.aimresearch.org</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Zahra SA, Neubaum DO, Larrañeta B, 2007.Knowledge sharing and technological capabilities: the moderating role of family involvement. J Bus Res, 60(10), pp. 1070-9.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Zemlickiene, V, 2011. Analysis of High-technology Product development Models. Intellectual Economics, 2(10), pp. 283–297.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, J. &amp; Duan, Y,2010. Empirical study on the impact of market orientation and innovation orientation on new product performance of Chinese manufacturers. Nankai Business Review International, 1(2),pp. 214-231.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, J,2003. High-Tech start-Ups and industry dynamics in Silicon Valley. Public Policy Institute of California.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>دهقان، حسین، 1392. برنامه‌های  پیشنهادی وزیر دفاع به مجلس شورای اسلامی، سایت خبرگزاری فارس، 15/05/1392.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>رابینز، استیفن ، پی ،1376 . تئوری سازمانی، ترجمه مهدی الوانی ، حسن دانائی فرد، تهران، انتشارات صفار</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>رضاییان، علی، 1379. مبانی سازمان و مدیریت، چاپ اول، تهران، سازمان انتشارات سمت.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>رضوانی، حمیدرضا، گرایلی نژاد، رزا، 1390. ارائه الگویی برای گونه شناسی انواع نوآوری سازمانی، فصلنامه پارک ها و مراکز رشد، 28، صص. 21-26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>زندحسامی، حسام، آشتیانی پور، زینب، 1392. تحلیل چگونگی تأثیر قابلیت‌های نوآوری فناورانه بر رقابت‌پذیری شرکت‌های کوچک و متوسط، مدیریت نوآوری، سال دوم، شماره 2، صص. 1-24.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>فضلی، صفر، درویشی، فرهاد، بوشهری، علیرضا، نظری زاده، فرهاد،1394 . شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی عوامل محیطی مؤثر بر نوآوری در صنعت دفاعی، مطالعات راهبردی بسیج، شماره 69، صص.  153-182 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>فقهی فرهمند، ناصر،1390. مدیریت فنّاوری سازمان (چاپ دوم). تبریز: انتشارات فروزش.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>محمدی، مهدی. باقر سلیمی، سعید. بوشهری، علیرضا. نظری زاده، فرهاد، 1388. طراحی نظام نوآوری دفاعی، تهران، موسسه آموزشی و تحقیقاتی صنایع دفاعی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>محمودزاده، ابراهیم، 1389. مدیریت بر آینده با تکنولوژی فردا (چاپ سوم). تهران: انتشارات انستیتو ایز ایران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>مدهوشی، م. طبیبی، م. ر و دلاوری، ه. ر، 1392. بررسی اثر رویکرد بازار و رویکرد کارآفرینی بر روی نوآوری در بنگاه‌های متوسط و کوچک، مطالعات معاملات، 17(65)، صص. 115-136.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>مرکز صنایع نوین،1384. پروژه شناسایی نهادهای سیاست‌گذار و پشتیبان صنایع با فناوری برتر در ایران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>مکنزی، کنت، 1385.چشم‌انداز مشترک ارتش آمریکا در افق 2020، ترجمه: حیدری، عبدالمجید و تمنایی، محمد، موسسه آموزشی و تحقیقاتی صنایع دفاعی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>هیر، جوزف، هالت، توماس، رینگل، کریستنسن، سارستد، مارکو، 1395. مدل­سازی معادلات ساختاری کمترین مربعات جزئی، ترجمه: آذر، عادل، غلام‌زاده، رسول، نشر نگاه دانش، چاپ اول._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Azar, G. Ciabu schi, F. 2017. Organizational innovation, technological innovation, and export performance: The effects of innovation radicalness and extensiveness, International Business Review, 26 (2017), pp. 324-336.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Banerjeea, T. Siebertb, R,2017. Dynamic impact of uncertainty on R&amp;D cooperation formation and research performance: Evidence from the bio-pharmaceutical industry, Research Policy, Volume(46), pp. 1255-1271</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Bauer, J. M., Lang, A., Schneide, V,2011. Innovation Policy and Governance in High-Tech Industries: The Complexity of Coordination</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Bi, K.X., Sun, D.H., Zheng R.F., &amp; Li, B.Z,2006. The construction of synergetic development system of product innovation and process innovation in manufacturing enterprises. Proceedings of the 13th International Conference on Management Science and Engineering (ICMSE), Lille, France, pp. 628–636.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Bunnell, T,2002. Positioning Malaysia: High-tech networks and the multicultural rescripting of national identity. Political Geography, Volume(21), pp. 105-124.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Camisón, C., Villar-López, A, 2014. Organizational innovation as an enabler of technological innovation capabilities and ﬁrm performance. Journal of Business Research, Volume(67), pp. 2891–2902.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Camisón, C., &amp; Villar-López, A, 2010. An examination of the relationship between manufacturing flexibility and firm performance: The mediating role of innovation. International Journal of Operations and Production Management, 30(8).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Chiaroni, D. Chiesa, V. Frattini, F,2011. The Open Innovation Journey: How Firms Dynamically Implement the Emerging Innovation Management Paradigm, Technovation, 31(1), pp. 34-43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Chin, W.W,1998.The Partial Least Squares Approach to Structural Equation Modeling. In ModernMethods for Business Research, Marcoulides, G.A. (ed.), Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, Mahwah, NJ, pp. 1295-1336.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Chorev, S., Anderson, A. R, 2006.  Success in Israeli high-tech start-ups; Critical factors and process. Technovation, 26(2), pp. 162-174.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Crawford,  C. M. Di Benedetto, C. A, 2015.New Products Management, 11 edition</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Damanpour, F, 2010. An integration of research ﬁndings of effects of ﬁrm size and market competition on product and process innovations. British Journal of Management, 21(4), pp. 996–1010.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Dehghan, h. (2013). The Proposed Plans of Minister of Defense to the Islamic Parliament, Fars News Agency, 2013/8/16</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>De Vol, R,1999. America's High Tech Economy: Growth, Development, and Risks for Metropolitan areas, CA: The Milken Institute.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Dovleac, L,2011. An Analisys Of Consumers’ Expenditures On High- Tech Products. Transilvania University of Braşov, Series V: Economic Sciences, pp. 93-98.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Erensal, Y. C., Oncan, T., Demircan, M. L, 2006. Determining key capabilities in technology management using fuzzy analytic hierarchy process: A case study of Turkey. Information Sciences, Volume(176), pp. 2755-2770.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Etemad H, Lee Y,2001. Technological capabilities and industrial concentration NICs and industrialized countries: Taiwanese SMEs versus Southern Korean chaebols. Int J Entrepr Innov Manage, 1(3), pp 329-55</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Eurostat,2005. what is High-tech Trade? Definition Based on the SITC Nomenclature. EuropeanUnion_Eurostat.March2005. information website: http://europa.eu.int/comm/eurostat/newcronos/ reference/ sdds/ en/ strind/ innore_high_tech_trade.pdf</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Feqhifarahmand, N. (2011). Organization's Technology Management (second edition), foroozesh publication, Tehran, Tabriz.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Gima, K., Murray, J.Y,2007. Exploratory and exploitative learning in new product development: a social capital perspective on new technology ventures in China. Journal of International Marketing, 15(2), pp. 1-29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Gu, Q, Jiang, W, Wang, G, 2016. Effects of external and internal sources on innovation Performance  in Chinese high-tech SMEs: A resource-based Perspective, J.Eng.Technol.Manage, Volume(40), pp. 76–86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Gunday, G., Ulusoy, G., Kilic, K., &amp; Alpkan, L, 2011. Effects of innovation types on ﬁrm performance. International Journal of Production Economics,Volume(133),pp. 662–676</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Han, Ch, Rhyn, S,  Yang, M, Ieromonachou, M, Zhang, H, 2018. Evaluating R &amp; D investment eciency in China's high-tech Industry, Journal of High Technology Management Research, http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.hitech.2017.04.007</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Hair, J. F., Hult, G. T. M., Ringle, C. M., &amp; Sarstedt, M. (2017). A Primer on Partial Least Squares Structural Equation Modeling. 1nd Ed. Thousand Oaks: Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Hao, Sh. Song, M, 2016. Technology-driven strategy and firm performance: Are strategic capabilities missing links? Journal of Business ResearchVolume(69),pp.  751–759</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Hecker, D. E, 2005. High-technology employment: a NAICS-based update. Monthly Labos Review,Volume(7), pp. 57-72.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Hill, C. Jones, G,1995. Strategic Management: an Integrated Approach, McGraw Hill, Boston, USA</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Hirunyawipada, T, 2006. Consumer innovativeness and perceived risk: implications for high technology product adoption. Journal of Consumer Marketing, 23(4),pp. 182-198.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Kerr, C., Farrukh, C., Phaal, R., Probert. D, 2013. Key principles for developing industrially relevant strategic Technology: management toolkits. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, Volume(80), pp. 1050-1070.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Lio, S., Chang, W., Wu, C. &amp; Katrichis, J.M, 2011. A Survey of Market Orientation Research (1995-2008). Industrial Marketing Management, 40(2), pp. 301-310.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>MacKenzie, K. (2006). The Vision of US Military in the Horizon 2020.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Madhooshi, M. Tayebi, M. R. Delavari, H. R. (2013). The Effect of Market Approach and Entrepreneurship Approach on Innovation in Small and Medium Enterprises, Trading studies, 17 (65), 115-136.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Mahmoudzadeh, E. (2010). Management of Future with Tomorrow's Technology (Third Edition). Tehran, Publication of IsIran Institute.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Medcof, J. W,1999. Identifying'super-technology'industries. Research-Technology Management, 42(4), pp. 31-36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Menguc, B., &amp; Auh, S, 2010. Development and return on execution of product innovation capabilities: The role of organizational structure. Industrial Marketing Management, Volume(39), pp. 820-831.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Modern Industries Center, (2005). Identifying of Policy Makers and Supporters of High-Tech Industries Project in Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammadi, M. Baghersalimi,  S. Booshehri, A. Nazarizadeh, F. (2009). Designing the Defense Innovation System, Tehran, Educational and Research Institute of Defense Industry.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Mishra, S. S., Saji, K. B, 2013. The impact of institutional variables in new high-tech product development processes: The moderating roles of perceived risk and project duration. Marketing Intelligence &amp; Planning, 31(2),pp. 160–178.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Mumford, M. D. Zaccaro, S. J. Connelly, M. S. Marks, M.A, 2000. Leader ship Skills: Conclusions and Future Directions, Leadership Quarterly, 11(1), pp.155–170</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Ortega, M. J, 2009. Competitive strategies and firm performance: Technological capabilities’ moderating role. Journal of Business Research, 63(12), pp. 1273-1281</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Porter, M. E, 2003. Building the Microeconomic Foundations of Competitiveness Report 2002-2003, World Economic Forum, New York, Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Rezvani, H. Gerayelinejad, R. (2011). The Model for Typology of Organizational Innovation, Parks and Growth Centers Journal, Volume(28), pp. 21-26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Ringle, C. M., Wende, S., &amp; Will, A, 2005. SmartPLS 2.0 [Computer soft­ware]. Retrieved from www.smartpls.de</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Santhapparaj, A.S. Sreenivasan, J.  Loong, J.C.K, 2006. Competitive Factors of Semiconductor Industry in Malaysia: the Managers’ Perspectives, Competitiveness Review, 16( 3&amp;4), pp.197-211.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Schilling, M.A. and Hill, C.W.L, 1998. Managing the new product development process: strategic imperatives, Academy of Management Executive, 12(3), pp. 67-81.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Shenhar, A. J,1993. From low- to high-tech project management. R&amp;D Management, 23(3),pp. 199-214.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>Song, M., Noh, J, 2006. Best new product development and management practices in the Korean high-tech industry. Industrial Marketing Management, Volume(35), pp. 262-278</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>Swamidass, P.M., Newell, W. T.,1987.Manufacturing Strategy, Environmental Uncertainty and Performance: A Path Analytic Model, management science,pp. 509-524.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Tenenhaus, M., Amato, S., &amp; Esposito Vinzi, V, 2004. A global goodness­of-fit index for PLS structural equation modeling. In Proceedings of the XLII SIS Scientific Meeting Padova, Italy: CLEUP, pp. 739-742.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>Tenenhaus, M., Esposito Vinzi, V., Chatelin, Y.-M., &amp; Lauro, C, 2005. PLS path modeling. Computational Statistics &amp; Data Analysis, Volume(48), pp. 159-205.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R115">
			<label>115</label>
			<element-citation>Tishler, A., Dvir, D., Shenhar, A. Lipovetsky, S,1996. Identifying critical success factors in defense development projects: A multivariate analysis, Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 51(2), pp. 151-171.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R116">
			<label>116</label>
			<element-citation>Tsai, K. H, 2004. The impact of technological capability on firm performance in Taiwan's electronics industry. Journal of High Technology Management Research, Volume(15), pp. 183–195.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R117">
			<label>117</label>
			<element-citation>Tuominen, M., &amp; Hyvönen, S, 2004. Organizational innovation capability: A driver for competitive superiority in marketing channels. International Review of Retail, Distribution and Consumer Research, 14(3), pp. 277-293.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R118">
			<label>118</label>
			<element-citation>Unger JM, Rauch A, Frese M, Rosenbusch N.,2011. Human capital and entrepreneurial success: a meta- analytical review. J Bus Ventur, Volume (26), pp. 341-358.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R119">
			<label>119</label>
			<element-citation>Viardot, E, 2004. Successful Marketing Strategy for High-Tech Firms (Third edition). Artech House Inc.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R120">
			<label>120</label>
			<element-citation>Walker, R. M, 2004. Innovation and Organisational Performance: Evidence and a Research  Agenda. Retreived 01.07.15, [from] http://www.aimresearch.org</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R121">
			<label>121</label>
			<element-citation>Zahra SA, Neubaum DO, Larrañeta B, 2007.Knowledge sharing and technological capabilities: the moderating role of family involvement. J Bus Res, 60(10), pp. 1070-9.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R122">
			<label>122</label>
			<element-citation>Zandhesami, H. Ashtiyanipour, Z. (2013). Analysis of how technology innovation capabilities affect the competitiveness of small and medium enterprises, innovation management, 2, 1-24</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R123">
			<label>123</label>
			<element-citation>Zemlickiene, V, 2011. Analysis of High-technology Product development Models. Intellectual Economics, 2(10), pp. 283–297.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R124">
			<label>124</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, J. &amp; Duan, Y,2010. Empirical study on the impact of market orientation and innovation orientation on new product performance of Chinese manufacturers. Nankai Business Review International, 1(2),pp. 214-231.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R125">
			<label>125</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, J,2003. High-Tech start-Ups and industry dynamics in Silicon Valley. Public Policy Institute of California.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>