<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" "journalpublishing3.dtd">
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14722_ec30d914c2613fc2eb7dcaa48f087954.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>پیکربندی سازوکارهای کنترلی در شرکتهای نوآور</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حسینی</surname>
			            <given-names>سید محمود</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رضائیان</surname>
			            <given-names>علی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>قر هچه</surname>
			            <given-names>منیژه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی،</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>پریزادی</surname>
			            <given-names>عیسی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>12</month>
			        <year>2014</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>3</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>1</fpage>
			      <lpage>32</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>14</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>16</day>
			          <month>03</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2014, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14722.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14722.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>نظریه‌های سنتی مدیریت، ‌‌کنترل و نوآوری را نقطة مقابل یکدیگر می‌دانستند و استدلال می‌کردند که نظام‌های کنترلی مانعی بر سر راه خلاقیت و نوآوری در درون سازمان هستند و اصولاً نوآوری با درجة رسمیت سازمانی رابطه  عکس دارد. اما رویکردهای جدید مطرح شده در ادبیات ‌‌کنترل و پژوهش‌های تجربی جدید نشان می‌دهند که ‌‌کنترل بر خلاف نگاه سنتی تنها پدیده‌‌‌ای غیرمنعطف، ایستا و متمرکز بر استانداردسازی و کمینه‌سازی تنوع و تازگی نیست و ‌‌‌نظام‌‌های ‌‌کنترل رسمی می‌توانند نقش مثبت و معناداری در فرآیند مدیریت نوآوری ایفا نمایند. در این مقاله با استفاده از رویکرد پیکربندی و از طریق توسعة چهار پیکربندی، چارچوب جدیدی برای سازگار کردن ‌‌کنترل و نوآوری در سازمان‌‌‌‌ها مفهومی سازمانی ارائه می‌شود. دو پیکربندی از میان پیکربندی‌های استخراج شده، زمینه و بستر لازم برای بروز نوآوری را فراهم می‌سازند. به عبارت دیگر، سازمان‌‌‌‌‌هایی که به‌دنبال نوآوری هستند و اقتضائات سازمانی آنها، نوآوری را الزامی می‌سازد، باید از ‌‌سازوکار‌‌های کنترلی مطرح‌شده در این دو پیکربندی استفاده نمایند تا امکان بروز نوآوری فراهم گردد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>بستة کنترل</kwd>
						<kwd>کنترل مدیریتی</kwd>
						<kwd>کنترل راهبردی</kwd>
						<kwd>نوآوری</kwd>
						<kwd>رویکرد پیکربندی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Abdel-Kader, M. &amp; Luther, R., 2008. The impact of firm characteristics on management accounting practices: a UK-based empirical analysis. The British Accounting Review, 40(1), p. 2–27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Abernethy, M. A., Bouwens, J. &amp; Van Lent, L., 2004. Determinants of control system design in divisionalized firms. The Accounting Review, 79(3), pp. 545-570.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Abernethy, M. A., Bouwens, J. &amp; Van Lent, L., 2010. Leadership and control system design. Management Accounting Research, 21(1), pp. 2-16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Abernethy, M. A. &amp; Brownell, P., 1999. The role of budgets in organizations facing strategic change: an exploratory study. Accounting, organizations and society, 24(3), pp. 189-204.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Abernethy, M. A. &amp; Chua, W. F., 1996. A Field Study of Control System “Redesign”: The Impact of Institutional Processes on Strategic Choice. Contemporary Accounting Research, 13(2), pp. 569-606.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Abernethy, M. &amp; Brownell, P., 1997. Management control systems in research and development organizations: the role of accounting, behavior and personnel controls. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 22(3/4), pp. 233-248.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Ahrens, T. &amp; Chapman, C., 2002. The Structuration of Legitimate Performance Measures and Management: Day-to-Day Contests of Accountability in a U.K. Restaurant Chain. Management Accounting Research, 13(2), pp. 1-21.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Allen, T., 1977. Communications, Technology Transfer, and the Role of Technical Gatekeeper. R&amp;D Management, p. 14–21.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Amabile, T., 1996. Creativity in context: Update to the Social Psychology of Creativity. S.l.:Westview Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Analoui, F., 2001. What motivates senior managers?: The case of Romania. Journal of Managerial Psychology, 15(4), p. 324–340.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Anderson, N., Potočnik, K. &amp; Zhou, J., 2014. Innovation and Creativity in Organizations A State-of-the-Science Review, Prospective Commentary, and Guiding Framework. Journal of Management, 40(5), pp. 1297-1333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Anderson, P. et al., 1999. Introduction to the special issue: Applications of complexity theory to organization science. Organization Science, 10(3), pp. 233-236.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Anthony, R., 1965. Planning and Control Systems: A Framework for Analysis. Boston: Harvard University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Ashby, W., 1960. Design for a Brain. s.l.:Springer Science &amp; Business Media.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Auzair, S. M. &amp; &amp;Langfield-Smith, K., 2005. The effect of service process type, business strategy and life cycle stage on bureaucratic MCS in service organizations. Management Accounting Research, 16(4), pp. 399-421.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Baer, M., 2010. The strength-of-weak-ties perspective on creativity: A comprehensive examination and extension. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 95, pp. 592-601.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Baer, M., 2012. Putting creativity to work: The implementation of creative ideas in organizations. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 55, pp. 1102-1119.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Baer, M., 2012. Putting creativity to work: The implementation of creative ideas in organizations. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 55, pp. 1102-1119.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Baer, M. &amp; Oldham, G. R., 2006. The curvilinear relation between experienced creative time pressure and creativity: Moderating effects of openness to experience and support for creativity. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 91, pp. 963-970.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Bedford, D. S. &amp; Malmi, T., 2015. Configurations of Control: An Exploratory Analysis. Managing Acconting Research, Volume 27, pp. 2-26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Benson, J. &amp; Hagtvet, K., 1996. The interplay among design, data analysis, and theory in the measurement of coping. In: Handbook of coping: Theory, research, applications. New York: John Wiley, pp. 83-106.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Berry, A. J., Broadbent, J. &amp; Otley, D. T., 1995. Managerial Control: Theories, Issues and Practices. London: Macmillan.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Bisbe, J. &amp; Malagueno, R., 2012. Using strategic performance measurement systems for strategy formulation: Does it work in dynamic environments?. Management Accounting Research, 23(4), pp. 296-311.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Bisbe, J. &amp; Otley, D., 2004. The effects of the interactive use of management control systems on product innovation. Accounting. organizations and society, 29(8), pp. 709-737.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Bledow, R. et al., 2009. A dialectic perspective on innovation: Conflicting demands, multiple pathways, and ambidexterity, Industrial and Organizational Psychology: Perspectives on Science and Practice, Volume 2, pp. 305-337.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Brownell, P. &amp; Merchant, K., 1990. The budgetary and performance influences of product standardization and manufacturing process automation. Journal of Accounting Research, 28(2), p. 388–397.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Burns, T. &amp; Stalker, G., 1961. The management of innovation. London: Tavistock.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Burns, W. J. &amp; Waterhouse, J. H., 1975. Budgetary control and organizational structure. Journal of Accounting Research, 13(2), pp. 177-203.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Burton, R. M. &amp; Obel, B., 2004. Strategic organizational diagnosis and design: The dynamics of fit. s.l.:Springer Science Business Media.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Camison-Zornoza, C., Lapiedra-Alcami, R., Segarra-Cipres, M. &amp; Boronat-Navarro, M., 2004. A meta-analysis of innovation and organizational size. Organization Studies, Volume 25, pp. 331-361.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Cardinal, L. B., 2001. Technological innovation in the pharmaceutical industry: managing research and development using input, behavior, and output controls. Organization Science, Volume 12, p. 19–36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Cardinal, L. B., Sitkin, S. B. &amp; Long, C. P., 2004. Balancing and rebalancing in the creation and evolution of organizational control. Organization Science, 15(4), pp. 411-431.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Chapman, C. S., 1997. Reflections on a contingent view ofaccounting. Accounting, Organizations and Society, Volume 22, p. 189–205.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Chenhall, R., 2003. Management control systems design within its organizational context: Findings from contingency- based research and directions for the future. Accounting, Organizations and Society, Volume 28, p. 127–168.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Chenhall, R. H., 2005. Integrative strategic performance measurement systems, strategic alignment of manufacturing, learning and strategic outcomes: an exploratory study. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 30(5), p. 395–422.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Chenhall, R. H. &amp; Langfield-Smith, K., 1998. The relationship between strategic priorities, management techniques and management accounting: an empirical investigation using a systems approach. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 23(3), pp. 243-264.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Chenhall, R. H. &amp; Morris, D., 1986. The impact of structure, environment, and interdependence on the perceived usefulness of management accounting systems. Accounting Review, 61(1), p. 16–35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Chenhall, R. H. &amp; Morris, D. E. I. G. A. N., 1995. Organic decision and communication processes and management accounting systems in entrepreneurial and conservative business organizations. Omega, 23(5), pp. 485-497.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Child, J., 1973. Strategies of control and organizational behavior. Administrative Science Quarterly, 18(1), pp. 1-17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Choi, J. N., Anderson, T. A. &amp; Veillette, A., 2009. Contextual inhibitors of employee creativity in organizations: The insulating role of creative ability. Group Organization Management, Volume 34, pp. 330-357.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Choi, J. N. &amp; Chang, J. Y., 2009. Innovation implementation in the public sector: An integration of institutional and collective dynamics. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 94, pp. 245-253.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Choi, J. N. &amp; Price, R. H., 2005. The effects of person-innovation fit on individual responses to innovation. Journal of Occupational and Organizational Psychology, Volume 78, pp. 83-96.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Christensen, C., 1997. The innovator’s dilemma: when new technologies cause great firms to fail. s.l.:Harvard Business Review Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Clark, K. &amp; Fujimoto, T., 1991. Product Development Performance. Boston: Harvard Business School Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Clegg, C., Unsworth, K., Epitropaki, O. &amp; Parker, G., 2002. Implicating trust in the innovation process. Journal of Occupational and Organizational Psychology, Volume 75, pp. 409-422.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Cohendet, P. &amp; Simon, L., 2007. Playing across the playground: Paradoxes of knowledge creation in the videogame firm. Journal of Organizational Behavior, Volume 28, pp. 587-605.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Collier, P. M., 2005. Entrepreneurial control and the construction of a relevant accounting. Management Accounting Research, 16(3), p. 321–339.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Daft, R. L. &amp; Macintosh, N. B., 1984. The nature and use of formal control systems for management control and strategy implementation. Journal of Management, 10(1), pp. 43-66.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Damanpour, F., 1991. Organizational innovation: ameta-analysis of effects of determinants and moderators. Academy of Management Journal, 34(3), p. 555–590.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Damanpour, F., 2010. An integration of research findings of effects of firm size and market competition on product and process innovations. British Journal of Management, Volume 21, pp. 996-1010.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Davila, A., 2005. An exploratory study on the emergence of management control systems: formalizing human resources in small growing firms. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 30(3), p. 223–248.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Davila, T., 2000. An empirical study on the drivers of management control systems’ design in new product development. Accounting, organizations and society, 25(4), pp. 383-409.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Dent, J. F., 1990. Strategy, organization and control: some possibilities for accounting research. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 15(1), pp. 3-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Ditillo, A., 2004. Dealing with uncertainty in knowledge-intensive firms: the role of management control systems as knowledge integration mechanisms. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 29(3/4), p. 401– 421.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Donaldson, L., 1996. For positivist organization theory: proving the hard core. London: Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Donaldson, L., 2001. The contingency theory of organizations. Thousand Oaks: Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Doty, H., Glick, W. H. &amp; Huber, G. P., 1993. Fit, equifinality, and organizational effectiveness: a test of two configurational theories. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 36, p. 1196–1250.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Dougherty, D., 1992. Interpretive barriers to successful product innovation in large firms. Organization Science, 3(2), p. 179–202.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Dougherty, D. &amp; Hardy, C., 1996. Sustained product innovation in large, mature organizations: Overcoming innovation-to-organization problems. Academy of Management Journal, 39(5), pp. 1120-1153.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Drazin, R. &amp; Van De Ven, A. H., 1985. Alternative forms of fit in contingency theory. Administrative Science Quarterly, 30(4), p. 514–539.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Dunk, A. S., 1992. Reliance on budgetary control, manufacturing process automation and production subunit performance: a research note. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 17(3-4), p. 195–203.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Durden, C. &amp; Perera, H., 2010. Towards control using strategic navigation in turbulent organisational environments. International Journal of Accounting, Auditing and Performance Evaluation, 6(4), pp. 397-421.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K. M., 1989. Building theories from case study research. Academy of management review, 14(4), pp. 532-550.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K. M., 2002. Has strategy changed?. MIT Sloan Management Review, 43(2), pp. 88-91.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Elliot, A. J. &amp; Church, M. A., 1997. A hierarchical model of approach and avoidance achievement motivation. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, Volume 72, pp. 218-232.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Ezzamel, M., 1990. The impact of environmental uncertainty, managerial autonomy and size on budget characteristics. Management Accounting Research, Volume 1, p. 181–197.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Ferreira, A. &amp; Otley, D., 2009. The design and use of management control systems: an extended framework for analysis. Management Accounting Research, Volume 20, p. 263–282.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Fisher, J., 1995. Contingency-based research on management control systems: categorisation by level of complexity. Journal of Accounting Literature, Volume 14, p. 24–53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Flamholtz, E., 1996. Effective organizational control: a framework, applications, and implications. European Management Journal, 14(6), pp. 596-611.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Flamholtz, E. G., Das, T. K. &amp; Tsui, A. S., 1985. Toward an integrative framework of organizational control. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 10(1), pp. 35-50.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Flamholtz, E. G. &amp; Randle, Y., 2000. Growing pains: Transitioning from an entrepreneurship to a professionally managed firm. s.l.:John Wiley Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Galbraith, I. R., 1973. Designing complex organizations, Reading. s.l.:MA: Addison-Wesley.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>George, J. M., 2007. Creativity in organizations. The Academy of Management Annals, Volume 1, pp. 439-477.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Gerdin, J., 2005. Management accounting system design in manufacturing departments: an empirical investigation using a multiple contingencies approach. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 30(2), pp. 99-126.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Gilson, L. L. &amp; Shalley, C. E., 2004. A little creativity goes a long way: An examination of teams’ engagement in creative processes. Journal of Management, Volume 30, pp. 453-470.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Gong, Y., Huang, J. &amp; Farh, J., 2009. Employee learning orientation, transformational leadership, and employee creativity: The mediating role of employee creative self-efficacy. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 52, pp. 765-778.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Goold, M. &amp; Quinn, J. J., 1990. The paradox of strategic controls. Strategic Management Journal, 11(1), pp. 43-57.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Gordon, L. A. &amp; Narayanan, V. K., 1984. Management accounting systems, perceived environmental uncertainty and organization structure: an empirical investigation. Accounting, Organizations and Society, Volume 1, p. 33–47.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Grabner, I. &amp; Moers, F., 2013. Management control as a system or a package? Conceptual and empirical issues. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 38(6), pp. 407-419.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Greiner, L. E., 1972. Evolution and revolution as organizations grow. Harvard Business Review, Volume 50, p. 37–46.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Gresov, C. &amp; Drazin, R., 1997. Equifinality: Functional equivalence in organization design. Academy of management review, 22(2), pp. 403-428.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Greve, H. R., 2003. A behavioral theory of R&amp;D expenditures and innovations: Evidence from shipbuilding. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 46, pp. 685-702.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Haustein, E., Luther, R. &amp; Schuster, P., 2014. Management control systems in innovation companies: a literature based framework. Journal of Management Control, 24(4), pp. 343-382.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Hirst, G., Van Knippenberg, D. &amp; Zhou, J., 2009. A cross-level perspective on employee creativity: Goal orientation, team learning behavior, and individual creativity. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 52, pp. 280-293.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Hirst, M. K., 1981. Accounting information and the evaluation of subordinate performance: a situational approach. Accounting Review, 56(4), p. 771–784.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Hofer, C. W., 1975. Toward a contingency theory of business strategy. Academy of Management Journal, 18(4), pp. 784-810.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Howard-Grenville, J. A., 2003. Making it work: The resilience of organizational routines, s.l.: Boston University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Hulsheger, U. R., Anderson, N. &amp; Salgado, J. F., 2009. Team-level predictors of innovation at work: A comprehensive meta-analysis spanning three decades of research. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 94, pp. 1128-1145.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Janssen, O. &amp; Van Yperen, N., 2004. Employees’ goal orientations, the quality of leader-member exchange, and the outcomes of job performance and job satisfaction. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 47, pp. 368-384.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Jung, D. I., Chow, C. &amp; Wu, A., 2003. The role of transformational leadership in enhancing organizational innovation: Hypotheses and some preliminary findings. The Leadership Quarterly, Volume 14, pp. 525-544.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Jung, D., Wu, A. &amp; Chow, C. W., 2008. Towards understanding the direct and indirect effects of CEOs’ transformational leadership on firm innovation. The Leadership Quarterly, Volume 19, pp. 582-594.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Karim, S., 2009. Business unit reorganization and innovation in new product markets. Management Science, Volume 55, pp. 1237-1254.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Karreman, D., Sveningsson, S. &amp; Alvesson, M., 2002. The return of the machine bureaucracy? Management control in the work settings of professionals. International Studies of Management Organization, 32(2), p. 70–92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Ketchen, D. J., Boyd, B. K. &amp; Bergh, D. D., 2008. Research methodology in strategic management: Past accomplishments and future challenges. Organizational Research Methods.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Khandwalla, P., 1977. Design of organizations. New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Kloot, L., 1997. Organizational learning and management control systems: responding to environmental change. Management Accounting Research, 8(1), pp. 47-73.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Kober, R., Ng, J. &amp; Paul, B. J., 2007. The interrelationship between management control mechanisms and strategy. Management Accounting Research, 18(4), pp. 425-452.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Langfield- Smith, K., 1997. Managerial control systems and strategy: a critical review. Accounting, Organizations and Society, Volume 22, pp. 207-232.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Lawrence, P. &amp; Lorsch, J., 1967. Organization and environment. Homewood: Irwin</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Lynham, S., 2000. Theory building in the human resource development profession. Human Resource Development Quarterly, 11(2), pp. 159-178.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Lynham, S. A., 2002. The general method of theory-building research in applied disciplines. Advances in Developing Human Resources, 4(3), pp. 221-241.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Madjar, N., 2008. Emotional and informational support from different sources and employee creativity. Journal of Occupational and Organizational Psychology, Volume 81, pp. 83-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Malmi, T. &amp; Brown, D., 2008. Management control systems as a package – opportunities, challenges and research directions. Management Accounting Research, Volume 19, p. 287–300.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Marginson, D., 2002. Management control systems and their effects on strategy formation at middle- management levels: evidence from a UK organization. Strategic Management Journal, Volume 23, pp. 1019-1031.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Martinez-Sanchez, A., Vela-Jimenez, M., Perez-Perez, M. &amp; De-Luis-Carnicer, P., 2011. The dynamics of labour flexibility: Relationships between employment type and innovativeness. Journal of management Studies, Volume 48, pp. 715-736.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>McGrath, R. G. &amp; MacMillan, I. C., 1995. Discovery driven planning. Harvard Business Review, 73(4), pp. 44-54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Merchant, K. A., 1981. The design of the corporate budgeting system: influences on managerial behavior and performance. Accounting Review, 56(4), p. 813–829.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Merchant, K. A., 1984. Influences on departmental budgeting: an empirical examination of a contingency model. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 9(3-4), p. 291–307.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Merchant, K. A., 1985. Control in business organizations. Cambridge: Ballinger.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Merchant, K. A. &amp; Otley, D. T., 2006. A review of the literature on control and accountability. In: The handbook of management accounting research. s.l.:Elsevier Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>Merchant, K. A. &amp; Van der Stede, W. A., 2012. Management control systems: Performance measurement, evaluation and incentives. Harlow: Pearson Education.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>Merton, R. K., 1967. On theoretical sociology. New York: Free Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Merton, R. K., 1968. Social theory and social structure. s.l.:Simon and Schuster.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>Meyer, A., Tsui, A. &amp; Hinings, C. R., 1993. Configurational approaches to organizational analysis. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 36, pp. 1175-1195.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R115">
			<label>115</label>
			<element-citation>Miles, R. E. &amp; Snow, C. C., 1978. Organizational strategy, structure, and process. New York: McGraw-Hill.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R116">
			<label>116</label>
			<element-citation>Miller, D. &amp; Friesen, H., 1984. Organizations, a quantum view. Englewood Cliffs: Prentice Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R117">
			<label>117</label>
			<element-citation>Mintzberg, H., 1979. The structuring of organization: A synthesis of the research. Englewood Cliffs: Prentice-Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R118">
			<label>118</label>
			<element-citation>Mintzberg, H., 1989. Mintzberg on management: Inside our strange world of organizations. s.l.:Simon and Schuster.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R119">
			<label>119</label>
			<element-citation>Mintzberg, H., 1994. The Rise and Fall of Strategic Planning: Reconceiving Roles for Planning, Plans, Planners. New York: Free Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R120">
			<label>120</label>
			<element-citation>Mintzberg, H., 2007. Tracking strategies: Toward a general theory. s.l.:Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R121">
			<label>121</label>
			<element-citation>Miron-Spektor, E., Erez, M. &amp; Naveh, E., 2011. The effect of conformist and attentive-to-detail members on team innovation: Reconciling the innovation paradox. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 54, pp. 740-760.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R122">
			<label>122</label>
			<element-citation>Moores, K. &amp; Yuen, S., 2001. Management accounting systems and organizational configuration: a life-cycle perspective. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 26(4), pp. 351-389.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R123">
			<label>123</label>
			<element-citation>Mundy, J., 2010. Creating dynamic tensions through a balanced use of management control systems. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 35(5), pp. 499-523.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R124">
			<label>124</label>
			<element-citation>Nilsson, F., Olve, N. G. &amp; Parment, A., 2011. Controlling for competitiveness: Strategy formulation and implementation through management control. s.l.:Copenhagen Business School Press DK.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R125">
			<label>125</label>
			<element-citation>Otley, D., 1980. The contingency theory of management accounting: achievement and prognosis. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 5(4), p. 413–428.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R126">
			<label>126</label>
			<element-citation>Otley, D. &amp; Berry, A., 1980. Control, organization and accounting. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 5(2), p. 231–244.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R127">
			<label>127</label>
			<element-citation>Otley, D., Broadbent, J. &amp; Berry, A., 1995. Research in management control: an overview of its development. British Journal of management, 6(S1), pp. S31-S44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R128">
			<label>128</label>
			<element-citation>Otley, D. T., 1999. Performance management: a framework for management control systems research. Management Accounting Research, 10(4), p. 363–382.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R129">
			<label>129</label>
			<element-citation>Ouchi, W., 1979. A conceptual framework for the design of organizational control mechanisms. Management Science, 25(9), p. 833–848.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R130">
			<label>130</label>
			<element-citation>Ouchi, W. G., 1978. The transmission of control through organizational hierarchy. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 21, p. 173–192.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R131">
			<label>131</label>
			<element-citation>Patterson, M. G. et al., 2005. Validating the organizational climate measure: Links to managerial practices, productivity and innovation. Journal of Organizational Behavior, Volume 26, pp. 379-408.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R132">
			<label>132</label>
			<element-citation>Pech, R. J. &amp; Durden, G., 2003. Manoeuvre warfare: a new military paradigm for business decision making. Management Decision, 41(2), pp. 168-179.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R133">
			<label>133</label>
			<element-citation>Perdomo-Ortiz, J., González-Benito, J. &amp; Galende, J., 2006. Total quality management as a forerunner of business innovation capability. Technovation, 26(10), p. 1170–1185.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R134">
			<label>134</label>
			<element-citation>Perrow, C., 1970. Organizational analysis: A sociological view. London: Tavistock.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R135">
			<label>135</label>
			<element-citation>Perrow, C., 1986. Economic theories of organization. Theory and society, 15(1), pp. 11-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R136">
			<label>136</label>
			<element-citation>Perry-Smith, J. &amp; Shalley, C. E., 2003. The social side of creativity: A static and dynamic social network perspective. Academy of Management Review, Volume 28, pp. 89-106.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R137">
			<label>137</label>
			<element-citation>Preble, J. F., 1992. Towards a Comrehensive System of Strategic Control. Journal of Management Studies, 29(4), pp. 391-408.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R138">
			<label>138</label>
			<element-citation>Quinn, J. B., 1980. Strategies for change: Logical incrementalism. s.l.:Irwin Professional Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R139">
			<label>139</label>
			<element-citation>Raja, U. &amp; Johns, G., 2010. The joint effects of personality and job scope on in-role performance, citizenship behaviors and creativity. Human Relations, Volume 63, pp. 981-1005.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R140">
			<label>140</label>
			<element-citation>Rosing, K., Frese, M. &amp; Bausch, A., 2011. Explaining the heterogeneity of the leadership-innovation relationship: Ambidextrous leadership. The Leadership Quarterly, Volume 22, pp. 956-974.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R141">
			<label>141</label>
			<element-citation>Samuel, Y. &amp; Mannheim, B. F., 1970. A multidimensional approach toward a typology of bureaucracy. Administrative Science Quarterly, pp. 216-228.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R142">
			<label>142</label>
			<element-citation>Schreyögg, G. &amp; Steinmann, H., 1987. Strategic control: a new perspective. Academy of Management Review, 12(1), pp. 91-103.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R143">
			<label>143</label>
			<element-citation>Shin, S. J. &amp; Zhou, J., 2003. Transformational leadership, conservation, and creativity: Evidence from Korea. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 46, pp. 703-714.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R144">
			<label>144</label>
			<element-citation>Shipton, H. J. et al., 2006. When promoting positive feelings pays: Aggregate job satisfaction, work design features, and innovation in manufacturing organizations. European Journal of Work and Organizational Psychology, Volume 15, pp. 404-430.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R145">
			<label>145</label>
			<element-citation>Simons, R., 1987. Accounting control systems and business strategy: an empirical analysis. Accounting, Organizations &amp; Society, 12(4), p. 357–374.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R146">
			<label>146</label>
			<element-citation>Simons, R., 1990. The role of management control systems in creating competitive advantage: new perspectives. Accounting, Organizations and Society, Volume 15, p. 127–143.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R147">
			<label>147</label>
			<element-citation>Simons, R., 1991. Strategic orientation and top management attention to control systems. Strategic Management Journal, Volume 12, p. 49–62.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R148">
			<label>148</label>
			<element-citation>Simons, R., 1994. How new top managers use control systems as levers of strategic renewal. Strategic Management Journal, Volume 15, p. 169–189.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R149">
			<label>149</label>
			<element-citation>Simons, R., 1995. Levers of Control. Boston: Harvard Business School Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R150">
			<label>150</label>
			<element-citation>Simons, R., 2000. Performance measurement and control systems for implementing strategies. Upper Saddle River: Prentice Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R151">
			<label>151</label>
			<element-citation>Snell, S. A., 1992. Control theory in strategic human resource management: The mediating effect of administrative information. Academy of management Journal, 35(2), pp. 292-327.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R152">
			<label>152</label>
			<element-citation>Speklé, R. F., 2001. Explaining management control structure variety: a transaction cost economics perspective. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 26(4), pp. 419-441.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R153">
			<label>153</label>
			<element-citation>Stacey, R., 1991. The chaos frontier: creative strategic control for business. s.l.:Butterworth-Heinemann.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R154">
			<label>154</label>
			<element-citation>Stacey, R., 2011. Strategic management and organizational dynamics: The challenge of complexity to ways of thinking about organizations. Harlow: Pearson Education, Ltd..</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R155">
			<label>155</label>
			<element-citation>Stacey, R. D., 1996. Complexity and creativity in organizations. s.l.:Berrett-Koehler Publishers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R156">
			<label>156</label>
			<element-citation>Su, S., Baird, K. &amp; Schoch, H., 2014. The moderating effect of organizational life cycle stages on the association between the interactive and diagnostic approaches to using controls with organizational performance. Management Accounting Research, Volume 26, pp. 40-53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R157">
			<label>157</label>
			<element-citation>Tessier, s. &amp; Otely, D., 2012. A conceptual development of Simons’ Levers of Control framework. Management Accounting Research, Volume 23, p. 171– 185.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R158">
			<label>158</label>
			<element-citation>Thompson, J. D., 1967. Organizations in action: social science bases of administrative theory. s.l.:New York: Mc GrawHill .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R159">
			<label>159</label>
			<element-citation>Tushman, M. L., 1997. Winning through innovation. Strategy &amp; Leadership. 25(4), pp. 14-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R160">
			<label>160</label>
			<element-citation>Tushman, M. L. &amp; O’Reilly III, C. A., 1997. Winning through innovations. s.l.:Harvard Business Review Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R161">
			<label>161</label>
			<element-citation>Vogus, T. J. &amp; Welbourne, T. M., 2003. Structuring for high reliability: HR practices and mindful processes in reliability-seeking organizations. Journal of Organizational Behavior, Volume 24, pp. 877-903.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R162">
			<label>162</label>
			<element-citation>Weick, K. E., 1987. Organizational culture as a source of high reliability. California Management Review, 29(2), p. 112–127.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R163">
			<label>163</label>
			<element-citation>Whetten, D. A., 2002. Modelling-as-theorizing: A systematic methodology for theory development. Essential skills for management research, Volume 45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R164">
			<label>164</label>
			<element-citation>Widener, S., 2007. An empirical analysis of the levers of control framework. Accounting, Organizations and Society , Volume 32, p. 757–788.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R165">
			<label>165</label>
			<element-citation>Wilkins, A. L. &amp; Ouchi, W. G., 1983. Efficient cultures: exploring the relationship between culture and organizational performance. Administrative Science Quarterly, 28(3), p. 468–481.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R166">
			<label>166</label>
			<element-citation>Williams, C. &amp; van Triest, S., 2009. The impact of corporate and national cultures on decentralization in multinational corporations. International Business Review, 18(2), p. 156–167.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R167">
			<label>167</label>
			<element-citation>Williams, J. J., Macintosh, N. B. &amp; Moore, J. C., 1990. Budget related behavior in public sector organizations: some empirical evidence. Accounting. Organizations and Society, 15(3), p. 221–246.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R168">
			<label>168</label>
			<element-citation>Williamson, O. E., 1975. Markets and hierarchies: analysis and antitrust implications. New York: The Free Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R169">
			<label>169</label>
			<element-citation>Wiltbank, R., Dew, N., Read, S. &amp; Sarasvathy, S. D., 2006. What to do next? The case for non predictive strategy. Strategic management journal, 27(10), pp. 981-998.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R170">
			<label>170</label>
			<element-citation>Wong, A., Tjosvold, D. &amp; Liu, C., 2009. Innovation by teams in Shanghai, China: Cooperative goals for group confidence and persistence. British Journal of Management, Volume 20, pp. 238-251.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R171">
			<label>171</label>
			<element-citation>Woodward, J., 1965. Industrial organization: theory and practice. London: Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R172">
			<label>172</label>
			<element-citation>Yang, B., 2002. Meta-analysis research and theory building. Advances in developing human resources, 4(3), pp. 296-316.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R173">
			<label>173</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, X. &amp; Bartol, K. M., 2010. The influence of creative process engagement on employee creative performance and overall job performance: A curvilinear assessment. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 95, pp. 862-873.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R174">
			<label>174</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, Z., Hempel, P. S., Han, Y. &amp; Tjosvold, D., 2007. Transactive memory system links work team characteristics and performance. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 92, pp. 1722-1730.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R175">
			<label>175</label>
			<element-citation>Zhou, J. et al., 2009. Social networks, personal values, and creativity: Evidence for curvilinear and interaction effects. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 94, pp. 1544-1552.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R176">
			<label>176</label>
			<element-citation>حسینی، م.، رضائیان، ع.، قره چه، م. &amp; پریزادی، ع.، 1393. توسعه یک چارچوب مفهومی جدید از نظامهای نظارت سازمانی مبتنی بر نگاه بسته ای. چشم انداز مدیریت بازرگانی, 20(53)._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R177">
			<label>177</label>
			<element-citation>Abdel-Kader, M. &amp; Luther, R., 2008. The impact of firm characteristics on management accounting practices: a UK-based empirical analysis. The British Accounting Review, 40(1), p. 2–27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R178">
			<label>178</label>
			<element-citation>Abernethy, M. A., Bouwens, J. &amp; Van Lent, L., 2004. Determinants of control system design in divisionalized firms. The Accounting Review, 79(3), pp. 545-570.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R179">
			<label>179</label>
			<element-citation>Abernethy, M. A., Bouwens, J. &amp; Van Lent, L., 2010. Leadership and control system design. Management Accounting Research, 21(1), pp. 2-16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R180">
			<label>180</label>
			<element-citation>Abernethy, M. A. &amp; Brownell, P., 1999. The role of budgets in organizations facing strategic change: an exploratory study. Accounting, organizations and society, 24(3), pp. 189-204.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R181">
			<label>181</label>
			<element-citation>Abernethy, M. A. &amp; Chua, W. F., 1996. A Field Study of Control System “Redesign”: The Impact of Institutional Processes on Strategic Choice. Contemporary Accounting Research, 13(2), pp. 569-606.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R182">
			<label>182</label>
			<element-citation>Abernethy, M. &amp; Brownell, P., 1997. Management control systems in research and development organizations: the role of accounting, behavior and personnel controls. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 22(3/4), pp. 233-248.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R183">
			<label>183</label>
			<element-citation>Ahrens, T. &amp; Chapman, C., 2002. The Structuration of Legitimate Performance Measures and Management: Day-to-Day Contests of Accountability in a U.K. Restaurant Chain. Management Accounting Research, 13(2), pp. 1-21.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R184">
			<label>184</label>
			<element-citation>Allen, T., 1977. Communications, Technology Transfer, and the Role of Technical Gatekeeper. R&amp;D Management, p. 14–21.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R185">
			<label>185</label>
			<element-citation>Amabile, T., 1996. Creativity in context: Update to the Social Psychology of Creativity. S.l.:Westview Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R186">
			<label>186</label>
			<element-citation>Analoui, F., 2001. What motivates senior managers?: The case of Romania. Journal of Managerial Psychology, 15(4), p. 324–340.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R187">
			<label>187</label>
			<element-citation>Anderson, N., Potočnik, K. &amp; Zhou, J., 2014. Innovation and Creativity in Organizations A State-of-the-Science Review, Prospective Commentary, and Guiding Framework. Journal of Management, 40(5), pp. 1297-1333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R188">
			<label>188</label>
			<element-citation>Anderson, P. et al., 1999. Introduction to the special issue: Applications of complexity theory to organization science. Organization Science, 10(3), pp. 233-236.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R189">
			<label>189</label>
			<element-citation>Anthony, R., 1965. Planning and Control Systems: A Framework for Analysis. Boston: Harvard University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R190">
			<label>190</label>
			<element-citation>Ashby, W., 1960. Design for a Brain. s.l.:Springer Science &amp; Business Media.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R191">
			<label>191</label>
			<element-citation>Auzair, S. M. &amp; &amp;Langfield-Smith, K., 2005. The effect of service process type, business strategy and life cycle stage on bureaucratic MCS in service organizations. Management Accounting Research, 16(4), pp. 399-421.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R192">
			<label>192</label>
			<element-citation>Baer, M., 2010. The strength-of-weak-ties perspective on creativity: A comprehensive examination and extension. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 95, pp. 592-601.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R193">
			<label>193</label>
			<element-citation>Baer, M., 2012. Putting creativity to work: The implementation of creative ideas in organizations. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 55, pp. 1102-1119.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R194">
			<label>194</label>
			<element-citation>Baer, M., 2012. Putting creativity to work: The implementation of creative ideas in organizations. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 55, pp. 1102-1119.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R195">
			<label>195</label>
			<element-citation>Baer, M. &amp; Oldham, G. R., 2006. The curvilinear relation between experienced creative time pressure and creativity: Moderating effects of openness to experience and support for creativity. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 91, pp. 963-970.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R196">
			<label>196</label>
			<element-citation>Bedford, D. S. &amp; Malmi, T., 2015. Configurations of Control: An Exploratory Analysis. Managing Acconting Research, Volume 27, pp. 2-26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R197">
			<label>197</label>
			<element-citation>Benson, J. &amp; Hagtvet, K., 1996. The interplay among design, data analysis, and theory in the measurement of coping. In: Handbook of coping: Theory, research, applications. New York: John Wiley, pp. 83-106.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R198">
			<label>198</label>
			<element-citation>Berry, A. J., Broadbent, J. &amp; Otley, D. T., 1995. Managerial Control: Theories, Issues and Practices. London: Macmillan.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R199">
			<label>199</label>
			<element-citation>Bisbe, J. &amp; Malagueno, R., 2012. Using strategic performance measurement systems for strategy formulation: Does it work in dynamic environments?. Management Accounting Research, 23(4), pp. 296-311.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R200">
			<label>200</label>
			<element-citation>Bisbe, J. &amp; Otley, D., 2004. The effects of the interactive use of management control systems on product innovation. Accounting. organizations and society, 29(8), pp. 709-737.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R201">
			<label>201</label>
			<element-citation>Bledow, R. et al., 2009. A dialectic perspective on innovation: Conflicting demands, multiple pathways, and ambidexterity, Industrial and Organizational Psychology: Perspectives on Science and Practice, Volume 2, pp. 305-337.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R202">
			<label>202</label>
			<element-citation>Brownell, P. &amp; Merchant, K., 1990. The budgetary and performance influences of product standardization and manufacturing process automation. Journal of Accounting Research, 28(2), p. 388–397.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R203">
			<label>203</label>
			<element-citation>Burns, T. &amp; Stalker, G., 1961. The management of innovation. London: Tavistock.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R204">
			<label>204</label>
			<element-citation>Burns, W. J. &amp; Waterhouse, J. H., 1975. Budgetary control and organizational structure. Journal of Accounting Research, 13(2), pp. 177-203.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R205">
			<label>205</label>
			<element-citation>Burton, R. M. &amp; Obel, B., 2004. Strategic organizational diagnosis and design: The dynamics of fit. s.l.:Springer Science Business Media.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R206">
			<label>206</label>
			<element-citation>Camison-Zornoza, C., Lapiedra-Alcami, R., Segarra-Cipres, M. &amp; Boronat-Navarro, M., 2004. A meta-analysis of innovation and organizational size. Organization Studies, Volume 25, pp. 331-361.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R207">
			<label>207</label>
			<element-citation>Cardinal, L. B., 2001. Technological innovation in the pharmaceutical industry: managing research and development using input, behavior, and output controls. Organization Science, Volume 12, p. 19–36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R208">
			<label>208</label>
			<element-citation>Cardinal, L. B., Sitkin, S. B. &amp; Long, C. P., 2004. Balancing and rebalancing in the creation and evolution of organizational control. Organization Science, 15(4), pp. 411-431.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R209">
			<label>209</label>
			<element-citation>Chapman, C. S., 1997. Reflections on a contingent view ofaccounting. Accounting, Organizations and Society, Volume 22, p. 189–205.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R210">
			<label>210</label>
			<element-citation>Chenhall, R., 2003. Management control systems design within its organizational context: Findings from contingency- based research and directions for the future. Accounting, Organizations and Society, Volume 28, p. 127–168.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R211">
			<label>211</label>
			<element-citation>Chenhall, R. H., 2005. Integrative strategic performance measurement systems, strategic alignment of manufacturing, learning and strategic outcomes: an exploratory study. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 30(5), p. 395–422.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R212">
			<label>212</label>
			<element-citation>Chenhall, R. H. &amp; Langfield-Smith, K., 1998. The relationship between strategic priorities, management techniques and management accounting: an empirical investigation using a systems approach. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 23(3), pp. 243-264.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R213">
			<label>213</label>
			<element-citation>Chenhall, R. H. &amp; Morris, D., 1986. The impact of structure, environment, and interdependence on the perceived usefulness of management accounting systems. Accounting Review, 61(1), p. 16–35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R214">
			<label>214</label>
			<element-citation>Chenhall, R. H. &amp; Morris, D. E. I. G. A. N., 1995. Organic decision and communication processes and management accounting systems in entrepreneurial and conservative business organizations. Omega, 23(5), pp. 485-497.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R215">
			<label>215</label>
			<element-citation>Child, J., 1973. Strategies of control and organizational behavior. Administrative Science Quarterly, 18(1), pp. 1-17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R216">
			<label>216</label>
			<element-citation>Choi, J. N., Anderson, T. A. &amp; Veillette, A., 2009. Contextual inhibitors of employee creativity in organizations: The insulating role of creative ability. Group Organization Management, Volume 34, pp. 330-357.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R217">
			<label>217</label>
			<element-citation>Choi, J. N. &amp; Chang, J. Y., 2009. Innovation implementation in the public sector: An integration of institutional and collective dynamics. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 94, pp. 245-253.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R218">
			<label>218</label>
			<element-citation>Choi, J. N. &amp; Price, R. H., 2005. The effects of person-innovation fit on individual responses to innovation. Journal of Occupational and Organizational Psychology, Volume 78, pp. 83-96.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R219">
			<label>219</label>
			<element-citation>Christensen, C., 1997. The innovator’s dilemma: when new technologies cause great firms to fail. s.l.:Harvard Business Review Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R220">
			<label>220</label>
			<element-citation>Clark, K. &amp; Fujimoto, T., 1991. Product Development Performance. Boston: Harvard Business School Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R221">
			<label>221</label>
			<element-citation>Clegg, C., Unsworth, K., Epitropaki, O. &amp; Parker, G., 2002. Implicating trust in the innovation process. Journal of Occupational and Organizational Psychology, Volume 75, pp. 409-422.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R222">
			<label>222</label>
			<element-citation>Cohendet, P. &amp; Simon, L., 2007. Playing across the playground: Paradoxes of knowledge creation in the videogame firm. Journal of Organizational Behavior, Volume 28, pp. 587-605.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R223">
			<label>223</label>
			<element-citation>Collier, P. M., 2005. Entrepreneurial control and the construction of a relevant accounting. Management Accounting Research, 16(3), p. 321–339.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R224">
			<label>224</label>
			<element-citation>Daft, R. L. &amp; Macintosh, N. B., 1984. The nature and use of formal control systems for management control and strategy implementation. Journal of Management, 10(1), pp. 43-66.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R225">
			<label>225</label>
			<element-citation>Damanpour, F., 1991. Organizational innovation: ameta-analysis of effects of determinants and moderators. Academy of Management Journal, 34(3), p. 555–590.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R226">
			<label>226</label>
			<element-citation>Damanpour, F., 2010. An integration of research findings of effects of firm size and market competition on product and process innovations. British Journal of Management, Volume 21, pp. 996-1010.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R227">
			<label>227</label>
			<element-citation>Davila, A., 2005. An exploratory study on the emergence of management control systems: formalizing human resources in small growing firms. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 30(3), p. 223–248.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R228">
			<label>228</label>
			<element-citation>Davila, T., 2000. An empirical study on the drivers of management control systems’ design in new product development. Accounting, organizations and society, 25(4), pp. 383-409.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R229">
			<label>229</label>
			<element-citation>Dent, J. F., 1990. Strategy, organization and control: some possibilities for accounting research. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 15(1), pp. 3-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R230">
			<label>230</label>
			<element-citation>Ditillo, A., 2004. Dealing with uncertainty in knowledge-intensive firms: the role of management control systems as knowledge integration mechanisms. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 29(3/4), p. 401– 421.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R231">
			<label>231</label>
			<element-citation>Donaldson, L., 1996. For positivist organization theory: proving the hard core. London: Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R232">
			<label>232</label>
			<element-citation>Donaldson, L., 2001. The contingency theory of organizations. Thousand Oaks: Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R233">
			<label>233</label>
			<element-citation>Doty, H., Glick, W. H. &amp; Huber, G. P., 1993. Fit, equifinality, and organizational effectiveness: a test of two configurational theories. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 36, p. 1196–1250.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R234">
			<label>234</label>
			<element-citation>Dougherty, D., 1992. Interpretive barriers to successful product innovation in large firms. Organization Science, 3(2), p. 179–202.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R235">
			<label>235</label>
			<element-citation>Dougherty, D. &amp; Hardy, C., 1996. Sustained product innovation in large, mature organizations: Overcoming innovation-to-organization problems. Academy of Management Journal, 39(5), pp. 1120-1153.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R236">
			<label>236</label>
			<element-citation>Drazin, R. &amp; Van De Ven, A. H., 1985. Alternative forms of fit in contingency theory. Administrative Science Quarterly, 30(4), p. 514–539.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R237">
			<label>237</label>
			<element-citation>Dunk, A. S., 1992. Reliance on budgetary control, manufacturing process automation and production subunit performance: a research note. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 17(3-4), p. 195–203.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R238">
			<label>238</label>
			<element-citation>Durden, C. &amp; Perera, H., 2010. Towards control using strategic navigation in turbulent organisational environments. International Journal of Accounting, Auditing and Performance Evaluation, 6(4), pp. 397-421.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R239">
			<label>239</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K. M., 1989. Building theories from case study research. Academy of management review, 14(4), pp. 532-550.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R240">
			<label>240</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K. M., 2002. Has strategy changed?. MIT Sloan Management Review, 43(2), pp. 88-91.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R241">
			<label>241</label>
			<element-citation>Elliot, A. J. &amp; Church, M. A., 1997. A hierarchical model of approach and avoidance achievement motivation. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, Volume 72, pp. 218-232.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R242">
			<label>242</label>
			<element-citation>Ezzamel, M., 1990. The impact of environmental uncertainty, managerial autonomy and size on budget characteristics. Management Accounting Research, Volume 1, p. 181–197.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R243">
			<label>243</label>
			<element-citation>Ferreira, A. &amp; Otley, D., 2009. The design and use of management control systems: an extended framework for analysis. Management Accounting Research, Volume 20, p. 263–282.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R244">
			<label>244</label>
			<element-citation>Fisher, J., 1995. Contingency-based research on management control systems: categorisation by level of complexity. Journal of Accounting Literature, Volume 14, p. 24–53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R245">
			<label>245</label>
			<element-citation>Flamholtz, E., 1996. Effective organizational control: a framework, applications, and implications. European Management Journal, 14(6), pp. 596-611.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R246">
			<label>246</label>
			<element-citation>Flamholtz, E. G., Das, T. K. &amp; Tsui, A. S., 1985. Toward an integrative framework of organizational control. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 10(1), pp. 35-50.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R247">
			<label>247</label>
			<element-citation>Flamholtz, E. G. &amp; Randle, Y., 2000. Growing pains: Transitioning from an entrepreneurship to a professionally managed firm. s.l.:John Wiley Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R248">
			<label>248</label>
			<element-citation>Galbraith, I. R., 1973. Designing complex organizations, Reading. s.l.:MA: Addison-Wesley.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R249">
			<label>249</label>
			<element-citation>George, J. M., 2007. Creativity in organizations. The Academy of Management Annals, Volume 1, pp. 439-477.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R250">
			<label>250</label>
			<element-citation>Gerdin, J., 2005. Management accounting system design in manufacturing departments: an empirical investigation using a multiple contingencies approach. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 30(2), pp. 99-126.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R251">
			<label>251</label>
			<element-citation>Gilson, L. L. &amp; Shalley, C. E., 2004. A little creativity goes a long way: An examination of teams’ engagement in creative processes. Journal of Management, Volume 30, pp. 453-470.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R252">
			<label>252</label>
			<element-citation>Gong, Y., Huang, J. &amp; Farh, J., 2009. Employee learning orientation, transformational leadership, and employee creativity: The mediating role of employee creative self-efficacy. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 52, pp. 765-778.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R253">
			<label>253</label>
			<element-citation>Goold, M. &amp; Quinn, J. J., 1990. The paradox of strategic controls. Strategic Management Journal, 11(1), pp. 43-57.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R254">
			<label>254</label>
			<element-citation>Gordon, L. A. &amp; Narayanan, V. K., 1984. Management accounting systems, perceived environmental uncertainty and organization structure: an empirical investigation. Accounting, Organizations and Society, Volume 1, p. 33–47.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R255">
			<label>255</label>
			<element-citation>Grabner, I. &amp; Moers, F., 2013. Management control as a system or a package? Conceptual and empirical issues. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 38(6), pp. 407-419.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R256">
			<label>256</label>
			<element-citation>Greiner, L. E., 1972. Evolution and revolution as organizations grow. Harvard Business Review, Volume 50, p. 37–46.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R257">
			<label>257</label>
			<element-citation>Gresov, C. &amp; Drazin, R., 1997. Equifinality: Functional equivalence in organization design. Academy of management review, 22(2), pp. 403-428.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R258">
			<label>258</label>
			<element-citation>Greve, H. R., 2003. A behavioral theory of R&amp;D expenditures and innovations: Evidence from shipbuilding. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 46, pp. 685-702.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R259">
			<label>259</label>
			<element-citation>Haustein, E., Luther, R. &amp; Schuster, P., 2014. Management control systems in innovation companies: a literature based framework. Journal of Management Control, 24(4), pp. 343-382.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R260">
			<label>260</label>
			<element-citation>Hirst, G., Van Knippenberg, D. &amp; Zhou, J., 2009. A cross-level perspective on employee creativity: Goal orientation, team learning behavior, and individual creativity. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 52, pp. 280-293.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R261">
			<label>261</label>
			<element-citation>Hirst, M. K., 1981. Accounting information and the evaluation of subordinate performance: a situational approach. Accounting Review, 56(4), p. 771–784.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R262">
			<label>262</label>
			<element-citation>Hofer, C. W., 1975. Toward a contingency theory of business strategy. Academy of Management Journal, 18(4), pp. 784-810.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R263">
			<label>263</label>
			<element-citation>Hoseini, M., Rezaeian, As., Gharehcheh, M. &amp; Prizadi, As., 2014. Develop a new conceptual framework of closed-door organizational surveillance systems. Journal of Business Management, 20(53).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R264">
			<label>264</label>
			<element-citation>Howard-Grenville, J. A., 2003. Making it work: The resilience of organizational routines, s.l.: Boston University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R265">
			<label>265</label>
			<element-citation>Hulsheger, U. R., Anderson, N. &amp; Salgado, J. F., 2009. Team-level predictors of innovation at work: A comprehensive meta-analysis spanning three decades of research. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 94, pp. 1128-1145.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R266">
			<label>266</label>
			<element-citation>Janssen, O. &amp; Van Yperen, N., 2004. Employees’ goal orientations, the quality of leader-member exchange, and the outcomes of job performance and job satisfaction. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 47, pp. 368-384.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R267">
			<label>267</label>
			<element-citation>Jung, D. I., Chow, C. &amp; Wu, A., 2003. The role of transformational leadership in enhancing organizational innovation: Hypotheses and some preliminary findings. The Leadership Quarterly, Volume 14, pp. 525-544.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R268">
			<label>268</label>
			<element-citation>Jung, D., Wu, A. &amp; Chow, C. W., 2008. Towards understanding the direct and indirect effects of CEOs’ transformational leadership on firm innovation. The Leadership Quarterly, Volume 19, pp. 582-594.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R269">
			<label>269</label>
			<element-citation>Karim, S., 2009. Business unit reorganization and innovation in new product markets. Management Science, Volume 55, pp. 1237-1254.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R270">
			<label>270</label>
			<element-citation>Karreman, D., Sveningsson, S. &amp; Alvesson, M., 2002. The return of the machine bureaucracy? Management control in the work settings of professionals. International Studies of Management Organization, 32(2), p. 70–92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R271">
			<label>271</label>
			<element-citation>Ketchen, D. J., Boyd, B. K. &amp; Bergh, D. D., 2008. Research methodology in strategic management: Past accomplishments and future challenges. Organizational Research Methods.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R272">
			<label>272</label>
			<element-citation>Khandwalla, P., 1977. Design of organizations. New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R273">
			<label>273</label>
			<element-citation>Kloot, L., 1997. Organizational learning and management control systems: responding to environmental change. Management Accounting Research, 8(1), pp. 47-73.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R274">
			<label>274</label>
			<element-citation>Kober, R., Ng, J. &amp; Paul, B. J., 2007. The interrelationship between management control mechanisms and strategy. Management Accounting Research, 18(4), pp. 425-452.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R275">
			<label>275</label>
			<element-citation>Langfield- Smith, K., 1997. Managerial control systems and strategy: a critical review. Accounting, Organizations and Society, Volume 22, pp. 207-232.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R276">
			<label>276</label>
			<element-citation>Lawrence, P. &amp; Lorsch, J., 1967. Organization and environment. Homewood: Irwin</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R277">
			<label>277</label>
			<element-citation>Lynham, S., 2000. Theory building in the human resource development profession. Human Resource Development Quarterly, 11(2), pp. 159-178.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R278">
			<label>278</label>
			<element-citation>Lynham, S. A., 2002. The general method of theory-building research in applied disciplines. Advances in Developing Human Resources, 4(3), pp. 221-241.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R279">
			<label>279</label>
			<element-citation>Madjar, N., 2008. Emotional and informational support from different sources and employee creativity. Journal of Occupational and Organizational Psychology, Volume 81, pp. 83-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R280">
			<label>280</label>
			<element-citation>Malmi, T. &amp; Brown, D., 2008. Management control systems as a package – opportunities, challenges and research directions. Management Accounting Research, Volume 19, p. 287–300.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R281">
			<label>281</label>
			<element-citation>Marginson, D., 2002. Management control systems and their effects on strategy formation at middle- management levels: evidence from a UK organization. Strategic Management Journal, Volume 23, pp. 1019-1031.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R282">
			<label>282</label>
			<element-citation>Martinez-Sanchez, A., Vela-Jimenez, M., Perez-Perez, M. &amp; De-Luis-Carnicer, P., 2011. The dynamics of labour flexibility: Relationships between employment type and innovativeness. Journal of management Studies, Volume 48, pp. 715-736.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R283">
			<label>283</label>
			<element-citation>McGrath, R. G. &amp; MacMillan, I. C., 1995. Discovery driven planning. Harvard Business Review, 73(4), pp. 44-54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R284">
			<label>284</label>
			<element-citation>Merchant, K. A., 1981. The design of the corporate budgeting system: influences on managerial behavior and performance. Accounting Review, 56(4), p. 813–829.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R285">
			<label>285</label>
			<element-citation>Merchant, K. A., 1984. Influences on departmental budgeting: an empirical examination of a contingency model. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 9(3-4), p. 291–307.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R286">
			<label>286</label>
			<element-citation>Merchant, K. A., 1985. Control in business organizations. Cambridge: Ballinger.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R287">
			<label>287</label>
			<element-citation>Merchant, K. A. &amp; Otley, D. T., 2006. A review of the literature on control and accountability. In: The handbook of management accounting research. s.l.:Elsevier Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R288">
			<label>288</label>
			<element-citation>Merchant, K. A. &amp; Van der Stede, W. A., 2012. Management control systems: Performance measurement, evaluation and incentives. Harlow: Pearson Education.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R289">
			<label>289</label>
			<element-citation>Merton, R. K., 1967. On theoretical sociology. New York: Free Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R290">
			<label>290</label>
			<element-citation>Merton, R. K., 1968. Social theory and social structure. s.l.:Simon and Schuster.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R291">
			<label>291</label>
			<element-citation>Meyer, A., Tsui, A. &amp; Hinings, C. R., 1993. Configurational approaches to organizational analysis. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 36, pp. 1175-1195.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R292">
			<label>292</label>
			<element-citation>Miles, R. E. &amp; Snow, C. C., 1978. Organizational strategy, structure, and process. New York: McGraw-Hill.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R293">
			<label>293</label>
			<element-citation>Miller, D. &amp; Friesen, H., 1984. Organizations, a quantum view. Englewood Cliffs: Prentice Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R294">
			<label>294</label>
			<element-citation>Mintzberg, H., 1979. The structuring of organization: A synthesis of the research. Englewood Cliffs: Prentice-Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R295">
			<label>295</label>
			<element-citation>Mintzberg, H., 1989. Mintzberg on management: Inside our strange world of organizations. s.l.:Simon and Schuster.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R296">
			<label>296</label>
			<element-citation>Mintzberg, H., 1994. The Rise and Fall of Strategic Planning: Reconceiving Roles for Planning, Plans, Planners. New York: Free Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R297">
			<label>297</label>
			<element-citation>Mintzberg, H., 2007. Tracking strategies: Toward a general theory. s.l.:Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R298">
			<label>298</label>
			<element-citation>Miron-Spektor, E., Erez, M. &amp; Naveh, E., 2011. The effect of conformist and attentive-to-detail members on team innovation: Reconciling the innovation paradox. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 54, pp. 740-760.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R299">
			<label>299</label>
			<element-citation>Moores, K. &amp; Yuen, S., 2001. Management accounting systems and organizational configuration: a life-cycle perspective. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 26(4), pp. 351-389.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R300">
			<label>300</label>
			<element-citation>Mundy, J., 2010. Creating dynamic tensions through a balanced use of management control systems. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 35(5), pp. 499-523.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R301">
			<label>301</label>
			<element-citation>Nilsson, F., Olve, N. G. &amp; Parment, A., 2011. Controlling for competitiveness: Strategy formulation and implementation through management control. s.l.:Copenhagen Business School Press DK.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R302">
			<label>302</label>
			<element-citation>Otley, D., 1980. The contingency theory of management accounting: achievement and prognosis. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 5(4), p. 413–428.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R303">
			<label>303</label>
			<element-citation>Otley, D. &amp; Berry, A., 1980. Control, organization and accounting. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 5(2), p. 231–244.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R304">
			<label>304</label>
			<element-citation>Otley, D., Broadbent, J. &amp; Berry, A., 1995. Research in management control: an overview of its development. British Journal of management, 6(S1), pp. S31-S44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R305">
			<label>305</label>
			<element-citation>Otley, D. T., 1999. Performance management: a framework for management control systems research. Management Accounting Research, 10(4), p. 363–382.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R306">
			<label>306</label>
			<element-citation>Ouchi, W., 1979. A conceptual framework for the design of organizational control mechanisms. Management Science, 25(9), p. 833–848.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R307">
			<label>307</label>
			<element-citation>Ouchi, W. G., 1978. The transmission of control through organizational hierarchy. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 21, p. 173–192.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R308">
			<label>308</label>
			<element-citation>Patterson, M. G. et al., 2005. Validating the organizational climate measure: Links to managerial practices, productivity and innovation. Journal of Organizational Behavior, Volume 26, pp. 379-408.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R309">
			<label>309</label>
			<element-citation>Pech, R. J. &amp; Durden, G., 2003. Manoeuvre warfare: a new military paradigm for business decision making. Management Decision, 41(2), pp. 168-179.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R310">
			<label>310</label>
			<element-citation>Perdomo-Ortiz, J., González-Benito, J. &amp; Galende, J., 2006. Total quality management as a forerunner of business innovation capability. Technovation, 26(10), p. 1170–1185.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R311">
			<label>311</label>
			<element-citation>Perrow, C., 1970. Organizational analysis: A sociological view. London: Tavistock.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R312">
			<label>312</label>
			<element-citation>Perrow, C., 1986. Economic theories of organization. Theory and society, 15(1), pp. 11-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R313">
			<label>313</label>
			<element-citation>Perry-Smith, J. &amp; Shalley, C. E., 2003. The social side of creativity: A static and dynamic social network perspective. Academy of Management Review, Volume 28, pp. 89-106.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R314">
			<label>314</label>
			<element-citation>Preble, J. F., 1992. Towards a Comrehensive System of Strategic Control. Journal of Management Studies, 29(4), pp. 391-408.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R315">
			<label>315</label>
			<element-citation>Quinn, J. B., 1980. Strategies for change: Logical incrementalism. s.l.:Irwin Professional Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R316">
			<label>316</label>
			<element-citation>Raja, U. &amp; Johns, G., 2010. The joint effects of personality and job scope on in-role performance, citizenship behaviors and creativity. Human Relations, Volume 63, pp. 981-1005.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R317">
			<label>317</label>
			<element-citation>Rosing, K., Frese, M. &amp; Bausch, A., 2011. Explaining the heterogeneity of the leadership-innovation relationship: Ambidextrous leadership. The Leadership Quarterly, Volume 22, pp. 956-974.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R318">
			<label>318</label>
			<element-citation>Samuel, Y. &amp; Mannheim, B. F., 1970. A multidimensional approach toward a typology of bureaucracy. Administrative Science Quarterly, pp. 216-228.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R319">
			<label>319</label>
			<element-citation>Schreyögg, G. &amp; Steinmann, H., 1987. Strategic control: a new perspective. Academy of Management Review, 12(1), pp. 91-103.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R320">
			<label>320</label>
			<element-citation>Shin, S. J. &amp; Zhou, J., 2003. Transformational leadership, conservation, and creativity: Evidence from Korea. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 46, pp. 703-714.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R321">
			<label>321</label>
			<element-citation>Shipton, H. J. et al., 2006. When promoting positive feelings pays: Aggregate job satisfaction, work design features, and innovation in manufacturing organizations. European Journal of Work and Organizational Psychology, Volume 15, pp. 404-430.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R322">
			<label>322</label>
			<element-citation>Simons, R., 1987. Accounting control systems and business strategy: an empirical analysis. Accounting, Organizations &amp; Society, 12(4), p. 357–374.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R323">
			<label>323</label>
			<element-citation>Simons, R., 1990. The role of management control systems in creating competitive advantage: new perspectives. Accounting, Organizations and Society, Volume 15, p. 127–143.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R324">
			<label>324</label>
			<element-citation>Simons, R., 1991. Strategic orientation and top management attention to control systems. Strategic Management Journal, Volume 12, p. 49–62.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R325">
			<label>325</label>
			<element-citation>Simons, R., 1994. How new top managers use control systems as levers of strategic renewal. Strategic Management Journal, Volume 15, p. 169–189.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R326">
			<label>326</label>
			<element-citation>Simons, R., 1995. Levers of Control. Boston: Harvard Business School Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R327">
			<label>327</label>
			<element-citation>Simons, R., 2000. Performance measurement and control systems for implementing strategies. Upper Saddle River: Prentice Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R328">
			<label>328</label>
			<element-citation>Snell, S. A., 1992. Control theory in strategic human resource management: The mediating effect of administrative information. Academy of management Journal, 35(2), pp. 292-327.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R329">
			<label>329</label>
			<element-citation>Speklé, R. F., 2001. Explaining management control structure variety: a transaction cost economics perspective. Accounting, Organizations and Society, 26(4), pp. 419-441.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R330">
			<label>330</label>
			<element-citation>Stacey, R., 1991. The chaos frontier: creative strategic control for business. s.l.:Butterworth-Heinemann.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R331">
			<label>331</label>
			<element-citation>Stacey, R., 2011. Strategic management and organizational dynamics: The challenge of complexity to ways of thinking about organizations. Harlow: Pearson Education, Ltd..</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R332">
			<label>332</label>
			<element-citation>Stacey, R. D., 1996. Complexity and creativity in organizations. s.l.:Berrett-Koehler Publishers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R333">
			<label>333</label>
			<element-citation>Su, S., Baird, K. &amp; Schoch, H., 2014. The moderating effect of organizational life cycle stages on the association between the interactive and diagnostic approaches to using controls with organizational performance. Management Accounting Research, Volume 26, pp. 40-53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R334">
			<label>334</label>
			<element-citation>Tessier, s. &amp; Otely, D., 2012. A conceptual development of Simons’ Levers of Control framework. Management Accounting Research, Volume 23, p. 171– 185.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R335">
			<label>335</label>
			<element-citation>Thompson, J. D., 1967. Organizations in action: social science bases of administrative theory. s.l.:New York: Mc GrawHill .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R336">
			<label>336</label>
			<element-citation>Tushman, M. L., 1997. Winning through innovation. Strategy &amp; Leadership. 25(4), pp. 14-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R337">
			<label>337</label>
			<element-citation>Tushman, M. L. &amp; O’Reilly III, C. A., 1997. Winning through innovations. s.l.:Harvard Business Review Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R338">
			<label>338</label>
			<element-citation>Vogus, T. J. &amp; Welbourne, T. M., 2003. Structuring for high reliability: HR practices and mindful processes in reliability-seeking organizations. Journal of Organizational Behavior, Volume 24, pp. 877-903.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R339">
			<label>339</label>
			<element-citation>Weick, K. E., 1987. Organizational culture as a source of high reliability. California Management Review, 29(2), p. 112–127.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R340">
			<label>340</label>
			<element-citation>Whetten, D. A., 2002. Modelling-as-theorizing: A systematic methodology for theory development. Essential skills for management research, Volume 45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R341">
			<label>341</label>
			<element-citation>Widener, S., 2007. An empirical analysis of the levers of control framework. Accounting, Organizations and Society , Volume 32, p. 757–788.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R342">
			<label>342</label>
			<element-citation>Wilkins, A. L. &amp; Ouchi, W. G., 1983. Efficient cultures: exploring the relationship between culture and organizational performance. Administrative Science Quarterly, 28(3), p. 468–481.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R343">
			<label>343</label>
			<element-citation>Williams, C. &amp; van Triest, S., 2009. The impact of corporate and national cultures on decentralization in multinational corporations. International Business Review, 18(2), p. 156–167.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R344">
			<label>344</label>
			<element-citation>Williams, J. J., Macintosh, N. B. &amp; Moore, J. C., 1990. Budget related behavior in public sector organizations: some empirical evidence. Accounting. Organizations and Society, 15(3), p. 221–246.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R345">
			<label>345</label>
			<element-citation>Williamson, O. E., 1975. Markets and hierarchies: analysis and antitrust implications. New York: The Free Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R346">
			<label>346</label>
			<element-citation>Wiltbank, R., Dew, N., Read, S. &amp; Sarasvathy, S. D., 2006. What to do next? The case for non predictive strategy. Strategic management journal, 27(10), pp. 981-998.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R347">
			<label>347</label>
			<element-citation>Wong, A., Tjosvold, D. &amp; Liu, C., 2009. Innovation by teams in Shanghai, China: Cooperative goals for group confidence and persistence. British Journal of Management, Volume 20, pp. 238-251.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R348">
			<label>348</label>
			<element-citation>Woodward, J., 1965. Industrial organization: theory and practice. London: Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R349">
			<label>349</label>
			<element-citation>Yang, B., 2002. Meta-analysis research and theory building. Advances in developing human resources, 4(3), pp. 296-316.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R350">
			<label>350</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, X. &amp; Bartol, K. M., 2010. The influence of creative process engagement on employee creative performance and overall job performance: A curvilinear assessment. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 95, pp. 862-873.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R351">
			<label>351</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, Z., Hempel, P. S., Han, Y. &amp; Tjosvold, D., 2007. Transactive memory system links work team characteristics and performance. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 92, pp. 1722-1730.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R352">
			<label>352</label>
			<element-citation>Zhou, J. et al., 2009. Social networks, personal values, and creativity: Evidence for curvilinear and interaction effects. Journal of Applied Psychology, Volume 94, pp. 1544-1552.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14723_0878fbc84a1fd8c17ad4326b69ed8a34.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی رابطه متقابل نوآوری درک شده سازمانی با سایر مولفه های جو سازمانی در کارکنان ستاد شرکت برق منطقه ای خراسان</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مرتضوی</surname>
			            <given-names>سعید</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد،</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>خوراکیان</surname>
			            <given-names>علیرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>ناصری نژاد</surname>
			            <given-names>الهه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>معماری</surname>
			            <given-names>علی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>12</month>
			        <year>2014</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>3</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>33</fpage>
			      <lpage>52</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>01</day>
			          <month>06</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>27</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2014, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14723.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14723.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>مفهوم نوآوری درک‌شده سازمانی به درک کارکنان از حمایت سازمان از نوآوری می‌پردازد که باعث افزایش رضایت و تعهد کارکنان می‌شود. پژوهشگران در پژوهش‌های خود اثر عوامل سازمانی بر نوآوری درک‌شده سازمانی را بررسی کرده‌اند. پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی میزان اثر جو سازمانی و ابعاد آن بر نوآوری درک‌شده سازمانی با توجه به نقش جنسیت به‌عنوان یک متغیر تعدیلگر انجام شده است. جامعه آماری پژوهش را 150 نفر از کارشناسان ستادی شرکت برق منطقه‌ای خراسان تشکیل می‌دهند. برای جمع‌آوری داده‌ها از ابزار پرسشنامه استفاده شده و روایی آن به صورت محتوایی و تحلیل عاملی مورد تایید قرار گرفته است. برای پردازش داده‌ها از نرم‌افزارهای آماری SPSS و AMOS استفاده شد. یافته‌های حاصل از آزمون مدل نشان داد که فقط سه بعد جو سازمان شامل خودمختاری، انسجام و اعتماد اثر مثبتی بر نوآوری درک‌شده سازمانی دارند و میان جو سازمانی و نوآوری درک‌شده رابطه بسیار قوی وجود دارد. همچنین فرض نقش تعدیلگری جنسیت کارکنان در رابطه میان جو سازمانی و نوآوری درک‌شده سازمانی مورد تایید واقع نشد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>جو سازمانی</kwd>
						<kwd>خودمختاری</kwd>
						<kwd>انسجام</kwd>
						<kwd>نوآوری درک شده سازمانی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Amabile, T.M., 1997 .Motivating creativity in organizations: On doing what you love and loving what you do. California Management Review, Vol.40, pp.39-58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Armbruster, H., Bikfalvi, A., Kinkel, S. &amp; Lay, G., 2008 .Organizational innovation: the challenge of measuring non-technical innovation in large-scale surveys. Technovation, Vol.28, pp. 644-57.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Armstrong, G. &amp; Griffin, M., 2004 .Does the job matter? Comparing correlates of stress among treatment and correctional staff in prisons. Journal of Criminal Justice, Vol.32, pp. 577-592.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Asif, F., 2011 .Estimating the impact of Denison’s, ‘what is the difference between organizational culture and organizational climate? A native’s point of view on a decade of paradigm wars’. Journal of Business Research, 64(5), pp. 454-459.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Brown, S.L. &amp; Eisenhardt, S., 1995 .Product development: past research, present findings, and future directions. Academy of Management Review, Vol.20, pp. 343-373.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, C.J. &amp; Hung, J.W., 2007 .How organizational climate and structure affect knowledge management. International Journal of Information Management, 27(2), pp. 104-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Cohen, J., Cohen, P., West, S.G. &amp; Aiken, L.S., 2003 .Applied Multiple Regression/Correlation Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Mahwah, NJ, Third Edition, pp.120-125.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>DeStefano, T., Clark, H., Gavin, M., &amp; Potter, T., 2006 .The relationship between work environment factors and job satisfaction among rural behavioral health professionals. Journal of Rural Community Psychology, Available from http://www.marshall.edu/jrcp/.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K.M. &amp; Tabrizi, B.N., 1995 .Accelerating adaptive processes: product innovation in the global computer industry. Administrative Science Quarterly, 40, pp. 84-110.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Hurt, H. &amp; Teigen, C., 1997 .The development of a measure of perceived organizational innovativeness. In B. Ruben (Ed), Comminucation Yearbook 1, New Brunwick, NJ: Transaction Books, pp. 377-385.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Huseyin, G., 2008 .Organizational climate and academic staff’s perception on climate factors. Humanity &amp; Social Sciences Journal, 3(1), pp. 37-48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Koys, D.J. &amp; DeCotiis, T.A., 1991 .Inductive Measures of Psychological Climate. Human Relations, 44(3), pp.265-285.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Lambert, E.G. &amp; Hogan, N.L., 2010 .Wanting Change: The Relationship of Perceptions of Organizational Innovation with Correctional Staff Job Stress, Job Satisfaction, and Organizational Commitment. Criminal Justice Policy, 21(2), pp.160-184.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Laurence, F. &amp; Ackermann, C., 2013 .Consumer innovativeness, perceived innovation and attitude towards “neo-retro”-product design. European Journal of Innovation Management, 16(4), pp. 495-516.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Montes, L., Javier, F., Moreno, R., Fernández, A., Fernández, M. &amp; Miguel, L., 2004 .Assessing the organizational climate and contractual relationship for perceptions of support for innovation. International Journal of Manpower, 25(2), pp.167 – 180.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Pfeifer, C. &amp; Wagner, J., 2012 .Is Innovative Firm Behavior Correlated with Age and Gender Composition of the Workforce? Evidence from a New Type of Data for German Enterprises. IZA Discussion Paper No. 7050.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Reader, S.M. &amp; Kevin, N.L., 2001 .Primate Innovation: Sex, Age and Social Rank Differences. International Journal of Primatology, 22(5), pp. 787-906.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Shahin, A., Shabani Naftchali, J. &amp; Khazaei Pool, J., 2014 .Developing a model for the influence of perceived organizational climate on organizational citizenship behaviour and organizational performance based on balanced score card. International Journal of Productivity and Performance Management, 63(3), pp. 290-307.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Schneider, B. &amp; Reichers, A.E., 1983 .On the Etiology of Climates. Personnel Psychology, 36(1), pp. 19–39.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Schneider, B. &amp; Hall, D.T., 1972 .Toward specifying the concept of work climate: A study of Roman Catholic diocesan priests. Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol.56, pp. 447-455.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Valencia, N., Sanz, R. &amp; Jimennez, J., 2010 .Organization culture as determinant of product innovation. European Journal of Innovation Management, 13(4), pp. 466-480.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, C.L. &amp; Ahmad, P.K., 2004 .The development and validation of the organizational innovativeness construct using confirmatory factor analysis. European journal of innovation management, 7(4), 303-13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Weerawardena, J., 2003 .The role of marketing capability in innovation-based competitive strategy. Journal of Strategic Marketing, 11(1), pp. 15-35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>West, M., 2002 .Sparkling foundations or stagnant ponds: An integrative model of creativity and innovation implementation in work groups. Applied Psychology, Vol.51, pp. 355-386.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Yeh-Yun Lin, C. &amp; Liu, F., 2012 .A cross-level analysis of organizational creativity climate and perceived innovation the mediating effect of work motivation. European Journal of Innovation Management, 15(1), pp. 55-76.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>آزاد،ن. وارشادی،ا.، 1388. بررسی تاثیرفرهنگ سازمانی بر درک حمایت از نوآوری(موردکاوی شرکت مادرتخصصی بازرگانی دولتی ایران)،بررسی‌های بازرگانی، 36،صص. 26-38.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>زارع،ح.،فیضی،آ.،ومحبوبی،ط.، 1389 .بررسی رابطه جو سازمانی با استرس شغلی وخلاقیت کارکنان (مرد و زن) اداری آموزش و پرورش استان آذربایجان غربی. تحقیقات علوم رفتاری، (2)8،صص  114-124.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>سلاجقه،س.،نیک‌پور،ا. ونوبریآیدیش،س.، 1390 .بررسی رابطه بین هوش هیجانی و نوآوری سازمانی در بین مدیران بخش خصوصی و سازمانهای دولتی شهر تهران. فرا سوی مدیریت، (18)5،صص.147 -166.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>شاکری،ف.،طحاری مهرجردی،م.،دهقان دهنوی،ح. وکاوندی،ر.، 1390 .بررسی ارتباط جوسازمانی و نوآور بودن در فرآیند. مجله علمی - پژوهشی مدیریت تولیدوعملیات، (1)2.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>فاتحیان،س.، 1391 .عوامل موثر بر نهادینه کردن نوآوری. کنفرانس ملی کارآفرینی و مدیریت کسب‌وکارهای دانشبنیان.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>کاظمی،ر.،جعفری‌مقدم،س. وسهیلی،س.، 1391 .شناسایی میزان تأثیر جوسازمانی برنوآوری (مطالعه موردی: بانک ملت). توسعه کارآفرینی، (2)5،صص. 67-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>موسوی،س.،شریف،م.،ورجایی پور،س.، 1392 .بررسی ارتباط بین ابعاد جوسازمانی و میزان پذیرش نوآوری برنامه درسی. پژوهش در برنامه ریزی درسی، (12)10،صص. 11-23._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Amabile, T.M., 1997 .Motivating creativity in organizations: On doing what you love and loving what you do. California Management Review, Vol.40, pp.39-58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Armbruster, H., Bikfalvi, A., Kinkel, S. &amp; Lay, G., 2008 .Organizational innovation: the challenge of measuring non-technical innovation in large-scale surveys. Technovation, Vol.28, pp. 644-57.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Armstrong, G. &amp; Griffin, M., 2004 .Does the job matter? Comparing correlates of stress among treatment and correctional staff in prisons. Journal of Criminal Justice, Vol.32, pp. 577-592.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Asif, F., 2011 .Estimating the impact of Denison’s, ‘what is the difference between organizational culture and organizational climate? A native’s point of view on a decade of paradigm wars’. Journal of Business Research, 64(5), pp. 454-459.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Azad, N. &amp; Arshadi, A., 2009. Investigating the Impact of Organizational Bidding on Innovation Support (Case Study of Iranian State Enterprise.Baressy Bazargani, Volume (36), pp. 26-38.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Brown, S.L. &amp; Eisenhardt, S., 1995 .Product development: past research, present findings, and future directions. Academy of Management Review, Vol.20, pp. 343-373.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, C.J. &amp; Hung, J.W., 2007 .How organizational climate and structure affect knowledge management. International Journal of Information Management, 27(2), pp. 104-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Cohen, J., Cohen, P., West, S.G. &amp; Aiken, L.S., 2003 .Applied Multiple Regression/Correlation Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Mahwah, NJ, Third Edition, pp.120-125.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>DeStefano, T., Clark, H., Gavin, M., &amp; Potter, T., 2006 .The relationship between work environment factors and job satisfaction among rural behavioral health professionals. Journal of Rural Community Psychology, Available from http://www.marshall.edu/jrcp/.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K.M. &amp; Tabrizi, B.N., 1995 .Accelerating adaptive processes: product innovation in the global computer industry. Administrative Science Quarterly, 40, pp. 84-110.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Fatehian, S., 2012. Effective factors in proposing innovation. National conference on entrepreneurship and management of knowledge based .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Hurt, H. &amp; Teigen, C., 1997 .The development of a measure of perceived organizational innovativeness. In B. Ruben (Ed), Comminucation Yearbook 1, New Brunwick, NJ: Transaction Books, pp. 377-385.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Huseyin, G., 2008 .Organizational climate and academic staff’s perception on climate factors. Humanity &amp; Social Sciences Journal, 3(1), pp. 37-48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Kazemi, R., Jafarimoghadam, S. &amp; Soheili, S., 2012. Identifying the Inclination Rate of Innovation (Case Study: Mellat Bank). Journal of Entrepreneurship Development, 2(5), pp. 67-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Koys, D.J. &amp; DeCotiis, T.A., 1991 .Inductive Measures of Psychological Climate. Human Relations, 44(3), pp.265-285.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Lambert, E.G. &amp; Hogan, N.L., 2010 .Wanting Change: The Relationship of Perceptions of Organizational Innovation with Correctional Staff Job Stress, Job Satisfaction, and Organizational Commitment. Criminal Justice Policy, 21(2), pp.160-184.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Laurence, F. &amp; Ackermann, C., 2013 .Consumer innovativeness, perceived innovation and attitude towards “neo-retro”-product design. European Journal of Innovation Management, 16(4), pp. 495-516.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Mousavi, S., Sharif, M. &amp; Rajaei Poor, S., 2013. Relationship between organizational dimensions climate and acceptance of rate of curriculum innovation (Case study of Isfahan University). Research in Curriculum Planning, 10(12), pp.11-23.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Montes, L., Javier, F., Moreno, R., Fernández, A., Fernández, M. &amp; Miguel, L., 2004 .Assessing the organizational climate and contractual relationship for perceptions of support for innovation. International Journal of Manpower, 25(2), pp.167 – 180.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Pfeifer, C. &amp; Wagner, J., 2012 .Is Innovative Firm Behavior Correlated with Age and Gender Composition of the Workforce? Evidence from a New Type of Data for German Enterprises. IZA Discussion Paper No. 7050.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Reader, S.M. &amp; Kevin, N.L., 2001 .Primate Innovation: Sex, Age and Social Rank Differences. International Journal of Primatology, 22(5), pp. 787-906.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Shahin, A., Shabani Naftchali, J. &amp; Khazaei Pool, J., 2014 .Developing a model for the influence of perceived organizational climate on organizational citizenship behaviour and organizational performance based on balanced score card. International Journal of Productivity and Performance Management, 63(3), pp. 290-307.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Salajagheh, S. &amp; Nikpoor, A. &amp; Nobari Adisheh, S., 2011. The Relationship between Emotional Intelligence and Organizational Innovation among Managers of the Private Sector and Public Organizations in Tehran. Quaterly  Productivity Managment (BEYOND MANAGEMENT), 5(18), pp. 147-166.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Schneider, B. &amp; Reichers, A.E., 1983 .On the Etiology of Climates. Personnel Psychology, 36(1), pp. 19–39.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Schneider, B. &amp; Hall, D.T., 1972 .Toward specifying the concept of work climate: A study of Roman Catholic diocesan priests. Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol.56, pp. 447-455.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Shakeri, F., Tahari Mehrgerdi, M., Dehghan Dehnavi, H. &amp; Kavadi, R., 2011. Innovativeness In Process; Study Relationship Between Organizational Climate &amp; Innovativeness In Process By SEM. journal of Production and Operations Management,  2(1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Valencia, N., Sanz, R. &amp; Jimennez, J., 2010 .Organization culture as determinant of product innovation. European Journal of Innovation Management, 13(4), pp. 466-480.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, C.L. &amp; Ahmad, P.K., 2004 .The development and validation of the organizational innovativeness construct using confirmatory factor analysis. European journal of innovation management, 7(4), 303-13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Weerawardena, J., 2003 .The role of marketing capability in innovation-based competitive strategy. Journal of Strategic Marketing, 11(1), pp. 15-35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>West, M., 2002 .Sparkling foundations or stagnant ponds: An integrative model of creativity and innovation implementation in work groups. Applied Psychology, Vol.51, pp. 355-386.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Yeh-Yun Lin, C. &amp; Liu, F., 2012 .A cross-level analysis of organizational creativity climate and perceived innovation the mediating effect of work motivation. European Journal of Innovation Management, 15(1), pp. 55-76.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Zare, H. &amp; Feizi, A. &amp; Mahboobi, T., 2010. Investigating the Relationship of Organizational Climate with Job Stress and Creativity of Employees (Man and Woman) Administrative Education of West Azarbaijan Province. Journal of Research in Behavioural Sciences, 8(2), pp. 114-124.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14724_78115de430cb6624b1bc833db38564f2.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی تاثیر شبکه دانش بر عملکرد نوآوری محصول با استفاده از مدل معادلات ساختاری (مطالعه موردی:شرکتهای تجارت الکترونیک استان اصفهان)</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نصری نصرآبادی</surname>
			            <given-names>شهره</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فلاح</surname>
			            <given-names>الهام</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>شیرانی لپری</surname>
			            <given-names>سمانه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه علوم تحقیقات</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>20</day>
			        <month>02</month>
			        <year>2024</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>3</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>53</fpage>
			      <lpage>75</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>01</day>
			          <month>01</month>
			          <year>1970</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>18</day>
			          <month>08</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2024, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2024</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14724.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14724.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>کسب دانش جدید، علاوه بر ایجاد مزیت رقابتی برای سازمان‌ها موجب ارتقاء عملکرد سازمانی نیز می‌شود. شبکه‌های دانشی، یکی از منابع اصلی کسب دانش در هر سازمان محسوب می‌شوند. پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی رابطه مدیریت شبکه‌ دانش و عملکرد نوآوری محصول انجام شد. برای این منظور، ابتدا یک چارچوب مفهومی از عملکرد نوآوری محصول با توجه به مولفه‌های مدیریت دانش و راهبردهای توسعه محصول ارائه گردید و در ادامه، تاثیر تمرکز راهبردی بر توسعه محصولات جدید و عملکرد نوآوری محصول از نقطه نظر دانش فنی، دانش رقابتی و  دانش مشتری مورد بررسی تجربی قرار گرفت. جامعه آماری این پژوهش را کارشناسان فناوری اطلاعات شرکت‌های تجارت الکترونیک استان اصفهان و خبرگان دانشگاهی در حوزه مدیریت دانش و نوآوری (جهت بررسی روایی محتوا) تشکیل می‌دهند. برای آزمون مدل مفهومی، روش معادلات ساختاری و نرم افزار AMOS و برای تایید شاخص‌ها و روایی سازه، تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. نتایج نشان داد که عملکرد نوآوری محصول از مدیریت شبکه‌های دانشی ایجاد می‌شود. همچنین مشخص گردید که برخی از  راهبردهای توسعه محصول بر عملکرد نوآوری محصول و شبکه‌های دانشی تاثیر معناداری دارند. از بین راهبردهای توسعه محصول، راهبرد افزایشی هیچ‌گونه تاثیر معناداری بر عملکرد نوآوری محصول ندارد. همچنین شبکه‌های دانشی بر عملکرد نوآوری محصول تاثیر مثبت و معناداری دارد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>مدیریت دانش</kwd>
						<kwd>شبکه دانش</kwd>
						<kwd>مدیریت نوآوری</kwd>
						<kwd>توسعه محصول جدید</kwd>
						<kwd>مدل معادلات ساختاری</kwd>
						<kwd>شرکتهای تجارت الکترونیکی استان اصفهان</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Argote, L. (2012). Organizational learning: Creating, retaining and transferring knowledge: Springer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Atuahene-Gima, K., &amp; Ko, A. (2001). An Empirical Investigation of the Effect of Market Orientation and Entrepreneurship Orientation Alignment on Product Innovation. Organization Science, 12(1), pp. 54-74. doi: 10.1287/orsc.12.1.54.10121</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Atuahene-Gima, K., &amp; Murray, J. Y. (2007). Exploratory and Exploitative Learning in New Product Development: A Social Capital Perspective on New Technology Ventures in China. Journal of International Marketing, 15(2), pp. 1-29. doi: 10.1509/jimk.15.2.1</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Bradley, M. (2000). Working Knowledge: How Organizations Manage What They Know. New Library World, 101(6), pp. 282-287.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Brockman, B. K., &amp; Morgan, R. M. (2003). The role of existing knowledge in new product innovativeness and performance. Decision Sciences, 34(2), pp. 385-419.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Brown, S. L., &amp; Eisenhardt, K. M. (1995). Product development: past research, present findings, and future directions. Academy of management review, 20(2), pp. 343-378.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, H. H., Kang, H.-Y., Xing, X., Lee, A. H. I., &amp; Tong, Y. (2008). Developing new products with knowledge management methods and process development management in a network. Computers in Industry, 59(2–3), pp. 242-253. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compind.2007.06.020</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Cheng, C.-F., Chang, M.-L., &amp; Li, C.-S. (2013). Configural paths to successful product innovation. Journal of Business Research, 66(12), pp. 2561-2573. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jbusres.2012.10.006</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Chwastyk, P., &amp; Kołosowski, M. (2014). Estimating the Cost of the New Product in Development Process. Procedia Engineering, 69(0), pp. 351-360. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.proeng.2014.02.243</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Clark, K. B. (1991). Product development performance: Strategy, organization, and management in the world auto industry. Harvard Business Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, R. G. (1979). The dimensions of industrial new product success and failure. Journal of Marketing Research, 43(3), p. 93.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, R. G. (1979). Identifying industrial new product success: Project NewProd. Industrial Marketing Management, 8(2), pp. 124-135.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, R. G., &amp; Kleinschmidt, E. J. (1987). New products: what separates winners from losers? Journal of Product Innovation Management, 4(3), pp. 169-184.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, R. G., &amp; Kleinschmidt, E. J. (1995). Benchmarking the firm’s critical success factors in new product development. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 12(5), pp. 374-391. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0737-6782(95)00059-3</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Danneels, E. (2002). The dynamics of product innovation and firm competences. Strategic management journal, 23(12), pp. 1095-1121.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Davenport, T. H., Harris, J. G., &amp; Kohli, A. K. (2001). How do they know their customers so well? Sloan Management Review, 42(2), pp. 63-74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>de Medeiros, J. F., Ribeiro, J. L. D., &amp; Cortimiglia, M. N. (2014). Success factors for environmentally sustainable product innovation: a systematic literature review. Journal of Cleaner Production, 65(0), pp. 76-86. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2013.08.035</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Dougherty, D., &amp; Hardy, C. (1996). Sustained product innovation in large, mature organizations: Overcoming innovation-to-organization problems. Academy of Management Journal, 39(5), pp. 1120-1153.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Ernst, H. (2002). Success Factors of New Product Development: A Review of the Empirical Literature. International Journal of Management Reviews, 4(1), pp. 1-40. doi: 10.1111/1468-2370.00075</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Gloet, M., &amp; Terziovski, M. (2004). Exploring the relationship between knowledge management practices and innovation performance. Journal of Manufacturing Technology Management, 15(5), pp. 402-409.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Gmelin, H., &amp; Seuring, S. (2014). Determinants of a sustainable new product development. Journal of Cleaner Production, 69(0), pp. 1-9. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2014.01.053</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Goedhuys, M., &amp; Veugelers, R. (2012). Innovation strategies, process and product innovations and growth: Firm-level evidence from Brazil. Structural Change and Economic Dynamics, 23(4), pp. 516-529. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.strueco.2011.01.004</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Gold, A. H., Malhotra, A., &amp; Segars, A. H. (2001). Knowledge Management: An Organizational Capabilities Perspective. J. Manage. Inf. Syst., 18(1), pp. 185-214.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Golder, P. N. (2000). Insights from senior executives about innovation in international markets. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 17(5), pp. 326-340. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0737-6782(00)00053-9</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Grant, R. M. (1996). Toward a knowledge-based theory of the firm. Strategic management journal, 17, pp. 109-122.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Gruner, K. E., &amp; Homburg, C. (2000). Does customer interaction enhance new product success? Journal of Business Research, 49(1), pp. 1-14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Henard, D. H., &amp; Szymanski, D. M. (2001). Why Some New Products Are More Successful Than Others. Journal of Marketing Research, 38(3), pp. 362-375. doi: 10.1509/jmkr.38.3.362.18861</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Im, S., Nakata, C., Park, H., &amp; Ha, Y.-W. (2003). Determinants of Korean and Japanese New Product Performance: An Interrelational and Process View. Journal of International Marketing, 11(4), pp. 81-112. doi: 10.1509/jimk.11.4.81.20149</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Johannessen, J.-A., &amp; Olsen, B. (2003). Knowledge management and sustainable competitive advantages: The impact of dynamic contextual training. International Journal of Information Management, 23(4), pp. 277-289.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Kok, R. A. W., &amp; Biemans, W. G. (2009). Creating a market-oriented product innovation process: A contingency approach. Technovation, 29(8), pp. 517-526. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.technovation.2008.12.004</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Kowang, T. O., Long, C. S., &amp; Rasli, A. (2014). New Product Development Framework for Multinational Multi-locations based Organizations in South East Asia. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 129(0), pp. 68-74. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sbspro.2014.03.649</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Kraiczy, N. D., Hack, A., &amp; Kellermanns, F. W. (2014). New product portfolio performance in family firms. Journal of Business Research, 67(6), pp. 1065-1073. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jbusres.2013.06.005</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Krishnan, V., &amp; Ulrich, K. T. (2001). Product Development Decisions: A Review of the Literature. Management Science, 47(1), pp. 1-21. doi: doi:10.1287/mnsc.47.1.1.10668</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Li, T., &amp; Calantone, R. J. (1998). The impact of market knowledge competence on new product advantage: conceptualization and empirical examination. The Journal of marketing, pp. 13-29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>López-Nicolás, C., &amp; Meroño-Cerdán, Á. L. (2011). Strategic knowledge management, innovation and performance. International Journal of Information Management, 31(6), pp. 502-509. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2011.02.003</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Madhavan, R., &amp; Grover, R. (2009). From embedded knowledge to embodied knowledge: new product development as knowledge management. The Journal of marketing, pp. 1-12.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>McEvily, S. K., &amp; Chakravarthy, B. (2002). The persistence of knowledge-based advantage: an empirical test for product performance and technological knowledge. Strategic Management Journal, 23(4), pp. 285-305. doi: 10.1002/smj.223</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Okatan, K. (2012). Managing Knowledge for Innovation and Intra Networking: A Case Study. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 62(0), pp. 59-63. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sbspro.2012.09.012</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Ottum, B. D., &amp; Moore, W. L. (1997). The role of market information in new product success/failure. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 14(4), pp. 258-273. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0737-6782(97)00013-1</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Parry, M. E., &amp; Song, X. M. (1994). Identifying new product successes in China. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 11(1), pp. 15-30. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0737-6782(94)90116-3</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Perry, N., Candlot, A., &amp; Corne, S. (2010). Collaborative Knowledge Networks Emergence for Innovation: Factors of Success Analysis and Comparison. Journal of Decision Systems, 19(1), pp. 75-91.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>R. Drazin, A. H. V. d. V. (1985). Alternative forms of fit in contingency theory. Administrative Science Quarterly, 30(4), pp. 514-540.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Rahimli, A. (2012). Knowledge Management and Competitive Advantage. Information &amp; Knowledge Management (2224-896X), 2(7).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Rindfleisch, A., &amp; Moorman, C. (2001). The acquisition and utilization of information in new product alliances:A strength-of-ties perspective. Journal o f Marketing, 65, pp. 1-18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Ritter, T., &amp; Gemünden, H. G. (2003). Network competence: its impact on innovation success and its antecedents. Journal of Business Research, 56(9), pp. 745-755.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Rodríguez-Elias, O. M., Morán, A. L., Lavandera, J. I., &amp; Vizcaíno, A. (2014). Improving Knowledge Flow Management in a Mexican Manufacturing Firm.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Rowley, J. E. (2002). Reflections on customer knowledge management in e-business. Qualitative Market Research: An International Journal, 5(4), pp. 268-280.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Schulz, M. (2001). The uncertain relevance of newness: Organizational learning and knowledge flows. Academy of Management Journal, 44(4), pp. 661-681.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Tohidi, H., &amp; Jabbari, M. M. (2012). Product Innovation Performance in Organization. Procedia Technology, 1(0), pp. 521-523. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.protcy.2012.02.112</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Tomas, G., &amp; Hult, M. (2003). An integration of thoughts on knowledge management. Decision Sciences, 34(2), 189-195.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Tsai, W. (2001). Knowledge transfer in intraorganizational networks: Effects of network position and absorptive capacity on business unit innovation and performance. Academy of Management Journal, 44(5), pp. 996-1004.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, Z., &amp; Wang, N. (2012). Knowledge sharing, innovation and firm performance. Expert Systems with Applications, 39(10), pp. 8899-8908. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2012.02.017</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Yeşil, S., Koska, A., &amp; Büyükbeşe, T. (2013). Knowledge Sharing Process, Innovation Capability and Innovation Performance: An Empirical Study. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 75(0), pp. 217-225. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sbspro.2013.04.025</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Zhen, L., Wang, L., &amp; Li, J.-G. (2013). A design of knowledge management tool for supporting product development. Information Processing &amp; Management, 49(4), pp. 884-894. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ipm.2013.01.008</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Zhuge, H. (2002a). Knowledge flow management for distributed team software development. Knowledge-Based Systems, 15(8), pp. 465-471..</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Zhuge, H. (2002b). A knowledge flow model for peer-to-peer team knowledge sharing and management. Expert Systems with Applications, 23(1), pp. 23-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>بدری آذین، ی. ، سید عامری، م.، ایمان پور، ع. (1390). تحلیل رگرسیونی رابطة بین اجزای مدیریت دانش و عملکرد منابع انسانی. مدیریت ورزشی، 15، صص.35-50.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>صباغچى، س. ، قاضى نورى، س. ، الهى، ش. (1390). انتخاب ابزارهاى مدیریت دانش در توسعة محصول جدید نرم افزارى. بهبود مدیریت، (5) 2، صص.80-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>صفرزاده ح.، تدین ا.، حر محمدی م.(1390). بررسی تأثیر استراتژی‌های مدیریت دانش بر نوآوری و عملکرد سازمانی. فصلنامه علمی‌پژوهشی دانشکده یزد (11)1، صص.76-87.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>طالقانی، غ.، انواری، ع. ، افتخاری، ل. (1391). رابطه بین مدیریت دانش و نوآوری سازمانی در یک شرکت بیمه. پژوهشنامه بیمه، (27)1، صص. 151-171.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>میرفخرالدینی، س.، حاتمی‌نسب، س.، طالعی فر، ر.، کنجکاو منفرد، ا. (1389). مدیریت دانش، نوآوری دانش و عملکرد نوآوری در شرکتهای کوچک و متوسط. چشم‌انداز مدیریت بازرگانی (35)2، صص. 103-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>یوسفی ا.، فیضی ج.، سلیمانی م.(1391).بررسی میزان تأثیر مدیریت دانش بر نوآوری. ابتکار و خلاقیت در علوم انسانی، (1)3، صص.30-53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation> جهانشیر، ح. و همت پور، ر. (1387). دانایی و ضرورت بکارگیری مدیریت دانش شبکه ای در سازمان ارزش آفرین. هفتمین همایش مراکز تحقیق و توسعه صنایع و معادن.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>صدقیانی، ج. تولایی، ر.، بامداد صوفی ، رضائیان، ع. و صالحی، ج. (1393). ارائه الگوی توسعه شبکه‌های دانش در‌هاب‌های پژوهش و فناوری صنعت نفت با استفاده از الگوهای جهانی. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مطالعات راهبردی جهانی شدن  .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation> نژاد طالب، ا . (1389). شبکة دانش وراهبردهای مدیریت دانش فردی و مدیریت دانش سازمانی. اولین همایش ملی مدیریت. _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Argote, L. (2012). Organizational learning: Creating, retaining and transferring knowledge: Springer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Atuahene-Gima, K., &amp; Ko, A. (2001). An Empirical Investigation of the Effect of Market Orientation and Entrepreneurship Orientation Alignment on Product Innovation. Organization Science, 12(1), pp. 54-74. doi: 10.1287/orsc.12.1.54.10121</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Atuahene-Gima, K., &amp; Murray, J. Y. (2007). Exploratory and Exploitative Learning in New Product Development: A Social Capital Perspective on New Technology Ventures in China. Journal of International Marketing, 15(2), pp. 1-29. doi: 10.1509/jimk.15.2.1</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Badri Azin, Y., Seed Ameri, M., Imanpoor, As., 2011. Regression Analysis of the Relationship between Knowledge Management Components and Human Resource Performance. Journal of Sport Management, Volume (5), pp. 35-50.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Bradley, M. (2000). Working Knowledge: How Organizations Manage What They Know. New Library World, 101(6), pp. 282-287.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Brockman, B. K., &amp; Morgan, R. M. (2003). The role of existing knowledge in new product innovativeness and performance. Decision Sciences, 34(2), pp. 385-419.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Brown, S. L., &amp; Eisenhardt, K. M. (1995). Product development: past research, present findings, and future directions. Academy of management review, 20(2), pp. 343-378.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, H. H., Kang, H.-Y., Xing, X., Lee, A. H. I., &amp; Tong, Y. (2008). Developing new products with knowledge management methods and process development management in a network. Computers in Industry, 59(2–3), pp. 242-253. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compind.2007.06.020</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Cheng, C.-F., Chang, M.-L., &amp; Li, C.-S. (2013). Configural paths to successful product innovation. Journal of Business Research, 66(12), pp. 2561-2573. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jbusres.2012.10.006</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Chwastyk, P., &amp; Kołosowski, M. (2014). Estimating the Cost of the New Product in Development Process. Procedia Engineering, 69(0), pp. 351-360. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.proeng.2014.02.243</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Clark, K. B. (1991). Product development performance: Strategy, organization, and management in the world auto industry. Harvard Business Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, R. G. (1979). The dimensions of industrial new product success and failure. Journal of Marketing Research, 43(3), p. 93.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, R. G. (1979). Identifying industrial new product success: Project NewProd. Industrial Marketing Management, 8(2), pp. 124-135.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, R. G., &amp; Kleinschmidt, E. J. (1987). New products: what separates winners from losers? Journal of Product Innovation Management, 4(3), pp. 169-184.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, R. G., &amp; Kleinschmidt, E. J. (1995). Benchmarking the firm’s critical success factors in new product development. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 12(5), pp. 374-391. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0737-6782(95)00059-3</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Danneels, E. (2002). The dynamics of product innovation and firm competences. Strategic management journal, 23(12), pp. 1095-1121.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Davenport, T. H., Harris, J. G., &amp; Kohli, A. K. (2001). How do they know their customers so well? Sloan Management Review, 42(2), pp. 63-74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>de Medeiros, J. F., Ribeiro, J. L. D., &amp; Cortimiglia, M. N. (2014). Success factors for environmentally sustainable product innovation: a systematic literature review. Journal of Cleaner Production, 65(0), pp. 76-86. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2013.08.035</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Dougherty, D., &amp; Hardy, C. (1996). Sustained product innovation in large, mature organizations: Overcoming innovation-to-organization problems. Academy of Management Journal, 39(5), pp. 1120-1153.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Ernst, H. (2002). Success Factors of New Product Development: A Review of the Empirical Literature. International Journal of Management Reviews, 4(1), pp. 1-40. doi: 10.1111/1468-2370.00075</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Gloet, M., &amp; Terziovski, M. (2004). Exploring the relationship between knowledge management practices and innovation performance. Journal of Manufacturing Technology Management, 15(5), pp. 402-409.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Gmelin, H., &amp; Seuring, S. (2014). Determinants of a sustainable new product development. Journal of Cleaner Production, 69(0), pp. 1-9. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2014.01.053</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Goedhuys, M., &amp; Veugelers, R. (2012). Innovation strategies, process and product innovations and growth: Firm-level evidence from Brazil. Structural Change and Economic Dynamics, 23(4), pp. 516-529. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.strueco.2011.01.004</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Gold, A. H., Malhotra, A., &amp; Segars, A. H. (2001). Knowledge Management: An Organizational Capabilities Perspective. J. Manage. Inf. Syst., 18(1), pp. 185-214.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Golder, P. N. (2000). Insights from senior executives about innovation in international markets. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 17(5), pp. 326-340. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0737-6782(00)00053-9</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Grant, R. M. (1996). Toward a knowledge-based theory of the firm. Strategic management journal, 17, pp. 109-122.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Gruner, K. E., &amp; Homburg, C. (2000). Does customer interaction enhance new product success? Journal of Business Research, 49(1), pp. 1-14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Henard, D. H., &amp; Szymanski, D. M. (2001). Why Some New Products Are More Successful Than Others. Journal of Marketing Research, 38(3), pp. 362-375. doi: 10.1509/jmkr.38.3.362.18861</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Im, S., Nakata, C., Park, H., &amp; Ha, Y.-W. (2003). Determinants of Korean and Japanese New Product Performance: An Interrelational and Process View. Journal of International Marketing, 11(4), pp. 81-112. doi: 10.1509/jimk.11.4.81.20149</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Jahanshir, H. &amp; Hematpoor, R., 2008. Knowledge and the necessity of using network knowledge management in a value-creating organization. Seventh Conference of Industries and Mines Research and Development Centers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Johannessen, J.-A., &amp; Olsen, B. (2003). Knowledge management and sustainable competitive advantages: The impact of dynamic contextual training. International Journal of Information Management, 23(4), pp. 277-289.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Kok, R. A. W., &amp; Biemans, W. G. (2009). Creating a market-oriented product innovation process: A contingency approach. Technovation, 29(8), pp. 517-526. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.technovation.2008.12.004</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Kowang, T. O., Long, C. S., &amp; Rasli, A. (2014). New Product Development Framework for Multinational Multi-locations based Organizations in South East Asia. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 129(0), pp. 68-74. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sbspro.2014.03.649</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Kraiczy, N. D., Hack, A., &amp; Kellermanns, F. W. (2014). New product portfolio performance in family firms. Journal of Business Research, 67(6), pp. 1065-1073. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jbusres.2013.06.005</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Krishnan, V., &amp; Ulrich, K. T. (2001). Product Development Decisions: A Review of the Literature. Management Science, 47(1), pp. 1-21. doi: doi:10.1287/mnsc.47.1.1.10668</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Li, T., &amp; Calantone, R. J. (1998). The impact of market knowledge competence on new product advantage: conceptualization and empirical examination. The Journal of marketing, pp. 13-29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>López-Nicolás, C., &amp; Meroño-Cerdán, Á. L. (2011). Strategic knowledge management, innovation and performance. International Journal of Information Management, 31(6), pp. 502-509. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2011.02.003</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Madhavan, R., &amp; Grover, R. (2009). From embedded knowledge to embodied knowledge: new product development as knowledge management. The Journal of marketing, pp. 1-12.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>McEvily, S. K., &amp; Chakravarthy, B. (2002). The persistence of knowledge-based advantage: an empirical test for product performance and technological knowledge. Strategic Management Journal, 23(4), pp. 285-305. doi: 10.1002/smj.223</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Mirfakhrodini, S., Hataminasab, S., Taleifar, R., Konjkav Monfared, A., 2010. Knowledge management, knowledge innovation and innovation performance in small and medium enterprises. Journal of Business Management, 2(35), pp.103-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Nejad Taleb, A.,  2010. Knowledge network and individual knowledge management and organizational knowledge management. First National Management Conference.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Okatan, K. (2012). Managing Knowledge for Innovation and Intra Networking: A Case Study. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 62(0), pp. 59-63. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sbspro.2012.09.012</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Ottum, B. D., &amp; Moore, W. L. (1997). The role of market information in new product success/failure. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 14(4), pp. 258-273. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0737-6782(97)00013-1</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Parry, M. E., &amp; Song, X. M. (1994). Identifying new product successes in China. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 11(1), pp. 15-30. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0737-6782(94)90116-3</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Perry, N., Candlot, A., &amp; Corne, S. (2010). Collaborative Knowledge Networks Emergence for Innovation: Factors of Success Analysis and Comparison. Journal of Decision Systems, 19(1), pp. 75-91.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>R. Drazin, A. H. V. d. V. (1985). Alternative forms of fit in contingency theory. Administrative Science Quarterly, 30(4), pp. 514-540.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>Rahimli, A. (2012). Knowledge Management and Competitive Advantage. Information &amp; Knowledge Management (2224-896X), 2(7).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Rindfleisch, A., &amp; Moorman, C. (2001). The acquisition and utilization of information in new product alliances:A strength-of-ties perspective. Journal o f Marketing, 65, pp. 1-18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>Ritter, T., &amp; Gemünden, H. G. (2003). Network competence: its impact on innovation success and its antecedents. Journal of Business Research, 56(9), pp. 745-755.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R115">
			<label>115</label>
			<element-citation>Rodríguez-Elias, O. M., Morán, A. L., Lavandera, J. I., &amp; Vizcaíno, A. (2014). Improving Knowledge Flow Management in a Mexican Manufacturing Firm.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R116">
			<label>116</label>
			<element-citation>Rowley, J. E. (2002). Reflections on customer knowledge management in e-business. Qualitative Market Research: An International Journal, 5(4), pp. 268-280.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R117">
			<label>117</label>
			<element-citation>Sabaghchi, S., Ghazinoori, S. &amp; Elahi, Sh., 2011. Choosing KM tools to develop new software products. Management Improvement Quarterly, 2(5), pp. 80-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R118">
			<label>118</label>
			<element-citation>Safarzadeh, H., Tadayon, A. &amp; Hor Mohammadi, M., 2011. The Effect of KM Strategies on Organizational Innovation and Performance. Quaterly Toloo-E-Behdasht,1(11), ppp.76-87.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R119">
			<label>119</label>
			<element-citation>Schulz, M. (2001). The uncertain relevance of newness: Organizational learning and knowledge flows. Academy of Management Journal, 44(4), pp. 661-681.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R120">
			<label>120</label>
			<element-citation>Sedghiyani, J., Tavallaei, R., Bamdad Soofi, J., Rezaeian, a., Salehi, J., 2014. Presenting a Pattern of Knowledge Network Development in Research and Technology Hubs of Oil Industry Based on Global Patterns. Annually  Strategic  Studies of  Public  Policy  (Strategic Studies of Globalization Journal).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R121">
			<label>121</label>
			<element-citation>Taleghani, Gh., Anvari, as., Eftekhari, L., 2012. :  Knowledge Management and Its Relationship with Organizational Innovation in Insurance Company Quarterly Sanaat-e-bimeh, 1(27), pp.151-171.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R122">
			<label>122</label>
			<element-citation>Tohidi, H., &amp; Jabbari, M. M. (2012). Product Innovation Performance in Organization. Procedia Technology, 1(0), pp. 521-523. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.protcy.2012.02.112</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R123">
			<label>123</label>
			<element-citation>Tomas, G., &amp; Hult, M. (2003). An integration of thoughts on knowledge management. Decision Sciences, 34(2), 189-195.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R124">
			<label>124</label>
			<element-citation>Tsai, W. (2001). Knowledge transfer in intraorganizational networks: Effects of network position and absorptive capacity on business unit innovation and performance. Academy of Management Journal, 44(5), pp. 996-1004.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R125">
			<label>125</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, Z., &amp; Wang, N. (2012). Knowledge sharing, innovation and firm performance. Expert Systems with Applications, 39(10), pp. 8899-8908. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2012.02.017</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R126">
			<label>126</label>
			<element-citation>Yeşil, S., Koska, A., &amp; Büyükbeşe, T. (2013). Knowledge Sharing Process, Innovation Capability and Innovation Performance: An Empirical Study. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 75(0), pp. 217-225. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sbspro.2013.04.025</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R127">
			<label>127</label>
			<element-citation>Yosefi, A., Feizi, J., Soleimani, M., 2012. Assessing the Impact of Knowledge Management on Innovation. Journal of Innovation and Creativity in Human Science, 3(1), pp.30-53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R128">
			<label>128</label>
			<element-citation>Zhen, L., Wang, L., &amp; Li, J.-G. (2013). A design of knowledge management tool for supporting product development. Information Processing &amp; Management, 49(4), pp. 884-894. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ipm.2013.01.008</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R129">
			<label>129</label>
			<element-citation>Zhuge, H. (2002a). Knowledge flow management for distributed team software development. Knowledge-Based Systems, 15(8), pp. 465-471..</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R130">
			<label>130</label>
			<element-citation>Zhuge, H. (2002b). A knowledge flow model for peer-to-peer team knowledge sharing and management. Expert Systems with Applications, 23(1), pp. 23-30</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14725_5891c3c0fdd5ca41fda2f15f04290403.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>شبیه سازی فرآیند اشاعه محصولات نوین با رویکرد پویایی های سیستم</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>موسوی حقیقی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد هاشم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیات علمی مرکز تحقیقات کشاورزی و منابع طبیعی استان فارس، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>تاجیک</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه شیراز</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>12</month>
			        <year>2014</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>3</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>77</fpage>
			      <lpage>99</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>25</day>
			          <month>01</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>14</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2014, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14725.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14725.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>فرآیند اشاعة نوآوری، فرآیندی پیچیده و پویاست و تحت تأثیر متغیر‌های متعددی مانند کیفیت، رقابت، قیمت، زمان ورود به بازار، تبلیغات و رضایت جامعه قرار دارد. الگوهای سنتی تبیین‌شده به منظور تحلیل و بررسی اشاعة نوآوری همچون الگوی باس، پویایی‌های موجود در این فرآیند را نادیده می‌گیرند و با فرضیه‌های ساده اقدام به تحلیل فرآیند اشاعه می‌کنند. از این رو، پژوهش حاضر با هدف ایجاد یک مدل توسعه‌یافته و پویا از فرآیند اشاعة محصولات مبتنی بر نوآوری با استفاده از روش‌ پویایی‌های سیستم انجام شد. ‌الگوی پیشنهادی این پژوهش بر اساس این رویکرد طراحی و با نرم‌افزار Vensim DSS شبیه‌سازی و اعتبار آن با استفاده از آزمون‌های آماری و سیستمی مورد سنجش قرار گرفته است. همچنین این الگو بر یک محصول نوین شرکت مواد غذایی «ب آ» پیاده‌سازی ‌گردیده و پس از اطمینان از باز تولید رفتار سیستم واقعی، سناریو‌هایی جهت بهبود روند پذیرش اجرا شده است. نتایج بیانگر آن هستند که عامل «خرید توصیه‌ای» نسبت به متغیر « خرید از طریق تبلیغات رسانه‌ای» تأثیر بیشتری بر تسریع فرآیند اشاعة نوآوری دارد. از این‌رو، عواملی همچون رضایت مشتریان اولیه که بر فرآیند خرید توصیه‌ای تأثیر گذارند، نقش مهمی در نرخ اشاعة نوآوری خواهند داشت.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>گسترش نوآوری</kwd>
						<kwd>الگوی باس</kwd>
						<kwd>رضایت مشتری</kwd>
						<kwd>پویاییهای سیستم</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Bass, F. (1969). A new product growth model for consumer durables. Management Science, 15, 215–217.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Bemmaor, A., &amp; Lee, J. (2002). The Impact of Heterogeneity and Ill-Conditioning on Diffusion Model Parameter Estimates. Marketing Science, 21(2), 209–220.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Danaher, P., Hardie, B., &amp; Putsis Jr., W. (2001). Marketing-Mix Variables and the Diffusion of Successive Generations of a Technological Innovation. Journal of Marketing Research, 38(4), 501–514.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Fischer, D., Norvell, J., Sonka, S., &amp; Nelson, M. (2000). Understanding technology adoption through system dynamics modeling: implications for agribusiness management. International Food and Agribusiness Management Review, 3, 269-281.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Fonseca, J. (2009). Customer satisfaction study via a latent segment model. Journal of retailing and consumer services, 16(5), 352-359.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Fornell, C., Johnson, M., Anderson, E., Cha, J., &amp; Bryant, B. (1996). The American customer satisfaction index: nature, purpose and findings. Journal of marketing, 60(4), 7-18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Golder, P. N., &amp; Tellis, G. (1997). Will It Ever Fly? Modeling the Takeoff of Really New Consumer Durables. Marketing Science, 16(3), 256–270.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Jain, D., Mahajan, V., &amp; Muller, E. (1991). Innovation Diffusion in the Presence of Supply Restrictions. Marketing Science, 10(1), 83–90.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Kumar, V., &amp; Krishnan, T. (2002). Multinational Diffusion Models: An Alternative Framework. Marketing Science, 21(3), 318–330.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Lane , D., &amp; Husemann, E. (2004). Movie marketing strategy formation with system dynamics: toward a multidisciplinary adoption; diffusion theory of cinema going. 22th International Conference of the System Dynamics Society. Oxford, England.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Mahjan, v., Muller, E., &amp; Bass, F. .. (1990). New Product Diffusion Models in Marketing: A Review and Directions for Research. Journal of marketing, 54(1), 1-20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Maier, F. (1995). Innovation diffusion models for decision support in strategic management. University of Manheim.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Marco, A., Cagliano, A., &amp; Rafele, C. (2012). Forecasting the Diffusion of a Mobile Service for Freight Distribution. 30th International Conference of the System Dynamics Society. Gallen, Switzerland.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Matsumoto, H. (2000). System Dynamic Model for Life Cycle Assessmental of Residential Buildings. Management science, 47, 123-132.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Norton, J., &amp; Bass, F. (1987). A Diffusion Theory Model of Adoption and Substitution for Successive Generations of High-Technology Products. Management Science, 1069–1086.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Radas, S. (2005). Diffusion Models in Marketing:How to Incorporate the Effect of External Influence?. Economic Trends and Economic Policy, 15(105).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Sterman, J. (2000). Business Dynamics: Systems Thinking and Modeling for a Complex World. Boston: Mac-Graw Hill.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Sutanto, J., Kankanhalli, A., Tay, J., Raman, K., &amp; Tan, B. (2008). Change Management in Interorganizational Systems for the Public. Journal of Management Information Systems, 25, 133–175.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Thun, j. h., Größler, A., &amp; Milling, P. (2000). The Diffusion of Goods Considering Network Externalities:A System Dynamics-Based Approach. The 18th International Confrence of The System Dynamic Society. Bergen.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Vilares, M., &amp; Coelho, S. (2003). The employee-customer satisfaction chain in the ECSI model. European journal of marketing, 37(11), 1703-1722.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Wieck, L. (1996). Learning Organization: From Idea to Action. Human Resource Management, 6.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Wilkie, W. (1994). Consumer Behavior. New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Williams, T., Eden, C., Ackermann, F., &amp; Tait, A. (1995). The effects of design changes and delays on project costs. Journal of the Operational Research Society, 46, 809–818.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Wunderlich, P., &amp; Grössler, A. (2012). Using system dynamics to analyze innovation diffusion processes within intra-organizational networks. 30th International System Dynamics Conference, (p. 111). Gallen.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Yeon , S., Park, S., &amp; Kim, S. (2006). A dynamic diffusion model for managing customer’s expectation and satisfaction. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, 73, 648–665.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Zhoa, W., &amp; Rena, H. (2011). A system dynamics model for evaluating the alternative of type in construction and demolition waste recycling center. Resources, Conservation and Recycling, 933-944.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Bass, F. (1969). A new product growth model for consumer durables. Management Science, 15, 215–217.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Bemmaor, A., &amp; Lee, J. (2002). The Impact of Heterogeneity and Ill-Conditioning on Diffusion Model Parameter Estimates. Marketing Science, 21(2), 209–220.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Danaher, P., Hardie, B., &amp; Putsis Jr., W. (2001). Marketing-Mix Variables and the Diffusion of Successive Generations of a Technological Innovation. Journal of Marketing Research, 38(4), 501–514.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Fischer, D., Norvell, J., Sonka, S., &amp; Nelson, M. (2000). Understanding technology adoption through system dynamics modeling: implications for agribusiness management. International Food and Agribusiness Management Review, 3, 269-281.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Fonseca, J. (2009). Customer satisfaction study via a latent segment model. Journal of retailing and consumer services, 16(5), 352-359.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Fornell, C., Johnson, M., Anderson, E., Cha, J., &amp; Bryant, B. (1996). The American customer satisfaction index: nature, purpose and findings. Journal of marketing, 60(4), 7-18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Golder, P. N., &amp; Tellis, G. (1997). Will It Ever Fly? Modeling the Takeoff of Really New Consumer Durables. Marketing Science, 16(3), 256–270.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Jain, D., Mahajan, V., &amp; Muller, E. (1991). Innovation Diffusion in the Presence of Supply Restrictions. Marketing Science, 10(1), 83–90.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Kumar, V., &amp; Krishnan, T. (2002). Multinational Diffusion Models: An Alternative Framework. Marketing Science, 21(3), 318–330.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Lane , D., &amp; Husemann, E. (2004). Movie marketing strategy formation with system dynamics: toward a multidisciplinary adoption; diffusion theory of cinema going. 22th International Conference of the System Dynamics Society. Oxford, England.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Mahjan, v., Muller, E., &amp; Bass, F. .. (1990). New Product Diffusion Models in Marketing: A Review and Directions for Research. Journal of marketing, 54(1), 1-20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Maier, F. (1995). Innovation diffusion models for decision support in strategic management. University of Manheim.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Marco, A., Cagliano, A., &amp; Rafele, C. (2012). Forecasting the Diffusion of a Mobile Service for Freight Distribution. 30th International Conference of the System Dynamics Society. Gallen, Switzerland.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Matsumoto, H. (2000). System Dynamic Model for Life Cycle Assessmental of Residential Buildings. Management science, 47, 123-132.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Norton, J., &amp; Bass, F. (1987). A Diffusion Theory Model of Adoption and Substitution for Successive Generations of High-Technology Products. Management Science, 1069–1086.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Radas, S. (2005). Diffusion Models in Marketing:How to Incorporate the Effect of External Influence?. Economic Trends and Economic Policy, 15(105).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Sterman, J. (2000). Business Dynamics: Systems Thinking and Modeling for a Complex World. Boston: Mac-Graw Hill.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Sutanto, J., Kankanhalli, A., Tay, J., Raman, K., &amp; Tan, B. (2008). Change Management in Interorganizational Systems for the Public. Journal of Management Information Systems, 25, 133–175.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Thun, j. h., Größler, A., &amp; Milling, P. (2000). The Diffusion of Goods Considering Network Externalities:A System Dynamics-Based Approach. The 18th International Confrence of The System Dynamic Society. Bergen.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Vilares, M., &amp; Coelho, S. (2003). The employee-customer satisfaction chain in the ECSI model. European journal of marketing, 37(11), 1703-1722.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Wieck, L. (1996). Learning Organization: From Idea to Action. Human Resource Management, 6.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Wilkie, W. (1994). Consumer Behavior. New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Williams, T., Eden, C., Ackermann, F., &amp; Tait, A. (1995). The effects of design changes and delays on project costs. Journal of the Operational Research Society, 46, 809–818.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Wunderlich, P., &amp; Grössler, A. (2012). Using system dynamics to analyze innovation diffusion processes within intra-organizational networks. 30th International System Dynamics Conference, (p. 111). Gallen.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Yeon , S., Park, S., &amp; Kim, S. (2006). A dynamic diffusion model for managing customer’s expectation and satisfaction. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, 73, 648–665.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Zhoa, W., &amp; Rena, H. (2011). A system dynamics model for evaluating the alternative of type in construction and demolition waste recycling center. Resources, Conservation and Recycling, 933-944.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14734_35a829be158fd12c23ca9777acfc2bd5.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>ارائه یک مدل مفهومی برای اثربخش نمودن واسط دانشی در فرآیند اشتراک دانش</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>وزیری گودرزی</surname>
			            <given-names>احسان</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>موحدی صبحانی</surname>
			            <given-names>فرزاد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>12</month>
			        <year>2014</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>3</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>101</fpage>
			      <lpage>120</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>01</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>15</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2014, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14734.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14734.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>مفهوم واسط دانشی، یک مفهوم سهل و ممتنع است. سهل است، زیرا واسط دانشی، وظیفة برقراری ارتباط میان شخص نیازمند دانش و شخص صاحب دانش را دارد. ممتنع است، زیرا انتقال دانش بدون نهادینه شدن دانش اثربخش نیست. هدف این پژوهش شناسایی ویژگی‌های واسط دانشی برای اثربخش نمودن فرآیند اشتراک دانش است. پژوهش حاضر از نظر روش‌شناسی، یک پژوهش کیفی با رویکرد داده‌بنیاد است. بر این اساس، وظایف واسط‌های دانشی و ویژگی‌های آنها در بستر یک سازمان دانش‌بنیان داخل کشور مورد بررسی قرار گرفت و ارتباط ساختاری میان ویژگی‌های فوق و وظایف واسط‌های دانشی برای اثربخش نمودن فرآیند اشتراک دانش تبیین شد. داده‌های پژوهش از طریق انجام مجموعه‌ای از مصاحبه‌های نیمه‌ساخت‌یافته با مدیران و خبرگان سازمان مورد مطالعه، جمع‌آوری گردید و با استفاده از شیوة کدگذاری باز، محوری و انتخابی تجزیه و تحلیل شدند. یافته‌های پژوهش، چهار ویژگی برون‌گرایی، جاذبة شخصیتی، برخورداری از جایگاه و اختیارات سازمانی و توانایی رهبری را برای واسط‌های دانشی آشکار ساخت. همچنین مدل مفهومی ارائه‌شده در این پژوهش نشان داد که واسط‌های دانشی، علاوه بر ایجاد ظرفیت ارتباطی، ظرفیت تغییر در سازمان را ارتقاء می‌بخشند و از این طریق منجر به اثربخش نمودن فرآیند اشتراک دانش می‌شوند.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>مدیریت دانش</kwd>
						<kwd>اشتراک دانش</kwd>
						<kwd>واسط دانشی</kwd>
						<kwd>ویژگی های واسط دانشی</kwd>
						<kwd>واسط دانشی اثربخش</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Ardichvili, A., Page, V. &amp; Wenling, T., 2003. Motivation &amp; Barriers to Participation in Virtual Knowledge Sharing Communities of Practice. Journal of Knowledge Management, 7(1), pp. 64-77.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Brown, S. &amp; Eisenhardt, K., 1997. The Art of Continuous Change: Linking Complexity Theory and Time-Paced Evolution in Relentlessly Shifting Organization. Administrative Science Quarterly , 42(1 ), pp. 1-34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>CHSRF, 2003. The Theory and Practice of Knowledge Broking in Canada’s Health System, Montreal: CHSRF.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Conklin, J., 2010. SHRTN Collaborative Evaluation Report, Covering years 4 and 5. Seniors Health Knowledge Network, Available at:  www. seniorshealthknowledgenetwork.com/taxonomy/term89.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, A., 2010. Knowledge Brokers - A Promising Knowledge Mobilization Strategy to Increase Research Use and Its Impact in Education. Ontario Institute for Studies in Education.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Cranefield, . J. &amp; Yoong, P., 2007. The Role of the translator/interpreter in knowledgetransfer environments. Knowledge and Process Management, 14(2), pp. 95-103.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Davenport, T. H. &amp; Prusak, L., 2000. Working knowledge: How organizations manage what they know, Harvard Business School Press, USA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Dobbins, M. &amp; et al, 2009. A description of aknowledge brokerrole implemented as part of a randomized controlled trial evaluating three knowledge translation strategies. Implementation Science,Volume 4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K., 1989. Building Theories from Case Study Research. Academy of Management Review, 14(4), pp. 532-550.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Fisher, C., 2011. Knowledge Brokering and Intermediary concepts. Brighton: IDS Knowledge Services.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Gao, S., 2004. Understanding Knowledge Sharing Behaviour, The Hong Kong University of Science &amp; Technology.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Giannakis, M., 2008. Facilitating learning and knowledge transfer through supplierdevelopment. Supply Chain Management: An International Journal, Vol. 13, pp. 62–72.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Glyn, W., 2000. A Comparative Discussion of Notion of the Validity in Qualitative Research. the Qualitative Report , 4(3).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Goh, S., 2002. Managing effective knowledge transfer: An integrativeframework and some practice implications. Journal of Knowledge Management, 6(1), pp. 23–30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Hammami, H., Amara, N. &amp; Landry, R., 2013. Organizational climate and its influence on brokers’ knowledge transfer activities: A structural equation modeling. International Journal of Information Management , 33 (2013), pp. 105– 118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Hansen, M., 2002. Knowledge networks: explaining effective knowledge sharing in multi-unit companies. Organization Science, 13(3), pp. 232-48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Hargadon, B., 1998. Firms as Knowledge brokers: Lessons in pursuing Continuous innovation. California Management Review, 40(3), pp. 209–227.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Honig, M., 2004. The new middle management: Intermediary organizations in education policy implementation. Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, 26(1), pp. 65-87.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Hooff, v. &amp; de Ridder, J., 2004. Knowledge sharing in context: the influence of organizational commitment, communication climate and CMC use on knowledge sharing. Journal of Knowledge Management, 8(6), pp. 117-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Horne, M., 2008. Honest brokers : brokering innovation in public services, The innovation Unit Inc..</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Jackson, N., 2003. Introduction to brokering in higher education. in: Engaging and changing higher education through brokerage. Ashgate Publishing , Aldershot.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Kerssens-van, D., 2001 . The Iterative Theory-Building Process: Rationale, Principlaes and Evaluation. Management Decision, 39(7), pp. 503-512 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Kidwell, D., 2013. Principal investigators as knowledge brokers: A multiple case study of thecreative actions of PIs in entrepreneurial science. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change , Volume 80, pp. 212–220.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Kim, S., Suha, E. &amp; Jun, Y., 2011. Building a Knowledge Brokering System using social network analysis: A casestudy of the Korean financial industry. Expert Systems with Applications , Volume 38, pp. 14633–14649.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>McGrath, J. &amp; Bringberg, D., 1983. External Validity and the Research Process: A Comment on the Calder/Lynch Dialouge. Journal of Consumer Research, Volume 10.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>O’Dell, C. &amp; Grayson, C., 1998. If only we knew what we know: identification and transfer of internal best practices. California Management Review, 40(3), pp. 154-74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Pandit, N., 1996. The Creation of Theory A Recent Application of the Grounded Theory Method. The qualitative Report, 2(4), pp. 1-20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Roxborough,  .,  Rivard,  .,  Russell,  . &amp;  , 2009. Knowledge Brokering in Health Care. CanChild  Centre for  Childhood  Disability  Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Scott-Findlay, S., 2004. Knowledge-Brokers, Linking Researchers and Policy Makers : Workshop Summary, Health Research Transfer Network of Alberta.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Sharifuddin, S. O. &amp; Rowland, F., 2004. Knowledge Management in a Public Organization: A Study on the Relationship Between Organization Elements and the Performance of Knowledge Transfer. Journal of Knowledge Management, 8(2), pp. 95-111.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Strauss, A. L. &amp; Corbin, I., 1990. Basics Of Qualitative Research: Grounded Theory Procedures And Techniques. Thousand Oaks.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Sundaresan, S. &amp; Zhang, Z., 2004. Facilitating Knowledge Transfer in Organizations through Incentive Alignment and IT Investment. Hawaii, Proceedings of the 37th Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Szulanski, G., 2000. The process of knowledge transfer: a diachronic analysis of stickiness. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Process, Volume 82, pp. 9–27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Teng, J. &amp; Song, S., 2011. An exploratory examination of knowledge sharing behaviors: solicited and voluntary. Journal of knowledge management , 15(1), pp. 104-117.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Yu, Y., 2004. Motivational Foundation of Individual Knowledge Sharing, Master Thesis, The Hong Kong University of Science &amp; Technology.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Zaltman, G., LeMasters, K. &amp; Heffring, M., 1982. Theory Construction in Marketing Some Thoughts on Thinking. John Wiley.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, J. &amp; Faerman, S. R., 2004. Nature of Knowledge and Its Influence on Knowledge Sharing Practice: Experiences from Building the MACROS System. Hawaii, Proceedings of the 37th Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>اخوان، پ. و رحیمی, ا.، 1391. شناسایی و رتبه بندی عوامل انگیزشی موثر بر اشتراک دانش در یک سازمان صنعتی. مدیریت نوآوری , 1(2), صص. 107-135.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>جعفری، م. و اخوان, پ.، 1385. بازارهای پویای دانش : راهی در تحقق مدیریت دانایی. ماهنامه علمی و آموزشی تدبیر، جلد 173.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>خاتمیان‌فر، پریسا، 1391.مروری تقلیلی بر عوامل بازدارنده و موانع اشتراک دانش در سازمان‌ها. نشریه الکترونیکی شمسه، (2)1.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>داونپورت، ت. ا. و پروساک، ل.، 1379. مدیریت دانش. اول تدوین مکان نشر نامشخص: ساپکو.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>صارمی نیا، ص.، مشبکی, ا. و دلاوری، و.، 1392. طراحی و ارزیابی الگوی مفهومی تدوین راهبرد داستان سرایی جهت مدیریت دانش. مدیریت نوآوری ، 2(3)، صص. 125-148.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>علامه, س.، الناز.، ش. ب. ع. و صدری، س.، 1391. شناسایی موانع تسهیم دانش در شرکت پالایش نفت اصفهان(مطالعه پدیدارشناسی). فصلنامه علمی و پژوهشی پژوهش های مدیریت منابع انسانی، 2(3)، صص. 119-143.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>گل افشانی، ن.، 1385. روایی و پایایی در پژوهش کیفی،. فصلنامه اطلاع رسانی، آموزشی و پژوهشی مدیریت فردا، (13-14)4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>مقیمی, س. م. و رمضان، م.، 1392. مدیریت دانش و فناوری اطلاعات. نشر سازمان مدیریت صنعتی._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Akhavan, P. &amp; Rahimi, A., 2012. Identify and rank the motivational factors affecting knowledge sharing in an industrial organization. Innovation Management, 1(2), pp.107-135.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Alameh, M., Shaemi Barzaki, A. &amp; Seyed Sadri, E., 2012. Identifying the Barriers of Knowledge Sharing In Isfahan Oil Refinig Company (the Phenomenology Research). Researches of Managemet Organizatinal Resources, 2(3), pp.119-143.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Ardichvili, A., Page, V. &amp; Wenling, T., 2003. Motivation &amp; Barriers to Participation in Virtual Knowledge Sharing Communities of Practice. Journal of Knowledge Management, 7(1), pp. 64-77.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Brown, S. &amp; Eisenhardt, K., 1997. The Art of Continuous Change: Linking Complexity Theory and Time-Paced Evolution in Relentlessly Shifting Organization. Administrative Science Quarterly , 42(1 ), pp. 1-34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>CHSRF, 2003. The Theory and Practice of Knowledge Broking in Canada’s Health System, Montreal: CHSRF.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Conklin, J., 2010. SHRTN Collaborative Evaluation Report, Covering years 4 and 5. Seniors Health Knowledge Network, Available at:  www. seniorshealthknowledgenetwork.com/taxonomy/term89.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, A., 2010. Knowledge Brokers - A Promising Knowledge Mobilization Strategy to Increase Research Use and Its Impact in Education. Ontario Institute for Studies in Education.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Cranefield, . J. &amp; Yoong, P., 2007. The Role of the translator/interpreter in knowledgetransfer environments. Knowledge and Process Management, 14(2), pp. 95-103.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Davenport, T. H. &amp; Prusak, L., 2000. Working knowledge: How organizations manage what they know, Harvard Business School Press, USA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Dobbins, M. &amp; et al, 2009. A description of aknowledge brokerrole implemented as part of a randomized controlled trial evaluating three knowledge translation strategies. Implementation Science,Volume 4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K., 1989. Building Theories from Case Study Research. Academy of Management Review, 14(4), pp. 532-550.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Fisher, C., 2011. Knowledge Brokering and Intermediary concepts. Brighton: IDS Knowledge Services.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Gao, S., 2004. Understanding Knowledge Sharing Behaviour, The Hong Kong University of Science &amp; Technology.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Giannakis, M., 2008. Facilitating learning and knowledge transfer through supplierdevelopment. Supply Chain Management: An International Journal, Vol. 13, pp. 62–72.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Glyn, W., 2000. A Comparative Discussion of Notion of the Validity in Qualitative Research. the Qualitative Report , 4(3).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Goh, S., 2002. Managing effective knowledge transfer: An integrativeframework and some practice implications. Journal of Knowledge Management, 6(1), pp. 23–30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Goolafshani, N., 2006. Validity and reliability in qualitative research. Quarterly Journal of Information, Education and Research Tomorrow's Management, 4(13_14).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Hammami, H., Amara, N. &amp; Landry, R., 2013. Organizational climate and its influence on brokers’ knowledge transfer activities: A structural equation modeling. International Journal of Information Management , 33 (2013), pp. 105– 118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Hansen, M., 2002. Knowledge networks: explaining effective knowledge sharing in multi-unit companies. Organization Science, 13(3), pp. 232-48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Hargadon, B., 1998. Firms as Knowledge brokers: Lessons in pursuing Continuous innovation. California Management Review, 40(3), pp. 209–227.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Honig, M., 2004. The new middle management: Intermediary organizations in education policy implementation. Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, 26(1), pp. 65-87.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Hooff, v. &amp; de Ridder, J., 2004. Knowledge sharing in context: the influence of organizational commitment, communication climate and CMC use on knowledge sharing. Journal of Knowledge Management, 8(6), pp. 117-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Horne, M., 2008. Honest brokers : brokering innovation in public services, The innovation Unit Inc..</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Jafari, M. &amp; Akhavan, P., 2006. Dynamic Knowledge Markets: A Way to Realize Knowledge Management. Monthly Scientific and Educational Tadbir, Volume (173).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Jackson, N., 2003. Introduction to brokering in higher education. in: Engaging and changing higher education through brokerage. Ashgate Publishing , Aldershot.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Kerssens-van, D., 2001 . The Iterative Theory-Building Process: Rationale, Principlaes and Evaluation. Management Decision, 39(7), pp. 503-512 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Khatemian Far, P., 2012. A brief overview of inhibitors and barriers to knowledge sharing in organizations. Shamsa Electronic Journal, 1(2).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Kidwell, D., 2013. Principal investigators as knowledge brokers: A multiple case study of thecreative actions of PIs in entrepreneurial science. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change , Volume 80, pp. 212–220.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Kim, S., Suha, E. &amp; Jun, Y., 2011. Building a Knowledge Brokering System using social network analysis: A casestudy of the Korean financial industry. Expert Systems with Applications , Volume 38, pp. 14633–14649.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>McGrath, J. &amp; Bringberg, D., 1983. External Validity and the Research Process: A Comment on the Calder/Lynch Dialouge. Journal of Consumer Research, Volume 10.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Moghimi, S.M. &amp; Ramazan, M., 2013. Knowledge management and information technology. Publication of Industrial Management Organization.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>O’Dell, C. &amp; Grayson, C., 1998. If only we knew what we know: identification and transfer of internal best practices. California Management Review, 40(3), pp. 154-74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Pandit, N., 1996. The Creation of Theory A Recent Application of the Grounded Theory Method. The qualitative Report, 2(4), pp. 1-20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Roxborough,  .,  Rivard,  .,  Russell,  . &amp;  , 2009. Knowledge Brokering in Health Care. CanChild  Centre for  Childhood  Disability  Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Sareminia, S., Moshabeki, A. &amp; Delavari, V., 2013. Designing and evaluating a conceptual model of storytelling strategy development for knowledge management. Innovation Management, 2(3), pp.125-148.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Scott-Findlay, S., 2004. Knowledge-Brokers, Linking Researchers and Policy Makers : Workshop Summary, Health Research Transfer Network of Alberta.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Sharifuddin, S. O. &amp; Rowland, F., 2004. Knowledge Management in a Public Organization: A Study on the Relationship Between Organization Elements and the Performance of Knowledge Transfer. Journal of Knowledge Management, 8(2), pp. 95-111.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Strauss, A. L. &amp; Corbin, I., 1990. Basics Of Qualitative Research: Grounded Theory Procedures And Techniques. Thousand Oaks.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Sundaresan, S. &amp; Zhang, Z., 2004. Facilitating Knowledge Transfer in Organizations through Incentive Alignment and IT Investment. Hawaii, Proceedings of the 37th Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Szulanski, G., 2000. The process of knowledge transfer: a diachronic analysis of stickiness. Organizational Behavior and Human Decision Process, Volume 82, pp. 9–27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Teng, J. &amp; Song, S., 2011. An exploratory examination of knowledge sharing behaviors: solicited and voluntary. Journal of knowledge management , 15(1), pp. 104-117.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Yu, Y., 2004. Motivational Foundation of Individual Knowledge Sharing, Master Thesis, The Hong Kong University of Science &amp; Technology.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Zaltman, G., LeMasters, K. &amp; Heffring, M., 1982. Theory Construction in Marketing Some Thoughts on Thinking. John Wiley.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, J. &amp; Faerman, S. R., 2004. Nature of Knowledge and Its Influence on Knowledge Sharing Practice: Experiences from Building the MACROS System. Hawaii, Proceedings of the 37th Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14735_24902358206bde3de7ae00d881d7bc29.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>طراحی محصول با استفاده از مدل ترکیبی کانو و گسترش عملکرد کیفیت با استفاده از تاپسیس (مطالعه موردی تلفن همراه)</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>طباطبایی نسب</surname>
			            <given-names>سید محمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه یزد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>ابراهیم پور</surname>
			            <given-names>مهسا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه یزد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>12</month>
			        <year>2014</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>3</volume>
			      <issue>3</issue>
			      <fpage>121</fpage>
			      <lpage>144</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>03</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>17</day>
			          <month>03</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2014, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14735.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14735.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>تاکنون روش‌های متعددی برای توسعة محصولات و خدمات، ابداع و آزمون شده است. امروزه با توجه به مزایا و معایب هر روش، رویکردهای تلفیقی بیشتر مورد توجه است. در این پژوهش نیز تلفیقی از دو روش گسترش عملکرد کیفیت و کانو مدنظر قرار گرفته است. خروجی روش تلفیقی، محصول جدیدی است که ضمن پوشش نیازهای اساسی و الزامات رقابتی، مشخصه‌های نوآورانه را نیز شامل می‌شود. در پژوهش حاضر، در گام اول نیازهای مشتریان از طریق مصاحبه با گروه کانون، شناسایی و با پیمایشی بر 282 نفر از کاربران به روش کانو گروه‌بندی گردید. سپس رابطة هر مشخصه و نیاز مرتبط با آن توسط خبرگان تعیین و در ماتریس نهایی گسترش عملکرد کیفیت لحاظ شد. همزمان، 18 مشخصه پس از رتبه‌بندی به کمک تاپسیس به ماتریس نهایی راه یافتند. بعد از تشکیل ماتریس گسترش عملکرد کیفیت با استفاده از تحلیل‌های گوناگون، اهداف تعیین شدند و گوشی تلفن همراه واجد مشخصه‌های نوآور و رقابتی معرفی گردید. در نهایت، مشخصه‌‌هایی که رضایت مشتری و همچنین مزیت رقابتی را به دنبال دارند، در ماتریس گسترش عملکرد کیفیت باقی‌ماندند و در طراحی نهایی محصول لحاظ گردیدند. مسیر طراحی با این روش می‌تواند خطر عرضة محصول جدید را کاهش و قدرت رقابت پذیری بنگاه‌ها را افزایش دهد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>گسترش عملکرد کیفیت</kwd>
						<kwd>مدل کانو</kwd>
						<kwd>توسعة محصول جدید</kwd>
						<kwd>تاپسیس</kwd>
						<kwd>تلفن همراه</kwd>
						<kwd>رضایت مندی مشتری</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Akao, Y. (1990). Quality Function Deployment: Integrating Customer Requirements into Product Design. Cambridge: Productivity Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Anderson, E. W., &amp; Mittal, V. (2000). Strengthening the satisfaction-profit chain. Journal of Service Research, 107–129.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Berger, C. (1993). Kano methods for understanding customer-defined quality. Centre for Quality Management Journal, 2(4), 3–35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Bilgilia, B., Erci, A., &amp; Unal, S. (2011). Kano model application in new product development and customer satisfaction (adaptation of traditional art of tile making to jewelries). Procedia Social and Behavioral Sciences, 24, 829–846.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Booz, A., &amp; Hamilton. New Products Management for the 1980s. 1982. New York.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Bossert, J. (1991). Quality Function Deployment: A Practitioner’s Approach. NewYork: ASQC Quality Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Büyükozkan, G., &amp; Berkol, C. (2011). Designing a sustainable supply chain using an integrated analytic network process and goal programming approach in quality function deployment. Expert Systems with Applications, 38, 13731-13748.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Chan, L., &amp; Wu, M. (2003). Quality Function Deployment: A Comprehensive Review of Its Concept and Methods. Quality Engineering, 15(1), 23-35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Chang, S., Hsiao, H., Huang, L., &amp; Chang, H. (2011). Taiwan quality indicator project and hospital productivity growth. Omega International Journal of Management Science, 39(1), 14–22.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, L., &amp; Kuo, Y. (2011). Understanding e-learning service quality of a commercial bank by using Kano’s model. Total Quality Management, 22(1), 99-116.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Chin, K. (2001). Quality Function Deployment approach for improving technical library and information services: a case study. Library Management, 22(4/5), 195-204.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Chin, K., Pun, K., Leung, W., &amp; Lau, H. (2001). A quality function deployment approach for improving technical library and information services: A case study. Library Management, 22(4), 195–204.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Chow, W., Madu, C., Kuei, C., Lu, M., Lin, C., &amp; Tseng, H. (2008). Supply chain management in the US and Taiwan: an empirical study. Omega International Journal of Management Science, 36(5), 665–679.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Cohen, L. (1995). Quality Function Deployment: How to Make QFDWork for You, Reading. Addison- Wesley.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Delano, G., Parnell, G., Smith, C., &amp; Vance, M. (2000). Quality function deployment and decision analysis: A R&amp;D case study. International Journal of Operations and Production Management, 20(5), 591–609.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Deszca, G. (1999). Developing breakthrough products: challenges and options for market assessment. Journal of Operations Management, 17, 613–630.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Edgett, S. (1993). Developing new financial services within UK building societies. International Journal of Bank Marketing, 11(3), 35-43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Eyob, E. (1998). Quality function deployment in management information systems. Journal of International Information Management, 7(2), 95–100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Garver, M. S. (2003). Best practices in identifying customer-driven improvement opportunities. Industrial Marketing Management, 32, 455–466.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Gustafsson, A., Ekdahl, F., &amp; Edvardsson, B. (1999). Customer focused service development in practice: A case study at scandinavian airlines system (SAS). International Journal of Service Management, 10(4), 344–358.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Hashim, A., &amp; Dawal, S. (2013). Kano Model and QFDintegration approach for Ergonomic Design Improvement. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 57, 22 – 32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Hua, Z., Zhang, X., &amp; Xu, X. (2011). Product design strategies in a manufacturer- retailer distribution channel. Omega International Journal of Management Science, 39(1), 23–32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Huiskonen, J., &amp; Pirttila, T. (1998). Sharpening logistics customer service strategy planning by applying Kano’s quality element classification. International Journal of Production Economics, 56–57, 253–260.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Jia, G., &amp; Bai, M. (2011). An approach for manufacturing strategy development based on fuzzy. Computers &amp; Industrial Engineering, 60, 445-454.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Kamvysi, K., Gotzamani, K., Andronikidis, A., &amp; Georgiou, A. (2014). Capturing and prioritizing students’ requirements for course design by embedding Fuzzy-AHP and linear programming in QFD. European Journal of Operational Research, 237(3), 1083-1094.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Kannan, G. (2008). Implementation of Fuzzy Quality Function Deployment in an Automobile Component to Improve the Quality Characteristics. Quality Engineering, 20, 321–333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Kano, N. (1984). Attractive quality ands must-be quality. Journal of the Japanese Society for Quality Control, 14(2), 39–48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Kwong, C., &amp; Bai, H. (2003). Determining the importance weights for the customer requirements in QFDusing a fuzzy AHP with an extent analysis approach. IIE Transactions, 35(7), 619–626.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Leba, M., Ionica, A., &amp; Edelhauser, E. (2013). QFD– Method for eLearning systems evaluation. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 83, 357 – 361.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Li, M., Jin, L., &amp; Wang, J. (2014). A new MCDM method combining QFDwith TOPSIS for knowledge management system selection from the user’s perspective in intuitionistic fuzzy environment. Applied Soft Computing, 21, 28-37.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Martins, A., &amp; Aspinwall, E. (2001). Quality Function Deployment: a empirical study in the UK. Total Quality Management, 12(5), 575-588.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Matzler, K. (1996). How to delight your customers. Journal of Product &amp; Brand Management, 2, 6–17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Matzler, K. (2004). The asymmetric relationship between attribute-level performance and overall customer satisfaction: a reconsideration of the importance-performance analysis. Industrial Marketing Management, 33(4), 271–277.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Matzler, K., &amp; Hinterhuber, H. H. (1998). How to make product development projects more successful by integrating Kano’s model of customer satisfaction into Quality Function Deployment. Technovation, 18(1), 25–72.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Mehrjerdi, Y.-Z. (2010). Applications and extensions of quality function deployment. Assembly Automation, 30(4), 388–403.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Ramanathan, R., &amp; Jiang, Y. (2009). Incorporating cost and environmental factors in quality function deployment using data envelopment analysis. Omega International Journal of Management Science, 37(3), 711–723.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Reichfeld, F. F., &amp; Sasser, W. E. (1990). Zero-defections: quality comes to services. Harvard Business Review, 105–111.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Sauerwein, E. (1999). Experiences with the reliability and validity of the Kano-method: comparison to alternate forms of classification of product requirements. Transactions of the 11th Symposium on QFD . Michigan: QFDInstitute.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Shil, N., &amp; Das, B. (2008). A Study of Customer Satisfaction with Regard to Banking: An Application of QFD. The Icfaian Journal of Management Research, 6(8), 7-26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Soota, T., Singh, H., &amp; Mishra, R. (2008). Defining Characteristics for Product Development Using Quality Function Deployment: A Case Study on Indian Bikes. Quality Engineering, 20, 195–208.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Tan, K. C., &amp; Shen, X. (2000). Integrating Kano’s model in the planning matrix of Quality Function Deployment. Total Quality Management, 11(8), 1141-1151.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Thakkar, J., Deshmukh, S. G., &amp; Shastree, A. (2006). Total Quality Management (TQM) in Self-financed Technical Institutions. Quality Assurance in Education, 14(1), 54-74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Ting, S. C., &amp; Shen, C. N. (2002). The asymmetrical and non-linear effects of store quality attributes on customer satisfaction. Total Quality Management, 13(14), 547–569.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Tontini, G., &amp; Silveira, A. (2005). Identification of critical attributes of success in products and services: an alternative to importance – performance analysis. BALAS Annual Conference. Madrid.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Tontini, J. (2007). Integrating the Kano Model and QFDfor Designing New Products. Total Quality Management, 18(6), 599–612.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Varela, J., &amp; Benito, L. (2005). New product development process in Spanish firms: typology, antecedents and technical/marketing activities. Technovation, 25, 395–405.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, C., &amp; Hsueh, O.-Z. (2013). A novel approach to incorporate customer preference and perception into product configuration. Computer Standards &amp; Interfaces, 35, 549-556.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, H., &amp; Wang, J. (2014). Combining fuzzy AHP and fuzzy Kano to optimize product varieties for smart cameras: A zero-one integer programming perspective. Applied Soft Computing, 22, 410-416.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Yamashina, H., Ito, T., &amp; Kawada, H. (2002). Innovative product development process by integrating QFDand TRIZ. International Journal Of Production Research, 40(5), 1031-1050.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Yeşilada, A., &amp; Yurdakul, D. (2009). Improving Healthcare Service Quality: An Application of Integrating Servqual and Kano Model in to Quality Function Deployment. International Journal of Business Research, 9(7), 156-165.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Yoshiki Matsui, Y., Filippini, R., Kitanaka, H., &amp; Sato, O. (2007). A comparative analysis of new product development by Italian and Japanese manufacturing companies: A case study. Int. J. Production Economics, 110, 16–24.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Zaim, S., Sevkli, M., Camgöz-Akdağ, H., Demirel, O., Yayla, A., &amp; Delen, D. (2014). Use of ANP weighted crisp and fuzzy QFDfor product development. Expert Systems with Applications, 41(9), 4464-4474.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>خان زاده، ن. (1388). بکارگیری مدل گسترش عملکرد کیفیت  در بهبود ابعاد کیفیت خدمات و افزایش سطح رضایت مندی مشتریان بانکی. اولین کنفرانس بین المللی بازاریابی خدمات بانکی. تهران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>دواس، د. ا. (1384). پیمایش در تحقیقات اجتماعی. تهران: نشر نی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>زنجیرچی، م., &amp; ترابی ، ز. (1387). رویکرد گسترش عملکرد کیفیت  در بهبود کیفیت خدمات بانکی. تدبیر، 193، 44-48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>عبدالباقی ، ع.، و رئیسی ، م. (1384). کاربرد تکنیک گسترش عملکرد کیفیت  در تعیین ویژگی های فیزیکی شعب بانکی ( مورد بانک رفاه ). ششمین کنفرانس بین المللی مدیران کیفیت. تهران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>فضلی، ص.، و  علیزاده، م. (1387). تجزیه و تحلیل و اولویت بندی بهینه نیازهای مشتریان: رویکرد مدل ادغامی KANO در گسترش عملکرد کیفیت . فصلنامه پژوهشنامه بازرگانی, 145-170.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>لاولاک، ک.، و رایت، ل. (1389). اصول بازرایابی و خدمات. تهران: انتشارات سمت._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Abdolbaghi, As. &amp; Raeisi, M., 2005. Application of Quality Expansion Technique in Determining the Physical Properties of Bank Branches (Refah Bank Case). Sixth International Quality Management Conference, Tehran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Akao, Y. (1990). Quality Function Deployment: Integrating Customer Requirements into Product Design. Cambridge: Productivity Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Anderson, E. W., &amp; Mittal, V. (2000). Strengthening the satisfaction-profit chain. Journal of Service Research, 107–129.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Berger, C. (1993). Kano methods for understanding customer-defined quality. Centre for Quality Management Journal, 2(4), 3–35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Bilgilia, B., Erci, A., &amp; Unal, S. (2011). Kano model application in new product development and customer satisfaction (adaptation of traditional art of tile making to jewelries). Procedia Social and Behavioral Sciences, 24, 829–846.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Booz, A., &amp; Hamilton. New Products Management for the 1980s. 1982. New York.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Bossert, J. (1991). Quality Function Deployment: A Practitioner’s Approach. NewYork: ASQC Quality Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Büyükozkan, G., &amp; Berkol, C. (2011). Designing a sustainable supply chain using an integrated analytic network process and goal programming approach in quality function deployment. Expert Systems with Applications, 38, 13731-13748.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Chan, L., &amp; Wu, M. (2003). Quality Function Deployment: A Comprehensive Review of Its Concept and Methods. Quality Engineering, 15(1), 23-35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Chang, S., Hsiao, H., Huang, L., &amp; Chang, H. (2011). Taiwan quality indicator project and hospital productivity growth. Omega International Journal of Management Science, 39(1), 14–22.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, L., &amp; Kuo, Y. (2011). Understanding e-learning service quality of a commercial bank by using Kano’s model. Total Quality Management, 22(1), 99-116.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Chin, K. (2001). Quality Function Deployment approach for improving technical library and information services: a case study. Library Management, 22(4/5), 195-204.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Chin, K., Pun, K., Leung, W., &amp; Lau, H. (2001). A quality function deployment approach for improving technical library and information services: A case study. Library Management, 22(4), 195–204.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Chow, W., Madu, C., Kuei, C., Lu, M., Lin, C., &amp; Tseng, H. (2008). Supply chain management in the US and Taiwan: an empirical study. Omega International Journal of Management Science, 36(5), 665–679.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Cohen, L. (1995). Quality Function Deployment: How to Make QFDWork for You, Reading. Addison- Wesley.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Delano, G., Parnell, G., Smith, C., &amp; Vance, M. (2000). Quality function deployment and decision analysis: A R&amp;D case study. International Journal of Operations and Production Management, 20(5), 591–609.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Deszca, G. (1999). Developing breakthrough products: challenges and options for market assessment. Journal of Operations Management, 17, 613–630.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Doos, D.A., 2005. Scrolling in social research, Tehran: Nashre Ney.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Edgett, S. (1993). Developing new financial services within UK building societies. International Journal of Bank Marketing, 11(3), 35-43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Eyob, E. (1998). Quality function deployment in management information systems. Journal of International Information Management, 7(2), 95–100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Fazli, S. &amp; Alizadeh, M., 2008. Analysis and Optimum Ranking of Customer Needs: Integrating Kano in QFD Models. Trade Studies Quarterly, pp.145-170.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Garver, M. S. (2003). Best practices in identifying customer-driven improvement opportunities. Industrial Marketing Management, 32, 455–466.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Gustafsson, A., Ekdahl, F., &amp; Edvardsson, B. (1999). Customer focused service development in practice: A case study at scandinavian airlines system (SAS). International Journal of Service Management, 10(4), 344–358.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Hashim, A., &amp; Dawal, S. (2013). Kano Model and QFDintegration approach for Ergonomic Design Improvement. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 57, 22 – 32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Hua, Z., Zhang, X., &amp; Xu, X. (2011). Product design strategies in a manufacturer- retailer distribution channel. Omega International Journal of Management Science, 39(1), 23–32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Huiskonen, J., &amp; Pirttila, T. (1998). Sharpening logistics customer service strategy planning by applying Kano’s quality element classification. International Journal of Production Economics, 56–57, 253–260.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Jia, G., &amp; Bai, M. (2011). An approach for manufacturing strategy development based on fuzzy. Computers &amp; Industrial Engineering, 60, 445-454.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Kamvysi, K., Gotzamani, K., Andronikidis, A., &amp; Georgiou, A. (2014). Capturing and prioritizing students’ requirements for course design by embedding Fuzzy-AHP and linear programming in QFD. European Journal of Operational Research, 237(3), 1083-1094.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Kannan, G. (2008). Implementation of Fuzzy Quality Function Deployment in an Automobile Component to Improve the Quality Characteristics. Quality Engineering, 20, 321–333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Kano, N. (1984). Attractive quality ands must-be quality. Journal of the Japanese Society for Quality Control, 14(2), 39–48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Khanzadeh, n., 2009. Application of Quality Expansion Model to improve the quality of services and increase the satisfaction of banking customers, First International Banking Services Marketing Conference, Tehran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Kwong, C., &amp; Bai, H. (2003). Determining the importance weights for the customer requirements in QFDusing a fuzzy AHP with an extent analysis approach. IIE Transactions, 35(7), 619–626.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Leba, M., Ionica, A., &amp; Edelhauser, E. (2013). QFD– Method for eLearning systems evaluation. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 83, 357 – 361.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Li, M., Jin, L., &amp; Wang, J. (2014). A new MCDM method combining QFDwith TOPSIS for knowledge management system selection from the user’s perspective in intuitionistic fuzzy environment. Applied Soft Computing, 21, 28-37.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Lovelock, Ch. &amp; Wright, L., 2010. Principles of service marketing and management. Tehran: The Organization for Researching and</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Composing University Textbooks in the Humanities (SAMT).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Martins, A., &amp; Aspinwall, E. (2001). Quality Function Deployment: a empirical study in the UK. Total Quality Management, 12(5), 575-588.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Matzler, K. (1996). How to delight your customers. Journal of Product &amp; Brand Management, 2, 6–17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Matzler, K. (2004). The asymmetric relationship between attribute-level performance and overall customer satisfaction: a reconsideration of the importance-performance analysis. Industrial Marketing Management, 33(4), 271–277.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Matzler, K., &amp; Hinterhuber, H. H. (1998). How to make product development projects more successful by integrating Kano’s model of customer satisfaction into Quality Function Deployment. Technovation, 18(1), 25–72.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Mehrjerdi, Y.-Z. (2010). Applications and extensions of quality function deployment. Assembly Automation, 30(4), 388–403.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Ramanathan, R., &amp; Jiang, Y. (2009). Incorporating cost and environmental factors in quality function deployment using data envelopment analysis. Omega International Journal of Management Science, 37(3), 711–723.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Reichfeld, F. F., &amp; Sasser, W. E. (1990). Zero-defections: quality comes to services. Harvard Business Review, 105–111.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Sauerwein, E. (1999). Experiences with the reliability and validity of the Kano-method: comparison to alternate forms of classification of product requirements. Transactions of the 11th Symposium on QFD . Michigan: QFDInstitute.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Shil, N., &amp; Das, B. (2008). A Study of Customer Satisfaction with Regard to Banking: An Application of QFD. The Icfaian Journal of Management Research, 6(8), 7-26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Soota, T., Singh, H., &amp; Mishra, R. (2008). Defining Characteristics for Product Development Using Quality Function Deployment: A Case Study on Indian Bikes. Quality Engineering, 20, 195–208.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Tan, K. C., &amp; Shen, X. (2000). Integrating Kano’s model in the planning matrix of Quality Function Deployment. Total Quality Management, 11(8), 1141-1151.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Thakkar, J., Deshmukh, S. G., &amp; Shastree, A. (2006). Total Quality Management (TQM) in Self-financed Technical Institutions. Quality Assurance in Education, 14(1), 54-74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Ting, S. C., &amp; Shen, C. N. (2002). The asymmetrical and non-linear effects of store quality attributes on customer satisfaction. Total Quality Management, 13(14), 547–569.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Tontini, G., &amp; Silveira, A. (2005). Identification of critical attributes of success in products and services: an alternative to importance – performance analysis. BALAS Annual Conference. Madrid.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Tontini, J. (2007). Integrating the Kano Model and QFDfor Designing New Products. Total Quality Management, 18(6), 599–612.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Varela, J., &amp; Benito, L. (2005). New product development process in Spanish firms: typology, antecedents and technical/marketing activities. Technovation, 25, 395–405.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, C., &amp; Hsueh, O.-Z. (2013). A novel approach to incorporate customer preference and perception into product configuration. Computer Standards &amp; Interfaces, 35, 549-556.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, H., &amp; Wang, J. (2014). Combining fuzzy AHP and fuzzy Kano to optimize product varieties for smart cameras: A zero-one integer programming perspective. Applied Soft Computing, 22, 410-416.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Yamashina, H., Ito, T., &amp; Kawada, H. (2002). Innovative product development process by integrating QFDand TRIZ. International Journal Of Production Research, 40(5), 1031-1050.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>Yeşilada, A., &amp; Yurdakul, D. (2009). Improving Healthcare Service Quality: An Application of Integrating Servqual and Kano Model in to Quality Function Deployment. International Journal of Business Research, 9(7), 156-165.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R115">
			<label>115</label>
			<element-citation>Yoshiki Matsui, Y., Filippini, R., Kitanaka, H., &amp; Sato, O. (2007). A comparative analysis of new product development by Italian and Japanese manufacturing companies: A case study. Int. J. Production Economics, 110, 16–24.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R116">
			<label>116</label>
			<element-citation>Zanjirchi, M. &amp; Torabi,Z., 2008. The approach of expanding the quality function in improving the quality of banking services, Tadbir, Volume (193), pp.44-48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R117">
			<label>117</label>
			<element-citation>Zaim, S., Sevkli, M., Camgöz-Akdağ, H., Demirel, O., Yayla, A., &amp; Delen, D. (2014). Use of ANP weighted crisp and fuzzy QFDfor product development. Expert Systems with Applications, 41(9), 4464-4474.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>