<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Developing a Framework for Aligning Adaptive Foresight with Science, Technology and Innovation Evidence-Based Policy-Making</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>چارچوبی برای همراستایی آینده نگاری انطباقی با سیاست گذاری مبتنی بر شواهد علم، فناوری و نوآوری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>21</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>50</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14626</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نامداریان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسن زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شعبان</FirstName>
					<LastName>الهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>مجید پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه امیرکبیر</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>A foresight activity can be assumed effective when its consequences are reflected in the policy-making process. This notion emphasizes the concept of foresight as a policy intelligence tool. No framework has yet been presented to show that foresight influences policy-making process. Therefore, the present study tries to provide a framework for aligning technology foresight with policy-making. This study mainly develops the proposed framework by integrating the concepts of evidence-based policy-making and adaptive foresight with the help of a mixed method. The &quot;mixed method&quot; approach used in this study has a sequential exploratory design characterized by the collection and analysis of qualitative data followed by the collection and analysis of quantitative data. First, a conceptual framework is developed in the qualitative part of the study by meta-synthesis and constant comparative method of analysis (CCM); second, in the quantitative part, the quantitative tests are done to evaluate the factors, dimensions, and components of the developed theoretical framework. To test the proposed model, questionnaires are distributed as the data collection tool among a sample of 15 experts active in the field of foresight and policy-making. The results confirm the hypotheses of the study and the validity of the proposed framework.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زمانی می‌توان یک فعالیت آینده نگاری را موثر تلقی نمود که بتوان آثار و نتایج آن را به گونه ای مناسب در سیاست‌گذاری ملاحظه کرد. این موضوع به مفهوم آینده نگاری به عنوان ابزار هوشمندی سیاستی اشاره دارد. تا کنون چارچوبی برای نشان دادن نحوه اثرگذاری آینده نگاری بر فرآیند سیاست‌گذاری، ارائه نشده است، لذا پژوهش حاضر با هدف ارائه چارچوبی برای همراستایی آینده نگاری با سیاست گذاری، انجام شد. برای این منظور، روش شناسی ترکیبی با رویکرد طراحی اکتشافی ترتیبی مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. برای نشان دادن اینکه هر گام آینده نگاری، یک کارکرد برای هر گام سیاست گذاری دارد، ابتدا با استفاده از روش فراترکیب، چارچوبهای جامعی برای آینده نگاری و سیاست گذاری استخراج گردید. سپس با روش تحلیل تطبیقی پایدار، میان گام های استخراج شده برای آینده نگاری و سیاست گذاری و نیز کارکردهای سیاستی آینده نگاری همراستایی برقرار شد. در ادامه برای اعتبارسنجی چارچوب مفهومی پژوهش، آزمون دوجمله‌ای مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. برای گردآوری داده های کمی، پرسش‌نامه‌ای طراحی و توسط 15 نفر از خبرگان حوزه آینده نگاری و سیاست گذاری علم، فناوری و نوآوری کشور تکمیل گردید. کلیه فرضیه های پژوهش تایید شد و  نتایج نشان‌دهنده اعتبار چارچوب پیشنهادی بود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آینده نگاری انطباقی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوشمندی سیاستی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاست گذاری مبتنی بر شواهد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراترکیب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویکرد اکتشافی ترتیبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل تطبیقی پایدار</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14626_711f766c0e4d867bf624c14f20a53997.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
