<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Status in Yazd Textile Industrial Cluster</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sabah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghaderian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Amir Kabir University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohsen</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Golrou Mofrad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Amir Kabir University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In the last decade, the policy of industrial clusters development as a relatively new approach in Iranian local and national economic development has been considered by policy makers and researchers. The development of industrial clusters can be evaluated based on different aspects, including: knowledge and technology, finance and investment, and innovation and entrepreneurship. In this study, different kinds of innovations and existing conditions, targets and limitations are identified by examining the formation of innovation in the production sector of the textile industrial cluster in Yazd, Iran. This study is of descriptive-analytical type conducted as a field research. In order to evaluate the innovation indicators, the OECD approach is used. The subject population of the study consists of Yazd textile manufacturing firms having at least 10 employees. The data is gathered through field study and from 51 production companies in Yazd textile industry from 2009 to 2011. The results show that the general status of innovation activities and cooperation is not desirable, with the main reason being &quot;the market conditions, lack of request for innovation and lack of collaboration culture&quot;. In other words, innovation is not a clear indicator of the development and competitiveness of the textile enterprises in Yazd. By contrast, expenditure and revenue factors are the main objective of innovation creation.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>25</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14637_13f20b3d62da8535a3d1263a2d1e62b5.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Effects of Dynamic Capabilities on Product Innovation Capability in Iranian Pharmaceutical Firms</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Naghizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allame Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mir Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Seydnaghavi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Razieh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ehsani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allame Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Pharmaceutical industry is nowadays considered as a strategic and knowledge-based industry with a high rate of innovation. Given the huge market, high R&amp;D investment and the increasing rate of change, pharmaceutical firms should increase their product innovations by improving their dynamic capabilities based on understanding of and responding to the transient opportunities of the competitive market and technology. In this paper, we present a model for improving the rate of product innovation in Iranian pharmaceutical firms, with a focus on dynamic capabilities effects. After designing a conceptual model and analyzing the data gathered from 60 pharmaceutical firms, the direction and intensity of the relations among latent variables are investigated by PLS. The results show that dynamic capabilities have considerable effects on the innovation capabilities of pharmaceutical firms, including quality, reducing the time of introduction to market, market share and the differentiation of new products.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>27</start>
					<end>51</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14638_ff89d1bfa0e35d6557c2ecc4c8dd9a01.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Presenting a Model for Selecting an Appropriate Method for Technology Valuation and Pricing: A Case Study of Antibacterial Nano-Tiles</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shafia</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amir</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aldaghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Aghil</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hamidi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Nowadays, the advent of technological businesses and the formation of knowledge-based economy have increased the demand for technology pricing. Although numerous methods have been proposed for technology pricing, they have deficiencies and limitations affecting their applications in certain conditions. This study aims to present a method selection model for technology pricing in various projects. To do so, the indicators affecting method selection are scored based on: the nature of technology, internal policies and external interactions. In the first part of the study, a review of the literature and the related concepts in the domain of technology pricing is presented, and four methods of technology pricing most widely used in theory and practice are comprehensively examined. After that, the research methodology and model indicators are introduced and scored by fuzzy Delphi-analytical hierarchy, and then the appropriate method for technology pricing is determined for various conditions. Finally, the results of the model are analyzed and used in a real case.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>51</start>
					<end>71</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14639_0bc9475fdb8b7af9d9f16c06cfcb959e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating and Analyzing the Impact of Successful Teaming Behaviors on the Perceived Organizational Innovation: A Case Study of Isfahan Railways Administration</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Yaghoob</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Maharati</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khorakian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Moslem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fakhri Fakhrabadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>When there is a need for different skills, experiences and expertise to achieve an aim, &quot;teaming&quot; will occur in organization, which consequently leads to innovation in organization by generating new capabilities through combination of realities and different viewpoints. The purpose of this study is to investigate and analyze the impacts of successful teaming behaviors on the organizational innovation perceived by the staff in Isfahan Railways Administration, Isfahan, Iran. Based on the research model, the impacts of successful teaming behaviors are analyzed and studied in five dimensions, namely expressing one&#039;s thoughts, experimenting, reflecting, intently listening and integrating, on the organizational innovation perceived by the staff. This survey is applied and descriptive in nature and uses a questionnaire as data collection tool. The population of the study consists of 538 employers of Isfahan Railways Administration, among whom a sample of 224 is selected by random sampling method. To test the hypotheses and the fitness of the model, structural equation modeling (SEM) and partial least squares (PLS) methods are used. The findings show that among the components of successful teaming there is a meaningful and positive relationship only between &quot;organizational innovation&quot; and &quot;integrating&quot;.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>73</start>
					<end>98</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14640_89aa8db09cc108452dd8e9f01cabe6ec.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Conceptual Framework for Holonic Inter-System Analysis: A Theoretical Study of the Relationship between Financial and Innovation Systems</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Roohallah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aboojafari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shaban</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Elahi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Adel</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Paighami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Imam Sadiq University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Kazem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Yavari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Innovation system studies are facing issues concerning the application of the concepts and theories of the field due to lack of precise theorizing. Innovation system studies used systematic approach to solve its problems, but failed to further benefit from new system approaches. In this paper, we review the weaknesses of two broad and narrow approaches in innovation system studies. The main goal is to provide a solution to resolve the shortcomings of innovation system studies using the new systems approach and recent debates in systems sociology. The solution is proposed as a holonic inter-system analysis conceptual framework. The research methodology is qualitative, and to validate the conceptual framework we use the holistic approach. The holistic approach is one of the issues raised in innovation system to analyze financing innovation in order to show the strengths of the new analysis in contrast to other frameworks. The findings show that by using the concept of function for defining system boundary and mediator holon, we can have a more precise perception of the relationship between financial and innovation systems, which itself results in less system errors in policy-makings. Based on the framework, risk coverage (such as insurance services in financial system) and policy-making authorities in financial system (such as central banks and stock market) should be addressed as a new sector in this field to promote functions of innovation system. This conceptual framework provides a more comprehensive analysis than the previous ones.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>99</start>
					<end>124</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14641_5d81d506f2d029bec38a382cc111dd4d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Designing and Evaluating a Conceptual Strategic Model for Storytelling in Knowledge Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Saba</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sareminia</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Moshabaki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Vahid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Delavari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Nowadays, innovation and organizational agilities are competitive advantages and knowledge management (KM) is one of the most important tools for creating competitive advantages, while having clear strategy is a way to succeed in KM. Moreover, storytelling is suggested as a simple and guaranteed tool for KM implementation. Therefore, this study aims to present a conceptual strategic model for storytelling in KM with two main stages and seven steps. The proposed model includes the following stages by concentrating on &quot;people&quot;, &quot;process&quot; and &quot;technology&quot;: The first stage, &quot;philosophy and theoretical fundamental steps&quot;, has one single step of &quot;analyzing organizational mission, vision and strategy&quot;, from the point of view of storytelling in KM. In this stage, the optimum organizational mission, vision and strategy are determined based on the effective elements. The second stage, &quot;executive steps&quot;, consists of six steps starting with &quot;analyzing status quo&quot; step from intra- and inter-organizational points of view, continuing with &quot;determining desirable status&quot; step to offer &quot;solutions for reaching the optimum status&quot;, and ending with &quot;selecting an appropriate strategy&quot; to &quot;implementing&quot; and &quot;constantly improving&quot; it based on feedbacks. Finally, the proposed model is evaluated using experts (in the fields of strategic and knowledge management) survey and verified by 95% certainty. Also, Friedman test shows that layers of the model are homogenous with a certainty of 95%.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>125</start>
					<end>148</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14642_80bcac4d11ae7c654605b78c3ee65154.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>