<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Conceptual Framework for Holonic Inter-System Analysis: A Theoretical Study of the Relationship between Financial and Innovation Systems</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>چارچوب مفهومی تحلیل بینسیستمی هولونیک: مطالعه نظری رابطه نظام مالی و نظام نوآوری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>99</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>124</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14641</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>روح اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>ابوجعفری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شعبان</FirstName>
					<LastName>الهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عادل</FirstName>
					<LastName>پیغامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه امام صادق(ع)</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کاظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>یاوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Innovation system studies are facing issues concerning the application of the concepts and theories of the field due to lack of precise theorizing. Innovation system studies used systematic approach to solve its problems, but failed to further benefit from new system approaches. In this paper, we review the weaknesses of two broad and narrow approaches in innovation system studies. The main goal is to provide a solution to resolve the shortcomings of innovation system studies using the new systems approach and recent debates in systems sociology. The solution is proposed as a holonic inter-system analysis conceptual framework. The research methodology is qualitative, and to validate the conceptual framework we use the holistic approach. The holistic approach is one of the issues raised in innovation system to analyze financing innovation in order to show the strengths of the new analysis in contrast to other frameworks. The findings show that by using the concept of function for defining system boundary and mediator holon, we can have a more precise perception of the relationship between financial and innovation systems, which itself results in less system errors in policy-makings. Based on the framework, risk coverage (such as insurance services in financial system) and policy-making authorities in financial system (such as central banks and stock market) should be addressed as a new sector in this field to promote functions of innovation system. This conceptual framework provides a more comprehensive analysis than the previous ones.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هم&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;اکنون جریان مطالعه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های نظام نوآوری با مساله میزان کاربردی بودن مفهوم&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها و نظریه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های این رشته روبروست که ناشی از عدم نظریه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;پردازی&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های دقیق است. اگر چه این رشته در ابتدا با استفاده از رویکرد سیستمی به حل مساله&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های خود پرداخت، اما در ادامه از روش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های سیستمی جدید کمتر بهره برد. &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;در این پژوهش ضمن اشاره به دو رویکرد گسترده و محدود در مطالعه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های نظام نوآوری، نقاط ضعف هر کدام در مورد تبیین دقیق نوآوری، مورد بررسی قرار می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;گیرد. هدف اصلی این پژوهش، ارائه راهکاری برای حل کاستی&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها در مطالعه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های نظام نوآوری با استفاده از رویکرد جدید سیستم&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها و بحث&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های اخیر جامعه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;شناسی سیستمی است که در قالب چارچوب مفهومی تحلیل بین&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;سیستمی هولونیک پیشنهاد می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;گردد. روش پژوهش مبتنی بر رویکرد کیفی است. برای اعتبارسنجی چارچوب مفهومی، با استفاده از رویکرد کل&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;نگر، یکی از موضوع&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های مطرح شده در مطالعه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های نظام نوآوری یعنی تامین مالی نوآوری با کمک این چارچوب مورد بررسی قرار گرفت تا نقاط قوت تحلیل جدید نسبت به چارچوب&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های گذشته مشخص گردد. &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;یافته&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های این پژوهش نشان داد که با استفاده از مفهوم کارکرد سیستم برای تعیین مرز سیستم و هولون واسطه، می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;توان برداشت دقیق&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;تری از رابطه بین دو نظام مالی و نظام نوآوری ارائه داد، به گونه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای که در سیاست&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;گذاری&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها، خطاهای سیستمی کمتر رخ دهد. بر این اساس برای توسعه کارکردهای نظام نوآوری، باید پوشش نااطمینانی (مانند خدمات بیمه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای در نظام مالی) و نهادهای سیاست&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;گذار نظام مالی (مانند بانک مرکزی و سازمان بورس اوراق بهادار) به عنوان بخش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های جدید در مطالعه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های این حوزه  مورد بررسی قرار گیرد. لذا این چارچوب مفهومی تحلیل جامع&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;تری نسبت به چارچوبهای قبلی ارائه می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;کند.&lt;/strong&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل بینسیستمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل هولونیک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14641_5d81d506f2d029bec38a382cc111dd4d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
