<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Developing Innovative Products: The Effect of Internal Market-Orientation and the Mediatory Role of Organizational Intelligence</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>توسعه محصولات نوآورانه: اثر بازارگرایی درونی و نقش میانجی هوش سازمانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>49</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>72</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14718</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالمجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>مصلح</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه خلیج فارس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>اله یاری بوزنجانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Innovation, as the most stable phenomenon in today&#039;s dynamic environment, is the only solution to the survival of corporations. It is especially of great importance for gaining competitive advantages, because of its effects on the raison d&#039;être of knowledge-based enterprises. Therefore, the aim of this study is to design a model for developing innovative products in knowledge-based enterprises. To this end, a total of 39 enterprises in Fars Science and Technology Park (FSTP), in Shiraz, Iran, are studied and the needed data is gathered through a questionnaire distributed among the employees in the park. Finally, the structural equation modeling with partial least square approach is used to analyze the data and examine the proposed hypotheses. The results show that internal marketing has an positive and significant effect on organizational intelligence and technological innovation. Furthermore, internal communications, and employees&#039; development and reward systems respectively have higher positive effect on organizational intelligence. Also, employees&#039; development has a positive and significant effect on products innovation, while internal communications and reward systems have no significant and positive effects on products innovation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;نوآوری، به عنوان پایدارترین پدیده در محیط پویای امروزی، تنها راه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;کاری است که ادامه حیات شرکت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها را در آن باید جستجو نمود. این امر به ویژه از جهت نقشی که در تشکیل فلسفة وجودی شرکت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های دانش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;بنیان ایفا می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;نماید، اهمیت بسیار بالایی در ادامه فعالیت و کسب مزیت رقابتی برای این گونه شرکت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها دارد. از این&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;رو، پژوهش حاضر با هدف طراحی الگویی برای توسعة محصولات نوآورانه در مؤسسه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های دانش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;بنیان انجام شد. برای این منظور، تعداد 39 شرکت فناور مستقر در پارک علم و فناوری فارس مورد مطالعه قرار گرفت و داده&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های مورد نظر از طریق توزیع پرسشنامه میان کارکنان آن&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها جمع&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;آوری گردید. همچنین، برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها و بررسی فرضیه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها نیز از روش مدل&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;سازی معادلات ساختاری با رویکرد حداقل مربعات جزیی استفاده شد. نتایج حاصل از تحلیل داده&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها نشان می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;دهد که وجود رویکرد بازار محور به محیط درونی سازمان، تأثیر مثبت و معنی&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;داری بر افزایش هوش سازمانی و توسعة محصولات نوآورانه دارد. علاوه بر این، بعد ارتباطات درونی مناسب بیشترین تأثیر را بر افزایش هوش سازمانی دارد. پس از آن نیز توسعة کارکنان و نظام پاداش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;دهی مناسب در رتبه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های بعدی اهمیت قرار دارند. همچنین، نتایج نشان می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;دهد توسعة کارکنان نیز بر ارائة محصولات نوآورانه تأثیر مستقیم و معنی&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;داری دارد؛ در حالی که نظام پاداش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;دهی و ارتباطات درونی فاقد چنین تأثیری هستند. &lt;/strong&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازاریابی درونی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوش سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محصولات نوآورانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارتباطات درونی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توسعة کارکنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام پاداشدهی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14718_56ea0ca88113e41652f60491bf7ddec4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
