<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Windows of opportunity for catch up in nanofibers technology in Iran from a sectoral systems of innovation perspective</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Emad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ahmadvand</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD student of technology management- Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University, Tehran, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Salami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty member of Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University, Tehran, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Habiboallah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tabatabaeian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty member of Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University, Tehran, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Jahanyar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bamdad Soofi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty member of Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University, Tehran, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract> 
Iran has experienced an evident progress on the path of catch up in nanofibers technology. This qualitative case study has analyzed the catch up process in this technology. The sectoral systems of innovation approach was used as the theoretical framework for the study. The effects of the technological regime, market regime, government policies and foreign sanctions on windows of opportunity in this sector has been explored. The study shows that: High technological opportunities, low appropriateness and low cumulativeness of nanofibers technology make this sector appropriate for a turbulent flow of innovators. Various and large local markets for nanofiber products can help domestic firms to build necessary capabilities for entering the foreign markets. However brand loyalty in one segment of the market and traditional players in another segment are two main market barriers for nanofibers development in Iran. Foreign sanctions against Iran on one hand have limited the financial transactions between Iranian and foreign firms. On the other hand, the sanctions have limited the entrance of foreign companies into Iran’s market. Government support programs for manufacturers of nanotechnology equipment had a crucial role in the success of the domestic firms in Entry Stage of the catch up cycle.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>28</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_87695_ba49c3cc8b7bb08e93dab0c3931a8b8b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Presenting a Framework of Organization Design in Technology-based International Strategic Alliances</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">S. Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jalali</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Tahmoores</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hasangholipour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Full Professor, Department of Business Management, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Strategic alliances have gained considerable attention, both among strategic management researches and across managerial decisions in business companies. Despite of this popularity, the failure rate of strategic alliances is high and theoretical literature has being sought the reason in governance mechanism and organizational design of alliances. With considering the importance of this issue and theoretical gap about it, current research devoted to the requirements and specifications of the structure of technology-based international strategic alliances. Findings from this multiple case study research are distinguished three designs and theirs requirements for effective application: parliamentary, technocratic and committee. In high vertical centralization-low horizontal centralization situation, the parliamentary form has most effectiveness; and in low vertical centralization-high horizontal centralization, the technocratic form is best suited. These forms are on a spectrum in which, any points between extremes, is a favourable place for applying of committee-based structure.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>29</start>
					<end>50</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_88267_86a8adcf36dbbcfbda321c7205b55f19.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identifying and prioritizing Critical Success Factors of product design in IT industry with Crowdsourcing Approach</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Morteza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Soltani</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">maysam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">shafiei</namePart>
				<affiliation>university of tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">s.javid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">hosseini</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty of Management and Accounting,university of tehran, College of Farabi</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Crowdsourcing is one of the new cooperative strategiesin open innovation that Using Information Technology (IT) facilities, provides a platform for active online crowds in various activities of companies such as product design. However, in this area, there were not too many projects which have achieved acceptable results. Therefore, this research attempts to identify and prioritize success factors of crowdsourcing in product design and improvement. the type of research is mixed method. The method of analysis for qualitative section is based on content analysis and for quantitative part is based on descriptive survey. Data were collected from experts and specialists in the field of crowdsourcing. Hence, several factors has been extracted from previous studies, then 36 main success factors has been recognized through interviewing approximately ten managers who are experienced in crowdsourcing for product design. The factors were assayed by Delphi method and final dimensions and factors were weighed by experts using best worth method. The study prioritized the quadruple dimensions of crowdsourcing as follows: contributors, IT system, organization management and employees. Among the factors of mentioned dimensions, “contributors operation quality”, “quality of IT System”, “control and supervision process” and “employees efficiency” are the most important ones, respectively.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>51</start>
					<end>84</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_88595_262a63e44f8bf824357e25fa56580b70.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identifying and analyzing challenges of forming of the engineered collaboration network
(a Case study of collaboration network of Poyandeghan Rah Saadat)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hashem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Moazzez</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor at University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Torabi Khargh</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hadi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nilforoushan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor at Shahid Beheshti University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sahebkar Khorasani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor at Technology Studies Institute</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In recent years, many studies have been conducted on collaboration networks, however, the process of evolution and network creation has been considered in a small number of studies. In this context, comprehensive identification and analysis of the challenges in the network forming process are important in order to solve them and to stabilize the network. In this research, an active collaboration network in the field of medical equipment that engineered by a Hub in 2009 and consisting of a large company, a small and medium-sized company, two subcontractors, three universities, a start-up, an accelerator and a venture capital fund, was studied. The presence of diverse members in the network is the basis for the emergence of various challenges and allows for a comparative analysis between them. For process-centric and rich analyze of information that gathered from deep interviews and supporting documents, a qualitative approach and case study were used. Finally, after analyzing the structure and framework of the network, 4 collaboration models and 28 different challenges were identified in the network, and in order to provide an analysis, those 28 different challenges (based on their existence or absence in each of the 4 identified collaboration models) divided into 7 categories and analyzed</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>85</start>
					<end>112</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_88488_17767829de49cc38f84bf2ceea611ffd.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A model for future-based knowledge management development; research study in the National Petrochemical Company</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Borumand Kakhki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Institute of Vision and Futures Studies, Islamic Azad University, Ph.D. Candidate of Futures Studies, National Research Institute for Science Policy of Iran,Tehran, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Niloofar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Radnezhad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Master of Technology Foresight,  Department of Management, Science and Technology, Amirkabir University of Technology (Tehran Polytechnic), Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amir Naser</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Akhavan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty member, Department of Management, Science and Technology, Amirkabir University of Technology Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">MohammadJavad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mostofi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Master of Technology Management, Department of Industrial Management, Faculty of Management &amp; Accounting, Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The pace of change, competition, informed customers and innovations makes to future challenges and uncertainties. So the efficiency of knowledge management (KM) and its adaptability to the future condition is necessary. If we don’t have a perspective on the organizational KM performance,not only the KM development activities will not be able to solve current problems, but also cannot benefit based on future knowledge needs. In this research, researchers by study on the National Petrochemical Company (NPC) have focused on how to integrate KM maturity to futures studies (FS), whose innovation relies on the combination and application of FS methods in this direction. Interviews, questionnaire and library studies were used for data collection. Using the logic of framework analysis, panels and focus groups on the future challenges of NPC KM result to break functional FS methods. Finally, a model for developing future-based KM has been proposed which consists of three stages: pathology and needs assessment, making knowledge base strategies and operational planning. The effect of this model is the value creation of knowledge strategies in accordance with the key state of the future (activity environment) and the convergence of macro strategies and the vision of organization with the objectives of knowledge management, which results in the evolution of the maturity level of KM from the perspective of the future.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>113</start>
					<end>142</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_88489_ff53c11d900e1961aba77758906b7980.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identifying the policies for improving the knowledge absorption  capacity and their effects on organizational performance : A System Dynamics Approach</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">saeed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">jahanyan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Department of Management, Faculty of Administrative Sciences and Economics, Isfahan University, Isfahan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">faeze</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">amini</namePart>
				<affiliation>Department of Management</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">shaemi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Department of Management</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The purpose of this research is to investigate the policies which are most effective on the knowledge absorption capacity and then their effects on organizational performance. In this study we use Balanced Score Card(BSC) as our performance measurement structure. In order to be able to measure the effects of each policy and also their combinations, A system dynamics methodology is applied through which the main variables of the system and its boundaries are identifies. After testing all sections of the model and also the whole model through various validity tests, three separate policies including increased training hours, the competency of interviewers and increased proportion of retired employees been interviewed are performed by a simulation tool by which a stock &amp; Flow model is made during the modeling process. According to the results the best policy for improving absorptive knowledge capacity and hence the organizational performance is a combination of all above mentioned policies. This study leads to a kind of decision support system through which managers in different levels would be able to simulate their potentially effective policies to see if they are actually effective on organizational performance or not. This study is a novel research which combines system dynamics with BSC in the field of knowledge absorption capacity in the organization.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>7</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>143</start>
					<end>168</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_88596_15e1cc4847f929a0801ee2f4611c7a6e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>