<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying the waves of military innovation in the Islamic Republic of Iran based on the ideas of the Supreme Leader</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی موج های نوآوری نظامی در کشور مبتنی بر اندیشه‌های فرمانده معظم کل قوا</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>123</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>149</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">102635</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خلیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوروزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه امام حسین علیه السلام</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>زاهدی خوزانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>علویان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه امام صادق علیه السلام</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The need for military innovation for defense industries in countries is increasingly felt today. Military innovation as a nascent field has special theoretical foundations. This study examines the foundations, goals, and requirements of realizing military innovation based on the ideas of the Supreme Leader Supreme Leader. The third wave refers to the institutional innovations that led to the establishment of revolutionary institutions in defense and military. The fourth wave is devoted to outlining their expectations of excellence in military and defense sciences during the current revolution. The Fifth Wave, one of the findings of the great think-tank&#039;s research process, is called Fundamental Knowledge Innovation, which addresses the concept of the fundamental sciences that can launch a new design in the military. Since then, the system of explicit expectations has been extracted from military organizations, military and defense commanders and commanders, and ultimately documented scholars in their field.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ضرورت پرداختن به نوآوری نظامی برای صنایع دفاعی کشورها امروزه بیش‌ازپیش احساس می‌شود. نوآوری نظامی به عنوان حوزه‌ای نوپا، بنیان‌های نظری ویژه‌ای دارد. در این پژوهش به بررسی بنیان‌ها، اهداف و الزامات تحقق نوآوری نظامی مبتنی بر اندیشه‌های مقام معظم رهبری مدظله‌العالی پرداخته‌شده‌است. برای نیل به این هدف، بیانات معظم له پیرامون نوآوری نظامی گردآوری گشت و مورد پژوهش و تحلیل قرارگرفت. روش استفاده شده درمقاله، کیفی بوده و از راهبرد تحلیل مضمون برای احصای الگوی مورد نظر استفاده گردید. موج سوم اشاره به نوآوری های نهادی دارد که منجر به تاسیس نهادهای انقلابی درحوزه دفاعی و نظامی شد. موچ چهارم به ترسیم انتظارات ایشان برای سرآمد شدن و مرزشکنی در علوم نظامی و دفاعی در دوران کنونی انقلاب اختصاص یافته است. موج پنجم که به عنوان یکی از یافته های روندپژوهی سیر اندیشه معظم له است،تحت عنوان نوآوری دانش پایه، به طرح مقوله علوم بنیادی که می تواند طرح نو در علوم نظامی در اندازند، می پردازد. پس از آن نظام انتظارات صریح معظم له از سازمان های نظامی، مدیران و فرماندهان حوزه نظامی و دفاع و نهایتا پژوهشگران این حوزه مستند به بیانات ایشان استخراج شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صنایع نوآور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری نظامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری دفاعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مقام معظم رهبری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_102635_408685297503e0e09162251e3a52c3fd.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
