<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Model of Decision-Making for New Venture Creation: A Grounded Theory Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>الگویی برای تصمیم‌گیری ایجاد کسب و کار جدید با رویکرد نظریه داده‌بنیاد</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>109</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>134</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">38499</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>زیودار</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نرگس</FirstName>
					<LastName>ایمانی پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کامبیز</FirstName>
					<LastName>طالبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید رسول</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه فرهنگیان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The decision-making process of entrepreneurs is not appropriately explicable by means of teleological approach. Through a non-teleological approach and employing a grounded theory research design, this study aims to explore a process of new venture creation decision-making in a sample of nascent entrepreneurs in Iranian high-tech businesses. The data collection is conducted through qualitative event-based interviews with 20 nascent entrepreneurs of the research theoretical sample. The analysis of the gathered data is done by three integrated procedures of open, axial and selective coding. The results determine six categories as the constituent elements of the studied process. These categories are &quot;entrepreneur’s characteristics and background&quot;, &quot;specific contextual conditions&quot;, &quot;general contextual conditions&quot;, &quot;entrepreneurial orientation and competency&quot;, &quot;identification, evaluation and empowerment&quot; and &quot;venture creation decision&quot;. Propositions concerning the relationships between the categories lead to the development of a model of new venture creation decision-making in the sample. Moreover, the studied process is explained by the story line of the substantive grounded theory.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">اتخاذ رویکرد غایت‌گرا، امکان تبیین مناسب فرآیند تصمیم‌گیری کارآفرینان را فراهم نمی‌کند. این پژوهش در تلاش است، ضمن اتخاذ رویکرد غیرغایت‌گرا و در چارچوب طرح پژوهش کیفی نظریه‌پردازی داده‌بنیاد، به واکاوی فرآیند تصمیم‌گیری ایجاد کسب‌وکار جدید، در نمونه‌ای از کارآفرینان نوپای حوزه کسب‌وکارهای فناور پیشرفته (نانو و زیست‌فناوری) ایران بپردازد. گردآوری داده‌ها با استفاده از مصاحبه‌های کیفی با 20 کارآفرین نمونه نظری پژوهش انجام شد. تحلیل داده‌های گردآوری‌شده، توسط سه رویه یکپارچه کدگذاری باز، محوری و انتخابی صورت پذیرفت. نتایج تحلیل‌ها، 6 مقوله را به‌عنوان عناصر تشکیل‌دهنده فرآیند مورد مطالعه، تعیین کرد. این مقوله‌ها شامل «ویژگی‌ها و پیشینه کارآفرین»، «شرایط خاص زمینه‌ای»، «شرایط عمومی زمینه‌ای»، «گرایش و شایستگی کارآفرینانه»، «شناسایی، ارزیابی و توانمندسازی»، و «تصمیم ایجاد کسب‌وکار» می‌باشند. گزاره‌های ناظر بر روابط میان مقوله‌ها، امکان توسعه الگوی تصمیم‌گیری ایجاد کسب‌وکار جدید در نمونه کارآفرینان حوزه کسب‌وکارهای فناور پیشرفته ایران را فراهم می‌کند. همچنین، فرآیند مورد مطالعه، در قالب خط داستان نظریه داده‌بنیاد، تبیین می‌گردد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایجاد کسب‌وکار جدید</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرآیند تصمیم‌گیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویکرد غیرغایت‌گرا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_38499_2058b0692f86494c7d57ac1204bcde0d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
