<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Effects of Company Resources and Environmental Variables on the Commercialization of New Product at the Iranian National Laser Center</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر منابع شرکت و متغیرهای محیطی در تجاری سازی محصول جدید در مرکز ملی علوم و فنون لیزر ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>24</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14759</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدحسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>نبوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مرکز ملی علوم و فنون لیزر ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>ثابتی فرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>مرکز ملی علوم و فنون لیزر ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داود</FirstName>
					<LastName>غیاثوند</LastName>
<Affiliation>مرکز ملی علوم و فنون لیزر ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شادی</FirstName>
					<LastName>قریشی</LastName>
<Affiliation>مرکز ملی علوم و فنون لیزر ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>25</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Clearly one of the main reasons for fast growth of technology development in developed countries is paying attention to commercialization process of internal researches&#039; results. It can be concluded that the basis of commercialization process is the cooperation of research and industrial sectors in conversion of research results into innovations and the development of new products. In this survey, we try to study the impact of resources and environmental variables on the commercialization of new product development, especially variables like &quot;dominant design&quot;, &quot;increase in market heterogeneity&quot; and &quot;network side-effects&quot; in Iranian National Laser Center (INLC). This study is applied in objective and descriptive-survey in nature. After reviewing the literature through library studies, a researcher-made questionnaire is applied to test the research hypotheses. The validity and reliability of the questionnaire are tested respectively by content and construct related validities, and &quot;Cronbach&#039;s alpha&quot;. Bivariate linear regression and structural equation modeling are used as inferential statistics methodology. Findings imply that &quot;dominant design&quot;, &quot;technology acquisition attitude&quot; and &quot;increase in market heterogeneity&quot; have significant effects on the commercialization of new product in INLC; whereas &quot;company&#039;s resources&quot; and &quot;network side-effect&quot; do not have any significant effects on the commercialization of new product in the center.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به طور قطع یکی از دلایل اصلی پیشرفت سریع توسعۀ فناوری در کشورهای توسعه یافتۀ صنعتی، توجه به فرآیند تجاری سازی نتایج پژوهش های داخلی بوده است. از این رو، می توان نتیجه گرفت اساس فرآیند تجاری سازی، مشارکت بخش پژوهشی و صنعت در تبدیل نتایج پژوهش ها به نوآوری و محصول جدید است. پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی تأثیر منابع شرکت و متغیرهای محیطی در تجاری سازی محصول جدید به ویژه بررسی تاثیر عواملی مانند طراحی غالب، افزایش ناهمگونی بازار و آثار جانبی شبکه در مرکز علوم و فنون لیزر ایران انجام شد. این پژوهش از لحاظ هدف، کاربردی و از لحاظ ماهیت توصیفی- پیمایشی است و در آن، برای بررسی ادبیات موضوع از روش کتابخانه ای و برای جمع آوری داده های پژوهش، از ابزار پرسشنامه استفاده شده است. روایی پرسشنامه با استفاده از روایی محتوا و سازه و پایایی آن با کمک روش محاسبۀ ضریب آلفای کرونباخ مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. روش های آمار استنباطی مورد استفاده، آزمون رگرسیون خطی دو متغیره و مدلسازی معادلات ساختاری بودند. یافته های پژوهش نشان داد که طراحی غالب، نگرش کسب فناوری و افزایش ناهمگونی بازار تأثیر معنی داری بر تجاری سازی محصول جدید در مرکز ملی علوم و فنون لیزر ایران دارند؛ این در حالی است که منابع شرکت و آثار جانبی شبکه تأثیر معنی داری بر تجاری سازی محصول جدید در این مرکز نداشته اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منابع شرکت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">متغیرهای محیطی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تجاری سازی محصول جدید</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مرکز ملی علوم و فنون لیزر ایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14759_dbb14cb771b3fc235f6d54faa7549413.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
