<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Decision-Making Model for Hi-Tech Organizational Buyers: SAIRAN&#039;s Patient&#039;s Heart Monitor</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مدلی برای تصمیم گیری خرید مشتریان محصولات فناورى برتر پژوهشی در نمایشگر قلب شرکت صاایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>61</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>75</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14595</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمودزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نفیسه</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحمتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و فرهنگ</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رفیعی راد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Why do customers prefer one product/brand to others? Which elements make one product more attractive than others? Nowadays, with the growth of markets, customers are growing too and understanding their behavior becomes accordingly more complicated than ever. &quot;Customer behavior&quot; is one of the most important issues for any marketer in SAIRAN organization to the extent that many decision-makings in the organization depend heavily on that. Hi-tech markets have special environmental characteristics, such as market/technology and competitive uncertainty, which differentiate them from low-tech markets; however, B2B and B2C marketing have many differences. One of the major objectives of this paper is to explore critical factors affecting the decision-making of hi-tech organizational buyers. Focusing on &quot;Patient&#039;s Heart Monitor&quot; as a hi-tech product in SAIRAN Company, we propose a new applicable model for the company marketing management. In this study, the &quot;grounded theory method&quot; is used, which is the best approach to find an applicable and useful model for B2B buying behavior in high-tech products. Finally, we compare this model with one of the latest models — i.e. Manabery &amp; Tina&#039;s model — to reveal its strengths and weaknesses.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">از آنجا که کالاهاى فناورى برتر داراى خصوصیات خاص و شرایط ناپایدارى است؛ لذا رفتار خریداران سازمانى امرى حساس و پیچیده است. این مقاله به بررسی و تحلیل حساسیت‌های کلیدی موثر در تصمیم‌گیری خریداران سازمانی در خرید کالای فناورى برتر می‌پردازد. برای این منظور از روش گرانددتئوری جهت ایجاد مدلى کاربردى و انتزاعى، استفاده شده است. پس از انجام مصاحبه با دست اندرکاران و خبرگان این  حوزه و تحلیل حساسیت‌ها و دستیابی به مفاهیم نهفته در آنها، مدلی برای فرآیند تصمیم‌گیری خریداران سازمانى ارائه شد که می‌تواند مراحل گوناگون تصمیم‌گیری را به خوبی نشان دهد و حساسیت‌های هر مرحله را ترسیم نماید. در انتها نیز مدل حاصل، با مدل مانابرى و تینا، مقایسه و بررسی گردید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصمیم گیری خرید مشتری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازاریابی کالای فناورى برتر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خرید سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گراندد تئوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14595_0077468d295fc8a45cb766fcfedbc140.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
