<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Human Resources Management: Vital and Effective Elements in Technological Innovation</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Narimani</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Nasser</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Noroozi</namePart>
				<affiliation>science and technology policy make at Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Saeed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Makkarian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allame Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Human resource management (HRM) is one of the most important resources of organizations and a basic element in obtaining organizational goals and strategies. This study aims to show the role of HRM in technology innovation and to investigate the effect of miscellaneous components of HRM on technology innovation. The participants in this study are active researchers in the field of nanotechnology. Based on a survey conducted among nanotechnology organizations and the subject matter experts, five groups of factors influencing innovation are determined. They include financial incentives, non-financial incentives, HR training, the evaluating and monitoring of process, and the evaluating and monitoring of output. Then, using appropriate statistical tests, the relationship among these factors are investigated. The results confirm all the hypotheses except the effect of financial incentives on technology innovation. In addition, the results indicate that external control has negative effect on technology innovation, whereas process control has positive effect on this variable.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>1</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>16</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14600_c909a4aa21d3a58d3103eeb3bcbfb6ea.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Effect of Technology Strategy Integration on Firms Performance</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyyed Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">A&rsquo;a rabi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allame Tabatba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Bamdad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Soofi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allame Tabatba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Jamshid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Salehe Sadeghiani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allame Tabatba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Booshehri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malekeashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Based on management and particularly technology management literature, the success of a firm depends on the effective integration of its technology strategy in accordance with business and corporate-level strategies. The question is how this integration should be achieved. Based on the theory of strategic reference points (SRP), organizations can select reference points for integration and then integrate their elements and systems with them. However, to study several firms, the same reference points are needed. In this study, the control and focus of the firms are selected as strategic reference points and a hypothesis is raised that integrating technology and corporate strategies around these reference points can lead to higher performance. This hypothesis is tested in 78 defense-related firms, revealing that certain types of corporate and technology strategies integration are associated with higher performance.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>1</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>17</start>
					<end>387</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14601_90343a2dc7bc088389641fac841f6015.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Relationship between Emotional Intelligence Capabilities and Organizational Entrepreneurship: A Case Study of Iran's Commercial Automotive Industry</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hussein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Norouzi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Asghar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Moshabaki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Hamid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khodadad Hosseini</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Asadollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kordnaeij</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Rapid changes, increased competition, reduced product life-cycles and rapid advance of technology are considered as unavoidable features of the current business environment. Creative and innovative entrepreneurs are necessary for organizations to survive. The particular interest of organizations and institutions in recent years reveals the importance of entrepreneurship in business environment. The present study aims to evaluate the effects of emotional intelligence capabilities on organizational entrepreneurship. The population studied in this study includes the commercial and cargo automotive industry of Iran. The study is based on a descriptive survey. In order to measure the emotional intelligence of managers and employees, the Afzalur &amp; Minors standard questionnaire is used to evaluate self-awareness, self-regulation, self-motivation, social awareness and social skills, while a researcher-made questionnaire is used to measure organizational entrepreneurship. The validity and reliability of the questionnaire are determined by experts and Cronbach&#039;s alpha. The data are analyzed using statistical methods, including Spearman correlation matrix, Friedman test and stepwise regression. The results show a significant positive relationship between the emotional intelligence of employees and organizational entrepreneurship. Also, confirmatory factor analysis is used to measure the total fitness of the model</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>1</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>39</start>
					<end>64</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14602_a8580e1d5da23c3aa04089a2d3285641.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Sociological Paradigms and Organizational Analysis: The Elements of Corporate Life Sociology</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sarlak</namePart>
				<affiliation>Payamenoor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyyed Ali Akbar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ahmadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Payamenoor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amir Hoseinn</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Amir Khani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Payamenoor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amir</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nikzad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Payamenoor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The present study is an interdisciplinary survey to identify the sociological basis of aviation technologies based on four well-known sociological paradigms: functionalism, interpretivism, humanism and structuralism. First, the main technologies of aviation industry are listed with a preliminary introduction to sociological paradigms. The main idea of the present study is to propose a conceptual framework for the classification and interpretation of aviation industry technologies philosophically, sociologically and technologically on the basis of a matrix created by integrating technological criteria in Perrow&#039;s typology with that of Burrell and Morgan&#039;s sociological paradigms. Based on the results of a questionnaire with a sample of 15 experts, aviation technologies location in each matrix is identified and finally four sets of technologies determined: functional technologies, interpretive technologies, humanistic technologies and structural technologies. At the end, some suggestions are proposed. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>1</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>65</start>
					<end>82</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14603_f510264c8fec6a41140bcafeff4eadf6.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Model for Outsourcing the Decisions of Manufacturing in a Governmental Organization</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Karimi Govareshaki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malekashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Elyasi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malekashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abedi Jozam</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malekashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Governmental organizations must change to agile organizations in order to achieve their goals and missions. According to the Article 44 of Iran&#039;s Constitution, one of the main policies of governmental organizations towards becoming agile organizations is to focus on core missions and to outsource technology and activities using the whole national research and industrial capacity. So, the government always has to deal with the issues concerning outsourcing decisions — which technologies/activities or products are outsourced and which are produced inside the organization? How much is the scope of outsourcing? And what is the best provider for outsourcing? This study investigates the outsourcing decision models and finally with the aids of AHP approach and Expert Choice software, presents a model for decisions on outsourcing, making or buying. Decision process in the proposed model deals first with the outsourcing of the whole system, then its components. Decision-making is done in three phases. In the first phase, decision-makings are based on the strategic importance of standards, technical knowledge maintenance and the security of information. In the second phase, decision-makings are founded on production in the internal network or external network based on the criteria of quality, price and delivery. In the third phase, final decision-makings are based on capacity. This model is tested on a real case and the results indicate that it is consistent with the experts&#039; opinions.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>1</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>83</start>
					<end>106</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14604_a891d01f3af9bdc3f0b7438051b52240.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Identification and Prioritization of Motivational Factors Affecting Knowledge-sharing in an Industrial-Research Organization</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Peyman</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Akhavan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malekashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Akbar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rahimi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Azad University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In today&#039;s competitive environment, gaining competitive advantage is one of the most fundamental challenges for managers. Nowadays, &quot;human resources&quot; are among the most important resources for creating competitive advantages, and those employees viewed as sources of knowledge will gain more value in organization. The importance and value the knowledge workers receive in an organization lead to a strategy known as knowledge preservation. Researchers have found that what leads to the creation of competitive advantage is employees&#039; knowledge and the process of sharing it. Managers try to promote knowledge-sharing, while employees tend to keep their knowledge secret. This paradox leads to different approaches taken by human resources and managers in hoarding or sharing knowledge. The solution proposed in this paper for aligning these two different approaches is using factors that cause human resources to share their knowledge with others voluntarily. In this study, motivations are introduced as factors that lead to human resources knowledge-sharing on a voluntary basis. After reviewing the literature and theories of motivation, and by using the questionnaire survey method, effective motivational factors in knowledge-sharing are identified in an industrial-research organization in Tehran, then ranked by Friedman method. The results show that in knowledge-sharing, intrinsic motivational factors have higher priorities than extrinsic ones. The results also demonstrate that &quot;friendly and sincere relations&quot; and &quot;job promotion&quot; are the most important intrinsic and extrinsic motivational factors affecting knowledge-sharing.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>1</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>107</start>
					<end>135</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14605_b3484e8c527c72f8bea134ce217afb35.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>