<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Evaluation of Technological Innovation Capabilities Impact on the Competitiveness of Small &amp; Medium Enterprises</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hessam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zandhessami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Qazvin Islamic Azad University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Zeinab</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ashtianipour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Industrial Management, Qazvin Kar university</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>One of the most important factors that stimulate firms to improve competitiveness and achieve competitive advantage is utilizing technological innovation capabilities. In this paper, various aspects of these capabilities are extracted, and their impacts on competitiveness are evaluated and prioritized. After reviewing the literature, the capabilities are categorized into six dimensions and different aspects of competitiveness are extracted. Due to the limited number of experts in the field of TICs and competitiveness, in this study, we use analysis and cause-and-effect equation methods in the form of multiple attribute decision-making analysis to determine the rate of the effects. The results based on DEMATEL techniques algorithm are analyzed and the rates of influencing and being influenced are measured. Based on the findings, TICs affect the competitiveness of small &amp; medium enterprises, and &quot;learning capability&quot; is determined as the most influential factor. Among the measures of competitiveness, &quot;profitability&quot; scored as the most influenced factor.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>24</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14631_e70daa76d64d85b19c0c40bce2ab24c9.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Evaluation of the Success Factors of Open Innovation Intermediaries: A Case Study of Nanotechnology Companies Network</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Manoochehr</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Manteghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malekashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abbas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Toloie Eshlaghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Islamic Azad University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Benyamin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Moshiri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Islamic Azad University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This paper aims to investigate and extract the success factors of innovation intermediary institutions in adopting open innovation approaches in the network of the nanotechnology companies. After reviewing the literature of open innovation with a focus on the role of mediating institutions, a validated questionnaire is developed based on interviews with experts. Moreover, using a statistical analysis software (SPSS) to analyze the factors, we develop a structural equations model (SEM) to determine the success factors. The results show that the success factors include S&amp;T policies and institutions, professional services, economic factors, collaboration networks, the characteristics of business models and the structure of the nanotechnology network in Iran.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>25</start>
					<end>44</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14632_ae8a667f43d9a834811eb193279f3b5d.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Enhancing New Product Development Success Based on Open Innovation Approach: A Case Study of a Research Organization</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hussein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Dehghani Poudeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malekashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Peyman</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Akhavan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malekashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sayyed Mahdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hosseini Sarkhosh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malekashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The advent of open innovation in innovation management workplace implies that organizations need to develop their cooperation with external partners as well as internal R&amp;D to ensure successful new product development. Thus, this paper tries to examine the effect of developing open innovation approach on new product development success in an R&amp;D organization. To do so, we develop a conceptual model and research hypotheses by reviewing the literature of open innovation and product development success. Then, for measuring open innovation dimensions and new product development success, we develop a questionnaire and distribute it among the target population. The research hypotheses are verified by correlation and regression statistical tests. In the organization under study, correlation analysis supports positive and significant relationship between all dimensions of open innovation and new product development success. Furthermore, regression analysis results indicate that among the open innovation initiatives, internal exploration and internal exploitation have positive and significant effects on new product development success. At the end, some practical implications are presented for innovation management practitioners to develop open innovation in the case study organization by increasing external practices of innovation, and some suggestions are proposed for future research to fill this research gaps.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>45</start>
					<end>68</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14633_22ef2606c7545b30d0cc9faed1aae7bf.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Analyzing the Impacts of Yazd Science and Technology Park Policies on Its Resident Institutions' Technology Development Using System Dynamics</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali Haji</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Gholam Saryazdi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of science and culture</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Manouchehr</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Manteghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malekashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Yazd Science and Technology Park (YSTP) has been established to develop the entrepreneurial skills of elite and talented people both at regional and national level, and to build a sustainable economy by creating, supporting and directing small and medium enterprises (SMEs). Since then, however, the policies adopted by the park have deeply impacted the resident companies&#039; performance and technological ideas. Since YSTP has revised its strategic planning and tried different policies, it is necessary to identify the impacts of its policies on the resident companies&#039; technology development with an aim to increase their effectiveness and promote technology. This paper investigates the impacts of YSTP policies during two strategic planning periods on the resident companies&#039; technology development by using system dynamics through library research, content analysis and individual interviews with technology and planning managers as well as interview with 7 of the top managers of the park. The findings indicate that the park policies over a decade have had high impacts on the level of its companies&#039; technology. Some policies (such as the Technology Research and Development Center (TRDC), the Technomarket (Technomart), the Innovation Center, and the Research and Technology Fund) have positive impacts, and some policies (such as focusing on regional markets and diversity of technology areas) have negative impacts on the level of the companies&#039; technology development.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>69</start>
					<end>98</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14634_8e6a8a0b328ba1d62102e55a63aa0d11.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Proposing a Process-Based Approach to Technology Planning at Supra-Corporation Level</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Nima</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mokhtarzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Arasti</namePart>
				<affiliation>Shaif University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sayyed Mostafa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Razavi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jafarnejad</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Competitive challenges have made it a critical need for industries to identify and choose enabling future technologies. Furthermore, the importance of defining direction for industry and the necessity of prioritizing technological investments in different subsectors demonstrate the significance of technology planning at industry level. Reviewing the literature of technology planning at industry level shows that the methodologies employed in most studies are either extended methods of technology planning at firm level or are resulted from a change in the frameworks of technology policy at national level. In this paper, by adopting a qualitative approach and grounded theory method and using semi-structured interviews with 40 academic and industrial experts in the field of oil &amp; gas, auto-making and aerospace, we present a three-level model for technology planning at industry level. At the reference level of the model, the main guidelines of technology development are chosen, and at the portfolio level, technology areas portfolios that best meet the main requirements of the system are defined. At the option level of the model, the technology options that have the potential to reach the desired functional goals are selected. At the end and after an analysis of the extended model, recommendations for further research are presented.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>99</start>
					<end>120</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14635_a7b8fe3153dd52eac83cdda21ab2fb7b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Decision Making Models of Knowledge-Based Small and Medium Enterprises in Complex Situation and Deep Uncertainty</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mashhadi Haji Ali</namePart>
				<affiliation>Arak Islamic Azad University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mojtaba</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rafiee</namePart>
				<affiliation>Payam-e-Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mostafa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ali Miri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Arak Islamic Azad University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2013</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Rapid changes in today&#039;s complex world have created a situation of uncertainty for businesses. In the turbulent and chaotic business environment, technology change is on the top of the list of today&#039;s major transformations. Knowledge-based enterprises as important elements of developing and using technology are facing many challenges, such as lack of information, unknown phenomena, high risks and emerging issues, where the task of decision-making is very hard. This study aims to identify patterns of decision-making to help managers make decisions in response to dynamic market changes. The decision-making principles and models are analyzed using rational and intuitive administrative decisions models. This paper examines three main features of decision-making environments, including conditions of deep uncertainty and complexity, decision-maker (entrepreneur) and the nature of decision-making (knowledge). This study is of descriptive-survey type conducted in the University of Tehran Science and Technology Park with the participation of 130 experts and managers. The results show that the intuitive model is the main decision-making model in firms working in uncertain environment. Also, it is clearly indicated that in this model, the features of decision-making play an important role in decision-making quality.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2013</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>121</start>
					<end>150</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14636_aaf7484c32aa12157c1e8b4a2b6c6535.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>