<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Modeling Factors Affecting Technological Collaboration Achievements: A Case Study of Technological Collaboration in the Field of Nanotechnology in Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مدل سازی عوامل موثر بر دستاوردهای همکاری های فناورانه: مورد کاوی همکاری های فناورانه نانوفناوری در ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>113</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>140</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14630</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابوالفضل</FirstName>
					<LastName>باقری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>بوشهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>04</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Many studies have been carried out on technological collaboration achievements in the field of science and technology policy. Some focus on the effectiveness of science and technology policies. Iran&#039;s science and technology policies support technological collaboration by providing many incentives, especially for emerging technologies like nanotechnology. There are still some debates about whether these policies are effective or not. This study is conducted to investigate the factors affecting achievements of technological collaborations. Based on the related literature, the factors affecting technological collaborations are classified into four groups: individual, institutional, organizational, and interactional. The model is verified by interviewing 20 experts active in the field of science and technology policy and nanotechnology sector in Iran. After that, the model is examined by structural equations modeling and path analysis methods. All the 72 researchers participated in the survey are randomly selected from nanotechnology experts&#039; database. The results show that the interactional factors, including social networks, individual interactions, organizational interactions and technological networks, directly and positively affect collaboration achievements.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در حوزه سیاست گذاری علم و فناوری، مطالعه‌های زیادی در مورد دستاوردهای همکاری های فناورانه صورت گرفته است. برخی از این مطالعه‌ها بر اثربخشی سیاست های علم و فناوری تمرکز کرده اند. در کشور ما نیز سیاست های علم و فناوری از طریق مشوق‌های متعدد بویژه در حوزه فناوری های نوظهور مانند نانو، از همکاری های فناورانه حمایت می کنند. با این وجود در اثر بخشی این سیاست ها تردید هایی وجود دارد.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; در پژوهش حاضر تلاش شد تا عوامل موثر بر دستاوردهای همکاری های فناورانه بررسی شود. برای این منظور، پس از مرور ادبیات، عوامل موثر بر دستاوردهای همکاری های فناورانه در 4 دسته عوامل فردی، سازمانی، نهادی و تعاملات دسته بندی گردید. این مدل از طریق مصاحبه با 20 خبره حوزه سیاست گذاری علم و فناوری و نانو کشور صحه گذاری شد. سپس مدل پژوهش از طریق روش معادلات ساختاری و تحلیل مسیر مورد آزمون قرار گرفت. 72 پژوهشگری که در این پیمایش مشارکت داشتند بصورت تصادفی از پایگاه داده ای خبرگان نانوفناوری انتخاب شده بودند. نتایج این پژوهش نشان می دهد که عوامل مرتبط با ارتباطات و تعاملات شامل تعاملات فردی، تعاملات سازمانی، شبکه اجتماعی و شبکه های فناوری تاثیر مستقیم و مثبتی بر دستاوردهای همکاری‌های فناورانه دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همکاری فناورانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نانو فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاست‌گذاری علم و فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ستاد نانوفناوری ایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14630_45fb4082cb96aa1cf905c965e2bf54c8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
