<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying the Critical Success Factors of Research Collaborations between Universities and Defense Industries in Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائه مدلی مشتمل بر عامل های کلیدی موفقیت برای همکاری میان دانشگاه ها و صنایع دفاعی کشور</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>25</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>52</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14764</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدعباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>دادور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منوچهر</FirstName>
					<LastName>منطقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابوالفضل</FirstName>
					<LastName>باقری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>There is an institutionalized connection between industry and university in developed countries. However, in Iran, despite a great emphasis on establishing and strengthening connections between defense industries and universities, there is no specific process to build an effective collaboration and the current policies are not highly sufficient for existing needs. The main reason is lack of proper identification of critical success factors in industry-university collaboration. So, the main purpose of this study is to identify the critical success factors of defense industries and university collaboration. To do so, 19 critical success factors are identified in four dimensions of interactions design, knowledge, social, and collaboration success through the literature review, then the research model and hypotheses are proposed consequently. A questionnaire is designed to collect experts&#039; opinions. The four dimensions and their factors are measured by frequency tables, mean and standard deviation. In addition, the effect of each factor on collaboration is determined through one sample test. Also, another questionnaire (including 36 items) is designed and distributed among users. Its questions are assessed and confirmed by conformity factor analysis. After that, the effects of all success factors are verified by path analysis, and the research model and hypothesis are confirmed by the findings resulted from structural equation modeling. Finally, some solutions and practical suggestions are made to improve and enhance the collaborations between university and defense industries.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در کشور ما، هر کی از صنایع دفاعی با روش متفاوتی ارتباط میان خود و دانشگاه ها را برقرار و از توانمندی های آن ها، برای پیشبرد اهداف و مأموریت های خود استفاده می کنند. در برخی موارد این روش ها چندان اثربخش نیست. دلیل اصلی این امر را می توان، نبود شناخت کافی از عوامل مؤثر بر موفقیت همکاری بین صنعت و دانشگاه دانست. پژوهش حاضر، سعی دارد با مطالعه مدل های ارتباط میان دانشگاه و صنعت در جامعه های پیشرفته و بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر موفقیت این تعاملات، عامل های کلیدی و میزان تأثیر هر کی بر موفقیت همکاری را در قالب مدلی ارائه نماید. بدین منظور، با مرور ادبیات موضوع، 19 عامل کلیدی مؤثر در موفقیت همکاری در قالب چهار بعُد شناسایی و در یک مدل ارائه گردید. سپس نظر اساتید و خبرگان با استفاده از ابزار پرسش نامه جمع آوری شد. با تحلیل داده های بدست- آمده، مؤثربودن با نبودن هر بعُد یا عامل بر موفقیت همکاری دانشگاه و صنایع دفاعی مشخص گردید. در ادامه، پرسشنامۀ دیگری برای کاربران طراحی و توزیع گردید و به وسیلۀ تحلیل عاملی تأ ییدی و تحلیل مسیر، تاثیرگذاری تمامی عامل ها بر موفقیت همکاری، تحلیل و تأ یید شد. در پایان، با استفاده از نتایج حاصل از مدل سازی معادلات ساختاری، فرضیه ها و مدل پیشنهادی تأ یید و راهکارها و پیشنهادات کاربردی جهت بهبود همکاری های دانشگاه ها و صنایع دفاعی کشور ارائه گردید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارتباط صنعت و دانشگاه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مارپیچ سه گانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عامل های موفقیت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14764_eed34a4df3eafdc817f0b05cc8c8193b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
