<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Formation of innovation networks with two hubs: A case study of mega-watt wind turbine network]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Haghighi, Majid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Arasti, Mohammad reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bahri, Abbas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Saifoddin, Amir ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nilforoushan, Hadi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[aslani, Alireza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[innovation networks with two hubs]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dual leadership in innovation networks]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Knowledge sub-network]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Industrial sub-network]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[wind turbine network]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Innovation networks are made up of individuals, firms, knowledge centers and industrial companies that work together to develop and commercialize a product or technology. The variety of activities ranging from R&amp;D to production, commercialization and coordination among them is done by one to several hubs in the network. In networks that their mission is innovation in products with complexity in design or manufacturing, there is a need for both industrial and knowledge hubs. The lack of expert manpower, prior experience, and knowledge/industrial infrastructure simultaneously in one hub is one of the most important reasons for the need for a second hub in these networks. The purpose of this paper is to present theoretical framework of innovation networks with two hubs and clarify the formation, main members and connections. In this regard, different leadership styles in innovation networks and the need for two hubs are described, and a preliminary theoretical framework is presented. To validate theoretical framework, a case study was conducted on the Mega-Watt wind turbine network. Based on the results, the theoretical framework is revised, which could be the basis for further studies.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_96988_84fa6eec20ac2d3c099e0fd4426188d4.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Meta synthesis of factors influencing strengthening the relationships among the members of S&amp;T collaborative networks from the perspective of social capital theory]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Saghafi, Fatemeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mazarei, ُSeyyedhamed]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khansari, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohammadi Kangarani, Hannane]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Asadifard, Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Collaboration networks]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Relationships among members]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social Capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[A major indicator of networks’ success is developing stable relationships and collaboration among the members. In fact, collaboration is the key to successful performance of members and the entire network. However, collaboration among the members of a network is a complex phenomenon requiring a comprehensive approach. A theory that can explain the relationships among the members of a network is Social Capital Theory. This research aims to develop a framework to analyze the relationships among the members of the formal collaborative networks of science and technology through the lens of Social Capital Theory. Using systematic review, 44 valid documents retrieved from WOS database, were selected, reviewed and codified using meta-synthesis approach. In the synthesis process, three main dimensions of relational, cognitive and structural and 24 sub-dimensions were revealed.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_97005_c59adfec55a7096cecc308eb52a78d95.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Model For The Development Of Iran's  Space Technological Capabilities]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Keramat, Shapor]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Manteghi, Manouchehr]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[JafarNejad, Ahmad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technological Capabilities]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[aerospace development plan]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Space Development]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Access to space and exploitation from it is achieved through space technological capabilities. The implementation of the first decade space program, the announcement of a comprehensive aerospace development plan and space achievements, represent the country's empowerment in this strategic field. While space development patterns of developing countries are based on learning and technology transfer, but due to the country's specific circumstances, the model of space technologies development and pace capability building does not match them. The unit of scale is aerospace sector and its period before the Islamic Revolution until now. The type of research is applied in order to develop knowledge and in the action aspect is mixed method. After documentary studies and exploratory interviews, qualitative data were collected and analyzed by content analysis and coding. In a quantitative section, a questionnaire was used and descriptive and inferential statistical methods were used.In addition to defining the developmental stages and growth of space capabilities , 61 factors were identified in the form of eight technological capability components Monitoring and paying attention to these factors in the current state of affairs that the spatial sector faces many challenges at the policy level, prioritizing and allocating resources to advance spatial plans can accelerate the acquisition and development of the required technological capabilities.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_97003_c620f25c00f1b51ff17281e97cb892d9.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Designing the Ambidextrous Innovation Model;A Study In A Defense Holding Company]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[akbari, mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Amini, Mohammad Taghi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mahmoudi Meimand, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Moradi, Mahmoud]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ambidexterity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ambidextrous Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[structural equation modeling]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[One of the main concerns of achieving an ambidextrous organization, is the determining of ambidextrous innovation features. In fact, finding the appropriate response which ones are the components and features of innovation in each of corporate strategic management approaches, forms the main purpose of designing and explaining the ambidextrous innovation in this research. In this study, structural equation modeling was used to design and explain the interactive model of this study while conducting library studies and using expert opinions. Accordingly, the model of ambidextrous innovation was shown in the 4 key components of Sectional, continuous, Revolutionary and Interactive innovation and 12 observed variables. The results of applying the proposed methodology in a Defense Holding firm are indicative of fit and acceptable validity of graphic relationships in the interactive model of this study.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_96994_f7947b6dc483e6ec6c063b2d392e4571.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Effect of Corporate Governance on the Innovative Efforts of Companies in the Tehran Stock Exchange]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[elyasi, mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mirzaei Azandaryani, Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[hasas yegane, seyed yahya]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[ghazinoori, soroush]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Corporate Governance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovative efforts]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tehran Stock Exchange]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[After corporate financial scandals such as Enron, Vantel and ... corporate governance matters, and attracted the attention of the researchers. In this study, the relationship between corporate governance and innovation Efforts in the companies active in the Tehran Stock Exchange (304 companies) has been investigated. This paper attempts to identify the dimensions and indicators of corporate governance, and then the most important factors affecting enterprise innovation are extracted, and indicators such as reliance on disclosed reports and the timeliness of reported disclosures, in other Studies have not been observed. The audited financial statements from 1391 to 1396 analyzed using the data panel method. The results show that the board of directors' education, choice of CEO from within or outside the company and the premium of the board of directors have a positive and significant effect on firm innovation, but the amount of payment for the right of the board of directors, the ability to rely on disclosed reports and the number of years of activity of the firm has a negative effect on the firm's innovation. CEO's education, the outsider board of directors, the ownership concentration and the timeliness of the disclosures by the company have no significant effect on the firm's innovation]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_96996_b5bec6e77887c04207d924150fd5a24e.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Comparative Conceptualisation of ‘Public Procurement for Capability Building’ (PPCB) In Relation to Public Procurement for Innovation (PPI): A Step Towards Implementation of Iranian Technology Annex]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Yazdi, Najmoddin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Jassbi, Abdollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Maleki, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bonyadi Naeini, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Public Procurement for Capability Building (PPCB)]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Public Procurement for Innovation (PPI)]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Iranian Technology Annex]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technological Capabilities of Suppliers]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Local Content Policies]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Considering the failure of local content policies (LCPs) in Iran and many developing countries, ‘Public procurement for innovation’ (PPI) as a trending demand-side innovation policy could provide a new theoretical basis for implementation of Technology Annex in the country. However, developing countries are of specificities compared with advanced economies, from which lack of technological capabilities of suppliers has a pivotal role in technological catch-up. The present paper suggests the new concept ‘public procurement for capability building’ (PPCB) based on the technology transfer projects of ten strategic groups of high-tech products based on the evidences of the case of Ten Strategic Equipment Groups in the oil industry of Iran, which is in fact an extension to PPI concept. The suggested concept puts building suppliers’ capabilities as the main goal of the policy.  The study showed various commonalities between these two policies, including needs for organisational changes in public procurers, risk management, utilising innovation (knowledge) intermediaries, and legal adjustment. However, two critical distinctions were conceptualised for PPCB, including 1) capability building as the main goal of the policy, and 2) establishment of a dual-track evaluation system which monitors and evaluates both the suppliers’ capabilities and the procured products.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_96998_fd92d8cb603c464ef1fe148b4331eac4.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>