<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing an Institutional Compatibility Ex-Ante Assessment Procedure for Science and Technology Policies</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی فرآیند ارزیابی پیشینی سازگاری نهادی سیاست های علم و فناوری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>59</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>86</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">38498</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوروزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شعبان</FirstName>
					<LastName>الهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حجت اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاجی حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>سازمان پژوهش های علمی و صنعتی ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسن زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>06</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>It is essential to consider policy assessment in policy cycle. However, ex-ante evaluation has been rarely reviewed in the policy evaluation literature. In this paper, a five-phase process of ex-ante evaluation of science and technology policies in policy cycle using grounded theory is offered. For this purpose, through the literature review, ten keywords are searched for, and finally 50 selected texts are selected for open and axial coding. After that, by structured interviews with experts, the process of ex-ante evaluation of institutional compatibility is extracted. The first step of the process is classifying the policy options. In the second step, Crucial Institutional Aspects (CIA) are identified in the policy cycle context. By determining some indicators, the third step measures these CIAs. The forth step analyzes the policy impacts, and in the fifth, these analyses are used to modify policy instruments with regards to the target institutions. This suggested process is a new subject and provides a tool for policy makers to conduct ex-ante evaluation of policies.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">توجه به ارزیابی سیاست‌ها در چرخه سیاست‌گذاری ضروری است، ولی ارزیابی پیشینی، در ادبیات ارزیابی سیاست، کمتر مورد توجه قرار گرفته است. در این مقاله، فرآیندی پنج مرحله‌ای برای ارزیابی پیشینی سیاست‌های علم‌وفناوری در چرخه سیاست با استفاده از روش نظریه‌پردازی داده‌بنیاد ارائه می‌شود. بدین منظور با بررسی ادبیات موضوع، بیش از ده کلید واژه، جستجو شد و در نهایت پس از انتخاب 50 متن منتخب، کدگذاری‌های باز و محوری صورت گرفت و با استفاده از مصاحبه‌های هدفمند با خبرگان، فرآیند ارزیابی پیشینی سازگاری نهادی استخراج و تایید شد. در این فرآیند پیشنهادی، اولین مرحله، دسته‌بندی گزینه‌های سیاستی است. در مرحله دوم جنبه‌های مهم نهادی در بافت چرخه سیاست در سه گام فرموله‌بندی، اجرا و ارزیابی شناسایی می‌گردند. مرحله سوم با تعیین شاخص‌هایی، این جنبه‌های مهم نهادی اندازه‌گیری می‌شوند. مرحله چهارم تحلیل‌هایی را از اثرات آتی سیاست ارائه می‌دهد و در مرحله پنجم، از این تحلیل‌ها برای تصحیح ابزارهای سیاستی، متناسب با نهادهای هدف استفاده می‌شود. این فرآیند پیشنهادی، ابزاری است برای سیاست‌گذاران که با پیروی از مراحل پیشنهادی آن، توانایی ارزیابی پیشینی سیاست‌ها را داشته باشند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاست های علم و فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاست گذاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزیابی پیشینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازگاری نهادی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_38498_43469fbb74235cbbfbe667a0f295e676.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
