<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Role of Talent Management in Organization&#039;s Intellectual Capital Development: A Case Study of Iran&#039;s PANHA</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی نقش مدیریت استعداد در توسعه سرمایه فکری سازمان (مورد مطالعه: سازمان پشتیبانی و نوسازی بالگردهای ایران- پنها)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>97</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>118</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14904</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داود</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسین پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منوچهر</FirstName>
					<LastName>منطقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سحر</FirstName>
					<LastName>ملک محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study is to investigate the role of talent management in Iranian Helicopter Support and Renewal Company (PANHA) intellectual capital development. This study is based on a main hypothesis and three sub-hypothesis which measure the effects of talent management on three intellectual capital factors, including human capital, relational structural capital and organizational structural capital. A sample consisted of 158 individuals (118 talented staff, and 40 deputies and experts of the organization) is selected and analyzed by inferential statistics using descriptive-surveyed research approach. The data is collected using questionnaires. For data analysis, first, we assess the base validity of all indicators using confirmatory factor analysis, and then the research hypotheses are examined by fitted model and structural equations model. The research findings indicate that talent management has positive and meaningful effect on intellectual capital of PANHA. Among the three components of intellectual capital, talent management has also positive and meaningful effect on the two components of human capital and relational structural capital, but has no impact on organizational structural capital.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف از این پژوهش بررسی نقش مدیریت استعداد در توسعه سرمایه فکری سازمان پنها می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;باشد. این پژوهش بر مبنای یک فرضیه اصلی و سه فرضیه فرعی بنا شده است که تاثیر مدیریت استعداد را بر سه مولفه سرمایه فکری شامل سرمایه انسانی، سرمایه ساختاری رابطه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای و سرمایه ساختاری سازمانی می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;سنجد. با استفاده از روش توصیفی- پیمایشی نمونه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای متشکل از 158 نفر (118 نفر از کارکنان بااستعداد و 40 نفر از معاونان و کارشناسان سازمان) انتخاب شد و با استفاده از آمار استنباطی مورد تجزیه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;وتحلیل قرار گرفت. ابزار جمع&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;آوری داده&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها، پرسش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;نامه بود. برای تحلیل داده&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها، ابتدا با استفاده از تحلیل عاملی تأییدی، روایی سازه تمام شاخص&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های مورد مطالعه محاسبه شد و سپس با استفاده از مدل برازش شده و مدل معادلات ساختاری، فرضیه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های پژوهش مورد آزمون قرار گرفت. یافته&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های پژوهش، نشان می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;دهد که مدیریت استعداد بر سرمایه فکری سازمان پنها تاثیر مثبت و معناداری دارد و از میان سه مولفه سرمایه فکری بر دو مولفه سرمایه انسانی و سرمایه ساختاری رابطه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای نیز تاثیر مثبت و معنادار دارد اما تاثیری بر سرمایه ساختاری سازمانی ندارد. &lt;/strong&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت استعداد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه فکری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه ساختاری رابطهای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه ساختاری سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان پشتیبانی و نوسازی بالگردهای ایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14904_60844d7a70dc181aebb97c0df723e089.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
