<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Analysis of the Policy Rationales of Conventional Economics in the Field of Science, Technology &amp; Innovation Policy-making Based on Thematic Method</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Sepehr</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghazinoory</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Meysam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Narimani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Zahra</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Afshari</namePart>
				<affiliation>AL Zahra University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hasanzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Policy rationales act as intermediator between theoretical foundations and policy implications, which are rooted in abstract concepts on the one hand, and present empirical implications in the field of policy-making on the other. Although conventional economics, also known as open market economy or neoclassic economy, evades offering any prescriptions, it implicitly and explicitly leads to policy rationales based on which specific policy implications are possible. Due to the significance of clear expression of these rationales in the field of science, technology and innovation policy-making, and purely implicit expression of the aforementioned concepts in the field of conventional economics, their explicit elicitation, especially by considering the role of conventional economics in science, technology and innovation policy decisions in Iran&#039;s society, bears considerable importance. Accordingly, eliciting conventional economics rationales in the field of science and technology in this study is examined drawing upon valid and relevant studies. By using thematic analysis and data-based strategy, we examine the core rationales of policy-making in the field of science, technology and innovation, having conventional economics approach in mind. As the findings show, some rationales and specific procedures are obtained alongside the concept of market as the core theme. The accumulation of intellectual and human capital, internalizing knowledge activities costs, the development of general-purpose technologies and improving business environment are among the most important rationales.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>22</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14716_01d40927431e6fffae189ef825407cc6.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Proposing a Model for Opening Iran's Defense Innovation System</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abbas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Montazeri</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hussein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khanifar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Elyasi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Elyasi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tehran of University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The evolution of innovation management and sectoral innovation systems literature shows a tremendous paradigm shift in the innovation context from closed innovation to an open one. Defense innovation context points to the need for taking an open approach toward the creation, development and diffusion of innovation as well. In this study, we propose a model for opening Iran&#039;s defense innovation system for the first time. By reviewing the literature and conducting exploratory interviews with experts, the dimensions and elements of the model are extracted. An initial 7 Likert-scale questionnaire is designed, and then its internal consistency is confirmed by the help of 30 experts and also by computing Cronbach&#039;s alpha. The developed questionnaire is answered by 245 defense innovation experts and the model dimensions and elements are confirmed by confirmatory factor analysis and structural equation modeling using LISREL software. The results show that for opening the defense innovation system, we have to take the following actions respectively: making the behavior of  main innovation players more open, taking a more open approach toward strategy making process, activating mediator actors in the section, and eventually designing and implementing more open interaction and relationship process between defense and non-defense innovation actors.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>23</start>
					<end>48</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14717_3643d1f65e6f353485feec573d9feb92.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Developing Innovative Products: The Effect of Internal Market-Orientation and the Mediatory Role of Organizational Intelligence</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abdolmajid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mosleh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Persian Gulf University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Allahyari Bouzanjani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Innovation, as the most stable phenomenon in today&#039;s dynamic environment, is the only solution to the survival of corporations. It is especially of great importance for gaining competitive advantages, because of its effects on the raison d&#039;être of knowledge-based enterprises. Therefore, the aim of this study is to design a model for developing innovative products in knowledge-based enterprises. To this end, a total of 39 enterprises in Fars Science and Technology Park (FSTP), in Shiraz, Iran, are studied and the needed data is gathered through a questionnaire distributed among the employees in the park. Finally, the structural equation modeling with partial least square approach is used to analyze the data and examine the proposed hypotheses. The results show that internal marketing has an positive and significant effect on organizational intelligence and technological innovation. Furthermore, internal communications, and employees&#039; development and reward systems respectively have higher positive effect on organizational intelligence. Also, employees&#039; development has a positive and significant effect on products innovation, while internal communications and reward systems have no significant and positive effects on products innovation.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>49</start>
					<end>72</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14718_56ea0ca88113e41652f60491bf7ddec4.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Evaluating the Impacts of Foresight on Science, Technology and Innovation (STI) Policy-Making</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Leila</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Namdarian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hassanzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Majidpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Amirkabir University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Technology foresight has shifted from R&amp;D policy to the broader context of social policy. So the foresight literature shows that there is a gap between foresight and policy-making. Most of the literature is focused on organizing and implementing foresight activities and converting foresight outcomes into policy. Despite the attempts made by some studies, forming foresight as an instrument for science, technology and innovation (STI) policy-making in a theoretical framework is still lacking in the literature of the subject. This paper tries to bridge the existing gap, with an emphasis on foresight role as a policy intelligence instrument, and uses a mixed method for this purpose. The mixed method approach in this paper is the sequential exploratory design &quot;characterized by the collection and analysis of qualitative data followed by the collection and analysis of quantitative data&quot;. First, the conceptual framework is developed in the qualitative part of this study by the concept of adaptive foresight and constant comparative method of analysis (CCM). Second, in the quantitative part, quantitative tests are done to evaluate the factors, dimensions and components of the developed theoretical framework. A questionnaire is used as data collection tool, and to test the proposed model, a sample of 15 experts in the field of foresight and policy-making answer the questions on the questionnaire. The results confirm the dimensions of the proposed framework.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>703</start>
					<end>102</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14719_79648e8188342765d0b466e115f5d0e0.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Proposing a Framework of Science and Technology Policy Instruments Based on Meta-Synthesis Approach</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Naser</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Norouzi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sha&rsquo;aban</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Elahi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hasanzade</namePart>
				<affiliation>at Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hojatolah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hajihoseini</namePart>
				<affiliation>Iran Research Organization for Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The realization of policy makers&#039; desired ideals and long-term objectives requires employing appropriate policy tools. Studying the theoretical foundations of policy-making tools makes it clear that each researcher&#039;s classification of policy tools depends on their respective policy-making environment and specific objective in their policy statement, and no specific classification covers all policy tools. In this study, more than 67 valid articles and books from the policy instruments literature are identified and different clusters are examined with qualitative meta-synthesis method. This selected framework is validated by conducting purposeful interviews with experts in the field of science and technology and five case-studies on policy documents. The framework merges supply side policies, demand side policies and framework policies. The results point to an imbalance between the supply and demand sides of national policies.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>103</start>
					<end>124</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14720_28ca89774ede7b13f5acecaf3eab64ad.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Entrepreneurial Aha! Experience: A Cognitive Science, Sociology and Psychology Synthetic Approach to Entrepreneurship</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Saeed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rezaei</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Armin</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khaleghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Eivazi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>&quot;Entrepreneurial Aha! Experience&quot; is a combinatorial approach from cognitive science, sociology and psychology to entrepreneurship, which we believe is a perfect view for extending Sarason&#039;s structuration view of entrepreneurship. Using the &quot;social representation&quot; concept, it provides novel understandings of structuration theory and clarifies the nature and process of structuration. &quot;Entrepreneurial Aha!&quot; argues that entrepreneurs create mental representation by perceiving external world, combine these mental representations to create fore-presentation (idea) of ideal social reality and try to externalize it through ventures. In other words, it is through social representation that entrepreneurs are influenced by opportunity and influence it by implementing the ideas.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>3</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>125</start>
					<end>144</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14721_83b6551fc06eb2f2098c0c431febd100.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>