<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An Analysis of the Policy Rationales of Conventional Economics in the Field of Science, Technology &amp; Innovation Policy-making Based on Thematic Method</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل خردمایه های سیاستی اقتصاد متعارف در حوزة سیاستگذاری علم، فناوری و نوآوری مبتنی بر روش زمینه محور</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>22</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14716</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید سپهر</FirstName>
					<LastName>قاضی نوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میثم</FirstName>
					<LastName>نریمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا افشاری</FirstName>
					<LastName>افشاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه الزهرا(س)</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسن زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Policy rationales act as intermediator between theoretical foundations and policy implications, which are rooted in abstract concepts on the one hand, and present empirical implications in the field of policy-making on the other. Although conventional economics, also known as open market economy or neoclassic economy, evades offering any prescriptions, it implicitly and explicitly leads to policy rationales based on which specific policy implications are possible. Due to the significance of clear expression of these rationales in the field of science, technology and innovation policy-making, and purely implicit expression of the aforementioned concepts in the field of conventional economics, their explicit elicitation, especially by considering the role of conventional economics in science, technology and innovation policy decisions in Iran&#039;s society, bears considerable importance. Accordingly, eliciting conventional economics rationales in the field of science and technology in this study is examined drawing upon valid and relevant studies. By using thematic analysis and data-based strategy, we examine the core rationales of policy-making in the field of science, technology and innovation, having conventional economics approach in mind. As the findings show, some rationales and specific procedures are obtained alongside the concept of market as the core theme. The accumulation of intellectual and human capital, internalizing knowledge activities costs, the development of general-purpose technologies and improving business environment are among the most important rationales.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">خردمایه‌های سیاست‌گذاری، واسطة میان مبانی نظری و دلالت‌های سیاستی هستند که از یک‌سو ریشه در مفهوم‌های انتزاعی نظری دارند و از سوی دیگر، دلالت‌های عملی چندی را در حوزة سیاست‌گذاری ارائه می‌دهند. رویکرد اقتصاد متعارف که با عنوان اقتصاد بازار آزاد و یا اقتصاد نئوکلاسیک هم از آن یاد می‌شود، اگر چه با ادعای اثباتی بودن، خود را از عرصة تجویز کنار می‌کشد، اما به‌صورت صریح و ضمنی به خردمایه‌های سیاستی چندی منجر می‌شود که دلالت‌های سیاستی ویژه‌ای مبتنی بر آن‌ها قابل ارائه است. به‌دلیل اهمیت بیان شفاف این خردمایه‌ها در حوزة سیاست‌گذاری علم، فناوری و نوآوری و تصریح صرفاً ضمنی این مفهوم‌ها در حوزة اقتصاد متعارف، استخراج صریح آنها به ویژه با توجه به نقش اقتصاد متعارف در تصمیم‌های سیاستی علم، فناوری و نوآوری جامعة ایران از اهمیت زیادی برخوردار است. بر همین اساس، در این پژوهش، استخراج خردمایه‌های اقتصاد متعارف در حوزة سیاست‌گذاری علم و فناوری مبتنی بر پژوهش‌های معتبر و مرتبط مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. با استفاده از روش تحلیل زمینه‌محور&lt;sup&gt;1 &lt;/sup&gt; و راهبرد داده‌بنیاد، خردمایه‌های محوری سیاست‌گذاری در حوزة علم، فناوری و نوآوری از منظر رویکرد اقتصاد متعارف مورد واکاوی قرار گرفته است. همانگونه که نتایج پژوهش حاضر نشان می‌دهد در کنار مفهوم بازار به عنوان زمینة محوری، خردمایه‌ها و روندهای خاصی از این پژوهش به‌دست آمده است. انباشت سرمایة فکری و انسانی، درونی‌سازی هزینة فعالیت‌های دانشی، توسعة فناوری‌های با کاربرد عمومی و بهبود فضای کسب‌و‌کار نیز از مهم‌ترین خردمایه‌های سیاستی اقتصاد متعارف هستند.&lt;br /&gt; </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اقتصاد متعارف</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازار رقابتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خردمایة سیاستی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل زمینه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14716_01d40927431e6fffae189ef825407cc6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
