<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" "journalpublishing3.dtd">
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60171_04c1aeac65a26c5420e2c7af5d324c0a.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>سیاست گذاری و مدیریت علم، فناوری، نوآوری و کارآفرینی و ارزیابی آن ها</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>یادگیری سیاستی در سیاستهای توسعه فناوری و نوآوری ایران (مطالعه قوانین برنامه سوم، چهارم و پنجم توسعه)</article-title>
			        <subtitle>یادگیری سیاستی در سیاستهای توسعه فناوری و نوآوری ایران (مطالعه قوانین برنامه سوم، چهارم و پنجم توسعه)</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فرتاش</surname>
			            <given-names>کیارش</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>الیاسی</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>قاضی نوری</surname>
			            <given-names>سید سروش</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>سازماناستادیار، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>طباطبائیان</surname>
			            <given-names>سید حبیب ا...</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار دانشکده حسابداری و مدیریت دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>23</day>
			        <month>08</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>6</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>1</fpage>
			      <lpage>30</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>16</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>12</day>
			          <month>12</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60171.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60171.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>مقاله حاضر با هدف بررسی یادگیری سیاستی و سازوکار‌های آن در عمده‌ترین تلاش‌های سیاست‌گذاری فناوری و نوآوری ایران، بر برنامه‌های توسعه به عنوان مهم‌ترین سیاست‌های توسعه‌ای میان مدت کشور تمرکز نموده است. با بررسی 5 برنامه‌ توسعه اخیر، برنامه‌های سوم تا پنجم توسعه که دارای نگاهی منسجم‌تر و یکپارچه در قالب یک فصل مجزا به توسعه فناوری و نوآوری هستند به عنوان سه قانون منتخب مورد مطالعه قرار گرفت. پس از بررسی و تحلیل محتوای اسناد سیاستی و مصاحبه با 18 نفر از بازیگران اصلی این فرآیند، 16 مقوله محوری در توسعه فناوری و نوآوری استخراج گردید. سهم غالب یادگیری سیاستی در این 16 مقوله به یادگیری سیاسی و فنی به ترتیب با 8 و 7 تکرار اختصاص یافته است. این سهم بالای یادگیری سیاسی به عنوان نازل‌ترین نوع یادگیری، نشان از بلوغ پایین یادگیری در بدنه سیاست‌گذاری فناوری و نوآوری کشور است. یادگیری فنی و مفهومی (با 7 و 5 وقوع) نشان از تلاش‌های نسبتاً موفق سیاستی است که عموماً بازیگران سیاستی سطح پایین و میانی درصدد بهبود و استمرار روند موفقیت‌های گذشته هستند نتایج این پژوهش می‌تواند در شناخت دقیق‌تر فضای سیاستی توسعه فناوری و نوآوری در دو دهه گذشته و تجارب آتی مفید باشد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>یادگیری سیاستی</kwd>
						<kwd>یادگیری</kwd>
						<kwd>قانون برنامه توسعه</kwd>
						<kwd>سیاستهای توسعه فناوری و نوآوری</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Argote, L., 2012. Organizational learning: Creating, retaining and transferring knowledge. Springer Science &amp; Business Media.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Bennett, C. J. &amp; Howlett, M., 1992. The lessons of learning: Reconciling theories of policy learning and policy change. Policy Sciences, 25(3), pp. 275-294.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Bernal, J. D., 1939. The Social Function of Science. London: George Routledge &amp; Sons LTD.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Biegelbauer, P., 2016. How different forms of policy learning influence each other: case studies from Austrian innovation policy-making. Policy Studies, 37(2), pp. 129-146.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Borrás, S. &amp; Edquist, C., 2013. The choice of innovation policy instruments. Technological forecasting and social change, 80(8), pp. 1513-1522.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Bush, V., 1945. Science, the endless frontier: A report to the president on a program for postwar scientific research,  National Science Foundation.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Creswell, J. W., 2014. Research design: Qualitative, quantitative and mixed methods approaches. 4th ed. SAGE.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Dolowitz, D. &amp; Marsh, D., 1996. Who Learns What from Whom: A Review of the Policy Transfer Literature. Political Studies, 44(2), pp. 343-573.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Dolowitz, D. &amp; Marsh, D., 2000. Learning from Abroad: The Role of Policy Transfer in Contemporary Policy Making. Governance, 13(1), pp. 5-23</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Dunlop, C. M. &amp; Radaelli, C. M., 2013. Systematizing policy learning: From monolith to dimensions. Political Studies, Volume (61), pp. 599-619</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Etheredge, L. S., 1985. Can Governments Learn? American Foreign Policy and Central American Revolutions. New York: Pergamon Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Eyestone, R., 1977. Confusion, diffusion and innovation. American Political Science Review, Volume (71), pp. 441-7.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Freeman, C., 1987. Technology policy and economic performance: lessons from Japan. Pinter Pub Ltd.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Freeman, R., 2006. Learning in public policy. In: M. Moran, M. Rein &amp; R. E. Goodin, eds. Oxford handbook of public policy. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Grin, J. &amp; Loeber, A., 2007. Theories of policy learning: Agency, structure and change. In: F. Fischer, G. J. Miller &amp; M. S. Sidney, eds. Handbook of public policy analysis: Theory, politics and methods. Boca Raton, FL: CRC Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Hall, P. A., 1993. Policy Paradigms, Social Learning and the State: The Case of Economic Policymaking in Britain. Comparative Politics, 25(3), p. 275–96.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Heclo, H., 1974. Modern Social Politics in Britain and Sweden. New Haven CT: Yale University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Kim, L., 1997. Imitation to innovation: The dynamics of Korea’s technological learning. Harvard Business Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Levy, J. S., 1994. Learning and Foreign Policy: Sweeping the Conceptual Minefield. International Organization, 48(2), pp. 279-312.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Lieu, J., 2013. Influences of policy learning, transfer, and post transfer learning in the development of China’s wind power policies, Doctoral dissertation, University of Sussex.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Majone,, G. &amp; Wildavsky, A., 1979. Implementation as evolution. In: J. L. Pressman &amp; A. Wildavsky, eds. Implementatron. Berkeley: University of California Press, pp. 177- 194.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>May, P. J., 1992. Policy Learning and Failure. Journal of Public Policy, 12(4), pp. 331-354.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>McCann, E. &amp; Ward, K., 2013. A multi-disciplinary approach to policy transfer research: geographies, assemblages, mobilities and mutations. Policy Studies, 34(1), pp. 2-18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Meseguer, C., 2008. Learning, Policy-Making and Market Reforms. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Murrall-Smith, S., 2012. Policy learning and the development of renewable energy policy in the United Kingdom, Doctoral dissertation, University of Plymouth.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Rietig, K. &amp; Perkins, R., 2017. Does learning matter for policy outcomes? The case of integrating climate finance into the EU budget. Journal of European Public Policy, pp. 1-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Rose, R., 1991. What Is Lesson-Drawing?. Journal of Public Policy, 11(1), pp. 3-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Sabatier, P. A., 1988. An advocacy Coalition Framework of Policy Change and the Role of Policy-Oriented Learning Therein. Policy Sciences, Volume (21), pp. 129-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Sabatier, P. A. &amp; Jenkins-Smith, H. C., 1999. The Advocacy Coalition Framework: an assessment. In: P. A. Sabatier, ed. In Theories of the Policy Process. Boulder, Colo: Westview.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Schneider, A. &amp; Ingram, H., 1988. Systematically Pinching Ideas: A Comparative Approach to Policy Design. Journal of Public Policy, 8(1), pp. 61-80.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Tuchman, B. W., 1984. The March of Folly: From Troy to Vietnam. New York: Knopf .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Wieczorek, A. J. &amp; Hekkert, M. P., 2012. Systemic instruments for systemic innovation problems: A framework for policy makers and innovation scholars. Science and Public Policy, 39(1), pp. 74-87.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>حبیب زاده، ط.، 1393. بررسی سیاست‌گذاری فناوری در آیینه اسناد و قوانین ایران: آیا با تورم اسناد کلی‌گو و اجرا نشده روبرو هستیم؟ http://drhabibzadeh.com/pages-106.html[Accessed 20 1 1396].</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>سالدانا، ج.، 1395. راهنمای کدگذاری برای پژوهشگران کیفی. تهران: انتشارات علمی و فرهنگی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>فراستخواه، م.، 1395. روش تحقیق کیفی در علوم اجتماعی: با تأکید بر نظریه‌ی بر پایه گراندد تئوری، تهران: انتشارات آگاه.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>فرتاش، ک.، 1393. تجزیه و تحلیل قوانین علم و فناوری و سیاست‌های کلان برنامه چهارم و پنجم توسعه با دیدگاه نظام ملی نوآوری.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>قاضی نوری، س س.، 1393. طرح تدوین احکام پیشنهادی برنامه ششم توسعه اقتصادی، اجتماعی و فرهنگی کشور در حوزه پژوهش و فناوری، به سفارش مرکز تحقیقات سیاست علمی کشور، انتشار به صورت محدود.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>قاضی نوری، س س.،  کاظمی، ح.،  روشنی، س.،  ردائی، نیلوفر.، 1394. بررسی اهداف و ابزارهای سیاستی در اسناد مرتبط با علم و فناوری، فصلنامه سیاست علم و فناوری، شماره 3، پاییز، صص 71-86 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>گودرزی، م.، 1393. آسیب شناسی مواد قانونی مرتبط با علم و فناوری در برنامه‌های توسعه 5 ساله کشور و ارائه رئوس مفاد پیشنهادی برنامه ششم توسعه در این حوزه، به سفارش پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری، انتشار به صورت محدود، با همکاری جلیل غریبی و حسین رضا علیزاده.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>گودرزی، م.،  علیزاده، ح ر.،  غریبی، ج.،  1393. آسیب‌شناسی سیاست‌های علم و فناوری در ایران: تحلیلی بر برنامه‌های پنج ساله توسعه، فصلنامه توسعه مدیریت فناوری، شماره 2، پاییز، صص 137-161.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>نوروززاده، ر.،  شفیع زاده، ح.،  روحانی، شادی.، 1392. ارزیابی و تحلیل بخش علم و فناوری: قانون برنامه پنجم توسعه از منظر  اسناد بالادستی، فصلنامه راهبرد، شماره 66، بهار، صص 285-314.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>ین، ر.، 1393. ورد پژوهی در تحقیقات اجتماعی. چاپ اول تهران: نشر نی._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Argote, L., 2012. Organizational learning: Creating, retaining and transferring knowledge. Springer Science &amp; Business Media.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Bennett, C. J. &amp; Howlett, M., 1992. The lessons of learning: Reconciling theories of policy learning and policy change. Policy Sciences, 25(3), pp. 275-294.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Bernal, J. D., 1939. The Social Function of Science. London: George Routledge &amp; Sons LTD.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Biegelbauer, P., 2016. How different forms of policy learning influence each other: case studies from Austrian innovation policy-making. Policy Studies, 37(2), pp. 129-146.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Borrás, S. &amp; Edquist, C., 2013. The choice of innovation policy instruments. Technological forecasting and social change, 80(8), pp. 1513-1522.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Bush, V., 1945. Science, the endless frontier: A report to the president on a program for postwar scientific research,  National Science Foundation.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Creswell, J. W., 2014. Research design: Qualitative, quantitative and mixed methods approaches. 4th ed. SAGE.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Dolowitz, D. &amp; Marsh, D., 1996. Who Learns What from Whom: A Review of the Policy Transfer Literature. Political Studies, 44(2), pp. 343-573.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Dolowitz, D. &amp; Marsh, D., 2000. Learning from Abroad: The Role of Policy Transfer in Contemporary Policy Making. Governance, 13(1), pp. 5-23</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Dunlop, C. M. &amp; Radaelli, C. M., 2013. Systematizing policy learning: From monolith to dimensions. Political Studies, Volume (61), pp. 599-619</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Etheredge, L. S., 1985. Can Governments Learn? American Foreign Policy and Central American Revolutions. New York: Pergamon Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Eyestone, R., 1977. Confusion, diffusion and innovation. American Political Science Review, Volume (71), pp. 441-7.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Farasatkhah, M., 2016. Qualitative research method in social sciences (with emphasis on theory) Grounded theory of GTM. Tehran: Agah Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Fartash, K., 2014. Analysis of the laws of science, technology and macro policies The fourth and fifth development plans with the view of the national innovation system. The 5th International Conference and 9th National Conference on Technology Management.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Freeman, C., 1987. Technology policy and economic performance: lessons from Japan. Pinter Pub Ltd.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Freeman, R., 2006. Learning in public policy. In: M. Moran, M. Rein &amp; R. E. Goodin, eds. Oxford handbook of public policy. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Ghazinoori, S. S., Kazemi, H., Roshani, S., Radaei, N., 2015. Review of policy goals and tools in science and technology related documents. Journal of Science &amp; Technology Policy, 7(3), pp. 71-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Ghazinoori, S. S., 2014. implementing proposals for the sixth program of economic, social and cultural development of the country in the field of research and technology, at the behest of the country's scientific policy research centre, diffusion is limited.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Goudarzi, M., 2014. Pathology of legal materials related to science and technology in the country's 5-year development plans and the presentation of the proposed provisions of the Sixth Development Plan in this area, commissioned by the Institute of Technology Studies. Limited Edition, in collaboration with Jalil Gharibi and Hossein Reza Alizadeh.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Goudarzi, M., Alizadeh, H. R., Gharibi, J., 2014. Pathology of Science and Technology Policies of Iran: An Analysis of five-year development plans. Journal of Development management, 2(2), pp. 137-161.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Grin, J. &amp; Loeber, A., 2007. Theories of policy learning: Agency, structure and change. In: F. Fischer, G. J. Miller &amp; M. S. Sidney, eds. Handbook of public policy analysis: Theory, politics and methods. Boca Raton, FL: CRC Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Habibzadeh, T., 2014. Technology Policy Considerations in the Mirror of Iran's Documents and Laws: Are We Having Clogo And Non-Executed Documents? http://drhabibzadeh.com/pages-106.html[Accessed 20 1 2017.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Hall, P. A., 1993. Policy Paradigms, Social Learning and the State: The Case of Economic Policymaking in Britain. Comparative Politics, 25(3), p. 275–96.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Heclo, H., 1974. Modern Social Politics in Britain and Sweden. New Haven CT: Yale University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Kim, L., 1997. Imitation to innovation: The dynamics of Korea’s technological learning. Harvard Business Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Levy, J. S., 1994. Learning and Foreign Policy: Sweeping the Conceptual Minefield. International Organization, 48(2), pp. 279-312.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Lieu, J., 2013. Influences of policy learning, transfer, and post transfer learning in the development of China’s wind power policies, Doctoral dissertation, University of Sussex.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Majone,, G. &amp; Wildavsky, A., 1979. Implementation as evolution. In: J. L. Pressman &amp; A. Wildavsky, eds. Implementatron. Berkeley: University of California Press, pp. 177- 194.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>May, P. J., 1992. Policy Learning and Failure. Journal of Public Policy, 12(4), pp. 331-354.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>McCann, E. &amp; Ward, K., 2013. A multi-disciplinary approach to policy transfer research: geographies, assemblages, mobilities and mutations. Policy Studies, 34(1), pp. 2-18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Meseguer, C., 2008. Learning, Policy-Making and Market Reforms. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Murrall-Smith, S., 2012. Policy learning and the development of renewable energy policy in the United Kingdom, Doctoral dissertation, University of Plymouth.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Norouzzadeh, R., Shafizadeh, H., Rouhani, Sh., 2013. Assessment and Analysis of Science and Technology Section of the Fifth Economic Development Plan Act in the Light of Large-Scale Instruments. Rahbord Publications, 66(22), pp. 285-314.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Rietig, K. &amp; Perkins, R., 2017. Does learning matter for policy outcomes? The case of integrating climate finance into the EU budget. Journal of European Public Policy, pp. 1-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Rose, R., 1991. What Is Lesson-Drawing?. Journal of Public Policy, 11(1), pp. 3-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Sabatier, P. A., 1988. An advocacy Coalition Framework of Policy Change and the Role of Policy-Oriented Learning Therein. Policy Sciences, Volume (21), pp. 129-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Sabatier, P. A. &amp; Jenkins-Smith, H. C., 1999. The Advocacy Coalition Framework: an assessment. In: P. A. Sabatier, ed. In Theories of the Policy Process. Boulder, Colo: Westview.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Saldana, J., 2016. The coding manual for qualitative researchers. Translated by: Givian, A., Tehran: Scientific and cultural publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Schneider, A. &amp; Ingram, H., 1988. Systematically Pinching Ideas: A Comparative Approach to Policy Design. Journal of Public Policy, 8(1), pp. 61-80.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Tuchman, B. W., 1984. The March of Folly: From Troy to Vietnam. New York: Knopf .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Wieczorek, A. J. &amp; Hekkert, M. P., 2012. Systemic instruments for systemic innovation problems: A framework for policy makers and innovation scholars. Science and Public Policy, 39(1), pp. 74-87.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Yin, R., 2014. Case study research: design and methods. 1th Edations, Translated By: Naeini, H., Tehran: Nashr-E-Ney.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60172_c4cdfd2c7a29f20bd937d21911a4b6c0.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>سیاست گذاری و مدیریت علم، فناوری، نوآوری و کارآفرینی و ارزیابی آن ها</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>اثر سیاست‌های تنظیمی بر توانمندی نوآوری بنگاه‌های تولید داروی ایران</article-title>
			        <subtitle>اثر سیاست‌های تنظیمی بر توانمندی نوآوری بنگاه‌های تولید داروی ایران</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>سلطان زاده</surname>
			            <given-names>جواد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>الیاسی</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بامداد صوفی</surname>
			            <given-names>جهانیار</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>کزازی</surname>
			            <given-names>ابوالفضل</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>23</day>
			        <month>08</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>6</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>31</fpage>
			      <lpage>64</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>29</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>27</day>
			          <month>01</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60172.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60172.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>فهم اثر سیاست‌های وضع شده در پاسخ به شکست‌های بازار و سیستم همواره مورد توجه محققان بوده است. آنها در مسیر مطالعات خود تلاش کرده‌اند با توسعه مفهوم افزودنی رفتاری، نگاه خروجی محور به ارزیابی سیاست را بسط داده تا بتوانند اثر مداخلات دولت را بر رفتار بنگاه رصد نمایند. در این تحقیقات بر توانمندی نوآوری و خردبنیان‌های آن به عنوان مبین‌های رفتاری بنگاه در ارزیابی مداخلات کمتر تمرکز شده است. از اینرو پژوهش حاضر با تاکید بر توانمندی نوآوری به عنوان یک افزودنی رفتاری تلاش می‌کند، اثرات سه سیاست تنظیمی طرح ژنریک، نظام قیمت‌گذاری و نظام تعرفه‌ گمرکی را بر رفتار نوآوری در شرکت‌های تولید دارو بسنجد. پژوهش حاضر از دسته پژوهش‌های آمیخته با استفاده از استراتژی مطالعه چند موردی و ابزار تحلیلی نگاشت شناختی است که الگوی اثر سیاست‌های تنظیمی را در سه سطح اهداف سیاستی پنجگانه (گسترش بازار، افزایش دسترسی‌پذیری، ارتقای کیفیت، انگیزش تحقیق و توسعه و ارتقای زنجیره تولید)، خردبنیان‌های توانمندی نوآوری (هوش نوآوری، تصمیم‌گیری، ترکیب و راهبری) و عملکرد نوآورانه (محصول و فرآیند) ترسیم کرده است. همچنین با استفاده از تحلیل حساسیت اثرات ذیل 26 سناریو، چگونگی تغییرات سه سطح مولفه مورد توجه قرار گرفته‌اند. نتایج نشان می‌دهد هر چند اعمال این سیاست‌ها بر اهداف سیاستی گسترش بازار دارویی، دسترس‌پذیری و ارتقای زنجیره تولید دارویی کشور و همچنین بر نوآوری فرآیند مفید بوده و توانسته الگوهایی را در هوش نوآوری و راهبری شرکت‌ها ایجاد نماید اما اثر منفی آنها بر کیفیت دارو و انگیزش تحقیق و توسعه و همچنین نوآوری محصول و خردبنیان ترکیب قابل توجه است.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>سیاستهای تنظیمی</kwd>
						<kwd>ارزیابی مداخلات سیاستی</kwd>
						<kwd>ابزارهای سیاستی</kwd>
						<kwd>توانمندی نوآوری</kwd>
						<kwd>خردبنیان</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Achilladelis, B. &amp; Antonakis, N. 2001. The dynamics of technological innovation: the case of the pharmaceutical industry. Research Policy, 30(4), pp. 535-588.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Adler, P.S. &amp; Shenbar, A. 1990. Adapting your technological base: the organizational challenge. Sloan Management Review, 32(1), pp.25-37.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Aerts, K. &amp; Schmidt, T. 2008. Two for the price of one?: Additionality effects of R&amp;D subsidies: A comparison between Flanders and Germany. Research policy, 37(5), pp. 806-822.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Afcha Chávez, S.M. 2011. Behavioural additionality in the context of regional innovation policy in Spain. Innovation, 13(1), pp. 95-110.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Ambrosini, V. &amp; Bowman, C. 2009. What are dynamic capabilities and are they a useful construct in strategic management? International Journal of Management Reviews, 11(1), pp.29-49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Arora, A., Gambardella, A., Magazzini, L. &amp; Pammolli, F. 2009. A breath of fresh air? Firm type, scale, scope, and selection effects in drug development. Management Science, 55(10), pp. 1638-1653.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Arrow, K. 1962. Economic welfare and the allocation of resources for invention. The rate and direction of inventive activity: Economic and social factors. Princeton University Press. pp. 609-626.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Ashford, N.A. &amp; Heaton, G.R. 1983. Regulation and technological innovation in the chemical industry. Law and Contemporary Problems, 46(3), pp. 109-157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Autio, E., Kanninen, S. &amp; Gustafsson, R. 2008. First-and second-order additionality and learning outcomes in collaborative R&amp;D programs. Research Policy, 37(1), pp. 59-76.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Barney, J. &amp; Felin, T. 2013. What are microfoundations? The Academy of Management Perspectives, 27(2), pp. 138-155.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Barouni, M., Ghaderi, H. &amp; Banouei, A. 2012. Pharmaceutical Industry and Trade Liberalization Using Computable General Equilibrium Model. Iranian Journal of Public Health, 41(12), pp. 66.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Basmenji, K. 2004. Pharmaceuticals in Iran: An Overview. Arch Iranian Med, 7(2), pp. 158-164.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Biernacki, P. &amp; Waldorf, D. 1981. Snowball sampling: Problems and techniques of chain referral sampling. Sociological Methods &amp; Research, 10(2), pp. 141-163.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Blind, K. 2010. The Use of the Regulatory Framework for Innovation Policy. In R. E. Smits, S. Kuhlmann &amp; P. Shapira eds. The theory and practice of innovation policy: An international research handbook. Edward Elgar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Blind, K., Buhrelen, B., Menrad, K., Hafner, S., Walz, R. &amp; Kotz, C., 2004. New Products and Services: Analysis of Regulations Shaping New Markets: Study Funded by the European Commission, DG Enterprise/Innovation Policy Unit, in the Framework of the Innovation/SMEs Programme, Part of the Fifth Research Framework Programme.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Blume-Kohout, M.E. &amp; Sood, N. 2013. Market size and innovation: Effects of Medicare Part D on pharmaceutical research and development. Journal of Public Economics, Volume (97), pp. 327-336.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Boeing, P. 2014. China’s R&amp;D Subsidies-Allocation and Effectiveness. ZEW-Centre for European Economic Research Discussion Paper(14-103).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Börjesson, S., Elmquist, M. &amp; Hooge, S. 2014. The challenges of innovation capability building: Learning from longitudinal studies of innovation efforts at Renault and Volvo Cars. Journal of Engineering and Technology Management, Volume (31), pp. 120-140.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Borrás, S. &amp; Edquist, C. 2013. Competence Building: A Systemic Approach to Innovation Policy. Lund University, CIRCLE-Center for Innovation, Research and Competences in the Learning Economy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Bowman, C. &amp; Ambrosini, V. 2003. How the resource-based and the dynamic capability views of the firm inform corporate-level strategy. British Journal of Management,14(4), pp. 289-303.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Bruni, D.S. &amp; Verona, G. 2009. Dynamic marketing capabilities in Science-based firms: An exploratory investigation of the pharmaceutical industry. British Journal of Management, 20(1), pp. 101-117.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Buisseret, T.J., Cameron, H.M. &amp; Georghiou, L. 1995. What difference does it make? Additionality in the public support of R&amp;D in large firms. International Journal of Technology Management,10(4), pp. 587-600.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Busom, I., Corchuelo, B. &amp; Martínez-Ros, E. 2014. Tax incentives or subsidies for business R&amp;D? Small Business Economics, 43(3), pp. 571-596.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, H.-h. 2003. Comparative Analysis and Benchmarking: Corporate Strategy Analysis of Four International Pharmaceutical Companies: Universal-Publishers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Cheraghali, A., Nikfar, S., Behmanesh, Y., Rahimi, V., Habibipour, F., Tirdad, R., Asadi, A. &amp; Bahrami, A.,. 2004. Evaluation of availability, accessibility and prescribing pattern of medicines in the Islamic Republic of Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Cheraghali, A.M. 2006. Iran pharmaceutical market. Iranian Journal of Pharmaceutical Research, Volume(1), pp.1-7.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Choi, J.Y., Lee, J.H. &amp; Sohn, S.Y. 2009. Impact analysis for national R&amp;D funding in science and technology using quantification method II. Research Policy, 38(10), pp. 1534-1544.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Christensen, J.F. 1995. Asset profiles for technological innovation. Research Policy, 24(5), pp.727-745.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Clarysse, B., Wright, M. &amp; Mustar, P. 2009. Behavioural additionality of R&amp;D subsidies: A learning perspective. Research policy, 38(10), pp. 1517-1533.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Cohen, W.M. &amp; Levinthal, D.A. 1990. Absorptive capacity: a new perspective on learning and innovation. Administrative Science Quarterly, 35(1), pp. 128-152.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Crafts, N. 2006. Regulation and productivity performance. Oxford Review of Economic Policy, 22(2), pp. 186-202.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Creswell, J.W. &amp; Clark, V.L.P. 2007. Designing and conducting mixed methods research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Czarnitzki, D., Ebersberger, B. &amp; Fier, A. 2007. The relationship between R&amp;D collaboration, subsidies and R&amp;D performance: empirical evidence from Finland and Germany. Journal of Applied Econometrics, 22(7), pp. 1347-1366.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Czarnitzki, D. &amp; Licht, G. 2006. Additionality of public R&amp;D grants in a transition economy. Economics of Transition, 14(1), pp. 101-131.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Dai, X. &amp; Cheng, L. 2015. The effect of public subsidies on corporate R&amp;D investment: An application of the generalized propensity score. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Volume (90), pp. 410-419.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Davari, M., Walley, T. &amp; Haycox, A. 2011. Pharmaceutical Policy and Market in Iran: Past Experiences and Future Challenges. Journal of Pharmaceutical Health Services Research, 2(1), pp. 47-52.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Davenport, S., Grimes, C. &amp; Davies, J. 1998. Research collaboration and behavioural additionality: a New Zealand case study. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 10(1), pp. 55-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Davit, B.M. et al. 2009. Comparing generic and innovator drugs: a review of 12 years of bioequivalence data from the United States Food and Drug Administration. Annals of Pharmacotherapy, 43(10), pp. 1583-1597.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>DiMasi, J.A., Hansen, R.W., Grabowski, H.G. &amp; Lasagna, L. 1991. Cost of innovation in the pharmaceutical industry. Journal of Health Economics, 10(2), pp.107-142.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Dinarvand, R. 2009. New national drug policy in Iran leading to expanded pharmaceutical market and extended access of public to medicines. Iranian J Publ Health, 38(1), pp. 158-161.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Dixon, S., Meyer, K. &amp; Day, M. 2014. Building dynamic capabilities of adaptation and innovation: a study of micro-foundations in a transition economy. Long Range Planning, 47(4), pp. 186-205.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Dolfsma, W. &amp; Seo, D. 2013. Government Policy and Technological Innovation—A Suggested Typology. Technovation, 33(6), pp. 173-179.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Dubois, P., de Mouzon, O., Scott‐Morton, F. &amp; Seabright, P. 2015. Market size and pharmaceutical innovation. The RAND Journal of Economics, 46(4), pp. 844-871.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Duguet, E. 2003. Are R&amp;D subsidies a substitute or a complement to privately funded R&amp;D? Evidence from France using propensity score methods for non-experimental data. Evidence from France using Propensity Score Methods for Non-Experimental Data (July 2003). University of Paris I Cahier de la MSE EUREQua Working Paper(2003.75).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Eden, C. 2004. Analyzing cognitive maps to help structure issues or problems. European Journal of Operational Research, 159(3), pp. 673-686.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. &amp; Georghiou, L. 2007. Public Procurement and Innovation—Resurrecting the Demand Side. Research Policy, 36(7), pp. 949-963.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Eger, S. &amp; Mahlich, J.C. 2014. Pharmaceutical regulation in Europe and its impact on corporate R&amp;D. Health Economics Review, 4(1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K.M. &amp; Martin, J.A. 2000. Dynamic capabilities: what are they? Strategic Management Journal, 21(10-11), pp. 1105-1121.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Elsenhardt, K.M. &amp; Martin, J.A. 2000. Dynamic capabilities: What are they. Strategic Management Journal , 21(1), pp. 1105-1121.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Falk, R. 2007. Measuring the effects of public support schemes on firms’ innovation activities: Survey evidence from Austria. Research Policy, 36(5), pp.665-679.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Felin, T., Foss, N.J., Heimeriks, K.H. &amp; Madsen, T.L. 2012. Microfoundations of routines and capabilities: Individuals, processes, and structure. Journal of Management Studies, 49(8), pp. 1351-1374.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Francis, J.G. 1993. The politics of regulation: a comparative perspective: Cambridge Univ Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Galunic, D.C. &amp; Eisenhardt, K.M. 2001. Architectural innovation and modular corporate forms. Academy of Management Journal, 44(6), pp. 1229-1249.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Gao, C. 2014. The effect of American industry deregulation on firm innovation behaviors: a difference in differences approach. University of Delaware.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Georghiou, L. 1994. Impact of the framework programme on European industry: European Commission, Directorate General Telecommunications, Information Market and Exploitation of Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Georghiou, L. 2002. Impact and additionality of innovation policy. IWT Studies, Volume (40), pp.57-64.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Georghiou, L. 2006. Effective innovation policies for Europe—The missing demand-side. Economic Council of Finland.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Georghiou, L. &amp; Clarysse, B. 2006. Introduction and synthesis. In OECD ed. Government R&amp;D Funding and Company Behaviour: Measuring Behavioural Additionality. Paris, Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development. pp. 9-38.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Georghiou, L. &amp; Office., C. 1993. The impact of European Community policies for research and technological development upon science and technology in the United Kingdom: a report prepared for DGXII of the Commission of the European Communities and the UK Office of Science &amp; Technology.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Giaccotto, C., Santerre, R. &amp; Vernon, J. 2005. Drug Prices And R&amp;D Investment Behavior In The Pharmaceutical Industry. The Journal Of Law &amp; Economics, 48(1), pp. 195-214.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Gök, A. 2010. An evolutionary approach to innovation policy evaluation: Behavioural additionality and organisational routines. Manchester Business School.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Golec, J. &amp; Vernon, J.A. 2010. Financial effects of pharmaceutical price regulation on R&amp;D spending by EU versus US firms. Pharmacoeconomics, 28(8), pp. 615-628.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>González, X. &amp; Pazó, C. 2008. Do Public Subsidies Stimulate Private R&amp;D Spending? Research Policy, 37(3), pp. 371-389.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Görg, H. &amp; Strobl, E. 2007. The effect of R&amp;D subsidies on private R&amp;D. Economica, 74(294), pp. 215-234.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Gray, S.A., Gray, S., Cox, L.J. &amp; Henly-Shepard, S. 2013. Mental modeler: a fuzzy-logic cognitive mapping modeling tool for adaptive environmental management. System Sciences (HICSS), 2013 46th Hawaii International Conference on, IEEE.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Guan, J. &amp; Ma, N. 2003. Innovative capability and export performance of Chinese firms. Technovation, 23(9), pp. 737-747.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Guan, J. &amp; Yam, R.C. 2015. Effects of government financial incentives on firms’ innovation performance in China: Evidences from Beijing in the 1990s. Research Policy, 44(1), pp. 273-282.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Haas, J.S., Phillips, K.A., Gerstenberger, E.P. &amp; Seger, A.C. 2005. Potential savings from substituting generic drugs for brand-name drugs: medical expenditure panel survey, 1997–2000. Annals of Internal Medicine, 142(11), pp. 891-897.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Hassali, M.A. et al. 2009. Consumers’ views on generic medicines: a review of the literature. International Journal of Pharmacy Practice, 17(2), pp. 79-88.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Helfat, C. &amp; Peteraf, M. 2009. Understanding dynamic capabilities: progress along a developmental path. Strategic Organization, 7(1), pp. 91.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Helfat, C.E. et al. 2007. Dynamic capabilities: Understanding strategic change in organizations: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Helfat, C.E. &amp; Peteraf, M.A. 2015. Managerial cognitive capabilities and the microfoundations of dynamic capabilities. Strategic Management Journal, 36(6), pp. 831-850.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Henly-Shepard, S., Gray, S.A. &amp; Cox, L.J. 2015. The use of participatory modeling to promote social learning and facilitate community disaster planning. Environmental Science &amp; Policy, Volume (45), pp. 109-122.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Heshmati, A. &amp; Loof, H. 2005. The impact of public funds on private R&amp;D investment: New evidence from a firm level innovation study.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Hotho, J.J., Becker-Ritterspach, F. &amp; Saka-Helmhout, A. 2012. Enriching absorptive capacity through social interaction. British Journal of Management, 23(3), pp. 383-401.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Hsu, F.-M., Horng, D.-J. &amp; Hsueh, C.-C. 2009. The effect of government-sponsored R&amp;D programmes on additionality in recipient firms in Taiwan. Technovation, 29(3), pp. 204-217.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Huff, A.S. 1990. Mapping strategic thought: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Hussinger, K. 2008. R&amp;D and subsidies at the firm level: An application of parametric and semiparametric two-step selection models. Journal of Applied Econometrics, 23(6), pp. 729-747.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Hyvärinen, J. &amp; Rautiainen, A.-M. 2007. Measuring additionality and systemic impacts of public research and development funding—the case of TEKES, Finland. Research Evaluation, 16(3), pp. 205-215.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Kale, D. &amp; Little, S. 2007. From imitation to innovation: The evolution of R&amp;D capabilities and learning processes in the Indian pharmaceutical industry. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 19(5), pp. 589-609.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Katz, A. 2007. Pharmaceutical lemons: innovation and regulation in the drug industry. Michigan Telecommunications and Technology Law Review, 14(1), pp. 1-41.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Kebriaeezadeh, A. et al. 2013. Trend analysis of the pharmaceutical market in Iran; 1997–2010; policy implications for developing countries. DARU journal of pharmaceutical Sciences, 21(1), pp. 52.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Kelly, G. 1955. Personal construct psychology. New York: Norton.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Kemp, R. &amp; Pontoglio, S. 2011. The innovation effects of environmental policy instruments-A typical case of the blind men and the elephant? Ecological Economics, Volume (72), pp. 28-36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Knockaert, M., Spithoven, A. &amp; Clarysse, B. 2014. The impact of technology intermediaries on firm cognitive capacity additionality. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Volume (81), pp. 376-387.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Kobayashi, Y. 2014. Effect of R&amp;D tax credits for SMEs in Japan: A Microeconometric Analysis Focused on Liquidity Constraints. Small Business Economics, 42(2), pp. 311-327.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Koch, T. 2006. Establishing rigour in qualitative research: the decision trail. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 53(1), pp. 91-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Koenig, P. &amp; MacGarvie, M. 2011. Regulatory policy and the location of bio-pharmaceutical foreign direct investment in Europe. Journal of Health Economics, 30(5), pp. 950-965.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Lach, S. 2002. Do R&amp;D subsidies stimulate or displace private R&amp;D? Evidence from Israel. The Journal of Industrial Economics, 50(4), pp. 369-390.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Langfield-Smith, K. &amp; Wirth, A. 1992. Measuring differences between cognitive maps. Journal of the Operational Research Society, 43(12), pp.1135-1150.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Lerner, J. 2000. The government as venture capitalist: the long-run impact of the SBIR program. The Journal of Private Equity, 3(2), pp. 55-78.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Lööf, H. &amp; Heshmati, A. 2005. The impact of public funds on private R&amp;D investment: New evidence from a firm level innovation study. MTT Discussion Papers, Volume (3), pp. 1-26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Luukkonen, T. 1998. The difficulties in assessing the impact of EU framework programmes. Research Policy, 27(6), pp. 599-610.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Mahoney, R. 2007. Building Product Innovation Capability in Health. In A. Krattiger et al. eds. Intellectual property management in health and agricultural innovation: a handbook of best practices. UK, Oxford.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Majone, G. 1996: Regulating Europe. London: Routledge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Markoczy, L. &amp; Goldberg, J. 1995. A method for eliciting and comparing causal maps. Journal of Management, 21(2), pp. 305-333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Metcalfe, J.S., Georghiou, L., Cunningham, P. &amp; Cameron, H.M. 1992. Evaluation of the impact of European Community research programmes upon the competitiveness of European industry-Concepts and approaches. EUR 14198 EN. Research evaluation. Science and Technology Policy Series.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Montibeller, G. &amp; Belton, V. 2006. Causal maps and the evaluation of decision options -a review. Journal of the Operational Research Society, 57(7), pp. 779-791.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Nadkarni, S. &amp; Nah, F.F.-H. 2003. Aggregated causal maps: An approach to elicit and aggregate the knowledge of multiple experts. Communications of the Association for Information Systems, 12(1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson, R.R. &amp; Winter, S. 1982. An evolutionary theory of economic change. Cambridge: Belknap.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Niosi, J. 2002. National systems of innovations are “x-efficient”(and x-effective): Why some are slow learners. Research Policy, 31(2), pp. 291-302.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>O’Connor, G.C. 2008. Major innovation as a dynamic capability: A systems approach. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 25(4), pp. 313-330.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Onishi, K. &amp; Nagata, A. 2010. Does Tax Credit for R&amp;D Induce Additional R&amp;D Investment?: Analysis on the effects of gross R&amp;D credit in Japan. Journal of Science Policy and Research Management, Volume (24), pp. 400-412.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Pammolli, F., Magazzini, L. &amp; Riccaboni, M. 2011. The productivity crisis in pharmaceutical R&amp;D. Nature reviews. Drug discovery, 10(6).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Paraskevopoulou, E. 2012. Non-technological regulatory effects: Implications for innovation and innovation policy. Research Policy, 41(6), pp. 1058-1071.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Porter 1991. America’s green strategy. Scientific American, 264(4).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Porter, M. &amp; Van der Linde, C. 1995. Toward a new conception of the environment-competitiveness relationship. The Journal of Economic Perspectives, 9(4), pp. 97-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Radas, S., Anić, I.-D., Tafro, A. &amp; Wagner, V., 2015. The effects of public support schemes on small and medium enterprises. Technovation, Volume (38), pp. 15-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Ramos Perez, C. 2016. Designing a behavioural additionality evaluation methodology for the Knowledge Transfer Partnerships Scheme employing case-based methods and theory-based evaluation approaches. University of Manchester.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Rasekh, H.R., Mehralian, G. &amp; Vatankhah-Mohammadabadi, A.A. 2012. Situation analysis of R &amp; D activities: an empirical study in Iranian pharmaceutical companies. Iranian Journal of Pharmaceutical Research, 1(4), pp. 1013-1025.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>Ratanawijitrasin, S. 2007. Drug Regulation and Incentives for Innovation: The Case of ASEAN. WHO. Available at: www. who. int/intellectualproperty/studies/Drugregulationincentives. pdf.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>Reinkowski, J., Mitze, T., Alecke, B. &amp; Untiedt, G. 2010. R&amp;D Subsidies and Private Sector Innovativeness: New Empirical Evidence for East German Firms.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Riege, A.M. 2003. Validity and reliability tests in case study research: a literature review with “hands-on” applications for each research phase. Qualitative Market Research: An International Journal, 6(2), pp. 75-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>Rodhain, F. 1999. Tacit to explicit: transforming knowledge through cognitive mapping—an experiment. Proceedings of the 1999 ACM SIGCPR conference on Computer personnel research, ACM.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R115">
			<label>115</label>
			<element-citation>Assessment of the public tools used to promote R&amp;D investment in Spanish SMEs. Small Business Economics, 43(4), pp. 959-976.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R116">
			<label>116</label>
			<element-citation>Romero-Jordán, D., Delgado-Rodríguez, M.J., Álvarez-Ayuso, I. &amp; de Lucas-Santos, S. 2014. Assessment of the public tools used to promote R&amp;D investment in Spanish SMEs. Small Business Economics, 43(4), pp. 959-976.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R117">
			<label>117</label>
			<element-citation>Santerre, C.G.R.E. &amp; Vernon, J.A. 2004. Drug Prices and R&amp;D Investment Behavior in the Pharmaceutical Industry.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R118">
			<label>118</label>
			<element-citation>Seyedifar, M. et al. 2015. An evaluation of policies and procedures of successful pharmaceutical exporters and the comparison of Iranian counterpart policy. Journal of Pharmacoeconomics and Pharmaceutical Management, 1(3/4), pp. 39-44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R119">
			<label>119</label>
			<element-citation>Shabaninejad, H. et al. 2014. Identifying and prioritizing industry-level competitiveness factors: evidence from pharmaceutical market. DARU journal of pharmaceutical Sciences, 22(1), pp. 35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R120">
			<label>120</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, K. 2000. Innovation as a systemic phenomenon: rethinking the role of policy. Enterprise and innovation management studies, 1(1), pp. 73-102.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R121">
			<label>121</label>
			<element-citation>Soete, L. et al. 2002. Benchmarking National Research Policies: The Impact of RTD on Competitiveness and Employ ment (IRCE). Strata-ETAN Expert Working Group, European Commission DG Research, Brussels.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R122">
			<label>122</label>
			<element-citation>Stewart, L.A. 2010. The Impact of Regulation on Innovation in the United States: A Cross-Industry Literature Review. USA, Information Technology &amp; Innovation Foundation.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R123">
			<label>123</label>
			<element-citation>Strauss, K., Lepoutre, J. &amp; Wood, G. 2017. Fifty shades of green: How microfoundations of sustainability dynamic capabilities vary across organizational contexts. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 38(9).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R124">
			<label>124</label>
			<element-citation>Teece, D. &amp; Pisano, G. 1994. The dynamic capabilities of firms: an introduction. Industrial and Corporate change, 3(3), pp. 537-556.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R125">
			<label>125</label>
			<element-citation>Teece, D.J. 2007. Explicating dynamic capabilities: the nature and microfoundations of (sustainable) enterprise performance. Strategic Management Journal, 28(13), pp. 1319-1350.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R126">
			<label>126</label>
			<element-citation>Teece, D.J. 2012. Dynamic capabilities: Routines versus entrepreneurial action. Journal of Management Studies, 49(8), pp.1395-1401.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R127">
			<label>127</label>
			<element-citation>Teece, D.J. 2017. Towards a capability theory of (innovating) firms: implications for management and policy. Cambridge Journal of Economics, 41(3), pp. 693-720.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R128">
			<label>128</label>
			<element-citation>Teece, D.J., Pisano, G. &amp; Shuen, A. 1997. Dynamic capabilities and strategic management. Strategic Management Journal, Volume(18), pp. 509-533.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R129">
			<label>129</label>
			<element-citation>Tran, T.A. &amp; Daim, T. 2008. A taxonomic review of methods and tools applied in technology assessment. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 75(9), pp. 1396-1405.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R130">
			<label>130</label>
			<element-citation>Van Den Ende, J. et al. 1998. Traditional and modern technology assessment: toward a toolkit. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 58(1), pp. 5-21.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R131">
			<label>131</label>
			<element-citation>Vernon, J.A. 2005. Examining the link between price regulation and pharmaceutical R&amp;D investment. Health Economics, 14(1), pp. 1-16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R132">
			<label>132</label>
			<element-citation>Wallsten, S.J. 2000. The effects of government-industry R&amp;D programs on private R&amp;D: the case of the Small Business Innovation Research program. The RAND Journal of Economics, 31(1), pp.82-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R133">
			<label>133</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, C.L. &amp; Ahmed, P.K. 2007. Dynamic capabilities: A review and research agenda. International Journal of Management Reviews, 9(1), pp. 31-51.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R134">
			<label>134</label>
			<element-citation>Weber, K.M. &amp; Rohracher, H. 2012. Legitimizing research, technology and innovation policies for transformative change: Combining insights from innovation systems and multi-level perspective in a comprehensive ‘failures’ framework. Research Policy, 41(6), pp. 1037-1047.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R135">
			<label>135</label>
			<element-citation>Winter, S.G. 2003. Understanding dynamic capabilities. Strategic Management Journal, 24(10), pp. 991-995.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R136">
			<label>136</label>
			<element-citation>Woolthuis, R.K., Lankhuizen, M. &amp; Gilsing, V. 2005. A system failure framework for innovation policy design. Technovation, 25(6), pp. 609-619.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R137">
			<label>137</label>
			<element-citation>Yang, C.-H., Huang, C.-H. &amp; Hou, T.C.-T. 2012. Tax incentives and R&amp;D activity: Firm-level evidence from Taiwan. Research Policy, 41(9), pp. 1578-1588.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R138">
			<label>138</label>
			<element-citation>Zaboli, P. et al. 2016. Pharmaceutical laws and regulations in Iran: An overview. Journal of Research in Pharmacy Practice, 5(3), pp. 155.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R139">
			<label>139</label>
			<element-citation>Zahra, S.A. &amp; George, G. 2002. Absorptive capacity: A review, reconceptualization, and extension. Academy of Management Review, 27(2), pp. 185-203.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R140">
			<label>140</label>
			<element-citation>Zahra, S.A., Sapienza, H.J. &amp; Davidsson, P. 2006. Entrepreneurship and Dynamic Capabilities: A Review, Model and Research Agenda. Journal of Management Studies, 43(4), pp. 917-955.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R141">
			<label>141</label>
			<element-citation>Zollo, M. &amp; Winter, S.G. 2002. Deliberate learning and the evolution of dynamic capabilities. Organization Science, 13(3), pp.339-351.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R142">
			<label>142</label>
			<element-citation> آذر، عادل و حسن زاده کریم آبادی، حمید رضا،1381، نگاشت مفهومی و کارکردهای مدیریتی آن  چشم انداز مدیریت بازرگانی، تابستان و پاییز، شماره 3 و 4، صص. 77-104.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R143">
			<label>143</label>
			<element-citation>دانائی‌فرد حسن،1386. پارادایم‌های رقیب در علم سازمان و مـدیـریـت: رویـکـرد تـطبـیقـی به هستـی‌شنـاسی، شنـاخت‌شنـاسی و روش‌شناسی. راهبردهای بازرگانی-دانشور رفتار سابق؛ ۱ (۲۶)،صص. ۸۹-۱۰۴</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R144">
			<label>144</label>
			<element-citation>رمضانی، ابوالفضل و  میرزامحمدی، علی،1392. تحلیل شبکه‌های اجتماعی. ایران: تهران: انتشارات جامعه شناسان.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R145">
			<label>145</label>
			<element-citation>سازمان غذا و دارو،1394.آیین‌نامه‌های و مقررات.:</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R146">
			<label>146</label>
			<element-citation>سلطان‌زاده، جواد، الیاسی، مهدی، بامداد صوفی، جهانیار و کزازی، ابوالفضل،1396. «شناسایی خردبنیان‌های توانمندی نوآوری شرکت‌های تولید داروی کشور: مطالعه چند موردی». فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی بهبود مدیریت. سال یازدهم، شمار 1، پیاپی 35،صص. 206-163.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R147">
			<label>147</label>
			<element-citation>صفری، حسین، حشمتی پور، فاطمه، مهرابی، علی و نصابی، وحیدرضا،1391. مدلسازی عوامل مؤثر بر به‌اشتراک‌گذاری اطلاعات در زنجیره تأمین شرکت ایران خودرو خراسان با استفاده از روش ترکیبی نگاشت علّی و شبکه‌های بیزین. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، 4(10)، صص. 65-92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R148">
			<label>148</label>
			<element-citation>صارمی، محمود، حسینی، سید محمود، محقر، علی و  حیدری، علی، 1388. مدل‌سازی کیفی مزیت رقابتی در صنایع مبتنی بر فن‌آوری‌های پیشرفته. نشریه مدیریت صنعتی، 1(3)، صص. 53-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R149">
			<label>149</label>
			<element-citation>ضرغامی فرد، مژگان و آذر، عادل،1394. تحلیلی بر شیوه نگاشت شناختی در ساختار بندی داده‌های کیفی مطالعات سازمانی. مطالعات رفتار سازمانی، 3(1 ، 2 (پیاپی 8 و 9))، صص. 185-159.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R150">
			<label>150</label>
			<element-citation>کارگر شهامت بهمن، تقوا محمدرضا، طباطبائیان سید حبیب اله، صالحی صدقیانی جمشید، الزامات شکل گیری شبکه نوآوری تحلیلی از قاعده بنگاه‌داری در بخش دارویی ایران، بهبود مدیریت، سال دهم، شماره 34، صص.  94-49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R151">
			<label>151</label>
			<element-citation>مدنی، حسام‌الدین، شاه‌حسینی، محمد حسن و خمسه، عباس،1390. تأثیر طرح ژنریک بر توسعه توانمندی‌های فناوری. مجله پژوهشی حکیم، (1) 14، صص. 31-23.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R152">
			<label>152</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R153">
			<label>153</label>
			<element-citation>Achilladelis, B. &amp; Antonakis, N. 2001. The dynamics of technological innovation: the case of the pharmaceutical industry. Research Policy, 30(4), pp. 535-588.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R154">
			<label>154</label>
			<element-citation>Adler, P.S. &amp; Shenbar, A. 1990. Adapting your technological base: the organizational challenge. Sloan Management Review, 32(1), pp.25-37.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R155">
			<label>155</label>
			<element-citation>Aerts, K. &amp; Schmidt, T. 2008. Two for the price of one?: Additionality effects of R&amp;D subsidies: A comparison between Flanders and Germany. Research policy, 37(5), pp. 806-822.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R156">
			<label>156</label>
			<element-citation>Afcha Chávez, S.M. 2011. Behavioural additionality in the context of regional innovation policy in Spain. Innovation, 13(1), pp. 95-110.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R157">
			<label>157</label>
			<element-citation>Ambrosini, V. &amp; Bowman, C. 2009. What are dynamic capabilities and are they a useful construct in strategic management? International Journal of Management Reviews, 11(1), pp.29-49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R158">
			<label>158</label>
			<element-citation>Arora, A., Gambardella, A., Magazzini, L. &amp; Pammolli, F. 2009. A breath of fresh air? Firm type, scale, scope, and selection effects in drug development. Management Science, 55(10), pp. 1638-1653.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R159">
			<label>159</label>
			<element-citation>Arrow, K. 1962. Economic welfare and the allocation of resources for invention. The rate and direction of inventive activity: Economic and social factors. Princeton University Press. pp. 609-626.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R160">
			<label>160</label>
			<element-citation>Ashford, N.A. &amp; Heaton, G.R. 1983. Regulation and technological innovation in the chemical industry. Law and Contemporary Problems, 46(3), pp. 109-157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R161">
			<label>161</label>
			<element-citation>Autio, E., Kanninen, S. &amp; Gustafsson, R. 2008. First-and second-order additionality and learning outcomes in collaborative R&amp;D programs. Research Policy, 37(1), pp. 59-76.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R162">
			<label>162</label>
			<element-citation>Azar, A. &amp; Hasanzadeh Karimabadi, H., 2002. Conceptual mapping and its management functions. Journal of  Business Management,1(3-4), pp. 77-104.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R163">
			<label>163</label>
			<element-citation>Barney, J. &amp; Felin, T. 2013. What are microfoundations? The Academy of Management Perspectives, 27(2), pp. 138-155.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R164">
			<label>164</label>
			<element-citation>Barouni, M., Ghaderi, H. &amp; Banouei, A. 2012. Pharmaceutical Industry and Trade Liberalization Using Computable General Equilibrium Model. Iranian Journal of Public Health, 41(12), pp. 66.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R165">
			<label>165</label>
			<element-citation>Basmenji, K. 2004. Pharmaceuticals in Iran: An Overview. Arch Iranian Med, 7(2), pp. 158-164.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R166">
			<label>166</label>
			<element-citation>Biernacki, P. &amp; Waldorf, D. 1981. Snowball sampling: Problems and techniques of chain referral sampling. Sociological Methods &amp; Research, 10(2), pp. 141-163.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R167">
			<label>167</label>
			<element-citation>Blind, K. 2010. The Use of the Regulatory Framework for Innovation Policy. In R. E. Smits, S. Kuhlmann &amp; P. Shapira eds. The theory and practice of innovation policy: An international research handbook. Edward Elgar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R168">
			<label>168</label>
			<element-citation>Blind, K., Buhrelen, B., Menrad, K., Hafner, S., Walz, R. &amp; Kotz, C., 2004. New Products and Services: Analysis of Regulations Shaping New Markets: Study Funded by the European Commission, DG Enterprise/Innovation Policy Unit, in the Framework of the Innovation/SMEs Programme, Part of the Fifth Research Framework Programme.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R169">
			<label>169</label>
			<element-citation>Blume-Kohout, M.E. &amp; Sood, N. 2013. Market size and innovation: Effects of Medicare Part D on pharmaceutical research and development. Journal of Public Economics, Volume (97), pp. 327-336.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R170">
			<label>170</label>
			<element-citation>Boeing, P. 2014. China’s R&amp;D Subsidies-Allocation and Effectiveness. ZEW-Centre for European Economic Research Discussion Paper(14-103).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R171">
			<label>171</label>
			<element-citation>Börjesson, S., Elmquist, M. &amp; Hooge, S. 2014. The challenges of innovation capability building: Learning from longitudinal studies of innovation efforts at Renault and Volvo Cars. Journal of Engineering and Technology Management, Volume (31), pp. 120-140.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R172">
			<label>172</label>
			<element-citation>Borrás, S. &amp; Edquist, C. 2013. Competence Building: A Systemic Approach to Innovation Policy. Lund University, CIRCLE-Center for Innovation, Research and Competences in the Learning Economy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R173">
			<label>173</label>
			<element-citation>Bowman, C. &amp; Ambrosini, V. 2003. How the resource-based and the dynamic capability views of the firm inform corporate-level strategy. British Journal of Management,14(4), pp. 289-303.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R174">
			<label>174</label>
			<element-citation>Bruni, D.S. &amp; Verona, G. 2009. Dynamic marketing capabilities in Science-based firms: An exploratory investigation of the pharmaceutical industry. British Journal of Management, 20(1), pp. 101-117.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R175">
			<label>175</label>
			<element-citation>Buisseret, T.J., Cameron, H.M. &amp; Georghiou, L. 1995. What difference does it make? Additionality in the public support of R&amp;D in large firms. International Journal of Technology Management,10(4), pp. 587-600.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R176">
			<label>176</label>
			<element-citation>Busom, I., Corchuelo, B. &amp; Martínez-Ros, E. 2014. Tax incentives or subsidies for business R&amp;D? Small Business Economics, 43(3), pp. 571-596.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R177">
			<label>177</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, H.-h. 2003. Comparative Analysis and Benchmarking: Corporate Strategy Analysis of Four International Pharmaceutical Companies: Universal-Publishers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R178">
			<label>178</label>
			<element-citation>Cheraghali, A., Nikfar, S., Behmanesh, Y., Rahimi, V., Habibipour, F., Tirdad, R., Asadi, A. &amp; Bahrami, A.,. 2004. Evaluation of availability, accessibility and prescribing pattern of medicines in the Islamic Republic of Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R179">
			<label>179</label>
			<element-citation>Cheraghali, A.M. 2006. Iran pharmaceutical market. Iranian Journal of Pharmaceutical Research, Volume(1), pp.1-7.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R180">
			<label>180</label>
			<element-citation>Choi, J.Y., Lee, J.H. &amp; Sohn, S.Y. 2009. Impact analysis for national R&amp;D funding in science and technology using quantification method II. Research Policy, 38(10), pp. 1534-1544.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R181">
			<label>181</label>
			<element-citation>Christensen, J.F. 1995. Asset profiles for technological innovation. Research Policy, 24(5), pp.727-745.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R182">
			<label>182</label>
			<element-citation>Clarysse, B., Wright, M. &amp; Mustar, P. 2009. Behavioural additionality of R&amp;D subsidies: A learning perspective. Research policy, 38(10), pp. 1517-1533.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R183">
			<label>183</label>
			<element-citation>Cohen, W.M. &amp; Levinthal, D.A. 1990. Absorptive capacity: a new perspective on learning and innovation. Administrative Science Quarterly, 35(1), pp. 128-152.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R184">
			<label>184</label>
			<element-citation>Crafts, N. 2006. Regulation and productivity performance. Oxford Review of Economic Policy, 22(2), pp. 186-202.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R185">
			<label>185</label>
			<element-citation>Creswell, J.W. &amp; Clark, V.L.P. 2007. Designing and conducting mixed methods research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R186">
			<label>186</label>
			<element-citation>Czarnitzki, D., Ebersberger, B. &amp; Fier, A. 2007. The relationship between R&amp;D collaboration, subsidies and R&amp;D performance: empirical evidence from Finland and Germany. Journal of Applied Econometrics, 22(7), pp. 1347-1366.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R187">
			<label>187</label>
			<element-citation>Czarnitzki, D. &amp; Licht, G. 2006. Additionality of public R&amp;D grants in a transition economy. Economics of Transition, 14(1), pp. 101-131.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R188">
			<label>188</label>
			<element-citation>Danaei Fard, H., 2008. the Paradigms in the Science of Organization and Management: a Comparative Approach to Ontology, Epistemology and Methodology. Semi-annually Daneshvar Raftar, 1(26), pp. 87-104.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R189">
			<label>189</label>
			<element-citation>Dai, X. &amp; Cheng, L. 2015. The effect of public subsidies on corporate R&amp;D investment: An application of the generalized propensity score. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Volume (90), pp. 410-419.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R190">
			<label>190</label>
			<element-citation>Davari, M., Walley, T. &amp; Haycox, A. 2011. Pharmaceutical Policy and Market in Iran: Past Experiences and Future Challenges. Journal of Pharmaceutical Health Services Research, 2(1), pp. 47-52.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R191">
			<label>191</label>
			<element-citation>Davenport, S., Grimes, C. &amp; Davies, J. 1998. Research collaboration and behavioural additionality: a New Zealand case study. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 10(1), pp. 55-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R192">
			<label>192</label>
			<element-citation>Davit, B.M. et al. 2009. Comparing generic and innovator drugs: a review of 12 years of bioequivalence data from the United States Food and Drug Administration. Annals of Pharmacotherapy, 43(10), pp. 1583-1597.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R193">
			<label>193</label>
			<element-citation>DiMasi, J.A., Hansen, R.W., Grabowski, H.G. &amp; Lasagna, L. 1991. Cost of innovation in the pharmaceutical industry. Journal of Health Economics, 10(2), pp.107-142.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R194">
			<label>194</label>
			<element-citation>Dinarvand, R. 2009. New national drug policy in Iran leading to expanded pharmaceutical market and extended access of public to medicines. Iranian J Publ Health, 38(1), pp. 158-161.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R195">
			<label>195</label>
			<element-citation>Dixon, S., Meyer, K. &amp; Day, M. 2014. Building dynamic capabilities of adaptation and innovation: a study of micro-foundations in a transition economy. Long Range Planning, 47(4), pp. 186-205.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R196">
			<label>196</label>
			<element-citation>Dolfsma, W. &amp; Seo, D. 2013. Government Policy and Technological Innovation—A Suggested Typology. Technovation, 33(6), pp. 173-179.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R197">
			<label>197</label>
			<element-citation>Dubois, P., de Mouzon, O., Scott‐Morton, F. &amp; Seabright, P. 2015. Market size and pharmaceutical innovation. The RAND Journal of Economics, 46(4), pp. 844-871.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R198">
			<label>198</label>
			<element-citation>Duguet, E. 2003. Are R&amp;D subsidies a substitute or a complement to privately funded R&amp;D? Evidence from France using propensity score methods for non-experimental data. Evidence from France using Propensity Score Methods for Non-Experimental Data (July 2003). University of Paris I Cahier de la MSE EUREQua Working Paper(2003.75).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R199">
			<label>199</label>
			<element-citation>Eden, C. 2004. Analyzing cognitive maps to help structure issues or problems. European Journal of Operational Research, 159(3), pp. 673-686.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R200">
			<label>200</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. &amp; Georghiou, L. 2007. Public Procurement and Innovation—Resurrecting the Demand Side. Research Policy, 36(7), pp. 949-963.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R201">
			<label>201</label>
			<element-citation>Eger, S. &amp; Mahlich, J.C. 2014. Pharmaceutical regulation in Europe and its impact on corporate R&amp;D. Health Economics Review, 4(1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R202">
			<label>202</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K.M. &amp; Martin, J.A. 2000. Dynamic capabilities: what are they? Strategic Management Journal, 21(10-11), pp. 1105-1121.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R203">
			<label>203</label>
			<element-citation>Elsenhardt, K.M. &amp; Martin, J.A. 2000. Dynamic capabilities: What are they. Strategic Management Journal , 21(1), pp. 1105-1121.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R204">
			<label>204</label>
			<element-citation>Falk, R. 2007. Measuring the effects of public support schemes on firms’ innovation activities: Survey evidence from Austria. Research Policy, 36(5), pp.665-679.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R205">
			<label>205</label>
			<element-citation>Felin, T., Foss, N.J., Heimeriks, K.H. &amp; Madsen, T.L. 2012. Microfoundations of routines and capabilities: Individuals, processes, and structure. Journal of Management Studies, 49(8), pp. 1351-1374.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R206">
			<label>206</label>
			<element-citation>Francis, J.G. 1993. The politics of regulation: a comparative perspective: Cambridge Univ Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R207">
			<label>207</label>
			<element-citation>Galunic, D.C. &amp; Eisenhardt, K.M. 2001. Architectural innovation and modular corporate forms. Academy of Management Journal, 44(6), pp. 1229-1249.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R208">
			<label>208</label>
			<element-citation>Gao, C. 2014. The effect of American industry deregulation on firm innovation behaviors: a difference in differences approach. University of Delaware.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R209">
			<label>209</label>
			<element-citation>Georghiou, L. 1994. Impact of the framework programme on European industry: European Commission, Directorate General Telecommunications, Information Market and Exploitation of Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R210">
			<label>210</label>
			<element-citation>Georghiou, L. 2002. Impact and additionality of innovation policy. IWT Studies, Volume (40), pp.57-64.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R211">
			<label>211</label>
			<element-citation>Georghiou, L. 2006. Effective innovation policies for Europe—The missing demand-side. Economic Council of Finland.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R212">
			<label>212</label>
			<element-citation>Georghiou, L. &amp; Clarysse, B. 2006. Introduction and synthesis. In OECD ed. Government R&amp;D Funding and Company Behaviour: Measuring Behavioural Additionality. Paris, Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development. pp. 9-38.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R213">
			<label>213</label>
			<element-citation>Georghiou, L. &amp; Office., C. 1993. The impact of European Community policies for research and technological development upon science and technology in the United Kingdom: a report prepared for DGXII of the Commission of the European Communities and the UK Office of Science &amp; Technology.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R214">
			<label>214</label>
			<element-citation>Giaccotto, C., Santerre, R. &amp; Vernon, J. 2005. Drug Prices And R&amp;D Investment Behavior In The Pharmaceutical Industry. The Journal Of Law &amp; Economics, 48(1), pp. 195-214.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R215">
			<label>215</label>
			<element-citation>Gök, A. 2010. An evolutionary approach to innovation policy evaluation: Behavioural additionality and organisational routines. Manchester Business School.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R216">
			<label>216</label>
			<element-citation>Golec, J. &amp; Vernon, J.A. 2010. Financial effects of pharmaceutical price regulation on R&amp;D spending by EU versus US firms. Pharmacoeconomics, 28(8), pp. 615-628.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R217">
			<label>217</label>
			<element-citation>González, X. &amp; Pazó, C. 2008. Do Public Subsidies Stimulate Private R&amp;D Spending? Research Policy, 37(3), pp. 371-389.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R218">
			<label>218</label>
			<element-citation>Görg, H. &amp; Strobl, E. 2007. The effect of R&amp;D subsidies on private R&amp;D. Economica, 74(294), pp. 215-234.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R219">
			<label>219</label>
			<element-citation>Gray, S.A., Gray, S., Cox, L.J. &amp; Henly-Shepard, S. 2013. Mental modeler: a fuzzy-logic cognitive mapping modeling tool for adaptive environmental management. System Sciences (HICSS), 2013 46th Hawaii International Conference on, IEEE.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R220">
			<label>220</label>
			<element-citation>Guan, J. &amp; Ma, N. 2003. Innovative capability and export performance of Chinese firms. Technovation, 23(9), pp. 737-747.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R221">
			<label>221</label>
			<element-citation>Guan, J. &amp; Yam, R.C. 2015. Effects of government financial incentives on firms’ innovation performance in China: Evidences from Beijing in the 1990s. Research Policy, 44(1), pp. 273-282.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R222">
			<label>222</label>
			<element-citation>Haas, J.S., Phillips, K.A., Gerstenberger, E.P. &amp; Seger, A.C. 2005. Potential savings from substituting generic drugs for brand-name drugs: medical expenditure panel survey, 1997–2000. Annals of Internal Medicine, 142(11), pp. 891-897.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R223">
			<label>223</label>
			<element-citation>Hassali, M.A. et al. 2009. Consumers’ views on generic medicines: a review of the literature. International Journal of Pharmacy Practice, 17(2), pp. 79-88.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R224">
			<label>224</label>
			<element-citation>Helfat, C. &amp; Peteraf, M. 2009. Understanding dynamic capabilities: progress along a developmental path. Strategic Organization, 7(1), pp. 91.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R225">
			<label>225</label>
			<element-citation>Helfat, C.E. et al. 2007. Dynamic capabilities: Understanding strategic change in organizations: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R226">
			<label>226</label>
			<element-citation>Helfat, C.E. &amp; Peteraf, M.A. 2015. Managerial cognitive capabilities and the microfoundations of dynamic capabilities. Strategic Management Journal, 36(6), pp. 831-850.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R227">
			<label>227</label>
			<element-citation>Henly-Shepard, S., Gray, S.A. &amp; Cox, L.J. 2015. The use of participatory modeling to promote social learning and facilitate community disaster planning. Environmental Science &amp; Policy, Volume (45), pp. 109-122.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R228">
			<label>228</label>
			<element-citation>Heshmati, A. &amp; Loof, H. 2005. The impact of public funds on private R&amp;D investment: New evidence from a firm level innovation study.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R229">
			<label>229</label>
			<element-citation>Hotho, J.J., Becker-Ritterspach, F. &amp; Saka-Helmhout, A. 2012. Enriching absorptive capacity through social interaction. British Journal of Management, 23(3), pp. 383-401.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R230">
			<label>230</label>
			<element-citation>Hsu, F.-M., Horng, D.-J. &amp; Hsueh, C.-C. 2009. The effect of government-sponsored R&amp;D programmes on additionality in recipient firms in Taiwan. Technovation, 29(3), pp. 204-217.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R231">
			<label>231</label>
			<element-citation>Huff, A.S. 1990. Mapping strategic thought: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R232">
			<label>232</label>
			<element-citation>Hussinger, K. 2008. R&amp;D and subsidies at the firm level: An application of parametric and semiparametric two-step selection models. Journal of Applied Econometrics, 23(6), pp. 729-747.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R233">
			<label>233</label>
			<element-citation>Hyvärinen, J. &amp; Rautiainen, A.-M. 2007. Measuring additionality and systemic impacts of public research and development funding—the case of TEKES, Finland. Research Evaluation, 16(3), pp. 205-215.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R234">
			<label>234</label>
			<element-citation>Kale, D. &amp; Little, S. 2007. From imitation to innovation: The evolution of R&amp;D capabilities and learning processes in the Indian pharmaceutical industry. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 19(5), pp. 589-609.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R235">
			<label>235</label>
			<element-citation>Katz, A. 2007. Pharmaceutical lemons: innovation and regulation in the drug industry. Michigan Telecommunications and Technology Law Review, 14(1), pp. 1-41.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R236">
			<label>236</label>
			<element-citation>Kargar Shahamat, B., Taghva, M., Tabatabaeian, S. H., Salehi Sedghiani, J., 2016. Requirements of Innovation Network formation An analysis of the Firms rule in Iran's Pharmaceutical sector. Behbood Modiriat, 10(34), pp. 49-94.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R237">
			<label>237</label>
			<element-citation>Kebriaeezadeh, A. et al. 2013. Trend analysis of the pharmaceutical market in Iran; 1997–2010; policy implications for developing countries. DARU journal of pharmaceutical Sciences, 21(1), pp. 52.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R238">
			<label>238</label>
			<element-citation>Kelly, G. 1955. Personal construct psychology. New York: Norton.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R239">
			<label>239</label>
			<element-citation>Kemp, R. &amp; Pontoglio, S. 2011. The innovation effects of environmental policy instruments-A typical case of the blind men and the elephant? Ecological Economics, Volume (72), pp. 28-36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R240">
			<label>240</label>
			<element-citation>Knockaert, M., Spithoven, A. &amp; Clarysse, B. 2014. The impact of technology intermediaries on firm cognitive capacity additionality. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Volume (81), pp. 376-387.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R241">
			<label>241</label>
			<element-citation>Kobayashi, Y. 2014. Effect of R&amp;D tax credits for SMEs in Japan: A Microeconometric Analysis Focused on Liquidity Constraints. Small Business Economics, 42(2), pp. 311-327.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R242">
			<label>242</label>
			<element-citation>Koch, T. 2006. Establishing rigour in qualitative research: the decision trail. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 53(1), pp. 91-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R243">
			<label>243</label>
			<element-citation>Koenig, P. &amp; MacGarvie, M. 2011. Regulatory policy and the location of bio-pharmaceutical foreign direct investment in Europe. Journal of Health Economics, 30(5), pp. 950-965.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R244">
			<label>244</label>
			<element-citation>Lach, S. 2002. Do R&amp;D subsidies stimulate or displace private R&amp;D? Evidence from Israel. The Journal of Industrial Economics, 50(4), pp. 369-390.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R245">
			<label>245</label>
			<element-citation>Langfield-Smith, K. &amp; Wirth, A. 1992. Measuring differences between cognitive maps. Journal of the Operational Research Society, 43(12), pp.1135-1150.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R246">
			<label>246</label>
			<element-citation>Lerner, J. 2000. The government as venture capitalist: the long-run impact of the SBIR program. The Journal of Private Equity, 3(2), pp. 55-78.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R247">
			<label>247</label>
			<element-citation>Lööf, H. &amp; Heshmati, A. 2005. The impact of public funds on private R&amp;D investment: New evidence from a firm level innovation study. MTT Discussion Papers, Volume (3), pp. 1-26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R248">
			<label>248</label>
			<element-citation>Luukkonen, T. 1998. The difficulties in assessing the impact of EU framework programmes. Research Policy, 27(6), pp. 599-610.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R249">
			<label>249</label>
			<element-citation>Madani, H., Shahhoseini, M. H. &amp; Khamseh, A., 2011. Impact of Generic Plan on Development of Technology Capabilities. Hakim Health Systems Research Journal, 1(14), pp. 23-31.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R250">
			<label>250</label>
			<element-citation>Mahoney, R. 2007. Building Product Innovation Capability in Health. In A. Krattiger et al. eds. Intellectual property management in health and agricultural innovation: a handbook of best practices. UK, Oxford.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R251">
			<label>251</label>
			<element-citation>Majone, G. 1996: Regulating Europe. London: Routledge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R252">
			<label>252</label>
			<element-citation>Markoczy, L. &amp; Goldberg, J. 1995. A method for eliciting and comparing causal maps. Journal of Management, 21(2), pp. 305-333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R253">
			<label>253</label>
			<element-citation>Metcalfe, J.S., Georghiou, L., Cunningham, P. &amp; Cameron, H.M. 1992. Evaluation of the impact of European Community research programmes upon the competitiveness of European industry-Concepts and approaches. EUR 14198 EN. Research evaluation. Science and Technology Policy Series.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R254">
			<label>254</label>
			<element-citation>Montibeller, G. &amp; Belton, V. 2006. Causal maps and the evaluation of decision options -a review. Journal of the Operational Research Society, 57(7), pp. 779-791.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R255">
			<label>255</label>
			<element-citation>Nadkarni, S. &amp; Nah, F.F.-H. 2003. Aggregated causal maps: An approach to elicit and aggregate the knowledge of multiple experts. Communications of the Association for Information Systems, 12(1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R256">
			<label>256</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson, R.R. &amp; Winter, S. 1982. An evolutionary theory of economic change. Cambridge: Belknap.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R257">
			<label>257</label>
			<element-citation>Niosi, J. 2002. National systems of innovations are “x-efficient”(and x-effective): Why some are slow learners. Research Policy, 31(2), pp. 291-302.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R258">
			<label>258</label>
			<element-citation>O’Connor, G.C. 2008. Major innovation as a dynamic capability: A systems approach. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 25(4), pp. 313-330.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R259">
			<label>259</label>
			<element-citation>Onishi, K. &amp; Nagata, A. 2010. Does Tax Credit for R&amp;D Induce Additional R&amp;D Investment?: Analysis on the effects of gross R&amp;D credit in Japan. Journal of Science Policy and Research Management, Volume (24), pp. 400-412.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R260">
			<label>260</label>
			<element-citation>Pammolli, F., Magazzini, L. &amp; Riccaboni, M. 2011. The productivity crisis in pharmaceutical R&amp;D. Nature reviews. Drug discovery, 10(6).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R261">
			<label>261</label>
			<element-citation>Paraskevopoulou, E. 2012. Non-technological regulatory effects: Implications for innovation and innovation policy. Research Policy, 41(6), pp. 1058-1071.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R262">
			<label>262</label>
			<element-citation>Porter 1991. America’s green strategy. Scientific American, 264(4).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R263">
			<label>263</label>
			<element-citation>Porter, M. &amp; Van der Linde, C. 1995. Toward a new conception of the environment-competitiveness relationship. The Journal of Economic Perspectives, 9(4), pp. 97-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R264">
			<label>264</label>
			<element-citation>Radas, S., Anić, I.-D., Tafro, A. &amp; Wagner, V., 2015. The effects of public support schemes on small and medium enterprises. Technovation, Volume (38), pp. 15-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R265">
			<label>265</label>
			<element-citation>Ramezani, A. &amp; Mirzaqmohammadi, A., 2013. Social network analysis.Iran, Tehran, Publications Sociologists.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R266">
			<label>266</label>
			<element-citation>Ramos Perez, C. 2016. Designing a behavioural additionality evaluation methodology for the Knowledge Transfer Partnerships Scheme employing case-based methods and theory-based evaluation approaches. University of Manchester.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R267">
			<label>267</label>
			<element-citation>Rasekh, H.R., Mehralian, G. &amp; Vatankhah-Mohammadabadi, A.A. 2012. Situation analysis of R &amp; D activities: an empirical study in Iranian pharmaceutical companies. Iranian Journal of Pharmaceutical Research, 1(4), pp. 1013-1025.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R268">
			<label>268</label>
			<element-citation>Ratanawijitrasin, S. 2007. Drug Regulation and Incentives for Innovation: The Case of ASEAN. WHO. Available at: www. who. int/intellectualproperty/studies/Drugregulationincentives. pdf.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R269">
			<label>269</label>
			<element-citation>Reinkowski, J., Mitze, T., Alecke, B. &amp; Untiedt, G. 2010. R&amp;D Subsidies and Private Sector Innovativeness: New Empirical Evidence for East German Firms.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R270">
			<label>270</label>
			<element-citation>Riege, A.M. 2003. Validity and reliability tests in case study research: a literature review with “hands-on” applications for each research phase. Qualitative Market Research: An International Journal, 6(2), pp. 75-86.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R271">
			<label>271</label>
			<element-citation>Rodhain, F. 1999. Tacit to explicit: transforming knowledge through cognitive mapping—an experiment. Proceedings of the 1999 ACM SIGCPR conference on Computer personnel research, ACM.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R272">
			<label>272</label>
			<element-citation>Assessment of the public tools used to promote R&amp;D investment in Spanish SMEs. Small Business Economics, 43(4), pp. 959-976.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R273">
			<label>273</label>
			<element-citation>Romero-Jordán, D., Delgado-Rodríguez, M.J., Álvarez-Ayuso, I. &amp; de Lucas-Santos, S. 2014. Assessment of the public tools used to promote R&amp;D investment in Spanish SMEs. Small Business Economics, 43(4), pp. 959-976. Safari, H., Heshmatipour, F., Mehrabi, A. &amp; Nassabi, V., 2012. Modeling of Factors Affecting Information Sharing in Supply Chain of IKKCo (Iran Khodro Khorasan Company) Using the Integrated Cognitive Mapping Method and Bayesian Networks. Journal of Information Technology Management (JITM), 4(10), pp. 65-92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R274">
			<label>274</label>
			<element-citation>Santerre, C.G.R.E. &amp; Vernon, J.A. 2004. Drug Prices and R&amp;D Investment Behavior in the Pharmaceutical Industry. Saromi, M., Hoseini, S. M., Mohaghar, A. &amp; Heydari, A., 2009. Proposing a Qualitative Model for Competitive Advantage in High Tech Industries. Industrial Management Journal, 1(3), pp. 53-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R275">
			<label>275</label>
			<element-citation>Seyedifar, M. et al. 2015. An evaluation of policies and procedures of successful pharmaceutical exporters and the comparison of Iranian counterpart policy. Journal of Pharmacoeconomics and Pharmaceutical Management, 1(3/4), pp. 39-44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R276">
			<label>276</label>
			<element-citation>Shabaninejad, H. et al. 2014. Identifying and prioritizing industry-level competitiveness factors: evidence from pharmaceutical market. DARU journal of pharmaceutical Sciences, 22(1), pp. 35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R277">
			<label>277</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, K. 2000. Innovation as a systemic phenomenon: rethinking the role of policy. Enterprise and innovation management studies, 1(1), pp. 73-102.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R278">
			<label>278</label>
			<element-citation>Soete, L. et al. 2002. Benchmarking National Research Policies: The Impact of RTD on Competitiveness and Employ ment (IRCE). Strata-ETAN Expert Working Group, European Commission DG Research, Brussels. Soltanzadeh, J., Elyasi, M., Bamdad Soofi, J. &amp; Kazazi, A., 2017.  Micro-Foundations of Innovation Capability in Iranian Pharma Firms; Multi case Studies. 11(35), pp. 163-206.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R279">
			<label>279</label>
			<element-citation>Stewart, L.A. 2010. The Impact of Regulation on Innovation in the United States: A Cross-Industry Literature Review. USA, Information Technology &amp; Innovation Foundation.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R280">
			<label>280</label>
			<element-citation>Strauss, K., Lepoutre, J. &amp; Wood, G. 2017. Fifty shades of green: How microfoundations of sustainability dynamic capabilities vary across organizational contexts. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 38(9).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R281">
			<label>281</label>
			<element-citation>Teece, D. &amp; Pisano, G. 1994. The dynamic capabilities of firms: an introduction. Industrial and Corporate change, 3(3), pp. 537-556.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R282">
			<label>282</label>
			<element-citation>Teece, D.J. 2007. Explicating dynamic capabilities: the nature and microfoundations of (sustainable) enterprise performance. Strategic Management Journal, 28(13), pp. 1319-1350.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R283">
			<label>283</label>
			<element-citation>Teece, D.J. 2012. Dynamic capabilities: Routines versus entrepreneurial action. Journal of Management Studies, 49(8), pp.1395-1401.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R284">
			<label>284</label>
			<element-citation>Teece, D.J. 2017. Towards a capability theory of (innovating) firms: implications for management and policy. Cambridge Journal of Economics, 41(3), pp. 693-720.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R285">
			<label>285</label>
			<element-citation>Teece, D.J., Pisano, G. &amp; Shuen, A. 1997. Dynamic capabilities and strategic management. Strategic Management Journal, Volume(18), pp. 509-533.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R286">
			<label>286</label>
			<element-citation>Tran, T.A. &amp; Daim, T. 2008. A taxonomic review of methods and tools applied in technology assessment. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 75(9), pp. 1396-1405.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R287">
			<label>287</label>
			<element-citation>Van Den Ende, J. et al. 1998. Traditional and modern technology assessment: toward a toolkit. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 58(1), pp. 5-21.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R288">
			<label>288</label>
			<element-citation>Vernon, J.A. 2005. Examining the link between price regulation and pharmaceutical R&amp;D investment. Health Economics, 14(1), pp. 1-16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R289">
			<label>289</label>
			<element-citation>Wallsten, S.J. 2000. The effects of government-industry R&amp;D programs on private R&amp;D: the case of the Small Business Innovation Research program. The RAND Journal of Economics, 31(1), pp.82-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R290">
			<label>290</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, C.L. &amp; Ahmed, P.K. 2007. Dynamic capabilities: A review and research agenda. International Journal of Management Reviews, 9(1), pp. 31-51.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R291">
			<label>291</label>
			<element-citation>Weber, K.M. &amp; Rohracher, H. 2012. Legitimizing research, technology and innovation policies for transformative change: Combining insights from innovation systems and multi-level perspective in a comprehensive ‘failures’ framework. Research Policy, 41(6), pp. 1037-1047.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R292">
			<label>292</label>
			<element-citation>Winter, S.G. 2003. Understanding dynamic capabilities. Strategic Management Journal, 24(10), pp. 991-995.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R293">
			<label>293</label>
			<element-citation>Woolthuis, R.K., Lankhuizen, M. &amp; Gilsing, V. 2005. A system failure framework for innovation policy design. Technovation, 25(6), pp. 609-619.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R294">
			<label>294</label>
			<element-citation>Yang, C.-H., Huang, C.-H. &amp; Hou, T.C.-T. 2012. Tax incentives and R&amp;D activity: Firm-level evidence from Taiwan. Research Policy, 41(9), pp. 1578-1588.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R295">
			<label>295</label>
			<element-citation>Zaboli, P. et al. 2016. Pharmaceutical laws and regulations in Iran: An overview. Journal of Research in Pharmacy Practice, 5(3), pp. 155.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R296">
			<label>296</label>
			<element-citation>Zahra, S.A. &amp; George, G. 2002. Absorptive capacity: A review, reconceptualization, and extension. Academy of Management Review, 27(2), pp. 185-203.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R297">
			<label>297</label>
			<element-citation>Zahra, S.A., Sapienza, H.J. &amp; Davidsson, P. 2006. Entrepreneurship and Dynamic Capabilities: A Review, Model and Research Agenda. Journal of Management Studies, 43(4), pp. 917-955.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R298">
			<label>298</label>
			<element-citation>Zarghami Fard, M. &amp; Azar, A., 2015. An Analysis of the Cognitive Mapping Method in the Qualitative Data Structuring of Organizational Studies. Organizational Behavior Studies Quarterly, 3(1-2), pp. 159-185.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R299">
			<label>299</label>
			<element-citation>Zollo, M. &amp; Winter, S.G. 2002. Deliberate learning and the evolution of dynamic capabilities. Organization Science, 13(3), pp.339-351.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60176_78c3d8ae784ca4215d86762daee94f31.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>سیاست گذاری و مدیریت علم، فناوری، نوآوری و کارآفرینی و ارزیابی آن ها</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>واکاوی اهداف و توانمندسازهای مشارکت در زیست بوم پلتفرم از دیدگاه نوآوران طرف عرضه در صنعت نرم افزار: شرکت های کوچک مستقر در تهران</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>یارمحمدی</surname>
			            <given-names>مریم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رضوانی</surname>
			            <given-names>مهران</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>البرزی</surname>
			            <given-names>محمود</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشیار گروه مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>23</day>
			        <month>08</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>6</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>65</fpage>
			      <lpage>86</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>30</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>13</day>
			          <month>01</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60176.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60176.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>نوآوران طرف عرضه نقش مهمی در موفقیت پلتفرم‌ و افزایش تعداد کاربران آن ایفا می‌کنند. مطالعه حاضر با تمرکز بر دیدگاه این نوآوران قصد دارد اهداف آن‌ها از مشارکت در زیست‌بوم پلتفرم‌ و توانمندسازهای آن‌ها را واکاوی نماید. جامعه آماری این پژوهش را شرکت‌های کوچک ایران در صنعت نرم‌افزار تشکیل می‌دهند. رویکرد مقاله حاضر کیفی است و در آن از راهبرد پژوهشی مطالعه چند موردی اکتشافی استفاده شده است. گردآوری داده‌ها از طریق42 مصاحبه‌ نیمه‌ساخت‌یافته با 26 شرکت کوچک در حوزه توسعه برنامه‌های کاربردی مبتنی‌ بر پلتفرم‌های اندروید یا آی‌اُاِس انجام شده است. تحلیل داده‌های گردآوری شده در دو مرحله کدگذاری باز و کدگذاری محوری صورت پذیرفته است. یافته‌های پژوهش اهداف اصلی نوآوران طرف عرضه از مشارکت در زیست‌بوم پلتفرم را در شش مقوله، دسترسی به مشتریان، پاسخگویی به مشتریان، توسعه گستره کسب‌و‌کار، افزایش اعتبار، صرفه‌جویی در هزینه‌ها، و تمرکز بر نوآوری نشان می‌دهد. اشتراک‌گذاری منابع، رهبری پلتفرم، شایستگی قوانین و مقررات، و بلوغ شرکای تجاری و سرمایه‌گذاران نیز به‌عنوان توانمندسازهای اصلی مشارکت از دیدگاه این نوآوران محسوب می‌شوند.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>توانمندسازها</kwd>
						<kwd>زیستبوم پلتفرم</kwd>
						<kwd>نوآوران طرف عرضه</kwd>
						<kwd>نوآوری</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Baldwin, C.Y., &amp; Woodard, C.J., 2009. The architecture of platforms: a unified view, in A. Gawer, (ed.) Platforms, Markets and Innovation. Edward Elgar, Cheltenham. Mass, UK and Northampton, pp. 19–44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Benlian, A., Hilkert, D., &amp; Hess, T., 2015. How Open Is This Platform? The Meaning and Measurement of Platform Openness from the Complementors’ Perspective. Journal of Information Technology, 30(3), pp. 209–228.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Berends, H., Jelinek, M., Reymen, I., &amp; Stultiëns, R., 2014. Product innovation processes in small firms: Combining entrepreneurial effectuation and managerial causation. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 31(3), pp. 616–635.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Boudreau, K., 2010. Open Platform Strategies and Innovation: Granting Access vs. Devolving Control. Management Science, 56(10), pp. 1849–1872.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Boudreau, K. J., &amp; Hagiu, A., 2009. Platform rules: multi-sided platforms as regulators, in A. Gawer, (ed.) Platforms, Markets and Innovation. Edward Elgar, Cheltenham. Mass, UK and Northampton, pp. 163–191.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Boudreau, K.J., &amp; Jeppesen, L.B., 2015. Unpaid crowd complementors: The platform network effect mirage. Strategic Management Journal, 36(12), pp. 1761–1777.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Casadesus-Masanell, R., &amp; Hałaburda, H., 2014. When does a platform create value by limiting choice? Journal of Economics and Management Strategy, 23(2), pp. 259–293.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Ceccagnoli, M., Forman, C., Huang, P., &amp; Wu, D.J., 2012. Cocreation of Value in a Platform Ecosystem: The Case of Enterpreise Software. MIS Quarterly, 36(1), pp. 263–290.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Ciriello, R.F., Richter, A., &amp; Schwabe, G., 2016. Designing an idea screening framework for employee-driven innovation. In: Proceedings of the Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences. pp. 4262–4271.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Creswell, J.W., 2008. Educational research: Planning, conducting, and evaluating quantitative and qualitative research. Educational Research, 3, p.670.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Cusumano, M.A., &amp; Gawer, A., 2002. The Elements of Platform Leaderhsip. MIT Sloan Management Review, (spring), pp. 51–58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K.M., 1989. Building Theories from Case Study Research. Academy of Management Review, 14(4), pp. 532–550.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenmann, T., Parker, G., &amp; Van Alstyne, M., 2011. Platform envelopment. Strategic Management Journal, 32(12), pp. 1270–1285.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Evans, D.S., 2003. The Antitrust Economics of Multi-Sided Platform Markets. Yale Journal on Regulation, 20(2), p.325.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Evans, D.S., 2009. How catalysts ignite: the economics of platform-based start-ups, in A. Gawer, (ed.) Platforms, Markets and Innovation. Edward Elgar, Cheltenham. Mass, UK and Northampton, pp. 99–128.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Gawer, A., 2009. Platform dynamics and strategies: from products to services, in A. Gawer, (ed.) Platforms, Markets and Innovation. Edward Elgar, Cheltenham. Mass, UK and Northampton, pp. 45–76.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Gawer, A., &amp; Cusumano, M.A., 2014. Industry platforms and ecosystem innovation. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 31(3), pp. 417–433.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Gawer, A., &amp; Henderson, R., 2007. Platform owner entry and innovation in complementary markets: Evidence from Intel. Journal of Economics and Management Strategy, 16, pp. 1–34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Ghanam, Y., Maurer, F., &amp; Abrahamsson, P., 2012. Making the leap to a software platform strategy: Issues and challenges. Information and Software Technology, 54(9), pp. 968–984.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Ghazawneh, A., &amp; Henfridsson, O., 2013. Balancing platform control and external contribution in third-party development: The boundary resources model. Information Systems Journal, 23(2), pp. 173–192.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Giardino, C., Unterkalmsteiner, M., Paternoster, N., Gorschek, T., &amp; Abrahamsson, P., 2014. What do we know about software development in startups? IEEE Software, 31(5), pp. 28–32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Hagiu, A., 2009. Two-Sided Platforms: Pricing and Social Efficiency. Journal of Economics &amp; Management Strategy, 18, pp. 1011–1043.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Hausman, A., 2005. Innovativeness among small businesses: Theory and propositions for future research. Industrial Marketing Management, 34(8), pp. 773–782.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Hidding, G.J., Williams, J., &amp; Sviokla, J.J., 2011. How platform leaders win. Journal of Business Strategy, 32(2), pp. 29–37.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Huang, P., Ceccagnoli, M., Forman, C., &amp; Wu, D.J., 2009. When Do ISVs Join a Platform Ecosystem? Evidence from the Enterprise Software Industry. In: ICIS 2009 Proceedings.  pp. 1–18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Jiao, J., Simpson, T.W., &amp; Siddique, Z., 2007. Product family design and platform-based product development: A state-of-the-art review. Journal of Intelligent Manufacturing, 18(1), pp. 5–29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Kude, T., Dibbern, J., &amp; Heinzl, A., 2012. Why do complementors participate an analysis of partnership networks in the enterprise software industry? IEEE Transactions on Engineering Management, 59(2), pp. 250–265.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Lee, S.M., Kim, T., Noh, Y., &amp; Lee, B., 2010. Success factors of platform leadership in web 2.0 service business. Service Business, 4(2), pp. 89–103.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Lu, J.W., &amp; Beamish, P.W., 2001. The internationalization and performance of SMEs. Strategic Management Journal, 22, pp. 565–586.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Marion, T.J., Friar, J.H., &amp; Simpson, T.W., 2012. New product development practices and early-stage firms: Two in-depth case studies. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 29(4), pp. 639–654.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Muffatto, M., &amp; Roveda, M., 2002. Product architecture and platforms: a conceptual framework. International Journal of Technology Management, 24(1), pp. 1–16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Muffatto, M., 1999. Platform strategies in international new product development. International Journal of Operations &amp; Production Management, 19(5/6), pp. 449–460.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Nambisan, S., &amp; Sawhney, M., 2011. Orchestration Processes in Network-Centric Innovation: Evidence from the Field. Academy of Management Perspectives, 25(3), pp. 40–57.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Ondrus, J., Gannamaneni, A., &amp; Lyytinen, K., 2015. The impact of openness on the market potential of multi-sided platforms: A case study of mobile payment platforms. Journal of Information Technology, 30(3), pp. 260–275.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Radas, S., &amp; Božić, L., 2009. The antecedents of SME innovativeness in an emerging transition economy. Technovation, 29(6-7), pp. 438–450.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Rickmann, T., Wenzel, S., &amp; Fischbach, K., 2014. Software Ecosystem Orchestration: The Perspective of Complementors. Twentieth Americas Conference on Information Systems, Savannah, pp. 1–14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Robertson, D., &amp; Ulrich, K., 1998. Planning for Product Platforms. Sloan Managament Review, 39(4), pp. 19–31.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Sarantakos, S., 2005. Social Research. Palgrave Macmillan, Hampshire.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Scozzi, B., C. Garavelli, &amp; K. Crowston., 2005. Methods for modelling and supporting innovation processes in SMEs. European Journal of Innovation Management, 8(1), pp. 120–137.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Song, M., Podoynitsyna, K., Van Der Bij, H., &amp; Halman, J.I.M., 2008. Success factors in new ventures: A meta-analysis. The Journal of Product Innovation Management, Volume (25), pp. 7–27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Swan, K.S., Kotabe, M., &amp; Allred, B.B., 2005. Exploring robust design capabilities, their role in creating global products, and their relationship to firm performance. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 22(2), pp. 144–164.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Tee, R., &amp; Gawer, A., 2009. Industry architecture as a determinant of successful platform strategies: a case study of the i-mode mobile Internet service. European Management Review, 6(4), pp. 217–232.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Voss, C., Tsikriktsis, N., &amp; Frohlich, M., 2002. Case research in operations management. International Journal of Operations &amp; Production Management, 22(2), pp. 195–219.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Weber, R.P., 1990. Basic content analysis. Sage, Newbury Par, CA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>West, J., 2003. How open is open enough? Melding proprietary and open source platform strategies. Research Policy, 32(7), pp. 1259–1285.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Wheelen, T.L., &amp; Hunger, J.D., 1999. Strategic Management and Business Policy. Addison-Wesley, Reading, MA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Wheelwright, S.C., &amp; Clark, K.B., 1992a. Creating project plans to focus product development. Harvard Business Review, 70(2), pp. 70–82.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Wheelwright, S.C., &amp; Clark, K.B., 1992b. Revolutionizing Product Development: Quantum Leaps in Speed, Efficiency, and Quality. New York, NY.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Yarmohammadi, M., Rezvani, M., &amp; Alborzi, M., 2017. How Complementors Screen New Product Ideas: A Qualitative Multiple Case Study. In: Proceedings of the 12th European Conference on Innovation and Entrepreneurship, Paris, France. pp. 669–676.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Yin, R. K., 2009. Case Study Research: Design and Methods. SAGE Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Yoffie, D.B., &amp; Kwak, M., 2006. With Friends Like these: The Art of Managing Complementors. Harvard Business Review, 84(9), pp.  88–98.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Zhu, F., &amp; Iansiti, M., 2012. Entry into Platform-based Markets. Strategic Management Journal, 33(1), pp. 88–106._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Baldwin, C.Y., &amp; Woodard, C.J., 2009. The architecture of platforms: a unified view, in A. Gawer, (ed.) Platforms, Markets and Innovation. Edward Elgar, Cheltenham. Mass, UK and Northampton, pp. 19–44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Benlian, A., Hilkert, D., &amp; Hess, T., 2015. How Open Is This Platform? The Meaning and Measurement of Platform Openness from the Complementors’ Perspective. Journal of Information Technology, 30(3), pp. 209–228.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Berends, H., Jelinek, M., Reymen, I., &amp; Stultiëns, R., 2014. Product innovation processes in small firms: Combining entrepreneurial effectuation and managerial causation. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 31(3), pp. 616–635.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Boudreau, K., 2010. Open Platform Strategies and Innovation: Granting Access vs. Devolving Control. Management Science, 56(10), pp. 1849–1872.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Boudreau, K. J., &amp; Hagiu, A., 2009. Platform rules: multi-sided platforms as regulators, in A. Gawer, (ed.) Platforms, Markets and Innovation. Edward Elgar, Cheltenham. Mass, UK and Northampton, pp. 163–191.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Boudreau, K.J., &amp; Jeppesen, L.B., 2015. Unpaid crowd complementors: The platform network effect mirage. Strategic Management Journal, 36(12), pp. 1761–1777.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Casadesus-Masanell, R., &amp; Hałaburda, H., 2014. When does a platform create value by limiting choice? Journal of Economics and Management Strategy, 23(2), pp. 259–293.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Ceccagnoli, M., Forman, C., Huang, P., &amp; Wu, D.J., 2012. Cocreation of Value in a Platform Ecosystem: The Case of Enterpreise Software. MIS Quarterly, 36(1), pp. 263–290.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Ciriello, R.F., Richter, A., &amp; Schwabe, G., 2016. Designing an idea screening framework for employee-driven innovation. In: Proceedings of the Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences. pp. 4262–4271.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Creswell, J.W., 2008. Educational research: Planning, conducting, and evaluating quantitative and qualitative research. Educational Research, 3, p.670.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Cusumano, M.A., &amp; Gawer, A., 2002. The Elements of Platform Leaderhsip. MIT Sloan Management Review, (spring), pp. 51–58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, K.M., 1989. Building Theories from Case Study Research. Academy of Management Review, 14(4), pp. 532–550.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenmann, T., Parker, G., &amp; Van Alstyne, M., 2011. Platform envelopment. Strategic Management Journal, 32(12), pp. 1270–1285.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Evans, D.S., 2003. The Antitrust Economics of Multi-Sided Platform Markets. Yale Journal on Regulation, 20(2), p.325.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Evans, D.S., 2009. How catalysts ignite: the economics of platform-based start-ups, in A. Gawer, (ed.) Platforms, Markets and Innovation. Edward Elgar, Cheltenham. Mass, UK and Northampton, pp. 99–128.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Gawer, A., 2009. Platform dynamics and strategies: from products to services, in A. Gawer, (ed.) Platforms, Markets and Innovation. Edward Elgar, Cheltenham. Mass, UK and Northampton, pp. 45–76.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Gawer, A., &amp; Cusumano, M.A., 2014. Industry platforms and ecosystem innovation. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 31(3), pp. 417–433.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Gawer, A., &amp; Henderson, R., 2007. Platform owner entry and innovation in complementary markets: Evidence from Intel. Journal of Economics and Management Strategy, 16, pp. 1–34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Ghanam, Y., Maurer, F., &amp; Abrahamsson, P., 2012. Making the leap to a software platform strategy: Issues and challenges. Information and Software Technology, 54(9), pp. 968–984.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Ghazawneh, A., &amp; Henfridsson, O., 2013. Balancing platform control and external contribution in third-party development: The boundary resources model. Information Systems Journal, 23(2), pp. 173–192.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Giardino, C., Unterkalmsteiner, M., Paternoster, N., Gorschek, T., &amp; Abrahamsson, P., 2014. What do we know about software development in startups? IEEE Software, 31(5), pp. 28–32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Hagiu, A., 2009. Two-Sided Platforms: Pricing and Social Efficiency. Journal of Economics &amp; Management Strategy, 18, pp. 1011–1043.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Hausman, A., 2005. Innovativeness among small businesses: Theory and propositions for future research. Industrial Marketing Management, 34(8), pp. 773–782.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Hidding, G.J., Williams, J., &amp; Sviokla, J.J., 2011. How platform leaders win. Journal of Business Strategy, 32(2), pp. 29–37.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Huang, P., Ceccagnoli, M., Forman, C., &amp; Wu, D.J., 2009. When Do ISVs Join a Platform Ecosystem? Evidence from the Enterprise Software Industry. In: ICIS 2009 Proceedings.  pp. 1–18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Jiao, J., Simpson, T.W., &amp; Siddique, Z., 2007. Product family design and platform-based product development: A state-of-the-art review. Journal of Intelligent Manufacturing, 18(1), pp. 5–29.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Kude, T., Dibbern, J., &amp; Heinzl, A., 2012. Why do complementors participate an analysis of partnership networks in the enterprise software industry? IEEE Transactions on Engineering Management, 59(2), pp. 250–265.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Lee, S.M., Kim, T., Noh, Y., &amp; Lee, B., 2010. Success factors of platform leadership in web 2.0 service business. Service Business, 4(2), pp. 89–103.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Lu, J.W., &amp; Beamish, P.W., 2001. The internationalization and performance of SMEs. Strategic Management Journal, 22, pp. 565–586.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Marion, T.J., Friar, J.H., &amp; Simpson, T.W., 2012. New product development practices and early-stage firms: Two in-depth case studies. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 29(4), pp. 639–654.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Muffatto, M., &amp; Roveda, M., 2002. Product architecture and platforms: a conceptual framework. International Journal of Technology Management, 24(1), pp. 1–16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Muffatto, M., 1999. Platform strategies in international new product development. International Journal of Operations &amp; Production Management, 19(5/6), pp. 449–460.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Nambisan, S., &amp; Sawhney, M., 2011. Orchestration Processes in Network-Centric Innovation: Evidence from the Field. Academy of Management Perspectives, 25(3), pp. 40–57.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Ondrus, J., Gannamaneni, A., &amp; Lyytinen, K., 2015. The impact of openness on the market potential of multi-sided platforms: A case study of mobile payment platforms. Journal of Information Technology, 30(3), pp. 260–275.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Radas, S., &amp; Božić, L., 2009. The antecedents of SME innovativeness in an emerging transition economy. Technovation, 29(6-7), pp. 438–450.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Rickmann, T., Wenzel, S., &amp; Fischbach, K., 2014. Software Ecosystem Orchestration: The Perspective of Complementors. Twentieth Americas Conference on Information Systems, Savannah, pp. 1–14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Robertson, D., &amp; Ulrich, K., 1998. Planning for Product Platforms. Sloan Managament Review, 39(4), pp. 19–31.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Sarantakos, S., 2005. Social Research. Palgrave Macmillan, Hampshire.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Scozzi, B., C. Garavelli, &amp; K. Crowston., 2005. Methods for modelling and supporting innovation processes in SMEs. European Journal of Innovation Management, 8(1), pp. 120–137.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Song, M., Podoynitsyna, K., Van Der Bij, H., &amp; Halman, J.I.M., 2008. Success factors in new ventures: A meta-analysis. The Journal of Product Innovation Management, Volume (25), pp. 7–27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Swan, K.S., Kotabe, M., &amp; Allred, B.B., 2005. Exploring robust design capabilities, their role in creating global products, and their relationship to firm performance. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 22(2), pp. 144–164.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Tee, R., &amp; Gawer, A., 2009. Industry architecture as a determinant of successful platform strategies: a case study of the i-mode mobile Internet service. European Management Review, 6(4), pp. 217–232.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Voss, C., Tsikriktsis, N., &amp; Frohlich, M., 2002. Case research in operations management. International Journal of Operations &amp; Production Management, 22(2), pp. 195–219.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Weber, R.P., 1990. Basic content analysis. Sage, Newbury Par, CA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>West, J., 2003. How open is open enough? Melding proprietary and open source platform strategies. Research Policy, 32(7), pp. 1259–1285.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Wheelen, T.L., &amp; Hunger, J.D., 1999. Strategic Management and Business Policy. Addison-Wesley, Reading, MA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Wheelwright, S.C., &amp; Clark, K.B., 1992a. Creating project plans to focus product development. Harvard Business Review, 70(2), pp. 70–82.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Wheelwright, S.C., &amp; Clark, K.B., 1992b. Revolutionizing Product Development: Quantum Leaps in Speed, Efficiency, and Quality. New York, NY.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Yarmohammadi, M., Rezvani, M., &amp; Alborzi, M., 2017. How Complementors Screen New Product Ideas: A Qualitative Multiple Case Study. In: Proceedings of the 12th European Conference on Innovation and Entrepreneurship, Paris, France. pp. 669–676.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Yin, R. K., 2009. Case Study Research: Design and Methods. SAGE Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Yoffie, D.B., &amp; Kwak, M., 2006. With Friends Like these: The Art of Managing Complementors. Harvard Business Review, 84(9), pp.  88–98.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Zhu, F., &amp; Iansiti, M., 2012. Entry into Platform-based Markets. Strategic Management Journal, 33(1), pp. 88–106.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60173_3d463691029462a5d93a813e65a72ac6.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>تجاری سازی محصول/فناوری</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تناسب سطح نوآوری در محصول با میزان تغییر در علامت تجاری: پیمایشی از مشتریان محصولات شوینده و بهداشتی</article-title>
			        <subtitle>تناسب سطح نوآوری در محصول با میزان تغییر در علامت تجاری: پیمایشی از مشتریان محصولات شوینده و بهداشتی</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>غریبی</surname>
			            <given-names>جلیل</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>ناظمی</surname>
			            <given-names>ندا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات شاهرود، شاهرود، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>23</day>
			        <month>08</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>6</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>87</fpage>
			      <lpage>108</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>14</day>
			          <month>01</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>05</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60173.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60173.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>انتخاب رویکرد مناسب برای علامت تجاری عاملی مهم در تعیین موفقیت محصولات جدید است. هدف از پژوهش حاضر پاسخ به این سوال است که الگوی مشتریان برای انتخاب محصولات نوآورانه با توجه به علامت تجاری همراه با این محصولات چیست؟ در این مقاله با اتکا بر رویکرد پیمایشی ، نظرات 385 نفر از مشتریانِ مراجعه کننده به فروشگاه‌های بزرگ شهر تهران در خصوص خرید و استفاده از مواد شوینده و بهداشتی جمع‌آوری شد. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که پذیرندگان اولیه، نوآوری‌های فنی جهشی‌تر (حاوی تفاوت اساسی با محصولات قبلی) را به‌همراه علائم تجاری جدید و محصولات فعلی را به‌همراه علامت تجاری فعلی می‌پذیرند اما در خصوص نوآوری‌های تدریجی‌تر (حاوی تفاوت جزئی با محصولات قبلی)، الگوی یکسانی را نشان نمی‌دهند. در حالیکه برای سایر پذیرندگان، محصولات فعلی که به‌همراه علامت تجاری فعلی عرضه می‌شوند منطقی‌تر به نظر می‌رسند، نوآوری‌های تدریجی‌تر را نیز معمولا با توسعه علامت تجاری شناخته و قبول می‌کنند اما در خصوص نوآوری‌های جهشی‌تر الگوی نسبتا پراکنده‌ای حول دو انتخاب متضاد علامت تجاری فعلی و علامت تجاری جدید نشان می‌دهند. در این مقاله دلایل این الگوها که از جمع‌آوری داده‌های کیفی حاصل شده است نیز تا حدودی توانسته به تبیین علل بوجود آمدن این الگوها کمک کند</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>نوآوری محصول</kwd>
						<kwd>نوآوری جهشی</kwd>
						<kwd>نوآوری تدریجی</kwd>
						<kwd>علامت تجاری جدید</kwd>
						<kwd>توسعه علامت تجاری</kwd>
						<kwd>پذیرندگان اولیه</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Aaker, D. &amp; Keller, K., 1990. Consumer Evaluations of Brand Extensions. Journal of Marketing , 54(1), pp. 27-41.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Assael, H., 1995. Consumer Behavior and Marketing Action. Cincinnati: South Western College Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Atashfaraz, M. &amp; Abadi, M., 2016. Impact of E-Service Innovation on Brand Equality and Customer Loyality in Samsung International Corporation. Procedia Economics and Finance, Volume 36, pp. 327-335.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Bauer, R., 1960. Consumer Behavior as Risk Taking. Chicago, Proceedings of the 43rd. Conference of the American Marketing Association.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Berthon, P., Hulbert, J. &amp; Leyland, . F., 1999. Brand Management Prognostications. MIT Sloan Management Review, 40(2), pp. 53-65.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Brexendorf, T. O., Bayus, B. &amp; Keller, K. L., 2015. Understanding the interplay between brand and innovation management: findings and future research directions. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, 43(5), pp. 548-557.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Brooker, G., 1984. An assessment of an expanded measure of perceived risk. In: T. C. Kinnear, ed. NA - Advances in Consumer Research. Provo: Association for Consumer Research, pp. 439-441.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Camisón, C. &amp; Villar-López, A., 2014. Organizational innovation as an enabler of technological innovation capabilities and firm performance. Journal of Business Research, 67(1), pp. 2891-2902.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Castaño, R., Sujan, m., Kacker , M. &amp; Sujan, H., 2008. Managing Consumer Uncertainty in the Adoption of New Products: Temporal Distance and Mental Simulation. Journal of Marketing Research, 45(3), pp. 320-336.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Chandy, R. K. &amp; Tellis, G., 2000. The incumbent’s curse? Incumbency, size, and radical product innovation. Journal of Marketing , 64(3), pp. 1-17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Chandy, R., Prabhu, J. &amp; Antia, K., 2003. What Will the Future Bring? Dominance, Technology Expectations, and Radical Innovation. Journal of Marketing, 67(3), pp. 1-18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, R. G., 1994. New products: the factors that drive success. International Marketing Review , 11(1), pp. 60-76.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Damanpour, F., Walker, R. &amp; Avellaneda, N., 2009. Combinative Effects of Innovation Types and Organizational Performance: A Longitudinal Study of Service Organizations. Journal of Management Studies , 46(4), pp. 650-675.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>DelVecchio, D. &amp; Smith, D., 2005. Brand-Extension Price Premiums: The Effects of Perceived Fit and Extension Product Category Risk. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science , 33(2), pp. 184-196.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Dhanora, M., Sharama, R. &amp; Khachoo, Q., 2017. Non-linear impact of product and process innovations on market power: A theoretical and empirical investigation. Economic Modelling. In Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Dowling, G. &amp; Staelin, R., 1994. A model of perceived risk and intended risk-handling activity. Journal of Consumer Research , 21(1), pp. 119-134.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Fadzline, P., Mat Nor, N.,  Mohamad, S.J. 2014. The Mediating Effect of Design Innovation between Brand Distinctiveness and Brand Performance: Evidence from Furniture Manufacturing Firms in Malaysia. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences 130, pp. 333-339.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Fang, E. 2008. Customer participation and the trade-off between new product innovativeness and speed to market. Journal of Marketing,72(4), pp. 90-104.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Florea, D.L. 2015. The Relationship between Branding and Diffusion of Innovation: A Systematic Review. Procedia Economics and Finance, 23, pp. 1527-1534.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Ghazinoory, S. &amp; Riahi, P. 1393. introduction to innovation system (broad approach). tehran, markaz-e-nashr-e daneshgahi.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Gill, T. &amp; Lei, J. 2009. Convergence in the High-Technology Consumer Markets: Not all Brands Gain Equally from Adding New Functionalities to Products. Marketing Letters, 20(1), pp. 91.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Gourville, J. T. 2006. Eager Sellers &amp; Stony Buyers. Harvard Business Review, 84(6), pp. 98-106.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Govindarajan, V. &amp; Kopalle, P.K. 2006. Disruptiveness of Innovations: Measurement and an Assessment of Reliability and Validity. Strategic Management Journal, 27(2), pp. 189-199.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Gunday, G. &amp; Alpkan, L., 2011. Effects of Innovation Types on Firm Performance. International Journal of production economics, 133(2), pp. 662-676.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Henderson, R. M. &amp; Clark, K.B. 1990. Architectural Innovation: The Reconfiguration of Existing Product Technologies and the Failure of Established Firms. Administrative Science Quarterly, 35(1), pp. 9-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Hoeffler, S. 2003. Measuring Preferences for Really New Products. Journal of Marketing Research, 40(4), pp. 406-420.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Janis, I.L. &amp; Mann, L. 1977. Decision making: A Psychological Analysis of Conflict, Choice, and Commitment, New York, NY: Free Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Karimian, H., Shekarchizadeh, A., Rismankarzadeh, R. 1394. An Investigation of Influential Factors in Choosing Brands of Washing Products by Female Isfahanis Customers. Marketing Management, Volume (10), pp. 17-34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Klink, R. R. &amp; Athaide, G. A. 2010. Consumer Innovativeness and the Use of New Versus Extended Brand Names for New Products. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 27(1), pp. 23-32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Kotler, P. &amp; Armstrong, G., 2016. Principles of Marketing, 16th Ed. Boston: Pearson.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Kotler, P. &amp; Dupree, J. 1997. Marketing Management: Analysis, Planning, Implementation, and Control, Test Item File, Prentice Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Lim, K. &amp; O’Cass, A. 2001. Consumer Brand Classifications: an Assessment of Culture-of-Origin Versus Country-of-Origin. Journal of Product &amp; Brand Management, 10(2), pp. 120-136.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Mortensen, P. S. &amp; Bloch, C. W. 2005. Oslo Manual-Guidelines for Collecting and Interpreting Innovation Data: Proposed Guidelines for Collecting and Interpreting Innovation Data, Organisation for Economic Cooporation and Development, OECD.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson, R.R. &amp; Rosenberg, N. 1993. Technical Innovation and National Systems. National Innovation Systems: A Comparative Analysis, Volume (1), pp. 3-21.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Ogiba, E.F. 1988. The Dangers of Leveraging. Adweek, (January 4), 42.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Rezayi, H. 1394. Investigating Marketing Strategy for Tage New Product (Ultrapower). Forsat Emrooz.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Riley, F. D. O., Pina, J.M. &amp; Rafael, B. 2013. Downscale Extensions: Consumer Evaluation and Feedback Effects. Journal of Business Research, 66(2), pp. 196-206.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Rogers, E. M. 2010. Diffusion of Innovations, Free Press, 5th Edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Roselius, T. 1971. Consumer Rankings of Risk Reduction Methods. The Journal of Marketing, 35(1), pp. 56-61.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Ross, I. 1979. An Information Processing Theory of Consumer Choice, JSTOR, MA: Addison-Wesley Publishing Company.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Sehumpeter, J. A. 1934. The Theory of Economic Development: An Inquiry into Profits, Capital, Credit, Interest, and the Business Cycle. Social Science Electronic Publishing, 25(1), pp. 90-91.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, D. C. &amp; C. W. Park. 1992. The Effects of Brand Extensions on Market Share and Advertising Efficiency. Journal of Marketing Research, 29(3), pp. 296-313.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Somji, A. 2000. Inside New Product Statistics. Unpublished MA in Marketing Thesis. Kingston Business School, Kingston upon Thames, UK.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Wernerfelt, B. 1988. Umbrella branding as a signal of New Product Quality: An Example of Signalling by Posting a Bond. The RAND Journal of Economics, pp. 458-466.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Wu, Y., Balasubramanian, S. &amp; Mahajan, V., 2004. When is a Preannounced New Product Likely to be Delayed? Journal of Marketing, 68(2), pp. 101-113.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>قاضی نوری، سید سپهر و پریسا ریاحی، 1393 مقدمه ای بر نظام نوآوری: رویکردی گسترده، تهران، مرکز نشر دانشگاهی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>کریمیان. حامد، احمدرضا شکرچی زاده، ریحانه ریسمان‌کارزاده، 1394، بررسی عوامل موثر بر انتخاب برند مواد شوینده از دیدگاه بانوان شهر اصفهان، مجله مدیریت بازاریابی، شماره 27، صص 34-17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>رضایی. هدی، 1394، بررسی راهبرد بازاریابی محصول جدید تاژ به نام مایع ظرفشویی اولتراپاور/ رونمایی از محصول کم‌ مصرف در دوران بحران آب، روزنامه فرصت امروز._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Aaker, D. &amp; Keller, K., 1990. Consumer Evaluations of Brand Extensions. Journal of Marketing , 54(1), pp. 27-41.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Assael, H., 1995. Consumer Behavior and Marketing Action. Cincinnati: South Western College Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Atashfaraz, M. &amp; Abadi, M., 2016. Impact of E-Service Innovation on Brand Equality and Customer Loyality in Samsung International Corporation. Procedia Economics and Finance, Volume 36, pp. 327-335.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Bauer, R., 1960. Consumer Behavior as Risk Taking. Chicago, Proceedings of the 43rd. Conference of the American Marketing Association.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Berthon, P., Hulbert, J. &amp; Leyland, . F., 1999. Brand Management Prognostications. MIT Sloan Management Review, 40(2), pp. 53-65.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Brexendorf, T. O., Bayus, B. &amp; Keller, K. L., 2015. Understanding the interplay between brand and innovation management: findings and future research directions. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, 43(5), pp. 548-557.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Brooker, G., 1984. An assessment of an expanded measure of perceived risk. In: T. C. Kinnear, ed. NA - Advances in Consumer Research. Provo: Association for Consumer Research, pp. 439-441.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Camisón, C. &amp; Villar-López, A., 2014. Organizational innovation as an enabler of technological innovation capabilities and firm performance. Journal of Business Research, 67(1), pp. 2891-2902.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Castaño, R., Sujan, m., Kacker , M. &amp; Sujan, H., 2008. Managing Consumer Uncertainty in the Adoption of New Products: Temporal Distance and Mental Simulation. Journal of Marketing Research, 45(3), pp. 320-336.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Chandy, R. K. &amp; Tellis, G., 2000. The incumbent’s curse? Incumbency, size, and radical product innovation. Journal of Marketing , 64(3), pp. 1-17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Chandy, R., Prabhu, J. &amp; Antia, K., 2003. What Will the Future Bring? Dominance, Technology Expectations, and Radical Innovation. Journal of Marketing, 67(3), pp. 1-18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Cooper, R. G., 1994. New products: the factors that drive success. International Marketing Review , 11(1), pp. 60-76.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Damanpour, F., Walker, R. &amp; Avellaneda, N., 2009. Combinative Effects of Innovation Types and Organizational Performance: A Longitudinal Study of Service Organizations. Journal of Management Studies , 46(4), pp. 650-675.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>DelVecchio, D. &amp; Smith, D., 2005. Brand-Extension Price Premiums: The Effects of Perceived Fit and Extension Product Category Risk. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science , 33(2), pp. 184-196.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Dhanora, M., Sharama, R. &amp; Khachoo, Q., 2017. Non-linear impact of product and process innovations on market power: A theoretical and empirical investigation. Economic Modelling. In Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Dowling, G. &amp; Staelin, R., 1994. A model of perceived risk and intended risk-handling activity. Journal of Consumer Research , 21(1), pp. 119-134.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Fadzline, P., Mat Nor, N.,  Mohamad, S.J. 2014. The Mediating Effect of Design Innovation between Brand Distinctiveness and Brand Performance: Evidence from Furniture Manufacturing Firms in Malaysia. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences 130, pp. 333-339.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Fang, E. 2008. Customer participation and the trade-off between new product innovativeness and speed to market. Journal of Marketing,72(4), pp. 90-104.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Florea, D.L. 2015. The Relationship between Branding and Diffusion of Innovation: A Systematic Review. Procedia Economics and Finance, 23, pp. 1527-1534.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Ghazinoory, S. &amp; Riahi, P. 1393. introduction to innovation system (broad approach). tehran, markaz-e-nashr-e daneshgahi.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Gill, T. &amp; Lei, J. 2009. Convergence in the High-Technology Consumer Markets: Not all Brands Gain Equally from Adding New Functionalities to Products. Marketing Letters, 20(1), pp. 91.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Gourville, J. T. 2006. Eager Sellers &amp; Stony Buyers. Harvard Business Review, 84(6), pp. 98-106.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Govindarajan, V. &amp; Kopalle, P.K. 2006. Disruptiveness of Innovations: Measurement and an Assessment of Reliability and Validity. Strategic Management Journal, 27(2), pp. 189-199.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Gunday, G. &amp; Alpkan, L., 2011. Effects of Innovation Types on Firm Performance. International Journal of production economics, 133(2), pp. 662-676.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Henderson, R. M. &amp; Clark, K.B. 1990. Architectural Innovation: The Reconfiguration of Existing Product Technologies and the Failure of Established Firms. Administrative Science Quarterly, 35(1), pp. 9-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Hoeffler, S. 2003. Measuring Preferences for Really New Products. Journal of Marketing Research, 40(4), pp. 406-420.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Janis, I.L. &amp; Mann, L. 1977. Decision making: A Psychological Analysis of Conflict, Choice, and Commitment, New York, NY: Free Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Karimian, H., Shekarchizadeh, A., Rismankarzadeh, R. 2015. An Investigation of Influential Factors in Choosing Brands of Washing Products by Female Isfahanis Customers. Marketing Management, Volume (10), pp. 17-34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Klink, R. R. &amp; Athaide, G. A. 2010. Consumer Innovativeness and the Use of New Versus Extended Brand Names for New Products. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 27(1), pp. 23-32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Kotler, P. &amp; Armstrong, G., 2016. Principles of Marketing, 16th Ed. Boston: Pearson.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Kotler, P. &amp; Dupree, J. 1997. Marketing Management: Analysis, Planning, Implementation, and Control, Test Item File, Prentice Hall.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Lim, K. &amp; O’Cass, A. 2001. Consumer Brand Classifications: an Assessment of Culture-of-Origin Versus Country-of-Origin. Journal of Product &amp; Brand Management, 10(2), pp. 120-136.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Mortensen, P. S. &amp; Bloch, C. W. 2005. Oslo Manual-Guidelines for Collecting and Interpreting Innovation Data: Proposed Guidelines for Collecting and Interpreting Innovation Data, Organisation for Economic Cooporation and Development, OECD.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson, R.R. &amp; Rosenberg, N. 1993. Technical Innovation and National Systems. National Innovation Systems: A Comparative Analysis, Volume (1), pp. 3-21.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Ogiba, E.F. 1988. The Dangers of Leveraging. Adweek, (January 4), 42.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Rezayi, H. 1394. Investigating Marketing Strategy for Tage New Product (Ultrapower). Forsat Emrooz.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Riley, F. D. O., Pina, J.M. &amp; Rafael, B. 2013. Downscale Extensions: Consumer Evaluation and Feedback Effects. Journal of Business Research, 66(2), pp. 196-206.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Rogers, E. M. 2010. Diffusion of Innovations, Free Press, 5th Edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Roselius, T. 1971. Consumer Rankings of Risk Reduction Methods. The Journal of Marketing, 35(1), pp. 56-61.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Ross, I. 1979. An Information Processing Theory of Consumer Choice, JSTOR, MA: Addison-Wesley Publishing Company.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Sehumpeter, J. A. 1934. The Theory of Economic Development: An Inquiry into Profits, Capital, Credit, Interest, and the Business Cycle. Social Science Electronic Publishing, 25(1), pp. 90-91.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, D. C. &amp; C. W. Park. 1992. The Effects of Brand Extensions on Market Share and Advertising Efficiency. Journal of Marketing Research, 29(3), pp. 296-313.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Somji, A. 2000. Inside New Product Statistics. Unpublished MA in Marketing Thesis. Kingston Business School, Kingston upon Thames, UK.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Wernerfelt, B. 1988. Umbrella branding as a signal of New Product Quality: An Example of Signalling by Posting a Bond. The RAND Journal of Economics, pp. 458-466.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Wu, Y., Balasubramanian, S. &amp; Mahajan, V., 2004. When is a Preannounced New Product Likely to be Delayed? Journal of Marketing, 68(2), pp. 101-113.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60175_cf8651aeea01a5d6df300d7fff3741e7.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>سیاست گذاری و مدیریت علم، فناوری، نوآوری و کارآفرینی و ارزیابی آن ها</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>دسته‌بندی ابزارهای سیاست نوآوری تقاضامحور با استفاده از رویکرد فراترکیب</article-title>
			        <subtitle>دسته‌بندی ابزارهای سیاست نوآوری تقاضامحور با استفاده از رویکرد فراترکیب</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محسنی کیاسری</surname>
			            <given-names>مصطفی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری ریاست جمهوری دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محمدی</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیات علمی دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>جعفر نژاد</surname>
			            <given-names>احمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیات علمی دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مختارزاده</surname>
			            <given-names>نیما</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیات علمی دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c5">
			          <name>
			            <surname>اسدی فرد</surname>
			            <given-names>رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>23</day>
			        <month>08</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>6</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>109</fpage>
			      <lpage>138</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>22</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>26</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60175.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60175.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>سیاست نوآوری تقاضامحور مجموعه‌ای از اقدامات عمومی برای افزایش تقاضای نوآوری، بهبود شرایط ادراک نوآوری یا بهبود بیان تقاضا به منظور ترغیب و انتشار نوآوری می‌باشد. این مقاله با بهره‌گیری از روش فراترکیب به دنبال ارائه دسته‌بندی جدیدی از ابزارهای سیاستی معرفی‌شده در مطالعات این حوزه می‌باشد. به‌این‌منظور بر اساس روش فراترکیب 252 مقاله و کتاب شناسایی شده از پایگاه‌های رسمی مقالات معتبر مورد بررسی قرار گرفته و پس از طی مراحل لازم 105 مقاله و کتاب مورد تحلیل نهایی قرار گرفته. تجزیه‌وتحلیل مقالات و نتایج روش فراترکیب نشان داد که ابزارهای تحریک طرف تقاضای نوآوری را می‌توان در قالب سه زمینه اصلی دسته‌بندی نمود که عبارتند از سیاست‌های محرک تقاضای دستگاه‌های دولتی(B2G)، سیاست‌های محرک تقاضای مصرف‌کنندگان نهایی(B2C) و سیاست‌های محرک تقاضای کسب‌وکارهای بزرگ‌تر (b2B). تحلیل انجام شده بیانگر این است که در دسته سوم از ابزارهای مذکور محققان مطالعات کمتری داشته‌اند و ابزارهای صریح و عملیاتی ارائه نشده و  خلاء پژوهشی در این دسته به چشم می‌آید که نیازمند پژوهش‌های بیشتر است.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>سیاستهای نوآوری تقاضامحور</kwd>
						<kwd>ابزارهای سیاستی</kwd>
						<kwd>فراترکیب</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Aschhoff, B. and Sofka, W. 2009. Innovation on demand-Can public procurement drive market success of innovations? Research Policy, 38(8), pp. 1235-1247.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Baindur, S. 2005. A demand-oriented stimulus program for university science commercialization. Ottaw a  Policy  Research  Associates.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Barroso, J. et al. 2003. The Challenges of Searching for and Retrieving Qualitative Studies. Western Journal of Nursing Research, 25(2), pp. 153-178.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Bench, S. and Day, T. 2010. The user experience of critical care discharge: A meta-synthesis of qualitative research. International Journal of Nursing Studies, 47(4), pp. 487-499.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Bilgram, V., Brem, A. and Voigt, K.-i. 2008. User-centric Innovations in New Product Development — Systematic Identification of Lead Users Harnessing Interactive and Collaborative Online-tools. International Journal of Innovation Management, 12(03), pp. 419-458.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Blind, K. 2004. New Products and Services:Analysis of Regulations Shaping New Markets. ReportKarlsruhe: European Commission.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Bogliacino, F.a.P., Mario 2009. Innovation performance in Europe: a long term perspective?, INNOMETRICS.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Boon, W.P.C., Moors, E.H.M., Kuhlmann, S. and Smits, R.E.H.M. 2011. Demand articulation in emerging technologies: Intermediary user organisations as co-producers? Research Policy, 40(2), pp. 242-252.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Borrás, S. and Edquist, C. 2013. The choice of innovation policy instruments. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 80(8), pp. 1513-1522.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Bottazzi, L., Da Rin, M. and Hellmann, T. 2003. The changing face of the European venture capital industry: Facts and analysis: Survey of European Venture Capital (SEVeCa).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Caiazza, R. 2016. A cross-national analysis of policies affecting innovation diffusion. The Journal of Technology Transfer, 41(6), pp. 1406-1419.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Cantner, U., Graf, H., Herrmann, J. and Kalthaus, M. 2016. Inventor networks in renewable energies: The influence of the policy mix in Germany. Research Policy, 45(6), pp. 1165-1184.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Cardullo, M.W. and Sage, A.P. 2004. Information, knowledge and systems management approaches for a new global reserve currency. Information, Knowledge, Systems Management, 10(1), pp. 427-444.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Caselli, S., Stefano, G. and Perrini, F. 2009. Are Venture Capitalists a Catalyst for Innovation? European Financial Management, 15(1), pp. 92-111.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Christensen, J.L. 2008. The IPR System, Venture Capital and Capital Markets-Contributions and Distortions of Small Firm Innovation? . Aalborg University, DRUID Copenhagen Business School, Department of Industrial Economics and Strategy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Cohen, B. and Amorós, J.E. 2014. Municipal demand-side policy tools and the strategic management of technology life cycles. Technovation, 34(12), pp. 797-806.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Cunningham, P. and Ramlogan, R. 2012. Compendium of Evidence on the Effectiveness of Innovation Policy Intervention: Innovation Networks. London and Manchester, NESTA and Manchester Institute of Innovation Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. 2007. Demand-based Innovation Policy. Manchester Business School Working Paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. 2009. Demand Policies for Innovation in EU CEE Countries. Manchester Business School Working Paper Research Paper No.579.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. 2010. Demand Oriented Innovation Policy. In R. K. Smits, S.; Shapira, P. ed. The Theory and Practice of Innovation Policy An International Research Handbook. Cheltenham, Edward Elgar,.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. 2011. Innovation in EU CEE – what role for demand based policy? In A. Kaderabkova and S. Radosevic eds. Challenges of innovation policy on European Periphery: A Schumpeterian Perspective. Cheltenham, Edward Elgar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J., Cameron, H. and Hajhashem, M. 2015. The intersection of intellectual property rights and innovation policy making - a literature review. World Intellectual Property Organization (WIPO).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. and Georghiou, L. 2007. Public procurement and innovation—Resurrecting the demand side. Research Policy, 36(7), pp. 949-963.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J., Georghiou, L., Blind, K. and Uyarra, E. 2012. Evaluating the demand side: New challenges for evaluation. Research Evaluation, 21(1), pp.33-47.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. and Yeow, J. 2016. Connecting demand and supply: The role of intermediation in public procurement of innovation. Research Policy, 45(2), pp. 414-426.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C. 2009. Public Procurement for Innovation (PPI) – a Pilot Study. Lund University, CIRCLE - Center for Innovation, Research and Competences in the Learning Economy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C. and Hommen, L. 1999. Systems of innovation: theory and policy for the demand side. Technology in Society, 21(1), pp. 63-79.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C., Hommen, L. and Tsipouri, L. 2000. Public Technology Procurement and Innovation. New York: Springer US.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C. and Zabala-Iturriagagoitia, J.M. 2012. Public Procurement for Innovation as mission-oriented innovation policy. Research Policy, 41(10), pp. 1757-1769.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C. and Zabala-Iturriagagoitia, J.M. 2015. Pre-commercial procurement: a demand or supply policy instrument in relation to innovation? R&amp;D Management, 45(2), pp. 147-160.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C., Zabala, J.M. and Timmermans, B. 2012. A Conceptual Framework for Analyzying the Relations between Demand and Public Innovative Procurement and between Knowledge Intensive Entrepreneurship and Innovation. Lund University, CIRCLE.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Elder, J. 2013. Review of Policy Measures to Stimulate Private Demand for Innovation. Concepts and Effects. Nesta Working Paper No. 13/13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>EuropeanCommission 2006. Creating an Innovative Europe. Report of the Independent Expert Group.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Frenkel, A., Maital, S., Leck, E. and Israel, E. 2015. Demand-Driven Innovation: An Integrative Systems-Based Review of the Literature. International Journal of Innovation and Technology Management,12(02).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Galbraith, B. and McAdam, R. 2013. The convergence of ICT, policy, intermediaries and society for technology transfer: evidence from European innovation projects. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management 25(3), pp. 249-252.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Georghiou, L., Edler, J., Uyarra, E. and Yeow, J. 2013. Policy instruments for public procurement of innovation: Choice, design and assessment. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Hannon, M.J., Foxon, T.J. and Gale, W.F. 2015. ‘Demand pull’ government policies to support Product-Service System activity: the case of Energy Service Companies (ESCos) in the UK. Journal of Cleaner Production, Volume (108), pp. 900-915.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Hospers, G., Sautet, F. and Desrochers, P. 2008. Silicon Somewhere: Is there a Need for Cluster Policy? In C. Karlsson ed. Handbook of research on innovation and clusters: cases and policies. Cheltenham, Edward Elgar Publishing. pp. 430-446.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Izsak, K. and Edler, J. 2011. Trends and Challenges in Demand-Side Innovation Policies in Europe. technopolis-group.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Kaiser, R. and Kripp, M. 2010. Demand-orientation in national systems of innovation: a critical review of current european innovation policy concepts. Druid Conference on “Opening Up Innovation: Strategy, Organization and Technology”  Imperial College London Business School, Druid.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Ketels, C., Lindqvist, G. and Sölvell 2006. Cluster Initiatives in Developing and Transition Economies. Stockholm, Center for Strategy and Competitiveness.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Kuusisto, J. 2008. Mapping Service Innovation Policy in the Nordic Countries. ServINNo.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Landoni, M. 2011. emand driven innovation policy by forward public procurement: The Italian aerospace industry case. Post-Crisis Post-Lisbon Economic and Social Policy: A New Era?</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Lember, V., Kattel, R. and Kalvet, T. 2011. Public procurement, innovation and policy : international perspectives. Urban Studies, 48(7), pp. 1373–1395.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B.-A. 1992. National Systems of innovation, Towards a Theory of Innovation and Interactive Learning. London: London UK and New York, USA: Pinter.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B.-A. 1998. Technological change and economic theory: innovation as an interactive process. From user-producer interaction to the national system 300 The Theory and Practice of Innovation Policy of innovation. In e. a. G. Dosi ed. Technical Change and Economic Theory. London, UK and New York, USA: Pinter. pp. 349-369.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Malhotra, A., Gosain, S. and Sawy, O.A.E. 2005. Absorptive Capacity Configurations in Supply Chains: Gearing for Partner-Enabled Market Knowledge Creation. MIS Quarterly, 29(1), pp. 145-187.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Miles, I. 2010. Demand-led innovation. INNO-GRIPS (Global Review of Innovation Intelligence and Policy Studies).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Moensted, M. 2007. Strategic networking in small high tech firms. International Entrepreneurship and Management Journal, 3(1), pp. 15-27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Moors, E., Enzing, C., Van Der Giessen, A. and Smits, R. 2003. User–producer interactions in functional genomics innovations. Innovation, 5(2-3), pp. 120-143.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>OECD 2014. Intelligent Demand: Policy Rationale, Design and Potential Benefits: OECD Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Porter, M.E. 2000. Location, Competition and Economic Development: Local Clusters in a Global Economy. Economic Development Quarterly, 14(1), pp. 15-34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Rank, D. 2002. Evaluation of the Networks of Centres of Excellence: Final Report. KPMG Consulting LP.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Rolfstam, M. 2005. Public Technology Procurement as a Demand-side Innovation Policy Instrument – an Overview of Recent Literatureand Events. European Commission.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Rolfstam, M. 2012a. An institutional approach to research on public procurement of innovation. Innovation, The European Journal of Social Science Research, 25(3), pp. 303-321.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Rolfstam, M. 2012b. Public procurement of innovation: demand as in command or facilitation of endogenous knowledge conversion?</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Rolfstam, M. 2012c. Understanding  Public  Procurement  of  Innovation: Definitions, Innovation types and Interaction modes. Social Science Research Network.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Roolaht, T. 2010a. The demand-side innovation policies in the context of small EU member country. Estonian Discussions on Economic Policy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Roolaht, T. 2010b. The demand-side innovation policies in the context of small EU member country. Estonian Discussions on Economic Policy 18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Rothwell, R. 1984. Technology-Based Small Firms and Regional Innovation Potential: The Role of Public Procurement. Journal of Public Policy, 4(4), pp. 307-332.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Sandelowski, M. and Barroso, J. 2007. Handbook for Synthesizing Qualitative Research. New York: Springer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Smits, R. 2002. Innovation studies in the 21st century;: Questions from a user’s perspective. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 69(9), pp. 861-883.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Spencer, G.M., Vinodrai, T., Gertler, M.S. and Wolfe, D.A. 2010. Do Clusters Make a Difference? Defining and Assessing their Economic Performance. Regional Studies, 44 (6), pp. 697-715.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Stephenson, K. 2010. How networks of trust can unlock innovation. . NESTA Guest Article.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Strauss, A. and Corbin, J. 1998. Basics of qualitative research: Techniques and procedures for Developing grounded theory. Thousand Oaks: CA: Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Summers, J.A. et al. 2008. A preliminary synthesis of qualitative research: Gaining emotional well-being from other parents. Beach Center on Disability State of the Science Conference. Washington, DC.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Swink, M. 2006. Building Collaborative Innovation Capability. Research-Technology Management, 49(2), pp.37-47.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Timmermans, B. and Zabala-Iturriagagoitia, J.M. 2013. Coordinated unbundling: A way to stimulate entrepreneurship through public procurement for innovation. Science and Public Policy, 40(5), pp. 674-685.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Uyarra, E. 2013. Review of Measures in Support of Public Procurement of Innovation. Nesta Working Paper. Nesta.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Uyarra, E. and Ramlogan, R. 2012. The effects of Cluster Policy on innovation. Compendium of Evidence on the Effectiveness of Innovation Policy Intervention. Manchester Institute of Innovation Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Vecchiato, R. and Roveda, C. 2014. Foresight  for  public  procurement  and  regional  innovation  policy: The  case  of  Lombardy, 43, pp. 438-450.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Zimmer, L. 2006. Qualitative meta-synthesis: a question of dialoguing with texts. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 53(3), pp. 311-318.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>قاضی‌نوری، س.، آزادگان مهر، م.، سیاست نوآوری در تئوری و عمل،1393. اصفهان، نشر دارخوین.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>نقی‌زاده، ر.، الهی، ش.، منطقی، م. قاضی‌نوری، س. 1393. فراترکیب مدل‌های نوآوری منطقه‌ای: مروری بر سال‌های 2013-1990. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مدیریت نوآوری سال سوم(شماره چهارم).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>نوروزی، ن.، الهی، ش.، حسنزاده، ع. حاجی‌حسینی، ح. 1393. ارائه چارچوبی از ابزارهای سیاستی علم و فناوری، با استفاده از رویکرد فراترکیب. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مدیریت نوآوری 3(2)، صص 124-103.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>ودادهیر، ا. 1390. فراترکیب نتایج واکاوی‌های کیفی و مطالعات فرهنگی: واقعیت یا توهم. فصلنامه مطالعات فرهنگی دانشگاه تهران. 22(برگ فرهنگ)،صص 24-45._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Aschhoff, B. and Sofka, W. 2009. Innovation on demand-Can public procurement drive market success of innovations? Research Policy, 38(8), pp. 1235-1247.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Baindur, S. 2005. A demand-oriented stimulus program for university science commercialization. Ottaw a  Policy  Research  Associates.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Barroso, J. et al. 2003. The Challenges of Searching for and Retrieving Qualitative Studies. Western Journal of Nursing Research, 25(2), pp. 153-178.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Bench, S. and Day, T. 2010. The user experience of critical care discharge: A meta-synthesis of qualitative research. International Journal of Nursing Studies, 47(4), pp. 487-499.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Bilgram, V., Brem, A. and Voigt, K.-i. 2008. User-centric Innovations in New Product Development — Systematic Identification of Lead Users Harnessing Interactive and Collaborative Online-tools. International Journal of Innovation Management, 12(03), pp. 419-458.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Blind, K. 2004. New Products and Services:Analysis of Regulations Shaping New Markets. ReportKarlsruhe: European Commission.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Bogliacino, F.a.P., Mario 2009. Innovation performance in Europe: a long term perspective?, INNOMETRICS.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Boon, W.P.C., Moors, E.H.M., Kuhlmann, S. and Smits, R.E.H.M. 2011. Demand articulation in emerging technologies: Intermediary user organisations as co-producers? Research Policy, 40(2), pp. 242-252.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Borrás, S. and Edquist, C. 2013. The choice of innovation policy instruments. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 80(8), pp. 1513-1522.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Bottazzi, L., Da Rin, M. and Hellmann, T. 2003. The changing face of the European venture capital industry: Facts and analysis: Survey of European Venture Capital (SEVeCa).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Caiazza, R. 2016. A cross-national analysis of policies affecting innovation diffusion. The Journal of Technology Transfer, 41(6), pp. 1406-1419.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Cantner, U., Graf, H., Herrmann, J. and Kalthaus, M. 2016. Inventor networks in renewable energies: The influence of the policy mix in Germany. Research Policy, 45(6), pp. 1165-1184.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Cardullo, M.W. and Sage, A.P. 2004. Information, knowledge and systems management approaches for a new global reserve currency. Information, Knowledge, Systems Management, 10(1), pp. 427-444.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Caselli, S., Stefano, G. and Perrini, F. 2009. Are Venture Capitalists a Catalyst for Innovation? European Financial Management, 15(1), pp. 92-111.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Christensen, J.L. 2008. The IPR System, Venture Capital and Capital Markets-Contributions and Distortions of Small Firm Innovation? . Aalborg University, DRUID Copenhagen Business School, Department of Industrial Economics and Strategy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Cohen, B. and Amorós, J.E. 2014. Municipal demand-side policy tools and the strategic management of technology life cycles. Technovation, 34(12), pp. 797-806.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Cunningham, P. and Ramlogan, R. 2012. Compendium of Evidence on the Effectiveness of Innovation Policy Intervention: Innovation Networks. London and Manchester, NESTA and Manchester Institute of Innovation Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. 2007. Demand-based Innovation Policy. Manchester Business School Working Paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. 2009. Demand Policies for Innovation in EU CEE Countries. Manchester Business School Working Paper Research Paper No.579.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. 2010. Demand Oriented Innovation Policy. In R. K. Smits, S.; Shapira, P. ed. The Theory and Practice of Innovation Policy An International Research Handbook. Cheltenham, Edward Elgar,.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. 2011. Innovation in EU CEE – what role for demand based policy? In A. Kaderabkova and S. Radosevic eds. Challenges of innovation policy on European Periphery: A Schumpeterian Perspective. Cheltenham, Edward Elgar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J., Cameron, H. and Hajhashem, M. 2015. The intersection of intellectual property rights and innovation policy making - a literature review. World Intellectual Property Organization (WIPO).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. and Georghiou, L. 2007. Public procurement and innovation—Resurrecting the demand side. Research Policy, 36(7), pp. 949-963.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J., Georghiou, L., Blind, K. and Uyarra, E. 2012. Evaluating the demand side: New challenges for evaluation. Research Evaluation, 21(1), pp.33-47.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Edler, J. and Yeow, J. 2016. Connecting demand and supply: The role of intermediation in public procurement of innovation. Research Policy, 45(2), pp. 414-426.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C. 2009. Public Procurement for Innovation (PPI) – a Pilot Study. Lund University, CIRCLE - Center for Innovation, Research and Competences in the Learning Economy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C. and Hommen, L. 1999. Systems of innovation: theory and policy for the demand side. Technology in Society, 21(1), pp. 63-79.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C., Hommen, L. and Tsipouri, L. 2000. Public Technology Procurement and Innovation. New York: Springer US.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C. and Zabala-Iturriagagoitia, J.M. 2012. Public Procurement for Innovation as mission-oriented innovation policy. Research Policy, 41(10), pp. 1757-1769.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C. and Zabala-Iturriagagoitia, J.M. 2015. Pre-commercial procurement: a demand or supply policy instrument in relation to innovation? R&amp;D Management, 45(2), pp. 147-160.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C., Zabala, J.M. and Timmermans, B. 2012. A Conceptual Framework for Analyzying the Relations between Demand and Public Innovative Procurement and between Knowledge Intensive Entrepreneurship and Innovation. Lund University, CIRCLE.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Elder, J. 2013. Review of Policy Measures to Stimulate Private Demand for Innovation. Concepts and Effects. Nesta Working Paper No. 13/13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>EuropeanCommission 2006. Creating an Innovative Europe. Report of the Independent Expert Group.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Frenkel, A., Maital, S., Leck, E. and Israel, E. 2015. Demand-Driven Innovation: An Integrative Systems-Based Review of the Literature. International Journal of Innovation and Technology Management,12(02).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>Galbraith, B. and McAdam, R. 2013. The convergence of ICT, policy, intermediaries and society for technology transfer: evidence from European innovation projects. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management 25(3), pp. 249-252.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>Georghiou, L., Edler, J., Uyarra, E. and Yeow, J. 2013. Policy instruments for public procurement of innovation: Choice, design and assessment. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Ghazinoori, S., Azadeganmehr, M., 2014. Policy of innovation in theory and practice. Isfahan, Darkhoein publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>Hannon, M.J., Foxon, T.J. and Gale, W.F. 2015. ‘Demand pull’ government policies to support Product-Service System activity: the case of Energy Service Companies (ESCos) in the UK. Journal of Cleaner Production, Volume (108), pp. 900-915.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R115">
			<label>115</label>
			<element-citation>Hospers, G., Sautet, F. and Desrochers, P. 2008. Silicon Somewhere: Is there a Need for Cluster Policy? In C. Karlsson ed. Handbook of research on innovation and clusters: cases and policies. Cheltenham, Edward Elgar Publishing. pp. 430-446.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R116">
			<label>116</label>
			<element-citation>Izsak, K. and Edler, J. 2011. Trends and Challenges in Demand-Side Innovation Policies in Europe. technopolis-group.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R117">
			<label>117</label>
			<element-citation>Kaiser, R. and Kripp, M. 2010. Demand-orientation in national systems of innovation: a critical review of current european innovation policy concepts. Druid Conference on “Opening Up Innovation: Strategy, Organization and Technology”  Imperial College London Business School, Druid.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R118">
			<label>118</label>
			<element-citation>Ketels, C., Lindqvist, G. and Sölvell 2006. Cluster Initiatives in Developing and Transition Economies. Stockholm, Center for Strategy and Competitiveness.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R119">
			<label>119</label>
			<element-citation>Kuusisto, J. 2008. Mapping Service Innovation Policy in the Nordic Countries. ServINNo.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R120">
			<label>120</label>
			<element-citation>Landoni, M. 2011. emand driven innovation policy by forward public procurement: The Italian aerospace industry case. Post-Crisis Post-Lisbon Economic and Social Policy: A New Era?</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R121">
			<label>121</label>
			<element-citation>Lember, V., Kattel, R. and Kalvet, T. 2011. Public procurement, innovation and policy : international perspectives. Urban Studies, 48(7), pp. 1373–1395.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R122">
			<label>122</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B.-A. 1992. National Systems of innovation, Towards a Theory of Innovation and Interactive Learning. London: London UK and New York, USA: Pinter.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R123">
			<label>123</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B.-A. 1998. Technological change and economic theory: innovation as an interactive process. From user-producer interaction to the national system 300 The Theory and Practice of Innovation Policy of innovation. In e. a. G. Dosi ed. Technical Change and Economic Theory. London, UK and New York, USA: Pinter. pp. 349-369.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R124">
			<label>124</label>
			<element-citation>Malhotra, A., Gosain, S. and Sawy, O.A.E. 2005. Absorptive Capacity Configurations in Supply Chains: Gearing for Partner-Enabled Market Knowledge Creation. MIS Quarterly, 29(1), pp. 145-187.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R125">
			<label>125</label>
			<element-citation>Miles, I. 2010. Demand-led innovation. INNO-GRIPS (Global Review of Innovation Intelligence and Policy Studies).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R126">
			<label>126</label>
			<element-citation>Moensted, M. 2007. Strategic networking in small high tech firms. International Entrepreneurship and Management Journal, 3(1), pp. 15-27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R127">
			<label>127</label>
			<element-citation>Moors, E., Enzing, C., Van Der Giessen, A. and Smits, R. 2003. User–producer interactions in functional genomics innovations. Innovation, 5(2-3), pp. 120-143.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R128">
			<label>128</label>
			<element-citation>Naghizadeh, R., Elahi, Sh., Manteghi, M.  Ghazinoori, S., 2014. The Meta-Synthesis of Regional Innovation Models: A Review of 1990–2013. Innovation Management Journal, 3(4), pp. 25-56.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R129">
			<label>129</label>
			<element-citation>Norouzi, N, Elahi, Sh., Hasanzadeh, As., Haji Hosseini, H., 2014. Proposing a Framework of Policy Instruments in Science and Technology Policies: Based on Meta-synthesis Approach. Innovation Management Journal. 3(2), pp. 103-124.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R130">
			<label>130</label>
			<element-citation>OECD 2014. Intelligent Demand: Policy Rationale, Design and Potential Benefits: OECD Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R131">
			<label>131</label>
			<element-citation>Porter, M.E. 2000. Location, Competition and Economic Development: Local Clusters in a Global Economy. Economic Development Quarterly, 14(1), pp. 15-34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R132">
			<label>132</label>
			<element-citation>Rank, D. 2002. Evaluation of the Networks of Centres of Excellence: Final Report. KPMG Consulting LP.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R133">
			<label>133</label>
			<element-citation>Rolfstam, M. 2005. Public Technology Procurement as a Demand-side Innovation Policy Instrument – an Overview of Recent Literatureand Events. European Commission.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R134">
			<label>134</label>
			<element-citation>Rolfstam, M. 2012a. An institutional approach to research on public procurement of innovation. Innovation, The European Journal of Social Science Research, 25(3), pp. 303-321.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R135">
			<label>135</label>
			<element-citation>Rolfstam, M. 2012b. Public procurement of innovation: demand as in command or facilitation of endogenous knowledge conversion?</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R136">
			<label>136</label>
			<element-citation>Rolfstam, M. 2012c. Understanding  Public  Procurement  of  Innovation: Definitions, Innovation types and Interaction modes. Social Science Research Network.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R137">
			<label>137</label>
			<element-citation>Roolaht, T. 2010a. The demand-side innovation policies in the context of small EU member country. Estonian Discussions on Economic Policy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R138">
			<label>138</label>
			<element-citation>Roolaht, T. 2010b. The demand-side innovation policies in the context of small EU member country. Estonian Discussions on Economic Policy 18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R139">
			<label>139</label>
			<element-citation>Rothwell, R. 1984. Technology-Based Small Firms and Regional Innovation Potential: The Role of Public Procurement. Journal of Public Policy, 4(4), pp. 307-332.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R140">
			<label>140</label>
			<element-citation>Sandelowski, M. and Barroso, J. 2007. Handbook for Synthesizing Qualitative Research. New York: Springer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R141">
			<label>141</label>
			<element-citation>Smits, R. 2002. Innovation studies in the 21st century;: Questions from a user’s perspective. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 69(9), pp. 861-883.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R142">
			<label>142</label>
			<element-citation>Spencer, G.M., Vinodrai, T., Gertler, M.S. and Wolfe, D.A. 2010. Do Clusters Make a Difference? Defining and Assessing their Economic Performance. Regional Studies, 44 (6), pp. 697-715.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R143">
			<label>143</label>
			<element-citation>Stephenson, K. 2010. How networks of trust can unlock innovation. . NESTA Guest Article.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R144">
			<label>144</label>
			<element-citation>Strauss, A. and Corbin, J. 1998. Basics of qualitative research: Techniques and procedures for Developing grounded theory. Thousand Oaks: CA: Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R145">
			<label>145</label>
			<element-citation>Summers, J.A. et al. 2008. A preliminary synthesis of qualitative research: Gaining emotional well-being from other parents. Beach Center on Disability State of the Science Conference. Washington, DC.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R146">
			<label>146</label>
			<element-citation>Swink, M. 2006. Building Collaborative Innovation Capability. Research-Technology Management, 49(2), pp.37-47.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R147">
			<label>147</label>
			<element-citation>Timmermans, B. and Zabala-Iturriagagoitia, J.M. 2013. Coordinated unbundling: A way to stimulate entrepreneurship through public procurement for innovation. Science and Public Policy, 40(5), pp. 674-685.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R148">
			<label>148</label>
			<element-citation>Uyarra, E. 2013. Review of Measures in Support of Public Procurement of Innovation. Nesta Working Paper. Nesta.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R149">
			<label>149</label>
			<element-citation>Uyarra, E. and Ramlogan, R. 2012. The effects of Cluster Policy on innovation. Compendium of Evidence on the Effectiveness of Innovation Policy Intervention. Manchester Institute of Innovation Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R150">
			<label>150</label>
			<element-citation>Vadadhir, A., 2011. The Meta-combination of Qualitative Analysis and Cultural Studies: Reality or Illusion. Quarterly Barg-e Farhang, Volume (22), pp. 24-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R151">
			<label>151</label>
			<element-citation>Vecchiato, R. and Roveda, C. 2014. Foresight  for  public  procurement  and  regional  innovation  policy: The  case  of  Lombardy, 43, pp. 438-450.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R152">
			<label>152</label>
			<element-citation>Zimmer, L. 2006. Qualitative meta-synthesis: a question of dialoguing with texts. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 53(3), pp. 311-318.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60174_d732e36b4d2fc00893877aa11dd1d441.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>نوآوری، اقتصاد و خلق ثروت</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>نقش مخارج تحقیق و توسعه در میان عوامل موثر بر بهره وری نیروی کار (مورد ایران و شرکای تجاری منتخب)</article-title>
			        <subtitle>نقش مخارج تحقیق و توسعه در میان عوامل موثر بر بهره وری نیروی کار (مورد ایران و شرکای تجاری منتخب)</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نجفی</surname>
			            <given-names>زهرا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>مربی گروه اقتصاد دانشگاه پیام نور</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>آذربایجانی</surname>
			            <given-names>کریم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استاد گروه اقتصاد، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد، اصفهان، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>23</day>
			        <month>08</month>
			        <year>2017</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>6</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>139</fpage>
			      <lpage>162</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2017</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>18</day>
			          <month>01</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2017, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2017</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60174.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60174.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>ارتقاء سطح بهره‌وری عوامل تولید یکی از مهم‌ترین مولفه‌های تاثیرگذار بر رشد و توسعه اقتصادی کشورها محسوب می‌شود براساس نظریه‌های رشد اقتصادی درون‌زا، فعالیت‌های تحقیق‌وتوسعه داخلی ، موجب استفاده موثرتر از منابع موجود و جذب فناوری پیشرفته خارجی در تولید کالاها و خدمات قابل تجارت می‌گردد و در نهایت بهبود بهره‌وری تولید ارتقاء می‌یابد. با توجه به اهمیت موضوع، این پژوهش سعی دارد  عوامل موثر بر بهره‌وری نیروی کار در کشور ایران و شرکای تجاری منتخب آن در طول سال‌های 2014-2004 با استفاده از روش پنل- دیتا بررسی کند. نتایج به دست آمده حاکی از آن است که متغیرهای امید به زندگی و سرمایه انسانی به ترتیب با داشتن ضریب 74/30 و 11/0، بیشترین و کمترین تاثیر را بر شاخص بهره‌وری نیروی کار دارند. از طرفی، متغیر مخارج تحقیق‌وتوسعه با ضریب 71/1 دارای تاثیر مثبت بر بهره‌وری نیروی کار است، اگرچه برطبق جایگاه مهم و حائز اهمیت این متغیر، توجه چندانی  به آن صورت نگرفته است.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>بهره وری نیروی کار</kwd>
						<kwd>مخارج تحقیق و توسعه</kwd>
						<kwd>سرمایه انسانی</kwd>
						<kwd>امید به زندگی</kwd>
						<kwd>روش پانل دیتا</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Aghion, P. a. H. P., 1992. A model of growth through creative destruction. Econometrica, 60(2), pp. 323-351.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Anon., 2013. Global Competitiveness Report, World Economic Forum.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Aparicio, S. D. U. &amp;. D. A., 2016. Institutional factors, Opportunity entrepreneurship and economic growth: panel data evidence. Technological Forcasting &amp; Social Change, Volume 102, pp. 45-61.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Baumol, W. J., 1990. Entrepreneurship: Productive, Unproductive, and Destructive. The Journal of Political Economy, 98(5), pp. 893-921.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Bowen, H. D. C. D., 2008. Institutional Context and the Allocation of Entrepreneurial Effort. Journal of International Business Studies, 39(4), pp. 747-767.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Cassiman, B. &amp;. G. E. &amp;. M.-R. E., 2010. Innovation, Export and Productivity. International Journal of Industrial Organization, 28(4), pp. 372-376.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Cavdar, S. C. a. A. A. D., 2015. An Empirical Analysis about Technological Development and Innovation Indicator. World Conference on Technology, Innovation and Entrepreneurship, Procedia- Social and Behavioral</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Coe, D. T. W. H. a. H. A., 2008. International R&amp;D Spillovers and Institutions. International Monetary Fund WP/08/104 IMF Working Paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Crespi, G. a. Z. p., 2012. Innovation and Productivity: Evidence from Six Latin American Countries. World Development, 40(2), pp. 273-290.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Dolores, A. H., 2007. The Impact of R&amp;D Spillovers on UK Manufacturing: A Dynamic Panel Approach. Research Policy, Volume 36, pp. 964-979.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Estrada, A. L.-S. D., 2001. Accounting for Spanish productivity growth using sectoral data: New Evidence. Working Papers 0110, Banco de España;Working Papers Homepage. .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Griliches, Z., 1979. Issues in assessing the contribution of Research &amp; Development to Productivity Growth. Bell Journal of Economics, Volume 10, pp. 92-116.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Griliches, Z., 1986. Productivity, R&amp;D and basic research at the firm level in the 1970’s. American Economic Review, Volume 76, pp. 141-154.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Grosman, G. M. a. H. E., 1991. Trade, Knowledge Spillovers, and Growth. European Economic Review, 35(2-3), pp. 517-526.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Harrison, R. T. M. C. M. &amp;. G. P., 2004. Financial Bootstrapping and Venture Development in the Software Industry. Entrepreneurship &amp; Regional Development, 16(4), pp. 307-333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Landon-Lane, J. S. &amp;. R. P. E., 2003. Accumulation and Productivity Growth in Industrializing Economies. Australia: The University of New South Wales, School of Economics.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Minniti, M., 2005. Entrepreneurship &amp; Network Externalities. Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, 57(1), pp. 1-27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>OECD, 2005. OsloManual. Proposed Guidelines for Collecting and Interpreting Technological Innovation Data , Paris.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Ortega, C. a. M. C., 2008. Exploring the Relationship Between R&amp;D and Productivity: A Country-level Study. Central Bank of Chile, Working Papers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Rodil Marzabal, O. V. X. &amp;. S. C. M. C., 2015. The relationship between innovation and export behaviour: The case of Galician firms. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Volume 113, pp. 248–265 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Romer, P. M., 1990. “Endogenous technological change. Journal of political Economy, 98(5), pp. 71-102.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Senhadji, A., 2000. Source of Economic Growth: An Extensive Growth Accounting Exercies. IMF Staff  Papers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Soderbom, M. T. F., 2003. Openness and human capital as source of productivity growth: An empirical investigation. Oxford: Centre for Study of African Economics.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Verner, D., 1999. Wages and Productivity Gaps: Evidence from Ghana. World Bank, Human Development, Africa technical Families, Volume 3.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Zachariadis, M., 2003. R&amp;D, Innovation, and Technological Progress: A test of the Schumpeterian Framework without Scale Effects. Canadian Journal of Economics, 36(3), pp. 566-686.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>ابونوری، عباسعلی، مهدی حنطه و آزیتا قربانی جاهد، 1392، بررسی نقش مولفه­های اقتصاد دانش بنیان بر بهر هوری کل عوامل تولید، پژوهشنامه اقتصاد کلان، سال هشتم، شماره 16، صص. 52 - 31 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>باقرزاده، علی و اکبر کمیجانی، 1389، تحلیل اثر تحقی قوتوسعه داخلی و خارجی بر بهر هوری کل عوامل تولید در بخش کشاورزی ایران، فصلنامه مدلسازی اقتصادی، شماره 1، صص. 93 - 119 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>تشکینی، احمد، 1384 ، اقتصاد سنجی کاربردی به کمک Microfit ، موسسه فرهنگی هنری دیباگران تهران، چاپ اول.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>تی اچ میوز، ماریوس و ادکوئیست، چارلز، 1389 ، مقدم های بر نوآوری در محصول و فرآیند، ترجمه: معصومه پورجعفری مقدم، مجله اقتصادی، ماهنامه بررسی مسائل و سیاس تهای اقتصادی، شمار ههای 7 و 8، صص 87 - 106 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>خاندوزی، سیداحسان، 1384 ، انگاره پورتر در تجارت و مزیت رقابتی، مجله راهبرد یاس )توسعه(، سال اول، شماره چهارم، صص 83 - 102 ._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Abasali, A., Hanteh, M. &amp; Ghorbani Jahed, A., 2013. Investigating the Role of Knowledge Based Economics Components on Total Productivity Productivity. Journal of Macroeconomics (Journal of Economics Sciences), 8(16), pp. 31-52.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Aghion, P. a. H. P., 1992. A model of growth through creative destruction. Econometrica, 60(2), pp. 323-351.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Anon., 2013. Global Competitiveness Report, World Economic Forum.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Aparicio, S. D. U. &amp;. D. A., 2016. Institutional factors, Opportunity entrepreneurship and economic growth: panel data evidence. Technological Forcasting &amp; Social Change, Volume 102, pp. 45-61.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Bagherzadeh, A., Komeijani, A., 2010. The Analysis of the Domestic and International R&amp;D Impact of Agricultural TFP in Iran. Quarterly Economic Modelling, 4(11), pp. 93-119.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Baumol, W. J., 1990. Entrepreneurship: Productive, Unproductive, and Destructive. The Journal of Political Economy, 98(5), pp. 893-921.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Bowen, H. D. C. D., 2008. Institutional Context and the Allocation of Entrepreneurial Effort. Journal of International Business Studies, 39(4), pp. 747-767.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Cassiman, B. &amp;. G. E. &amp;. M.-R. E., 2010. Innovation, Export and Productivity. International Journal of Industrial Organization, 28(4), pp. 372-376.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Cavdar, S. C. a. A. A. D., 2015. An Empirical Analysis about Technological Development and Innovation Indicator. World Conference on Technology, Innovation and Entrepreneurship, Procedia- Social and Behavioral Science.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Coe, D. T. W. H. a. H. A., 2008. International R&amp;D Spillovers and Institutions. International Monetary Fund WP/08/104 IMF Working Paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Crespi, G. a. Z. p., 2012. Innovation and Productivity: Evidence from Six Latin American Countries. World Development, 40(2), pp. 273-290.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Dargahi, H. &amp; Ghdiri, A., 2003. The Determinants of Economic Growth in the Iranian Economy: (With Emphasis on Endogenous Growth Models). Iranian Journal of Trade Studies (Ijts), 7(26), pp. 1-33.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Dolores, A. H., 2007. The Impact of R&amp;D Spillovers on UK Manufacturing: A Dynamic Panel Approach. Research Policy, Volume 36, pp. 964-979.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Estrada, A. L.-S. D., 2001. Accounting for Spanish productivity growth using sectoral data: New Evidence. Working Papers 0110, Banco de España;Working Papers Homepage. .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Gujarati, D., 2006. Basic econometrics. 4rd ed, Translated By: Abrishami, H., Tehran University Press. </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Griliches, Z., 1979. Issues in assessing the contribution of Research &amp; Development to Productivity Growth. Bell Journal of Economics, Volume 10, pp. 92-116.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Griliches, Z., 1986. Productivity, R&amp;D and basic research at the firm level in the 1970’s. American Economic Review, Volume 76, pp. 141-154.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Grosman, G. M. a. H. E., 1991. Trade, Knowledge Spillovers, and Growth. European Economic Review, 35(2-3), pp. 517-526.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Harrison, R. T. M. C. M. &amp;. G. P., 2004. Financial Bootstrapping and Venture Development in the Software Industry. Entrepreneurship &amp; Regional Development, 16(4), pp. 307-333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Komeijani, A., Padash, H. &amp; Sadeghin, A., 2013. A Strategic Analysis on the Effect of Human Capital on Labour Productivity Growth. Economic Strategy, 1(3), pp. 7-36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Khandoozi, S. E., 2005. Porter's idea of trading and competitive advantage. Development Strategy, 1(4), pp. 83-102.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Landon-Lane, J. S. &amp;. R. P. E., 2003. Accumulation and Productivity Growth in Industrializing Economies. Australia: The University of New South Wales, School of Economics.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation> Meeus, M. &amp; Edquist, Ch., 2010. Introduction to Part I: Product and process innovation. Economic Journal, 10(7-8), pp. 87-106.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Mehregan, N. &amp; Soltani Sehat, L., 2014. R &amp; D costs and total industrial productivity of the industrial sector. Quarterly Journal of the Marco and Strategic Policies, 2(5), pp. 1-14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Minniti, M., 2005. Entrepreneurship &amp; Network Externalities. Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, 57(1), pp. 1-27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Najafi, Z. &amp; Azarbaiijani, K., 2017. Investigating the Effective Factors is Labor Force Productivity in Production Function, Frame Work (With emphasis on entrepreneurship. Journal of Productivity Managementm, 11(42), pp. 7-35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Nikoomaram, H., Rahnemay Roudposhti, F., Jokar Tang Karami, I., 2014. Determination of the Role of Foreign Trade and Innovation on Economic Growth of Iran by the Acquisition of Foreign Technology. Financial Knowledge of Security Analysis (Financial Studies), 6(20), pp. 91-108.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>OECD, 2005. OsloManual. Proposed Guidelines for Collecting and Interpreting Technological Innovation Data , Paris.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Ortega, C. a. M. C., 2008. Exploring the Relationship Between R&amp;D and Productivity: A Country-level Study. Central Bank of Chile, Working Papers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Rabiei, M., 2009. The Effect of Innovation and Human Capital on Iran’s Economic Growth. Quarterly Knowledge and Development, 16(26), pp.122-142.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Romer, D., 2010. Advanced Macroeconomics. Translated By: Taghavi, M., Islamic Azad University Press, Science and Research Branch, Tehran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Rodil Marzabal, O. V. X. &amp;. S. C. M. C., 2015. The relationship between innovation and export behaviour: The case of Galician firms. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Volume 113, pp. 248–265 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Romer, P. M., 1990. “Endogenous technological change. Journal of political Economy, 98(5), pp. 71-102.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Senhadji, A., 2000. Source of Economic Growth: An Extensive Growth Accounting Exercies. IMF Staff  Papers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Shahabadi, A. &amp; Amiri, M., 2014. The Effect of Domestic R&amp;d Stock and R&amp;d Stock Spillovers on Total Factor Productivity Growth of Agriculture Sector in Iran. Quarterly Journal of Applied Economics Studies, 3(9), pp. 93-114.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Shavalpour, S., 2013. Estimating the Effects of Technology Development on Total Factor Productivity in Iran. Journal of Economic Modeling Research, 3(11), pp. 141-160.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Soderbom, M. T. F., 2003. Openness and human capital as source of productivity growth: An empirical investigation. Oxford: Centre for Study of African Economics.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Souri, A., 2015. Advanced econometrics (Volume 2). Tehran: Nashre Cultural science.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Tabrizi Moghadam, N., &amp; Valizadeh Zenoor, P., 2006.  Efficiency Survey in Iranian Economy. Trend (Trend of Economic Research), 16(49), pp. 15-41.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Taher, B., 2015. Investigating Factors Affecting Human Resource Efficiency. Monthly Social, Economic, Scientific and Cultural Work and Society, Volume(190), pp. 58-71.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Taiebi, K., Emadzadeh, M. &amp; Sheikh Bahaei, A., 2009. The Effect of Foreign Trade and Human Capital on Economic Growth in Oic Countries. Tahghighat-e-eghtesadim, 43(85), pp. 238-256.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Tashkini, A., 2005. Applied Econometrics with the help of Microfit. 1th edition, Dbagaran Tehran Art and Cultural Institute</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Valizadeh Zenooz, P., 2009. Productivity of labor, capital and total factors of production. Policy Department and Economic Reaserch, Volume (40).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Valinia, S. A., Amini, A., Soleimani, U., Ansari, Z., 2015. The Role of Entrepreneurship Development on Promoting Labor Productivity: a Comparative Perspective of the Developing and Developed Countries. Quarterly Roshd-e-fanavari, 11(43), pp. 62-70.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Verner, D., 1999. Wages and Productivity Gaps: Evidence from Ghana. World Bank, Human Development, Africa technical Families, Volume 3.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Zachariadis, M., 2003. R&amp;D, Innovation, and Technological Progress: A test of the Schumpeterian Framework without Scale Effects. Canadian Journal of Economics, 36(3), pp. 566-686.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Zamanian, Gh., Fotros, M., Rezaei, E., 2014. Impact of Research and Development Spillovers on the Total Factor Productivity of Iranian Manufacturing Industries.  Journal  of  Economic Growth and Development research,  5(17),  pp. 91-108.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>