<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1396</YEAR>
<VOL>6</VOL>
<NO>3</NO>
<MOSALSAL>21</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>168</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تحلیلی از نظام نوآوری فناورانه در تولید زیست‎فرآورده‎ها (با تمرکز بر واکسن‎های انسانی)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>An Analysis on Technological Innovation System Regarding Iranian Bio-Products 
(Focused on Human Vaccines)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>با توجه به اهمیت راهبردی زیست‎‎فناوری در اقتصاد دنیا، ایران نیز از دو دهه پیش برای ورود به این عرصه، سرمایه‎گذاری نموده و توفیقاتی را حاصل کرده است. این پژوهش در نظر دارد تا بر مبنای ابعاد و کارکردهای کلیدی معرفی‎شده به تحلیل تلاش‎های کشور در حوزه زیست‎فناوری با تمرکز به تولید واکسن‎های انسانی، هم‎چنین کیفیت تکامل نظام نوآوری فناورانه در این مورد بپردازد. از این‎رو اهمیت زیست‎فناوری و وضعیت بازار آن در دنیا به‎اختصار، اشاره شده و سابقه‎ای از تولید واکسن در کشور، مطرح گردیده است. پس از بیان الزامات ورود کشور به این عرصه، کارکردهای نظام نوآوری مربوط، توسط روش نگاشت تاریخی داده‎ها، بررسی و به نتایج و اثرات مترتب بر هر کارکرد، اشاره شده است. در پایان، وضعیت نظام نوآوری فناورانه کشور در تولید واکسن از نظر سازوکارهای مشوق و مسدودکننده، کارکردها و موضوعات سیاستی مربوط در قالب روش دلفی، شناسایی و مورد تحلیل قرار گرفته و به منظور مهار 8 سازوکار محدودکننده و تحریک 3 سازوکار مشوق شناسایی‎شده، 6 توصیه سیاستی ارائه شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Regarding strategic importance of biotechnology in world’s economy, Iran has made investments in this field since twenty years ago which resulted in several achievements. This paper is going to analyze the domestic efforts in Biotech industry and the quality of innovation system evolution, focusing on vaccine production, based on seven innovation key functions introduced by Bergek, et al. (2007). The importance of Biotech industry, its market condition and a brief history of domestic human vaccine production is presented. After addressing the necessity for the country to enter in this high-tech industry, which was commenced with technology transfer project for production of HB vaccine, the functions of its innovation system will be investigated and the results will be discussed by historical data mapping method. Situation of domestic vaccine production innovation system with regard to the blocking and inducement mechanisms at functional level will be analyzed by Delphi method and policy making issues will be pointed out finally. Accordingly to inhibit 8 blocking mechanisms and stimulate 3 inducement mechanisms, 6 political issues were recommended.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>26</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>وحید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مرندی</Family>
						<NameE>Vahid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Marandi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری تخصصی / دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران، گروه مدیریت تکنولوژی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری تخصصی / دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>vahid.marandi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید حبیب ا...</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>طباطبائیان</Family>
						<NameE>Seyyed Habibollah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tabatabaeian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیات علمی / دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، گروه مدیریت، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیات علمی / دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>seyyedhabibollahtabatabaeian@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پریوش</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جعفری</Family>
						<NameE>Parivash</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jafari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیات علمی / دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران، گروه مدیریت آموزشی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیات علمی / دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>pjaafari@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مرتضی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آذرنوش</Family>
						<NameE>Morteza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Azarnoosh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیات علمی / انستیتو پاستور ایران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیات علمی / انستیتو پاستور ایران، تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>morteza.azarnoosh1330@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیاست‎گذاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>زیست‎فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدل برگک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دلفی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نگاشت تاریخی داده‎ها</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aldrich, H., Fiol, C., 1994, Fools rush in? The institutional context of industry creation, Academy of Management Review, 19 (4), pp. 645-670.##AndrusWagstaff, 2014. Andrus Wagstaff. [Online]. Available at: https://www.andruswagstaff.com/blog/big-pharma-has-higher-profit-margins-than-any-other-industry/. [Accessed 2014].##Bergek, A., Jacobsson, S., 2003, The Emergence of a Growth Industry: A Comparative Analysis of the German, Dutch and Swedish Wind Turbine Industries, In: S. Metcalfe and U. Cantner (Eds.), Change, Transformation and Development, Physica-Verlag, Heidelberg, pp. 197-227.##Bergek, A., Jacobsson, S., Carlsson, B., Lindmark, S., Rickne, A., 2007,  Analyzing the dynamics and functionality of sectoral innovation systems: a manual for policy makers, VINNOVA (the Swedish Agency for Innovation Systems).##Bergek, A., Jacobsson, S. and Hekkert, M., 2007, Functions in innovation systems: a framework for analyzing energy system dynamics and identifying goals for system-building activities by entrepreneurs and policy makers, In: T. Foxon, J. K¨ohler and C. Oughton (Eds.), Innovations for a Low Carbon Economy: Economic, Institutional and Management Approaches, Edward Elgar, Cheltenham.##Breschi, S., Malerba, F., 2001, The geography of innovation and economic clustering: some introductory notes, Industrial and corporate change, 10 (4), pp.817-833.##Carlsson, B., Stankiewicz, R., 1991, On the nature, function, and composition of technological systems, Journal of Evolutionary Economics, Volume (I), pp. 93-108.##Dobos. E, Grønning. T, Knell.M, Olsen.D.S., Veistein, B.K, 2004, Case study on Biotech innovation systems - Norway, Vol. 1: Biopharmaceuticals, Centre for Technology, Innovation and Culture, DSTI/STP/TIP(2002), University of Oslo, Norway.##Enzing C., van der Giessen A., Kern S., 2004, The Dutch Pharmaceutical and Food Biotechnology Innovation Systems, TNO report, STB-04-12, Nederland.##Euler Hermes Economic Research, Pharmaceuticals global sector report, Feb.2017, http://www.eulerhermes.com/economic-research/sector-risks/Global-Pharmaceuticals-Report/Pages/default.aspx.##Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, 2013. Fact and Comparison in Industries: Pharmaceuticals, Chap: Market research, , Sixty-Eighth edition.##Feldman, M., Schreuder, Y., 1996, Initial advantage: the origins of the geographic concentration of the pharmaceutical industry in the Mid-Atlantic region, Industrial and corporate change, 5(3), pp.839-862.##Fontenay, C.de., Carmell, E., 2001, Captured-Palestine Silicon Wadi: the forces behind cluster formation, SIEPR discussion paper No. 00-40, Stanford Institute of Economic Policy Research, Stanford, USA.##HSBC contributor, 2014, HSBC Voice: Crowdfunding’s Untapped Potential in Emerging Markets, Forbes, August 5.##Hung, H.L, Altschuld.J.W, Lee, Y.F., 2008, Methodological and conceptual issues confronting a cross-country Delphi study of educational program evaluation. Evaluation and Program Planning, Volume (31), pp.191–198.##Huzair. F, Sturdy. S., 2017, Biotechnology and the transformation of vaccine innovation: The case of the hepatitis B vaccines 1968-2000, Studies in History and Philosophy of Biological and Biomedical Sciences, Volume (64), pp.11-21.##IranBioTech Festival, 2015, Biotechnology Science situation report in Iran, IRAN.##Jansma.S.R., Gosselt.J.F., De Jong.M.D.T., 2018, Technological start-ups in the innovation system: an actor-oriented perspective, Technology Analysis  &amp; Strategic Management, 30(3), pp.282–294.##Mesa. E.G, 2004, Study on the national innovation system in the Spainish biopharmaceutical sector, UEM, DSTI/STP/TIP (2002)1 – OECD, Spain.##Motohashi, K, 2004, OECD/TIP Project on Biopharmaceutical National Innovation Systems, National Report: Japan, OECD/TIP, Tokyo, Japan.##Okoli.C, Pawlowski.S.D, 2004, The Delphi method as a research tool: An example, design considerations and applications, Information &amp; Management, 42(1), pp. 15-29.##Porter, M., 1998, Clusters and competition: new agendas for companies, governments and institutions, On Competition, Boston: Harvard Business School Press, pp. 197-287.##Powell, C, 2003, Myths and realities of the Delphi technique, J Adv Nurs, Volume (41), pp. 376–382.##Rao, H., 2004,  Institutional activism in the early American automobile industry, Journal of Business Venturing, 19 (3), pp. 359-384.##Reiss, T., Hinze.S., 2004, Case study on biotechnology innovation systems: National Report Germany, Fraunhofer Institute for Systems and Innovation Research, Germany.##Rochepeau, A., 2004, The Pharmaceutical Biotechnology Industry in France, French Ministry of Research and New Technologies, France.##Statista, 2016. Statista. [Online]. Available at: https://www.statista.com/statistics/272717/top-global-biotech-and-pharmaceutical-companies-based-on-revenue/ [Accessed 2016].##Van de Van, A., 2005, Running in packs to develop knowledge-intensive technologies, MIS Quarterly, 29 (2), pp.365-378.##Van Teijlingen, E., Pitchforth, E., Bishop, C., Russell, E., 2006 Oct., Delphi method and nominal group technique in family planning and reproductive health research, J Fam Plann Reprod Health Care; 32(4), 249-52.##Von Blankenfeld-Enkvist, G, Brännback, M., Söderlund, R., Petrov, M., 2004, OECD Case Study on Innovation: The Finnish Biotechnology Innovation System, INNOMARKET, Finland.##Windisch, P., 2015, Biosimilars versus original biologics. Similarities and differences from development to approval, Z Rheumatol. 74(8), pp.672-81. doi: 10.1007/s00393-014-1486-9.##Windle, P.E., 2004 Feb; Delphi technique: assessing component needs, J Perianesth Nurs, 19(1), pp. 46-47.##Woolthuis, R.K., Lankhuizen, M, Gilsing, V., 2005, A system failure framework for innovation policy design, Technovation, 25 (6), pp.609-619.##Zimmerman, M., Zeitz, G., 2002, Beyond survival: achieving new venture growth by building legitimacy, Academy of Management Review, 27 (3), pp. 414-431.##اسلامی.ح.، مرندی.و.، 1377، پروژة تولید واکسن هپاتیت‌ب، مبانی اقتصادی فضاهای تمیز در کشور و تلاش‌های خودکفایی، دومین کنفرانس بین‌المللی اتاق‌های تمیز و مهندسی فیلتر: دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر- شرکت تهران‌سکو.##حاجی‎حسینی.ح.، محمدی.م.، عباسی.ف.، الیاسی.م.، پاییز 1390، تحلیل حکمرانی نظام نوآوری ایران بر پایه چرخه سیاست‎گذاری نوآوری، فصلنامه سیاست علم و فناوری، سال چهارم، شماره 1، صص 48-33.##خبرگزاری شفاآنلاین، 2014. شفاآنلاین. [برخط]. قابل دسترس در: http://shafaonline.ir/fa/news/35956. [رویت شده در 2017].##سازمان غذا و دارو، 1393 . آمارنامه دارویی کشور، وزارت بهداشت، درمان و آموزش پزشکی، ایران.##ستاد توسعه زیست‎‎فناوری، 1395. بررسی و ارزیابی مستندات علمی زیست‎فناوری در ایران و جهان (1996- 2015). معاونت علمی و فناوری ریاست‎جمهوری.##ستاد توسعه زیست‎ فناوری کشور، 1394. برنامه عملیاتی کارگروه واکسن، تهران.##سرمد.ز.،  بازرگان.ع.، حجازی، ا.، 1384، روش‎های تحقیق در علوم رفتاری، چاپ دهم، تهران: نشر آگه.##شورای فناوری سلامت، 1393. جایگاه اجرایی اقتصاد مقاومتی در حوزه سلامت، کارگروه اقتصاد مقاومتی.##قاسم‎شربیانی.م.، رادفر.ر.، عابدی، ز.، 1389، الگوی مناسب تجاری‎سازی زیست‎فن‎آوری در حوزه محیط‎زیست در ایران، چهارمین کنفرانس ملی مدیریت تکنولوژی ایران، انجمن مدیریت تکنولوژی ایران، تهران.##قدسی.م، 1350، تاریخچه خدمات 50 ساله انستیتو پاستور ایران، تهران، انتشارات انستیتو پاستور ایران.##محمدپور.ا.، 1388، ارزیابی کیفیت در تحقیق کیفی: اصول و راهبردهای اعتباریابی و تعمیم‎پذیری، فصلنامه علوم اجتماعی، ش 48، 106-73.##محمدی، م.، الیاسی، م.، تقوی‎فرد. م.، حاجی‎حسینی.ح.، دلاور. ع.، 1391، مدل‎سازی شکل‎گیری نظام نوآوری فناورانه در زیست‎فناوری کشور با استفاده از مدل‎یابی معادلات ساختاری، نشریه مدیریت نوآوری، سال اول، ش 1، صص. 40-21.##مرندی.و.، 1380، توسعة صنعتی زیست‎فنآوری در کشور، اهمیت و راهکارها، دومین همایش ملی بیوتکنولژی: وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری- مرکز ملی تحقیقات مهندسی‎ژنتیک و تکنولوژی‎زیستی.##مرندی.و.، 1382، شناسایی مزیت‌های نسبی و فرصت‌های سرمایه‌گذاری در کشور، شالودة رویکرد موثّر به تحقیق و توسعه، چهارمین همایش بین‌المللی مراکز تحقیق و توسعه: جامعة مراکز تحقیق و توسعة صنایع و معادن- وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری- وزارت صنایع و معادن.##مرندی.و.،a 1383، موردکاوی تحقّق اهداف و تحلیل رویکردهای مدیریت در یک پروژة عمرانی ملّی، دومین کنفرانس بین‌المللی مدیریت: دانشگاه صنعتی شریف- سازمان گسترش و نوسازی صنایع ایران- گروه پژوهشی صنعتی‎آریانا.##مرندی.و.، 1383b، نگرش لقمانی: راه‌بردی موفّق در مطالعة موردی تحقّق اهداف در یک پروژة ملّی، پنجمین کنفرانس مدیران کیفیت: مؤسسة استاندارد و تحقیقات صنعتی ایران، سازمان مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی کشور، فرآیند تحقیق.##مرندی.و.، 1384، تحلیل مؤلّفة مدیریت دانایی در یک پروژة راهبردی ملّی، پنجمین همایش بین‌المللی مراکز تحقیق و توسعه: جامعة مراکز تحقیق و توسعة صنایع و معادن- وزارت علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری- وزارت صنایع و معادن.##مرندی.و.، 1394، تحلیلی از وضعیت نوآوری در عرصه تولید واکسن کشور، مجموعه سیاست‎های علوم و فناوری: دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی- واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارائه چارچوبی ترکیبی به منظور ارزیابی عملکرد توسعه‌ خدمت‌ جدید (مورد مطالعه: صنعت بهداشت و درمان)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Hybrid Framework for Evaluating New Service Development Performance in Healthcare Industry</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>وجود چارچوبی به منظور سنجش عملکرد توسعه خدمت جدید علاوه ‌بر آنکه می‌تواند معیاری برای ارزیابی میزان موفقیت برنامه‌های توسعه خدمت جدید یک سازمان باشد، در شناسایی نقاط قوت و ضعف و برنامه‌ریزی پروژه‌های بهبود بسیار مفید خواهد بود. پژوهش حاضر با هدف ارائه چارچوبی به منظور ارزیابی عملکرد توسعه خدمت جدید در صنعت بهداشت ‌و درمان با بهره‌گیری از رویکرد ترکیبی معادلات ساختاری تفسیری و روش‌های تصمیم‌گیری چندشاخصه انجام شده است. شاخص‌های احصاء شده، با کمک خبرگان در قالب مدل کارت امتیازی متوازن دسته‌بندی شده است. بدلیل وجود ارتباط داخلی میان معیارها، این مدل با استفاده ‌از رویکرد مدل‌سازی ساختاری تفسیری مورد ارزیابی قرارگرفته و در 5 سطح مختلف مدل‌سازی ‌گردید. وزن هر شاخص با استفاده ‌از روش فرآیند تحلیل شبکه‌ای محاسبه شده است. در نهایت، عملکرد توسعه خدمت بیمارستان‌ محب‌مهر به‌عنوان مورد مطالعه، مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفته است. نتایج حاکی ‌از آن است که معیارهای ارزش برند و میزان جذب‌مشتریان به‌عنوان مهم‌ترین معیارهای ارزیابی عملکرد توسعه خدمت جدید انتخاب شده‌اند. عملکرد توسعه خدمت جدید بیمارستان ‌محب‌مهر در مجموع، 54 امتیاز از 100 امتیاز را کسب ‌نموده ‌است. بر ‌این ‌اساس می‌توان بیان نمود که عملکرد توسعه خدمت این بیمارستان در سطح متوسط‌ روبه‌بالا قرار دارد. در نهایت چارچوبی پیشنهاد گردیده است تا با کمک آن بیمارستان بتواند سیاست‌های عملکردی خود را متناسب با امتیازهای کسب شده اصلاح نماید و اقدامات حوزه توسعه خدمات جدید خود را به نحوی اثربخش بهبود بخشد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Developing a framework to evaluate New Service Development performance, besides usefulness for evaluation of the success of NSD programs, can be helpful to identify strengths and weaknesses of improvement projects. Current paper aims to develop a framework to evaluate NSD performance by ISM and ANP. Extracted criteria finalized by experts and categorized in BSC framework. Because of internal communication among criteria, this model was evaluated by interpretive structural modelling (ISM) and modelled in 5 levels. Next, the analytic network process (ANP) approach was applied to weighting this criterion. Finally, New Service Development performance of Moheb-e Mehr Hospital as the case of current study was evaluated by this proposed model.The results indicate that the brand value and attraction of customers are the most important criteria for NSD performance. Moheb-e Mehr Hospital overall performance score was 54 points out of 100 points. So NSD performance of Moheb-e Mehr Hospital is moderate to high level. Finally, a framework proposed to help the aforementioned hospital in which could adjust the performance policies relative to the gained points along with developing actions in New Service Development performance domain.  </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>27</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>52</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جلیل</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حیدری دهویی</Family>
						<NameE>Jalil</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Heidari Dehvi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>heidaryd@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نوید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Navid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>navid.m@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزیابی عملکرد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توسعه خدمت جدید</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بهداشت و درمان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ISM</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ANP</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Agarwal, A., Shankar, R. &amp; Tiwari, M., 2007. Modeling Agility of Supply Chain. Industrial Marketing Management, Volume 36, pp. 443-457.##Azar, A., Tizro, A., Moghbel, A. &amp; Rostami, A. R., 2010. Designing Supply Chain Agile Model: Interpretive Structural Modeling Approach. Management Reserches in Iran (In Persian), 14(4).##Bendoly, E., Bharadwaj, A. &amp; Bharadwaj, S., 2011. Complementary Drivers of New Product Development Performance: Cross Functional Coordination, Information System Capability, and Intelligence Quality. Production and Operations Management, 21(4), pp. 653-667.##Blindenbach-Driessen, F., Van Dalen, J. &amp; Van Den Ende, J., 2010. Subjective performance assessment of innovation projects. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 27(4), pp. 572-592.##Cheng, C. C. &amp; Krumwiede, D., 2012. The role of service innovation in the market orientation—new service performance linkage. Technovation, 32(7), pp. 487-497.##De Brentani, U. &amp; Ragot, E., 1996. Developing new business-to-business professional services: what factors impact performance?. Industrial Marketing Management, 25(6), pp. 517-530.##Drejeris, R. &amp; Tunčikienė, Ž., 2010. Complex assessment of the methods for new service idea generation.##Ergebnisse, A., 2015. Jahre Nationale branchen konferenz Gesundheit swirts chaft, Ausgewählte Ergebnisse.##Fitzsimmons, J. &amp; Fitzsimmons, M., 2008. Service management: Operations, strategy, information technology. McGraw-Hill Higher Education.##Gorane, S. &amp; Kant, R., 2012. Modelling the SCM enablers: an integrated ISM-fuzzy MICMAC approach. Asia Pacific Journal of Marketing and Logistics, 25(2), pp. 263-286.##Hillebrand, B., Kemp, R. G. &amp; Nijssen, E. J., 2011. Customer orientation and future market focus in NSD. Journal of Service Management, 22(1), pp. 67-84.##Jiménez-Zarco, A. I., Pilar Martínez-Ruiz, M. &amp; Izquierdo-Yusta, A., 2011. The impact of market orientation dimensions on client cooperation in the development of new service innovations. European Journal of Marketing, 45(1/2), pp. 43-67.##Kaplan, R. &amp; Norton, D. P., 2005. The balanced scorecard: measures that drive performance. Harvard business review, 83(7).##Khan, J. &amp; Haleem, A., 2013. An Integrated Ism and Fuzzy Micmac Approach for Modeling of the Enablers of Technology Management. Indian Journal of Applied Research, 3(7), pp. 236-242.##Kim, K. J. &amp; Meiren, T., 2010. New service development process. In: Introduction to service engineering.  pp. 253-267.##Kriegel, J., 2013. New service development in German and Austrian health care–bringing e-health services into the market. International Journal of Healthcare Management.##Lee, H., Kim, C. &amp; Park, Y., 2010. Evaluation and management of new service concepts: An ANP-based portfolio approach. Computers &amp; Industrial Engineering, 58(4), pp. 535-543.##Lee, S., Lee, D. &amp; Schniederjan, M., 2011. Supply chain innovation and organizational performance in the healthcare industry. International Journal of Operations &amp; Production Management, 31(11).##Lin, F. R. &amp; Hsieh, P. S., 2011. A SAT view on new service development. Service Science, 3(2), pp. 141-157.##Melton, H. L. &amp; Hartline, M. D., 2010. Customer and frontline employee influence on new service development performance. Journal of Service Research, 13(4), pp. 411-425.##Melton, H. L. &amp; Hartline, M. D., 2013. Employee collaboration, learning orientation, and new service development performance. Journal of Service Research, 16(1), pp. 67-81.##Menor, L. &amp; Roth, A., 2007. New service development competence in retail banking: Construct development and measurement validation. Journal of Operations Management, 25(4), pp. 825-846.##Menor, L. &amp; Roth, A., 2008. New service development competence and performance: An empirical investigation in retail banking. Production and Operations Management.##Menor, L. &amp; Roth, A., 2008. New service development competence and performance: An empirical investigation in retail banking. Production and Operations Management, 17(3), pp. 267-284.##Mikolajczyk, K. &amp; Schmid, C., 2005. A performance evaluation of local descriptors. Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, IEEE Transactions, 27(10).##Pfohl, H., Gallus, P. &amp; Thomas, D., 2011. Interpretive Structural Modeling of Supply Chain Risks. International Journal of Physical Distribution &amp; Logistics Management, 41(9), p. 839 – 859.##PWC, 2014. Top health industry issues of 2015, Health Research Institute.##Sage, A. P., 1977. Interpretive structural modeling: methodology for large-scale systems.##Shyu, J. Z., Wang, J. S., Peng, C. C. &amp; Tang, Y. H., 2012. Service Innovation Elements in Energy Service Company (ESCO) Business Model. Advanced Materials Research, Volume 524, pp. 3139-3153.##Storey, C. &amp; Hughes, M., 2013. The relative impact of culture, strategic orientation and capability on new service development performance. European Journal of Marketing, 47(5/6), 47(5/6), pp. 833-856.##Storey, C. &amp; Kelly, D., 2001. Measuring the performance of new service development activities. Service Industries Journal, 21(2), pp. 71-90.##Tseng, M. L., Lin, Y. H., Lim, M. K. &amp; Teehankee, B. L., 2015. Using a hybrid method to evaluate service innovation in the hotel industry. Applied Soft Computing, Volume (28), pp. 411-421.##Tseng, M., Yuan, H. &amp; Ming K, L., 2015. Using a hybrid method to evaluate service innovation in the hotel industry. Applied Soft Computing, Volume (28).##Victorino, L., Verma, R., Plaschka, G. &amp; Dev, C., 2005. Service innovation and customer choices in the hospitality industry. Managing Service Quality: An International Journal, 15(6), pp. 555-576.##Wang, W. &amp; Tang, M., 2012. Evaluating New Service Development Performance Based on Multigranular Linguistic Assessment. World Academy of Science, Engineering and Technology, International Journal of Mechanical, Aerospace, Industrial, Mechatronic and Manufacturing Engineering, 6(7), pp. 1313-1318.##Warfield, J. N., 1974. Developing interconnection matrices in structural modeling. IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics, Volume (1), pp. 81-87.##Weng, R. &amp; Huang, C., 2012. The impact of customer knowledge capability and relational capability on new service development performance: The case of health service. Journal of Management &amp; Organization, 18(5).##اصغرپور، م.، 1387. تصمیم‌گیری‌های چند معیاره، چاپ ششم. انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##دری، ب. و حمزه‌ای، ا.، 1389. تعیین استراتژی پاسخ به ریسک در مدیریت ریسک به وسیله تکنیک ANP (مطالعه موردی: پروژه توسعه میدان نفتی آزادگان شمالی)،. مدیریت صنعتی، (4) 2، صص.92-75.##شفابخش، غ.، علیزاده، ح. و اکبری، م.، 1391. شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی نقاط حادثه‌خیز با روش فرآیند تحلیل شبکه‌ای(ANP). فصلنامه مطالعات مدیریت ترافیک، شماره 24.##صادق عمل‌نیک، م.، انصاری‌نژاد، ا. و انصاری‌نژاد، ص.، 1389. یافتن روابط علی و معلولی و رتبه‌بندی عوامل بحرانی موفقیت و شکست پروژه‌های پیاده‌سازی سیستم‌های اطلاعاتی به کمک ترکیب روش‌های ANP و DEMATEL فازی گروهی،. نشریه تخصصی مهندسی صنایع، (2) 44، صص. 195-212.##کیانی، ا. و سالاری سردری، ف.، 1390. بررسی و ارزیابی اولویت‌های منظر فضاهای عمومی شهر عسلویه با استفاده از مدل ANP. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی باغ نظر، مرکز پژوهشی هنر معماری و شهرسازی نظر، (18) 8.##ولیسامانی، ج. و دلاور، م.، 1389. کاربرد فرآیند تحلیل شبکه‌ای (ANP) در اولویت‌بندی ساختگاه‌های پرورش میگو. تحقیقات منابع آب ایران، 6(2)، صص. 56-46.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تاثیر ظرفیت جذب در اثربخشی فرآیند انتقال بین‌المللی فنّاوری؛ بررسی قطعه سازهای حاضر در پروژه موتور ملی EF7</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Role of Absorptive Capacity in Effectiveness of International Technology Transfer: Investigation of Part Suppliers in EF7 Project</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در عصر دانش و فناوری، مزیت رقابتی سازمان‌ها بیش از آن‌که وابسته به منابع فیزیکی باشد، به دارایی‌های دانشی و توانایی آن‌ها در جذب دانش و فناوری خارجی وابسته است. هدف اصلی پژوهش حاضر بررسی تاثیر ابعاد ظرفیت جذب در اثربخشی فرایند انتقال فناوری موتور ملی EF7 از طریق بررسی شرکت‌های حاضر در آن پروژه می‌باشد.در این راستا 4 فرضیه ارائه و برای تحلیل مدل، از آزمون‌های تحلیل واریانس و رگرسیون با استفاده از داده‌های پنج شرکت قطعه‌سازی لاتون، واشر مشهد، شرکت STYM، پیستون‌سازی تبریز و فراصنعت شمال استفاده شده است. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که ظرفیت جذب کلیه شرکت‌های مورد مطالعه به‌طور معناداری با اثربخشی انتقال فناوری مرتبط می‌باشد، به‌طوری‌که شرکت‌هایی که از ظرفیت جذب بالاتری قبل از آغاز پروژه طراحی موتور ملی EF7 برخوردار بودند، به سطح بالاتری از توانمندی‌ها پس از اتمام پروژه یادشده دست یافتند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In era of knowledge and technology, the completive advantage of companies depends on their knowledge assets and their capabilities to absorb external technologies rather than their physical assets. The ultimate aim of current research is to investigate the influence of dimensions of absorptive capacity in success of international technology transfer process for the Iranian National Engine (EF7) project by elaborating the manufacturing companies which accompany the project. Therefore, four hypotheses are proposed and tested in five manufacturing companies namely, STYM, Laton, IMPC, Mashad Washer and Fara Sanat, those which engaged in the project. Also the model was analyzed through regression and variance methods by data gathered from the five aforementioned companies. The results show that the level of absorptive capacity of companies significantly affects the effectiveness of technology transfer in so called project; companies having higher level of absorptive capacity before starting the project were able to achieve a higher level of technological capabilities after ending the project.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>53</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>80</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مجیدپور</Family>
						<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Majidpour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیات علمی دانشکده مدیریت، علم و فناوری، دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیات علمی دانشکده مدیریت، علم و فناوری،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>majidpour.mehdi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>آرمان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خالدی</Family>
						<NameE>Arman</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>khaledi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری سیاستگذاری علم و فناوری دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری سیاستگذاری علم و فناوری دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>armankhaledi1102@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نصری</Family>
						<NameE>Shohreh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nasri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shohreh_nasri@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صابر</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Saber</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ali.saber@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مینائی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Minaee</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mr_minaee@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ظرفیت جذب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انتقال فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>موتور ملی EF7</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Boynton, A. C., Zmud, R. W. &amp; Jacobs, G. C. 1994. The influence of IT management practice on IT use in large organizations. Mis Quarterly, pp. 299-318.##Cadiz, D., Sawyer, J. E. &amp; Griffith, T. L. 2009. Developing and validating field measurement scales for absorptive capacity and experienced community of practice. Educational and Psychological Measurement, Volume (69), pp. 1035-1058.##Cho, S. W. 2014. The Evaluation on the Three Critical Models of Absorptive Capacity: A Case Study on Logistics Company in Korea. Universal Journal of Industrial and Business Management, Volume (2), pp. 119-125.##Cockburn, I. M. &amp; Henderson, R. M. 1998. Absorptive capacity, coauthoring behavior, and the organization of research in drug discovery. The Journal of Industrial Economics, Volume (46), pp. 157-182.##Cohen, W. M. &amp; Levinthal, D. A. 1990. Absorptive capacity: A new perspective on learning and innovation. Administrative Science Quarterly, pp. 128-152.##Duchek, S. 2013. Capturing absorptive capacity: a critical review and future prospects. Schmalenbach Business Review, pp. 312-329.##Fabrizio, K. R. 2009. Absorptive Capacity and the Search for Innovation. Research Policy, Volume (38), pp. 255-267.##Flatten, T. C., Engelen, A., Zahra, S. A. &amp; Brettel, M. 2011. A Measure of Absorptive Capacity: Scale Development and Validation. European Management Journal, Volume (29), pp. 98-116.##Freeman, C. &amp; Hagedoorn, J. 1994. Catching up or falling behind: Patterns in international interfirm technology partnering. World Development, Volume (22), pp. 771-780.##Gao, S., Xu, K. &amp; Yang, J. 2008. Managerial Ties, Absorptive Capacity, and Innovation. Asia Pacific Journal of Management, Volume (25), pp. 395-412.##George, G., Zahra, S. A., Wheatley, K. K. &amp; Khan, R. 2001. The Effects of Alliance Portfolio Characteristics and Absorptive Capacity on Performance: A Study of Biotechnology Firms. The Journal of High Technology Management Research, Volume (12), pp. 205-226.##Glass, A. J. &amp; Saggi, K. 1998. International Technology Transfer and the Technology Gap. Journal of Development Economics, Volume (55), pp. 369-398.##Günsel, A. 2015. Research on Effectiveness of Technology Transfer from a Knowledge based Perspective. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume (207), pp. 777-785.##Heeley, M. 1997. Appropriating rents from external knowledge: the impact of absorptive capacity on firm sales growth and research productivity. Frontiers of Entrepreneurship Research, Volume (17), pp. 390-404.##Indarti, N. 2010. The effect of knowledge stickiness and interaction on absorptive capacity. University of Groningen, Groningen.##Jafari, M., Akhavan, P. &amp; Rafiei, A. 2014. Technology Transfer Effectiveness in Knowledge-Based Centers Providing a Model Based on Knowledge Management.##Jansen, J. J., Van Den Bosch, F. A. &amp; Volberda, H. W. 2005. Managing potential and realized absorptive capacity: how do organizational antecedents matter? Academy of Management Journal, Volume (48), pp. 999-1015.##Kedia, B. L. &amp; Bhagat, R. S. 1988. Cultural Constraints on Transfer of Technology across Nations: Implications for Research in International and Comparative Management. Academy of Management Review, Volume (13), pp. 559-571.##Khan, S. Z. A. 2011. Technology transfer effectiveness through international joint ventures (IJVs) to their component suppliers: a study of the automotive industry of Pakistan. University of Birmingham.##Kinoshita, Y. 2000. R&amp;D and technology spillovers via FDI: Innovation and absorptive capacity.##Kostopoulos, K., Papalexandris, A., Papachroni, M. &amp; Ioannou, G. 2011. Absorptive capacity, innovation, and financial performance. Journal of Business Research, Volume (64), pp. 1335-1343.##Lall, S. 1992. Technological capabilities and industrialization. World Development, Volume (20), 165-186.##Lall, S. &amp; Teubal, M. 1998. “Market-stimulating” technology policies in developing countries: A framework with examples from East Asia. World Development, Volume (26), pp. 1369-1385.##Lane, P. J., Koka, B. &amp; Pathak, S. 2002. A Thematic analysis and critical assessment of absorptive capacity research.  Academy of Management proceedings, Academy of Management, M1-M6.##Lane, P. J. &amp; Lubatkin, M. 1998. Relative absorptive capacity and interorganizational learning. Strategic management journal, pp. 461-477.##Lane, P. J., Salk, J. E. &amp; Lyles, M. A. 2001. Absorptive capacity, learning, and performance in international joint ventures. Strategic Management Journal, Volume (22), pp. 1139-1161.##Laursen, K. &amp; Salter, A. 2006. Open for innovation: the role of openness in explaining innovation performance among UK manufacturing firms. Strategic Management Journal, Volume (27), pp. 131-150.##Lee, K. &amp; Lim, C. 2001. Technological Regimes, Catching-up and Leapfrogging: Findings from the Korean Industries. Research Policy,  Volume (30), pp. 459-483.##Levinson, N. S. &amp; Asahi, M. 1995. Cross-national Alliances and Interorganizational Learning. Organizational Dynamics, Volume (24), pp. 50-63.##Lichtenthaler, U. 2009. Absorptive Capacity, Environmental Turbulence, and the Complementarity of Organizational Learning Processes. Academy of Management Journal, Volume (52), pp. 822-846.##Liu, X. &amp; White, R. S. 1997. The Relative Contributions of Foreign Technology and Domestic Inputs to Innovation in Chinese Manufacturing Industries. Technovation, Volume (17), pp. 119-125.##Lund Vinding, A. 2006. Absorptive capacity and innovative performance: A human capital approach. Economics of Innovation and New Technology, Volume (15), pp. 507-517.##Luo, Y. 1997. Partner Selection and Venturing Success: The Case of Joint Ventures with Firms in the People’s Republic of China. Organization Science, Volume (8), pp. 648-662.##Majidpour, M. 2017. International Technology Transfer and the Dynamics of Complementarity: A New Approach. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Volume (122), pp. 196-206.##Mowery, D. C. &amp; Oxley, J. E. 1995. Inward technology transfer and competitiveness: the role of national innovation systems. Cambridge Journal of Economics, Volume (19), pp. 67-93.##Mowery, D. C., Oxley, J. E. &amp; Silverman, B. S. 1996. Strategic Alliances and Interfirm Knowledge Transfer. Strategic Management Journal, Volume (17), pp. 77-91.##Mukherjee, A., Mitchell, W. &amp; Talbot, F. B. 2000. The impact of new manufacturing requirements on production line productivity and quality at a focused factory. Journal of Operations Management, Volume (18), pp. 139-168.##Nambisan, S., Agarwal, R. &amp; Tanniru, M. 1999. Organizational Mechanisms for Enhancing User Innovation in Information Technology. MIS Quarterly, pp. 365-395.##Noor, S. M., Yusoff, R. Z. &amp; Hashim, F., 2010. Firms’ absorptive capacity and technology compatibility in transferred technology.   2010, International Conference on Science and Social Research (CSSR), IEEE, pp. 613-617.##Oltra, M. J. &amp; Flor, M. 2003. The impact of technological opportunities and innovative capabilities on firms’ output innovation. Creativity and Innovation Management, Volume (12), pp. 137-144.##Omar, R., Takim, R. &amp; Nawawi, A. H. Measuring Absorptive Capacity in Technology Transfer (TT) Projects.  Business Innovation and Technology Management (APBITM), 2011 IEEE International Summer Conference of Asia Pacific. IEEE, pp. 328-332.##Petroni, A. &amp; Panciroli, B. 2002. Innovation as a Determinant of Suppliers’ Roles and Performances: an Empirical Study in the Food Machinery Industry. European Journal of Purchasing &amp; Supply Management, Volume (8), pp. 135-149.##Rogers, E. M., Yin, J. &amp; Hoffmann, J. 2000. Assessing the effectiveness of technology transfer offices at US research universities. The Journal of the Association of University Technology Managers, Volume (12), pp. 47-80.##Schmidt, T. 2010. Absorptive capacity—one size fits all? A firm level analysis of absorptive capacity for different kinds of knowledge. Managerial and Decision Economics, Volume (31), pp. 1-18.##Schroer, B. J., Farrington, P. A., Messimer, S. L. &amp; Thornton, J. R. 1995. Measuring technology transfer performance: A case study. The Journal of Technology Transfer, Volume (20), pp. 39-47.##Thomas, R. &amp; Wood, E. 2014. Innovation in tourism: Re-conceptualising and measuring the absorptive capacity of the hotel sector. Tourism Management, Volume (45), pp. 39-48.##Todorova, G. &amp; Durisin, B. 2007. Absorptive capacity: Valuing a Reconceptualization. Academy of Management Review, Volume (32), pp. 774-786.##Tran, T. A. 2013. Strategic Evaluation of University Knowledge and Technology Transfer Effectiveness. Portland State University.##Uotila, T., Harmaakorpi, V. &amp; Melkas, H. 2006. A method for assessing absorptive capacity of a regional innovation system. Fennia-International Journal of Geography, Volume (184), pp. 49-58.##Van Den Bosch, F. A., Volberda, H. W. &amp; De Boer, M. 1999. Coevolution of firm absorptive capacity and knowledge environment: Organizational forms and combinative capabilities. Organization Science, Volume (10), pp. 551-568.##Vega-Jurado, J., Gutiérrez-Gracia, A. &amp; Fernández-De-Lucio, I. 2008. An Analytical Model of Absorptive Capacity. INGENIO (CSIC-UPV).##Veugelers, R. 1997. Internal R &amp; D Expenditures and External Technology Sourcing. Research Policy, Volume (26), pp. 303-315.##Whangthomkum, N., Igel, B. &amp; Speece, M. 2006. An empirical study of the relationship between absorptive capacity and technology transfer effectiveness. International Journal of Technology Transfer and Commercialisation, Volume (5), pp. 31-55.##Wilkens, U., Menzel, D. &amp; Pawlowsky, P. 2004. Inside the black-box: Analysing the generation of core competencies and dynamic capabilities by exploring collective minds. An Organisational Learning Perspective. Management Revue, pp. 8-26.##Xia, T. &amp; Roper, S. 2008. From capability to connectivity-Absorptive capacity and exploratory alliances in biopharmaceutical firms: A US–Europe comparison. Technovation, Volume (28), pp. 776-785.##Zahra, S. A. &amp; George, G. 2002. Absorptive capacity: A review, reconceptualization, and extension. Academy of Management Review, Volume (27), pp. 185-203.##بزمی، م.، تاجریان، م.، قدیری، ر. ا. و نقی‏پور، پ. 1391. رزیابی فرآیند انتقال فناوری DMD  از دیدگاه مدیریت فناوری. مدیریت صنعت هوشمند، 138، صص. 35-20.##قلیزاده، ح.، معینی، ع.، بنیادی‏نایینی، ع. و محمدی، م. 1394. ارائه مدل برای شناسایی ابعاد و اندازه‏گیری ظرفیت جذب: مطالعه موردی نانو فناوری ایران. رشد فناوری، 42.##مجیدپور، م. و همکاران 1394. استخراج فناوری‏های کلیدی طراحی وساخت هواپیمای مسافربری 150 نفره. طرح کلان شورای عالی علوم، تحقیقات و فناوری. تهران: دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>آسیب شناسی روش های انتقال فنّاوری در صنعت مواد غذائی و آشامیدنی با بکارگیری الگوی CIPP</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Pathology of Technology Transfer Methods in the Food and Beverage Industry through applying CIPP Model</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>صنایع مواد غذایی و آشامیدنی از جمله مهم‌ترین گروه‌های صنعتی هستند که در توسعه اقتصادی کشورها به‌ویژه کشورهای درحال‌توسعه نقش کارآمدی ایفا می‌کنند. علت اصلی بروز سهم عمده‌ای از مشکلات صنایع مواد غذایی و آشامیدنی ایران، وجود ضعف‌هایی در مقوله انتقال فناوری در صنعت یادشده است. ازاین‌رو در پژوهش حاضر، به آسیب‌شناسی روش‌های انتقال فناوری در صنعت مواد غذایی و آشامیدنی ایران با به‌کارگیری الگوی CIPP پرداخته‌ شده است. از روش تصمیم‌گیری چندمعیاره ترکیبی BWM و الکتره در بخش درونداد الگوی CIPP با هدف تعیین اهمیت معیارهای شناسایی ‌شده و رتبه‌بندی روش‌های انتقال فناوری استفاده‌ گردید. با توجه به تجزیه‌وتحلیل نتایج حاصل از پیاده‌سازی الگوی CIPP و مشاهده عدم تطابق در بهره‌گیری از روش‌های کارای انتقال فناوری، عارضه‌یابی و معرفی آسیب‌ها، روش‌ها و راهکارهای پیشنهادی برای رفع موانع و محدودیت‌های انتقال فناوری مبتنی بر نظرات خبرگان صنعت ارائه ‌شده است. نتایج پژوهش حاکی از آن است که صنایع مواد غذایی و آشامیدنی کشورمان برخلاف برخی صنایع دیگر، توانایی سرمایه‌گذاری در انتقال فناوری به شیوه‌های توسعه درون‌زا را ندارند. برخی از مهم‌ترین راه‌کارهای معرفی‌شده توسط خبرگان در راستای انتخاب روش مناسب انتقال فناوری عبارت است از مدیریت ارتباط مؤثر با شرکت‌های واسطه، بهره‌گیری از مدیران متخصص حوزه مدیریت فناوری و در نظر گرفتن عوامل بومی تأثیرگذار در صنعت تحت بررسی. راهکارهای پیشنهادی برای هر یک از روش‌ها نیز به‌تفصیل ارائه گردیده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The food and beverage industry are important industrial entities which have essential role in the developing of economies mainly in developing countries.  A major problem existed in this industry can be attributed to the weaknesses of technology transfer to this industry. Therefore, in current research, authors aim at studying the pathology of technology transfer methods in Iran&#039;s food and beverage industry using CIPP model. To do so, fuzzy BWM and ELECTRE methods have been used to determine the relative importance of identified criteria and to rank the technology transfer methods in the food and beverage industry. Having evaluated the processes of implementing CIPP model and founding incompatibility in utilizing methods of technology transfer, industry experts proposed the solutions for removing obstacles. The research results indicate that food and beverage industries in Iran unlike some other industries do not have the ability to invest in technology transfer in the ways of internal development. Also, some of the most important solutions introduced by the experts in order to select the appropriate technology transfer methods are: effective communication management with intermediary companies, the use of expert managers in the field of technology management and considering effective native factors at the industry.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>81</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>112</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حاصلی</Family>
						<NameE>Gholamreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Haseli</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده مهندسی صنایع ومدیریت،دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده مهندسی صنایع ومدیریت،دانشگاه صنعتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ghr.haseli@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حکمی نسب</Family>
						<NameE>Saeed</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hakami Nasab</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشکده مهندسی صنایع و مدیریت، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشکده مهندسی صنایع و مدیریت، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>saeedhakami@shahroodut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی اکبر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسنی</Family>
						<NameE>Aliakbar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hasani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشکده مهندسی صنایع و مدیریت، دانشگاه صنعتی شاهرود</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشکده مهندسی صنایع و مدیریت، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aa.hasani@shahroodut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آسیب شناسی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انتقال فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>BWM</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الکتره</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگوی CIPP</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Asghari, M., Rakhshanikia, M.A., 2013. Technology transfer in oil industry, significance and challenges. 2nd International Conference on Leadership, Technology and Innovation Management. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 75. pp. 264 – 271.##Attride-Stirling, J. 2001, Thematic Networks: An Analytic Tool for Qualitative Research. Qualitative Research,1(3), pp. 385-405.##Carrillo, P., 1996. Technology transfer on joint venture projects in developing countries. Construction Management and Economics, 14(1), pp.45-54.##Chen, X. and Sun, C., 2000. Technology transfer to China: alliances of Chinese enterprises with western technology exporters. Technovation, 20(7), pp.353-362.##Chiesa, V. and Manzini, R., 1998. Organizing for technological collaborations: a managerial perspective. R&amp;D Management, 28(3), pp.199-212.##Ford, D., 1998. Develop your technology strategy. Long range planning, 21(5), pp.85-95.##Gilbert, A. 1995. Negotiating technology acquisitions: getting the tools you need to succeed, Singapore : Nanyang Technological University.##Günsel, A., 2015. Research on effectiveness of technology transfer from a knowledge based perspective. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume (207), pp.777-785.##INE. 2002. High Technology Indicators, General Methodology. INE. National Statistics Institute, pp.4-57.##Khalil, T.M., 2000. Management of technology: The key to competitiveness and wealth creation. McGraw-Hill Science, Engineering &amp; Mathematics.##Lai, W.H. and Tsai, C.T., 2010. Analyzing influence factors of technology transfer using fuzzy set theory. International Journal of Innovation and Technology Management, 7(01), pp.71-87.##Lee, G.A. 1998. Negotiating technology acquisition: gettinge tools you need to succeed. Working Paper, Nanyang Technology University.##Liu, S., Fang, Z., Shi, H. and Guo, B., 2016. Theory of science and technology transfer and applications. CRC Press.##Louise, G.M., 2009. Technology Transfer trough Foreign Direct Investment to developing countries the role of home countries Measures, UNESCO - Encyclopedia Of Life Support System, [Online] Available at: https://www.eolss.net/sample-chapters/C15/E1-31-03-01.pdf##OECD. 2013. OECD Science, Technology and Industry Scoreboard 2013. Innovation for Growth. OECD Publishing, pp.4-532.##Roberts. E and Berry. C. 1985. Entering new business: selecting strategies for success, Sloan Management Review. 26(3), 3-17.##Skardon, J. 2011. The role of trust in innovation networks, Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume (26(, pp. 85-93.##Stufflebeam, D., 2003. The CIPP Model for Evaluation. In: T. Kellaghan &amp; D. Stufflebeam, eds. International Handbook of Educational Evaluation. Kluwer International Handbooks of Education. Dordrecht : Springer, pp. 297-317.##Stufflebeam, D. L., Shinkfield, A. J. 1988. Systematic Evaluation. A self instructional guide to theory and practice. Kluwer-Nijhoff pub.##Tanaka, H., Iwaisako, T. and Futagami, K., 2007. Dynamic analysis of innovation and international transfer of technology through licensing. Journal of International Economics, 73(1), pp.189-212.##Tidd, J., Bessant, J. &amp; Pavitt, K. 2001. Managing Innovation: Integrating Technological, Market and Organisational Change, 2nd ed. Chichester: Wiley.##UNIDO. 2011. Industrial Energy Efficiency for Sustainable Wealth Creation, Capturing environmental, economic and social dividends. Industrial Development Organization. pp. 4-571.##United Nations Statistical Commission, 2002. ISIC Rev 3.1. International Standard Industrial Classification of All Economic Activities.##آراستی، محمدرضا، مدرس‌یزدی، محمد، دلاوری، محمد. 1387، ارائه مدلی جامع برای انتخاب روش مناسب انتقال فناوری، مجله علمی پژوهشی شریف، شماره 43، صص. 145-153.##اکبری، اکرم، پورعبادالهان کویچ، محسن، محمدزاده، پرویز، رضایی، ستاره. 1396، تحلیل فضایی عوامل موثر بر صادرات صنایع مواد غذایی و آشامیدنی، نظریه‌های کاربردی اقتصاد، سال چهارم، شماره 1،صص. 197-218.##الیاسی، مهدی، میرزایی، حسین، صفردوست، عاطیه. 1396، آسیب‌شناسی فرآیند انتقال فناوری(موردمطالعه: انتقال فناوری نوعی سلاح شکاری از کشور ترکیه)، دو فصلنامه توسعه فناوری صنعتی، شماره 29، بهار و تابستان 1396، صص. 89-100.##بیدگلی، محمدرضا، نوری، فیروز، خادم، مهیار. 1390، الگوی جامع FPSS رویکردی نوین در آسیب‌شناسی، اولین کنفرانس بین‌المللی و پنجمین کنفرانس ملی مدیریت فناوری.##حق‌بین، اشکان، برارثانی، کوروش، ایمانی، علیرضا. 1390، آسیب‌شناسی فرآیند انتقال فناوری در صنعت لوکوموتیوسازی، اولین کنفرانس بین‌المللی و پنجمین کنفرانس ملی مدیریت فناوری.##خمسه، عباس، بختیاری، مرضیه. 1392، ارزیابی فرآیند انتقال فناوری در صنایع نیروگاهی ایران، کنفرانس مدیریت چالش‌ها و راهکارها.##رادفر، رضا، خمسه، عباس. 1395، مدیریت فناوری: نگرشی جامع بر فناوری، نوآوری و تجاری‌سازی شرکت، انتشارات علمی و فرهنگی، تهران، شماره 1، چاپ اول.##سیدکاوسی، الهه. 1392، آسیب‌شناسی فرآیند انتقال فناوری در صنعت ملی نفت ایران، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه اصفهان.##عابدی، زهرا. 1378، تنگناهای ساختار علمی-صنعتی و تکنولوژیک کشور و راهبردهای لازم برای انتقال و توسعه موفق فناوری، نشریه رهیافت، شماره 20، صص. 42-53.##علیزاده، پریسا، رفوگرآستانه، حسین، اعظمی، علی، زین‌العابدینی، اکبر. 1394، آسیب‌شناسی پروژه انتقال فناوری هواپیمایی ایران – 140، دفتر مطالعات ارتباطات و فناوری‌های نوین.##فیض‌پور، محمدعلی، لطفی، عزت‌الله.، امامی‌میبدی، مهدی. 1392، اندازه بهینه تولید در صنایع مواد غذایی و آشامیدنی و تغییرات آن طی سال های اول برنامه های دوم، سوم و چهارم توسعه، نشریه پژوهش‌های صنایع غذایی، جلد 23، شماره 1، صص. 25-36.##کندری، اسمعیل. 1389، انتخاب روش مناسب انتقال فناوری با استفاده از مدل AHP فازی در صنعت ماشین‌آلات کمپوست‌سازی و قارچ خوراکی، ماهنامه روش، سال نوزدهم، شماره 125.##کیامنش، علیرضا. 1392، الگوی ارزشیابی سیپ (CIPP)، دانشنامه ایرانی برنامه‌ریزی، محور 7 ارزشیابی، صص. 1-6.##گودرزی، مهدی، خواجه‌نصیری، شهرام. 1393، انتخاب روش مناسب همکاری فناوری برای تولید الکترود گرافیتی در ایران، فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه فناوری، سال اول، شماره 4، صص. 131-160.##محمدی، مهدی، حسینی، سید علی، حمیدی، مهدی، محمودی، بهروز، سعدآبادی، علی‌اصغر. 1393، شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی روش‌های مناسب همکاری فناورانه در بنگاه‌های با محصولات و سیستم‌های پیچیده (مورد مطالعه: شرکت توگا)، فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه فناوری، دوره دوم، شماره 3، صص. 55-84..##نوتاش، محمدرضا، عقبی طلب، علی. 1386، عوامل کلیدی انتشار فناوری در صنایع کوچک و متوسط ایران، فصلنامه توسعه فناوری، سال پنجم، شماره 11، بهار و تابستان 1386، صص. 63-79.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مسائل کارگزاری در سرمایه‌گذاری خطرپذیر و راهکارهای رفع آنها در مراحل مختلف رشد شرکت‌های نوآور در ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Mitigating Agency Problems in Venture Capital Contracting in Different Stage of Iranian Entrepreneurial Firms Growth</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف از این پژوهش ارائه راهکارهای عملی در قراردادهای سرمایه‌گذاری خطرپذیر با توجه به مرحله رشد شرکت‌های نوآور است. در سرمایه‌گذاری خطرپذیر، چالش‌های مختلفی به علت عدم‌تقارن اطلاعاتی و عدم‌همسویی منافع میان سرمایه‌گذار و کارآفرینان رخ می‌دهد که در چارچوب نظریه کارگزاری بررسی می‌شود و ابزارهای گوناگون کنترلی و انگیزشی را پیشنهاد می‌نماید. اما عاملی که بر اتخاذ راهبردهای متناسب هر کسب‌وکار تاثیر می‌گذارد، میزان رشدیافتگی آن است، زیرا در هر یک از این مراحل، نیازها و ویژگی‌های شرکت تغییر می‌یابد و در نتیجه چالش‌های میان آنها نیز متفاوت خواهد بود. در این مطالعه‌، با استفاده از روش نظریه داده‌بنیاد، راهکارهای مورد استفاده سرمایه‌گذاران از طریق مصاحبه نیمه‌ساختاریافته و گردآوری اطلاعات واقعی مورد بررسی قرار گرفته است. تحلیل داده‌ها از طریق کدگذاری و شناسایی ارتباط میان مقولات مختلف، نشان می‌دهد با تغییر در مولفه‌های توسعه کسب‌وکار، مهارت‌های کارآفرین و نوع ریسک در مراحل مختلف رشد، رویکرد سرمایه‌گذاری نیز تغییر می‌کند. در عین حال، تاثیر عوامل محیطی بر فضای حاکم بر کسب‌وکار اعم از بازار تامین مالی و نقش مستقیم دولت در آن، ضعف‌های قانونی و زیرساخت‌های فرهنگی نیز بر تنظیم رویکرد قرارداد تاثیر می‌گذارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The purpose of current study is to find practical solutions in venture capital (VC) contracting according to entrepreneurial firm’s stage of growth. In venture capital (VC) contracting, Information asymmetry and conflict of interest causes lots of challenges between VC and entrepreneurs that will be investigate based on agency theory, then suggest diverse control and motivational mechanisms to mitigate agency problems. The factor affects on firm’s taking adequate strategies is its growth rate, because the firms needs and characteristics varies during stages so the problems change with the growth. Using grounded theory approach, authors tried to find different solutions which VCs usually use by semi-structured interviews and data gathering. Data analysis using open and axial coding shows the contracting approach varies due to changes of business developing factors, improving entrepreneur’s abilities and risks type in different stages of firm growth. Also business environment such as market, government’s intervention, legal shortcomings and cultural infrastructure affects the contracting approach as well.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>113</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>140</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهرناز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حیدری</Family>
						<NameE>Mehrnaz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Heidari Soureshjani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده مهندسی صنایع و سیستمها، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده مهندسی صنایع و سیستمها، دانشگاه تربیت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehrnaz.heidari@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پرستو</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>Parastoo</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohammadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار. دانشکده مهندسی صنایع و سیستمها دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار. دانشکده مهندسی صنایع و سیستمها</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>p.mohammadi@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایه‌گذاری خطرپذیر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظریه کارگزاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مراحل رشد شرکتهای نوآور</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظریه داده‌بنیاد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Amit, R., Glosten , L. &amp; Muller, E. 1990. Entrepreneurial ability, venture investments, and risk sharing. Management Science, 36(10),  pp. 1232-1246.##Arcot, S. 2014. Participating convertible preferred stock in venture capital exits. Journal of Business Venturing, 29(1), pp. 72-87.##Baker, M.P. &amp; Gompers, P.A. 1999. Executive Ownership and Control in Newly Public Firms: The Role of Venture Capitalists. Working Paper. Harvard Business School.##Bender, M. 2011. Spatial Proximity in Venture Capital Financing: A Theoretical and Empirical Analysis of Germany. 1st ed. Germany: Springer Fachmedien Wiesbaden.##Bengtsson, O. &amp; Hand, J. 2011. CEO compensation in venture-backed firms. Journal of Business Venturing, 26(4),  pp. 391-411.##Bergemann, D. &amp; Hege, U. 1998. Venture capital Financing, Moral Hazard and learning. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, Volume (22),  pp. 703-735.##Bergemann, D., Hege, U. &amp; Peng , L. 2009. Venture Capital and Sequential Investments. Cowles Foundation Discussion Paper No. 1682R.##Berry, T.K., Paige Fields, L. &amp; Wilkins, M.S. 2006. The interaction among multiple governance mechanisms in young newly public firms. Journal of Corporate Finance, 12(3), pp. 449-466.##Bertoni, F., Colombo, M.G. &amp; Grilli, L. 2011. Venture Capital Financing and the Growth of High-Tech Start-Ups: Disentangling Treatment from Selection Effects. Research Policy,  40(7), pp. 1028-1043.##Bienz, C. &amp; Hirsch, J. 2012. The Dynamics of Venture Capital Contracts. Review of Finance, 16(1),  pp. 157-195.##Bitler, M.P., Vissing-Jorgensen, A. &amp; Moskowitz, T.J. 2009. Why Do Entrepreneurs Hold Large Ownership Shares? Testing Agency Theory Using Entrepreneur Effort and Wealth. Working Paper. Graduate School of Business, University of Chicago.##Broughman, B. &amp; Fried, J. 2010. Renegotiation of cash flow rights in the sale of VC-backed firms. Journal of Financial Economics, 95(3),  pp. 384-399.##Cai, C.X., Duxbury, D. &amp; Keasey, K. 2007. A New Test of Signaling Theory. Finance Letters,  5(2), pp. 1-5.##Carrizosa, M.T. 2007. A Review of the Literature of Firm Growth. Universitat Rovira I Virgili.##Casamatta, C. &amp; Haritchabalet, C. 2007. Experience, screening and syndication in venture capital investments. Journal of Financial Intermediation, 16(3), pp. 368-398.##Chen, Y.-R. &amp; Chuang, W.-T. 2009. Alignment or entrenchment? Corporate governance and cash holdings in growing firms. Journal of Business Research,  62(11), pp. 1200-1206.##Cole, R., Cumming, D. &amp; Li, D. 2016. Do banks or VCs spur small firm growth? Journal of International Financial Markets, Institutions and Money, Volume ( 41), pp. 60-72.##Cornelli, F. &amp; Yosha, O. 2003. Stage Financing and the Role of Convertible Securities. The Review of Economic Studies, 70(1), pp. 1-32.##Creswell, J.W. &amp; Miller, D.L. 2000. Determining Validity in Qualitative Inquiry. Theory Into Practice, 39(3), pp. 124-130.##Croce, A., Martí, J. &amp; Murtinu, S. 2013. The impact of venture capital on the productivity growth of European entrepreneurial firms: ‘Screening’ or ‘value added’ effect? Journal of Business Venturing, 28(4), pp. 489-510.##Cumming &amp; Johan 2009. Venture Capital and Private Equity Contracting: An International Perspective: Elsevier Science.##Cumming, D.J. 2005. Agency costs, institutions, learning, and taxation in venture capital contracting. Journal of Business Venturing, 20(5), pp. 573-622.##Daunfeldt, Elert &amp; Johansson 2013. The economic contribution of high growth firms: do policy implications depend on the choice of growth indicator? Journal of Industry, Competition and Trade.##Davila, A., Foster, G. &amp; Gupta, M. 2003. Venture capital financing and the growth of startup firms. Journal of Business Venturing, 18(6), pp. 689-708.##de Bettignies, J.-E. &amp; Brander, J.A. 2007. Financing entrepreneurship: Bank finance versus venture capital. Journal of Business Venturing, 22(6), pp. 808-832.##Dewatripont, M. &amp; Tirole, J. 1994. A Theory of Debt and Equity: Diversity of Securities and Manager-Shareholder Congruence, The Quarterly Journal of Economics, 109(4).##Dimov, D., Shepherd, D.A. &amp; Sutcliffe, K.M. 2007. Requisite expertise, firm reputation, and status in venture capital investment allocation decisions. Journal of Business Venturing, 22(4), pp. 481-502.##Doh, S. &amp; Kim, B. 2014. Government support for SME innovations in the regional industries: The case of government financial support program in South Korea. Research Policy,  43(9), pp. 1557-1569.##Ebbers, J.J. &amp; Wijnberg, N.M. 2012. Nascent ventures competing for start-up capital: Matching reputations and investors. Journal of Business Venturing, 27(3), pp. 372-384.##Elitzur, R. &amp; Gavious, A. 2003. Contracting, signaling, and moral hazard: a model of entrepreneurs, ‘angels,’ and venture capitalists. Journal of Business Venturing, 18(6), pp.  709-725.##Florin, J. 2005. Is venture capital worth it? Effects on firm performance and founder returns. Journal of Business Venturing, 20(1), pp. 113-135.##Fluck, Z., Garrison, K. &amp; Myers, S.C. 2005. Venture Capital Contracting and Syndication: An Experiment in Computational Corporate Finance. National Bureau of Economic Research Working Paper Series No.11624.##Giot, P. &amp; Schwienbacher, A. 2007. IPOs, trade sales and liquidations: Modelling venture capital exits using survival analysis. Journal of Banking &amp; Finance, 31(3), pp. 679-702.##Gompers, P. 1997. Ownership and Control in Entrepreneurial firm: An examination of convertible securities in Venture Capital Investment. Harvard University.##Gompers, P.A. 1995. Optimal Investment, Monitoring, and the Staging of Venture Capital. The Journal of Finance, 50(5), pp. 1461-1489.##Gonzalez-Diaz, M. &amp; Solis-Rodriguez, V. 2012. Why do entrepreneurs use franchising as a financial tool? An agency explanation. Journal of Business Venturing, 27(3), pp. 325-341.##Gundry, L.K. &amp; Welsch, H.P. 2001. The Ambitious Entrepreneur: High Growth Strategies of Women-owned Enterprises. Journal of Business Venturing, Volume (16), pp. 453-470.##Harrison, R.T. &amp; Mason, C.M. 1996. Developing the informal Venture Capital market: A review of the department of trade and industry’s informal invesmtent demonstration projects. Regional Studies, 30(8).##Hellmann, T. 2006. IPOs, acquisitions, and the use of convertible securities in venture capital. Journal of Financial Economics, 81(3), pp. 649-679.##Holmstrom, B. 1979. Moral Hazard and Observability. Bell Journal of Economics, 10(1), pp. 74-91.##Hsu, D.H. 2007. Experienced entrepreneurial founders, organizational capital, and venture capital funding. Research Policy, 36(5), pp. 722-741.##Jensen, M.C. &amp; Meckling, W.H. 1976. Theory of the Firm: Managerial Behavior, Agency Costs and Ownership Structure, Journal of Financial Economics, 3(4).##Kaplan, S.N. &amp; Strömberg, P. 2003. Financial Contracting Theory Meets the Real World: An Empirical Analysis of Venture Capital Contracts. The Review of Economic Studies, 70(2),  pp. 281-315.##Kruger, M. 2004. Entrepreneurial theory and creativity (Chapter 2). University of Pretoria.##Laffont, J.J. &amp; Tirole, J. 1998. The Dynamics of Incentive Contracts. Econometrica, 56(5).##Leisen, D.P.J. 2012. Staged venture capital contracting with ratchets and liquidation rights. Review of Financial Economics, 21(1).##Lewis, C.M. &amp; Verwijmeren, P. 2011. Convertible security design and contract innovation. Journal of Corporate Finance, 17(4), pp. 809-831.##Li, Y. 2008. Duration Analysis of Venture Capital Staging: A Real Options Perspective. Journal of Business Venturing, 23(5), pp. 497-512.##Metrick, A. &amp; Yasuda, A. 2011. Venture Capital and the Finance of Innovation. 2nd ed: John Wiley and Sons, Inc.##OECD 2003. Venture Capital Policy Review: United State. Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development.##Sahlman, W.A. 1990. The Structure and Governance of Venture-Capital Organizations. Journal of Financial Economics, 27(2), pp. 473-521.##Strauss, A. &amp; Corbin, J.M. 1998. Basics of Qualitative Research: Techniques and Procedures for Developing Grounded Theory: SAGE Publications.##Tian, X. 2011. The causes and consequences of venture capital stage financing. Journal of Financial Economics, 101(1), pp. 132-159.##Tirole, J. 2010. The Theory of Corporate Finance: Princeton University Press.##Trester, J.J. 1998. Venture Capital Contracting under Asymmetric Information. Journal of Banking and Finance, 22(6–8), pp. 675-699.##Truls, E. 2002. Entrepreneurial Capital: the Emerging Venture’s Most Important Asset and Competitive Advantage. Journal of Business Venturing, 17(3), pp. 275-290.##Tykvová, T. &amp; Schertler, A. 2011. Cross-border venture capital flows and local ties: Evidence from developed countries. The Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance, 51(1), pp. 36-48.##Wennberg, K., Wiklund, J., DeTienne, D.R. &amp; Cardon, M.S. 2010. Reconceptualizing entrepreneurial exit: Divergent exit routes and their drivers. Journal of Business Venturing,  25(4), pp. 361-375.##Wirtz, P. 2011. The cognitive dimension of corporate governance in fast growing entrepreneurial firms. European Management Journal, 29(6), pp. 431-447.##حیدری، مهرناز. و محمدی، پرستو. 1395. شناسایی مولفه‌های مراحل مختلف رشد شرکت‌های نوآور در تعامل با سرمایه‌گذاران خطرپذیر. نشریه توسعه کارآفرینی, 9, صص59-78.##رستمی، محمد. 1385. چالش‌های سرمایه‌گذاری خطر پذیر در ایران . دومین کنفرانس ملی سرمایه‌گذاری مخاطره پذیر.تهران##قمری منظر، محمد حسین. 1396. شناسایی و اولویت بندی توانمندی‌های موثر بر موفقیت سرمایه‌گذاران خطرپذیر در تامین مالی پروژه‌های نوآور. پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد دانشگاه علم و صنعت.##کولیوند، ریحانه. 1395. بررسی ویژگی‌های قراردادهای شرکت‌های سرمایه‌گذاری خطرپذیر و شناسایی ریسک‌های مرتبط. کارشناسی ارشد, دانشگاه تهران.##معاونت برنامه‌ریزی و نظارت راهبردی رئیس جمهور. 1389. برنامه پنجم پنج ساله جمهوری اسلامی ایران##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی چرایی عدم پذیرش فناوری آبیاری قطرهای توسط کشاورزان در شهرستان سلماس</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Impediments to Adoption of Agricultural Technologies in Regions with Water Shortage from the Viewpoint of Farmers: The Case of Drip Irrigation in SALMAS</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> 
با توجه به کم‌‌آبی فزاینده در دنیا، لازم است روش‌های کشاورزی به منظور افزایش بهره‌وری اصلاح شود. با این حال به نظر می‌رسد در مناطقی که با معضل کم‌آبی دست‌وپنجه نرم می‌کنند، مشکلاتی وجود دارد که مانع از پذیرش فناوری‌های نوین توسط کشاورزان می‌شود. برای بررسی این مشکل، فناوری آبیاری قطره‌ای در شهرستان سلماس از منطقه‌ی دریاچه‌ی ارومیه مورد واکاوی قرار گرفته است. 
 
یافته‌های پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که ناآگاهی، ذهنیت دولتی، خوانش عدم صرفه‌ی اقتصادی، سیاست‌گذاری و پیاده‌سازی نامناسب دولت، بی‌اعتمادی به دولت، خوانش ناکارآیی فناوری، تجربه‌ی ناموفق همکاران، عدم رغبت به پیش‌قدمی و عدم احساس مسئولیت اجتماعی در قبال مصرف صیانتی دلایل عام عدم پذیرش فناوری آبیاری قطره‌ای بین کشاورزان سلماس است. همچنین برای مناطق شرق سلماس، ناهماهنگی ارگان‌های دولتی یکی از دلایل تأثیرگذار تلقی می‌شود. مردم جنوب سلماس دارای احساس ناامنی ناشی از اختلاط قومی‌اند و مردم غرب سلماس به دلیل احساس نیاز کمتر، تمایل به حفظ زیبایی و دست‌نخوردگی طبیعی زمین دارند و علاقه‌ای به استفاده از آبیاری قطره‌ای ندارند. 
 </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Regarding water crises in the world it is necessary to change and reform agricultural methods in order to increase efficacy.  Although it seems that farmers in some regions do not accept new technologies due to some problems. To address these problems, drip irrigation technology was investigated in Salmas near to zone Lake Urumia. Despite the government supports, the adoption of drip irrigation technologies in the SALMAS region is even lower than its neighbouring regions with less shortage of water crises. Through a qualitative, exploratory research based on the literature of technology adoption, this paper tries to uncover the reasons behind this lower than expected level of adoption among farmers. The findings suggest that farmers in the southern parts of the region suffer from insecurities that are caused by ethnic diversity of the local communities. The farmers in the western part, however, prefer having a pretty field over consuming less water. The implications for theories and practice are outlined.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>141</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>168</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پوریا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>چوبچیان</Family>
						<NameE>Pooria</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Choobchian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>pooria.choobchian@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کیامهر</Family>
						<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kiamehr</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>kiamehr@sharif.edu</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ملکی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Maleki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>پژوهشکده سیاست گذاری علم فناوری و صنعت، دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>پژوهشکده سیاست گذاری علم فناوری و صنعت، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.maleki@sharif.edu</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پذیرش فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انتشار فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آبیاری قطره ای</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دریاچه ارومیه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abdulai, A., Owusu, V. &amp; Bakang, J.-E. A. 2011. Adoption of Safer Irrigation Technologies and Cropping Patterns: Evidence from Southern Ghana. Ecological Economics, Volume (70), pp. 1415-1423.##Bagheri, A. &amp; Ghorbani, A. 2011. Adoption and non-adoption of sprinkler irrigation technology in Ardabil Province of Iran. African Journal of Agricultural Research, Volume (6), pp. 1085-1089.##Bagozzi, R. P. 2007. The legacy of the technology acceptance model and a proposal for a paradigm shift. Journal of the Association for Information Systems, Volume (8).##Barse, K., Gohad, V. &amp; Lunge, M. 2010. Adoption of Drip Irrigation System by Orange Growers in Amravati Taluka. Agriculture Update, Volume (5), pp. 346-348.##Carey, J. M. &amp; Zilberman, D. 2002. A Model of Investment under Uncertainty: Modern Irrigation Technology and Emerging Markets in Water. American Journal of Agricultural Economics, Volume (84), pp. 171-183.##Caswell, M. F. &amp; Zilberman, D. 1986. The Effects of Well Depth and Land Quality on the Choice of Irrigation Technology. American Journal of Agricultural Economics, Volume (68), pp. 798-811.##Chris perry, P. S., FAWZI KARAJEH 2017. Does Improved Irrigation Technology Save Water? A Review of the Evidence. Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations CAIRZO.##David, P. A. 1969. A Contribution to the Theory of Diffusion, Research Center in Economic Growth, Stanford University.##Davis, F. D. 1989. Perceived Usefulness, Perceived Ease of Use, and User Acceptance of Information Technology. Mis Quarterly, pp. 319-340.##Dixit, A. K. &amp; Pindyck, R. S. 1994. Investment under uncertainty, Princeton University Press.##Feder, G., Just, R. E. &amp; Zilberman, D. 1985. Adoption of agricultural innovations in developing countries: A survey. Economic Development and Cultural Change, Volume (33), pp. 255-298.##Feder, G. &amp; O’mara, G. T. 1981. Farm size and the diffusion of green revolution technology. Economic Development and Cultural Change, Volume (30), pp. 59-76.##Hoseinpour, M., Fakheri fard, A. &amp; Naghili, R. 2010. Death of Urmia Lake, a Silent Disaster Investigating Causes, Results and Solutions of Urmia Lake Drying.  1st International Applied Geological Congress, Department of Geology, Islamic Azad University, Islamic Azad University-Mashad Branch, Iran.##Hultman, J. 2004, Technology adoption and embeddedness. Propositions on a four facet framework.  20th Annual IMP Conference.##ISIK, M. 2001, Technology Adoption Decisions Under Uncertainty: Impacts of Alternative Return Assumptions on Timing of Adoption.  AAEA Annual Meeting, Chicago IL, pp. 5-8.##Jafari shalamzari, M., Sadoddin, A., Sheikh, V. &amp; Abedi sarvestani, A. 2016. Analysis of Adaptation Determinants of Domestic Rainwater Harvesting Systems (DRWHs) in Golestan Province, Iran. Environmental Resources Research, Volume (4), pp. 27-43.##Just, R. E. &amp; Zilberman, D. 1988. The effects of agricultural development policies on income distribution and technological change in agriculture. Journal of Development Economics, Volume (28), pp. 193-216.##Kalantari, K., Rahimian, M., Mohammadi, Y., Asadi, A. &amp; Ardali, A. A. 2010. Investigation of Effective Factors on Admission and Refusing of Sprinkler Irrigation System of Ardal Township, Iran. Journal of Food, Agriculture &amp; Environment, Volume (8), pp. 1218-1224.##Kiruthika, N. 2014. Determinants of Adoption of drip Irrigation in Sugarcane Cultivation in Tamil Nadu. Analysis, Volume (143).##Kumar, D. S. 2012. Adoption of drip irrigation system in India: Some Experience and Evidence. Bangladesh Development Studies, Volume (35), pp. 61-78.##Lapar, M. L. A. &amp; Ehui, S. K. 2004. Factors Affecting Adoption of Dual-Purpose Forages in the Philippine Uplands. Agricultural Systems, Volume (81), pp. 95-114.##Mcdonald, R. &amp; Siegel, D. 1986. The value of waiting to invest. The Quarterly Journal of Economics, Volume (101), pp. 707-727.##Mohamend, Y. A. 1982. Diffusion of agricultural innovations among traditional farmers of Western Sudan—The case of East Kordofan and El Fasher districts. GeoJournal, Volume (6), pp. 31-40.##Namara, R. E., Nagar, R. &amp; Upadhyay, B. 2007. Economics, Adoption Determinants, And Impacts Of Micro-Irrigation Technologies: Empirical Results from India. Irrigation Science, Volume (25), pp. 283-297.##Ogada, M. J., Mwabu, G. &amp; Muchai, D. 2014. Farm Technology Adoption in Kenya: a Simultaneous Estimation of Inorganic Fertilizer and Improved Maize Variety Adoption Decisions. Agricultural and Food Economics, Volume (2), pp. 1-18.##Ranjan, R. &amp; athalye, S. 2009. Drought resilience in agriculture: The role of Technological Options, Land Use Dynamics, and Risk Perception. Natural Resource Modeling, Volume (22), pp. 437-462.##Rogers everett, M. 1995. Diffusion of innovations. New York, 12.##Rossi, F. R., Souza filho, H. M. D. &amp; CARRER, M. J. Irrigation adoption by orange producers of the state of São Paulo-Brazil: determinants and barriers.  2016 Annual Meeting, February 6-9, 2016, San Antonio, Texas, 2016. Southern Agricultural Economics Association.##Shahzadi, E. 2013. Investigating Factors Influencing Adoption of Pressurized Irrigation Systems by Farmers Case Study: Garmsar County, Iran. American-Eurasian Journal of Agriculture and Environment Science, Volume (13), pp. 32-37.##Singh, P., Patel, S., Trivedi, M. &amp; PATEL, G. 2015. Assessing the Relative Impacts of the Factors Affecting MIS Adoption Process. International Journal of Sustainable Development &amp; World Ecology, Volume (22), pp. 213-218.##Sunding, D. &amp; Zilberman, D. 2001. The Agricultural Innovation Process: Research and Technology Adoption in a Changing Agricultural Sector. Handbook of Agricultural Economics, Volume (1), pp. 207-261.##Vaezi, L., Daran, H.H. 2012. Evaluation of the Effective Parameters on Pressurized Irrigation System by Iranian Farmers. Middle-East Journal of Scientific Research, Volume (11), pp. 39-45.##Van raaij, E. M. &amp; Schepers, J. J. 2008. The Acceptance and Use of a Virtual Learning Environment in China. Computers &amp; Education, Volume (50), pp. 838-852.##Venkatesh, V. 2000. Determinants of Perceived Ease of Use: Integrating Control, Intrinsic Motivation, and Emotion into the Technology Acceptance Model. Information Systems Research, Volume (11), pp. 342-365.##Venkatesh, V. &amp; Bala, H. 2008. Technology Acceptance Model 3 and a Research Agenda on Interventions. Decision Sciences, Volume (39), pp.  273-315.##Venkatesh, V. &amp; Davis, F. D. 2000. A Theoretical Extension of the Technology Acceptance Model: Four Longitudinal Field Studies. Management Science, Volume (46), pp. 186-204.##Venkatesh, V., Morris, M. G., Davis, G. B. &amp; Davis, F. D. 2003. User Acceptance of Information Technology: Toward a Unified View. MIS quarterly, pp. 425-478.##Wilson, P. N. 2001. First-order economizing: Irrigation Technology Adoption and the Farm. Agrekon, Volume (40), pp. 231-248.##Wubeneh, N. G. &amp; SANDERS, J. 2006. Farm-level Adoption of Sorghum Technologies in Tigray, Ethiopia. Agricultural Systems, Volume (91), pp. 122-134.##Yearbook, F. S. 2014. Europe and Central Asia Food and Agriculture. Budapest: FAO.##Yin, R. K. 2013. Case study research: Design and Methods, Sage Publications.##الهی، ش.، غریبی، ج.، مجیدپور، م. و انواری رستمی، ع. ا. 1394. مسیر اشاعه فناوری‌های انرژی‌های تجدیدپذیر: رویکرد نظریه‌سازی بنیادی. نشریه علمی پژوهشی مدیریت نوآوری، صص 33-56.##موسوی حقیقی، م. و تاجیک، م. 1393. شبیه سازی فرآیند اشاعه محصولات نوین با رویکرد پویایی های سیستم. نشریه علمی پژوهشی مدیریت نوآوری، صص 77-99.##وب سایت احیای دریاچه ارومیه، 1395، وضعیت مالکیت اراضی در حوزه دریاچه ارومیه، [برخط]، قابل دسترس در: ulrp.sharif.ir/fa##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				