<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1395</YEAR>
<VOL>5</VOL>
<NO>2</NO>
<MOSALSAL>16</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>162</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر عوامل زمینه‌ای بیرونی بر اتخاذ نوآوری باز با تأکید بر ویژگی‌های بخش: شواهدی از شرکت‌های بخش مواد پیشرفته در ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Impact of External Contextual Factors on Open Innovation Adoption with an Emphasis on Sectorial Characteristics: Evidences from Iran&#039;s Advanced Materials Firms</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>طی دهه گذشته نوآوری باز به‌عنوان یکی از نظریات حوزه مدیریت نوآوری، مورد توجه محققان قرار گرفته است. پژوهشگران معتقدند اتخاذ و کارایی این رویکرد، تحت تأثیر اقتضائات مختلف درون‌بنگاهی و برون‌بنگاهی قرار دارد. شرایط زمینه‌ای صنعت یا بخشی که بنگاه‌ها در آن فعالیت می‌کنند و نیز شرایط محیط نهادی، از جمله اقتضائات برون‌بنگاهی مؤثر بر نوآوری باز به شمار می‌آیند. بخش مواد پیشرفته به‌عنوان یکی از ارکان اقتصاد دانش‌بنیان کمتر مورد توجه محققان حوزه مدیریت نوآوری قرار داشته است. به علاوه، بررسی ادبیات نشان‌دهنده فقدان پژوهش‌های عمیق در رابطه با اتخاذ و کارایی نوآوری باز در بافتار کشورهای درحال توسعه به ویژه ایران است. با شناسایی این شکاف مطالعاتی، پژوهش حاضر با رویکردی کیفی مبتنی بر استراتژی مطالعه چندموردی، به بررسی نوآوری باز در میان بنگاه‌های بخش مواد پیشرفته در ایران پرداخته است. نتایج این پژوهش با تأیید رواج نوآوری باز در میان بنگاه‌های این بخش، نشان‌دهنده غلبه راهبرد نوآوری باز به درون با استفاده از روش‌های مالی و غیرمالی است. بنگاه‌های مورد مطالعه، از راهبردهای نوآوری باز برای فائق آمدن بر هر دو دسته چالش‌های فنی و بازار بهره جسته‌اند. اگرچه بنگاه‌های مورد مطالعه در اتخاذ رویکرد نوآوری باز با چالش‌های مختلفی روبرو بوده‌اند؛ اما دو عامل گسترش آموزش عالی و تحقیقات و نیز رواج اینترنت از جمله عوامل تسهیل‌کننده اتخاذ نوآوری باز در میان شرکت‌های ایرانی هستند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Over the past decade, open innovation has been of interest to several researchers as one of the innovation management theories. These researchers believe that the adoption and efficacy of this approach are influenced by different internal and external contingencies to firms. Sector or industry contextual properties and institutional environment conditions are among those external contingencies affecting open innovation in firms. Advanced materials sector, as a pillar of knowledge-based economy, has been less studied by innovation management scholars. In addition, a review of the literature indicates a lack of in-depth research on the adoption and efficacy of open innovation in the context of developing countries, especially in Iran. Having identified these research gaps, this study uses qualitative approach based on multiple case studies to examine open innovation among advanced materials firms in Iran. The results of this study confirms the prevalence of open innovation among the firms in this sector, reflecting the dominance of inbound open innovation strategy using financial and non-financial methods. The studied firms use open innovation strategies to overcome both technical and market challenges. Although they face several challenges in their open innovation practices, the expansion of higher education and research, and the spread of the internet are among the factors facilitating the adoption of open innovation among Iranian firms.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>31</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جواد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مشایخ</Family>
						<NameE>Javad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mashayekh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت فناوری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی و پژوهشگر پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت فناوری دانشگاه علامه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mashayekh313@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید حبیب‌اله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>طباطبائیان</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Habibollah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tabatabaeian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>tabatabaeian@atu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مقصود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امیری</Family>
						<NameE>Maghsoud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Amiri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مدیریت صنعتی، دانشکده مدیریت و</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>amiri@atu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمود مهرداد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شکریه</Family>
						<NameE>Mahmood Mehrdad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shokrieh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه طراحی کاربردی، دانشکده مهندسی مکانیک، دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه طراحی کاربردی، دانشکده مهندسی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shokrieh@iust.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوآوری باز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کشورهای درحال توسعه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مواد پیشرفته</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مطالعه موردی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Baba, Y., Shichijo, N. &amp; Sedita, S. R., 2009. How do collaborations with universities affect firms’ innovative performance? The role of “Pasteur scientists” in the advanced materials field. . Research Policy, 38(5), pp. 756-764.##Chesbrough, H. &amp; Bogers, M., 2014. Explicating open innovation: clarifying an emerging paradigm for understanding innovation. In: H. Chesbrough, W. Vanhaverbeke &amp; J. West, eds. New Frontiers in Open Innovation. Oxford: Oxford University Press, pp. 3-28.##Chesbrough, H. &amp; Crowther, A. K., 2006. Beyond high tech: early adopters of open innovation in other industries. R&amp;D Management, 36(3), pp. 229-236.##Chesbrough, H. W., 2003. Open innovation: The new imperative for creating and profiting from technology. USA: Harvard Business Press.##Creswell, J. W., 2013. Research design: Qualitative, quantitative, and mixed methods approaches. Sage publications.##Dahlander, L. &amp; Gann, D. M., 2010. How open is innovation?. , 39(6),. Research policy, 39(6), pp. 699-709.##Eisenhardt, K. M., 1989. Building theories from case study research.. Academy of management review, 14(4), pp. 532-550.##Eisenhardt, K. M. &amp; Graebner, M. E., 2007. Theory building from cases: Opportunities and challenges. Academy of management journal, 50(1), pp. 25-32.##Faems, D., Janssens, M. &amp; Van Looy, B., 2010. Managing the Co-operation–Competition Dilemma in R&amp;D Alliances: A Multiple Case Study in the Advanced Materials Industry. Creativity and Innovation Management, 19(1), pp. 3-22.##Gassmann, O., 2006. Opening up the innovation process: towards an agenda. R&amp;D Management, 36(3), pp. 223-228.##Hagedoorn, J. &amp; Schakenraad, J., 1991. Inter-firm partnerships for generic technologies—the case of new materials. Technovation, 11(7), pp. 429-444.##Holloway, I. &amp; Wheeler, S., 2013. Qualitative research in nursing and healthcare. John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Hsieh, H. F. &amp; Shannon, S. E., 2005. Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qualitative health research, 15(9), pp. 1277-1288.##Huizingh, E., 2011. Open innovation: State of the art and future perspectives. Technovation, 31(1), pp. 2-9.##Lubik, S., Garnsey, E. .., Minshall, T. &amp; Platts, K., 2013. Value creation from the innovation environment: partnership strategies in university spin-outs. R&amp;D Management, 43(2), pp. 136-150.##Lubik, S. &amp; Garnsey, E., 2015. Early Business Model Evolution in Science-based Ventures: The Case of Advanced Materials. Long Range Planning.##Maine, E. &amp; Garnsey, E., 2006. Commercializing generic technology: The case of advanced materials ventures. Research Policy, 35(3), pp. 375-393.##Maine, E. &amp; Garnsey, E., 2007. The commercialisation environment of advanced materials ventures. International Journal of Technology Management, 39(1-2), pp. 49-71.##Maine, E., Lubik, S. &amp; Garnsey, E., 2012. Overcoming commercialization challenges in science-based business: Strategies for advanced materials ventures. PICMET.##Maine, E., Lubik, S. J. &amp; Garnsey, E. W., 2010. Embracing Uncertainty: Value Creation by Advanced Materials Ventures,  Centre for Technology Management.##Maine, E. &amp; Seegopaul, P., 2016. Accelerating advanced-materials commercialization. Nature Materials, 15(5), pp. 487-491.##Malaman, R., 1990. Innovation in Advanced Materials. In: B. Dankbaar, J. Groenewegen &amp; H. Schenk, eds. Perspectives in Industrial Organization. Springer Netherlands, pp. 151-170.##Mertens, D. M., 2014. Research and Evaluation in Education and Psychology: Integrating Diversity With Quantitative, Qualitative, and Mixed Methods. Sage Publications.##Meyer, C. B., 2001. A case in case study methodology. Field methods, 13(4), pp. 329-352.##Mowery, D., 2009. Plus ca change: Industrial R&amp;D in the “third industrial revolution”. Industrial and corporate change, 18(1), pp. 1-50.##Musso, C., 2009. New learning from old plastics: The effects of value-chain-complexity on adoption time. Technovation, 29(4), pp. 299-312.##National Research Council, 1993. Commercialization of new materials for a global economy . National Academy Press.##Niosi, J., 1993. Strategic partnerships in Canadian advanced materials. R&amp;D Management, 23(1), pp. 17-28.##OECD, 2000. 21st Century Technologies: Promises and Perils of a Dynamic Future. Paris: OECD.##Pavitt, K., 1984. Sectoral patterns of technical change: towards a taxonomy and a theory. Research Policy, 13(6), pp. 343-373.##Schuster, D., 1992. The World Won’t Beat a Path to Your Door. Key Engineering Materials, January, pp. 337-348.##Vanhaverbeke, W., Vermeersch, I. &amp; De Zutter, S., 2012. Open innovation in SMEs: How can small companies and start-ups benefit from open innovation strategies?. Flanders DC study.##Viotti, E. B., 2002. National learning systems: a new approach on technological change in late industrializing economies and evidences from the cases of Brazil and South Korea.. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 69(7), pp. 653-680.##Wang, Y. &amp; Zhou, Z., 2012. Can open innovation approach be applied by latecomer firms in emerging countries?. Journal of Knowledge-based Innovation in China, 4(3), pp. 163-173.##Xiaobao, P., Wei, S. &amp; Yuzhen, D., 2013. Framework of open innovation in SMEs in an emerging economy: firm characteristics, network openness, and network information. . International Journal of Technology Management, 62(2/3/4), pp. 223-250.##Yin, R. K., 2003. Case study research: Design and methods. Sage publications.##Yoruk, E., 2011. The influence of technological capabilities on the knowledge network component of innovation systems: evidence from advanced materials in Turkey. International Journal of Technological Learning, Innovation and Development, 4(4), pp. 330-362.##رنجبر، ه. و غیره، 1391. نمونه‌گیری در پژوهش‌های کیفی: راهنمایی برای شروع. سالنامه پژوهش علوم سلامت و نظامی، 10(3)، صص. 250-238.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>حرکتهای «جمعی» و تغییرات نهاد و فناوری: بررسی شکل گیری بنگاه های علم محور در صنعت زیست‌داروی ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Collective Action and Institutional and Technological Change: A Case Study of Iran Bio-Pharmaceutical Industry</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>شواهد متعددی در مورد تاثیر حرکت‌های جمعی بر تحولات نهادی-فناورانة صنایع وجود دارد. با این حال، تاکنون پژوهش‌های «نظام‌مند» اندکی توانسته‌اند «تنوع و میزان» حرکت‌های جمعی در این تغییرات را توضیح دهند. پژوهش حاضر ضمن ارائه چارچوبی برای تحلیل «نظام‌مندِ» تنوع و میزان فعالیت‌های جمعی در شکل‌گیری بنگاه‌های علم‌محور زیست‌دارو، به عنوان مهمترین تغییر نهادی در صنعت زیست‌داروی ایران،  میزان جمعی بودن فعالیت «کارآفرینان نهادی» در طیف متنوعی از اقدامات نهادی مورد بررسی قرار داد و تلاش کرد به این سوال پاسخ دهد که تا چه حد تغییر قاعده بازی برای حرکت از صنایع سنتی به سمت صنایع دارای قابلیت نوآورانه متاثر از حرکت‌های جمعی است. این مقاله از نوع کیفی است و داده‌های آن بر اساس مصاحبه هدفمند با 57 نفر از افراد تاثیرگذار در این صنعت گردآوری شدند. نتایج پژوهش، از طریق تحلیل زمینه و کدگذاری یافته‌ها بدست آمدند. صنعت داروسازی ایران، صنعتی است که در تجاری‌سازی «زیست‌شبیه‌داروها» موفقیت چشمگیری داشته است. این موفقیت، بیش از هر چیز نتیجة وقوع یک تغییر نهادی قابل توجه، از «شرکت‌های تامین‌محور دولتی» به سمت «شرکت‌های علم‌محور خصوصی» بوده است. یافته‌های پژوهش حاضر نشان می‌دهد که در پسِ شکل‌گیریِ این بنگاه‌های علم‌محور، چهار اقدام نهادی مهم وجود دارد و شبکه‌ای از افراد و کنشگران کلیدی (کارآفرینان نهادی) از بخش‌های خصوصی و دولتی و به صورت رسمی یا غیررسمی در تحقق تک‌تک این کارنهادها حضور داشته‌اند و هیچ‌یک از اقدامات نهادی بررسی شده به تنهایی از سوی کارآفرینان نهادی یک بخش توسعه نیافته‌اند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>There is a wide range of evidence emphasizing the role of collective action in the process of institutional change. Collective collaboration as well as individualistic profit-seeking activities of entrepreneurs are two complementary wings of institutional and technical change in innovation systems. In this paper, based on empirical evidence from Iran bio-pharmaceutical sector, we develop a framework to link the institutional change of innovation systems to practices and institutional entrepreneurs (IEs). Then we use the framework to see to what extent IEs&#039; practices are collective. We analyze institutional change as a shift from supplier-dominated governmental firms to science-based private firms. After that, we analyze four practices as mainly influential practices with institutional change effects, and finally we elaborate on IEs who are actively involved in directing the practices. Our analysis shows that in all the practices, collective action has been influential. We also find that there is a network of entrepreneurs involved in all the practices. These IEs are from both governmental and non-governmental organizations and play formal as well as informal roles in directing the practices. Our analysis criticizes both government-centric and individualistic views of institutional and technical change in catching up on innovation systems.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>33</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>58</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>روح الله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حمیدی مطلق</Family>
						<NameE>Roohollah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hamidimotlagh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه صنعتی شریف؛ پژوهشکده سیاستگذاری علم، فناوری و صنعت دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه صنعتی شریف؛</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hamidimotlagh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدتقی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عیسایی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Taghi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Isaai</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار - دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار - دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>isaai@sharif.edu</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>یمین</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Yamin</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مدرسه کسب و کار دانشگاه منچستر</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مدرسه کسب و کار دانشگاه منچستر</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mo.yamin@manchester.ac.uk</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بابایی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Babaee</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکدۀ مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه صنعتی شریف؛ پژوهشکده سیاستگذاری علم، فناوری و صنعت دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکدۀ مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه صنعتی شریف؛</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ali.babaee.1395@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کرمانشاه</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kermanshah</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار - دانشکدۀ مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار - دانشکدۀ مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.kermanshah@sharif.edu</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حرکت جمعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تغییرات نهادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارنهاد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارآفرین نهادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Bell, M. &amp; Pavitt, K., 1993. Technological accumulation and industrial growth: contrasts between developed and developing countries.. Industrial and corporate change, 2(1), pp. 157-210.##Chandler, A. D., 1969. Strategy and Structure: Chapters in the History of the American Industrial Enterprise. Massachusetts: MIT Press Books.##Chandler, A. D., 1977. The visible hand: The management revolution in American business. . Massachusetts: Harvard University Press.##Commons, J. R., 1924. Legal foundations of capitalism. United States: Transaction Publishers.##Crabtree, B. &amp; Miller, W., 1992. A template approach to text anyalysis: Developing and using codebooks. In: B. Crabtree &amp; W. Miller, eds. Doing qualitative research in primary care: Multiple strategies. CA: Sage Publications, pp. 93-109.##Creswell, J., 2013. Qualitative inquiry and research design: Choosing among five approaches. SAGE Publications Inc.##Davis, L. &amp; North, D., 1971. Institutional change and American economic growth: A First Step Towards a Theory of Institional Innovation. The journal of Economic History, 30(1), pp. 131-149.##Demil, B. &amp; Bensédrine, J., 2005. Processes of legitimization and pressure toward regulation: corporate conformity and strategic behavior. International Studies of Management &amp; Organization, 35(2), pp. 56-77.##DiMaggio, P., 1988. Interest and agency in institutional theory. Institutional patterns and organizations: Culture and environment, Volume 1, pp. 3-22.##Dorado, S., 2005. Institutional entrepreneurship, partaking, and convening. Organization studies, 26(3), pp. 385-414.##Dosi, G., 1982. Technological paradigms and technological trajectories: a suggested interpretation of the determinants and directions of technical change. Research policy, 11(3), pp. 147-162.##Evans, P., 1995. Embedded autonomy: states and industrial transformation . NJ: Princeton University Press.##Garud, R. &amp; Jain, S., 1996. The embeddedness of technological system. Advances in strategic management, Volume 13, pp. 389-408.##Hannan, M. &amp; Freeman, J., 1977. The population ecology of organizations. American journal of sociology, 82(5), pp. 929-964.##Hardy, C. &amp; Maguire, S., 2008. Institutional entrepreneurship. In: The SAGE Handbook of Organizational Institutionalism . Singapore: Sage Publications Ltd, pp. 198-217.##Hayek, F. A., 1973. Rules and Order. Law, Legislation and Liberty. London and Henley: Routledge and Kegan Paul.##Hodgson, G. M., 1988. Economics and institutions: A Manifesto for a Modern Institutional Economics. Journal of the History of Economic Thought, 11(2), pp. 304-313.##Hung, S. C. &amp; Whittington, R., 2011. Agency in national innovation systems: Institutional entrepreneurship and the professionalization of Taiwanese IT. Research Policy, 40(4), pp. 526-538.##Kemp, R., Schot, J. &amp; Hoogma, R., 1998. Regime shifts to sustainability through processes of niche formation: the approach of strategic niche management. Technology analysis &amp; strategic management, 10(2), pp. 175-198.##Lawrence, T. B., Hardy, C. &amp; Phillips, N., 2002. Institutional effects of interorganizational collaboration: The emergence of proto-institutions. Academy of management journal, 45(1), pp. 281-290.##Lundvall, B., Joseph, K. J., Chaminade, C. &amp; Vang, J., 2011. Handbook of innovation systems and developing countries: building domestic capabilities in a global setting. Edward Elgar Publishing.##Maguire, S., Hardy, C. &amp; Lawrence, T. B., 2004. Institutional entrepreneurship in emerging fields: HIV/AIDS treatment advocacy in Canada.. Academy of management journal, 47(5), pp. 657-679.##Mahboudi, F., Hamedifar, H. &amp; Aghajani, H., 2012. Medical biotechnology trends and achievements in Iran. Avicenna journal of medical biotechnology, 4(4), pp. 200-205.##Murmann, J. P., 2003. Knowledge and competitive advantage: The coevolution of firms, technology, and national institutions. Cambridge : Cambridge University Press.##Nelson, R., 1994. The co-evolution of technology, industrial structure, and supporting institutions. Industrial and corporate change, 3(1), pp. 47-63.##Nelson, R., 2008. What enables rapid economic progress: What are the needed institutions?. Research policy, 37(1), pp. 1-11.##Nelson, R. &amp; Nelson, K., 2002. Technology, institutions, and innovation systems. . Research policy, 31(2), pp. 265-272.##Niosi, J., 2011. Complexity and path dependence in biotechnology innovation systems. Industrial and Corporate Change, 20(6), pp. 1795-1826.##North, D., 1990. Institutions, institutional change and economic performance. Cambridge : Cambridge university press.##Rao, H., Morrill, C. &amp; Zald, M., 2000. Power plays: How social movements and collective action create new organizational forms. Research in organizational behavior, Volume 22, pp. 237-281.##Scott, W. R., 2013. Institutions and organizations: Ideas, interests, and identities. Sage Publications.##Strauss, A. &amp; Corbin, J., 1994. Grounded theory methodology. In: N. Denzin &amp; Y. Lincoln, eds. Handbook of qualitative research. Sage Publications, pp. 273-285.##Suchman, L., Blomberg, J., Orr, J. E. &amp; Trigg, R., 1999. Reconstructing technologies as social practice. American behavioral scientist, 43(3), pp. 392-408.##Van de Ven, A. H. &amp; Garud, R., 1994. The coevolution of technical and institutional events in the development of an innovation. In: J. A. Baum &amp; J. V. Singh, eds. Evolutionary dynamics of organizations. Oxford: Oxford University Press, p. 425.##Veblen, T., 1912. The Theory of the Leisure Class: An Economic Study of Institutions. USA: Macmillan.##Williamson, O., 1975. Markets and Hierarchies: Analysis and Antitrust Implications. New York: Free Press.##Williamson, O. E., 1985. The economic intstitutions of capitalism: Firms, Markets, Relational Contracting. Free Press.##معاونت علمی و فناوری ریاست جمهوری, 1393. گزارش عملکرد. [درون خطی]##Available at: http://isti.ir/uploads/58_734_21_aboutus1.pdf##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>طراحی فرآیند ارزیابی پیشینی سازگاری نهادی سیاست های علم و فناوری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Designing an Institutional Compatibility Ex-Ante Assessment Procedure for Science and Technology Policies</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>توجه به ارزیابی سیاست‌ها در چرخه سیاست‌گذاری ضروری است، ولی ارزیابی پیشینی، در ادبیات ارزیابی سیاست، کمتر مورد توجه قرار گرفته است. در این مقاله، فرآیندی پنج مرحله‌ای برای ارزیابی پیشینی سیاست‌های علم‌وفناوری در چرخه سیاست با استفاده از روش نظریه‌پردازی داده‌بنیاد ارائه می‌شود. بدین منظور با بررسی ادبیات موضوع، بیش از ده کلید واژه، جستجو شد و در نهایت پس از انتخاب 50 متن منتخب، کدگذاری‌های باز و محوری صورت گرفت و با استفاده از مصاحبه‌های هدفمند با خبرگان، فرآیند ارزیابی پیشینی سازگاری نهادی استخراج و تایید شد. در این فرآیند پیشنهادی، اولین مرحله، دسته‌بندی گزینه‌های سیاستی است. در مرحله دوم جنبه‌های مهم نهادی در بافت چرخه سیاست در سه گام فرموله‌بندی، اجرا و ارزیابی شناسایی می‌گردند. مرحله سوم با تعیین شاخص‌هایی، این جنبه‌های مهم نهادی اندازه‌گیری می‌شوند. مرحله چهارم تحلیل‌هایی را از اثرات آتی سیاست ارائه می‌دهد و در مرحله پنجم، از این تحلیل‌ها برای تصحیح ابزارهای سیاستی، متناسب با نهادهای هدف استفاده می‌شود. این فرآیند پیشنهادی، ابزاری است برای سیاست‌گذاران که با پیروی از مراحل پیشنهادی آن، توانایی ارزیابی پیشینی سیاست‌ها را داشته باشند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>It is essential to consider policy assessment in policy cycle. However, ex-ante evaluation has been rarely reviewed in the policy evaluation literature. In this paper, a five-phase process of ex-ante evaluation of science and technology policies in policy cycle using grounded theory is offered. For this purpose, through the literature review, ten keywords are searched for, and finally 50 selected texts are selected for open and axial coding. After that, by structured interviews with experts, the process of ex-ante evaluation of institutional compatibility is extracted. The first step of the process is classifying the policy options. In the second step, Crucial Institutional Aspects (CIA) are identified in the policy cycle context. By determining some indicators, the third step measures these CIAs. The forth step analyzes the policy impacts, and in the fifth, these analyses are used to modify policy instruments with regards to the target institutions. This suggested process is a new subject and provides a tool for policy makers to conduct ex-ante evaluation of policies.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>59</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>86</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ناصر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نوروزی</Family>
						<NameE>Naser</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Noroozi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه اصفهان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه اصفهان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nassernor@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شعبان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>الهی</Family>
						<NameE>Shaban</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Elahi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>elahi@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حجت اله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حاجی حسینی</Family>
						<NameE>Hojatolah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hajihoseini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>سازمان پژوهش های علمی و صنعتی ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>سازمان پژوهش های علمی و صنعتی ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hajihoseini@irost.org</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسن زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hasanzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>تربیت مدرس</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>تربیت مدرس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ar_hassanzadeh@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیاست های علم و فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیاست گذاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ارزیابی پیشینی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سازگاری نهادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF> Amblard, L. &amp; Mann, C., 2011. Ex-ante institutional compatibility assessment of policy options: methodological insights from a case study on the Nitrate Directive in Auvergne, France. Journal of Environmental Planning and Management, pp. 661-684.##Aoki, M. &amp; Rothwell, G., 2013. A comparative institutional analysis of the Fukushima nuclear disaster: Lessons and policy implications. Energy Policy, Volume 53, pp. 240-247.##Bakshi, A., Talaei-Khoei, A. &amp; Ray, P., 2013. Adaptive policy framework:Asystematic review. Journal of Network and Computer Applications, 36(4), pp. 1261-1271.##Bickers, K. N. &amp; Williams, J. T., 2001. Public Policy analysis: a political economy approach. Boston and New York: Houghton Mifflin.##Bikar, V., Capron, H. &amp; Cincera, M., 2004. An Integrated Scheme for the Evaluation on Institutional set-Ups: The case of the Belgian Regional Innovation system. Working Paper- Universite Libre De Bruxelles.##Birks, M. &amp; Miles, J., 2015. Grounded Theory: A practical Guide. London: Sage.##Bocher, M., 2012. A theoretical framework for explaining the choice of instruments in environmental policy. Forest Policy and Econimics, pp. 14-22.##Boekholt, P., Cozzens, S. &amp; Johnston, R., 2001. An international review of methods to measure relative effectiveness of technology policy instruments, Amsterdam- Netherlands: Dutch Ministry of Economic Affairs.##Bridgman, P. &amp; Davis, G., 2000. Australian Policy Handbook. 2nd ed. Sydney: Allen &amp; Unwin.##Cárcamo, P., Garay-Flühmann, R. &amp; Gaymer, C., 2013. Opportunities and constraints of the institutional framework for the implementation of ecosystem-based management: the case of the Chilean coast. Ocean &amp; coastal management, Volume 84, pp. 193-203.##Carter, S. K. et al., 2015. An evaluation of environmental, institutional and socio-economic factors explaining successful conservation plan implementation in thenorth-central United States. Biological Conservation, Volume 192, pp. 135-144.##Chaffin, B., Garmestani, A., Gosnell, H. &amp; Craig, R., 2016. Institutional networks and adaptive water governance in the Klamath River Basin, USA.. Environmental Science &amp; Policy, Volume 57, pp. 112-121.##Clark, J. &amp; Guy, K., 1997. Innovation and Competitiveness, London: Technopolis &amp; Brighton.##Creswell, J. W. &amp; Hanson, W., 2007. Qualitative Research Designs: Selection and Implementation. The Counseling Psychologist, 35(2), pp. 236-264.##Edquist, C., 2004. Reflections on the systems of innovation approach. Science and Public Policy, 31(6), pp. 485-489.##Edquist, C. &amp; Johnson, B., 1997. Systems of Innovation: Technologies, institutions and organizations. In: C. Edquist, ed. Institutions and organization in systems of innovation. London: Pinter, pp. 41-63.##Elliot, N. &amp; Lazenbatt, A., 2005. How to recognise a quality grounded Theory research Study. Australian Journal of Advanced Nursing, p. Volume 22 Number 3.##EU, 2001. Evaluation- General Issues, Poland- Warsaw: European Union.##Fahrenkrog, G., Polt, W., Rojo, J. &amp; Tubke, A., 2002. Evaluation Toolbox: Assessing the Socio Economic Impact of RTD-Policies,  European Commission.##Filippi, F., Nuzzolo, A., Comi, A. &amp; Delle Site, P., 2010. Ex-ante Assessment of urban freight trasport policies. Procedia Social and Behavioral Science, pp. 6332-6342.##Fitzpatrick, J., 2016. Environmental sustainability assessment of using forest wood for heat. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, Volume 57, pp. 1287-1295.##Haasnoot, M., Kwakkel, J. H., Walker, W. E. &amp; Maat, J., 2013. Dynamic adaptive policy pathways: A method for crafting robust decisions for a deeply uncertain world. Global Environmental Change, 23(2), pp. 485-498.##Henwood, K. &amp; Pidgeon, N., 2003. Grounded Theory in psychological Research. In: Qualitative Research In psychology. Washington DC: American Psychological Association, pp. 131-155.##Hong, J., Ren, L., Hong, J. &amp; Xu, C., 2016. Environmental impact assessment of corn straw utilization in China. Journal of Cleaner Production, 112(2), pp. 1700-1708.##Howlett, M., Ramesh, M. &amp; Perl, A., 2009. (). Studying Public policy: Policy Cycles and policy subsystems. Oxford : Oxford University Press.##Izsak, K. &amp; Edler, J., 2011. Trends and Challenges in Demand-side Innovation Policies in Europe,  technopolis.##Jann, W. &amp; Wegrich, K., 2007. Theories of the Policy cycle. In: Handbook of public policy analysis- Theory, Politics and Methods. New York: Taylor &amp; Francis Group, LLC, pp. 43-63.##Korten, D. C., 1980. Community Organization and Rural Development: A Learning Process Approach. Public Administration Review, pp. 480-511.##Lee, J., 2001. A Grounded Theory: Integration and Internalization in ERP, Adoption and Use, In Proquest UMI Database: University Of Nebreska.##Legro, J., 1997. Which norms matter? Revisiting the “failure” of internationalism. International Organization, 51(1), pp. 31-63.##Lings, B. &amp; Lundell, B., 2005. On the Adaption of Grounded Theory procedures: Insights from the evolution of the 2G method. Information Technology &amp; People, pp. 196-211.##lundberg, f. c., 2006. Evaluation, Definition, Methods and Models,  Swedish Institute for Groth Policy Studies.##Marsden, G. &amp; Groer, S., 2016. Do institutional structures matter? A comparative analysis of urban carbon management policies in the UK and Germany. Journal of Transport Geography, Volume 51, pp. 170-179.##Morgan, J. &amp; Olsen, W., 2011. Conceptual issues in institutional economics: clarifying the fluidity of rules. Journal of Institutional Economics, pp. 425-454.##Mowery, D. C., 1995. The Practice of Technology Policy. In: Handbook of the Economics of Innovation and Technological change. Oxford: Wiley-Blackwell, pp. 513-557.##Niosi, J., 2002. National Systems of Innovation are X-Efficient. Research Policy, 31(2), pp. 291-302.##Ostrom, E., 1986. A Method of Institutional Analysis. In: Guidance, Control, and Evaluation in the Public Sector. The University of Michigan: W. de Gruyter, pp. 459-475.##Ostrom, E., 1998a. The Institutional Analysis and Development Approach. In: Designing Institutions for Environmental and Resource Management. University of Michigan: Edward Elgar.##Ostrom, E., 1998b. Institutional Analysis, Design Principles, and Threats to Sustainable Community Governance and Management of Commons. In: Law and the Governance of Renewable Resources: Studies from Northern Europe and Africa. Oakland: ICS Press.##Ostrom, E., 2005a. Doing Institutional Analysis- Digging Deeper Than Markets and Hierarchies. In: Handbook of new Institutional Economics. Netherland: Springer, pp. 819-848.##Ostrom, E., 2005b. Understanding Institutional Diversity. Prinston- New jersey: Princeton University Press.##Parto, s., Ciarli, T. &amp; Arora, S., 2005. Economic Groth, Innovation systems, and Institutional change: A Trilogy in five Parts, Maastricht, Netherlands: Mssdtricht Economic Research, Institute on Innovation and Technology.##Pfahl, S., 2005. Institutional Sustainability. Int. J. Sustainable Development, pp. Vol. 8, Nos. 1/2, 80-97.##Raheem, N., 2014 . Using the institutional analysis and development (IAD)framework to analyze the acequias of El Rیo de las Gallinas,New Mexico. The Social Science Journal, 51(3), pp. 447-454.##Rahman, H. T., Hickey, G. M. &amp; Kumar Sarker, S., 2012. A framework for evaluating collective action and informal institutional dynamics under a resource management policy of decentralization. Ecological Economics, Volume 83, pp. 32-41.##Ralph, N., Birks, M. &amp; Chapman, Y., 2014. Contextual Positioning: Using Documents as Extant Data in Grounded Theory Research. Sage Open.##Rogers, B. C., Brown, R. R., de Haan, F. J. &amp; Deletic, A., 2015. Trajectories in Water Infrastructure Systems of Melbourne, Australia.. Environmental Innovation and Societal Transitions, Volume 15, pp. 42-64.##Roper, S., Dundas, N. H. &amp; Love, J. H., 2004. An ex-ante evaluation framework for the regional benefits of publicly supported R&amp;D Projects. Research Policy, pp. 87-09.##Salbu, B., 2016. (). Environmental impact and risk assessments and key factors contributing to the overall uncertainties. Journal of Environmental Radioavtivity, 151(2), pp. 352-360.##Salehi-Isfahani, D. &amp; Majbouri, M., 2013. Mobility and the dynamics of poverty in Iran: Evidence from the 1992-1995 panel survey. The Quarterly Review of Economics and Finance, pp. 257-267.##Saleth, M. &amp; Dinar, A., 1999. Evaluating Water Institutions and Water Sector Performance. ,  World Bank, Technical Report No. 447..##Sarkissian, A., 2008. Intellectual Property rights for developing countries: Lessons from Iran. Technovation, pp. 786-798.##Schleyer, C., Thhesfeld, I., Hagedorn, K. &amp; al, e., 2007. Approach towards an operational tool to apply institutional analysis for the assessment of policy feasibility within SEAMLESS-IF,  EU.##Selden, L., 2005. on Ground Theory - with some malice. Journal of Documentation, pp. 114-129.##Sengupta, A. et al., 2016. An evaluation of risk assessment framework for industrial accidents in India. Journal of Loss Prevention in the Process Industries, Volume 41, p. 295–302.##Shin Park, Y., Egilmez, G. &amp; Kucukvar, M., 2016. Emergy and end-point impact assessment of agricultural and food production in the United States: A supply chain-linked Ecologically-based Life Cycle Assessment. Ecological Indicators, Volume 62, pp. 117-137.##Silverman, D., 1998. Qualitative research: Meaning or practices?. information system journal, pp. 3-20.##Soofi, A. S. &amp; Ghazinoory, S., 2011. The network of the Iranian techno-economic system. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, pp. 591-609.##Spangenberg, J. H., Pfahl, S. &amp; Deller, K., 2002. Towards indicators for institutional sustainability: lessons from an analysis of Agenda 21. Ecological Indicators, 2(1-2), p. 61–77.##Staronova, K., 2007. Mapping of ex-ante policy impact assessment experiences and tools in Europe- Based on a literature Survey and Case Studies from Southeast Europe, Bratislava, Slovak Republic: UNDP.##Strauss, A. &amp; Corbin, J., 1998. Basics of Qualitative Research: Techniques and Procedures for Developing Grounded Theory. Sage Publications.##Sun, Z., Li, X., Qiao, W. &amp; Haghani, A., 2013. Entropy-based performance evaluation on institutional structures of trunk highway management—Case study in China. Transport Policy, Volume 27, p. 85–91.##Swanson, D. et al., 2010. Seven tools for creating adaptive policies. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, 77(6), pp. 924-939.##Tabatabaeian, H., Khaledi, A. &amp; Norouzi, N., 2009. World Technological Capability Monitoring (WTCM), Tehran- Iran: Iranian Association for Management of Technology.##Tambach, M., Hasselaar, E. &amp; Itard, L., 2010. Assessment of current Dutch energy transition policy instruments for the existing housing stock. Energy Policy, pp. 981-996.##Theesfeld, I., Schleyer, C. &amp; Aznar, O., 2010. The Procedure for institutional compatibility assessment: ex-ante policy assessment from an institutional perspective. Journal of Institutional Economics, pp. 377-399.##Van Gossum, P. et al., 2009. New environmental policy instruments to realize forest expansion in Flanders (northen Belgium): A base for smart regulation?. Land Use Policy, pp. 935-946.##Weijermars, W. &amp; Wesemann, P., 2013. Road safety forecasting and ex-ante evaluation of policy in the netherlands. Transportation Research, pp. Part A 52 64-72.##WTO, 2002. A taxonomy on country experiences on international technology transfers,  Working group on trade and transfer of technology.##الوانی، س.، آذر، ع. و دانایی فرد، ح.، 1394. روش‌شناسی پژوهش کیفی در مدیریت: رویکردی جامع. تهران: اشراقی، صفار.##امامی میبدی، ر. و اشتریان، ک.، 1391. طراحی نظام ارزیابی سیاست‌های عمومی در جمهوری اسلامی ایران. پژوهشنامه علوم سیاسی، صص. 7-47.##پریزادی، ع.، 1393. چه منابعی می‌توانند ورودی‌های نظریه‌پردازی داده‌بنیاد باشند [مصاحبه] (30 بهمن 1393).##هومن، ح. ع.، 1385. راهنمای عملی پژوهش کیفی. تهران: انتشارات سمت.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>رتبه بندی طرح های کسب وکار سرمایه گذاری خطرپذیر با روش تحلیل پوششی داده ها- مورد مطالعه: یک شرکت سرمایه گذاری خطرپذیر ایرانی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Ranking Venture Capital Business Plans by Data Envelopment Analysis Method: A Case Study of an Iranian venture capital company</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>ارزیابی در صنعت سرمایه‌گذاری ریسک‌پذیر یکی از موضوعات چالشی فعالان و محققان این حوزه است. زمان بسیار محدود ارزیابی، عدم وجود اطلاعات مورد نیاز برای امکان‌سنجی اقتصادی طرح‌های سرمایه‌گذاری ریسک‌پذیر، خطاهای شناختی ارزیاب و ... همگی موجب شده تا ارزیابی طرح‌ها در سرمایه‌گذاری ریسک‌پذیر از دیگر موارد مشابه مجزا گردد و دقت و سرعت در ارزیابی به یکی از مزیت‌های سرمایه‌گذاران ریسک‌پذیر تبدیل شود. در این مقاله تلاش می‌شود تا با استفاده از روش ریاضی تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها، کارآیی متقاطع و روش تصمیم‌گیری ویکور، بخشی از مشکلات ارزیابی به وسیله کاهش زمان غربال‌گری، کاهش تأثیر سلیقه و تعصبات ارزیاب، فراهم کردن امکان تصمیم‌گیری گروهی، فراهم کردن امکان مقایسه تعداد زیاد گزینه‌ها با در نظر گرفتن تعداد زیاد معیارها و وزن آنها، عدم نیاز به تعیین وزن‌ معیارها تعدیل گردد. برای این منظور از طریق مصاحبه با فعالان داخلی سرمایه‌گذاری ریسک‌پذیر معیارهای بومی استخراج شدند و عملکرد مدل ریاضی پیشنهادی با پیاده‌سازی در شرکت سرمایه‌گذاری کارآفرینی هاتف و مقایسه با نظر خبرگان، بررسی گردید. مجموعه‌ معیارهای بومی و همچنین ارائه روش ساده و کارآمد ریاضی تصمیم‌گیری، بدون نیاز به وزن معیارها و یکسان کردن بعد معیارها از جمله دستاوردهای این پژوهش می‌باشد. نتیجه به‌دست‌آمده از مدل برای طرح رتبه اول با نظر ارزیابان شرکت برای اطلاق طرح نمونه به آن، همخوانی داشت البته اطلاعات کافی برای مقایسه رتبه‌بندی سایر طرح‌ها با نظر کارشناسان در دست نبود.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>of Hatef Company Evaluation in venture capital industry is one of the most challenging issues from practitioners&#039; and researchers&#039; points of view. Limited time of evaluation, lack of financial data especially from ventures, heuristics and biases in evaluating and some other issues differentiate venture capital evaluation process from other investment methods. Also the speed and accuracy of evaluation are two key success factors for venture capitalists. In this paper, we attempt to overcome some of evaluation challenges by using several mathematical methods including data envelopment analysis (DEA), cross efficiency and VIKOR through decreasing screening time, reducing biased effects and enabling group decision-making with variety of weights. This method does not need any weights as they are calculated within the model. For the purpose of this study, some interviews are conducted and domestic criteria are extracted. The performance of the proposed model is investigated with the aid of the Hatef Company case study. Thereafter, we present a group of domestic criteria, and a standard and mathematical method to support decision-making without any needs for criteria weights or normalization. The results derived from the model are similar to the experts&#039; opinions about the best project, but there are not adequate data to compare the ranking of another project with the experts&#039; opinions.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>87</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>108</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سامان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>احسنی زاد</Family>
						<NameE>Saman</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ahsanizadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>saman.ahsanizadeh@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>میرسامان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>پیشوایی</Family>
						<NameE>Mir Saman</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Pishvaee</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>pishvaee@iust.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امیر علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کریمی</Family>
						<NameE>Amir Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Karimi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>akarimi@mehr.sharif.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رتبه بندی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایه گذاری خطر پذیر</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل پوششی داده ها</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارآیی متقاطع</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ویکور</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Audretsch, D., Bönte, W. &amp; Mahagaonkar, P., 2012. Financial signaling by innovative nascent ventures: The relevance of patents and prototypes. Res. Policy, 41(8), pp. 1407-1421.##Banker, A., Charnes, R. &amp; Cooper, W., 2012. Some Models for Estimating Technical and Scale Inefficiencies in Data Envelopment Analysis. S. M. Science, and N. Sep, 30(9), pp. 1078–1092.##Beim, G., 2004. Selecting Projects for Venture Capital Funding: A Multiple Criteria Decision Approach. 1 ed. Moren Lé vesque: Whistler.##Block, J. &amp; De Vries, G., 2014. Trademarks and venture capital valuation. J. Bus. Venture, 29(4), pp. 525–542.##Chan, C. S. R. &amp; Park, H., 2013. The influence of dispositional affect and cognition on venture investment portfolio concentration. J. Bus. Ventur., 28(3), pp. 397–412.##Charnes, A., Cooper, W. W. &amp; Rhodes, E., 1979. Measuring the efficiency of decision-making units. Eur. J. Oper. Res, 3(6), pp. 339.##Dawes, R. M., Faust, D. &amp; Meehl, P. E., 1989. Clinical versus actuarial judgment. Science, 243(4899), p. 1668–1674.##Dotzler, F., 2001. What do venture capitalist really do, and where do they learn to do it?. J. Priv. Equity, 5(1), pp. 6-12.##Franke, N., Gruber, M., Harhoff, M. &amp; Henkel, J., 2006. What you are is what you like—similarity biases in venture capitalists’ evaluations of start-up teams. J. Bus. Ventur, 21(6), pp. 802–826.##Hall, J. &amp; Hofer, C., 1993. Venture capitalists› decision criteria in new venture evaluation. Journal of Business Venturing, 8(1), pp. 25-42.##Herron, L. &amp; Robinson, R., 1993. A structural model of the effects of entrepreneurial characteristics on venture performance. J. Bus. Ventur, 8(3), pp. 281–294.##Kollmann, T. &amp; Kuckertz, A., 2010. Evaluation uncertainty of venture capitalists’ investment criteria. J. Bus. Res, 63(7), pp. 741-747.##Macmillan, I., Siegel, R. &amp; Narasimha, P., 1985. Criteria used by venture capitalists to evaluate new venture proposals. Journal of Business Venturing, 1(1), pp. 119-128.##Macmillan, I., Zemann, L. &amp; Subbanarasimha, P., 1987. Criteria distinguishing successful from unsuccessful ventures in the venture screening process. Journal of Business Venturing, 2(2), pp. 123-137.##Opricovic, S. &amp; Tzeng, G. H., 2004. European journal of operational research. European journal of operational research, 165(2), pp. 445-455.##Pandey, I. M. &amp; Jang, A., 1996. Venture capital for financing technology in Taiwan. Technovation, 16(9), pp. 499-514.##Rah, J., Jung, K. &amp; Lee, J., 1994. Validation of the venture evaluation model in Korea. Journal of Business Venturing, 9(6), pp. 509-524.##Ramsinghani, M., 2014. «The Business of Venture Capital». 1 ed. New Jersey: John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Ramsinghani, M., 2014. The business of venture capital. New Jersey: John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Sandberg, W. &amp; Hofer, C., 1987. Improving new venture performance: The role of strategy, industry structure, and the entrepreneur. Journal of Business Venturing, 2(1), pp. 5-28.##Siri Terjesen, R. D., Patel, P. C., Fiet, J. O. &amp; D’Souza, R., 2013. Normative rationality in venture capital financing.. technovation, 33(1), pp. 255–264.##Siskos, J. &amp; Zopounidis, C., 1987. The evaluation criteria of the venture capital investment activity: An interactive assessment. Eur. J. Oper. Res, 31(3), pp. 304–313.##Timmons, J. A. &amp; Bygrave, W. D., 1986. Venture capital’s role in financing innovation for economic growth. J. Bus. Ventur, 1(2), pp. 161-176.##Treville, S., Petty, J. S. &amp; Wager, S., 2014. Economies of extremes : Lessons from venture-capital decision making. J. Oper. Manag, 32(6), pp. 387–398.##Tyebjee, T. &amp; Bruno, A., 1984. A Model of Venture Capitalist Investment Activity. Management Science, 30(9), pp. 1051-1066.##Zacharakis, A. L. &amp; Shepherd, D., 2001. The nature of information and overconfidence on venture capitalists’ decision making. J. Bus. Ventur, 16(4), pp. 311–332.##Zacharakis, A. &amp; Meyer, G., 2000. The potential of actuarial decision models. Journal of Business Venturing, 15(4), pp. 323-346.##Zhang, X., 2012a. Venture Capital Investment Base on Grey Relational Theory. Phys. Procedia, 33(1), pp. 1825-1832.##Zhang, X., 2012b. Venture Capital Investment Selection Decision-making Base on Fuzzy Theory. Phys. Procedia., 25(1), pp. 1369–1375.##Zopounidis, C., 1994. Venture capital modeling: Evaluation criteria for the appraisal of investments. The Financier ACMT, 1(2), pp. 54-64.##اسلامی بیدگلی،غ. و بیگدلو،م.،1384. بررسی معیارهای موثر در ارزیابی کسب وکارهای مخاطره آمیز کارآفرینانه. دانش مدیریت،جلد 68،صص. 3-29.##اسلامی بیدگلی، م. و احمدی اول، غ.، 1389. بررسی عوامل اثرگذار بر ارزیابی طرح‌های کارآفرینانه در شرکت‌های سرمایه‌گذاری خطرپذیر با استفاده از روش فرآیند تحلیل شبکه‌ای. نشریه توسعه کارآفرینی، 8(1)، صص. 99-120.##باقری،ک.،1383. سرمایه‌گذاری خطرپذیر. تهران: انتشارات بنیاد توسعه فردا.##درخشان، ش. و محمدی، پ.،1393. اولویت‌بندی عوامل تأثیرگذار بر ارزیابی طرح‌های سرمایه‌گذاری خطرپذیر. نشریه علمی-پژوهشی مدیریت نوآوری، (4)3، صص. 131-152.##طحاری مهرجردی، م.، شاکری، ف. و بابایی، ح.، 1391. تحلیل کارآیی و رتبه‌بندی سیستم فرودگاه های کشور با استفاده از رویکرد ارزیابی کارآیی متقاطع. پژوهشنامه حمل و نقل، (3)9،صص. 275-291.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>الگویی برای تصمیم‌گیری ایجاد کسب و کار جدید با رویکرد نظریه داده‌بنیاد</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Model of Decision-Making for New Venture Creation: A Grounded Theory Approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>اتخاذ رویکرد غایت‌گرا، امکان تبیین مناسب فرآیند تصمیم‌گیری کارآفرینان را فراهم نمی‌کند. این پژوهش در تلاش است، ضمن اتخاذ رویکرد غیرغایت‌گرا و در چارچوب طرح پژوهش کیفی نظریه‌پردازی داده‌بنیاد، به واکاوی فرآیند تصمیم‌گیری ایجاد کسب‌وکار جدید، در نمونه‌ای از کارآفرینان نوپای حوزه کسب‌وکارهای فناور پیشرفته (نانو و زیست‌فناوری) ایران بپردازد. گردآوری داده‌ها با استفاده از مصاحبه‌های کیفی با 20 کارآفرین نمونه نظری پژوهش انجام شد. تحلیل داده‌های گردآوری‌شده، توسط سه رویه یکپارچه کدگذاری باز، محوری و انتخابی صورت پذیرفت. نتایج تحلیل‌ها، 6 مقوله را به‌عنوان عناصر تشکیل‌دهنده فرآیند مورد مطالعه، تعیین کرد. این مقوله‌ها شامل «ویژگی‌ها و پیشینه کارآفرین»، «شرایط خاص زمینه‌ای»، «شرایط عمومی زمینه‌ای»، «گرایش و شایستگی کارآفرینانه»، «شناسایی، ارزیابی و توانمندسازی»، و «تصمیم ایجاد کسب‌وکار» می‌باشند. گزاره‌های ناظر بر روابط میان مقوله‌ها، امکان توسعه الگوی تصمیم‌گیری ایجاد کسب‌وکار جدید در نمونه کارآفرینان حوزه کسب‌وکارهای فناور پیشرفته ایران را فراهم می‌کند. همچنین، فرآیند مورد مطالعه، در قالب خط داستان نظریه داده‌بنیاد، تبیین می‌گردد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The decision-making process of entrepreneurs is not appropriately explicable by means of teleological approach. Through a non-teleological approach and employing a grounded theory research design, this study aims to explore a process of new venture creation decision-making in a sample of nascent entrepreneurs in Iranian high-tech businesses. The data collection is conducted through qualitative event-based interviews with 20 nascent entrepreneurs of the research theoretical sample. The analysis of the gathered data is done by three integrated procedures of open, axial and selective coding. The results determine six categories as the constituent elements of the studied process. These categories are &quot;entrepreneur’s characteristics and background&quot;, &quot;specific contextual conditions&quot;, &quot;general contextual conditions&quot;, &quot;entrepreneurial orientation and competency&quot;, &quot;identification, evaluation and empowerment&quot; and &quot;venture creation decision&quot;. Propositions concerning the relationships between the categories lead to the development of a model of new venture creation decision-making in the sample. Moreover, the studied process is explained by the story line of the substantive grounded theory.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>109</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>134</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زیودار</Family>
						<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zivdar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehdizivdar@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نرگس</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ایمانی پور</Family>
						<NameE>Narges</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Imanipour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nimanip@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>کامبیز</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>طالبی</Family>
						<NameE>Kambeiz</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Talebi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ktalebi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید رسول</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسینی</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Rasul</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hosseini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه فرهنگیان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه فرهنگیان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hosseinirasul@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارآفرینی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ایجاد کسب‌وکار جدید</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرآیند تصمیم‌گیری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رویکرد غیرغایت‌گرا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abelson, R. P., &amp; Levi, A., 1985. Decision making and decision theory. Handbook of social psychology,Volume (1), pp. 231-309.##Birks, M., &amp; Mills, J., 2015. Grounded theory: A practical guide. Sage.##Buchanan, J. M., &amp; Vanberg, V. J., 1991. The market as a creative process. Economics and Philosophy, 7(2), pp. 167-186.##Busenitz, L. W., &amp; Lau, C. M., 1996. A cross-cultural cognitive model of new venture creation. Entrepreneurship: Theory and Practice, 20(4), pp. 25-40.##Casson, M., 2005. Entrepreneurship and the theory of the firm. Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization, 58(2), pp. 327-348.##Chandler, G. N., DeTienne, D. R., McKelvie, A., &amp; Mumford, T. V., 2011. Causation and effectuation processes: A validation study. Journal of Business Venturing, 26, pp. 375-390.##Creswell, J. W., 2013. Qualitative inquiry and research method: Choosing among five approaches. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.##Dale, A. I., 1991. A History of Inverse Probability: from Thomas Bayes to Karl Pearson. New York:Spring-Verlag.##De Carolis, D. M., &amp; Saparito, P., 2006. Social capital, cognition, and entrepreneurial opportunities: A theoretical framework. Entrepreneurship theory and practice, 30(1), pp. 41-56.##Dimov, D., 2010. Nascent entrepreneurs and venture emergence: Opportunity confidence, human capital, and early planning. Journal of Management Studies, 47(6), pp. 1123-1153.##Dyer, W. G., 1994. Toward a Theory of Entrepreneurial Careers. Entrepreneurship: Theory &amp; Practice, pp. 27(2), pp. 7-21.##Gibcus, P., Vermeulen, P. A., &amp; De Jong, J. P., 2008. Strategic decision making in small firms: a taxonomy of small business owners. International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Small Business, 7(1), pp. 74-91.##Global Entrepreneurship Monitor of Iran, 2014. 7th. Executive Report of the research program for Evaluation of Iran Entrepreneurship Indexes based on Global Entrepreneurship Monitor model. GEM-Iran office. (in Persian)##Guba, E.G., &amp; Lincoln, Y.S., 1989. Forth generation evaluation. Newbury park, CA: sage.##Gustafsson, V., 2006. Entrepreneurial decision-making: Individuals, tasks and cognitions. Edward Elgar Publishing.##Hayek, M., 2012. Control Beliefs and Positive Psychological Capital: Can Nascent Entrepreneurs Discriminate between What Can and cannot be controlled? Journal of Management Research. 12(1), pp. 3-13.##Haynie, J. M., Shepherd, D., Mosakowski, E., &amp; Earley, P. C., 2010. A situated metacognitive model of the entrepreneurial mindset. Journal of business venturing, 25(2), pp. 217-229.##Kahneman, D., 2003. A perspective on judgment and choice: mapping bounded rationality. American psychologist, 58(9), p. 697.##Kirzner, I., 1997. Entrepreneurial discovery and the competitive market process: An Austrian approach. Journal of Economic Literature, 35, pp. 60-85.##Knight, F., 1921. Risk, Uncertainty and Profit, 1933 edition. New York: Houghton Mifflin.##Kvale, S., 1996. Interviews: an Introduction to Qualitative Research Interviewing. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.##Lachmann, L. M., 1976. From Mises to Shackle: An essay on Austrian economics and the Kaleidic Society. Journal of Economic Literature, 14(1), pp. 54-62.##Maine, E., Soh, P. H., &amp; Dos Santos, N., 2015. The role of entrepreneurial decision-making in opportunity creation and recognition. Technovation, 39, pp. 53-72.##March, J. G., &amp; Simon, H. A., 1958. Organizations. Wiley, NY.##McMullen, J. S., 2015. Entrepreneurial judgment as empathic accuracy: a sequential decision-making approach to entrepreneurial action. Journal of Institutional Economics, 11(3), pp. 651-681.##McMullen, J. S., &amp; Dimov D., 2013. Time and the Entrepreneurial Journey: The Problems and Promise of Studying Entrepreneurship as a Process. Journal of Management Studies, 50(8), pp. 1481–1512.##Miao, Q., &amp; Liu, L., 2010. A Psychological Model of Entrepreneurial Decision Making. Social Behavior &amp; Personality: An International Journal, 38(3), pp. 132-145.##Morris, M. H., Kuratko, D. F., Schindehatte, M., &amp; Spivack, A. J., 2012. Framing the Entrepreneurial Experience. Entrepreneurship: Theory &amp; Practice, 36(1), pp. 11-40.##Natanios, M., 2009. Individual differences between entrepreneurs and managers. Doctoral Thesis. Wayne state University.##North, D., 1990. Institutions, Institutional Change and Economic Performance. Cambridge University Press.##Ratner, M. A., &amp; Ratner, D., 2003. Nanotechnology: A gentle introduction to the next big idea. Prentice Hall Professional.##Renko, M, Shrader, R. C., &amp; Simon, M., 2012. Perception of entrepreneurial opportunity: a general framework. Management Decision, 50(7), pp. 1233–1251.##Sarasvathy, S. D., 2001. Causation and effectuation: Toward a theoretical shift from economic inevitability to entrepreneurial contingency. Academy of management Review, 26(2), pp. 243-263.##Sarasvathy, S. D., 2008. Effectuation: Elements of Entrepreneurial Expertise. Edward Elgar Publishing Limited, Cheltenham, UK.##Sarasvathy, S. D., &amp; Dew, N., 2013. Without Judgement: An Empirically-based Entrepreneurial Theory of the Firm. Review of Austrian Economics, 26(3), pp. 277-296.##Sarasvathy, S. D., Dew, N., Velamuri, S. R., &amp; Venkataraman, S., 2003. Three views of Entrepreneurial opportunity. Handbook of Entrepreneurship Research, Edited by Z. J. Acs and D. B. Audretch. Kluwer##Academic Publishers, Great Britain.##Schade, C., 2010. Entrepreneurial decision making: A paradigm rather than a set of questions. Journal of Business Venturing, 25(2), pp. 173-174.##Schulte, J., 2005. Nanotechnology: global strategies, industry trends and applications. John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Shane, S., &amp; Venkataraman, S., 2000. The Promise of Entrepreneurship as a Field of Research. Academy of Management Review, 25(1), pp. 217-226.##Shane, S., Locke, E. A., &amp; Collins, C. J., 2003. Entrepreneurial Motivation. Human Resource Management Review, 13, pp. 257-279.##Shepherd, D. A., McMullen, J. S., &amp; Jennings, P. D., 2007. The formation of opportunity beliefs: Overcoming ignorance and reducing doubt. Strategic Entrepreneurship Journal, 1(1-2), pp. 75-95.##Simon, H. A., 1979. Rational decision making in business organizations. The American economic review, pp. 493-513.##Strauss, A. L., &amp; Corbin, J. M., 1990. Basics of qualitative research. Newbury Park, CA: Sage.##Tumasjan, A., &amp; Braun, R., 2012. In the eye of the beholder: How regulatory focus and self-efficacy interact in influencing opportunity recognition. Journal of Business Venturing, 27(6), pp. 622-636.##Valliere, D., 2013. Towards a schematic theory of entrepreneurial alertness. Journal of Business Venturing, 28(3), pp. 430-442.##Venkataraman, S., Sarasvathy, S. D., Dew, N., &amp; Forster, W., 2012. Whither the promise? Moving forward with entrepreneurship as a science of the artificial. Academy of Management Review, 37(1), pp. 33-21.##Vermeulen, P. A. M., &amp; Curseu, P. L., 2008. Entrepreneurial Strategic Decision-Making: A Cognitive Perspective. Edward Elgar, Cheltenham, UK – Northampton, MA, USA.##Wood, M. S., &amp; Williams, D. W., 2014. Opportunity evaluation as rule-based decision making. Journal of Management Studies, 51(4), pp. 573-602.##Worthington, I., &amp; Britton, C., 2009. The business environment. Pearson Education.##Zahra, S. A., Wright, M., &amp; Abdelgawad, S. G., 2014. Contextualization and the advancement of entrepreneurship research. International Small Business Journal, 32(5), pp. 479-500.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نقش توانمندی مدیریت فناوری در فرآیند توسعه محصولات جدید دفاعی (یافته های تجربی)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Role of Technology Management Capability in Defense New Product Development Process (The Empirical Findings)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف اصلی فرآیند توسعه محصولات جدید در صنایع دفاعی، تبدیل ایده‌ها و نیازهای مختلف به محصول یا سامانه‌ای است که این نیاز را رفع نماید. فرآیند توسعه محصول جدید، شامل 6 مرحله اصلی است که عبارتند از: توسعه ایده، توسعه مفهوم، تعریف مساله و برنامه‌ریزی، طراحی و توسعه مهندسی و تولید، اعتبارسنجی، پیش‌تجاری‌سازی و معرفی به بازار. در این مقاله، نقش مدیریت فناوری و توانمندی‌های مرتبط با آن در فرآیند توسعه محصولات جدید دفاعی مورد بررسی قرار گرفته و در هر یک از مراحل شش‌گانه فرآیند یاد شده نقش مدیریت فناوری تببین گردیده و همچنین ابزارهای حوزه مدیریت فناوری مرتبط در هر یک از این 6 مرحله تشریح شده است. طی این پژوهش، پس از مصاحبه با خبرگان در سطح صنایع دفاعی، ابتدا ابزارهای مورد استفاده مرتبط با مدیریت فناوری در هر فاز شناسایی‌شد و در ادامه با توزیع پرسش‌نامه 7‌ مقیاسی فازی داده‌ها جمع‌آوری گردید و در ادامه ‌با کمک فن دلفی فازی تجزیه‌وتحلیل شد. بررسی‌های انجام‌شده در سطح صنایع دفاعی نشان می‌دهد، مدیریت فناوری به‌عنوان یکی از اصلی‌ترین ابزارهای فرآیند توسعه محصول جدید، در فازهای اولیه توسعه بسیار پررنگ است و با حرکت به سمت فازهای پایانی، این تأثیرگذاری کم‌رنگ‌تر می‌گردد. در پایان، 14 فرآیند و 8 ابزار مرتبط با مدیریت فناوری در فرآیند توسعه محصول جدید به کمک منطق فازی شناسایی و تحلیل گردید.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The main purpose of defense new product development (NPD) process is to transform different ideas to a product or a system that fulfill some needs. NPD process consists of six phases: idea development; concept development; problem definition and planning; engineering and production design and development; validation; and pre-commercialization and market launch. In this paper, we discuss the role of technology management and its related capabilities in new defense products and systems acquisition process and in each of the six phases, and discuss the role of technology management and its important and essential tools in each phase. For understanding this relationship, after interviews with the experts of defense industries, first the tools associated with technology management used at different phases are identified, and then a Fuzzy seven-scaled questionnaire is designed for data gathering. The data are analyzed using Fuzzy Delphi Technique. The results show that technology management, as one of the most important tools in defense new products development process, is more influential in initial phases. As we go through the NPD process, the role of technology management becomes less influential. The role of technology management, as a supporting tool in NPD process, is significant, and in this paper we aim to comprehensively cover this role. Finally, by using Fuzzy logic 14 processes and 8 tools associated with technology management are identified and analyzed.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>135</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>162</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>کیارش</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فرتاش</Family>
						<NameE>Kiarash</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Fartash</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشگاه علامه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>kiarash.fartash@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مصطفی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>محسنی کیاسری</Family>
						<NameE>Mostafa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mohseni Kiasari</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری و دانشجوی دکتری سیاستگذاری علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری و دانشجوی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mohseni@tsi.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی اصغر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سعدآبادی</Family>
						<NameE>Aliasghar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sadabadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری سیاستگذاری علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری سیاستگذاری علم و فناوری دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>alisadabadi@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توانمندی مدیریت فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فرآیندهای توسعه محصول جدید دفاعی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Balachandra, R. &amp; Friar, J., 1997. Factors for Success in R&amp;D Projects and New Product Innovation: A Contextual Framework. IEEE Transactions on Engineering Management, 44(3), pp. 276-287.##Blanchette, S. J., Albert C, .. &amp; Garcia-Miller, S., December 2010. Beyond Technology Readiness Levels for Software: U.S. Army Workshop Report [TECHNICAL REPORT]. s.l.:Acquisition Support Program, Research, Technology, and System Solutions Program.##Brown, S. &amp; Eisenhardt, K., 1995. Product development: past research, present findings and future directions. Academy of Management Review, 20(2), pp. 343-78.##Cetindamar, D., Phaal, R. &amp; Probert, D., 2009. Understanding technology management as a dynamic capability: A framework for technology management activities. Technovation, 29(2), pp. 237-246.##Chang, Y. H., 1998. Transportation plan appraisal and decision making-discussion and application of the fuzzy theory. Hwatai, Taipei: s.n.##Chen, M. K. &amp; Wang, S. C., 2010. The use of a hybrid fuzzy-Delphi-AHP approach to develop global business intelligence for information service firms. Expert Systems with Applications, Volume 37, pp. 7394-7407.##Clark, K., Chew, W. &amp; Fujimoto, T., 1987. Product Development in the World Auto Industry. Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, Volume 3, pp. 729-781.##Clark, K. &amp; Fujimoto, T., 1991. Product Development Performance: Strategy, Organization and Management in the World Auto Industry. Boston, MA: Harvard Business School Press.##Cooper, R., 1979. The Dimensions of Industrial New Product Success and Failure. Journal of Marketing, 43(3), pp. 93-103.##Cooper, R., 1995. Developing products on time, in time. Research-Technology Management, 38(5), pp. 40-50.##C, O. &amp; Pawlowski, S., 2004. The Delphi method as a research tool: an example, design considerations and applications. Information and Management, Volume 42, pp. 15-29.##Corea, P. et al., 1998. U.S. Army New Product Development: A Case Study. Engineering Management Journal, 10(3).##Davies, M., 1994. A Multicriteria Decision Model Application for Managing Group Decisions. The Journal of the Operational Research Society, Volume 45, pp. 47-58.##Davila, T., 2000. ‌An Empirical Study on the Drivers of Management Control Systems: Design in New Product Development. Accounting, Organizations and Society, Volume 25, pp. 383-409.##DOD, 2013. US Department of Defense Acquisition GuideBook. s.l.:s.n.##Foray, D., Mowery, D. C. &amp; Nelson, R. R., 2012. Public R&amp;D and social challenges: What lessons from mission R&amp;D programs?. Research Policy, 41(10), pp. 1697-1702.##Ford, D., 1988. Develop your technology strategy. Long Range Planning, 21(5), pp. 85-94.##GAO., 1999. Better Management of Technology Development Can Improve Weapon System Outcomes, s.l.: Report to the Chairman and Ranking Minority Member, Subcommittee on Readiness and Management Support, Committee on Armed Services, U.S. Senate.##González, F. &amp; Palacios, T., 2002. ‌The Effect of New Product Development Techniques on New Product Success in Spanish Firms. Industrial Marketing Management, Volume 31, pp. 261-271.##Gregory, M., 1995. Technology management: a process approach. s.l., s.n.##Hayes, R., Wheelwright, S. &amp; Clark, K., 1988. Dynamic Manufacturing. New York: The Free Press.##Hinkin, T. R., 2005. Scale Development Principles and Practices. In: R. A. Swanson &amp; E. F. Holton III, eds. Research in Organizations, Foundations and Methods of Inquiry. s.l.:USA: Berrett-Koehler Publishers, pp. 161-180.##Hsu, T. &amp; Yang, T., 2000. Application of fuzzy analytic hierarchy process in the selection of advertising media. Journal of Management and Systems, Volume 7, pp. 583-99.##Iansiti, M., 1993. Real-world R&amp;D: Jumping the Product Generation Gap. Harvard Business Review, 71(3), pp. 138-147.##Imai, K., Ikujiro, N. &amp; Takeuchi, H., 1985. Managing the new product development process: how Japanese companies learn and unlearn. In: R. Hayes, K. Clark &amp; C. Lorenz, eds. The Uneasy Alliance: Managing the Productivity- Technology Dilemma. Boston, Mass: Harvard Business School Press, pp. 337-375.##Ishikawa, A. et al., 1993. The max–min Delphi method and fuzzy Delphi method via fuzzy integration. Fuzzy Sets and Systems, Volume 55, p. 241–53.##Katz, R., 1982. The Effects of Group Longevity on Project Communication and Performance. Administrative Science Quarterly, Volume 27, pp. 81-104.##Katz, R. &amp; Allen, T., 1985. Project Performance and the Locus of Influence in the R&amp;D Matrix. Academy of Management Journal, Volume 28, pp. 67-87.##Kerr, C., Farrukh, C., Phaal, R. &amp; Probert, D., 2013. Key principles for developing industrially relevant strategic technology management toolkits. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 80(6), pp. 1050-1070.##Kim, L., 1997. Imitation to Innovation: The Dynamics of Korea&#039;s Technological Learning. s.l.:Harvard Business School Press.##Klir, G. &amp; Yuan, B., 1995. Fuzzy sets and fuzzy logic – Theory and application. s.l.:New Jersey: Prentice-Hall Inc.##Kuo, Y. F. &amp; Chen, P. C., 2008. Constructing performance appraisal indicators for mobility of the service industries using fuzzy Delphi method. Journal of Expert Systems with Applications, Volume 35, pp. 1930-1939.##Lall, S., 1992. Technological Capabilities and Industrialization. World Development, 20(2), pp. 165-186.##Lall, S., 1992. Technological Capabilities and Industrialization. World Development, 20(2), pp. 165-186.##Lynn, G., Morone, J. &amp; Paulson, A., 1996. Marketing and Discontinuous Innovation: The Probe and Learn Process. California Management Review, Volume 38, pp. 8-37.##Maidique, M. &amp; Zirger, B., 1984. A Study of Success and Failure in Product Innovation: The Case of the U.S. Electronics Industry. IEEE Transactions in Engineering Management, Volume 4, pp. 192-203.##Maidique, M. &amp; Zirger, B., 1985. The New Product Learning Cycle. Research Policy, Volume 14, pp. 299-313.##Mikhailov, L., 2003. Deriving priorities from fuzzy pairwise comparison judgements. Fuzzy Sets and Systems, Volume 134, pp. 365-385.##Morone, J., 1993. Winning in High-Tech Markets: The Role of General Management: How Motorola, Corning, and General Electric Have Built Global Leadership Through Tech. s.l.:Cambridge, MA: Harvard Business School Press.##Mowery, D. C., 2012. Defense-related R&amp;D as a model for “Grand Challenges” technology policies. Research Policy, 41(10), pp. 1703-1715.##NRC, N. R. C., 1987. Management of Technology: The Hidden Competitive Advantage, Washington, DC: National Academy Press.##Okoli, C. &amp; Pawlowski, . S., 2004. The Delphi method as a research tool: an example, design considerations and applications. Information and Management, Volume 42, pp. 15-29.##Phaal, R., Farrukh, C. &amp; and Probert, R., 2004. Technology roadmapping A planning framework for evolution and revolution. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, Volume 7, p. 5–26.##Phaal, R., Farrukh, C. &amp; Probert, D., 2006. Technology management tools: generalization, integration and configuration. International Journal of Innovation and Technology Management, 3(3), pp. 321-339.##Rainey, D., 2005. Product Innovation: Leading Change through Integrated Product Development. s.l.:Cambridge University Press.##Riggs, B. A., 2010. A Data Acquisition System For The NASA Specialized Center Of Research And Training Cuvette, s.l.: College of Technology Theses and Projects.##Rothwell, R., 1972. Factors for Success in Industrial Innovations from Project SAPPHO- A Comparative Study of Success and Failure in Industrial Innovation, ‌Brighton, Sussex, England: SPRU.##Rothwell, R. et al., 1974. SAPPHO updated-project SAPPHO phase II. Research Policy, 3(3), pp. 258-291.##Sharif, N., 1997. The Evolution of Technology Management Studies. Technoeconomies to Technometries.##Söderquist, K. &amp; Nellore, R., 2000. Information Systems in Fast Cycle Development: Identifying User Needs in Integrated Automotive Component Development. R&amp;D Management, 30(3), pp. 199-211.##Subramaniam, M., Rosenthal, S. R. &amp; Hatten, K. J., 1998. Global New Product Development Processes: Preliminary Findings and Research Propositions. Journal of Management Studies, 35(6), pp. 773-796.##T.H., H. &amp; Yang, T., 2000. Application of fuzzy analytic hierarchy process in the selection of advertising media. Journal of Management and Systems, Volume 7, pp. 583-99.##Takeuchi, H. &amp; Nonaka, I., 1986. The New Product Development Game. Harvard Business Review, Volume January, pp. 137-146.##U. D. o. D., 2013. Acquisition GuideBook, s.l.: s.n.##UNIDO, 1996. Manual on Technology Transfer Negotiation, United Nations Industrial Development Organization: Vienna.##Veryzer, J. R., 1998. Discontinuous Innovation and the New Product Development Process. Journal of Product Innovation Management, Volume 15, p. 304–321.##Zirger, B. J. &amp; Maidique, M. A., 1990. A model of new product development: An empirical test. Management science, 36(7), pp. 867-883.##اثباتی، ح.، کریمیان، ا. و آقاپور، ح.، 1387. آشنایی با مبانی و الگوهای تدوین استراتژی فناوری. 1 تدوین تهران: انتشارات سازمان صنایع دفاع.##اشتریان، ک. و امامی میبدی، ر.، 1389. دانش ضمنی و سیاست‌های انتقال فناوری با تاکید بر فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات. تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه تهران.##بنیاد توسعه فردا، 1384. روش‌های آینده نگاری فناوری. تهران: گروه آینده اندیشی بنیاد توسعه فردا.##حبیبی، آ.، ایزدیار، ص. و سرافرازی، ا.، 1393. تصمیم گیری چند معیاره فازی. مکان نشر نامشخص:انتشارات کتیبه گیل.##خلیل، ط.، 1389. مدیریت فناوری رمز موفقیت در رقابت و خلق ثروت. چاپ‌چهارم. تهران: انتشارات دفتر پژوهش‌های فرهنگی.##رفیع‌پور، ف.، 1370. کند و کاوها و پنداشته‌ها. تهران: شرکت سهامی انتشار.##شریف، ن.، 1376. مدیریت انتقال فناوری و توسعه. تهران: انتشارات وزارت برنامه و بودجه، مرکز مدارک اقتصادی اجتماعی و انتشارات.##صالحی، خ.، 1389. مدیریت یکپارچه‌ی تأمین،‌اکتساب و پشتیبانی چرخه عمر محصولات و فناوری‌های دفاعی. تهران: موسسه آموزشی و تحقیقاتی صنایع دفاعی.##طاهری، س. ا.، 1388. راهکارهای ارتقاء کارکردهای مدیریت تکنولوژی در شرکت برق منطقه‌ای تهران. تهران: پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.##طباطبائیان، س. ح. و غریبی، ج.، 1388. مبانی ارزش‌گذاری فناوری. تهران: مرکز آموزش و تحقیقات صنعتی ایران.##فولادی، ق.، 1390.  ارزیابی و استفاده از سطوح آمادگی فناوری. تهران: موسسه آموزشی و تحقیقاتی صنایع دفاعی.##قاضی زاده فرد، س. ا. و اتابکی، م. س.، پاییز 1391. معرفی الگوی برون‌سپاری در سازمان‌های نظامی. فصلنامه راهبرد دفاعی، 10(39)، صص. 195-153.##گال و مردیت، 1386. روش‌های کمی و کیفی در علوم تربیتی و روان شناسی. تهران: انتشارات دانشگاه شهید بهشتی و سمت.##مرتضوی، س. و فرتاش، ک.، 1390. انواع جهش‌های تکنولوژیکی به همراه مطالعه پنج بنگاه موفق چینی. تهران: اولین کنفرانس بین المللی،پنجمین کنفرانس ملی مدیریت تکنولوژی.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				