<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Ranking Venture Capital Business Plans by Data Envelopment Analysis Method: A Case Study of an Iranian venture capital company</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رتبه بندی طرح های کسب وکار سرمایه گذاری خطرپذیر با روش تحلیل پوششی داده ها- مورد مطالعه: یک شرکت سرمایه گذاری خطرپذیر ایرانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>87</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>108</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">41314</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سامان</FirstName>
					<LastName>احسنی زاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میرسامان</FirstName>
					<LastName>پیشوایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیر علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>&lt;strong&gt;of Hatef Company&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Evaluation in venture capital industry is one of the most challenging issues from practitioners&#039; and researchers&#039; points of view. Limited time of evaluation, lack of financial data especially from ventures, heuristics and biases in evaluating and some other issues differentiate venture capital evaluation process from other investment methods. Also the speed and accuracy of evaluation are two key success factors for venture capitalists. In this paper, we attempt to overcome some of evaluation challenges by using several mathematical methods including data envelopment analysis (DEA), cross efficiency and VIKOR through decreasing screening time, reducing biased effects and enabling group decision-making with variety of weights. This method does not need any weights as they are calculated within the model. For the purpose of this study, some interviews are conducted and domestic criteria are extracted. The performance of the proposed model is investigated with the aid of the Hatef Company case study. Thereafter, we present a group of domestic criteria, and a standard and mathematical method to support decision-making without any needs for criteria weights or normalization. The results derived from the model are similar to the experts&#039; opinions about the best project, but there are not adequate data to compare the ranking of another project with the experts&#039; opinions.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ارزیابی در صنعت سرمایه‌گذاری ریسک‌پذیر یکی از موضوعات چالشی فعالان و محققان این حوزه است. زمان بسیار محدود ارزیابی، عدم وجود اطلاعات مورد نیاز برای امکان‌سنجی اقتصادی طرح‌های سرمایه‌گذاری ریسک‌پذیر، خطاهای شناختی ارزیاب و ... همگی موجب شده تا ارزیابی طرح‌ها در سرمایه‌گذاری ریسک‌پذیر از دیگر موارد مشابه مجزا گردد و دقت و سرعت در ارزیابی به یکی از مزیت‌های سرمایه‌گذاران ریسک‌پذیر تبدیل شود. در این مقاله تلاش می‌شود تا با استفاده از روش ریاضی تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها، کارآیی متقاطع و روش تصمیم‌گیری ویکور، بخشی از مشکلات ارزیابی به وسیله کاهش زمان غربال‌گری، کاهش تأثیر سلیقه و تعصبات ارزیاب، فراهم کردن امکان تصمیم‌گیری گروهی، فراهم کردن امکان مقایسه تعداد زیاد گزینه‌ها با در نظر گرفتن تعداد زیاد معیارها و وزن آنها، عدم نیاز به تعیین وزن‌ معیارها تعدیل گردد. برای این منظور از طریق مصاحبه با فعالان داخلی سرمایه‌گذاری ریسک‌پذیر معیارهای بومی استخراج شدند و عملکرد مدل ریاضی پیشنهادی با پیاده‌سازی در شرکت سرمایه‌گذاری کارآفرینی هاتف و مقایسه با نظر خبرگان، بررسی گردید. مجموعه‌ معیارهای بومی و همچنین ارائه روش ساده و کارآمد ریاضی تصمیم‌گیری، بدون نیاز به وزن معیارها و یکسان کردن بعد معیارها از جمله دستاوردهای این پژوهش می‌باشد. نتیجه به‌دست‌آمده از مدل برای طرح رتبه اول با نظر ارزیابان شرکت برای اطلاق طرح نمونه به آن، همخوانی داشت البته اطلاعات کافی برای مقایسه رتبه‌بندی سایر طرح‌ها با نظر کارشناسان در دست نبود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رتبه بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه گذاری خطر پذیر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل پوششی داده ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآیی متقاطع</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ویکور</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_41314_6c8fcedbb3184cb32b725ec571bf6a68.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
