<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Model for Product Technology Strategizing in a Firm Based on its Suppliers&#039; Technological Capabilities</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی مدلی برای تدوین راهبرد فناوری های محصول در سطح یک بنگاه مادر براساس توانمندی های فناورانه شبکه زنجیره تامین</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>53</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>85</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14765</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریم پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>آراستی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>اکبری جوکار</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>شیخ زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>With the increasing complexity of products and necessity for development, today&#039;s products, processes and the relevant technologies are planned, designed and finally manufactured with the participation of suppliers in the wide range of the corporation&#039;s supply chain. Lack of attention of corporations to the technological capabilities of supply chains has made them experience different problems in implementing product and process development strategies. This paper tries to design an integrated model for product technology strategizing in the supply chain of a firm based on the technological capabilities of its suppliers. This study is conducted with qualitative approach in two stages. First, after reviewing the literature and studying the documents of automotive companies, the preliminary data is gathered through in-depth interviews with a group of experts of Iranian automotive industry, and then the collected data is analyzed by theme methodology. After that, based on the identified themes and exploring the relations between them, a conceptual model is designed. At the second phase, the validity and reliability of the designed model are tested and confirmed using the methodology of focus group with another group of experts of the industry. The designed model makes it possible for corporations to develop a strategy of technology with the participation of supply chain.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با افزایش پیچیدگی در محصولات و نیز لزوم توسعه و کاربرد فناوری های پیشرفته در آنها، امروزه محصولات، فرآیندها و نیز فناوری های مرتبط با آنها با مشارکت تامین کنندگان و در گستره زنجیره تامین یک بنگاه طرح ریزی، طراحی و ساخته می شوند. عدم توجه بنگاه های مادر به توانمندی های فناورانه زنجیره تامین در زمان تدوین راهبرد فناوری، آنها را در اجرای راهبردهای توسعه محصول و فرآیند دچار مشکلات زیادی می نماید. پژوهش حاضر با هدف طراحی مدلی یکپارچه برای تدوین راهبرد فناوری های محصول در گستره زنجیره تامین یک بنگاه مادر براساس توانمندی های فناورانه تامین ک‌نندگان و با رویکرد کیفی و در دو مرحله انجام شد. ابتدا پس از مرور ادبیات و بررسی پیشینه پژوهش و نیز مطالعه مستندات بنگاه های خودروسازی، داده های اولیه از طریق انجام مصاحبه های عمیق اکتشافی با گروهی از خبرگان صنعت خودروسازی ایران که بصورت نظری نمونه برداری شده بودند، جمع آوری و سپس با استفاده از روش تحلیل زمینه مورد تجزیه وتحلیل قرار گرفتند. در ادامه براساس زمینه های شناسایی شده و کشف ارتباطات بین آن ها، یک مدل مفهومی طراحی شد. در مرحله دوم، اعتبار مدل طراحی شده با استفاده از روش گروه کانونی با تعداد دیگری از خبرگان صنعت یادشده مورد تصحیح و تصدیق قرار گرفت. مدل طراحی شده این امکان را برای بنگاه های مادر فراهم می آورد که آنها بتوانند با مشارکت زنجیره تامین و بصورت یکپارچه به تدوین راهبرد فناوری بپردازند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توسعه محصول جدید</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت راهبردی فناوری (SMOT)</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فناوری محصول</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معماری محصول</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنجیره تامین فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزیابی فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14765_cf353041b8069c7a95da5b1009ce5afc.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
