<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying The Dimensions and Causes of Decline In Satisfaction Of Knowledge-Based Companies In Collaboration With The Fund&#039;s From The Perspective Of Executives And Policy Makers: A Case Study Of Innovation And Prosperity Fund</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی ابعاد و علل کاهش رضایت شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان در همکاری با صندوق‌های مالی از نگاه مجریان و سیاستگذاران: مطالعه موردی صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>92</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>120</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">86889</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نقی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی مرکز تحقیقات سیاست علمی کشور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>هاجری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکترای سیاست گذاری علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ساجده</FirstName>
					<LastName>بساوند</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت فناوری</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Since the concept of knowledge-based economy emerged, the knowledge-based firms, as a main driver of economic growth and development, has become more important. Therefore, identifying and solving their challenges is important too. One of the main challenges of knowledge-based firms is providing their essential funding which need different mechanisms because of their different nature from other enterprises. Understanding the importance of these firms funding, increase the importance of financing funds in technology such as the Innovation and Prosperity Fund. Thus the interaction knowledge-based firms with financial funding and increasing their satisfaction from getting services tailored to their needs has become one of the policy issues for financing funds in innovation area. In this regard, in this research, the affecting factors on reducing satisfaction of knowledge-based firms in cooperation with the Innovation and Prosperity Fund from the viewpoint of the executives and policymakers are identifiead and analyzed based on quantitative and qualitative combination methodology and focusing on the case study research strategy. In the first step, 18 factors that affect on reducing satisfaction of knowledge-based firms in cooperation with national financial funds were identified and classified in 6 categories. After that, based on case study research strategy, these factors are examined in the Innovation and Prosperity Fund and a framework, which shows the affecting factors on reducing satisfaction of knowledge-based firms in cooperation with the Innovation and Prosperity Fund from the viewpoint of the executives and policymakers , is presented.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان به عنوان قلپ تپنده و محرک اصلی رشد و توسعه اقتصاد دانش بنیان از اهمیت فراوانی برخوردارند. با توجه به اهمیت این شرکت ها، شناسایی و برطرف ساختن چالش‌ها آنها از اهمیت ویژه ای برخوردار است. یکی از چالش های جدی شرکت های دانش بنیان تأمین سرمایه مالی مورد نیاز آنها، متناسب با مرحله توسعه این شرکت ها می‌باشد که با توجه به ماهیت متفاوت فعالیت آنان نیاز به ساز و کارهای متفاوتی نسبت به سایر بنگاه‌های اقتصادی دارد. درک لزوم تأمین سرمایه مالی در این شرکت‌ها اهمیت صندوق های تامین مالی حوزه فناوری همچون صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی را افزایش داده است و نوع تعامل شرکت های دانش بنیان و صندوق های تامین مالی و افزایش رضایتمندی شرکت های دانش بنیان به یکی از مسائل سیاستی در حوزه نوآوری تبدیل شده است. در این پژوهش تلاش شده است تا با استفاده از روش شناسی ترکیبی کمی و کیفی و با تمرکز بر استراتژی پژوهش مطالعه موردی، عوامل موثر بر کاهش رضایتمندی شرکت‌های دانش بنیان در همکاری با صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی از نگاه مجریان و سیاستگذاران شناسایی و تحلیل شوند. در همین راستا، بر اساس 18 عامل مؤثر شناسایی شده و بررسی آن در صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی، چارچوب عوامل موثر بر کاهش رضایتمندی شرکت‌های دانش بنیان در همکاری با صندوق های تامین مالی ارائه شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تأمین مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صندوق‌های مالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کاهش رضایتمندی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86889_ecdda8d4491cd0cf830e6af75100f6b0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
