<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Improving Impact of Research Papers</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bonyadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Iran University of Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Esfandi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Iran University of Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>6</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_58553_b103511998baded90d98684f796833c8.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Technology Transfer Challenges in Iran's International Commercial Contracts based on a thematic Approach</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Naghizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Amini</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sara</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nouri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract> Technology is one of the main determinants of international trade. Firms try to acquire beneficial technologies through different ways. One of these ways, regarded by active firms in developing countries, is technology transfer. However, many technology transfer projects have confronted with different serious challenges toward their knowledge goals realization. This research tries to identify and explain these technology transfer challenges in Iran&#039;s important commercial contracts with a thematic analysis approach. regarding the importance of deep understanding of aforementioned  challenges and its dependence on the analyzed field, we used thematic analysis in order to analyze deep interviews of 10 industrial and scientific experts . After coding the results,  18 challenges have been classified into four main groups. The necessity of having comprehensive approach to different aspects of technology transfer and considering the special context and circumstance of Iran are some of the main results. As well, unwillingness to technology transfer due to economic, political, and project based reasons related to the factor of technology transferor factor, low absorptive capacity of Iranian firms related to technology transferee factor, lack of economic sustainability related to context factor and finally different nature of technologies related to content factor were introduced as the main challenges of technology transfer in important commercial projects in Iran. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>19</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_57421_87978100349a7bae44e798dcc7272770.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Conceptualization and Prioritization of Competitive Intelligence Components at Knowledge-based Companies: Mixed method Study</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohammad ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">siahsarani kojouri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Student  International Marketing Management, Semnan University, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Azim</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zarei</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Semnan</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Morteza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Maleki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof., Faculty of Economic, Management and Administrative Sciences, Semnan University, Semnan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Adel</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azar</namePart>
				<affiliation>3. Prof., Faculty of Management and Economic, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Davod</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Feiz</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof., Faculty of Economic, Management and Administrative Sciences, Semnan University, Semnan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Identifying the problems of Knowledge-based companies is important because of their special position in country&#039;s economy, despite of the increasing export value of Knowledge-based products, these companies suffer from two main problems, areas of investment and unsustainable export, the issues that have challenged the competitiveness of these companies; it is an issue that needs to be explored further. The aim of this study was to conceptualize and Prioritize the intelligence components in knowledge-based companies through a mixed method approach. The present study aimed to explore the mixed and the functional result. The first step in research in order to achieve the objectives, is using semi-structured content analysis and interviews with activist’s knowledge-based companies (professionals, managers and relevant officials), 95 code as intelligent concepts competitive knowledge-based mining companies and 10 components were classified according to semantic relationships. At the second step, 12 experts were selected to extract their views by theoretical sampling  through a 5-point Likert-scale questionnaire then analyzed the data collected through Fuzzy Delphi technique. The results of study led to the identification of eight main components of  competitors intelligence, financial intelligence, market intelligence, technical intelligence,  management intelligence, regulatory intelligence, human intelligence and political intelligence, in order to gain competitive intelligence in the knowledge-based companies.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>21</start>
					<end>44</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_57422_08fb4446dc52e89c2675c8aecb30b8e6.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Influences of Cross-functional Collaboration on Technology Commercialization Function Regarding the Role of Knowledge Creation and Support  of Superior Management</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Homa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Doroudi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Islamic Azad University of Zanjan,Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Masoud</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sharafpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Islamic Azad University of Zanjan,Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Maintaining competitive advantage and organizational survival depends on maintaining and strengthening the commercialization of technology. The main objective of this study is to investigate the relationship between cross-functional collaboration, knowledge creation, superior management support and commercialization of technology in knowledge-based companies. The aim of the current study is practical and it is an descriptive-analytic survey which is conducted by a metrical approach. The Statistical Society were 122  knowledge-based companies located in the area of Pardis science and technology park. A questionnaire was used to collect data and structural equation modeling and data analysis methods were used by SmartPLS to analyze the data. According to the results of this study, there was positive and significant relationship between the variable cross-functional cooperation and technology commercialization   and knowledge creation mediate this relationship and superior management support also equates the aforementioned relationship positively. Finally, according to the results suggestions are presented.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>45</start>
					<end>72</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_57420_7e56ce4f35a424126f516a286a9b961c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Effect of Entrepreneurship Training on Entrepreneurial Mindset: Mediating Role of Creativity and Entrepreneurial Alertness. (Organizations of MOD)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">naeiji</namePart>
				<affiliation>Shahid Beheshti University,Tehran,Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ebrahim</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ebrahimi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Shahid Beheshti Universty,Tehran,Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This study aims to investigate the impact of entrepreneurship training on entrepreneurial mindset according to mediating role of creativity and entrepreneurial alertness. By Cochrane formula, 105 companies from 140 organizations of Ministry of Defence (MOD) have been selected randomly. The main tool for collecting data is questionnaire, which its level of validity and reliability has been acceptable for all structures. To analyze the data, structural simulating equations and Lisrel software is used. Results show that entrepreneurship training and creativity on the entrepreneurship mindset system is not effective, but entrepreneurship training on creativity and awareness is effective. Also, awareness plays the role of mediator in the relationship of entrepreneurship training and entrepreneurship mindset system.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>73</start>
					<end>100</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_57423_b7e286e4aa1c570575f435a56a897e66.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating the Effect of Intellectual Capital on Innovative Behavior through the Role of Knowledge Sharing as a Mediator (Case of Sun-Air Research Institute)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khorakian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad.Mashhad,Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Negar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kadkhoda</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad.Mashhad,Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Bahareh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Molazadeh Yazdani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ferdowsi University of Mashhad.Mashhad,Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Research organizations survival depends on innovation. Considering the variability and unpredictability of environmental changes, these organizations desperately need to foster innovation and creativity. In the knowledge-based economy, innovative behavior plays a significant role in creating and enhancing organizational values and this matter in research facilities of the Department of Defense with respect to their activity field is significant. The aim of this study is to design and fit a model of the relationship between intellectual capital components and innovative behavior with regard to the interventionist behavior role of knowledge sharing among employees who work in research facilities of the Department of Defense. A questionnaire included 25 questions to measure variables were used. The questionnaire was distributed among 80 employees of the studied organizations. In order to analyze data, structural equation modeling was used. The result of this research proves the relationship between intellectual capital human dimension and innovative behavior by best practices sharing and also structural dimension of intellectual capital and both dimensions of knowledge sharing behavior. In the following, Considering the importance of innovation in the organization and to strengthen its return to the field and qualitative interviews were conducted also factors influencing variables and the systematic relationships between these factors and variables were identified in order for the organization to improve them. System analysis results indicate the important role of individual creativity.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>101</start>
					<end>134</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_38490_2e59ae91c7144e49e8fc6faeea228547.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Impact Analysis of Customer Knowledge Management (CKM) on the Critical Success Factors (CSFs)  and New Product Development Performance in Field of Industrial Technology</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shayeste</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.Sc. in Business Administration,Azad University,Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hosein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jalilian</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran,Tehran,Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abootaleb</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shafaghat</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allame Tabatabaei University,Tehran,Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Open innovation relies on external knowledge sources such as customers, and Customer knowledge has been neglected in researches about Iranian Defense Industry. In addition, new product failure rate is high in defense industries. This study aims to investigate the impact of Customer Knowledge Management (CKM) on the Critical Success Factors (CSFs) of New Product Development and New Product Development (NPD) performance. This is a metrical and descriptive study. Considering the literature of the study, conceptual models and the hypothesis were presented. Then, in order to evaluate the models and the hypothesis, a questionnaire was designed in order to get elite&#039;s opinions about users of defense products. Using relative categorized method, the sample members were selected among the users of new defense products. The analysis of the data through Structural Equation Modeling (SEM) showed that there is a positive and significant correlation between customer knowledge management (knowledge from, about and for customer) with performance of the new product development and critical sources factors. Also the relation between the knowledge “from and the knowledge “about” with critical Success factors was confirmed, but the knowledge “for” customers was not confirmed. The results show that applying customer management knowledge in the process of developing new defense products has a great impact on successes and performance promotion of new product.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>135</start>
					<end>164</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_57424_dcbf27bf4ea220091c0dc7f50df3fe84.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>