<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2020</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Diagnosis of Science and Technology Budget in Iran Using Meta-synthesis Method</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آسیب شناسی بودجه ریزی پژوهش و فناوری درایران ﺑﺎ اﺳﺘﻔﺎده از روش ﻓﺮاﺗﺮﮐﯿﺐ</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>85</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>122</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">102634</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیرحسام</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهروز</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی اصغر</FirstName>
					<LastName>پورعزت</LastName>
<Affiliation>مدیرکل دفتر اسناد و کتابخانه مرکزی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرهاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>دژپسند</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده علوم اقتصادی و سیاسی، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present paper is a meta-synthesis study on the research and technology budget areas in Iran with the aim of comprehensive and holistic diagnosis. The statistic of the present paper consists of 96 documents, including research papers, review papers, reports and research projects which have been published in Persian during the years 2002-2019. In this study, Sandlowski and Barroso&#039;s seven-step method was used, and after screening by helping the COREQ 32-item index, 69 documents were identified as high-quality and medium-quality research for deeper analysis, and they have been reviewed in the two sections of descriptive and qualitative. The themes were analyzed and extracted from the articles and final findings using the theme analysis method. The results showed that the barriers to implementation of research and technology budgeting consisted of 139 main factors and obstacles in 19 components (sub themes) in 5 dimensions (Main theme) includes science and technology policy making, budget planning, budget approval, budget execution and budget monitoring.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ﻣﻄﺎﻟﻌﺔ ﺣﺎﺿـﺮ ، ﻓﺮاﺗرکیبی ﺑـﺮ ﭘـﮋوﻫﺶ‌ﻫـﺎی ﺣـﻮزه بودجه پژوهش و فناوری در ایران، با هدف آسیب شناسی جامع و کل نگر آن است. ﺟﺎﻣﻌﺔ ﭘـﮋوﻫﺶ ﺣﺎﺿـﺮ، مشتمل بر 96 ﻣﻘﺎﻟﺔ ﻋﻠﻤﻲ ﭘﮋوﻫﺸﻲ، علمی -ترویجی، گزارش و طرح پژوهشی است که در بازه سالهای 1381-1398 به زبان فارسی ﺑﻪ ﭼﺎپ رﺳﻴﺪه اﻧﺪ. در این پژوهش از روش هفت مرحله سندلوسکی و باروسو برای فراترکیب مقالات بهره گرفته شده است که پس از غربال گری، به کمک فهرست COREQ 32-item، 69 سند به منزله پژوهش با کیفیت بالا و متوسط جهت تحلیل عمیق تر شناسایی شدند و دردو ﺑﺨـﺶ ﺗﻮﺻـ ﻴﻔﻲ و تحلیلی ﺑﺮرﺳﻲ ﺷﺪه اﻧﺪ. با استفاده از روش تحلیل تم ، به تحلیل و استخراج اطلاعات از مقالات و ارائه یافته های نهایی اقدام شده است. ﻣﻮاﻧﻊ اﺟﺮای بودجه ریزی پژوهش و فناوری، در قالب 139 عامل و مانع اصلی در 19 مولفه ( تم فرعی) در 5 بعد (تم اصلی) خط مشی گذاری حوزه علم و فناوری، تهیه و تنظیم بودجه، تصویب بودجه، اجرای بودجه و نظارت بر بودجه، دسته بندی شدند. چ</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بودجه ریزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ﻓﺮاﺗرکیب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بودجه علم و فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بودجه پژوهشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تامین مالی پژوهش و فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_102634_3ff094bd73e286bc919c13c1ceb1567b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
