<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Elaborating on Technology Management Functions in New Product Development by Fuzzy AHP Method</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تبیین کارکردهاى مدیریت فناورى در توسعه محصول جدید با روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبى فازى</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>41</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>60</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14594</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری خانشیر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم تحقیقات</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رادفر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم تحقیقات</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسنوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>New product development (NPD) is a modern approach for responding to environmental changes in firms according to critical success factors (CSF), and for achieving competitive advantages. The alignment of technology change management — with concentration on technology acquisition planning and filling technological gap — with new product development process is a necessary. The purpose of this study is to prioritize technology management functions in NPD process by considering CSFs as criteria and concentrating on a knowledge-based organization. In this descriptive and survey study, Fuzzy AHP method is used. Based on the experts&#039; views, 5 technology management functions are identified, and 3 groups of key success factors are used to prioritize them. The results show that the function of identifying and selecting technology in feasibility stage, the function of technology acquisition in technology development stage, and the function of technology exploitation in product development stage have the highest priorities. Accordingly, a design theme for an efficient technology management system in NPD is achieved. The reliability of the study is confirmed by Cronbach&#039;s Alpha and its validity is verified by technology management and NPD experts&#039; views.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">فرآیند توسعه محصول جدید یکرویکرد نوین براى بقا در محیط رقابتى است و عوامل کلیدى موفقیت واسطه‌اى براى کسب مزیت‌هاى رقابتى است. همراستایى مدیریت تغییر فناورى (با هدف برنامه‌ریزى براى کسب فناورى و پر کردن شکاف فناورانه) و فرآیند توسعه محصول یک ضرورت جدى مىباشد. هدف این تحقیق اولویت‌بندى کارکردهاى مدیریت فناورى در فرآیند توسعه محصول با معیار ارتقاى اثربخشى فرآیند و از طریق عوامل کلیدى موفقیت فرآیند و با بهره‌گیرى از مطالعه موردى در یک صنعت دانش‌بنیان می‌باشد. این تحقیق از نوع توصیفى پیمایشى است که در آن، با توجه به فقدان داده‌هاى قطعى، روش تحلیل سلسله مراتب فازى مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. بر اساس دیدگاه صاحبنظران،5 کارکرد اصلى مدیریت فناورى شناسایى و 3 گروه عوامل کلیدى موفقیت (معیار اثربخشى فرآیند) براى اولویت‌بندى کارکردهاى مدیریت فناورى استفاده شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد کارکرد شناسایى و انتخاب فناورى در مرحله امکان‌سنجى، کارکرد اکتساب فناورى در مرحله توسعه سیستمى و کارکرد بهره‌بردارى در مرحله توسعه فناورى از بیشترین اولویت برخوردار است. بر اساس نتایج این تحقیق (شناسایى رابطه کارکردهاى مدیریت فناورى و مراحل فرآیند)، زمینه طراحى الگوى مدیریت فناورى در بستر فرآیند با هدف همسویى، یکپارچگى و تقویت تناسب و افزایش بهره‌ورى کل نظام‌هاى مدیریتى ایجاد می‌گردد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارکردهاى مدیریت فناورى</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرآیند توسعه محصول جدید</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل کلیدى موفقیت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14594_cadad187d6f2d3423a8b50eda314fd62.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
