<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2024</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Impacts of Knowledge Network on Product Innovation Performance Using Structural Equation Modeling: A Case Study of E-Commerce Companies in Isfahan Province</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تاثیر شبکه دانش بر عملکرد نوآوری محصول با استفاده از مدل معادلات ساختاری (مطالعه موردی:شرکتهای تجارت الکترونیک استان اصفهان)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>53</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>75</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14724</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>نصری نصرآبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهام</FirstName>
					<LastName>فلاح</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سمانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>شیرانی لپری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علوم تحقیقات</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Acquiring new knowledge enables organizations to gain competitive advantage and improves their organizational performance. Knowledge networks are among the main sources of knowledge. The purpose of this study is to investigate the relationship between knowledge management and product innovation performance. To do so, a conceptual framework of product innovation performance is proposed with respect to the factors of knowledge management and product development strategies. Next, the impact of strategic focus on new product development and product innovation performance is empirically studied from the perspective of technical knowledge, customer&#039;s knowledge and competitive knowledge. The statistical population is selected from IT experts in the field of knowledge management and innovation, working for e-commerce companies in Esfahan province, Iran, and academics of the field. In this study, structural equation modeling and AMOS software are used to examine and test the conceptual model, and exploratory factor analysis is used to confirm the validity of the research criteria and structural validity. The results show that product innovation performance is created by knowledge management systems. The findings also reveal that some product development strategies have significant impacts on product innovation performance and knowledge networks. Among product development strategies, incremental strategy has no significant impacts on product innovation performance. Also, knowledge networks have a significantly positive effect on product innovation performance.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;کسب دانش جدید، علاوه بر ایجاد مزیت رقابتی برای سازمان&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها موجب ارتقاء عملکرد سازمانی نیز می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;شود. شبکه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های دانشی، یکی از منابع اصلی کسب دانش در هر سازمان محسوب می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;شوند. پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی رابطه مدیریت شبکه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; دانش و عملکرد نوآوری محصول انجام شد. برای این منظور، ابتدا یک چارچوب مفهومی از عملکرد نوآوری محصول با توجه به مولفه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های مدیریت دانش و راهبردهای توسعه محصول ارائه گردید و در ادامه، تاثیر تمرکز راهبردی بر توسعه محصولات جدید و عملکرد نوآوری محصول از نقطه نظر دانش فنی، دانش رقابتی و  دانش مشتری مورد بررسی تجربی قرار گرفت. جامعه آماری این پژوهش را کارشناسان فناوری اطلاعات شرکت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های تجارت الکترونیک استان اصفهان و خبرگان دانشگاهی در حوزه مدیریت دانش و نوآوری (جهت بررسی روایی محتوا) تشکیل می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;دهند. برای آزمون مدل مفهومی، روش معادلات ساختاری و نرم افزار &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMOS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; و برای تایید شاخص&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها و روایی سازه، تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. نتایج نشان داد که عملکرد نوآوری محصول از مدیریت شبکه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های دانشی ایجاد می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;شود. همچنین مشخص گردید که برخی از  راهبردهای توسعه محصول بر عملکرد نوآوری محصول و شبکه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های دانشی تاثیر معناداری دارند. از بین راهبردهای توسعه محصول، راهبرد افزایشی هیچ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;گونه تاثیر معناداری بر عملکرد نوآوری محصول ندارد. همچنین شبکه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های دانشی بر عملکرد نوآوری محصول تاثیر مثبت و معناداری دارد.&lt;/strong&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شبکه دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توسعه محصول جدید</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل معادلات ساختاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرکتهای تجارت الکترونیکی استان اصفهان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14724_78115de430cb6624b1bc833db38564f2.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
