<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the Impacts of Social Capital on Innovation Performance with an Emphasis on the Mediatory Role of Knowledge Transfer: A Case Study of Iranian IT Knowledge-based Firms]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Dehghanan, Hamed]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hrandi, Ata ollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social Capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Knowledge transfer]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation Performance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Information technology]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[structural equation modeling]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Nowadays, innovational performance is one of the key factors of knowledge-based organizations survival. Innovation in performance leads organizations to maintain competitive advantage and organizational development. Creating an innovational performance needs effective and sustainable communications with all stakeholders and public environment in organization. Social capital is a kind of capital that facilitates the access to information and vital resources in order to improve environmental performance, while takes advantage of environmental opportunities. This study seeks to develop a systematic framework concerning social capital, the mediatory role of knowledge transfer and innovational performance in Iranian knowledge-based organizations, and tries to push the frontiers of knowledge in this area. This study is an applied research of survey type. The data is gathered through random sampling method from information technology knowledge-based organizations in Iran by means of a questionnaire. Structural equation modeling is used here to analyze the data by the help of SmartPLS software. The results indicate that social capital and knowledge transfer have impacts on the innovational performance of Iranian knowledge-based organizations. In addition, the mediatory role of knowledge transfer in increasing the effectiveness of social capital and innovational performance of Iranian knowledge-base organizations is confirmed.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14671_762a43d03d2302876bda83321723c785.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[An Analysis of Factors Affecting the Formation and Development of Innovative Cluster in Iranian Helicopter Industry]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Kazazi, Abolfazl]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tabatabaeian, Seyed Habibollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Amiri, Maghsoud]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shirazi Shayesteh, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Industry cluster]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sectoral Innovation System]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovative Cluster]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Industrial Factors]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[economy-related and market-related factors]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Having decades of experience and appropriate internal market, Iran's helicopter industry is one of the most attractive sections for investment at national level, because of providing employment and development for other industries. The main aim of this study is to identify and analyze factors affecting the formation and development of innovative civil helicopter industrial cluster in Iran. By reviewing the literature of industrial clusters and sectoral innovation system, we categorize the affecting factors in a primary model, and then by conducting interviews with 20 science and technology policy-makers and helicopter industry experts, we localize and revise the model. The revised model is tested by confirmatory factor analysis (CFA) and path analysis methods through a questionnaire answered by a statistical population of 404. The results show that economy- and market-related factors, scientific and technological factors, and political and human factors affect the formation and development of civil helicopter industry cluster of Iran.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14672_f68b36d06000ca41b765de0d4e3b6abb.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Proposing a Model for Improving the Self-Organization and Learning of Innovation Networks in Ahwaz Science and Technology Park]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Elahi, Sha&rsquo;ban]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shayan, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghazinoory, Sepehr]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khodadad Hosseini, Hamid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation Network]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ahwaz Science and Technology Park]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Self-Organization]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Learning]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Science and Technology Policy-making]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Embeddedness]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Innovation is considered as a factor of nations' advantage and reaching wealth and development. Countries make and implement special policies for innovation development. One way of developing innovation is innovation networks approach. These networks are based on cooperation and learning. In the last decade, there was a major focus on the self-organization and learning of networks, but there is not enough evidence for such studies in Iran. This survey research aims to study through a questionnaire the innovation network of Ahwaz Science and Technology Park, in Ahwaz, Iran. The questionnaire is validated by interviewing 11 experts, and is distributed among 25 companies based in the park. To analyze the data, we perform path analysis and regression test using SPSS software. According to the results, different factors, such as enabling companies, networks embeddedness and favorable environment, have different effects on the cooperation, self-organization and learning of innovation networks. In addition, these factors have different effects on innovation development and network efficiency.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14684_5406e5fdeead724f9dbb1d0db5942b90.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Effective Factors in Creating Innovation Capabilities: A Case Study of an Iranian Aviation Industrial-Research Center]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hashemzadeh, Ebrahim]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hajihosseini, Hojjat-ollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Radfar, Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Malekzadeh, Keramat]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation Capability]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[technology]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Aviation industry]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The need for technological Innovation and the importance of developing advanced technologies, such as aviation industry technologies, have made the identification of necessary factors and contexts for the creation of innovation capabilities a strategic process. In this study, effective factors in creating and enhancing innovation capabilities are identified and ranked, their influences on different innovations achieved in a research centers in Iran's aviation industry are investigated, and some solutions are suggested to enhance these capabilities. First, through library studies, the effective factors in innovation and innovation capabilities are identified and classified into four main groups. Next, data is collected by the designed questionnaire and analyzed by correlation, Friedman and regression tests, which indicate that the network cooperation and interaction have the greatest positive effects on innovation capabilities in the research center. Other important influencing factors are technological efforts, managerial features and the characteristics of human resources. Also, the priorities of the achieved innovations (as the results of innovation capabilities), in order of importance, include product innovation, organizational innovation and process innovation. Moreover, technological efforts is identified as the most important factor in the creation of product innovation, while managerial features is considered as the most important factor in organizational and process innovation.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14712_69b213647477cf0f5de9c8de85c58e99.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the Impacts of Emotional Intelligence on Organizational Learning with an Emphasis on the role of Cooperative Culture: A Case Study of a Governmental Organization]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sanjaghi, Mohammad Ebrahim]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghazanfari, Seyed Mohammad Javad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Saeidizadeh, Afsaneh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Emotional Intelligence (EI)]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational Learning (OL)]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organizational Culture (OC)]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cooperative Culture (COC)]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In the past decade, many studies have examined the impact of emotional intelligence on different variables, while their focus has been only on organizational learning as an important factor for adaptability to environment. However, there is a lack of research on the relationship between three variables: emotional intelligence, organizational learning and organizational culture. This study tries to investigate the mediating role of cooperative culture in the relationship between emotional intelligence and organizational learning in a governmental organization. To this end, a conceptual model is designed based on library studies, and a quantitative approach is adopted. To gather data, we distribute a questionnaire among 120 participants selected randomly from the organization and asked them to express their viewpoints about the variables. The gathered data is analyzed through structural equation modeling (SEM) using LISREL 8.8. The results indicate that emotional intelligence has not any direct effects on organizational learning, but has an indirect meaningful and positive effect through organizational culture. In addition, this study introduces a new conceptual model concerning the impacts of emotional intelligence on organizational learning through cooperative culture.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14713_0fc41da772b6012efcfe77d245aa9886.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Conceptualizing Technology Management Based on Content Analysis and Clustering the Constructs of Definitions]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohammadi, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Roshani, Saeed]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rezaeinik, Nafiseh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2014]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technology Management Definitions]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[technology management aims]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[technology management processes]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[technology management nature]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This paper is focused on a systematic review of definitions offered in the literature of technology management and related concepts, such as the aims and processes of technology management. The reviews show that there is no consensus about definitions among researchers of this field, so it is necessary to propose an integrated definition for technology management. In this study, to identify researchers' approaches, we use a quantitative content analysis method for different technology management definitions. Also, NVIVO software is used to count the frequencies of words, and QDA miner software for clustering different definitions. According to the results, clustering different definitions of technology management indicates that there are at least three main approaches: 1) Goal-oriented definitions; 2) Nature-oriented definitions; and 3) Process-oriented definitions. Finally, after analyzing the content of the definitions, we propose a new and appropriate definition for technology management.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14714_b2a1c1275f1bf3551ba2ae5a40c5f61f.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>