<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the capabilities of the  SME firms in the formation and continuation of technological collaborations: a multi case study]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[samimi, ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[ghazinoori, soroush]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Moazzez, Hashem]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Keshmiri, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technological Collaborations]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Collaborations capabilities]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Collaborations Formation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Collaborations Continuity]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Today, the development of technological collaboration is one of the important strategies for developing resources, capabilities and gaining competitive advantage among organizations. This kind of collaboration among small and SME firms is important for creating significant effects on their success. One of the important pillars to create and maintain partnerships is to create the necessary capabilities to enter and use these collaborations. In this paper, we have tried to examine the various capabilities of several SME technology companies through interviews with corporate executives and partners, and studying documents and observation and by analyzing the theme, based on a few case studies. The results show that the capabilities required in collaborative technology in firms include four types of interoperability and continuity capabilities, product / service support capabilities, product / service collaboration support capabilities, and the same or complementary capabilities for collaboration that a set of The capabilities are based on the type of collaboration and its purpose in these sets. These capabilities are the basis for the formation and continuity of cooperation as well as the amount of operation and the result of cooperation for the firm.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_90183_c2ab84d13a439d27cdebacaa970c3de5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Exploration of Enablers for Complex Product Manufacturing; Identify, Prioritize and and Determine the Intermediate Relationships of Required Capabilities in Manufacturing of Complex Product Systems (COPS)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[karimi gavareshki, mohammad hosein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Gheidar-Kheljani, Jafar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Karimy, Pourya]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Complex Product Systems (CoPS)]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Capability]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Manufacturing]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[ANP]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[ISM]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Complex product systems (COPS) play an important role in industry, economics and technology of countries. On the other hand,Due to the complexity and the need for in depth and high level knowledge; organizations face challenges in Manufacturing and developing these products.To succeed in manufacturing of these products, organizations need to recognize the required capabilities.Therefore, the current research was conducted to identify the capabilities and enablers needed to manufacturing complex products And analyzes the causal relationships between these enablers.The other purpose of this study was to determine the importance of these factors for the accurate planning in the organization.For this purpose, with using the library studies and semi-structured interviews, the mentioned capabilities were identified and then validated by distributing the questionnaire. Eventually, 10 main factors and 46 sub-factors were identified. In the next step, with using Interpretative Structural Modeling (ISM) method , the relationships between these factors were determined and partitioned into four levels.Then ANP was used to determine the weights and ranking of factors.The research results show that networking capabilities, projects management, system integration and interactions at macro levels are the most important factors in manufacturing complex products and have underlying impacts on other factors. at the end of paper, after concluding the content, some suggestions were proposed for future research.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_90184_963eaa4c8082485ba74bc0519570e3ec.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Strategic Capabilities in the Oil and Gas Industry: A Study in the Midstream Sector]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Jalali, Seyed Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khalil Nezhad, Shahram]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[golmohammadi, emad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA['strategic capabilities]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[dynamic capability theory]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Competitive advantage]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Theme analysis]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[oil and gas industry']]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Different theories are presented by strategic management scholars and thinkers to explain how to achieve a competitive advantage, and dynamic capability theory which believed that gaining a competitive advantage is closely linked with organizational capabilities; is one of the clearest theories about competitive advantage in today's business world. In this regard, current research, based on dynamic capability view, employs a qualitative and explorative approach to identify and analyze of capabilities which influence the competitiveness and gaining competitive advantage in the midstream sector of oil and gas industry. In order to achieve this goal, data were gathered through 21 semi-structured interviews with top level managers of 6 refineries, integrated with comments of some experts, and analyzed by theme analysis method. Findings showed that gaining competitive advantage in the midstream of oil and gas industry rooted in both of inward capability of productivity and value-addition (products qualification, operational efficiency and technological capability) and outward capability of business strategic sustainability (business development, market orientation and sustainability of supply chain). This result reveals the importance of balanced approach in gaining competitive advantage in the oil and gas industry.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_90185_ef111ff8ecafb03b9840c9403ac19b79.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Role of knowledge management system and open innovation in developing innovation capacity]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Negarestani, Mahdieh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[knowledge management system]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation Capacity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Open Innovation]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The purpose of the study was to investigating the role of open innovation in the effect of knowledge management system on innovation capacity. The study population which was an applied and descriptive-survey research was composed of 177 managers of Companies in Industrial Town No. 2 &amp; companies in Kerman Science and Technology Park. The questionnaire was used to collect data.Validity and reliability of the questionnaire were verified and confirmed. After data analysis by Spss &amp; Amos, findings suggested that: knowledge management system had effect on open innovation andinnovation capacity. Also, the impact of knowledge management system on innovation capacity was mediated by open innovation.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_90186_f1450565ab2b48169db5855d6a6c4523.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Role of Organizational Resources and Innovation Capability in Creating the Competitive Advantage of Knowledge Based Companies: The moderating role of Technology Commercialization Performance]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shirazi, Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hashemzadeh, Gholamreza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[radfar, reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Torabi, Taghi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA["Organization Resource]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovative Capability]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technology Commercialization Performance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Competitive advantage]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Knowledge-Based Start-Up Companies"]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[knowledge-based companies can achieve competitive advantage through employing productivity from organizational resources and continuously upgrading innovation capability. In this regard, it is important to understand how the technology commercialization performance as the most important stage in technology management can moderating the impact of innovation capability and organizational resources on competitive advantage. Therefore, the purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of innovation capability and organizational resources on the competitive advantage of startup companies by considering the moderating variable of technology commercialization performance. The statistical population of This study was 166 top managers in growth stage of centers of growth of science and technology parks and the sample size was selected according to Cochran's formula by stratified random sampling method to ensure the retum of number of 128 respondents was completed. Finally, 117 questionnaires were collected and entered into the analysis stage. The present research is applied in a practical, descriptive and survey-oriented way. The results are extracted by structural equations modeling using partial least squares (by Smart PLS software). The findings show that innovation capabilitiy and organizational resources are effective on the competitive advantage of Knowledge Based Companies, as well as the moderating role of the technology commercialization performance in the impact of innovation capabilities and organizational resources on the competitive advantage.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_90187_c0ae26d8dc13c6790699c65bc4c938d9.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Foresight on the Impact of Convergent Technologies on Public Policies for Innovative capability Building]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Kargar Shouroki, Hedayat]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mirghafoori, seyed Habibollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Soltani, Ali Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Zare, Habib]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2019]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation Capability]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Public policies]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technological Convergence]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Convergent Technologies]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[NBIC]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Scenario-Building]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The present study attempts to introduce the role and function of the government in innovative capability building under the influence of the technological convergence flow as a foresight study and introduce the predictable futures of convergent technologies (NBIC). The approach of this research is qualitative and descriptive and has been used in morphological and scenario-building strategies. Thus, the most common mechanisms of public support in the process of innovation capability enhancement are identified and modeled; in parallel, the most important achievements of convergent technologies are derived from one of the valid models. Then, the intensity of the impacts of technological convergence on each aspect of governmental support is estimated through expert panel &amp; morphological analysis techniques. Finally, by implementing the scenario-building technique, three alternative scenarios of the future (including minimal, moderate, and maximum scenarios) are designed. The results show that by utilizing intelligently the revolutionary capacities of convergent technologies, the governments can establish the desirable future of the role of governance in development of innovative capabilities, and this position can be evolved strongly compared to the current situation.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_90188_48258bb8b993475858436445e8f897c8.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>