<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Entrepreneurship Training on Entrepreneurial Mindset: Mediating Role of Creativity and Entrepreneurial Alertness. (Organizations of MOD)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر آموزش کارآفرینی بر دستگاه فکری کارآفرینانه: نقش میانجی خلاقیت و هوشیاری کارآفرینانه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>73</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>100</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">57423</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدجواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>نائیجی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی،تهران،ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>ابراهیمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>11</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study aims to investigate the impact of entrepreneurship training on entrepreneurial mindset according to mediating role of creativity and entrepreneurial alertness. By Cochrane formula, 105 companies from 140 organizations of Ministry of Defence (MOD) have been selected randomly. The main tool for collecting data is questionnaire, which its level of validity and reliability has been acceptable for all structures. To analyze the data, structural simulating equations and Lisrel software is used. Results show that entrepreneurship training and creativity on the entrepreneurship mindset system is not effective, but entrepreneurship training on creativity and awareness is effective. Also, awareness plays the role of mediator in the relationship of entrepreneurship training and entrepreneurship mindset system.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی تأثیر آموزش کارآفرینی بر دستگاه فکری کارآفرینانه با توجه به نقش میانجی خلاقیت و هوشیاری کارآفرینانه است. جامعه آماری این پژوهش، مدیران ارشد 140 شرکت راهبردی کشور است که از این میان، 105 شرکت به عنوان نمونه مورد بررسی قرار گرفته‌اند. ابزار اصلی گردآوری داده‌ها، پرسشنامه است که سطح روایی و پایایی آن، برای تمامی سازه‌ها مورد قبول بوده است. به منظور تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها ، از روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری و نرم‌افزار لیزرل استفاده شده است. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که آموزش کارآفرینی و خلاقیت بر دستگاه فکری کارآفرینانه بی‌تأثیر است، اما آموزش کارآفرینی بر خلاقیت و هوشیاری تأثیر دارد. همچنین، هوشیاری نقش میانجی را در رابطه‌ی آموزش کارآفرینی و دستگاه فکری کارآفرینانه ایفا می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آموزش کارآفرینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خلاقیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوشیاری کارآفرینانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دستگاه فکری کارآفرینانه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_57423_b7e286e4aa1c570575f435a56a897e66.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
