<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effect of Regulatory Policies on the Innovation Capability of Iranian Pharmaceutical Companies</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اثر سیاست‌های تنظیمی بر توانمندی نوآوری بنگاه‌های تولید داروی ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>31</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>64</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60172</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>سلطان زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>الیاسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جهانیار</FirstName>
					<LastName>بامداد صوفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابوالفضل</FirstName>
					<LastName>کزازی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Many scholars focus on the effects of policies that make response to market failures and systems. To understand behaviour of the firm as a result of government interventions, they have tried to develop the concept of Behavioural Additionality (BA) in Innovation Policy Assessment. This research emphasis on the Innovation Capability and its Micro-Foundation as indicators of the firms behaviour that received less attention by scholars. Therefore, we attempt to evaluate the effects of three regulatory policies (Generic plan, Pricing system and Tariff system) on innovative behaviour (Innovation capability and Performance) in Iranian pharmaceutical companies. This study is a cross-sectional study which uses Multi-Case study strategy and cognitive-analytic tool, the effect of regulatory policies on three levels of five policy objectives (Market Expansion, Availability Enhancement, Quality Promotion, R&amp;D Motivation, and Value Chain Improvement), Micro-Foundation of Innovation Capability (Innovation Intelligence, Decision Making, Combination, and Governance) and Innovative Performance (Product and Process). Also, using the sensitivity analysis of the effects of the following 26 scenarios, the three levels of the component have been considered. The results show that although these policies are aimed at policy goals of Market Expansion, Availability Enhancement, and Value Chain Improvement, as well as on the process innovation, they have been able to create patterns in the innovation and management intelligence of firms, but their negative effects on Quality Promotion, R&amp;D Motivation as well as product innovation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">فهم اثر سیاست‌های وضع شده در پاسخ به شکست‌های بازار و سیستم همواره مورد توجه محققان بوده است. آنها در مسیر مطالعات خود تلاش کرده‌اند با توسعه مفهوم افزودنی رفتاری، نگاه خروجی محور به ارزیابی سیاست را بسط داده تا بتوانند اثر مداخلات دولت را بر رفتار بنگاه رصد نمایند. در این تحقیقات بر توانمندی نوآوری و خردبنیان‌های آن به عنوان مبین‌های رفتاری بنگاه در ارزیابی مداخلات کمتر تمرکز شده است. از اینرو پژوهش حاضر با تاکید بر توانمندی نوآوری به عنوان یک افزودنی رفتاری تلاش می‌کند، اثرات سه سیاست تنظیمی طرح ژنریک، نظام قیمت‌گذاری و نظام تعرفه‌ گمرکی را بر رفتار نوآوری در شرکت‌های تولید دارو بسنجد. پژوهش حاضر از دسته پژوهش‌های آمیخته با استفاده از استراتژی مطالعه چند موردی و ابزار تحلیلی نگاشت شناختی است که الگوی اثر سیاست‌های تنظیمی را در سه سطح اهداف سیاستی پنجگانه (گسترش بازار، افزایش دسترسی‌پذیری، ارتقای کیفیت، انگیزش تحقیق و توسعه و ارتقای زنجیره تولید)، خردبنیان‌های توانمندی نوآوری (هوش نوآوری، تصمیم‌گیری، ترکیب و راهبری) و عملکرد نوآورانه (محصول و فرآیند) ترسیم کرده است. همچنین با استفاده از تحلیل حساسیت اثرات ذیل 26 سناریو، چگونگی تغییرات سه سطح مولفه مورد توجه قرار گرفته‌اند. نتایج نشان می‌دهد هر چند اعمال این سیاست‌ها بر اهداف سیاستی گسترش بازار دارویی، دسترس‌پذیری و ارتقای زنجیره تولید دارویی کشور و همچنین بر نوآوری فرآیند مفید بوده و توانسته الگوهایی را در هوش نوآوری و راهبری شرکت‌ها ایجاد نماید اما اثر منفی آنها بر کیفیت دارو و انگیزش تحقیق و توسعه و همچنین نوآوری محصول و خردبنیان ترکیب قابل توجه است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاستهای تنظیمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزیابی مداخلات سیاستی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ابزارهای سیاستی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندی نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خردبنیان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60172_c4cdfd2c7a29f20bd937d21911a4b6c0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
