<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Exploring the Goals and Enablers of Participating in the Platform Ecosystem from the Supply-Side Innovators’ Perspective in Software Industry: Small Companies in Tehran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>واکاوی اهداف و توانمندسازهای مشارکت در زیست بوم پلتفرم از دیدگاه نوآوران طرف عرضه در صنعت نرم افزار: شرکت های کوچک مستقر در تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>65</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>86</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60176</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>یارمحمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهران</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضوانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمود</FirstName>
					<LastName>البرزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>30</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Supply-side innovators play an important role in the success of a platform and in increasing the number of its users. This paper takes on the perspective of the innovators and looks the goals they have in mind when participating in the platform ecosystem and the factors that enable this participation. This research is comprised of small Iranian companies in the software industry. This paper uses a qualitative approach and utilizes a multiple case study method. Data is collectd using 42 semi-structured interviews with 26 small companies that develop Android/ IOS- based applications. Secondary information, including news and interviews published in web concerning the innovation of the companies, is utilized as well, in order to supplement the interviews. The collected data is analyzed based on the qualitative content analysis method in the open coding and axial coding stages. The findings indicate that, the supply-side innovators’ goals in platform ecosystem participation, are as follows:, customer access, customer accountability, business expansion,credit increase, cost savings, and focus on innovation. Resource sharing, platform leadership, rules and regulations competency, maturity of investors and business partners are also, from the innovators&#039; perspective, identified as the main factors that enable the participation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">نوآوران طرف عرضه نقش مهمی در موفقیت پلتفرم‌ و افزایش تعداد کاربران آن ایفا می‌کنند. مطالعه حاضر با تمرکز بر دیدگاه این نوآوران قصد دارد اهداف آن‌ها از مشارکت در زیست‌بوم پلتفرم‌ و توانمندسازهای آن‌ها را واکاوی نماید. جامعه آماری این پژوهش را شرکت‌های کوچک ایران در صنعت نرم‌افزار تشکیل می‌دهند. رویکرد مقاله حاضر کیفی است و در آن از راهبرد پژوهشی مطالعه چند موردی اکتشافی استفاده شده است. گردآوری داده‌ها از طریق42 مصاحبه‌ نیمه‌ساخت‌یافته با 26 شرکت کوچک در حوزه توسعه برنامه‌های کاربردی مبتنی‌ بر پلتفرم‌های اندروید یا آی‌اُاِس انجام شده است. تحلیل داده‌های گردآوری شده در دو مرحله کدگذاری باز و کدگذاری محوری صورت پذیرفته است. یافته‌های پژوهش اهداف اصلی نوآوران طرف عرضه از مشارکت در زیست‌بوم پلتفرم را در شش مقوله، دسترسی به مشتریان، پاسخگویی به مشتریان، توسعه گستره کسب‌و‌کار، افزایش اعتبار، صرفه‌جویی در هزینه‌ها، و تمرکز بر نوآوری نشان می‌دهد. اشتراک‌گذاری منابع، رهبری پلتفرم، شایستگی قوانین و مقررات، و بلوغ شرکای تجاری و سرمایه‌گذاران نیز به‌عنوان توانمندسازهای اصلی مشارکت از دیدگاه این نوآوران محسوب می‌شوند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندسازها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زیستبوم پلتفرم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوران طرف عرضه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60176_78c3d8ae784ca4215d86762daee94f31.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
