<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Comparative Study of Innovation Modes and HR Configurations in Knowledge-Based Firms in Science and Technology Parks</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Vajhollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghorbanizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty of Management and Accounting, Allameh Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Rahele</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Montazer</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mirali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Seyed Nagavi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Davoud</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hosseinpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Human capital is one of the most important factors for innovation in companies. In this paper, we focus on two characteristics of human capital, i.e. uniqueness and value creation, to conduct a comparative study on the modes of innovation and human resource (HR) configurations in knowledge-based firms located in Pardis Technology Park and the University of Tehran Science and Technology Park. Managing human capital in innovative companies needs a set of HR practices suitable for work force characteristics and special aims of firm. In this study, we try to answer the question: Do knowledge-based firms choose their HR configuration according to their human capital characteristics and innovation mode? This study is a descriptive survey, with questionnaire as data collecting tool. We perform confirmatory factor analysis to assess the construct validity and model verification, and use binominal test to assess the level of coordination between the modes. In the first stage, the maximum level of coordination is identified between productivity-based HR system and market-oriented innovation, and in the next stage, the maximum coordination is between collaborative HR system and science-based innovation mode. Also, the average of value creation scores higher than uniqueness.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>22</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14844_050f4482bacd27960386681baec0bc9a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating the Formation Factors of Technological Spillovers Resulted from Foreign Direct Investment in Iran's Free Trade Zone</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahyar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khadem</namePart>
				<affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Razavi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Science and Research Branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Yeganehsadat</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Moosavi Jahromi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Payam-e-Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Technological spillover at micro-level has always been one of the main works of foreign direct investment. In this paper, we study spillovers and their determining factors in free trade zones. According to the conditions of Iran&#039;s free trade zones, technological spillovers in the form of vertical links are chosen as dependent variable and the factors determining technological spillovers, including research and development activities, the presence of qualified and skilled human resources, access to information and communication technologies, and centers for scientific and technical service are selected as independent variables. Due to the limited number of statistical samples, i.e. foreign investor companies in Iran&#039;s free trade zones, the method of partial least squares (PLS) is used to test the hypotheses. The results show that all these determinant factors have positive and significant impacts on promotion of vertical links in Iran&#039;s free trade zones.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>23</start>
					<end>46</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14857_10a183c178bd378d77a9c386a8a87771.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Designing a Capability-Based Model for Defense Need Assessment and Proposing a List of Defense Capability Components for Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Siamak</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azizzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malek Ashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fesharaki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malek Ashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Siamak</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tahmasebi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malek Ashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Mohammad Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghazanfari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malek Ashtar University of Technology,</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamidreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fartookzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malek Ashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Nowadays, need assessment is one of the most important inputs to defense acquisition systems in the world. Due to the dynamic, complex and uncertain nature of future environments, the classic approach of need assessment (threat-based) is not effective anymore, therefore, some countries have recently changed their approach from threat-based to capability-based. Using threat-based approach and lack of an integrated and comprehensive model for need assessment impose high costs on defense sector of our country. This study is aimed to present a comprehensive capability-based model for need assessment and extract likely capability components of the country. For this purpose, defensive information related to need assessment of the United States, Australia, Britain and Canada are collected, interpreted, compared and analyzed. Then, their need assessment models are investigated qualitatively by meta-synthesismethod, and finally a capability-based need assessment model is presented for defense field. Also, a list of capability components of the country is proposed.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>47</start>
					<end>74</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14901_46b81c01252e4dcc0f62cb70b5861206.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identifying Factors Affecting the Successful Transfer of Nanotechnology</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Morteza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Akbari</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Leila</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mehrabi Firozabad</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mobini Dehkordi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>For successful technology transfer, identifying Industry needs, required technologies, technological resources, transfer methods and its factors are necessary. The purpose of this study is to evaluate and prioritize factors affecting the successful transfer of nanotechnology as an issue concerning the development of Iran. We use an exploratory mixed method in this study and the statistical samples of the qualitative phase are academic and industrial experts of nanotechnology, selected with purposeful sampling until theoretical saturation point is reached. The samples of quantitative PHASE are 83 experts selected by simple random sampling. A semi-structured interview is conducted in the qualitative phase and a questionnaire in the quantitative phase. The collected data are analyzed by SPSS 18 software. According to the results, effective components include knowledge, organizational, technological, communicational, training human resources, and understanding physical environment. These factors have different significances in the receiver and provider organizations. Technological, organizational, knowledge, communicational, training human resources and understanding physical environment components have the highest priorities in the receiver organization, and technological, organizational, communicational, knowledge, understanding physical environment and training human resources have the highest in the provider organization.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>75</start>
					<end>96</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14903_859a8cf00ec651f5e45c73e703ff2ae6.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating the Role of Talent Management in Organization's Intellectual Capital Development: A Case Study of Iran's PANHA</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Davood</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hossinpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Manouchehr</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Manteghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malek Ashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sahar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Malekmohamadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The purpose of this study is to investigate the role of talent management in Iranian Helicopter Support and Renewal Company (PANHA) intellectual capital development. This study is based on a main hypothesis and three sub-hypothesis which measure the effects of talent management on three intellectual capital factors, including human capital, relational structural capital and organizational structural capital. A sample consisted of 158 individuals (118 talented staff, and 40 deputies and experts of the organization) is selected and analyzed by inferential statistics using descriptive-surveyed research approach. The data is collected using questionnaires. For data analysis, first, we assess the base validity of all indicators using confirmatory factor analysis, and then the research hypotheses are examined by fitted model and structural equations model. The research findings indicate that talent management has positive and meaningful effect on intellectual capital of PANHA. Among the three components of intellectual capital, talent management has also positive and meaningful effect on the two components of human capital and relational structural capital, but has no impact on organizational structural capital.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>97</start>
					<end>118</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14904_60844d7a70dc181aebb97c0df723e089.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Presenting a Model for Analyzing the Risks of Strategic and Technological Alliances</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Nima</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mokhtarzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shapor</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Keramat</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2015</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Technological alliance is an intelligence solution to obtaining the strategic goals of firms. While the trend of this type of collaboration is increasing, the failure rate is still high. The high rate of risk is due to the nature of internal cooperation of organizations in technological alliance. Most analytical methods and models consider the sources of risk in alliance process in two types: relational and functional risks. In this paper, the resources of risk are identified in the phases of strategic alliance process based on the literature. Then the level of importance of differenr phases of alliance and their influence on the success of alliance is weighted in a checklist by expert panel through Delphi technique. The method used in this study is design science with method output and design precision strategy using two Delphi panel rounds. The results show that risk factors in each phases of alliance are not the same and also the same risk factors in different phases of alliance process do not have the same weights. The aim of this paper is to present a flexible, dynamic and reliable method for alliance risk assessment, including identification, analysis and evaluation of risk resources. Proposing a structured method that can predict and estimate the level of risk for each phase of alliance based on the opinions of the employees and stakeholders of two sides of alliance is a significant result of this study.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>4</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2015</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>119</start>
					<end>140</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14905_6258eb20f9a24efb190934c2f4018904.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>