<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Effects of Organizational Health on Organizational Entrepreneurship with an Emphasis on the Mediatory Role of Creative Climate</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تاثیر سلامت سازمانی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی، نقش میانجی: جو خلاقیت</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>135</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>153</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14835</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>نصراصفهانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرخی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زینب</FirstName>
					<LastName>امیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه لرستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>روح الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>سلحشوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>پردیس البرز دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract> 
The concept of health in an organization points to the conditions that facilitate growth and development or stimulate organizational dynamics. Organizational health is not only the organization&#039;s ability to function effectively, but to continuously improve the organization&#039;s ability to grow. The purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of organizational health on organizational entrepreneurship with an emphasis on the mediatory variable of creative climate. This study is a practical in purpose and descriptive-survey in nature and methodology. The statistical population of the study includes 280 employees of Iran Chemical Industrial Investment Company. A standard questionnaire is used to collect data. Its validity is tested and confirmed by AVE index, and its reliability by composite reliability and Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient. Structural equation modelling is used to analyse the data in SmartPLS software. The results reveal that organizational health influences organizational entrepreneurship and creative climate. The results also show that creative climate influences organizational entrepreneurship significantly. On the other hand, it is revealed that creative climate can be considered as a mediating factor in the relationship between organizational health and organizational entrepreneurship.
 </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مفهوم سلامتی در یک سازمان توجه را به شرایطی جلب می‌کند که رشد و توسعه سازمان را تسهیل می‌نماید و یا موجب پویایی‌های سازمانی می‌شود. سلامت سازمانی تنها شامل توانایی سازمان برای انجام وظایف به طور موثر نیست، بلکه شامل توانایی سازمان برای رشد و بهبود مداوم است. هدف این پژوهش بررسی تاثیر سلامت سازمانی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی با متغیر میانجی جو خلاقیت می‌باشد. پژوهش حاضر از لحاظ ماهیت و روش توصیفی- پیمایشی و از لحاظ هدف از نوع کاربردی است. جامعه آماری پژوهش شامل280 نفر، کارکنان شرکت سرمایه‌گذاری صنایع شیمیایی ایران می‌باشد. برای‌ جمع‌آوری اطلاعات از ابزار پرسش‌نامه استفاده شد. جهت آزمون فرضیه‌های پژوهش مدل‌یابی معادلات ‌ساختاری با استفاده از نرم‌افزار SMART-PLS  انجام شد. نتایج حاصل از پژوهش نشان داد که سلامت سازمانی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی با شدت (414/0)، سلامت سازمانی بر جو خلاقیت با شدت (822/0) و همچنین جو خلاقیت بر کارآفرینی سازمانی با شدت (563/0) تاثیر دارد و در نهایت جو خلاقیت به‌عنوان میانجی در تاثیر سلامت سازمانی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی با شدت (462/0) تاثیرگذار است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جو سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرکت سرمایه گذاری صنایع شیمیایی ایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14835_6fb55f8b0625af6750300bd8d5705187.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
