<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Looking at the concept and dimensions of science and technology diplomacy: 
A meta-synthesis approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>واکاوی مفهوم و ابعاد دیپلماسی علم و فناوری مبتنی بر رویکرد فراترکیب</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>24</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">86887</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عفت</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوروزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>مشایخ</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>محسنی کیاسری</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In spite of the widespread attention of politicians and scholars in the field of science and technology diplomacy in recent years, it seems there is no consensus on this interdisciplinary concept. Naturally, understanding a concept and its constituent parts is necessary for deal with it wisely. In this paper, it has been attempted to provide a conceptual framework for the configuration of the science and technology diplomacy, using the meta-synthesis approach and the systematic analysis of scientific literature in this field. For this purpose, identifying 120 related sources and conducting the necessary methodological steps, 58 sources were finally analyzed. Meta-synthesis on previous studies shows that the developed academic concepts about science and technology diplomacy can be classified under the four main pillars including the what (nature), the why (purpose), the how (implementation considerations), and the which (outcomes and effects). Additionally, more details of the identified dimensions were extracted as subcategories. For example, the implications of science and technology diplomacy consist of sub-categories of diplomacy and foreign policy, science and technology, economics, security, and soft power. These different dimensions of science and technology diplomacy will provide scholars with a platform for the development of academic literature based on proposed dimensions and will provide policy makers and decision makers with a reasonable logic to begin planning and evaluating actions taken.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">علی‌رغم اقبال گسترده سیاستمداران و محققان طی سال‌های اخیر به موضوع دیپلماسی علم و فناوری، به نظر می‌رسد تلقی مشترکی از این مفهوم میان‌رشته‌ای حاصل نشده است. به‌طور طبیعی درک یک مفهوم و ابعاد تشکیل‌دهنده آن، برای مواجهه عالمانه‌ی با آن ضروری است. در این مقاله با استفاده از رویکرد فراترکیب تلاش شده است با تحلیل نظام‌مند ادبیات علمی این حوزه، یک چارچوب مفهومی برای پیکربندی موضوع دیپلماسی علم و فناوری ارائه شود. بدین منظور ضمن شناسایی 120 منبع مرتبط، پس از طی مراحل لازم، در نهایت 58 منبع مورد بررسی و تحلیل قرار گرفت. فراترکیب مطالعات پیشین نشان می‌دهد مفاهیم دانشی توسعه‌یافته حول موضوع دیپلماسی علم و فناوری را می‌توان ذیل چهار بعد اصلی چیستی (ماهیت)، چرایی (هدف)، چگونگی (ملاحظات پیاده‌سازی و اجرا) و پیامدها (اثرات) دسته‌بندی نمود. علاوه‌ بر این، جزییات دقیق‌تری از ابعاد شناسایی‌شده به‌صورت مقوله‌های فرعی استخراج گردید. به‌عنوان مثال، پیامدهای دیپلماسی علم و فناوری متشکل از مقوله‌های فرعی دیپلماسی و سیاست‌خارجی، علم و فناوری، اقتصاد، امنیت و قدرت نرم می‌باشد. این نوع ترسیم ابعاد مختلف دیپلماسی علم و فناوری، برای محققان و اندیشمندان، بستری برای توسعه‌ی ادبیات آکادمیک بر اساس ابعاد پیشنهادی فراهم خواهد نمود و برای سیاستگذاران و تصمیم‌گیران نیز منطقی کاربردی برای شروع برنامه‌ریزی و ارزیابی اقدامات انجام شده به دست می‌دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دیپلماسی علم و فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چارچوب مفهومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">میان‌رشته‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراترکیب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کدگذاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86887_8eb7ef190e60f49413e147728948ee23.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
