<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Model for Designing Communities of Practice based on Organizational Variables</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>الگوی طراحی ساختار اجتماعات کاری بر مبنای متغیرهای سازمان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>81</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>100</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14668</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالله</FirstName>
					<LastName>جاسبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>جاسبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد علوم و تحقیقات</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مصطفی</FirstName>
					<LastName>جعفری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پیمان</FirstName>
					<LastName>اخوان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>پیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علم و صنعت</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Communities of practice (CoP) are tools for exchanging best practices and a chance for increasing the level of individual and organizational learning. Developing these social structures has become a fundamental strategy for improving innovation process. Researchers and practitioners of knowledge management believe that managing CoPs in alignment with organizational goals will have favorable results for organization. Reviewing previous studies and experiences reveals that the relationships between organizational variables and CoPs designing and managing have not been investigated properly; that is the development of communities of practice has only been investigated as independent from organizational variables. This study aims to investigate the relationships between organizational variables and CoPs&#039; design elements, applying fuzzy method in the context of an industrial and strategic organization. The data is gathered through interviews with and questionnaires distributed among 11 experts in the aforementioned organization. The results show that 17 organizational variables have effects on 13 CoPs designing elements. Furthermore, the conceptual model of this study besides providing a pattern for managers to evaluate and select CoPs, clearly confirms the relationship between organizational variables and CoPs designing elements.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;اجتماعات کاری، ابزاری برای تبادل تجربه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های برتر و فرصتی برای افزایش سطح یادگیری فردی و سازمانی هستند. توسعه این ساختارهای اجتماعی، به یک راهبرد اساسی برای بهبود فرآیند نوآوری تبدیل شده است. محققان و فعالان مدیریت دانش اعتقاد دارند، مدیریت کردن اجتماعات کاری، همسو با اهداف سازمان، نتایج بسیار مطلوبی در فرآیند نوآوری سازمان خواهد داشت. بررسی پژوهش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های قبلی نشان می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;دهد که در توسعه و مدیریت اجتماعات کاری، روابط میان متغیرهای سازمانی و مولفه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های موثر در طراحی اجتماعات کاری بررسی نشده است. به عبارت دیگر، توسعه اجتماعات کاری مستقل از متغیرهای سازمانی بررسی شده است. از این رو پژوهش حاضر با هدف شناسایی روابط میان متغیرهای سازمانی و مولفه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های طراحی اجتماعات کاری انجام شد. بدین منظور پس از شناسایی 17 متغیر سازمانی و 13 مولفه مؤثر در طراحی اجتماعات کاری، روش دلفی فازی برای تبیین ارتباط میان این متغیرها مورد استفاده قرار گرفت. محدوده مطالعه این پژوهش، یک سازمان صنعتی راهبردی بود. داده&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های پژوهش با نظرخواهی و توزیع پرسش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;نامه میان 11 نفر از خبرگان سازمان مورد مطالعه جمع&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;آوری گردید. نتایج این پژوهش نشان می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;دهد 17 متغیر سازمانی شناسایی شده بر 13 مولفه طراحی اجتماعات کاری اثر گذار هستند. الگوی طراحی شده در این پژوهش، علاوه بر اینکه مبنای مناسبی برای ارزیابی و انتخاب اجتماعات کاری محسوب می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;شود، به روشنی روابط میان متغیرهای سازمانی و اجتماعات کاری را نیر مشخص می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;کند. &lt;/strong&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اجتماعات کاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوعشناسی اجتماعات کاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">متغیرهای سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دلفی فازی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14668_c687c5e212b0dbb653605fbc08023d8c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
