<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" "journalpublishing3.dtd">
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86887_8eb7ef190e60f49413e147728948ee23.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>واکاوی مفهوم و ابعاد دیپلماسی علم و فناوری مبتنی بر رویکرد فراترکیب</article-title>
			        <subtitle>واکاوی مفهوم و ابعاد دیپلماسی علم و فناوری مبتنی بر رویکرد فراترکیب</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نوروزی</surname>
			            <given-names>عفت</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مشایخ</surname>
			            <given-names>جواد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>محسنی کیاسری</surname>
			            <given-names>مصطفی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>23</day>
			        <month>08</month>
			        <year>2018</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>1</fpage>
			      <lpage>24</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>26</day>
			          <month>11</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>05</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86887.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86887.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>علی‌رغم اقبال گسترده سیاستمداران و محققان طی سال‌های اخیر به موضوع دیپلماسی علم و فناوری، به نظر می‌رسد تلقی مشترکی از این مفهوم میان‌رشته‌ای حاصل نشده است. به‌طور طبیعی درک یک مفهوم و ابعاد تشکیل‌دهنده آن، برای مواجهه عالمانه‌ی با آن ضروری است. در این مقاله با استفاده از رویکرد فراترکیب تلاش شده است با تحلیل نظام‌مند ادبیات علمی این حوزه، یک چارچوب مفهومی برای پیکربندی موضوع دیپلماسی علم و فناوری ارائه شود. بدین منظور ضمن شناسایی 120 منبع مرتبط، پس از طی مراحل لازم، در نهایت 58 منبع مورد بررسی و تحلیل قرار گرفت. فراترکیب مطالعات پیشین نشان می‌دهد مفاهیم دانشی توسعه‌یافته حول موضوع دیپلماسی علم و فناوری را می‌توان ذیل چهار بعد اصلی چیستی (ماهیت)، چرایی (هدف)، چگونگی (ملاحظات پیاده‌سازی و اجرا) و پیامدها (اثرات) دسته‌بندی نمود. علاوه‌ بر این، جزییات دقیق‌تری از ابعاد شناسایی‌شده به‌صورت مقوله‌های فرعی استخراج گردید. به‌عنوان مثال، پیامدهای دیپلماسی علم و فناوری متشکل از مقوله‌های فرعی دیپلماسی و سیاست‌خارجی، علم و فناوری، اقتصاد، امنیت و قدرت نرم می‌باشد. این نوع ترسیم ابعاد مختلف دیپلماسی علم و فناوری، برای محققان و اندیشمندان، بستری برای توسعه‌ی ادبیات آکادمیک بر اساس ابعاد پیشنهادی فراهم خواهد نمود و برای سیاستگذاران و تصمیم‌گیران نیز منطقی کاربردی برای شروع برنامه‌ریزی و ارزیابی اقدامات انجام شده به دست می‌دهد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>دیپلماسی علم و فناوری</kwd>
						<kwd>چارچوب مفهومی</kwd>
						<kwd>میان‌رشته‌ای</kwd>
						<kwd>فراترکیب</kwd>
						<kwd>کدگذاری</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Bandyopadhyay, m. Basu, S. (2014). Science and Technology Diplomacy in India Towards Achieving MDG 7 To Ensure Enviromental Sustainability. Centre for Science and Technology of the Non-Aligned and Other Developing Countries (Nam S&amp;T Centre), New Delhi, India. International Workshop on Perspectives on Science &amp; Technology Diplomacy for Sustainable Development in Nam and Other Developing Countries, 27-30 May 2014. PPT files.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Bench, S., &amp; Day, T. (2010). The user experience of critical care discharge: A meta-synthesis of qualitative research. International Journal of Nursing Studies, 47(4), 487-499. doi:10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2009.11.013.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Berg, Lutz-Peter. (2010), “Science Diplomacy Networks,” Swiss Sci. Diplomacy, Politorbis, Rev. Polit. étrangère, no. 49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Berkman, P. Balton, D. Dye, T. Gjerde, K. (2015). Transbpundary and Shared Resources.  Science Diplomacy2015: Scientific Drivers for Diplomacy. American Association for the Advancement of Science, April 29, 2015, Washington DC. PPT File.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Bondas, T., &amp; Hall, E. (2007). Challenges in Approaching Metasynthesis Research. The International Journal for Quality in Health Care, 17, 113-121.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Boutwell, J. (2015). Triangulating Science, Security and Society: Science Cooperation and International Security Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? (pp. 201-217): World Scientific..</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Carayanis, E. G. (2011), EU-US S&amp;T collaboration, challenges and opportunities for development, EURC ACES report.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Colglazier, William. (2012). Science and Diplomacy. Networks of Trust: Will the New Social Media Change Global Science? Proceedings of the 6th Forum on the Internationalization of Sciences and Humanities. Berlin.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Colglazier, W. (2016). Diplomacy for Science and Science for Sustainable Development. AAAS Center for Science Diplomacy, Washington DC, 8p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Congressional Research Service (1977). Science, Technology, and Diplomacy in the Age of Interdependence. Prepared for the Subcommittee on International Security and Scientific Affairs of the Committee on International Relations. US House of Representatives, by the Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress.(Washington, DC, 1976. Pp. xxi, 492.). American Journal of International Law, 71(2), 386-386.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Copeland, D. (2010). “A Role for Science Diplomacy? Soft Power and Global Challenges – Part I. Retrieved From: http://www.guerrilladiplomacy.com/2010/11/a-role-for-science-diplomacy-soft-power-and-global-challenges-part-i/.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Copeland, D. (2011). Science Diplomacy: What’s It All About. CEPI-CIPS Policy Brief (13), 1-4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Copeland, D. (2015). Science, Technology and WikiLeaks ‘Cablegate’: Implications for Diplomacy and International Relations Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? (pp. 171-198): World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Copeland, D. (2015). Bridging the Chasm: Why Science and Technology Must Become Priorities for Diplomacy and International Policy. Science &amp; Diplomacy, 4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>CSTI (2008). Toward the reinforcement of science diplomacy in japan. the Council for Science, Technology and Innovation, Tokyo.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Davis, L. S. (2015). Science diplomacy: new day or false dawn? : World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>DOĞAN, E. Ö. (2015). SCIENCE DIPLOMACY IN THE GLOBAL AGE: EXAMPLES FROM TURKEY AND THE WORLD (Doctoral dissertation, MIDDLE EAST TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Eivazi, M. R.  Moghaddam, M. H. (2014). "Islamic &amp; non Islamic Countries Cooperation: Perspective on Science Diplomacy Model". The Quarterly Journal of Political Studies of Islamic World. vol.2 (8), pp: 53-67.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>EU Commission for Research, Science and Innovation. (2015). Science diplomacy contributes to prosperity and stability in the Middle East. Research and Innovation, European Commission. Issue56. Page 4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Fedoroff, N. V. (2009). “Science diplomacy in the 21st century.,” Cell, vol. 136, no. 1, pp. 9–11.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Flink, T., &amp; Schreiterer, U. (2010). Science diplomacy at the intersection of S&amp;T policies and foreign affairs: toward a typology of national approaches. Science and Public Policy, 37(9), 665-677.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Gluckman, P.D., Turekian, V., Grimes, R.W. and Kishi, T. “Science Diplomacy: A Pragmatic Perspective from the Inside,” Science &amp; Diplomacy, Vol. 6, No. 4 (December 2017). http:// www.sciencediplomacy.org/article/2018/pragmatic-perspective.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Grübler, A. (2003). Technology and global change. Cambridge University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Hollander, Edwina. (2015), How Does Science Diplomacy Cope with Challenges Facing Diplomacy More Broadly? online article, Retrived from: http://www.e-ir.info/2015/08/30/how-does-science-diplomacy-cope-with-challenges-facing-diplomacy-more-broadly.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Hsu, J. 2011. Backdoor Diplomacy: How U.S. Scientists Reach Out to Frenemies. innovationnewsdaily, April 8. https://www.livescience.com/13638-science-diplomacy-soft-power.html.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Knorr-Cetina, K., 1983, "The ethnographic study of scientific work: towards a constructivist interpretation of science", In K.D. Knorr-cetina and M. Mulkay (eds.), science observed: perspectives on the social study of science, London, Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Khalil, T. M. 2000.Management of Technology: The Key to Competitiveness and Wealth Creation. New York: Irwin Mcgraw-Hill.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Koppelman, B., Day, N., Davison, N., Elliott, T., &amp; Wilsdon, J. (2010). New frontiers in science diplomacy: Navigating the changing balance of power.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Landis, J. R., &amp; Koch, G. G. (1977). The measurement of observer agreement for categorical data. biometrics, 159-174.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Leijten, J. (2017). Exploring the future of innovation diplomacy. European Journal of Futures Research, 5(1), 20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Lijesevic, J. (2010). “Science diplomacy at the heart of international relations,” E-international Relations, pp. 1–6, 2010. Retrieved From: http://www.e-ir.info/2010/04/01/science-diplomacy-at-the-heart-of-international-relations/.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Liu, E. T. (2015). Global Health Research Diplomacy Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? (pp. 219-229): World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>López de San Román, A., &amp; Schunz, S. (2018). Understanding European Union Science Diplomacy. JCMS: Journal of Common Market Studies, 56(2), 247-266.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Lowenthal, M. D. (2011). Science diplomacy for nuclear security. Special Report. United State Institue of Peace. Retrieved from: http://purl.fdlp.gov/GPO/gpo19355.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Milkoreit, M. (2015). Science and Climate Change Diplomacy: Cognitive Limits and the Need to Reinvent Science Communication Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? (pp. 109-131): World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Miremadi, T. (2016). A Model for Science and Technology Diplomacy: How to Align the Rationales of Foreign Policy and Science. Available at https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2737347.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Mupeyiwa, Clifford. (2014). Science and Technology Diplomacy; Impacts, Achievements, Opportunities and Challenge. Workshop of “Perspectives on Science &amp; Technology Diplomacy For Sustainable Development in NAM And Other Development Countries” Manesar (Haryana), India 27-30 May 2014, Retrieved From PPT Files.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Newsome, S. S. (2010). A case study in science and technology diplomacy: understanding diplomats' technical competency and interaction with technical experts (Doctoral dissertation, Massachusetts Institute of Technology).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Ngwenya, L. (2015). Case Study Report: science and technology diplomacy and the 2012-2013 German–South African Year of Science (Doctoral dissertation, University of Pretoria).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Norman, A. (1977). Science, Technology, and Diplomacy in the Age of Interdependence. Prepared for the Subcommittee on International Security and Scientific Affairs of the Committee on International Relations. US House of Representatives, by the Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress.(Washington, DC, 1976. Pp. xxi, 492.). American Journal of International Law, 71(2), 386-386.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Olugbemi, B. (2014) Nigeria’s Technical Aid Corps Scheme- A Model for Science and Technology Diplomacy in Developing Countries. Centre for Science and Technology of the Non-Aligned and Other Developing Countries (Nam S&amp;T Centre), New Delhi, India. International Workshop on Perspectives on Science &amp; Technology Diplomacy for Sustainable Development in Nam and Other Developing, Countries, 27-30 May 2014. PPT files.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Oshioluemoh, Victor. (2014). Science Diplomacy.Online Resource.National Daily Newspaper. Retrieved from: http://nationaldailyng.com/test/index.php/exclusive/mgt-and-diplomacy/870-science-diplomacy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Oxford. (2018). Oxford Dictionary.  Retrieved from http://www.oxforddictionaries.com/us/definition/american_english/diplomacy?q=diplomacy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Parliamentary Office of Science and Technology (2018), Science diplomacy, Westminster, London, POSTNOTE Number 568 February 2018.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Paterson, B. L. (2001). Meta-study of qualitative health research: A practical guide to meta-analysis and meta-synthesis Sage, 3.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Royal Society. (2010). New frontiers in science diplomacy: navigating the changing balance of power. RS Policy document/ science and diplomacy 01/10.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Ruffini, P. B. (2017). Science and Diplomacy A New Dimension of International Relations. Springer, Cham.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Sandelowski, M., &amp; Barroso, J. (2006). Handbook for synthesizing qualitative research: Springer Publishing Company.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Sandelowski, M., &amp; Barroso, J. (2007). Handbook for Synthesizing Qualitative Research. New York: Springer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Schlegel, F., Jacot, O., &amp; Fetscherin, M. (2011). Science diplomacy with swissnex China: A Swiss nation brand initiative. Place Branding and Public Diplomacy, 7(4), 289-298.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Science Diplomacy for France Report, French Ministry of Foreign Affairs, France, 2013, p.3. </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Scientific Exchanges and Research Department – SERD. (2013). “SCIENCE DIPLOMACY FOR FRANCE,” Scientific Exchanges and Research Department, MINISTERE DES AFFAIRES ETRANGERES, Scientific Exchanges and Research Department.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Sherwood, G. (1999). Meta-synthesis: Merging qualitative studies to develop nursing knowledge. International Journal for Human Caring, 3, 37-42.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation> Summers, J. A., Brotherson, M. J., Naig, L., Ethridge, B., Singer, G. H., Kruse, A., &amp; Wang, W. (2008, March). A preliminary synthesis of qualitative research: Gaining emotional well-being from other parents. Paper presented at the Beach Center on Disability State of the Science Conference, Washington, DC.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Sunami, A., Hamachi, T., and Kitaba, Sh. (2013). “The Rise of Science and Technology Diplomacy in Japan,” Science &amp; Diplomacy, Vol. 2, No. 1. Retrieved From: http://www.sciencediplomacy.org/article/2013/rise-science-and-technology-diplomacy-in-japan.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Tananbaum, Greg (2013) "I Hear the Train A Comin' -- Center for Science Diplomacy," Against the Grain: Vol. 20: Iss. 5, Article 40. Retrieved From: http://docs.lib.purdue.edu/atg/vol20/iss5/40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Turekian, V., &amp; Lord, K. M. (2009). The science of diplomacy. Foreign Policy, 5.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Turekian, V. C., Macindoe, S., Copeland, D., Davis, L. S., Patman, R. G., &amp; Pozza, M. (2015). The Emergence of Science Diplomacy Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? (pp. 3-24): World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Turekian V. C. (2015). A New Era for Science Diplomacy. Science Diplomacy: Scientific Drivers for Diplomacy. American Association for the Advancement of Science, April 29, 2015, Washington DC. PPT File.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>United Nations Conference on Trade and Development – UNCTAD. (2003), Science and Technology Diplomacy, Concepts and Elements of a Work Programme. United Nations. New York and Geneva.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Uygun, Z (2015), SCIENCE DIPLOMACY: A PROACTIVE POLICY APPROACH FOR INTERNATIONAL COOPERATION IN SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY AND AN ALTERNATIVE MODEL FOR TURKEY, IN FULFILLMENT OF THE REQUIREMENTS FOR THE DEGREE OF MASTER OF SCIENCE IN DEPARTMENT OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY POLICY STUDIES, MIDDLE EAST TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY    .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Van Langenhove, L. (2017). Tools for EU Science Diplomacy. Publications Office of the European Union, Brussels, 34p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Van Wyk, R. 2004. Technology: A Unifying Code: A Simple and Coherent View of Technology. Cape Town: StageMedia Group.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Walker, M. Karen. (2008). Science Diplomacy and Rhetoric-as-Epistemic: Finding Common Cause.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, T., C., (2013), the evolution and future of science diplomacy: A U.S. Perspective, Workshop on science diplomacy, university of Tokyo, by American Association for Advancement of science.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Wilson, G. (2015). Antarctic Science: A Case for Extending Diplomacy for Science Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? (pp. 69-85): World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Yakushiji, Taizo. (2009). the Potential of Science and Technology Diplomacy, Asia-Pacific Review, 16:1, 1-7, DOI: 10.1080/13439000902957640.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Zimmer, L. (2006). Qualitative meta-synthesis: a question of dialoguing with texts. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 53(3), 311-318. doi:10.1111/j.1365-2648.2006.03721.x</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Zolfagharzadeh, M. M., Aslani, A., Sadabadi, A. A., Sanaei, M., Lesan Toosi, F., &amp; Hajari, M. (2017). Science and technology diplomacy: a framework at the national level. Journal of Science and Technology Policy Management, 8(2), 98-128.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>احمدی، مهدی و زیبا کلام، سعید (1390) ، "رابطه علم و فناوری: طرح و نقد الگوی فناوری به مثابه علم کاربردی"، فصلنامه سیاست علم و فناوری، شماره 3.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>براتی، م. (1389). دیپلماسی علم و فناوری چیست؟ قابل دسترس در:http://itan.ir/9567</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>پژوهشکده سیاستگذاری علم، فناوری و صنعت دانشگاه صنعتی شریف (1392). تجربیات بیست نفر از مدیران و مشاوران معاونت علمی و فناوری رئیس‌جمهور (1386-1392). چاپ اول</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>داودی. (2015). دیپلماسی علم و فناوری ایران در افغانستان: فرصت‌ها و چالش‌ها. پژوهش های راهبردی سیاست, 3(11), 103-127.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>دیویس،ل. و پتمن،ر. (1396). دیپلماسی علم: روزی نو یا صبحی کاذب، ترجمه‌ی مشایخ، ج.، نوروزی، ع. و صارمی،س.، تهران، انتشارات رسا.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>ذوالفقارزاده، م.، و ثنایی، م. (1392)، دیپلماسی علم و فناوری: چارچوبی نظری و پیشنهادهایی عملی، رهیافت، شماره 54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>ذوالفقارزاده، م.، و هاجری، م. (1395)، شناسایی ابعاد و مؤلفه‌های مؤثر بر توسعه دیپلماسی علم و فناوری کشور: پژوهشی مبتنی بر روش تحلیل مضمون، سیاست نامه علم و فناوری، سال ششم، شماره 2.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>ذوالفقارزاده, م. م. و هاجری, م. (1396). ارائه چارچوبی برای توسعه دیپلماسی علم و فناوری کشور به روش دلفی فازی. سیاست علم و فناوری, 35(9), 1-17.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>سجادپور, م. و نگین‌راز, پ. (2014). بایسته‌ها در مدل ارزیابی تکنیک دیپلماسی مسیر دوم. فصلنامه سیاست خارجی, 28(2), 213-236.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>شبکه تحلیل‌گران تکنولوژی ایران – ایتان (1390). بررسی مفهومی دیپلماسی علم و فناوری و ترسیم وضع موجود آن در جمهوری اسلامی ایران. معاونت علمی و فناوری ریاست جمهوری.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>صدوق، سیدمحمود (1394). طراحی مدل بومی توسعه دیپلماسی علم و فناوری در کشور. پایان‌نامه منتشر نشده‌ی کارشناسی ارشد. دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>صنیع اجلال, م. (1395). رویکردی میان‌رشته‌ای به نقش دیپلماسی در سیاستگذاری علم و فنّاوری در ایران. مطالعات میان رشته ای در علوم انسانی, 9(3), 125-148. doi:10.22631/isih.2017.2592.2992</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>صنیع اجلال، م. (1396)، دیپلماسی علم فناوری: راهبردی نو در توسعه کشورهای اسلامی، فصلنامه مطالعات سیاسی جهان اسلام، سال ششم، شماره 23.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>عبدالحسین‌زاده، م. (1394)، رویکردهای جدید در دیپلماسی علم و فناوری، نشریه نشاء علم، سال ششم ،شماره اول</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>قدیمی, اکرم. منوچهری قشقایی, آزیتا. (1392). چیستی دیپلماسی علم و فناوری. فصلنامه ترویج علم. سال 4، شمار 4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>قدیمی، ا. (1396)، کارکرد دیپلماسی علم و فناوری در جمهوری اسلامی ایران و ایالات متحدة آمریکا، فصلنامه سیاست، مجلة دانشکده حقوق و علوم سیاسی، دوره 47 ، شماره 1.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>لرستانی، سعیده و رحیمی راد، زهره (1393)، نوع شناسی دیپلماسی علم و فناوری در ایران: یک نقد و بررسی، چهارمین کنفرانس بین المللی و هشتمین کنفرانس ملی مدیریت فناوری.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>مقیمی، طلیعه؛ آراسته، حمیدرضا؛ و محمدخانی، کامران (1395)، مدل پیشبرد دیپلماسی علم و فناوری در کشور از زاویه مطالعات میان رشته ای نظامهای آموزش عالی و سیاست خارجی؛ مورد مطالعه، دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیرالدین طوسی. فصلنامه مطالعات میان رشته‌ای در علوم انسانی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>میرعمادی، ط.، شریعتی نیا، م.، دهقان،م.ج. وعرب،م. (1392). "دیپلماسی فناوری رژیم اشغالگر قدس"، مرکز پژوهش‌های سیاستگذاری و دیپلماسی علم و فناوری، سازمان پژوهش‌های علمی و صنعتی ایران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>میرعمادی، طاهره (1394)، مدل تحلیل دیپلماسی علم و فناوری در یک کشور، فصلنامه علمی ترویجی رهیافت، شماره 59.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>موسوی موحد، ع. ا. کیانی بختیاری، ا. (1392). “دیپلماسی علمی و فناوری". نشاء علم.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>هادیان، ناصر. (1392). "انتظار جامعه علمی از دستگاه دیپلماسی کشور". چهارشنبه ۳۰ مرداد.مصاحبه.  قابل دسترس در:http://www.cgie.org.ir/fa/news/_||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Ahmadi, M. and Zibakalam, S. (2011), Science-Technology Relationship: Reconstruction and Critique of “Technology as Applied Science” Model, Science and technology policy, No. 4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Barati, M. (2010), what is science and technology diplomacy, available at: http://itan.ir/9567?</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Bandyopadhyay, m. Basu, S.,2014. Science and Technology Diplomacy in India Towards Achieving MDG 7 To Ensure Enviromental Sustainability. Centre for Science and Technology of the Non-Aligned and Other Developing Countries (Nam S&amp;T Centre), New Delhi, India. International Workshop on Perspectives on Science &amp; Technology Diplomacy for Sustainable Development in Nam and Other Developing Countries, pp. 27-30 May 2014. PPT files.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Bench, S., &amp; Day, T.,2010. The user experience of critical care discharge: A meta-synthesis of qualitative research. International Journal of Nursing Studies, 47(4), pp. 487-499. doi:10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2009.11.013.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Berg, Lutz-Peter.,2010. “Science Diplomacy Networks,” Swiss Sci. Diplomacy, Politorbis, Rev. Polit. étrangère, no. 49.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Berkman, P. Balton, D. Dye, T. Gjerde, K.,2015. Transbpundary and Shared Resources.  Science Diplomacy2015: Scientific Drivers for Diplomacy. American Association for the Advancement of Science, April 29, 2015, Washington DC. PPT File.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Bondas, T., &amp; Hall, E.,2007. Challenges in Approaching Metasynthesis Research. The International Journal for Quality in Health Care, Volume(17), pp. 113-121.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Boutwell, J.,2015. Triangulating Science, Security and Society: Science Cooperation and International Security Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? (pp. 201-217): World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Carayanis, E. G.,2011, EU-US S&amp;T collaboration, challenges and opportunities for development, EURC ACES report.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Colglazier, William.,2012. Science and Diplomacy. Networks of Trust: Will the New Social Media Change Global Science? Proceedings of the 6th Forum on the Internationalization of Sciences and Humanities. Berlin.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Colglazier, W., 2016. Diplomacy for Science and Science for Sustainable Development. AAAS Center for Science Diplomacy, Washington DC, 8p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Congressional Research Service., 1977. Science, Technology, and Diplomacy in the Age of Interdependence. Prepared for the Subcommittee on International Security and Scientific Affairs of the Committee on International Relations. US House of Representatives, by the Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress.(Washington, DC, 1976. Pp. xxi, 492.) American Journal of International Law, 71(2), pp. 386-386.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Copeland, D., 2010. “A Role for Science Diplomacy? Soft Power and Global Challenges – Part I. Retrieved From: http://www.guerrilladiplomacy.com/2010/11/a-role-for-science-diplomacy-soft-power-and-global-challenges-part-i/.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Copeland, D., 2011. Science Diplomacy: What’s It All About? CEPI-CIPS Policy Brief (13), pp. 1-4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Copeland, D., 2015. Science, Technology and WikiLeaks ‘Cablegate’: Implications for Diplomacy and International Relations Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? (pp. 171-198): World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Copeland, D., 2015. Bridging the Chasm: Why Science and Technology Must Become Priorities for Diplomacy and International Policy. Science &amp; Diplomacy, Volume(4).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>CSTI., 2008. Toward the reinforcement of science diplomacy in japan. the Council for Science, Technology and Innovation, Tokyo.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Davis, L. S., 2015.Science diplomacy: new day or false dawn?: World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Davoodi, A. (2015), the Iranian Science and Technology Diplomacy in Afghanistan: Challenges and Opportunities, Strategic Research of Politics, 3(11).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>Davis, L. and Patmant, R. (2017), Science diplomacy: new day or false dawn, Rasa Publication, Tehran, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>DOĞAN, E. Ö., 2015. SCIENCE DIPLOMACY IN THE GLOBAL AGE: EXAMPLES FROM TURKEY AND THE WORLD (Doctoral dissertation, MIDDLE EAST TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Eivazi, M. R. Moghaddam, M. H., 2014. "Islamic &amp; non Islamic Countries Cooperation: Perspective on Science Diplomacy Model". The Quarterly Journal of Political Studies of Islamic World.2 (8), pp: 53-67.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>EU Commission for Research, Science and Innovation., 2015. Science diplomacy contributes to prosperity and stability in the Middle East. Research and Innovation, European Commission. Issue56. Page 4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R115">
			<label>115</label>
			<element-citation>Fedoroff, N. V., 2009. “Science diplomacy in the 21st century.” Cell, 136(1), pp. 9–11.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R116">
			<label>116</label>
			<element-citation>Flink, T., &amp; Schreiterer, U., 2010. Science diplomacy at the intersection of S&amp;T policies and foreign affairs: toward a typology of national approaches. Science and Public Policy, 37(9), pp. 665-677.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R117">
			<label>117</label>
			<element-citation>Gluckman, P.D., Turekian, V., Grimes, R.W. and Kishi, T., 2017. “Science Diplomacy: A Pragmatic Perspective from the Inside,” Science &amp; Diplomacy, 6(4), (December 2017). http:// www.sciencediplomacy.org</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R118">
			<label>118</label>
			<element-citation>Grübler, A., 2003. Technology and global change. Cambridge University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R119">
			<label>119</label>
			<element-citation>Hadian, N. (2012). "Expecting the scientific community from the country's diplomacy apparatus". Wednesday 30 August. An interview. Available at: http://www.cgie.org.ir/fa/news.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R120">
			<label>120</label>
			<element-citation>Hollander, Edwina., 2015, How Does Science Diplomacy Cope with Challenges Facing Diplomacy More Broadly? Online article, Retrived from: http://www.e-ir.info/2015/08/30/how-does-science-diplomacy-cope-with-challenges-facing-diplomacy-more-broadly.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R121">
			<label>121</label>
			<element-citation>Hsu, J., 2011. Backdoor Diplomacy: How U.S. Scientists Reach Out to Frenemies. innovationnewsdaily, April 8. https://www.livescience.com/13638-science-diplomacy-soft-power.html.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R122">
			<label>122</label>
			<element-citation>Knorr-Cetina, K., 1983, "The ethnographic study of scientific work: towards a constructivist interpretation of science", In K.D. Knorr-cetina and M. Mulkay (eds.), science observed: perspectives on the social study of science, London, Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R123">
			<label>123</label>
			<element-citation>Khalil, T. M., 2000.Management of Technology: The Key to Competitiveness and Wealth Creation. New York: Irwin Mcgraw-Hill.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R124">
			<label>124</label>
			<element-citation>Koppelman, B., Day, N., Davison, N., Elliott, T., &amp; Wilsdon, J., 2010. New frontiers in science diplomacy: Navigating the changing balance of power.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R125">
			<label>125</label>
			<element-citation>Landis, J. R., &amp; Koch, G. G., 1977. The measurement of observer agreement for categorical data. biometrics, pp. 159-174.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R126">
			<label>126</label>
			<element-citation>Leijten, J., 2017. Exploring the future of innovation diplomacy. European Journal of Futures Research, 5(1), 20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R127">
			<label>127</label>
			<element-citation>Lijesevic, J.,2010. “Science diplomacy at the heart of international relations,” E-international Relations, pp. 1–6, 2010. Retrieved From: http://www.e-ir.info/2010/04/01/science-diplomacy-at-the-heart-of-international-relations/.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R128">
			<label>128</label>
			<element-citation>Liu, E. T., 2015. Global Health Research Diplomacy Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? (pp. 219-229): World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R129">
			<label>129</label>
			<element-citation>López de San Román, A., &amp; Schunz, S., 2018. Understanding European Union Science Diplomacy. JCMS: Journal of Common Market Studies, 56(2), pp. 247-266.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R130">
			<label>130</label>
			<element-citation>Lorestani, S. and Rahimi Rad, Z. (2012), Typology of Diplomacy of Science and Technology in Iran: A Review, Fourth International Conference and 8th National Conference on Technology Management.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R131">
			<label>131</label>
			<element-citation>Lowenthal, M. D., 2011. Science diplomacy for nuclear security. Special Report. United State Institue of Peace. Retrieved from: http://purl.fdlp.gov/GPO/gpo19355.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R132">
			<label>132</label>
			<element-citation>Milkoreit, M., 2015. Science and Climate Change Diplomacy: Cognitive Limits and the Need to Reinvent Science Communication Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? (pp. 109-131): World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R133">
			<label>133</label>
			<element-citation>Miremadi, T., 2016. A Model for Science and Technology Diplomacy: How to Align the Rationales of Foreign Policy and Science. Available at https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2737347.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R134">
			<label>134</label>
			<element-citation>Miramadi, T., Shariatiya, M., Dehghan, M.J. and Arab, M. (2011). "Diplomacy of technology in Israel", Research and Policy Research Center, Science and Technology Diplomacy, Iranian Scientific and Industrial Research Organization.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R135">
			<label>135</label>
			<element-citation>Miramadi, T. (2014), Model of the Analysis of the Diplomacy of Science and Technology in a Country, Rahyaft Journal, No. 59.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R136">
			<label>136</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammad Kazem Sajjadpour; Parvin Negin-Raz (2014), The Essentialities of the Model for Assessing Track Two Diplomacy Techniques, Journal of foreign policy, 28(2).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R137">
			<label>137</label>
			<element-citation>Moghimi, T., Arasteh, H., and Mohammad Khani, K. (2014), The Model of Advancing the Diplomacy of Science and Technology in the Country from the Point of View of the Interdisciplinary Studies of Higher Education Systems and Foreign Policy; Case Study, Khaje Nasir-Al-Din Tusi University of Technology. Journal of Interdisciplinary Studies in the Humanities.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R138">
			<label>138</label>
			<element-citation>Mousavi Movahed, AS. and Kiani Bakhtiari, A. (2011). "Scientific and Technological Diplomacy", journal of nesha elm.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R139">
			<label>139</label>
			<element-citation>Mupeyiwa, Clifford., 2014. Science and Technology Diplomacy; Impacts, Achievements, Opportunities and Challenge. Workshop of “Perspectives on Science &amp; Technology Diplomacy For Sustainable Development in NAM And Other Development Countries” Manesar (Haryana), India 27-30 May 2014, Retrieved From PPT Files.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R140">
			<label>140</label>
			<element-citation>Network of Iranian Technology Analysts (2011), Conceptual study of science and technology diplomacy and its current status in the Islamic Republic of Iran, Vice Presidency of Science and Technology.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R141">
			<label>141</label>
			<element-citation>Newsome, S. S., 2010. A case study in science and technology diplomacy: understanding diplomats' technical competency and interaction with technical experts (Doctoral dissertation, Massachusetts Institute of Technology).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R142">
			<label>142</label>
			<element-citation>Ngwenya, L., 2015. Case Study Report: science and technology diplomacy and the 2012-2013 German–South African Year of Science (Doctoral dissertation, University of Pretoria).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R143">
			<label>143</label>
			<element-citation>Norman, A., 1977. Science, Technology, and Diplomacy in the Age of Interdependence. Prepared for the Subcommittee on International Security and Scientific Affairs of the Committee on International Relations. US House of Representatives, by the Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress.(Washington, DC, 1976. Pp. xxi, 492.). American Journal of International Law, 71(2), pp. 386-386.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R144">
			<label>144</label>
			<element-citation>Olugbemi, B., 2014. Nigeria’s Technical Aid Corps Scheme- A Model for Science and Technology Diplomacy in Developing Countries. Centre for Science and Technology of the Non-Aligned and Other Developing Countries (Nam S&amp;T Centre), New Delhi, India. International Workshop on Perspectives on Science &amp; Technology Diplomacy for Sustainable Development in Nam and Other Developing, Countries, pp. 27-30 May 2014. PPT files.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R145">
			<label>145</label>
			<element-citation>Oshioluemoh, Victor., 2014. Science Diplomacy.Online Resource.National Daily Newspaper. Retrieved from: http://nationaldailyng.com/test/index.php/exclusive/mgt-and-diplomacy/870-science-diplomacy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R146">
			<label>146</label>
			<element-citation>Oxford., 2018. Oxford Dictionary. Retrieved from http://www.oxforddictionaries.com.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R147">
			<label>147</label>
			<element-citation>Parliamentary Office of Science and Technology., 2018, Science diplomacy, Westminster, London, POSTNOTE Number 568 February 2018.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R148">
			<label>148</label>
			<element-citation>Paterson, B. L., 2001. Meta-study of qualitative health research: A practical guide to meta-analysis and meta-synthesis Sage, 3.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R149">
			<label>149</label>
			<element-citation>Qadimi, A. and Manuchehri Qashqai, A. (2011). What is the science and technology diplomacy. Quarterly Journal of Science Promotion. Year 4, No. 4.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R150">
			<label>150</label>
			<element-citation>Qadimi, A. (2015), The Function of Science and Technology Diplomacy in the Islamic Republic of Iran and the United States, Journal of Law and Political Science, 47(1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R151">
			<label>151</label>
			<element-citation>Research Institute of Science, Technology and Industry Policy of Sharif University of Technology (2013), the experiences of twenty directors and advisors of the Vice President of Science and Technology, first edition.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R152">
			<label>152</label>
			<element-citation>Royal Society., 2010. New frontiers in science diplomacy: navigating the changing balance of power. RS Policy document/ science and diplomacy 01/10.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R153">
			<label>153</label>
			<element-citation>Ruffini, P. B., 2017. Science and Diplomacy A New Dimension of International Relations. Springer, Cham.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R154">
			<label>154</label>
			<element-citation>Sadouq, M. (2016) Designing a native model for the development of science and technology diplomacy in the country, Unpublished Master's thesis, Iran University of Science and Technology.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R155">
			<label>155</label>
			<element-citation>Saniejlal, M. (2017), a multidisciplinary approach to diplomacy role in science and technology development policy in Iran: a case study, Journal of interdisciplinary studies in Humanities, 9(3).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R156">
			<label>156</label>
			<element-citation>Saniejlal, M. (2017), Diplomacy of Science and Technology: A New Strategic Plan for the Development of Islamic Countries, Islamic World Political Studies, 6(3).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R157">
			<label>157</label>
			<element-citation>Abdul Husseinzadeh, M. (2015), New Approaches to the Diplomacy of Science and Technology, journal of nesha elm, year 6, No.1.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R158">
			<label>158</label>
			<element-citation>Sandelowski, M., &amp; Barroso, J., 2006. Handbook for synthesizing qualitative research: Springer Publishing Company.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R159">
			<label>159</label>
			<element-citation>Sandelowski, M., &amp; Barroso, J., 2007. Handbook for Synthesizing Qualitative Research. New York: Springer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R160">
			<label>160</label>
			<element-citation>Schlegel, F., Jacot, O., &amp; Fetscherin, M., 2011. Science diplomacy with swissnex China: A Swiss nation brand initiative. Place Branding and Public Diplomacy, 7(4), 289-298.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R161">
			<label>161</label>
			<element-citation>Science Diplomacy for France Report, French Ministry of Foreign Affairs, France, 2013, p.3.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R162">
			<label>162</label>
			<element-citation>Scientific Exchanges and Research Department – SERD., 2013. “SCIENCE DIPLOMACY FOR FRANCE,” Scientific Exchanges and Research Department, MINISTERE DES AFFAIRES ETRANGERES, Scientific Exchanges and Research Department.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R163">
			<label>163</label>
			<element-citation>Sherwood, G.,1999. Meta-synthesis: Merging qualitative studies to develop nursing knowledge. International Journal for Human Caring, Volume(3), pp. 37-42.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R164">
			<label>164</label>
			<element-citation> Summers, J. A., Brotherson, M. J., Naig, L., Ethridge, B., Singer, G. H., Kruse, A., &amp; Wang, W.,2008. A preliminary synthesis of qualitative research: Gaining emotional well-being from other parents. Paper presented at the Beach Center on Disability State of the Science Conference, Washington, DC.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R165">
			<label>165</label>
			<element-citation>Sunami, A., Hamachi, T., and Kitaba, Sh., 2013. “The Rise of Science and Technology Diplomacy in Japan,” Science &amp; Diplomacy, 2(1). Retrieved From: http://www.sciencediplomacy.org/article/2013/rise-science-and-technology-diplomacy-in-japan.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R166">
			<label>166</label>
			<element-citation>Tananbaum, Greg., 2013."I Hear the Train A Comin' - Center for Science Diplomacy," Against the Grain: Vol. 20: Iss. 5, Article 40. Retrieved From: http://docs.lib.purdue.edu/atg/vol20/iss5/40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R167">
			<label>167</label>
			<element-citation>Turekian, V., &amp; Lord, K. M., 2009. The science of diplomacy. Foreign Policy, 5.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R168">
			<label>168</label>
			<element-citation>Turekian, V. C., Macindoe, S., Copeland, D., Davis, L. S., Patman, R. G., &amp; Pozza, M., 2015. The Emergence of Science Diplomacy Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? (pp. 3-24): World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R169">
			<label>169</label>
			<element-citation>Turekian V. C., 2015. A New Era for Science Diplomacy. Science Diplomacy: Scientific Drivers for Diplomacy. American Association for the Advancement of Science, April 29, 2015, Washington DC. PPT File.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R170">
			<label>170</label>
			<element-citation>United Nations Conference on Trade and Development – UNCTAD., 2003, Science and Technology Diplomacy, Concepts and Elements of a Work Programme. United Nations. New York and Geneva.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R171">
			<label>171</label>
			<element-citation>Uygun, Z., 2015, Science Diplomacy: A Proactive Policy Approach For International Cooperation In Science And Technology And An Alternative Model For Turkey, In Fulfillment Of the Requirements For The Degree Of Master Of Science In Department Of Science And Technology Policy Studies, Middle East Technical University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R172">
			<label>172</label>
			<element-citation>Van Langenhove, L., 2017. Tools for EU Science Diplomacy. Publications Office of the European Union, Brussels, 34p.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R173">
			<label>173</label>
			<element-citation>Van Wyk, R., 2004. Technology: A Unifying Code: A Simple and Coherent View of Technology. Cape Town: StageMedia Group.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R174">
			<label>174</label>
			<element-citation>Walker, M. Karen., 2008. Science Diplomacy and Rhetoric-as-Epistemic: Finding Common Cause.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R175">
			<label>175</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, T., C., 2013. the evolution and future of science diplomacy: A U.S. Perspective, Workshop on science diplomacy, university of Tokyo, by American Association for Advancement of science.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R176">
			<label>176</label>
			<element-citation>Wilson, G., 2015. Antarctic Science: A Case for Extending Diplomacy for Science Science Diplomacy: New Day or False Dawn? (pp. 69-85): World Scientific.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R177">
			<label>177</label>
			<element-citation>Yakushiji, Taizo.,2009. the Potential of Science and Technology Diplomacy, Asia-Pacific Review, 16:1, 1-7, DOI: 10.1080/13439000902957640.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R178">
			<label>178</label>
			<element-citation>Zimmer, L., 2006. Qualitative meta-synthesis: a question of dialoguing with texts. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 53(3), 311-318. doi:10.1111/j.1365-2648.2006.03721.x</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R179">
			<label>179</label>
			<element-citation>Zolfagharzadeh, M. M., Aslani, A., Sadabadi, A. A., Sanaei, M., Lesan Toosi, F., &amp; Hajari, M., 2017. Science and technology diplomacy: a framework at the national level. Journal of Science and Technology Policy Management, 8(2), pp. 98-128 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R180">
			<label>180</label>
			<element-citation>Zolfagharzadeh, M. and Sanaei, M. (2013), Science and Technology Diplomacy:Theoretical framework and practical suggestions, 23(54).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R181">
			<label>181</label>
			<element-citation>Zolfagharzadeh, M. and Hajari, M. (2016), Identifying the Aspects and Affecting Factors on Science and Technology Diplomacy Development: a Research Based on Thematic Analysis, Science and technology policy letters, 6(2).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R182">
			<label>182</label>
			<element-citation>Zolfagharzadeh, M. and Hajari, M. (2017), A Framework of Science and Technology Diplomacy Development Based on Fuzzy Delphi Method, Science and technology policy, 9(3).</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86885_df5cd4e0d2913fdf04f84f6bd17f19eb.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>موانع نوآوری</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>برهم‌کنش سکوت سازمانی و نوآوری در سازمان‌های بخش عمومی: مطالعه‌ای درباره کارکنان دانشی دانشکده‌های علوم انسانی استان تهران</article-title>
			        <subtitle>بر هم کنش سکوت سازمانی و نوآوری در سازمان‌های بخش عمومی</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نوروزی</surname>
			            <given-names>خلیل</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دکترای سیاست گذاری علم و فناوری، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، ایران.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>صادقی کیا</surname>
			            <given-names>محمدعلی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناس ارشد سیاست‌گذاری عمومی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه امام صادق (ع)، تهران، ایران.</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>23</day>
			        <month>08</month>
			        <year>2018</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>25</fpage>
			      <lpage>46</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>29</day>
			          <month>07</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>31</day>
			          <month>12</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86885.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86885.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>نوآوری با اطلاعات سروکار دارد و موفقیت آن متوقف به جریان مطلوبی از اطلاعات و ارتباطات است. در این میان، آن چه جریان دانش و اطلاعات را مختل می‌کند، سکوت سازمانی است. سکوت سازمانی، پدیده‌ای است که طی آن، کارکنان به صورت آگاهانه از اظهار نظرها، نقدها، پیشنهادها و در کل از تسهیم دانش و اطلاعات آشکار و پنهان خودداری می‌کنند. این پژوهش به دنبال آن است که به عنوان یکی از مهم‌ترین موانع نوآوری در سازمان‌های بخش عمومی، ابعاد اصلی سکوت کارکنان دانشی دانشکده‌های علوم انسانی استان تهران را شناسایی کند. پژوهش حاضر به لحاظ هدف، کاربردی و به لحاظ روش متکی بر روش‌شناسی داده ‌بنیاد است. جامعه آماری پژوهش کارکنان دانشی دانشکده‌های علوم انسانی استان تهران بوده و نمونه‌گیری تا اشباع داده‌ها پیش رفته است. در این پژوهش تلاش شده است، پس از شناسایی انواع سکوت در سازمان، عوامل سکوت، پیامدها و راهبردهای کاهش سکوت به عنوان ابعاد اصلی سکوت سازمانی کارکنان دانشی، روایتی بر اجتناب از شکستن سکوت سازمانی و عدم توفیق در حرکت به سمت نوآوری در دانشکده‌های علوم انسانی ارائه گردد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>نوآوری</kwd>
						<kwd>بخش عمومی</kwd>
						<kwd>سکوت سازمانی</kwd>
						<kwd>کارکنان دانشی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Agolla, J. E. &amp; van Lill, J. B., 2013. Public sector innovation drivers: A process model. Journal of Social Sciences, 34(2), pp. 165–176.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Akbarian, A., Ansari, M. E., Shaemi, A. &amp; Keshtiaray, N., 2015. Review organizational silence factors. Journal of Scientific Research and Development, 2(1), pp. 178–181.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Answerhub, 2016. is silence killing your innovation. [Online] Available at: http://www.dzonesoftware.com/blog/is-silence-killing-your-innovation. [Accessed 2018].</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Avery, D. R. &amp; Quiñones, M. A., 2002. Disentangling the effects of voice: The incremental roles of opportunity, behavior, and instrumentality in predicting procedural fairness. Journal of Applied Psychology, 87(1), pp. 81.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Beheshtifar, M., Borhani, H. &amp; Moghadam, M. N., 2012. Destructive role of employee silence in organizational success. International Journal of Academic Research in Business and Social Sciences, 2(11), p. 275.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Bloch, C. W., Jørgensen, L. L., Norn, M. T. &amp; Vad, T. B., 2010. Public Sector Innovation Index-A Diagnostic Tool for measuring innovative performance and capability in public sector organisations.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Brinsfield, C. T., 2009. Employee silence: Investigation of dimensionality, development of measures, and examination of related factors. The Ohio State University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Carstensen, H. V. &amp; Bason, C., 2012. Powering collaborative policy innovation: Powering collaborative policy innovation. The Innovation Journal: The Public Sector Innovation Journal, 17(1), pp. 1–26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Çınar, O., Karcıoğlu, F. &amp; Alioğulları, Z. D., 2013. The relationship between organizational silence and organizational citizenship behavior: A survey study in the province of Erzurum, Turkey. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume 99, pp. 314–321.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Clark, J., Good, B. &amp; Simmonds, P., 2008. Innovation Index: 2008 Summer Mini-Projects. Innovation in Public Sector and Third Sectors. The National Endowment for Science Technology and the Arts NESTA,(Retrieved Nov 21, 2009, from http://moemesto. ru/alz59/file/3939674/display/42. InnovationinthePublicandThirdSectorsSimmondsetal. pdf).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Clemmer, J., 2007. Moose on the Table: A Novel Approach to Communications@ Work. s.l.:Jim Clemmer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Creswell, J. W., 2012. Educational research. Planning, conducting, and evaluating quantitative and qualitative research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Cruz, S. &amp; Paulino, S., 2013. Public service innovation and evaluation indicators. Journal of technology management &amp; innovation, Volume 8, p. 26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Donaghey, J., Cullinane, N., Dundon, T. &amp; Wilkinson, A., 2011. Reconceptualising employee silence: Problems and prognosis. Work, employment and society, 25(1), pp. 51–67.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Eshraghi, M., Afrasiabi, R. &amp; Asgarzadeh, H., 2013. A Study on the Relationship between Management Styles andOrganizational Silence of North Khorasan Cultural and Islamic GuidanceHeadquarters Staff. International Journal of Management and Humanity Sciences, pp. 579–585.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Gambarotto, F. &amp; Cammozzo, A., 2010. Dreams of silence: Employee voice and innovation in a public sector community of practice. Innovation, 2(12), pp. 166–179.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Gorard, S. &amp; Taylor, C., 2004. Combining methods in educational and social research. s.l.:McGraw-Hill Education (UK).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Hafnidar, 2013. The Relationship among Five Factor Model of Personality, Spirituality, and Forgiveness. International Journal of Social Science and Humanity, 2(3), pp. 167–170.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Johnson, L. &amp; Phillips, B., 2003. Absolute honesty: Building a corporate culture that values straight talk and rewards integrity. s.l.:AMACOM Div American Mgmt Assn.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Karaca, H., 2013. An exploratory study on the impact of organizational silence in hierarchical organizations: Turkish national police case. European Scientific Journal, ESJ, 9(23).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Kattel, R. et al., 2013. Can we measure public sector innovation? A literature review. LIPSE project paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Martocchio, J., 2008. Research in personnel and human resources management. s.l.:Emerald Group Publishing Limited.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Moore, M. &amp; Hartley, J., 2008. Innovations in governance. Public management review, 10(1), pp. 3–20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Mulgan, G. &amp; Albury, D., 2003. Innovation in the Public Sector, Strategy Unit, Cabinet Office (London), s.l.: s.n.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Panahi, B., Veiseh, S., Divkhar, S. &amp; Kamari, F., 2012. An empirical analysis on influencing factors on organizational silence and its relationship with employee’s organizational commitment. Management Science Letters, 2(3), p. 735–744.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Penttila, C., 2003. Get Talking. [Online] Available at: https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/65036 [Accessed 2018].</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Pinder, C. C. &amp; Harlos, K. p., 2001. Employee silence: Quiescence and acquiescence as responses to perceived injustice. Research in Personnel and Human Resources Management, Volume 20, pp. 331–369.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Raipa, A. &amp; Giedraityte, V., 2014. Innovation process barriers in public sector: A comparative analysis in Lithuania and the European Union. International Journal of Business and Management, 9(10), pp. 10.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Rivera León, L., Simmonds, P. &amp; Roman, L., 2012. Trends and challenges in public sector innovation in Europe, s.l.: published by DG Enterprise, Brussels.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Şevket, Y., 2012. Analysis Of The Hotel Personnel’s Conceptions Of Organizational Justice, Organizational Silence, Mobbing, Organizational Commitment In Terms Of Demographic Variables.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Slade, M. R., 2008. The adaptive nature of organizational silence: A cybernetic exploration of the hidden factory. s.l.:The George Washington University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Soliman, S. A. H., 2005. Systems and creative thinking. s.l.:Pathways to Higher Education.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Sørensen, E. &amp; Torfing, J., 2011. Enhancing collaborative innovation in the public sector. Administration &amp; Society, 43(8), pp. 842–868.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Strauss, A. &amp; Corbin, J., 1990. Basics of qualitative research. s.l.:Sage publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Tahmasebi, F., Sobhanipour, S. M. &amp; Aghaziarati, M., 2013. Burnout; explaining the role of organizational silence and its influence (Case study: Selected executive organizations of Qom province). Journal of Basic and Applied Scientific Research, 3(8), pp. 272–282.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Tiwari, S., 2011. Employee engagement-the key to organizational success. Academy for professional excellence, Kolkata.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Tulubas, T. &amp; Celep, C., 2012. Effect of perceived procedural justice on faculty members’ silence: The mediating role of trust in supervisor. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume 47, pp. 1221–1231.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Vries, H. d., Bekkers, V. &amp; Tummers, L., 2015. Innovation in the Public Sector: A Systematic Review and Future Research Agenda.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Walker, R. M., 2006. Innovation type and diffusion: An empirical analysis of local government. Public administration, 84(2), pp. 311–335.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Yildiz, E., 2013. Enigma of Silence in Organizations: What Happens To Whom and Why?. Journal of Social Sciences, 6(2), pp. 30-44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>اصفهانی نصر، ع. رادمهر، ر. حاتم پور، ف. و حاتم پور، ا. ، 1393. عوامل مؤثر بر سکوت سازمانی کارکنان (مورد مطالعه): بیمارستان حضرت زهرا (س) اصفهان. تحقیقات نظام سلامت،4(10) ، صص. 838–830.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>افخمی اردکانی، م. و خلیلی، ص. ا. ، 1391. بررسی رابطه بین عوامل شخصیتی و سکوت کارکنان دانشی. پژوهش‌های مدیریت عمومی،18(5)، صص. 83-65.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>آقاباباپور دهکردی، ط. و نصر اصفهانی، ع.، 2013. بررسی رابطه هویت سازمانی با سکوت سازمانی کارکنان مورد مطالعه کارکنان دانشگاه اصفهان. جامعه شناسی کاربردی، 24(4)، صص. 162–139.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>بهزاد، آ. صالحی، م. صفرپور، س. ی. و شوقی، س.، 1394. تحلیل عوامل مؤثر بر سکوت سازمانی و تأثیر آن بر تعهد کارکنان دانشگاه علوم پزشکی اصفهان. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی تحقیقات مدیریت آموزشی، 7(25)، صص. 187–110.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>تید، ج. و بسنت، ج.، 1394. مدیریت نوآوری؛ یکپارچهسازی تغییرات فناورانه، بازار و سازمان. تهران: مؤسسه خدمات فرهنگی رسا.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>دانایی فرد، ح. و پناهی، ب.، 1389. تحلیل نگرش های شغلی کارکنان سازمان های دولتی تبیین جو سکوت سازمانی و رفتار سکوت سازمانی. پژوهش نامه مدیریت تحول، 3(2)، صص. 19–1.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>رستگار، ع. و روزبان، ف.، 1393. شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر سکوت سازمانی به روش آمیخته تشریحی انتخاب مشارکت‌کننده. فصلنامه علمی ـ پژوهشی مدیریت سازمان های دولتی، 4(2)، صص. 18-7.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>زارعی متین، ح.، 1393. مدیریت رفتار سازمانی پیشرفته. تهران: نشر آگه.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>سیار، ا. زارعی متین، ح. و طاهری، ف.، 1391. بررسی و تبیین عوامل ایجاد کننده سکوت سازمانی از دیدگاه مدیران و کارکنان بر مبنای مدل سه شاخگی (3C). فصلنامه مطالعات رفتار سازمانی، 1(1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>زارعی متین، ح. طاهری، ف. و سیار، ا.، 1390. سکوت سازمانی: مفاهیم، علل و پیامدها. فصلنامه علوم مدیریت ایران، 6(21)، صص. 104-77.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>صلواتیان، س. نعمتی انارکی، د. و نیستانی اصفهانی، ک.، 2017. عوامل مؤثر بر سکوت سازمانی نیروهای رسانه‌ای بر مبنای تجربة کارکنان ادارة کل روابط عمومی سازمان صدا و سیما. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی مدیریت دولتی، 8(4)، صص. 690–665.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>عظیم زاده پارسی، آ. حسینی مهر، ع. و رحمانی، ع.، 1390. بررسی ارتباط بین مولفه های مدل پنج عاملی شخصیت و شادکامی در دانشجویان. فصلنامه روانشناسی تربیتی، 2(2)، صص. 12–1.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>صلصالی، م.، پرویزی، س. و ادیب حاج باقری، م.، 1390. روش های تحقیق کیفی. تهران: بشری.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>نوه ابراهیم، ع. و یوسفی، ف.، 1395. عوامل موثر بر سکوت سازمانی، مانع ایجاد کارآفرینی سازمانی. رهیافتی نو در مدیریت آموزشی، 2(7)، صص. 156-133.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>هیوز، آ.، 1377. مدیریت دولتی نوین. تهران: انتشارات مروارید._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Agolla, J. E. &amp; van Lill, J. B., 2013. Public sector innovation drivers: A process model. Journal of Social Sciences, 34(2), pp. 165–176.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Aghababapour Dehkordi, T. &amp; Nasresfahani, A., 2013. Investigating the Relationship between Organizational Identity and Organizational Silence of Employees Staff of Isfahan University. Applied Sociology, 4(24), pp. 139-162.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Akbarian, A., Ansari, M. E., Shaemi, A. &amp; Keshtiaray, N., 2015. Review organizational silence factors. Journal of Scientific Research and Development, 2(1), pp. 178–181.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Azimzadeh Parsi, A. Hoseini Mehr, A. &amp; Rahmani, A., 2010. Investigating the Relationship between the Components of the Five-factor Model of Personality and Happiness in Students. Quarterly Journal of Educational Psychology, 2(2), pp. 1-12.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Afkhami Ardakani, M. &amp; Khalili, S, A., 2011. The Relationship between Personality Factors and Silence of Knowledge Employees. Public Management Research, 18(5), pp. 65-83.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Answerhub, 2016. is silence killing your innovation. [Online]  Available at: http://www.dzonesoftware.com/blog/is-silence-killing-your-innovation. [Accessed 2018].</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Avery, D. R. &amp; Quiñones, M. A., 2002. Disentangling the effects of voice: The incremental roles of opportunity, behavior, and instrumentality in predicting procedural fairness. Journal of Applied Psychology, 87(1), pp. 81.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Beheshtifar, M., Borhani, H. &amp; Moghadam, M. N., 2012. Destructive role of employee silence in organizational success. International Journal of Academic Research in Business and Social Sciences, 2(11), p. 275.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Behzad, A, Salehi, M, Safarpour, S, Y. &amp; Showghi, S., 2014. The Analysis of Factors Affecting Organizational Silence and Its Impact on Employees' Commitment in Isfahan University of Medical Sciences. Educational Management Research, 7(25), pp. 110-187.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Bloch, C. W., Jørgensen, L. L., Norn, M. T. &amp; Vad, T. B., 2010. Public Sector Innovation Index-A Diagnostic Tool for measuring innovative performance and capability in public sector organisations.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Brinsfield, C. T., 2009. Employee silence: Investigation of dimensionality, development of measures, and examination of related factors. The Ohio State University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Carstensen, H. V. &amp; Bason, C., 2012. Powering collaborative policy innovation: Powering collaborative policyinnovation. The Innovation Journal: The Public Sector Innovation Journal, 17(1), pp. 1–26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Çınar, O., Karcıoğlu, F. &amp; Alioğulları, Z. D., 2013. The relationship between organizational silence and organizational citizenship behavior: A survey study in the province of Erzurum, Turkey. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume 99, pp. 314–321.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Clark, J., Good, B. &amp; Simmonds, P., 2008. Innovation Index: 2008 Summer Mini-Projects. Innovation in Public Sector and Third Sectors. The National Endowment for Science Technology and the Arts NESTA,(Retrieved Nov 21, 2009, from http://moemesto. ru/alz59/file/3939674/display/42. InnovationinthePublicandThirdSectorsSimmondsetal. pdf).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Clemmer, J., 2007. Moose on the Table: A Novel Approach to Communications@ Work. s.l.:Jim Clemmer.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Creswell, J. W., 2012. Educational research. Planning, conducting, and evaluating quantitative and qualitative research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Cruz, S. &amp; Paulino, S., 2013. Public service innovation and evaluation indicators. Journal of technology management &amp; innovation, Volume 8, p. 26.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Esfahani Nasr, A., Radmehr, R., Hatampour, R &amp; Hatampour, F., 2013. Factors Affecting Organizational Silence of Employees (Case Study): Hazrat Zahra Hospital. Health system research, 4(10), pp. 830-838.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Danaeefard, H. &amp; Panahi, B., 2009, A Study of the Attitudes of the Employees of Government Organizations on the Clarification of Organizational Silence and Organizational Silence. Bulletin of Transformation Management, 3(2), pp. 1-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Donaghey, J., Cullinane, N., Dundon, T. &amp; Wilkinson, A., 2011. Reconceptualising employee silence: Problems and prognosis. Work, employment and society, 25(1), pp. 51–67.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Eshraghi, M., Afrasiabi, R. &amp; Asgarzadeh, H., 2013. A Study on the Relationship between Management Styles andOrganizational Silence of North Khorasan Cultural and Islamic GuidanceHeadquarters Staff. International Journal of Management and Humanity Sciences, pp. 579–585.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Gambarotto, F. &amp; Cammozzo, A., 2010. Dreams of silence: Employee voice and innovation in a public sector community of practice. Innovation, 2(12), pp. 166–179.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Gorard, S. &amp; Taylor, C., 2004. Combining methods in educational and social research. s.l.:McGraw-Hill Education (UK).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Hafnidar, 2013. The Relationship among Five Factor Model of Personality, Spirituality, and Forgiveness. International Journal of Social Science and Humanity, 2(3), pp. 167–170.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Johnson, L. &amp; Phillips, B., 2003. Absolute honesty: Building a corporate culture that values straight talk and rewards integrity. s.l.:AMACOM Div American Mgmt Assn.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Karaca, H., 2013. An exploratory study on the impact of organizational silence in hierarchical organizations: Turkish national police case. European Scientific Journal, ESJ, 9(23).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Kattel, R. et al., 2013. Can we measure public sector innovation? A literature review. LIPSE project paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Martocchio, J., 2008. Research in personnel and human resources management. s.l.:Emerald Group Publishing Limited.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Moore, M. &amp; Hartley, J., 2008. Innovations in governance. Public management review, 10(1), pp. 3–20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Mulgan, G. &amp; Albury, D., 2003. Innovation in the Public Sector, Strategy Unit, Cabinet Office (London), s.l.: s.n.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Naveh Ebrahim, A. &amp; Yousefi, F., 2015. Factors affecting organizational silence prevent the creation of entrepreneurial organization. New Approach in Educational Management, 2(7), pp. 133-156.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Owen E, Hughes., 1997. Public Management and Administration. Tehran: Morvarid Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Panahi, B., Veiseh, S., Divkhar, S. &amp; Kamari, F., 2012. An empirical analysis on influencing factors on organizational silence and its relationship with employee’s organizational commitment. Management Science Letters, 2(3), p. 735–744.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Penttila, C., 2003. Get Talking. [Online]  Available at: https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/65036 [Accessed 2018].</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Pinder, C. C. &amp; Harlos, K. p., 2001. Employee silence: Quiescence and acquiescence as responses to perceived injustice. Research in Personnel and Human Resources Management, Volume 20, pp. 331–369.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Rastegar, A. &amp; Roozban, F., 2013. Identifying the factors affecting organizational silence by using an associate selection method. Journal of Management of Governmental Organizations, 4(2), pp. 7-18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Raipa, A. &amp; Giedraityte, V., 2014. Innovation process barriers in public sector: A comparative analysis in Lithuania and the European Union. International Journal of Business and Management, 9(10), pp. 10.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Rivera León, L., Simmonds, P. &amp; Roman, L., 2012. Trends and challenges in public sector innovation in Europe, s.l.: published by DG Enterprise, Brussels.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Sayyar, A, Zarei Matin, H. &amp; Taheri, F., 2011. Investigating and explaining the causes of organizational silence from the viewpoint of managers and employees based on three-branch model (3C). Quarterly Journal of Organizational Behavior Studies, 1(1).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Salavatian, S. Nemati Anarak, D. &amp; Neyestani Esfahani, K., 2017. Factors Affecting the Silence of Media Organizations Based on the Experiences of Public Relations Officers of the Voice and Television Organization. Journal of Public and Management. 8(4), pp. 665-660.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Salsali, M. Parvizi, S. &amp; Adib Haj Bagheri, M., 2010. Qualitative research methods. Tehran: Boshra publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Şevket, Y., 2012. Analysis Of The Hotel Personnel’s Conceptions Of Organizational Justice, Organizational Silence, Mobbing, Organizational Commitment In Terms Of Demographic Variables.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Slade, M. R., 2008. The adaptive nature of organizational silence: A cybernetic exploration of the hidden factory. s.l.:The George Washington University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Soliman, S. A. H., 2005. Systems and creative thinking. s.l.:Pathways to Higher Education.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Sørensen, E. &amp; Torfing, J., 2011. Enhancing collaborative innovation in the public sector. Administration &amp; Society, 43(8), pp. 842–868.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Strauss, A. &amp; Corbin, J., 1990. Basics of qualitative research. s.l.:Sage publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Tahmasebi, F., Sobhanipour, S. M. &amp; Aghaziarati, M., 2013. Burnout; explaining the role of organizational silence and its influence (Case study: Selected executive organizations of Qom province). Journal of Basic and Applied Scientific Research, 3(8), pp. 272–282.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Tidd, J. &amp; Bessant, J., 2014. Managing Innovation: Integrating Technological, Market and Organizational Change. Tehran: Rasa Cultural Services Institute.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Tiwari, S., 2011. Employee engagement-the key to organizational success. Academy for professional excellence, Kolkata.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Tulubas, T. &amp; Celep, C., 2012. Effect of perceived procedural justice on faculty members’ silence: The mediating role of trust in supervisor. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume 47, pp. 1221–1231.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Vries, H. d., Bekkers, V. &amp; Tummers, L., 2015. Innovation in the Public Sector: A Systematic Review and Future Research Agenda.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Walker, R. M., 2006. Innovation type and diffusion: An empirical analysis of local government. Public administration, 84(2), pp. 311–335.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Yildiz, E., 2013. Enigma of Silence in Organizations: What Happens To Whom and Why?. Journal of Social Sciences, 6(2), pp. 30-44.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Zarei Matin, H., 2013. Advanced Organizational Behavior Management. Tehran: Agah publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Zarei Matin, H. Taheri, F. &amp; Sayyar, A., 2010. Organizational Silence: Concepts, Causes, and Consequences. Journal of Management Science of Iran, 6(21), pp. 77-104.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86890_bd57eb79c59aafc532a1a73d43a02840.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>زیست بوم و فرهنگ نوآوری (موانع، چالش ها و فرصت ها)</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>بررسی تأثیر کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی برخلاقیت و نوآوری در محصول و فرآیند (مورد مطالعه: شرکت‌های دانش بنیان مستقر در پارک علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران)</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>طاهری عطار</surname>
			            <given-names>غزاله</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رستم لو</surname>
			            <given-names>رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه مدیریت دولتی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>23</day>
			        <month>08</month>
			        <year>2018</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>47</fpage>
			      <lpage>68</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>10</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>24</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86890.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86890.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>خلاقیت کارکنان تاثیر بسزایی در نوآوری و بقای سازمانی دارد. عملکرد خوب سازمان در حوزه نوآوری می‌تواند موجب حفظ مزیت رقابتی و رشد و توسعه سازمان شود. سازمانی که به دنبال خلاقیت و نوآوری است نباید از اهمیت و تاثیر کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی بر خلاقیت و نوآوری غافل شود. در این پژوهش با استفاده از نمونه‌ای 107 تایی از شرکت‌های دانش بنیان پارک علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران به بررسی رابطه بین کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی با خلاقیت کارکنان و نوآوری محصول و نوآوری فرآیند پرداخته شده است. پژوهش حاضر بر اساس هدف، پژوهشی کاربردی و از نظر جمع‌آوری داده‌ها پژوهشی پیمایشی- توصیفی است. جمع‌آوری داده‌های پژوهش از طریق پرسشنامه انجام شده است. پایایی پرسشنامه‌ها با محاسبه ضریب آلفای کرونباخ و پایایی ترکیبی (CR) و روایی پرسشنامه‌ها با محاسبه دو معیار روایی همگرا و واگرا که مختص مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری است، مورد تایید قرار گرفت. همچنین برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌های جمع‌آوری شده از روش معادلات ساختاری با استفاده از نرم‌افزار اسمارت پی.ال.اس استفاده گردیده است. نتایج پژوهش نشان داد که کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی تاثیر مثبت و مستقیمی بر خلاقیت کارکنان و خلاقیت کارکنان تاثیر مستقیم و مثبتی بر نوآوری محصول و نوآوری فرآیند دارد. همچنین نقش میانجی خلاقیت کارکنان در اثرگذاری کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی بر نوآوری محصول و نوآوری فرآیند مورد تایید قرار گرفت.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی</kwd>
						<kwd>خلاقیت کارکنان</kwd>
						<kwd>نوآوری محصول</kwd>
						<kwd>نوآوری فرآیند</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>احمدی، عباداله. 1395. رابطه خلاقیت و نوآوری با بهره‌وری منابع انسانی. رهیافتی نو در مدیریت آموزشی، 27 (7)، 209-222.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>اژدری گلناز؛ لگزیان، محمد؛ شیرازی، علی؛ فیاضی، بی­بی مرجان. 1397. نوآوری و خلاقیت در اجرای اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی در شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان. ابتکار و خلاقیت در علوم انسانی، 7 (4)، 1-32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>اصغری، حرمت؛ دانش فرد، کرم اله؛ میرسپا سی، ناصر. 1397. تحلیل عملکرد شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان موردمطالعه: شرکت‌های موجود در پارک‌های علم و فناوری تهران، مدیریت بهره­وری، 12 (45)، 30-7.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>آقایی، عنایت‌الله؛ ستوده کویری آرانی، حسین. 1385. خلاقیت و نوآوری. پژوهش‌های مدیریت راهبردی 37 (13) 24-40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>آناهید، محمد. 1392. منابع انسانی و عملیات نوآوری در سازمان. پژوهش‌های علوم انسانی، 30 (5)، 45-60.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>پورتیمور فرد تبریزی، فرزین؛ جمشیدی، لاله. 1393. بررسی عملکرد نوآورانه شرکت های دانش بنیان مستقر در مرکز رشد علم و فناوری دانشگاه سمنان. صنعت و دانشگاه، 7 (23 و 24)، 52-37.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>جهانیان، رمضان؛ حدادی، طاهره. 1394. بررسی رابطه‌ی بین سرمایه‌ی فکری با نوآوری و خلاقیت منابع انسانی در سازمان. ابتکار و خلاقیت در علوم انسانی، 17(5)، 65-92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>حسینی، ابوالحسن؛ تبسمی، امیر؛ دادفر، زهرا. 1396. بررسی تأثیر کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی بر عملکرد سازمانی. چشم‌انداز مدیریت دولتی، 29، 171-155.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>دلال نصیری، سمانه؛ احمدی، عبادالله؛ برزگر، مجید. 1391. رابطه خلاقیت و نوآوری با رضایت شغلی در شاغلان صنایع‌دستی شیراز. ابتکار و خلاقیت در علوم انسانی، 2 (3)، 204-169.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>رجبی فرجاد، حاجیه. 1395. بررسی نقش میانجی قابلیت‌های مدیریت دانش در ارتباط بین اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی و نوآوری. پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی، 8(3)، 239-265.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>رجبی فرجاد، حاجیه. 1395. بررسی نقش میانجی قابلیت‌های مدیریت دانش در ارتباط بین اقدامات مدیریت منابع انسانی و نوآوری. پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی، 25(0)، 239-265.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>رجبی، مریم؛ حسنی، محمد؛ مهاجران، بهناز. 1395. بررسی نقش فعالیت‌های توسعه منابع انسانی بر نوآوری کارکنان با آزمون نقش میانجی مدیریت دانش و یادگیری سازمانی در میان کارکنان کمیته امداد امام خمینی (ره)، استان آذربایجان غربی. ابتکار و خلاقیت در علوم انسانی، 6(3)، 151-178.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>رشیدی، اسماعیل؛ شهرآرای، مهرناز. 1387. بررسی رابطه خلاقیت با منبع کنترل. نوآوری‌های مدیریت آموزشی (اندیشه‌های تازه در علوم تربیتی)، 3 (3)، 99-81.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>سید نقوی، میرعلی؛ پور برخورداری، امین. 1391. نقش کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی و رفتار شهروندی سازمانی در کارآفرینی سازمان. منابع انسانی ناجا، 28، 7-28.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>طالبی، کامبیز؛ داوری، علی؛ نجم­آبادی، عامر. 1392. شناسایی تأثیر سرمایه فکری بر تشخیص فرصت‌های کارآفرینانه در شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان. مطالعات مدیریت (بهبود و تحول)، 22(71)، 19-48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>عباسپور، عباس. 1381. مقایسه‌ی کارکردهای منابع انسانی دانشگاه با کارکردهای مدیریت راهبردی منابع انسانی، مجله دانش مدیریت، 51، 106-85.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>میرغفوری، سیدحبیب­الله؛ صیادی تورانلو، حسین؛ کریمی­نیا، مریم. 1392. رتبه بندی عوامل مؤثر بر ارتقای نوآوری در شرکت­های وابسته به مراکز رشد با استفاده از تکنیک تاپسیس فاز[i]ی، مطالعه موردی پارک علم و فناوری یزد. رشد فناوری، 9(36)، 28-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Ahlin, B., Drnovšek, M., &amp; Hisrich, R. D. 2013. Entrepreneurs’ creativity and firm innovation: the moderating role of entrepreneurial self-efficacy. Small Business Economics, 43(1), pp. 101–117.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Anand, N., Gardner, H. K., &amp; Morris, T. 2007. Knowledge-based innovation: Emergence and embedding of new practice areas in management consulting firms. Academy of Management Journal, 50(2), pp. 406-428.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Anderson, N., Potočnik, K., &amp; Zhou, J. 2014. Innovation and creativity in organizations: A state-of-the-science review and prospective commentary. Journal of Management, 40(5), pp. 1297–1333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Axtell, C.M., Holman, D.J., Wall, T., 2006. Promoting innovation: a change study. J. Occup. Organ. Psychol. 79 (3), pp. 509–516.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Baer, M. 2012. Putting creativity to work: The implementation of creative ideas in organizations. Academy of Management Journal, 55, pp. 1102-1119.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Batey, M. 2012. The measurement of creativity: From definitional consensus to the introduction of a new heuristic framework. Creativity Research Journal, 24(1), pp. 55–65.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Byron, K., Khazanchi, S., and Nazarian, D. 2010, ‘The Relationship Between Stressors and Creativity: A Meta-Analysis Examining Competing Theoretical Models, Journal of Applied Psychology, 95, pp. 201–212.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Ceylan, C. 2013. Commitment-based HR practices, different types of innovation activities and firm innovation performance, The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 24(1), pp. 208-226.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Carboni, O. A. and Russu, P. 2018. Complementarity in product, process, and organizational innovation decisions: evidence from European firms. R&amp;D Management, 48, pp. 210-222.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, C. and Huang, J. 2007. How Organizational Climate and Structure Affect Knowledge Management: The Social Interaction Perspective. International Journal of Information Management, 27 (2), pp.104-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, C.-J., &amp; Huang, J.-W. 2009. Strategic human resource practices and innovation performance—The mediating role of knowledge management capacity. Journal of business research, 62(1), pp. 104-114.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Collins, C. J., &amp; Smith, K. G. 2006. Knowledge exchange and combination: The role of human resource practices in the performance of high-technology firms. Academy of Management Journal, 49(3), pp. 544-560.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Damanpour F,Walker RM and Avellaneda CN. 2009. Combinative effects of innovation types and organizational performance: A longitudinal study of service organizations. Journal of Management Studies, 46(4), pp. 650–675.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>David J. Hughes, Allan Lee, Amy Wei Tian, Alex Newman, Alison Legood. 2018. Leadership, creativity, and innovation: A critical review and practical recommendations, The Leadership Quarterly, 29(5), pp. 549-569.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>De Leede, J., &amp; Looise, J. K. 2005. Innovation and HRM: Towards an integrated framework. Creativity and Innovation Management, 14, pp. 108–117.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Delery, J.E. and Doty, D.H. 1996. Modes of theorizing in strategic human resource management: Tests of universalistic, contingency, and configurational performance predictions. Academy of management journal 39(4), pp. 802-835.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Demo, G., Neiva, E.R., Nunes, I. and Rozzett, K. 2012. Human resources management policies and practices scale (HRMPPS): Exploratory and confirmatory factor analysis. BAR-Brazilian Administration Review, 9(4), pp. 395-420.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Dorenbosch, L., Engen, M. L. v., &amp; Verhagen, M. 2005. On‐the‐job innovation: the impact of job design and human resource management through production ownership. Creativity and innovation management, 14(2), pp. 129-141.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Dul, J., &amp; Ceylan, C. 2014. The Impact of a Creativity-supporting Work Environment on a Firm’s Product Innovation Performance. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 31(6), pp. 1254–1267.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Egan, T.M. 2005, ‘Factors Influencing Individual Creativity in the Workplace: An Examination of Quantitative Empirical Research, Advances in Developing Human Resources, 7, pp. 160–181.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Escribá-Carda N., Canet-Giner M.T., Balbastre-Benavent F. 2014. The Key Role of Human Resource Practices for the Promotion of Creativity and Innovation: A Spanish Case Study. In: Hervás-Oliver JL., Peris-Ortiz M. (eds) Management Innovation. Springer Proceedings in Business and Economics. Springer, Cham</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Global Innovation Index, 2018. Data from https://www.globalinnovationindex.org/analysis-indicator</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Hanedaa,S; Itob, K. 2014. Organizational and human resource management and innovation: Which management practices are linked to product and/or process innovation?. Research Policy, 47(1), pp. 194-208.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Hirst, Giles., Van Knippenberg, Daan., Zhou, Jing. 2009. A cross-level perspective on employee creativity: Goal orientation, team learning behavior, and individual creativity. Academy of management journal, 52(2), pp. 280-293.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Hsu, C. H., Chang, A. Y., &amp; Luo, W. 2017. Identifying key performance factors for sustainability development of SMEs–integrating QFD and fuzzy MADM methods. Journal of Cleaner Production, 161, pp. 629-645.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Huselid, M. A., Jackson, S. E., &amp; Schuler, R. S. 1997. Technical and strategic human resources management effectiveness as determinants of firm performance. Academy of Management Journal, 40(1), pp. 171-188.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Jiang, J., Wang, S. and Zhao, S. 2012. Does HRM facilitate employee creativity and organizational innovation? A study of Chinese firms. The International Journal of Human Resource Management 23(19), pp. 4025-4047.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Jimenez-Jimenez, D., &amp; Sanz-Valle, R. 2005. Innovation and human resource management fit: an empirical study. International journal of Manpower, 26(4), pp. 364-381.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Jimenez-Jimenez, D., &amp; Sanz-Valle, R. 2008. Could HRM support organizational innovation? The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 19(7), pp. 1208-1221.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Kiantoa, A., Sáenzb, J., Aramburub, N. 2017. Knowledge-based human resource management practices, intellectual capital and innovation. Journal of Business Research, (81), pp. 11–20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Lau, C.M., and Ngo, H.Y., (2004), ‘The HR System, Organizational Culture, and Product Innovation. International Business Review, 13, pp. 685–703.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Laursen, K., &amp; Foss, N. J. (2014). Human resource management practices and innovation. In M. Dodgson, D. Gann, &amp; N. Phillips (Eds.), Handbook of innovation management (pp. 505–530). Oxford: Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Licuanan, B.F., Dailey, L.R., and Mumford, M.D. (2007), ‘Idea Evaluation: Error in Evaluating Highly Original Ideas. Journal of Creative Behavior, 41, pp. 1–27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Lin, L.H. 2011. Electronic Human Resource Management and Organizational Innovation: the Roles of Information Technology and Virtual Organizational Structure. The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 22, pp. 235–257.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Ling, T. C., &amp; Mohd Nasurdin, A. 2010. Human resource management practices and organizational innovation: An empirical study in Malaysia. Journal of Applied Business Research, 26(4), pp. 105-116.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>McLean, Laird D. 2005. Organizational culture’s influence on creativity and innovation: A review of the literature and implications for human resource development. Advances in developing human resources, 7(2), pp. 226-246.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Mumford, M. D., &amp; McIntosh, T. 2017. Creative thinking processes: The past and the future. The Journal of Creative Behavior, 51(4), pp. 317–322.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Nieves, J., Quintana, A. and Osorio, J. 2016. Organizational knowledge and collaborative human resource practices as determinants of innovation. Knowledge management research &amp; practice, 14(3), pp. 237-245.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>OECD (2005), Oslo Manual. Guidelines for Collecting and Interpreting Innovation Data (3rd ed.), Paris: OECD.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Parker, S. 2000. From Passive to Proactive Motivation: The Importance of Flexible Role Orientations and Role Breadth Self-Efficacy. Applied Psychology, 49, pp. 447–469.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Revilla, Elena &amp; Rodriguez-Prado, Beatriz. 2018. Bulding ambidexterity through creativity mechanisms: Contextual drivers of innovation success. Research Policy. 47(9), pp. 1611-1625.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Salem IE-B .2014. Toward better understanding of knowledge management: Correlation to hotel performance and innovation in five-star chain hotels in Egypt. Tourism and Hospitality Research, 14(4), pp. 176–196.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Sarooghi, H., Libaers, D., Burkemper, A. 2015. Examining the relationship between creativity and innovation: a meta-analysis of organizational, cultural, and environmental factors. J. Bus. Ventur. 30 (5), 714–731.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Tenenhaus, M., Vinzi, V.E., Chatelin, Y.-M. and Lauro, C. 2005. PLS path modeling. Computational statistics &amp; data analysis, 48(1), pp. 159-205.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, C; Ahmed, P. 2004. The development and validation of the organizational innovativeness construct using confirmatory factor analysis. European Journal of Innovation Management, 7(4), pp. 303–313.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, P. et al. 2013. A workgroup climate perspective on the relationships among transformational leadership, workgroup diversity, and employee creativity. Group &amp; Organization Management, 38(3), pp. 334-360.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Wen Wu, S. 2010. Linking Bayesian networks and PLS path modeling for causal analysis. Expert Systems with Applications, 37 (1), pp. 134–139.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Yang, M.-L., Wang, A. M.-L., &amp; Cheng, K.-C. 2009. The impact of quality of is information and budget slack on innovation performance. Technovation, 29(8), pp. 527–536.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, X., and Bartol, K.M. 2010. Linking Empowering Leadership and Employee Creativity: The Influence of Psychological Empowerment, Intrinsic Motivation, and Creative Process Engagement. The Academy of Management Journal, 53, pp. 107–128.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Zhou, J., &amp; Shalley, C. E. 2003. Research on employee creativity: A critical review and directions for future research. Research in personnel and human resources management (pp. 165-217): Emerald Group Publishing Limited.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Zhou, K. Z. (2006). Innovation, imitation, and new product performance: The case of China. Industrial Marketing Management, 35(3), pp. 394-402</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>   _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Abbaspour, A. 2002. Comparison of human resources functions of the university with the functions of strategic human resource management, Management Knowledge, 58, pp. 85-106.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Aghai, E., Setoudeh Arani, H. 2006. Creativity and Innovation. Strategic Management Research, 37 (13), pp. 24-40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Ahlin, B., Drnovšek, M., &amp; Hisrich, R. D. 2013. Entrepreneurs’ creativity and firm innovation: the moderating role of entrepreneurial self-efficacy. Small Business Economics, 43(1), pp. 101–117.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Ahmadi, E. 2016. The Relationship between Creativity and Productivity of Human Resources.   New Approach In Educational Administration, 7 (27), pp. 209-222.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Anahid, M. 2013. Human Resources and Operations Innovation in the organization. Human Sciences Research, 30 (5), pp. 45-60.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Anand, N., Gardner, H. K., &amp; Morris, T. 2007. Knowledge-based innovation: Emergence and embedding of new practice areas in management consulting firms. Academy of Management Journal, 50(2), pp. 406-428.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Anderson, N., Potočnik, K., &amp; Zhou, J. 2014. Innovation and creativity in organizations: A state-of-the-science review and prospective commentary. Journal of Management, 40(5), pp. 1297–1333.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Asghari, H., Daneshfard, K., Mirsepasi, N. 2018. Performance Analysis of Knowledge-Based Firms: The Case of Tehran Science and Technology Park Firms. Productivity Management, 12, 2(45), pp. 7-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Axtell, C.M., Holman, D.J., Wall, T., 2006. Promoting innovation: a change study. J. Occup. Organ. Psychol. 79 (3), pp. 509–516.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Azhdari, G., Lagzian, M., Shirazi, A., Fayyazi, M. 2018. Innovation in Human Resource Management Functions ‎in Knowledge-Based Enterprises. Innovation And Creativity In Human Sciences, 7 (4), pp. 1-32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Baer, M. 2012. Putting creativity to work: The implementation of creative ideas in organizations. Academy of Management Journal, 55, pp. 1102-1119.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Batey, M. 2012. The measurement of creativity: From definitional consensus to the introduction of a new heuristic framework. Creativity Research Journal, 24(1), pp. 55–65.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Byron, K., Khazanchi, S., and Nazarian, D. 2010, ‘The Relationship Between Stressors and Creativity: A Meta-Analysis Examining Competing Theoretical Models, Journal of Applied Psychology, 95, pp. 201–212.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Carboni, O. A. and Russu, P. 2018. Complementarity in product, process, and organizational innovation decisions: evidence from European firms. R&amp;D Management, 48, pp. 210-222.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Ceylan, C. 2013. Commitment-based HR practices, different types of innovation activities and firm innovation performance, The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 24(1), pp. 208-226.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, C. and Huang, J. 2007. How Organizational Climate and Structure Affect Knowledge Management: The Social Interaction Perspective. International Journal of Information Management, 27 (2), pp.104-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, C.-J., &amp; Huang, J.-W. 2009. Strategic human resource practices and innovation performance—The mediating role of knowledge management capacity. Journal of business research, 62(1), pp. 104-114.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Collins, C. J., &amp; Smith, K. G. 2006. Knowledge exchange and combination: The role of human resource practices in the performance of high-technology firms. Academy of Management Journal, 49(3), pp. 544-560.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Dallal Nasiri, S., Ahmadi, E., Barzegar, M. 2013. Study the relationship between creativity and job satisfaction in Shiraz handcraft employees. Innovation And Creativity In Human Sciences, 2 (3), pp. 169-205.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Damanpour F,Walker RM and Avellaneda CN. 2009. Combinative effects of innovation types and organizational performance: A longitudinal study of service organizations. Journal of Management Studies, 46(4), pp. 650–675.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>David J. Hughes, Allan Lee, Amy Wei Tian, Alex Newman, Alison Legood. 2018. Leadership, creativity, and innovation: A critical review and practical recommendations, The Leadership Quarterly, 29(5), pp. 549-569.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>De Leede, J., &amp; Looise, J. K. 2005. Innovation and HRM: Towards an integrated framework. Creativity and Innovation Management, 14, pp. 108–117.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Delery, J.E. and Doty, D.H. 1996. Modes of theorizing in strategic human resource management: Tests of universalistic, contingency, and configurational performance predictions. Academy of management journal 39(4), pp. 802-835.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Demo, G., Neiva, E.R., Nunes, I. and Rozzett, K. 2012. Human resources management policies and practices scale (HRMPPS): Exploratory and confirmatory factor analysis. BAR-Brazilian Administration Review, 9(4), pp. 395-420.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Dorenbosch, L., Engen, M. L. v., &amp; Verhagen, M. 2005. On‐the‐job innovation: the impact of job design and human resource management through production ownership. Creativity and innovation management, 14(2), pp. 129-141.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Dul, J., &amp; Ceylan, C. 2014. The Impact of a Creativity-supporting Work Environment on a Firm’s Product Innovation Performance. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 31(6), pp. 1254–1267.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Egan, T.M. 2005, ‘Factors Influencing Individual Creativity in the Workplace: An Examination of Quantitative Empirical Research, Advances in Developing Human Resources, 7, pp. 160–181.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Escribá-Carda N., Canet-Giner M.T., Balbastre-Benavent F. 2014. The Key Role of Human Resource Practices for the Promotion of Creativity and Innovation: A Spanish Case Study. In: Hervás-Oliver JL., Peris-Ortiz M. (eds) Management Innovation. Springer Proceedings in Business and Economics. Springer, Cham</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Global Innovation Index, 2018. Data from https://www.globalinnovationindex.org/analysis-indicator</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Hanedaa,S; Itob, K. 2014. Organizational and human resource management and innovation: Which management practices are linked to product and/or process innovation?. Research Policy, 47(1), pp. 194-208.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Hirst, Giles., Van Knippenberg, Daan., Zhou, Jing. 2009. A cross-level perspective on employee creativity: Goal orientation, team learning behavior, and individual creativity. Academy of management journal, 52(2), pp. 280-293.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Hosseini, A., Tabassomy, A., Dadfar, Z. 2017. Investigating the Impact of Human Resources Management Functioning on Organizational Performance. Public Administration Perspaective, 8 (29), pp. 155- 171.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Hsu, C. H., Chang, A. Y., &amp; Luo, W. 2017. Identifying key performance factors for sustainability development of SMEs–integrating QFD and fuzzy MADM methods. Journal of Cleaner Production, 161, pp. 629-645.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Huselid, M. A., Jackson, S. E., &amp; Schuler, R. S. 1997. Technical and strategic human resources management effectiveness as determinants of firm performance. Academy of Management Journal, 40(1), pp. 171-188.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Jahanian, R., Hadadi, T. 2015. The Relationship between Intellectual Capital and Human Resources Creativity and Innovation in an organization. Innovation And Creativity In Human Sciences, 5 (1), pp. 65-92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Jiang, J., Wang, S. and Zhao, S. 2012. Does HRM facilitate employee creativity and organizational innovation? A study of Chinese firms. The International Journal of Human Resource Management 23(19), pp. 4025-4047.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Jimenez-Jimenez, D., &amp; Sanz-Valle, R. 2005. Innovation and human resource management fit: an empirical study. International journal of Manpower, 26(4), pp. 364-381.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Jimenez-Jimenez, D., &amp; Sanz-Valle, R. 2008. Could HRM support organizational innovation? The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 19(7), pp. 1208-1221.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Kiantoa, A., Sáenzb, J., Aramburub, N. 2017. Knowledge-based human resource management practices, intellectual capital and innovation. Journal of Business Research, (81), pp. 11–20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Lau, C.M., and Ngo, H.Y., (2004), ‘The HR System, Organizational Culture, and Product Innovation. International Business Review, 13, pp. 685–703.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Laursen, K., &amp; Foss, N. J. (2014). Human resource management practices and innovation. In M. Dodgson, D. Gann, &amp; N. Phillips (Eds.), Handbook of innovation management (pp. 505–530). Oxford: Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>Licuanan, B.F., Dailey, L.R., and Mumford, M.D. (2007), ‘Idea Evaluation: Error in Evaluating Highly Original Ideas. Journal of Creative Behavior, 41, pp. 1–27.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>Lin, L.H. 2011. Electronic Human Resource Management and Organizational Innovation: the Roles of Information Technology and Virtual Organizational Structure. The International Journal of Human Resource Management, 22, pp. 235–257.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Ling, T. C., &amp; Mohd Nasurdin, A. 2010. Human resource management practices and organizational innovation: An empirical study in Malaysia. Journal of Applied Business Research, 26(4), pp. 105-116.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>McLean, Laird D. 2005. Organizational culture’s influence on creativity and innovation: A review of the literature and implications for human resource development. Advances in developing human resources, 7(2), pp. 226-246.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R115">
			<label>115</label>
			<element-citation>Mirghafouri, S. H., Sayyadi Toranloo, H., Kariminia, M. 2013. Ranking of Factors Affecting Innovation Promotion in Growth Centers Affiliated Companies Using Fuzzy Topsis Technique, A Case Study of Yazd Science and Technology Park. Technology Growth, 9 (36), pp. 19-28.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R116">
			<label>116</label>
			<element-citation>Mumford, M. D., &amp; McIntosh, T. 2017. Creative thinking processes: The past and the future. The Journal of Creative Behavior, 51(4), pp. 317–322.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R117">
			<label>117</label>
			<element-citation>Nieves, J., Quintana, A. and Osorio, J. 2016. Organizational knowledge and collaborative human resource practices as determinants of innovation. Knowledge management research &amp; practice, 14(3), pp. 237-245.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R118">
			<label>118</label>
			<element-citation>OECD (2005), Oslo Manual. Guidelines for Collecting and Interpreting Innovation Data (3rd ed.), Paris: OECD.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R119">
			<label>119</label>
			<element-citation>Parker, S. 2000. From Passive to Proactive Motivation: The Importance of Flexible Role Orientations and Role Breadth Self-Efficacy. Applied Psychology, 49, pp. 447–469.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R120">
			<label>120</label>
			<element-citation>pourteymour Farde Tabrizi, F., jamshidi, L. 2015. investigate the innovative performance through emerging knowledge based companies in Semnan University Incubator. Journal Of Industry And University, 7 (23), pp. 37-52.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R121">
			<label>121</label>
			<element-citation>Rajabi Farjad, H. 2016. Assessment of the Mediation Role of Knowledge Management in the Relationship between Human Resource Management and Innovation Practices. Research In Human Resources Management, 8 (3), pp. 239-265.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R122">
			<label>122</label>
			<element-citation>Rajabi, M Hassani, M., Mohajeran, B. 2017. The purpose of this paper is to examine the role of Human Resource management practices on innovation, test the role of mediator organizational learning and knowledge management among employers by Imam Khomeini Committee in West Azarbaijan. Innovation And Creativity In Human Sciences, 6 (3), pp. 151-178.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R123">
			<label>123</label>
			<element-citation>Rashidi, I., Shahraray, M. 2008. Investigate the relationship between creativity and control source. Educational Management Innovations (New Thoughts in Educational Sciences), 3 (3), pp. 81-99.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R124">
			<label>124</label>
			<element-citation>Revilla, Elena &amp; Rodriguez-Prado, Beatriz. 2018. Bulding ambidexterity through creativity mechanisms: Contextual drivers of innovation success. Research Policy. 47(9), pp. 1611-1625.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R125">
			<label>125</label>
			<element-citation>Salem IE-B .2014. Toward better understanding of knowledge management: Correlation to hotel performance and innovation in five-star chain hotels in Egypt. Tourism and Hospitality Research, 14(4), pp. 176–196.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R126">
			<label>126</label>
			<element-citation>Sarooghi, H., Libaers, D., Burkemper, A. 2015. Examining the relationship between creativity and innovation: a meta-analysis of organizational, cultural, and environmental factors. J. Bus. Ventur. 30 (5), 714–731.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R127">
			<label>127</label>
			<element-citation>Sayyed Naghavi, M. A., Pour Barkhordari, A. 2012. Role of Human Resources Management and Organizational Citizenship Behavior in Organizational Entrepreneurship. Naja Human Resources, 7 (28), pp.7- 28.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R128">
			<label>128</label>
			<element-citation>Talebi, K., Davari, A., najmabadi, A. 2012. The effect of intellectual capital on entrepreneurial opportunity recognition. Management Studies in Development and Evolution, 22 (71), pp. 19-48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R129">
			<label>129</label>
			<element-citation>Tenenhaus, M., Vinzi, V.E., Chatelin, Y.-M. and Lauro, C. 2005. PLS path modeling. Computational statistics &amp; data analysis, 48(1), pp. 159-205.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R130">
			<label>130</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, C; Ahmed, P. 2004. The development and validation of the organizational innovativeness construct using confirmatory factor analysis. European Journal of Innovation Management, 7(4), pp. 303–313.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R131">
			<label>131</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, P. et al. 2013. A workgroup climate perspective on the relationships among transformational leadership, workgroup diversity, and employee creativity. Group &amp; Organization Management, 38(3), pp. 334-360.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R132">
			<label>132</label>
			<element-citation>Wen Wu, S. 2010. Linking Bayesian networks and PLS path modeling for causal analysis. Expert Systems with Applications, 37 (1), pp. 134–139.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R133">
			<label>133</label>
			<element-citation>Yang, M.-L., Wang, A. M.-L., &amp; Cheng, K.-C. 2009. The impact of quality of is information and budget slack on innovation performance. Technovation, 29(8), pp. 527–536.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R134">
			<label>134</label>
			<element-citation>Zhang, X., and Bartol, K.M. 2010. Linking Empowering Leadership and Employee Creativity: The Influence of Psychological Empowerment, Intrinsic Motivation, and Creative Process Engagement. The Academy of Management Journal, 53, pp. 107–128.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R135">
			<label>135</label>
			<element-citation>Zhou, J., &amp; Shalley, C. E. 2003. Research on employee creativity: A critical review and directions for future research. Research in personnel and human resources management (pp. 165-217): Emerald Group Publishing Limited.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R136">
			<label>136</label>
			<element-citation>Zhou, K. Z. 2006. Innovation, imitation, and new product performance: The case of China. Industrial Marketing Management, 35(3), pp. 394-402.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86889_ecdda8d4491cd0cf830e6af75100f6b0.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>سیاست گذاری و مدیریت علم، فناوری، نوآوری و کارآفرینی و ارزیابی آن ها</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>شناسایی ابعاد و علل کاهش رضایت شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان در همکاری با صندوق‌های مالی از نگاه مجریان و سیاستگذاران: مطالعه موردی صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نقی زاده</surname>
			            <given-names>رضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>عضو هیات علمی مرکز تحقیقات سیاست علمی کشور</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>هاجری</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشجوی دکترای سیاست گذاری علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بساوند</surname>
			            <given-names>ساجده</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت فناوری</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>23</day>
			        <month>08</month>
			        <year>2018</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>92</fpage>
			      <lpage>120</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>09</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>24</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86889.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86889.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>با شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان به عنوان قلپ تپنده و محرک اصلی رشد و توسعه اقتصاد دانش بنیان از اهمیت فراوانی برخوردارند. با توجه به اهمیت این شرکت ها، شناسایی و برطرف ساختن چالش‌ها آنها از اهمیت ویژه ای برخوردار است. یکی از چالش های جدی شرکت های دانش بنیان تأمین سرمایه مالی مورد نیاز آنها، متناسب با مرحله توسعه این شرکت ها می‌باشد که با توجه به ماهیت متفاوت فعالیت آنان نیاز به ساز و کارهای متفاوتی نسبت به سایر بنگاه‌های اقتصادی دارد. درک لزوم تأمین سرمایه مالی در این شرکت‌ها اهمیت صندوق های تامین مالی حوزه فناوری همچون صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی را افزایش داده است و نوع تعامل شرکت های دانش بنیان و صندوق های تامین مالی و افزایش رضایتمندی شرکت های دانش بنیان به یکی از مسائل سیاستی در حوزه نوآوری تبدیل شده است. در این پژوهش تلاش شده است تا با استفاده از روش شناسی ترکیبی کمی و کیفی و با تمرکز بر استراتژی پژوهش مطالعه موردی، عوامل موثر بر کاهش رضایتمندی شرکت‌های دانش بنیان در همکاری با صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی از نگاه مجریان و سیاستگذاران شناسایی و تحلیل شوند. در همین راستا، بر اساس 18 عامل مؤثر شناسایی شده و بررسی آن در صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی، چارچوب عوامل موثر بر کاهش رضایتمندی شرکت‌های دانش بنیان در همکاری با صندوق های تامین مالی ارائه شد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان</kwd>
						<kwd>تأمین مالی</kwd>
						<kwd>صندوق‌های مالی</kwd>
						<kwd>صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی</kwd>
						<kwd>کاهش رضایتمندی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, . K. M., 1989. Building theories from case study research. Academy of management review, 14(4), pp. 532-550.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Jeston, J., Nelis, J. &amp; Davenport, T., 2008. Business Process Management: Practical Guidelines to Successful Implementations. s.l.:NV.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Kline, P., 2014. An easy guide to factor analysis. s.l.: Routledge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Maswadeh, S. N., 2015. An evaluation of SMEs satisfaction toward Jordanian Islamic banks service quality. Procedia economics and finance, Volume 23, pp. 86-94.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Phan, P., Siegel, D. S. &amp; Wright, M., 2005. Science parks and incubators: observations, synthesis and future research. Journal of Business Venturing, 20(2), pp. 165-182.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Saarenketo, S., Puumalainen, K., Kuivalai, O. &amp; Kyläheiko, K., 2004. Dynamic knowledge-related learning processes in internationalizing high-tech SMEs. nternational Journal of Production Economics, 89(3), pp. 363-378.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Sabir, . R. I. et al., 2014. Factors affecting customer satisfaction in banking sector of Pakistan. International Review of Management and Business Research, 3(2), pp. 1014-1025.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Skordoulis, M. &amp; Pekka-Economou, V., 2015. Analysis of the Factors Affecting Customers’ Satisfaction from the Greek Banks. Proceedings of eRA-10 International Scientific Conference: Economy I Session, pp. 32-40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Tallon, P., Kraemer, K. &amp; Gurbaxani, V., 2000. Executives’ Perceptions of the Business Value of Information Technology: A Process-Oriented Approach. Journal of Management Information Systems, 16(4), pp. 145-173.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Yin, R. K., 2003. Case Study Research, Design and Methods. s.l.:Sage Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Yin, R. K., 2012. Applications of Case Study Research. s.l.: SAGE Publications, Inc .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>ابوجعفری, ر. ا., الهی, ش., پیغامی, ع. و یاوری, ک., 1392. چارچوب مفهومی تحلیل بین سیستمی هولونیک: مطالعه نظری رابطه نظام مالی و نظام نوآوری. مدیریت نوآوری, 2(3), صص99-124.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>احمدی, پ. و پوراشرف, ی. ا., 1386. مسیر رضایتمندی مشتری در بانک های تجاری. مدرس علوم انسانی, 11(3), صص 29-58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>بازایی, ق. و رضائیان , ن., 1394. بررسی و رتبه بندی عوامل مؤثر بر رضایتمندی مشتریان بانک شهر از ارائه خدمات و رابطه آن با وفاداری به برند (مورد مطالعه: شعب بانک شهر در تهران). فصلنامه مدیریت کسب و کار, جلد شماره 27, صص 27-46.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>بشیری, ج., گیلوری, ع. و کولائیان, ف., 1394. میزان کاربست نتایج طرح‌های تحقیقاتی سازمان تحقیقات، آموزش و ترویج کشاورزی از نگاه مجریان طرح‌ها. فصلنامه علوم و فنون مدیریت اطلاعات, 1(1), صص 47-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>دهقان, ن. ا. و دهقان, . ک., ۱۳۸۸. شناسایی و اولویت بندی عوامل موثر بر رضایت مشتریان بانک ها. اولین کنفرانس بازاریابی خدمات بانکی، تهران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>رادفر, ر. و خمسه, ع., 1387. تبیین تأثیر شبکه سازی تحقیق و توسعه بر افزایش ارزش در شرکت­های کوچک. رشد فناوری, 4(14), صص 2-12.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>رنگریز, ح. و کرمی, ن., 1391. بررسی تاثیر رضایت و سهولت استفاده از وب سایت در افزایش سطح وفاداری مشتریان و تبلیغات دهان به دهان مثبت در خدمات بانکداری الکترونیکی (مطالعه موردی بانک ملت استان زنجان). مطالعات کمی در مدیریت, 3(1), صص 81-98.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>روانبند, ف., 1384. بررسی عوامل اصلی ایجاد و افزایش اعتماد در بین مشتریان کلیدی سیستم بانکی (مورد پژوهشی: مشتریان کلیدی بانک کارآفرین), تهران: پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد دانشگاه الزهرا (س).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی, 1395. عملکرد دو ساله صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی در دولت تدبیر و امید (1392-1394), تهران: صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی, 1397. گزارش اجمالی عملکرد صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی, تهران: صندوق نوآوری و شکوفایی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>طبرسا, غ., رضائیان, ع. و نظرپوری, ا., 1391. طراحی و تبیین مدل مزیت رقابتی مبتنی بر هوشمندی سازمانی در سازمان‌های دانش­بنیان. تحقیقات بازاریابی نوین, 2(1), صص 47-72.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>عبدالوند, م. و عبدلی, ک., 1387. بررسی عوامل موثر بر وفاداری مشتریان بانک تجارت. مجله مدیریت بازاریابی, 3(5), صص 1-20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>عزیزی, م. و ملایجردی, م., 1396. روش های تأمین مالی کارآفرینی اجتماعی. تحقیقات مالی, 19(1), صص 119-138.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>فخاری, ح., سلیمانی, د. و دارایی, م., 1392. بررسی اثرات تحریم های اقتصادی بر عملکرد شرکت­های دانش­بنیان کشور. سیاست علم و فناوری, 5(3), صص 1-16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>قاضی نوری نائینی, س. س., سرکیسیان, آ. و علیزاده, پ., 1388. دولت و کارآفرینی تکنولوژیک: مقدمه ای بر سیاست های حمایت از شرکت­های تازه تأسیس تکنولوژی محور. تهران: مرکز آموزش و تحقیقات صنعتی ایران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>قاضی نوری, س. س., بامداد صوفی, ج. و ردائی, ن., 1396. چارچوب انتخاب ابزارهای تامین مالی بر اساس خوشه بندی شرکت­های دانش­بنیان. سیاست علم و فناوری, 9(2), صص 13-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>قانون حمایت از شرکت­ها و مؤسسات­دانش بنیان, 1389.تهران: مجلس شورای اسلامی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>کارگروه ارزیابی و تشخیص صلاحیت شرکت­ها و موسسات دانش­بنیان, 1397. وب سایت کارگروه ارزیابی و تشخیص صلاحیت شرکت­ها و مؤسسات دانش­بنیان.   http://daneshbonyan.isti.ir [دستیابی در 1397].</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>کاوسی, س. و سقائی, ع., 1393. روشهای اندازه گیری رضایت مشتری. تهران: آمه.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>گلعلی زاده, م., طباطبائیان, س. ح. ا. و زعفرانیان, ر., 1387. ارائه راهکار سیستمی ایجاد نهادهایی جهت تأمین مالی بنگاه های نوپا دانش­بنیان در ایران. پارک فناوری پردیس, جلد 17, صص 46-52.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>گوهری, م., 1393. تعیین و طبقه بندی عوامل مؤثر بر رضایت مشتریان بانک. ماهنامه داخلی بانک اقتصاد نوین, صص 30-38.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>محمدی, س., 1390. بررسی و رتبه‌بندی عوامل موثر بر رضایت مشتریان بانکی (مطالعه موردی: مدیریت شعب منطقه 5 بانک ملت), مکان نشر نامشخص: پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>محمدی, ع. و حسین زاده, ح., 1387. برنامه­ریزی راهبردی و نقش آن در تحول سازمان­های دانش­بنیان. فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی, جلد 31, صص 29-48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>مختاری, غ., 1387. روش های نوین مشتری­مداری و بازاریابی علمی در بانکداری ایران. دانش بانکداری, جلد شماره 29 و 30, صص 46-48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>مسلمی, ن. و موسوی, ع., 1394. ارزیابی کیفیت برنامه­ریزی درسی از دیدگاه مجریان آموزش سازمان آموزش فنی و حرفه ای کشور. مهارت آموزی, 14(4), صص 57-68.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>نقی زاده, ر., الهی, ش. و منطقی, م., 1395. الگوی توسعه نوآوری­های فناورانه در مناطق ایران؛ مطالعه موردی فناوری­های زیستی، نانو، اطلاعات و ارتباطات و هوایی. فصلنامه سیاست علم و فناوری, جلد 29, صص 43-60._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation> Abdolvand, M. A. &amp; Abdoli, K., 2008 . Investigating Factors Influencing Tejarat bank's Customer Loyalty. Journal of Marketing Management, 3(5), pp. 1-20 (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Aboojafari, R., Elahi, S., Paighami, A. &amp; Yavari, K., 2013. A Conceptual Framework for Holonic Inter-System Analysis: A Theoretical Study of the Relationship between Financial and Innovation Systems. Innovation Management Journal, 2(3), pp. 99-124. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Ahmadi, P. &amp; Pourashraf, Y., 2007. Customer's Path to Satisfaction at Commercial Banks. Management Research in Iran, 11(3), pp. 29-58. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Azizi, M. &amp; Malayjerdi, M., 2017. Social Entrepreneurship Financing Methods. Financial Research Journal, 19(1), pp. 119-139. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Bashiri, J., Gilvari, A. &amp; Koulaian, F., 2016. The Application of the Results of Research Projects of the Agricultural Research, Education and Extension Organization as Viewed by the Researchers. Science and Technologies of Information Management, 1(1), pp. 47-68. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Bazayi, G. A. &amp; Rezaeian, N., 2015. Investigating and ranking the affecting factors on the Shahr Bank customers satisfaction from the provision of services and its relationship with brand loyalty (Case study: The Shahr Bank Branches in Tehran). Journal of Business Management, Volume 27, pp. 27-46. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Dehghan, N. o. l. &amp; Dehghan, K., 2009. Identifying and prioritizing affecting factors of banks customer satisfaction. Tehran, The First International Conference of Banking Services Marketing. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenhardt, . K. M., 1989. Building theories from case study research. Academy of management review, 14(4), pp. 532-550.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Fakhari, H., Salmani, D. &amp; Daraei, M. R., 2013. The Impact of Economic Sanctions on the Knowledge-Based Companies in Iran. Journal of Science &amp; Technology Policy, 5(3), pp. 1-16 (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Working Group on Assessment and Recognition of Knowledge Based Firms. Available at: http://daneshbonyan.isti.ir/. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Ghazinoori, S., Bamdad Soofi, J. &amp; Radaei, N., 2017. A Framework for Selecting Financing Instruments Based on Knowledge-Based Firms Clustering. Journal of Science &amp; Technology Policy, 9(2), pp. 13-30. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Ghazinoori, S. S., Sirkisian, A. &amp; Alizadeh, P., 2009. Government and Technological Entrepreneurship: An Introduction to Policy Support for Newly Founded Technology Based Firms. Tehran: Industrial Research &amp; Training Center of Iran. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Gohari, M., 2014. Identifying and classifying the affecting factors of customer satisfaction. Monthly Journal of the Eghtesad Novin Bank, pp. 30-38. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Golalizadeh, M. R., Tabatabaeeian, s. H. &amp; Zaeferanian, R., 2008. Providing a systemic solution for establishing institutions to fund the newly established knowledge-based firms in Iran.. Pardis Technology Park, Volume 17, pp. 46-52. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Innovation and Prosperity Fund, 2017. Two-year performance of Iran Innovation and Prosperity Fund in the government of Tadbir and Omid (1392-1394), Tehran: Innovation and Prosperity Fund. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Innovation and Prosperity Fund, 2018. Overview of Iran Innovation and Prosperity Fund Performance, Tehran: Innovation and Prosperity Fund. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Jeston, J., Nelis, J. &amp; Davenport, T., 2008. Business Process Management: Practical Guidelines to Successful Implementations. s.l.:NV.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Kavoosi, S. M. R. &amp; Saghaee, A., 2006. Methods of customer satisfaction measurement. 4 ed. Tehran: Ameh Book.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Kline, P., 2014. An easy guide to factor analysis. s.l.: Routledge. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Maswadeh, S. N., 2015. An evaluation of SMEs satisfaction toward Jordanian Islamic banks service quality. Procedia economics and finance, Volume 23, pp. 86-94.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammadi, A. R. &amp; Hosein Zadeh, H., 2008. Strategic Planning and its Role in the Evolution of Knowledge Based Institutions. A Research Quarterly In Military Management, Volume 31, pp. 29-48. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammadi, S., 2011. Investigating and ranking the affecting factors on the satisfaction of banking customers (Case study: Managing Branches of District 5 of Mellat Bank), s.l.: M.A Thesis, Islamic Azad University of Central Tehran Branch, Faculty of Management. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Mokhtari, G. R., 2008. New methods of customer orientation and scientific marketing in Iranian banking. Banking Knowledge, Volume 29 &amp; 30, pp. 46-48. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Moslemi, N. &amp; Moosavi, A., 2016 . Evaluating the quality of curricula from the perspective of education executives Technical and Vocational Training Organization (Case study: profession of an industrial electrician, and building electrician). Skill Training, 14(4), pp. 57-68. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Naghizadeh, R., Elahi, S. &amp; Manteghi, M., 2016. The Pattern Of Technological Innovation Development In The Regions Of Iran; The Case Of BIO, NANO, AERO and ICT. Journal of Science &amp; Technology Policy, 8(1), pp. 43-60. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Phan, P., Siegel, D. S. &amp; Wright, M., 2005. Science parks and incubators: observations, synthesis and future research. Journal of Business Venturing, 20(2), pp. 165-182.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Radfar, R. &amp; Khamse, A., 2008. Explanation of Research and Developments Networking Effect in the Valus Improvement of SMEs. Roshd-e-Fanavari, 4(14), pp. 2-12. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Rangriz, H. &amp; Karami, N., 2011. The Impact Of Satisfaction And Website Usability In Developing Customer Loyalty And Positive Word-Of-Mouth In The E-Banking Services (Case Study: Zanjan Province Mellat Bank). Quantitative Researches in Management, 3(1), pp. 81-98. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Ravanband, F., 2005. Investigating the main factors of creating and increasing trust among key customers of the banking system (Case Study: Key Customers of the KarAfarini Bank), Tehran: M.A Thesis, Alzahra University. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Saarenketo, S., Puumalainen, K., Kuivalai, O. &amp; Kyläheiko, K., 2004. Dynamic knowledge-related learning processes in internationalizing high-tech SMEs. nternational Journal of Production Economics, 89(3), pp. 363-378.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Sabir, . R. I. et al., 2014. Factors affecting customer satisfaction in banking sector of Pakistan. International Review of Management and Business Research, 3(2), pp. 1014-1025.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Skordoulis, M. &amp; Pekka-Economou, V., 2015. Analysis of the Factors Affecting Customers’ Satisfaction from the Greek Banks. Proceedings of eRA-10 International Scientific Conference: Economy I Session, pp. 32-40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Tabarsa, G., Rezaeian, A. &amp; Nazarpouri, A., 2012. Designing and Describing the Model of Competitive Advantage based on Organizational Intelligence in Knowledge-Based Organizations. Journal of New Marketing Research, 2(1), pp. 47-72. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Tallon, P., Kraemer, K. &amp; Gurbaxani, V., 2000. Executives’ Perceptions of the Business Value of Information Technology: A Process-Oriented Approach. Journal of Management Information Systems.16(4). pp. 145-173.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>The Law of Protecting the Knowledge-Based Firms, 2010. The Law of Protecting the Knowledge-Based Firms and Institutions and the Commercialization of Innovations and Inventions, Tehran: Parliament of Islamic Republic of Iran. (In Persian)</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Yin, R. K., 2003. Case Study Research, Design and Methods. s.l.:Sage Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Yin, R. K., 2012. Applications of Case Study Research. s.l.: SAGE Publications, Inc .</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86886_a7b338d8129ce6c5699ad8a659a21886.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>ساختارها و فرآیندهای پشتیبان نوآوری</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>عوامل مؤثر بر موفقیت شتاب دهنده های حوزه زیست فناوری در ایران</article-title>
			        <subtitle>عوامل مؤثر بر موفقیت شتاب دهنده های حوزه زیست فناوری در ایران</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>گودرزی</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نقی زاده</surname>
			            <given-names>محمد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>استادیار دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>بیگلر</surname>
			            <given-names>احسان</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>23</day>
			        <month>08</month>
			        <year>2018</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>95</fpage>
			      <lpage>112</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>24</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>02</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86886.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86886.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>ظهور پدیده شتابدهنده ها مسیری نوین پیش روی کارآفرینان و کسب‌و‌کارهای نوپا گذاشته است. ویژگی های خاص حوزه زیست فناوری و همچنین جدید بودن مفهوم شتابدهنده ها در ایران، شناخت عوامل موفقیت این موسسات را ضروری می نماید. در فرایند انجام این پژوهش، بیست عامل کلیدی موفقیت در حوزه مورد نظر با مطالعه پژوهش های پیشین و مصاحبه های صورت گرفته با مدیران و خبرگان شتاب دهنده های زیست فناوری که می تواند باعث موفقیت شتاب دهنده ها شود، شناسایی گردید. پس از طراحی پرسشنامه و توزیع آن بین نمونه منتخب و جمع آوری نظرات، با استفاده از آزمون دوجمله ای تعداد یازده عامل مهم در چهار مرحله آگاهی، انتخاب و ثبت‏نام، برنامه شتابدهی و در نهایت روز نمایش شناسایی گردید. عواملی همچون اهداف استراتژیک شتاب دهنده برای توسعه و حمایت از تیم ها، معیارهای بررسی تیم ها بر اساس ایده، توانایی و جذابیت توسط شتاب دهنده، خدمات ارائه شده توسط شتاب دهنده به تیم ها، نحوه اجرای برنامه آموزش و میزان انعطاف پذیری آن نسبت به زمان استقرار تیم ها، دسترسی شتاب دهنده به شبکه بازارها، مشتریان و سرمایه گذاران در طول برنامه شتابدهی و عامل دسترسی به شبکه سرمایه گذاران برای تزریق سرمایه بعد از پایان برنامه به تیم های خروجی برخی از عوامل مهم را شکل می دهند.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>شتاب دهنده</kwd>
						<kwd>زیست فناوری</kwd>
						<kwd>عامل موفقیت</kwd>
						<kwd>مرکز رشد</kwd>
						<kwd>شرکت نوپا</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>AERTS et al. (2007). Critical role and screening practices of European business incubator. Technovation, 27(5).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Barrehag, Barrehag, L., Fornell, A., Larsson, V., Mardstrom, V., Vestergard, V., et al. (2012). Accelerating Success: A Study of Seed Accelerators and Their Defining Characteristics. Gothenburg,: CHALMERS UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Bergek and Norrman. (2008). Incubator best practice: a framework. Technovation, 28.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Blank. (2006). The Four Steps to the Epiphany: Successful Strategies for Products that Win (second ed.). Lulu.com .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Blank, S. and B. Dorf. (2012). The Startup Owner's Manual,. K&amp;S Ranch (publishers),.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Bound and Miller. (2011). ‘The Startup Factories: The rise of accelerator programmes to support new technology ventures. London: NESTA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Butcher. (2011). Seed camp named top European Accelerator, with Startup boot campclosing in TechCrunch Europe, Hot topics.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Carr. (2012). Are Accelerators Losing Speed. Fast Company. Retrieved 8 6, 2016, from http://www.fastcompany.com/3000036/techstars-david-tisch-highly-recommends-well-techstars.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Carr, A. (2012). Are Accelerators Losing Speed. Fast Company. Retrieved 8 6, 2016, from http://www.fastcompany.com/3000036/techstars-david-tisch-highly-recommends-well-techstars.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Christiansen. (2009). Copying Y Combinator: A Framework for developing Seed Accelerator Programmes. Cambridge: University of Cambridge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Christiansen. (2009). Copying Y Combinator: A Framework for developing Seed Accelerator Programmes. Cambridge: University of Cambridge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Clarysse, B. , B., &amp; Yusubova, A. (2014). Success factors of business accelerators. Technology Business Incubation Mechanisms and Sustainable Regional Development.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Cohen. (2014). What Do Accelerators Do? Insights from Incubators and Angels. Innovations: Technology, Governance, Globalization , 8(3-4), 19-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Dempwolf, C., Auer, J., &amp; D'lppolito, M. (2014). Innovation Accelerators:. Small Business Administration, Office of Advocacy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Drof, R., &amp; Byers, T. (2005). Technology ventures: From idea to enterprise. New York: McGraw-Hill.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Hoffman, D., &amp; Radojevich-Kelley, N. (2012). Analysis of Accelerator Companies: An Exploratory Case Study of Their Programs, Processes, and Early Results. Small Business Institute Journal.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Isabelle, D. (2013). Key Factors Affecting a Technology Entrepreneur’s Choice of Incubator or Accelerator. Technology innovation management review.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>isfahanplus. (1396). https://isfahanplus.ir. Retrieved 2 5, 1396, from https://isfahanplus.ir/%D9%84%DB%8C%D8%B3%D8%AA-%D8%B4%D8%AA%D8%A7%D8%A8-%D8%AF%D9%87%D9%86%D8%AF%D9%87-%D9%87%D8%A7%DB%8C-%D8%A7%DB%8C%D8%B1%D8%A7%D9%86/</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Kim, J.-H., &amp; Wagman, L. (2012). Early-Stage Financing and Information Gathering: An Analysis of Startup Accelerators.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Konczal. (2012). Evaluating the Effects of Accelerators? Not So Fast. Forbes,. Retrieved 6 16, 2016, from http://www.forbes.com/sites/kauffman/2012/08/08/evaluating-the-effects-of-accelerators-not-so-fast.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Lall et al. (2013). Bridging the “Pioneer Gap”: The Role of Accelerators in Launching High-Impact Enterprises. Innovations: technology, governance globalization,, 8, 105-137.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Miller, P., &amp; Bound, K. (2011). The Startup Factories: The rise of accelerator programmes to support new technology ventures. Nesta.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Norton, p. P. (2005). Biotechnology in India. Drug discovery today, 10(16).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Pauwels, C., Clarysse, B., Wright, M., &amp; Van Hove, J. (2016). Understanding a new generation incubation model: The accelerator. Technovation.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Peng, X., &amp; Zhang, G. (2008). The Moderating Effect of Governance Form on the Relationship between Corporate Technological Entrepreneurship Activities and Corporate Financial Performance: An Empirical Study on Chinese High-Tech Firms. Cape Town: PICMET.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Smytan. (2012). Where to get help and money for startups in California. The complete guide: Angel investors, accelerators, incubators for seed and early-stage funding.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Teague. (2000). Technopreneurs. Design News, 55(14).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>اعیانی ثانی, ا., &amp; شریف, ح. (1393). سرعت بخشی فرآیند تجاریسازی فناوری های تجارت الکترونیک از طریق ایجاد و توسعه شتاب دهنده کسب و کار. دومین کنفرانس بین المللی تجاری سازی فناوری. تهران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>تابش و همکاران. (1394). شناخت دره سیلیکون. معاونت علمی و فناوری ریاست جمهوری اسلمی ایران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>صالحی, م. (1396). تعداد شرکتهای دانش بنیان در حوزه زیست فناوری. Retrieved شهریور 15, 1396, from خبرگزاری مهر: mehrnews.com/news/4080408</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>صیادی تورانلو، , ح., منصوری،, ح., &amp; جمالی، , ر. (1387). شناسایی و رتبه بندی ابعاد کیفیت خدمات کتابخانه ای با رویکرد فازی (مطالعه مورد: کتابخانه های دانشگاه یزد. فصلنامه کتابداری و اطلاع رسانی, 11(44).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>قاسم شربیانی، رادفر و عابدی. (1389). الگوی مناسب تجاری سازی زیست فناوری در حوزه محیط زیست. کنفرانس مدیریت فناوری. تهران: انجمن مدیریت فناوری.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>سلطانی لرگانی. (1388). ارزیابی کارایی زیست فناوری در کشف علمی جرایم (با تاکید بر فناوری DNA). کارآگاه, 6(2)._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>AERTS et al. (2007). Critical role and screening practices of European business incubator. Technovation, 27(5).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Barrehag, Barrehag, L., Fornell, A., Larsson, V., Mardstrom, V., Vestergard, V., et al. (2012). Accelerating Success: A Study of Seed Accelerators and Their Defining Characteristics. Gothenburg,: CHALMERS UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Bergek and Norrman. (2008). Incubator best practice: a framework. Technovation, 28.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Blank. (2006). The Four Steps to the Epiphany: Successful Strategies for Products that Win (second ed.). Lulu.com .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Blank, S. and B. Dorf. (2012). The Startup Owner's Manual,. K&amp;S Ranch (publishers),.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Bound and Miller. (2011). ‘The Startup Factories: The rise of accelerator programmes to support new technology ventures. London: NESTA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Butcher. (2011). Seed camp named top European Accelerator, with Startup boot campclosing in TechCrunch Europe, Hot topics.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Carr. (2012). Are Accelerators Losing Speed. Fast Company. Retrieved 8 6, 2016, from http://www.fastcompany.com/3000036/techstars-david-tisch-highly-recommends-well-techstars.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Carr, A. (2012). Are Accelerators Losing Speed. Fast Company. Retrieved 8 6, 2016, from http://www.fastcompany.com/3000036/techstars-david-tisch-highly-recommends-well-techstars.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Christiansen. (2009). Copying Y Combinator: A Framework for developing Seed Accelerator Programmes. Cambridge: University of Cambridge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Christiansen. (2009). Copying Y Combinator: A Framework for developing Seed Accelerator Programmes. Cambridge: University of Cambridge.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Clarysse, B. , B., &amp; Yusubova, A. (2014). Success factors of business accelerators. Technology Business Incubation Mechanisms and Sustainable Regional Development.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Cohen. (2014). What Do Accelerators Do? Insights from Incubators and Angels. Innovations: Technology, Governance, Globalization , 8(3-4), 19-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Dempwolf, C., Auer, J., &amp; D'lppolito, M. (2014). Innovation Accelerators:. Small Business Administration, Office of Advocacy.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Drof, R., &amp; Byers, T. (2005). Technology ventures: From idea to enterprise. New York: McGraw-Hill.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Hoffman, D., &amp; Radojevich-Kelley, N. (2012). Analysis of Accelerator Companies: An Exploratory Case Study of Their Programs, Processes, and Early Results. Small Business Institute Journal.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Isabelle, D. (2013). Key Factors Affecting a Technology Entrepreneur’s Choice of Incubator or Accelerator. Technology innovation management review.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>isfahanplus. (1396). https://isfahanplus.ir. Retrieved 2 5, 1396, from https://isfahanplus.ir/%D9%84%DB%8C%D8%B3%D8%AA-%D8%B4%D8%AA%D8%A7%D8%A8-%D8%AF%D9%87%D9%86%D8%AF%D9%87-%D9%87%D8%A7%DB%8C-%D8%A7%DB%8C%D8%B1%D8%A7%D9%86/</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Kim, J.-H., &amp; Wagman, L. (2012). Early-Stage Financing and Information Gathering: An Analysis of Startup Accelerators.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Konczal. (2012). Evaluating the Effects of Accelerators? Not So Fast. Forbes,. Retrieved 6 16, 2016, from http://www.forbes.com/sites/kauffman/2012/08/08/evaluating-the-effects-of-accelerators-not-so-fast.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Lall et al. (2013). Bridging the “Pioneer Gap”: The Role of Accelerators in Launching High-Impact Enterprises. Innovations: technology, governance globalization,, 8, 105-137.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Miller, P., &amp; Bound, K. (2011). The Startup Factories: The rise of accelerator programmes to support new technology ventures. Nesta.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Norton, p. P. (2005). Biotechnology in India. Drug discovery today, 10(16).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Pauwels, C., Clarysse, B., Wright, M., &amp; Van Hove, J. (2016). Understanding a new generation incubation model: The accelerator. Technovation.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Peng, X., &amp; Zhang, G. (2008). The Moderating Effect of Governance Form on the Relationship between Corporate Technological Entrepreneurship Activities and Corporate Financial Performance: An Empirical Study on Chinese High-Tech Firms. Cape Town: PICMET.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Smytan. (2012). Where to get help and money for startups in California. The complete guide: Angel investors, accelerators, incubators for seed and early-stage funding.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Teague. (2000). Technopreneurs. Design News, 55(14).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>اعیانی ثانی, ا., &amp; شریف, ح. (1393). سرعت بخشی فرآیند تجاریسازی فناوری های تجارت الکترونیک از طریق ایجاد و توسعه شتاب دهنده کسب و کار. دومین کنفرانس بین المللی تجاری سازی فناوری. تهران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>تابش و همکاران. (1394). شناخت دره سیلیکون. معاونت علمی و فناوری ریاست جمهوری اسلمی ایران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>صالحی, م. (1396). تعداد شرکتهای دانش بنیان در حوزه زیست فناوری. Retrieved شهریور 15, 1396, from خبرگزاری مهر: mehrnews.com/news/4080408</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>صیادی تورانلو، , ح., منصوری،, ح., &amp; جمالی، , ر. (1387). شناسایی و رتبه بندی ابعاد کیفیت خدمات کتابخانه ای با رویکرد فازی (مطالعه مورد: کتابخانه های دانشگاه یزد. فصلنامه کتابداری و اطلاع رسانی, 11(44).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>قاسم شربیانی، رادفر و عابدی. (1389). الگوی مناسب تجاری سازی زیست فناوری در حوزه محیط زیست. کنفرانس مدیریت فناوری. تهران: انجمن مدیریت فناوری.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>سلطانی لرگانی. (1388). ارزیابی کارایی زیست فناوری در کشف علمی جرایم (با تاکید بر فناوری DNA). کارآگاه, 6(2).</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86989_71cb8640d39f3916db64ba1693b5d58a.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
					          		<subject>نوآوری باز و شبکه های نوآوری</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>استراتژی های راه انداری یک کسب و کار پلتفرمی در صنعت بانکی و پرداخت</article-title>
			        <subtitle>استراتژی های راه انداری یک کسب و کار پلتفرمی در صنعت بانکی و پرداخت</subtitle>
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>کیال</surname>
			            <given-names>کاظم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشکده مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>البدوی</surname>
			            <given-names>امیر</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>گروه مهندسی فناوری اطلاعات، دانشکده مهندسی صنایع و سیستم‌ها، دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>23</day>
			        <month>08</month>
			        <year>2018</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>7</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>142</fpage>
			      <lpage>168</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>15</day>
			          <month>12</month>
			          <year>2018</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>28</day>
			          <month>04</month>
			          <year>2019</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2018, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2018</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86989.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86989.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>در دهه‌های اخیر نیاز به نوآوری از یک سو و هزینه های زیاد توسعه آن از سوی دیگر، موجب شده است تا بنگاه‌های اقتصادی بیش از پیش از رویکرد نوآوری باز استفاده کنند. یکی از مدل‌های پیاده‌سازی این رویکرد، پلتفرمی‌کردن کسب و کار بنگاه است که در سال‌های اخیر پژوهش های زیادی را به خود اختصاص داده است. با این حال، نیاز به تحقیقاتی برای استراتژی های اصلی کسب و کارهای پلتفرمی در کشور ایران با شرایط اقتصادی ویژه خود، وجود دارد. علاوه بر این در هر صنعتی با توجه به ویژگی های خاص آن، این استراتژی ها می تواند متفاوت باشد. هدف از این تحقیق ارائه استراتژی های عملی برای راه‌اندازی یک کسب و کار پلتفرمی در صنعت بانکی و پرداخت ایران است. در این تحقیق پس از مرور مقالات مختلف در حوزه کسب و کارهای پلتفرمی، اطلاعاتی بر اساس مصاحبه‌های نیمه ساختار یافته و منابع آرشیوی جمع آوری شده و با استفاده از روش نظریه‌پردازی داده بنیاد، تحلیل و بررسی شده است. بانک‌ها می توانند برای پلتفرمی کردن کسب و کار خود از پنج استراتژی اصلی &quot;ارائه سرویس به صورت محدود&quot;، &quot;ایجاد پلتفرم عمومی&quot;، &quot;الحاق به یک پلتفرم موجود&quot;، &quot;مشارکت در ایجاد و مدیریت پلتفرم&quot; و &quot;سرمایه گذاری&quot; استفاده کنند.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>نوآوری باز</kwd>
						<kwd>پلتفرم</kwd>
						<kwd>کسب و کار پلتفرمی</kwd>
						<kwd>استراژی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Akamavi, R.K., 2005. A research agenda for investigation of product innovation in the financial services sector. Journal of Services Marketing, 19(6), pp.359-378.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Babcock, C., 2011. Easy-to-use APIs key to business growth. Information Week, 1313, p.14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Baldwin, C.Y. and Clark, K.B., 2000. Design rules: The power of modularity (Vol. 1). MIT press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Belussi, F., Sammarra, A. and Sedita, S.R., 2010. Learning at the boundaries in an “Open Regional Innovation System”: A focus on firms’ innovation strategies in the Emilia Romagna life science industry. Research Policy, 39(6), pp.710-721.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Birkinshaw, J., Bessant, J. and Delbridge, R., 2007. Finding, forming, and performing: Creating networks for discontinuous innovation. California management review, 49(3), pp.67-84.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Boudreau, K., 2007. Does opening a platform stimulate innovation? The effect on systemic and modular innovations.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Boudreau, K., 2008. Opening the platform vs. opening the complementary good? The effect on product innovation in handheld computing. HEC working paper available on SSRN; abstract=1251167.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Boudreau, K.J. and Hagiu, A., 2009. Platform rules: Multi-sided platforms as regulators. Platforms, markets and innovation, 1, pp.163-191.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Bresnahan, T.F. and Greenstein, S., 1999. Technological competition and the structure of the computer industry. The Journal of Industrial Economics, 47(1), pp.1-40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Creswell, J. W. 2005. Educational Research: Planning. Conducting and Evaluating Quantitative and Qualitative Research (2nd edition).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Caillaud, B., and Jullien, B., 2003. Chicken &amp; egg: Competition among intermediation service providers. RAND journal of Economics,34(2), pp. 309-328</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Charmaz, K., 2000. Grounded Theory: objectivist and constructivist methods in Norman K. Denzin and Yvonne S. Lincoln (eds.) Handbook of Qualitative Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H.W., 2003. Open innovation: The new imperative for creating and profiting from technology. Boston: Harvard Business School Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H., 2006. Open innovation: a new paradigm for understanding industrial innovation. Open innovation: Researching a new paradigm, 400, pp.0-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H., Vanhaverbeke, W. and West, J., 2006. Open Innovation: Researching a New Paradigm. Oxford: Oxford University Press. </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H. and Crowther, A.K., 2006. Beyond high tech: early adopters of open innovation in other industries. R&amp;d Management, 36(3), pp.229-236.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Cusumano, M.A. and Gawer, A., 2002. The elements of platform leadership. MIT Sloan management review, 43(3), p.51.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Dittrich, K. and Duysters, G., 2007. Networking as a means to strategy change: the case of open innovation in mobile telephony. Journal of product innovation management, 24(6), pp.510-521.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenmann, T., Parker, G. and Van Alstyne, M.W., 2006. Strategies for two-sided markets. Harvard business review, 84(10), p.92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenmann, T.R., Parker, G. and Van Alstyne, M., 2009. Opening platforms: how, when and why?. Platforms, markets and innovation, pp.131-162.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenmann, T.R., Parker, G. and Van Alstyne, M., 2011. Platform Envelopment. Strategic Management Journal 32(12) 1270-1285.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Enkel, E., Gassmann, O. and Chesbrough, H., 2009. Open R&amp;D and open innovation: exploring the phenomenon. R&amp;d Management, 39(4), pp.311-316.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Evans, D., Hagiu, A. and Schmalensee, R., 2006. Invisible Engines: How Software Platforms Drive Innovation and Transform Industries (Vol. 1). The MIT Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Farrell, J., Monroe, H.K. and Saloner, G., 1998. The vertical organization of industry: Systems competition versus component competition. Journal of Economics &amp; Management Strategy, 7(2), pp.143-182.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Gawer, A. and Cusumano, M.A., 2002. Platform leadership: How Intel, Microsoft, and Cisco drive industry innovation (Vol. 5, pp. 29-30). Boston, MA: Harvard Business School Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Gawer, A. and Henderson, R., 2007. Platform owner entry and innovation in complementary markets: Evidence from Intel. Journal of Economics &amp; Management Strategy, 16(1), pp.1-34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Gawer, A., 2009. Platforms, Markets and Innovation: An Introduction. Edward Elgar Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Glaser, B. and Strauss, A.1967. Discovery of grounded theory: Strategies for qualitative research. Chicago: Alidline.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Greenstein, S., 1998. Industrial economics and strategy: Computing platforms. IEEE Micro, 18(3), pp.43-53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Henderson, R.M. and Clark, K.B., 1990. Architectural innovation: The reconfiguration of existing product technologies and the failure of established firms. Administrative science quarterly, pp.9-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Komninos, N., 2004. Regional Intelligence: distributed localised information systems for innovation and development. International Journal of Technology Management, 28(3-6), pp.483-506.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Lee, J., 2001. A Grounded Theory: Integration and Internalization in ERP Adoption and Use, Unpublished Doctoral Dissertation, University of Nebreska, In Proquest UMI Database.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Martovoy, A., Mention, A.L. and Torkkely, M., 2012. Role of the inbound open innovation in banking services. Proceedings of the 2nd Innovation for Financial Services Summit. Luxembourg: Public Research Centre Henri Tudor.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Martovoy, A. and Dos Santos, J., 2012. Co-creation and co-profiting in financial services. International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Innovation Management 1, 16(1-2), pp.114-135.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Mention, A.L. and Martovoy, A., 2013. Open and collaborative innovation in banking services: Evidence from Luxembourg. Luxembourg-Kirchberg: Public Research Centre Henri Tudor.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Nambisan, S. and Sawhney, M., 2007. A buyer's guide to the innovation bazaar. Harvard Business Review, 85(6), pp.109-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Nieto, M.J. and Santamaría, L., 2007. The importance of diverse collaborative networks for the novelty of product innovation. Technovation, 27(6-7), pp.367-377.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Oliveira, P. and von Hippel, E., 2011. Users as service innovators: The case of banking services. Research policy, 40(6), pp.806-818.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Parker, G.G. and Van Alstyne, M.W., 2000, October. Internetwork externalities and free information goods. In Proceedings of the 2nd ACM Conference on Electronic Commerce (pp. 107-116). ACM.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Parker, G.G. and Van Alstyne, M.W., 2005. Two-sided network effects: A theory of information product design. Management science, 51(10), pp.1494-1504.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Parker, G and Van Alstyne, M., 2008. Managing Platform Ecosystems. In Proceedings of the 29th International Conference on Information Systems, Paris, France, December 14-17.Paper 53. http://aisel.aisnet.org/icis2008/53</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Parker, G. and Van Alstyne, M., 2012. A digital postal platform: Definitions and a roadmap. MIT Center for Digital Business, Working Paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Rochet, J.C. and Tirole, J., 2003. Platform competition in two‐sided markets. Journal of the european economic association, 1(4), pp.990-1029.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Schueffel, P.E. and Vadana, I.I., 2015. Open Innovation in the Financial Services Sector-A global literature review. Journal of innovation management, 3(1), pp.25-48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Shapiro, C., Varian, H.R. and Becker, W.E., 1999. Information rules: a strategic guide to the network economy. Journal of Economic Education, 30, pp.189-190.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Strauss, A. and Corbin, J., 1998. Basics of Qualitative Research: Techniques and Procedures for Developing Grounded Theory, 2nd Ed., Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Van Alstyne, M.W., Parker, G.G. and Choudary, S.P., 2016. Pipelines, platforms, and the new rules of strategy. Harvard business review, 94(4), pp.54-62.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Vanhaverbeke, W., 2011. The benefits of open innovation in low tech SMEs: The quilts of Denmark story.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>West, J., 2003. How open is open enough?: Melding proprietary and open source platform strategies. Research policy, 32(7), pp.1259-1285.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Zeng, S.X., Xie, X.M. and Tam, C.M., 2010. Relationship between cooperation networks and innovation performance of SMEs. Technovation, 30(3), pp.181-194.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>ادیب حاج باقری، محسن. 1385. روش تحقیق گراند تئوری: راه و روش نظریه پردازی در علوم انسانی و بهداشتی. تهران. انتشارات بشری.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>استروالدر، الکساندر، پیگنیور، ایو. 1391. خلق مدل کسب و کار. ترجمه توکلی، غلامرضا، وطن دوست، بابک، ساروقی، حسام الدین، توفیقی، بهامین. تهران. انتشارات آریانا قلم.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>افسری، مهران. 1394. معرفی دو روش برای تحقق بانکداری باز / چرا به بانکداری باز نیاز داریم؟. وب سایت راه پرداخت. قابل دسترس در: https://way2pay.ir/49129 </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>باقری نژاد جعفر، جاوید غزاله. 1393. ارائه مدل نوآوری باز در صنعت بانکداری ایران : مطالعه موردی بانک پارسیان. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی نوآوری و ارزش­آفرینی، (۵)، ۲۱-۴۲</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>تید، جو. بسنت، جان. 1394. ترجمه آراستی، محمدرضا و همکاران. مدیریت نوآوری یکپارچه سازی تغییرات فناورانه، بازار و زمان. تهران. انتشارات رسا.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>چسبرو، ه.1389. ترجمه باقری س. ک.، شاوردی م. نوآوری باز پارادایم نوین آفرینش و تجاری‌سازی فناوری. تهران. انتشارات رسا</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>دانایی‌فرد، حسن، امامی، سیدمجتبی. 1386. استراتژی‌های پژوهش کیفی: تأملی بر نظریه‌پردازی ‌داده‌بنیاد. دوفصلنامه علمی - پژوهشی اندیشه مدیریت راهبردی، 1(2)، 69-97</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>فتحی، سایه. 1396. آینده روشن: بررسی الزامات بانکداری مدرن در میزگرد مسعود خاتونی و حمیدرضا مختاریان. روزنامه دنیای اقتصاد (ضمیمه)، شماره 4270. قابل دسترس در: https://way2pay.ir/92054</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>فراستخواه, مقصود. 1395. روش تحقیق کیفی در علوم اجتماعی، با تاکید بر «نظریه برپایه». تهران. انتشارات آگاه</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>مختاریان، حسن. 1396. چرا بانکداری باز و بررسی چالش‌های آن در ایران / قلعه‌ها مشغول فرو ریختن‌اند. وب سایت راه پرداخت. قابل دسترس در: https://way2pay.ir/81412</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>مختاریان، حمید رضا. 1396. حرکت به سمت بانکداری باز / تصویر آینده بانک ملی ایران با وجود فناوری‌های مدرن مالی. وب سایت راه پرداخت. قابل دسترس در  https://way2pay.ir/92095</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>نامداری، نیما. 1395. بانکداری باز و چشم‌اندازهای پیش رو. وب سایت راه پرداخت. قابل دسترس در:  https://way2pay.ir/59847</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>وب سایت راه پرداخت. 26 فروردین 1397. حضور کاسپین با رویکرد بانکداری باز و حمایت از فین‌تک‌ها در فاینکس ۲۰۱۸، گفتگو با مصطفی جاویده معاون توسعه نرم‌افزار شرکت کاسپین. قابل دسترس در: https://way2pay.ir/95861</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>وب سایت راه پرداخت. 30 مرداد 1396. مدرن‌سازی کربنکینگ بانک ملت جهت ارائه زیرساخت به فین‌تک‌ها، گفتگو با مرتضی ترک تبریزی، مدیر امور فناوری اطلاعات بانک ملت. قابل دسترس در: https://way2pay.ir/76175 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>وب سایت راه پرداخت. گفتگوها و یادداشت های مربوط به فینوتک در راه پرداخت. قابل دسترس در: https://way2pay.ir/89105 و https://way2pay.ir/116606 و https://way2pay.ir/109758 و https://way2pay.ir/59855</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>ویکی پدیا. دانش نامه آزاد. 1397. رابط برنامه نویسی کاربردی. <https://fa.wikipedia.org/wiki/رابط_برنامه‌نویسی_کاربردی></element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>ویکی پدیا. دانش نامه آزاد. 1397. کیت توسعه نرم افزار. <https://fa.wikipedia.org/wiki/کیت_توسعه_نرم‌افزار>_||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Adib Hajbagheri, M., 2007. Qualitative research methods. Boshra Publication, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Akamavi, R.K., 2005. A research agenda for investigation of product innovation in the financial services sector. Journal of Services Marketing, 19(6), pp.359-378.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Afsari, M., 2015. Introducing Two Methods to Implement Open Banking: Why Do We Need Open Banking?. Available at https://way2pay.ir/49129 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Bagherinejad, J. and Javid, G., 2015. A model for Open Innovation in Banking Industry of Iran: Case study of Parsian Bank. Quarterly Journal of Innovation and Enterpreneurship, 0(5), pp.21-42.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Babcock, C., 2011. Easy-to-use APIs key to business growth. Information Week, 1313, p.14.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Baldwin, C.Y. and Clark, K.B., 2000. Design rules: The power of modularity (Vol. 1). MIT press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Belussi, F., Sammarra, A. and Sedita, S.R., 2010. Learning at the boundaries in an “Open Regional Innovation System”: A focus on firms’ innovation strategies in the Emilia Romagna life science industry. Research Policy, 39(6), pp.710-721.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Birkinshaw, J., Bessant, J. and Delbridge, R., 2007. Finding, forming, and performing: Creating networks for discontinuous innovation. California management review, 49(3), pp.67-84.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Boudreau, K., 2007. Does opening a platform stimulate innovation? The effect on systemic and modular innovations.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Boudreau, K., 2008. Opening the platform vs. opening the complementary good? The effect on product innovation in handheld computing. HEC working paper available on SSRN; abstract=1251167.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Boudreau, K.J. and Hagiu, A., 2009. Platform rules: Multi-sided platforms as regulators. Platforms, markets and innovation, 1, pp.163-191.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Bresnahan, T.F. and Greenstein, S., 1999. Technological competition and the structure of the computer industry. The Journal of Industrial Economics, 47(1), pp.1-40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H., 2011. Open Service Innovation. Rasa Publication, Tehran, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Creswell, J. W. 2005. Educational Research: Planning. Conducting and Evaluating Quantitative and Qualitative Research (2nd edition).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Caillaud, B., and Jullien, B., 2003. Chicken &amp; egg: Competition among intermediation service providers. RAND journal of Economics,34(2), pp. 309-328</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Charmaz, K., 2000. Grounded Theory: objectivist and constructivist methods in Norman K. Denzin and Yvonne S. Lincoln (eds.) Handbook of Qualitative Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H.W., 2003. Open innovation: The new imperative for creating and profiting from technology. Boston: Harvard Business School Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H., 2006. Open innovation: a new paradigm for understanding industrial innovation. Open innovation: Researching a new paradigm, 400, pp.0-19.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H., Vanhaverbeke, W. and West, J., 2006. Open Innovation: Researching a New Paradigm. Oxford: Oxford University Press. </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H. and Crowther, A.K., 2006. Beyond high tech: early adopters of open innovation in other industries. R&amp;d Management, 36(3), pp.229-236.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Cusumano, M.A. and Gawer, A., 2002. The elements of platform leadership. MIT Sloan management review, 43(3), p.51.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Danaeifard, H. and Emami, S., 2007. Strategies of Qualitative Research: A Reflection on Grounded Theory. Strategic Management Thought, 1(2), pp. 69-97.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Dittrich, K. and Duysters, G., 2007. Networking as a means to strategy change: the case of open innovation in mobile telephony. Journal of product innovation management, 24(6), pp.510-521.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenmann, T., Parker, G. and Van Alstyne, M.W., 2006. Strategies for two-sided markets. Harvard business review, 84(10), p.92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenmann, T.R., Parker, G. and Van Alstyne, M., 2009. Opening platforms: how, when and why?. Platforms, markets and innovation, pp.131-162.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Eisenmann, T.R., Parker, G. and Van Alstyne, M., 2011. Platform Envelopment. Strategic Management Journal 32(12) 1270-1285.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Enkel, E., Gassmann, O. and Chesbrough, H., 2009. Open R&amp;D and open innovation: exploring the phenomenon. R&amp;d Management, 39(4), pp.311-316.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Evans, D., Hagiu, A. and Schmalensee, R., 2006. Invisible Engines: How Software Platforms Drive Innovation and Transform Industries (Vol. 1). The MIT Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Fathi, S., 2018. A Bright Future: A Review of Modern Banking Requirements at the Roundtable by Masoud Khatouni and Hamidreza Mokhtarian. Donya-e-Eghtesad Newspaper (Appendix), No. 4270. Available at https://way2pay.ir/92054.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Farasatkhah, M., 2016. Qualitative research method in social sciences with emphasis on grounded theory. Agah Publication, Tehran, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Farrell, J., Monroe, H.K. and Saloner, G., 1998. The vertical organization of industry: Systems competition versus component competition. Journal of Economics &amp; Management Strategy, 7(2), pp.143-182.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Gawer, A. and Cusumano, M.A., 2002. Platform leadership: How Intel, Microsoft, and Cisco drive industry innovation (Vol. 5, pp. 29-30). Boston, MA: Harvard Business School Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Gawer, A. and Henderson, R., 2007. Platform owner entry and innovation in complementary markets: Evidence from Intel. Journal of Economics &amp; Management Strategy, 16(1), pp.1-34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Gawer, A., 2009. Platforms, Markets and Innovation: An Introduction. Edward Elgar Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Glaser, B. and Strauss, A.1967. Discovery of grounded theory: Strategies for qualitative research. Chicago: Alidline.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Greenstein, S., 1998. Industrial economics and strategy: Computing platforms. IEEE Micro, 18(3), pp.43-53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Henderson, R.M. and Clark, K.B., 1990. Architectural innovation: The reconfiguration of existing product technologies and the failure of established firms. Administrative science quarterly, pp.9-30.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Komninos, N., 2004. Regional Intelligence: distributed localised information systems for innovation and development. International Journal of Technology Management, 28(3-6), pp.483-506.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Lee, J., 2001. A Grounded Theory: Integration and Internalization in ERP Adoption and Use, Unpublished Doctoral Dissertation, University of Nebreska, In Proquest UMI Database.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Martovoy, A., Mention, A.L. and Torkkely, M., 2012. Role of the inbound open innovation in banking services. Proceedings of the 2nd Innovation for Financial Services Summit. Luxembourg: Public Research Centre Henri Tudor.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Martovoy, A. and Dos Santos, J., 2012. Co-creation and co-profiting in financial services. International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Innovation Management 1, 16(1-2), pp.114-135.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Mokhtarian, H., 2017. Why open banking and Reviewing its Challenges in Iran: Castles are collapsing. Available at https://way2pay.ir/81412</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Mokhtarian, H.R., 2017. Moving towards open banking: Future image of the National Bank of Iran despite modern financial technologies. Available at https://way2pay.ir/92095.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>Namdari, N., 2016. Open Banking and Future Perspectives. Available at https://way2pay.ir/59847</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>Mention, A.L. and Martovoy, A., 2013. Open and collaborative innovation in banking services: Evidence from Luxembourg. Luxembourg-Kirchberg: Public Research Centre Henri Tudor.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Nambisan, S. and Sawhney, M., 2007. A buyer's guide to the innovation bazaar. Harvard Business Review, 85(6), pp.109-118.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>Nieto, M.J. and Santamaría, L., 2007. The importance of diverse collaborative networks for the novelty of product innovation. Technovation, 27(6-7), pp.367-377.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R115">
			<label>115</label>
			<element-citation>Osterwalder, A. and Pigneur, Y., 2010. Business model generation: a handbook for visionaries, game changers, and challengers. Aryana Ghalam Publication, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R116">
			<label>116</label>
			<element-citation>Oliveira, P. and von Hippel, E., 2011. Users as service innovators: The case of banking services. Research policy, 40(6), pp.806-818.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R117">
			<label>117</label>
			<element-citation>Parker, G.G. and Van Alstyne, M.W., 2000, October. Internetwork externalities and free information goods. In Proceedings of the 2nd ACM Conference on Electronic Commerce (pp. 107-116). ACM.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R118">
			<label>118</label>
			<element-citation>Parker, G.G. and Van Alstyne, M.W., 2005. Two-sided network effects: A theory of information product design. Management science, 51(10), pp.1494-1504.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R119">
			<label>119</label>
			<element-citation>Parker, G and Van Alstyne, M., 2008. Managing Platform Ecosystems. In Proceedings of the 29th International Conference on Information Systems, Paris, France, December 14-17.Paper 53. http://aisel.aisnet.org/icis2008/53</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R120">
			<label>120</label>
			<element-citation>Parker, G. and Van Alstyne, M., 2012. A digital postal platform: Definitions and a roadmap. MIT Center for Digital Business, Working Paper.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R121">
			<label>121</label>
			<element-citation>Rochet, J.C. and Tirole, J., 2003. Platform competition in two‐sided markets. Journal of the european economic association, 1(4), pp.990-1029.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R122">
			<label>122</label>
			<element-citation>Schueffel, P.E. and Vadana, I.I., 2015. Open Innovation in the Financial Services Sector-A global literature review. Journal of innovation management, 3(1), pp.25-48.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R123">
			<label>123</label>
			<element-citation>Shapiro, C., Varian, H.R. and Becker, W.E., 1999. Information rules: a strategic guide to the network economy. Journal of Economic Education, 30, pp.189-190.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R124">
			<label>124</label>
			<element-citation>Strauss, A. and Corbin, J., 1998. Basics of Qualitative Research: Techniques and Procedures for Developing Grounded Theory, 2nd Ed., Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R125">
			<label>125</label>
			<element-citation>Tidd, J. and Bessant, J., 2005. Managing innovation integrating technological, market and organizational change. Rasa Publication, Tehran, Iran.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R126">
			<label>126</label>
			<element-citation>Van Alstyne, M.W., Parker, G.G. and Choudary, S.P., 2016. Pipelines, platforms, and the new rules of strategy. Harvard business review, 94(4), pp.54-62.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R127">
			<label>127</label>
			<element-citation>Vanhaverbeke, W., 2011. The benefits of open innovation in low tech SMEs: The quilts of Denmark story.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R128">
			<label>128</label>
			<element-citation>West, J., 2003. How open is open enough?: Melding proprietary and open source platform strategies. Research policy, 32(7), pp.1259-1285.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R129">
			<label>129</label>
			<element-citation>Way to Pay website. April 15, 2018. Caspian Presence with Open Banking Approach and Fintech Support at Finex 2018, Talk to Mostafa Javideh, Deputy Director of Software Development at Caspian Corporation. Available at https://way2pay.ir/95861.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R130">
			<label>130</label>
			<element-citation>Way to Pay website. July 21, 2017. Modernization of Mellat Corebanking to Provide Infrastructure to Fintech, Talks with Morteza Turk Tabarizi, Mellat Bank Information Technology Manager. Available at https://way2pay.ir/76175 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R131">
			<label>131</label>
			<element-citation>Way to Pay website. Talks and and notes about Fintechs. Available at https://way2pay.ir/89105, https://way2pay.ir/116606 , https://way2pay.ir/109758 , https://way2pay.ir/59855</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R132">
			<label>132</label>
			<element-citation>Wikipedia. Free Encyclopedia. 2018. Application Programming Interface.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R133">
			<label>133</label>
			<element-citation><https://fa.wikipedia.org/wiki/رابط_برنامه‌نویسی_کاربردی></element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R134">
			<label>134</label>
			<element-citation>Wikipedia. Free Encyclopedia. 2018. Software Development Kit.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R135">
			<label>135</label>
			<element-citation><https://fa.wikipedia.org/wiki/کیت_توسعه_نرم‌افزار></element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R136">
			<label>136</label>
			<element-citation>Zeng, S.X., Xie, X.M. and Tam, C.M., 2010. Relationship between cooperation networks and innovation performance of SMEs. Technovation, 30(3), pp.181-194.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>