<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" "journalpublishing3.dtd">
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14769_a1dc47c8c69e7822fd45ea994602cf76.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>موج های سه گانه گذار در صنعت دفاعی ایران با نگاهی خاص به صنعت ضد زره</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>وزیری</surname>
			            <given-names>جواد</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>قاضی نوری</surname>
			            <given-names>سیدسپهر</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>قانعی راد</surname>
			            <given-names>سیدمحمدامین</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>مرکز تحقیقات سیاست علمی کشور</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فرتوک زاده</surname>
			            <given-names>حمیدرضا</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2015</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>4</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>1</fpage>
			      <lpage>34</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>23</day>
			          <month>11</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2015, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2015</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14769.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14769.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>این مقاله سعی دارد تفسیری اجتماعی- تکنیکی از شکل گیری و گذار صنعت دفاعی ایران در طول چند دهه اخیر را ارائه نماید. برای این منظور، ابتدا با الهام از نظریه میدان بوردیو، چارچوبی برای تحلیل گذار ارائه شده است. در ادامه با ترکیبی از روش شناسی سه مرحله ای بوردیو و روش نظریه پردازی زمینه محور تلاش شده است فرآیند گذار با تاکید بر صنعت ضد زره تحلیل گردد و ایده های نظری جدیدی پیرامون تحول اجتماعی- تکنیکی در صنعت دفاع ارائه شود. بر اساس چارچوب و ایده های ارائه شده در این پژوهش، برای فهم نوآوری و تغییرات فنی در صنعت دفاعی باید به بررسی تحولاتی که در کنش و قشربندی مهندسان و عادت واره، سبک و ارزش های مهندسی رخ می دهد، پرداخت. تجربه صنعت دفاعی نشان می دهد که توازن و هماهنگی بین سرمایه تکنیکی و سرمایه نمادین مهندسان، مهم ترین عامل در توسعه فناورانه و پایداری میدان صنعت دفاعی است. این توازن باعث ایجاد یک قشربندی اجتماعی و روابط کاری مولد بین نیروهای صنعت م یشود. در صورتی که این توازن وجود نداشته باشد، روابط کاری مولد به وجود نمی آید و در نتیجه انباشت سرمایه ممکن نمیشود. میدان سیاست با مداخله در میدان صنعت تاثیر به سزایی بر این توازن و هماهنگی دارد. توجه به این تاثیرگذاری برای سیاست گذاری علم وفناوری در ایران از ضرورت مضاعف برخوردار است.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>میدان صنعت دفاعی ایران</kwd>
						<kwd>صنعت ضد زره</kwd>
						<kwd>عادت واره مهندسی</kwd>
						<kwd>گذار اجتماعی- تکنیکی</kwd>
						<kwd>دیدگاه چندسطحی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Berkhout, F., Smith, A. &amp; Stirling, A., 2004. Socio-technological regimes and transition contexts. In: B.Elzen, F. Geels &amp; K. Green, eds. System Innovation and the transition to sustainability. Edward Elgar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Callon, M., 1991. Techno-economic networks and irreversibility. In: J. Law, ed. A Sociology of Monsters, Essays on Power, Technology and Domination. London: Routledge, pp. 132-161.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Cordesman, A. H., 1999. Iran's military forces in transition: conventional threats and weapons of mass destruction. Greenwood Publishing Group.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Cordesman, A. &amp; Hashim, A., 1997. Iran: dilemmas of dual containment. Colo: Westview Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Cordesman, A. H. &amp; Wagner, A. R., 1990. The Lessons of Modern War: Volume II. The Iran-Iraq War.Boulder: Westview Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Dosi, G., 1982. Technological paradigms and technological trajectories: a suggested interpretation of the determinants and directions of technical change. Research Policy, Volume 6, pp. 147–162.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Elzen, B., Geels, F. &amp; green, K., 2004. System Innovation and the Transition to Sustainability: Theory, Evidence and Policy. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Farazmand, A., 1989. The State Bureaucracy, and Revolution in modern Iran, Agrarian Reforms and Regim Politics. New York: Praeger.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Freeman, C. &amp; Perez , C., 1988. Structural crisis of adjustment, business cycles and investment behaviour.In: Technical Change and Economic Theory. London: Francis Printer, pp. 38-60.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2002. Technological transitions as evolutionary reconfiguration processes: a multi-level perspective and a case-study. Res. Policy, 31(8/9), pp. 1257-1274.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2004. From sectoral systems of innovation to socio-technical systems: insights about dynamics and change from sociology and institutional theory. Research Policy , Volume 33, pp. 897–920.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2005a. The dynamics of transitions in socio-technical systems: amulti-level analysis of the transition pathway from horse-drawn carriages to automobiles(1860–1930). Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, Volume 17, pp. 445–476.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2005b. Processes and patterns in transitions and system innovations: refining the co-evolutionary multi-level perspective. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change , Volume 72, pp. 681–696.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2005. Technological Transitions and System Innovations; A Co-Evolutionary and Socio-Technical Analysis. Edward Elgar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2010. Ontologies, socio-technical transitions (to sustainability), and the multi-level perspective. Research Policy, Volume 39, pp. 495–510.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2011. The multi-level perspective on sustainability transitions:Responses to seven criticisms. Environmental Innovation and Societal Transitions , Volume 1, pp. 24–40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F. &amp; Schot, J., 2007. Typology of sociotechnical transition pathways. Research Policy , Volume 36,pp. 399–417.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F. &amp; Schot, J., 2010. The dynamics of transitions: a socio-technical perspective. . In: J. Grin, et al.eds. Transitions to Sustainable Development: New Directions in the Study of Long Term Transformative Change. New York: Routledge, pp. 9–87.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F. &amp; Schot, J. W., 2007. Typology of sociotechnical transition pathways. Research Policy, 36(3), pp.399-417.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F. W., 2004. From sectoral systems of innovation to socio-technical systems: Insights about dynamics and change from sociology and institutional theory. Res. Pol., Volume 33, pp. 6-7.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Genus, A. &amp; Coles, A., 2008. Rethinking the multi-level perspective of technological transitions. Research Policy, Volume 37, pp. 1436–1445.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Giddens, A., 1984. The Constitution of Society: Outline of the Theory of Structuration. Berkeley: University of California Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Hughes, T. P., 1994. Technological momentum. In: M. R. Smith &amp; L. Marx, eds. Does Technology Drive History? The Dilemma of Technological Determinism. Cambridge: The MIT Press, pp. 101–13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Karshenas, M., 1990. Oil, State and Industrialisation In Iran. Cambridge University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Malerba, F., 2002. Sectoral systems of innovation. Research Policy, 31(2), pp. 247–64.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson, R. &amp; Winter, S., 1982. An Evolutionary Theory of Economic Change. Cambridge: Bellknap Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Reichertz, J., 2009. Abduction: The Logic of Discovery of Grounded Theory. Qualitative Social Research, 11(1), pp. 13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Richardson , R. &amp; Karamer , E., 2006. Abduction as a type of inference that characterizes the development of a grounded theory. Qualitative Research, 6(4), pp. 497-513.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Rip, A. &amp; Kemp, R., 1998. Technological change. In: S. Rayner &amp; E. Malone, eds. Human Choice and Climate Change. Columbus: Battelle Press, pp. 327–399.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Rotmans, J., Kemp, R. &amp; Van Asselt, M., 2001. More evolution than revolution: transition management in public policy. Foresight, 3(1), pp. 15–31.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Schulz, A. T., 1989. Buying Security: Iran under the Monarchy. San Francisco: Westview Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Skacpol, T., 1996. Rentier state and Shiie Islam in the Iranian Revolution. In: Social Revolution in the Modern World. New York: Cambridge University Press, pp. 240-258.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, A., Stirling, A. &amp; Berkhout, F., 2005. The governance of sustainable socio-technical transitions. Research Policy, Volume 34, pp. 1491–1510.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Zarbafian, S., 1979. Technology Transfer and Economic Development in Iran (1962-1977). Michigan: University Microfilms International.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>اخوان کاظمی، ب.، 1389. نقد و ارزیابی گفتما نهای اجتماعی- سیاسی مطرح در جمهوری اسلامی، پژوهشگاه فرهنگ و اندیشه اسلامی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>امجد، م.، 1380. ایران؛ از دیکتاتوری سلطنتی تا دین سالاری. موسسه فرهنگ هنر و ارتباطات.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>اندیشگاه شریف، 1388 . مطالعات تطبیقی انقلاب در امور نظامی.، تهران: موسسه آموزشی تحقیقاتی صنایع دفاعی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>بحرانی، م.، 1389. طبقه متوسط و تحولات سیاسی در ایران معاصر1320 – 1380، تهران: نشر آگاه.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>بشیریه، ح.، 1380. جامع هشناسی سیاسی. تهران: نشر نی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>بوردیو، پ.، 1381. نظریه کنش. تهران: نقش و نگار.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>بونویتز، پ.، 1389. در سهایی از جامع هشناسی پیر بوردیو. تهران: آگه.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>تقوی، م. و گلشنی، م.، 1391. نقد دو مدل »شریف « و »پیت « از تکنولوژی. بهبود مدیریت، (16) 6.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>حاجی یوسفی، ا.، 1376 . رانت، دولت رانتیر و رانتیریسم. اطلاعات سیاسی اقتصادی، بهمن و اسفند(125 - 126)، صص. 152 - 155.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>رواسانی ، ش.، 1387 . دولت و حکومت در ایران، در دوره سلطه استعمار سرمای هداری. تهران: امیرکبیر.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>سلطانی، ع. ا.، 1384 . قدرت، گفتمان و زبان (سازوکارهای جریان قدرت در جمهوری اسلامی ایران)، تهران: نشر نی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>سینایی، و.، 1379 . نقش ارتش در تکوین و تداوم دولت مطلقه، در ایران از شک لگیری ارتش نوین تا پایان سلسله پهلوی. تهران: دانشکده حقوق</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>و علوم سیاسی تهران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>شمسینی غیاثوند، ح.، 1389 . واکاوی نظریات استعماری نسبت به ماهیت دولت مدرن پهلوی دوم. فصلنامه مطالعات سیاسی، (10)3.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>فرتوک زاده، ح. و وزیری، ج.، 1388 . شایستگی دستیابی به سامان ههای دفاعی، یک نظریه داده بنیان. سیاست عل موفناوری، (2)2، صص. 77 - 96 .</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>فوران، ج.، 1378 . مقاومت شکننده، تاریخ تحولات اجتماعی ایران، از صفویه تا سا لهای پس از انقلاب اسلامی. تهران: رسا.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>گرنفل، م.، 1389 . مفاهیم کلیدی پیر بوردیو. تهران: نشر افکار.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>لیون، ت.، 1373 . باتلاق آمریکا در خاورمیانه. تهران: اطلاعات.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>میلانی، م.، 1381 . شک لگیری انقلاب اسلامی (از سلطنت پهلوی تا جمهوری اسلامی)،. تهران: گام نو.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>هالیدی، ف.، 1358 . ایران، دیکتاتوری و توسعه. تهران: علم.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>هانت، د.، 1989 . نظریه های اقتصادی توسعه. نشریه نی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Akhavan Kazemi, B., 2010. Reviewing and evaluating socio-political dialogue in the Islamic Republic. Islamic Research Institute for Culture and Thought.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Amjad, M., 2001. Iran: from dictatorship to theocracy. Institute of Culture, Art and Communication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Bahrani, M., 2010. The Middle Class and Political Developments in Contemporary Iran1940 – 2001. Tehran: Agah Publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Bashirieh, H., 2001. Political Sociology. Tehran: Ney Publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Bonnewitz, P., 2010. Premieres lecons sur la sociologie de Pierre Bourdieu. Tehran: Agah Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Bourdieu, P., 2002. Practical Reason: On the Theory of Action. Tehran: Naghshonegar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Berkhout, F., Smith, A. &amp; Stirling, A., 2004. Socio-technological regimes and transition contexts. In: B.Elzen, F. Geels &amp; K. Green, eds. System Innovation and the transition to sustainability. Edward Elgar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Callon, M., 1991. Techno-economic networks and irreversibility. In: J. Law, ed. A Sociology of Monsters, Essays on Power, Technology and Domination. London: Routledge, pp. 132-161.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Cordesman, A. H., 1999. Iran's military forces in transition: conventional threats and weapons of mass destruction. Greenwood Publishing Group.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Cordesman, A. &amp; Hashim, A., 1997. Iran: dilemmas of dual containment. Colo: Westview Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Cordesman, A. H. &amp; Wagner, A. R., 1990. The Lessons of Modern War: Volume II. The Iran-Iraq War.Boulder: Westview Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Dosi, G., 1982. Technological paradigms and technological trajectories: a suggested interpretation of the determinants and directions of technical change. Research Policy, Volume 6, pp. 147–162.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Elzen, B., Geels, F. &amp; green, K., 2004. System Innovation and the Transition to Sustainability: Theory, Evidence and Policy. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Farazmand, A., 1989. The State Bureaucracy, and Revolution in modern Iran, Agrarian Reforms and Regim Politics. New York: Praeger.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Fartouk zadeh, h. &amp; Vaziri, J., 2009. Competency to achieve defense systems, a basic data theory. journal of science and technology policy, 2(2), PP. 77-96.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Fouran, J., 2009. Fragile resistance, the history of social change in Iran, from Safavid to the time after the Islamic Revolution. Tehran: Rasa.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Freeman, C. &amp; Perez , C., 1988. Structural crisis of adjustment, business cycles and investment behaviour.In: Technical Change and Economic Theory. London: Francis Printer, pp. 38-60.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2002. Technological transitions as evolutionary reconfiguration processes: a multi-level perspective and a case-study. Res. Policy, 31(8/9), pp. 1257-1274.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2004. From sectoral systems of innovation to socio-technical systems: insights about dynamics and change from sociology and institutional theory. Research Policy , Volume 33, pp. 897–920.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2005a. The dynamics of transitions in socio-technical systems: amulti-level analysis of the transition pathway from horse-drawn carriages to automobiles(1860–1930). Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, Volume 17, pp. 445–476.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2005b. Processes and patterns in transitions and system innovations: refining the co-evolutionary multi-level perspective. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change , Volume 72, pp. 681–696.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2005. Technological Transitions and System Innovations; A Co-Evolutionary and Socio-Technical Analysis. Edward Elgar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2010. Ontologies, socio-technical transitions (to sustainability), and the multi-level perspective. Research Policy, Volume 39, pp. 495–510.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F., 2011. The multi-level perspective on sustainability transitions:Responses to seven criticisms. Environmental Innovation and Societal Transitions , Volume 1, pp. 24–40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F. &amp; Schot, J., 2007. Typology of sociotechnical transition pathways. Research Policy , Volume 36,pp. 399–417.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F. &amp; Schot, J., 2010. The dynamics of transitions: a socio-technical perspective. . In: J. Grin, et al.eds. Transitions to Sustainable Development: New Directions in the Study of Long Term Transformative Change. New York: Routledge, pp. 9–87.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F. &amp; Schot, J. W., 2007. Typology of sociotechnical transition pathways. Research Policy, 36(3), pp.399-417.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Geels, F. W., 2004. From sectoral systems of innovation to socio-technical systems: Insights about dynamics and change from sociology and institutional theory. Res. Pol., Volume 33, pp. 6-7.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Genus, A. &amp; Coles, A., 2008. Rethinking the multi-level perspective of technological transitions. Research Policy, Volume 37, pp. 1436–1445.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Giddens, A., 1984. The Constitution of Society: Outline of the Theory of Structuration. Berkeley: University of California Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Grenfell, M., 2010. Pierre Bourdieu : key concepts. Tehran: Nashre Afkar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Halliday, F., 2002. Iran dictatorship and development. Tehran: Elm Publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Haji Yosefi, A., 1997. Rents, Ranch, and Rantics. Political &amp; Economic Ettelaat. Volume(125&amp;126), PP. 152-155.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Hughes, T. P., 1994. Technological momentum. In: M. R. Smith &amp; L. Marx, eds. Does Technology Drive History? The Dilemma of Technological Determinism. Cambridge: The MIT Press, pp. 101–13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Hunt, D., 2010. Economic Theories of development: an analysis of competing paradigms. Tehran: Nashr-e Ney.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Karshenas, M., 1990. Oil, State and Industrialisation In Iran. Cambridge University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Leon T, H., 1994. Quagmire: American in the Middle East. Tehran: Ettelaat Publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Malerba, F., 2002. Sectoral systems of innovation. Research Policy, 31(2), pp. 247–64.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Milani, M., 2002. The making of Iran's Islamic revolution: from monarchy to Islamic republic. Tehran: Game Now Publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson, R. &amp; Winter, S., 1982. An Evolutionary Theory of Economic Change. Cambridge: Bellknap Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Ravasani, Sh., 2008. Government and government in Iran, during the colonial domination of capitalism. Tehran: Amirkabir Publisher.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Reichertz, J., 2009. Abduction: The Logic of Discovery of Grounded Theory. Qualitative Social Research, 11(1), pp. 13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Richardson , R. &amp; Karamer , E., 2006. Abduction as a type of inference that characterizes the development of a grounded theory. Qualitative Research, 6(4), pp. 497-513.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Rip, A. &amp; Kemp, R., 1998. Technological change. In: S. Rayner &amp; E. Malone, eds. Human Choice and Climate Change. Columbus: Battelle Press, pp. 327–399.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Rotmans, J., Kemp, R. &amp; Van Asselt, M., 2001. More evolution than revolution: transition management in public policy. Foresight, 3(1), pp. 15–31.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Schulz, A. T., 1989. Buying Security: Iran under the Monarchy. San Francisco: Westview Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Shamsini Ghiyasvand, h., 2010. Evolution of colonial views on the nature of the modern state of Pahlavi II. Journal of Political Studies, 3(10).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Sharif ThinkTank, 2009. Comparative Studies of the Revolution in Military Affairs. Tehran: Research Institute for Defense Industries.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Sinaei, V., 2000. The role of the army in the development and continuation of an absolute state in Iran from the suspicion of the modern army until the end of the Pahlavi dynasty. Tehran: Tehran School of Political Science.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Skacpol, T., 1996. Rentier state and Shiie Islam in the Iranian Revolution. In: Social Revolution in the Modern World. New York: Cambridge University Press, pp. 240-258.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, A., Stirling, A. &amp; Berkhout, F., 2005. The governance of sustainable socio-technical transitions. Research Policy, Volume 34, pp. 1491–1510.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Soltani, As. A., 2005. Power, discourse and language (mechanisms of power flow in the Islamic Republic of Iran). Tehran: Nashr-e Ney.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Taghavi, M. &amp; Golshani, M., 2012. A critique of the two models of "Noble" and "Pete" of technology. Journal of Management Improved. 6 (16).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Zarbafian, S., 1979. Technology Transfer and Economic Development in Iran (1962-1977). Michigan: University Microfilms International.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14834_7b6d583b93a3583ddbba41d0aa3e3ba8.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>مسیر اشاعه فناوری های انرژی های تجدیدپذیر: رویکرد نظریه سازی بنیادی</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>الهی</surname>
			            <given-names>شعبان</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>غریبی</surname>
			            <given-names>جلیل</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مجیدپور</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>انواری رستمی</surname>
			            <given-names>علی اصغر</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2015</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>4</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>33</fpage>
			      <lpage>56</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>23</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>28</day>
			          <month>08</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2015, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2015</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14834.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14834.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>اشاعه فناوری، یکی از مهمترین اهداف نظام‌های نوآوری به ویژه در کشورهای در حال توسعه و البته به همان اندازه از مساله‌های دشوار پیش روی سیاست‌گذاران است. یکی از بخش‌هایی که بطور جدی با مساله اشاعه فناوری مواجه شده، بخش انرژی‌های تجدیدپذیر است. در سال‌های اخیر حمایت از گسترش استفاده از انرژی‌های تجدیدپذیر در ایران مورد تاکید قرار گرفته است. از این رو مقاله حاضر به مطالعه اشاعه فناوری‌های انرژی تجدیدپذیر پرداخته است. برای این منظور، با توجه به وجود محتوای اطلاعاتی غنی در اسناد مطالعاتی و از طرفی پراکنده بودن جنبه‌های مورد مطالعه و دیدگاه‌های مختلف تحلیلی، سعی شد متون معتبر و مرتبط شناسایی و با استفاده از روش نظریه‌سازی بنیادی مورد تحلیل و مدل‌سازی قرار گیرند. نتایج پژوهش، الگویی را آشکار کرد که نشان‌دهنده وجود 4 دسته عوامل اصلی است فشار علم، کشش تقاضا، جذابیت سرمایه‌گذاری، و چارچوبی و زیرساختی.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>اشاعه فناوری</kwd>
						<kwd>انرژی های تجدیدپذیر</kwd>
						<kwd>نظریه سازی بنیادی</kwd>
						<kwd>مرور نظام مند</kwd>
						<kwd>مدل سازی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Ardehali, M. M. (2006). Rural energy development in Iran: non-renewable and renewable resources. Renewable Energy, 31(5), 655-662.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Ashworth, J. (1980). Technology diffusion through foreign assistance: Making renewable energy sources available to the world›s poor. Policy Sciences, 11(3), 241-261.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Aslani, A., &amp; Mohaghar, A. (2013). Business structure in renewable energy industry: Key areas. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 27, 569-575.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Atabi, F. (2004). Renewable energy in Iran: Challenges and opportunities for sustainable development. International Journal of Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 1(1), 69-80.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Cong, R.-G. (2013). An optimization model for renewable energy generation and its application in China: a perspective of maximum utilization. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 17, 94-103.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Corbin, J., &amp; Strauss, A. (2014). Basics of qualitative research: Techniques and procedures for developing grounded theory: Sage publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Dinica, V. (2006). Support systems for the diffusion of renewable energy technologies—an investor perspective. Energy Policy, 34(4), 461-480.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Dixon-Woods, M., Agarwal, S., Jones, D., Young, B., &amp; Sutton, A. (2005). Synthesising qualitative and quantitative evidence: a review of possible methods. Journal of health services research &amp; policy, 10(1), 45-53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C., &amp; Hommen, L. (2009). Small country innovation systems: globalization, change and policy in Asia and Europe: Edward Elgar Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Fadai, D. (2007). Utilization of renewable energy sources for power generation in Iran. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 11(1), 173-181.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Fadai, D., Esfandabadi, Z. S., &amp; Abbasi, A. (2011). Analyzing the causes of non-development of renewable energy-related industries in Iran. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 15(6), 2690-2695.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Freitas, I. M. B., Dantas, E., &amp; Iizuka, M. (2012). The Kyoto mechanisms and the diffusion of renewable energy technologies in the BRICS. Energy Policy, 42, 118-128.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Ghorashi, A. H., &amp; Rahimi, A. (2011). Renewable and non-renewable energy status in Iran: Art of know-how and technology-gaps. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 15(1), 729-736.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Glaser, B., &amp; Strauss, A. (1967). The discovery ofgrounded theory. London: Weidenfeld and Nicholson.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Glaser, B. G. (2001). The grounded theory perspective: Conceptualization contrasted with description: Sociology Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Glaser, B. G., &amp; Strauss, A. L. (2009). The discovery of grounded theory: Strategies for qualitative research: Transaction Publishers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Hekkert, M. P., Suurs, R. A., Negro, S. O., Kuhlmann, S., &amp; Smits, R. (2007). Functions of innovation systems: A new approach for analysing technological change. Technological forecasting and social change, 74(4), 413-432.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Hitzeroth, M., &amp; Megerle, A. (2013). Renewable energy projects: acceptance risks and their management. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 27, 576-584.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Huh, S.-Y., &amp; Lee, C.-Y. (2014). Diffusion of renewable energy technologies in South Korea on incorporating their competitive interrelationships. Energy Policy, 69, 248-257.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Huijts, N., Molin, E., &amp; Steg, L. (2012). Psychological factors influencing sustainable energy technology acceptance: A review-based comprehensive framework. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 16(1), 525-531.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Jacobsson, S., &amp; Johnson, A. (2000). The diffusion of renewable energy technology: an analytical framework and key issues for research. Energy Policy, 28(9), 625-640.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Jacobsson, S., &amp; Lauber, V. (2006). The politics and policy of energy system transformation—explaining the German diffusion of renewable energy technology. Energy Policy, 34(3), 256-276.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Jochem, E., Madlener, R., &amp; Mannsbart, W. (2002). Renewable energy technology diffusion, prospects of the German and Swiss industry in the world markets. Paper presented at the World Renewable Energy Congress.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Kumbaroğlu, G., Madlener, R., &amp; Demirel, M. (2008). A real options evaluation model for the diffusion prospects of new renewable power generation technologies. Energy Economics, 30(4), 1882-1908.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Lacasa, I. D. (2014). Ceremonial Encapsulation and the Diffusion of Renewable Energy Technology in Germany. Journal of Economic Issues, 48(4), 1073-1093.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Lomborg, K., &amp; Kirkevold, M. (2003). Truth and validity in grounded theory–a reconsidered realist interpretation of the criteria: fit, work, relevance and modifiability. Nursing Philosophy, 4(3), 189-200.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B.-Å. (2010). National systems of innovation: Toward a theory of innovation and interactive learning (Vol. 2): Anthem Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Mani, S., &amp; Dhingra, T. (2012). Diffusion of innovation model of consumer behaviour–Ideas to accelerate adoption of renewable energy sources by consumer communities in India. Renewable Energy, 39(1), 162-165.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Mostafaeipour, A., &amp; Mostafaeipour, N. (2009). Renewable energy issues and electricity production in Middle East compared with Iran. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 13(6), 1641-1645.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Negro, S. O., Alkemade, F., &amp; Hekkert, M. P. (2012). Why does renewable energy diffuse so slowly? A review of innovation system problems. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 16(6), 3836-3846.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Palm, A. (2015). An emerging innovation system for deployment of building-sited solar photovoltaics in Sweden. Environmental Innovation and Societal Transitions, 15, 140-157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Pfeiffer, B., &amp; Mulder, P. (2013). Explaining the diffusion of renewable energy technology in developing countries. Energy Economics, 40(0), 285-296. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.eneco.2013.07.005</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Popp, D., Hascic, I., &amp; Medhi, N. (2011). Technology and the diffusion of renewable energy. Energy Economics, 33(4), 648-662.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Purohit, P., &amp; Kandpal, T. C. (2005). Renewable energy technologies for irrigation water pumping in India: projected levels of dissemination, energy delivery and investment requirements using available diffusion models. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 9(6), 592-607.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Quitzow, R. (2015). Dynamics of a policy-driven market: The co-evolution of technological innovation systems for solar photovoltaics in China and Germany. Environmental Innovation and Societal Transitions.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Radomes, A. A., &amp; Arango, S. (2015). Renewable energy technology diffusion: an analysis of photovoltaic-system support schemes in Medellín, Colombia. Journal of Cleaner Production, 92, 152-161.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Ralph, N., Birks, M., &amp; Chapman, Y. (2014). Contextual Positioning. Sage Open, 4(3).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Rao, K. U., &amp; Kishore, V. V. N. (2010). A review of technology diffusion models with special reference to renewable energy technologies. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 14(3), 1070-1078. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2009.11.007</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Reddy, S., &amp; Painuly, J. P. (2004). Diffusion of renewable energy technologies—barriers and stakeholders’ perspectives. Renewable Energy, 29(9), 1431-1447.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Richards, L., &amp; Morse, J. M. (2012). Readme first for a user›s guide to qualitative methods: Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Rogers, E. M. (2010). Diffusion of innovations: Simon and Schuster.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Schumpeter, J. A. (1939). Business cycles (Vol. 1): Cambridge Univ Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>SuriÃ±ach, J., Autant-Bernard, C., Manca, F., Massard, N., &amp; Moreno, R. (2009). The diffusion/adoption of innovation in the internal market: Directorate General Economic and Monetary Affairs (DG ECFIN), European Commission.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Tigabu, A. D., Berkhout, F., &amp; van Beukering, P. (2015). The diffusion of a renewable energy technology and innovation system functioning: Comparing bio-digestion in Kenya and Rwanda. Technological forecasting and social change, 90, 331-345.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Tsoutsos, T. D., &amp; Stamboulis, Y. A. (2005). The sustainable diffusion of renewable energy technologies as an example of an innovation-focused policy. Technovation, 25(7), 753-761. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.technovation.2003.12.003</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Viotti, E. B. (2002). National learning systems: a new approach on technological change in late industrializing economies and evidences from the cases of Brazil and South Korea. Technological forecasting and social change, 69(7), 653-680.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Wirth, S., Markard, J., Truffer, B., &amp; Rohracher, H. (2013). Informal institutions matter: Professional culture and the development of biogas technology. Environmental Innovation and Societal Transitions, 8, 20-41.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Wüstenhagen, R., &amp; Bilharz, M. (2006). Green energy market development in Germany: effective public policy and emerging customer demand. Energy Policy, 34(13), 1681-1696.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>شریفی, ع. م., آقائی, ک., صادقی, م., دلالی, ر., و شوال پور, س. (1388). تاثیر یادگیری فنی بر توسعه فنآوری های انرژی های تجدیدپذیر در بخش برق ایران در شرایط اختلالات قیمت انرژی. فصلنامه مطالعات اقتصاد انرژی, 21, 137-160.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>قانون اصلاح الگوی مصرف انرژی. (1389). مجلس شورای اسلامی._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Ardehali, M. M. (2006). Rural energy development in Iran: non-renewable and renewable resources. Renewable Energy, 31(5), 655-662.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Ashworth, J. (1980). Technology diffusion through foreign assistance: Making renewable energy sources available to the world›s poor. Policy Sciences, 11(3), 241-261.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Aslani, A., &amp; Mohaghar, A. (2013). Business structure in renewable energy industry: Key areas. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 27, 569-575.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Atabi, F. (2004). Renewable energy in Iran: Challenges and opportunities for sustainable development. International Journal of Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 1(1), 69-80.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Cong, R.-G. (2013). An optimization model for renewable energy generation and its application in China: a perspective of maximum utilization. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 17, 94-103.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Corbin, J., &amp; Strauss, A. (2014). Basics of qualitative research: Techniques and procedures for developing grounded theory: Sage publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Dinica, V. (2006). Support systems for the diffusion of renewable energy technologies—an investor perspective. Energy Policy, 34(4), 461-480.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Dixon-Woods, M., Agarwal, S., Jones, D., Young, B., &amp; Sutton, A. (2005). Synthesising qualitative and quantitative evidence: a review of possible methods. Journal of health services research &amp; policy, 10(1), 45-53.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Edquist, C., &amp; Hommen, L. (2009). Small country innovation systems: globalization, change and policy in Asia and Europe: Edward Elgar Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Fadai, D. (2007). Utilization of renewable energy sources for power generation in Iran. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 11(1), 173-181.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Fadai, D., Esfandabadi, Z. S., &amp; Abbasi, A. (2011). Analyzing the causes of non-development of renewable energy-related industries in Iran. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 15(6), 2690-2695.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Freitas, I. M. B., Dantas, E., &amp; Iizuka, M. (2012). The Kyoto mechanisms and the diffusion of renewable energy technologies in the BRICS. Energy Policy, 42, 118-128.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Ghorashi, A. H., &amp; Rahimi, A. (2011). Renewable and non-renewable energy status in Iran: Art of know-how and technology-gaps. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 15(1), 729-736.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Glaser, B., &amp; Strauss, A. (1967). The discovery ofgrounded theory. London: Weidenfeld and Nicholson.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Glaser, B. G. (2001). The grounded theory perspective: Conceptualization contrasted with description: Sociology Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Glaser, B. G., &amp; Strauss, A. L. (2009). The discovery of grounded theory: Strategies for qualitative research: Transaction Publishers.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Hekkert, M. P., Suurs, R. A., Negro, S. O., Kuhlmann, S., &amp; Smits, R. (2007). Functions of innovation systems: A new approach for analysing technological change. Technological forecasting and social change, 74(4), 413-432.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Hitzeroth, M., &amp; Megerle, A. (2013). Renewable energy projects: acceptance risks and their management. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 27, 576-584.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Huh, S.-Y., &amp; Lee, C.-Y. (2014). Diffusion of renewable energy technologies in South Korea on incorporating their competitive interrelationships. Energy Policy, 69, 248-257.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Huijts, N., Molin, E., &amp; Steg, L. (2012). Psychological factors influencing sustainable energy technology acceptance: A review-based comprehensive framework. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 16(1), 525-531.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Jacobsson, S., &amp; Johnson, A. (2000). The diffusion of renewable energy technology: an analytical framework and key issues for research. Energy Policy, 28(9), 625-640.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Jacobsson, S., &amp; Lauber, V. (2006). The politics and policy of energy system transformation—explaining the German diffusion of renewable energy technology. Energy Policy, 34(3), 256-276.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Jochem, E., Madlener, R., &amp; Mannsbart, W. (2002). Renewable energy technology diffusion, prospects of the German and Swiss industry in the world markets. Paper presented at the World Renewable Energy Congress.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Kumbaroğlu, G., Madlener, R., &amp; Demirel, M. (2008). A real options evaluation model for the diffusion prospects of new renewable power generation technologies. Energy Economics, 30(4), 1882-1908.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Lacasa, I. D. (2014). Ceremonial Encapsulation and the Diffusion of Renewable Energy Technology in Germany. Journal of Economic Issues, 48(4), 1073-1093.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Lomborg, K., &amp; Kirkevold, M. (2003). Truth and validity in grounded theory–a reconsidered realist interpretation of the criteria: fit, work, relevance and modifiability. Nursing Philosophy, 4(3), 189-200.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B.-Å. (2010). National systems of innovation: Toward a theory of innovation and interactive learning (Vol. 2): Anthem Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Mani, S., &amp; Dhingra, T. (2012). Diffusion of innovation model of consumer behaviour–Ideas to accelerate adoption of renewable energy sources by consumer communities in India. Renewable Energy, 39(1), 162-165.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Mostafaeipour, A., &amp; Mostafaeipour, N. (2009). Renewable energy issues and electricity production in Middle East compared with Iran. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 13(6), 1641-1645.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Negro, S. O., Alkemade, F., &amp; Hekkert, M. P. (2012). Why does renewable energy diffuse so slowly? A review of innovation system problems. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 16(6), 3836-3846.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Palm, A. (2015). An emerging innovation system for deployment of building-sited solar photovoltaics in Sweden. Environmental Innovation and Societal Transitions, 15, 140-157.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Pfeiffer, B., &amp; Mulder, P. (2013). Explaining the diffusion of renewable energy technology in developing countries. Energy Economics, 40(0), 285-296. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.eneco.2013.07.005</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Popp, D., Hascic, I., &amp; Medhi, N. (2011). Technology and the diffusion of renewable energy. Energy Economics, 33(4), 648-662.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Purohit, P., &amp; Kandpal, T. C. (2005). Renewable energy technologies for irrigation water pumping in India: projected levels of dissemination, energy delivery and investment requirements using available diffusion models. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 9(6), 592-607.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Quitzow, R. (2015). Dynamics of a policy-driven market: The co-evolution of technological innovation systems for solar photovoltaics in China and Germany. Environmental Innovation and Societal Transitions.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Radomes, A. A., &amp; Arango, S. (2015). Renewable energy technology diffusion: an analysis of photovoltaic-system support schemes in Medellín, Colombia. Journal of Cleaner Production, 92, 152-161.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Ralph, N., Birks, M., &amp; Chapman, Y. (2014). Contextual Positioning. Sage Open, 4(3).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Rao, K. U., &amp; Kishore, V. V. N. (2010). A review of technology diffusion models with special reference to renewable energy technologies. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 14(3), 1070-1078. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2009.11.007</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Reddy, S., &amp; Painuly, J. P. (2004). Diffusion of renewable energy technologies—barriers and stakeholders’ perspectives. Renewable Energy, 29(9), 1431-1447.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Richards, L., &amp; Morse, J. M. (2012). Readme first for a user›s guide to qualitative methods: Sage.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Rogers, E. M. (2010). Diffusion of innovations: Simon and Schuster.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Schumpeter, J. A. (1939). Business cycles (Vol. 1): Cambridge Univ Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Sharifi, As., aghaei, K., Sadeghi, M., Dalali, R. &amp; Shavalpoor, S., 2009. The Impact of Technological Learning on The Development of Renewable Technologicies Iran Power Sector Under Conditions of Energy Price Distortion. Quarterly Energy Economics Review, Volume(21), PP. 137-168.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>SuriÃ±ach, J., Autant-Bernard, C., Manca, F., Massard, N., &amp; Moreno, R. (2009). The diffusion/adoption of innovation in the internal market: Directorate General Economic and Monetary Affairs (DG ECFIN), European Commission.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>The law on the reform of the pattern of energy consumption. 2010. Islamic Consultative Assembly.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Tigabu, A. D., Berkhout, F., &amp; van Beukering, P. (2015). The diffusion of a renewable energy technology and innovation system functioning: Comparing bio-digestion in Kenya and Rwanda. Technological forecasting and social change, 90, 331-345.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Tsoutsos, T. D., &amp; Stamboulis, Y. A. (2005). The sustainable diffusion of renewable energy technologies as an example of an innovation-focused policy. Technovation, 25(7), 753-761. doi: http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.technovation.2003.12.003</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Viotti, E. B. (2002). National learning systems: a new approach on technological change in late industrializing economies and evidences from the cases of Brazil and South Korea. Technological forecasting and social change, 69(7), 653-680.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Wirth, S., Markard, J., Truffer, B., &amp; Rohracher, H. (2013). Informal institutions matter: Professional culture and the development of biogas technology. Environmental Innovation and Societal Transitions, 8, 20-41.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Wüstenhagen, R., &amp; Bilharz, M. (2006). Green energy market development in Germany: effective public policy and emerging customer demand. Energy Policy, 34(13), 1681-1696.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14826_bf7bd2eb6c96840c28e3073e305eb00e.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>شناسایی و اولویت بندی اصول مورد نیاز برای بهبود فضای نوآوری بنگاه های دفاعی ایران با رویکرد باز</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>حورعلی</surname>
			            <given-names>مریم</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>منتظری</surname>
			            <given-names>عباس</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>الیاسی</surname>
			            <given-names>مهدی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2015</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>4</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>57</fpage>
			      <lpage>86</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>07</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>29</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2015, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2015</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14826.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14826.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>رویکردهای جدید به نوآوری در سطح بنگاه و همچنین تغییرات شدید محیطی و فضای رقابتی حاکم بر فعالیت بنگاه‌های تولیدی، استفاده از رویکرد نوآوری باز را اجتناب‌ناپذیر کرده است. پژوهش حاضر با هدف پیشنهاد اصولی برای باز شدن فضای نوآوری در سطح بنگاه‌های دفاعی ایران انجام شد. در این راستا، پس از مرور ادبیات، 21 اصل برای بکارگیری رویکرد باز در سطح بنگاه‌ها استخراج شد و با مصاحبه‌های اکتشافی با خبرگان، به 25 اصل افزایش یافت و سپس پرسش‌نامه‌ای برای دسته‌بندی این اصول، طراحی گردید. بر اساس نظرات خبرگان، اصول پیشنهادی با استفاده از تحلیل مولفه‌های اصلی و محاسبه بارهای عاملی با مقادیر ویژه بزرگتر از یک و استفاده از چرخش متعامد به روش واریماکس با مقادیر بار مطلق عاملی بزرگتر از 6/0، در سه دسته‌بندی کلی با عنوان اصول مورد نیاز برای ایجاد نظام‌های زیرساختی نوآوری در سطح بنگاه با رویکرد باز، اصول مورد نیاز برای اجرای فرآیند نوآوری در سطح بنگاه با رویکرد باز و اصول مورد نیاز برای ایجاد فضای سازمانی مناسب نوآوری باز  قرار گرفت. در ادامه پرسش‌نامه اصلی طراحی و به خبرگان نوآوری دفاعی سپرده شد و داده‌های حاصل توسط نرم‌افزار لیزرل تحلیل گردید. نتایج نشان داد که برای بازشدن فضای نوآوری بنگاه‌های دفاعی ایران، باید ابتدا فرآیند یکپارچه مدیریت نوآوری باز، طراحی شود و استقرار یابد. سپس نظام‌های زیرساختی مناسب برای فرآیند نوآوری در سطح بنگاه مستقر و در نهایت فضای سازمانی مناسب برای نوآوری، باز شود.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>نوآوری باز</kwd>
						<kwd>مدیریت نوآوری</kwd>
						<kwd>بنگاه دفاعی</kwd>
						<kwd>نظامهای زیرساختی مناسب برای نوآوری باز</kwd>
						<kwd>فرآیند یکپارچه نوآوری باز</kwd>
						<kwd>فضای سازمانی مناسب نوآوری باز</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Balaguer, A. et al., 2008. the rise and growth of a policy-driven economy: Taiwan. In: C. Edquist &amp; L. Hommen, eds. Small Country Innovation Systems: Globalization, Change and Policy in Asia and Europe. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar Publishing Limited, pp. 31–70.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Bergek, A. &amp; Jacobsson, S., 2003. The Emergence of a Growth Industry : A Comparative Analysis of the German , Dutch and Swedish Wind Turbine Industries. In: Change, Transformation and Development. Berlin: Physica Verlag HD.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Bitard, P., Edquist, C. &amp; Hommen, L., 2008. Reconsidering the paradox of high R&amp;D input and low innovation: Sweden. In: Small Country Innovation Systems: Globalization, Change and Policy in Asia and Europe. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar Publishing Limited, pp. 237–280.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Bryman, A., 1989. Research methods and organization studies. London: Unwin Hyman Ltd.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Chaminade, C. &amp; Edquist, C., 2005. From theory to practice: the use of systems of innovation approach in innovation policy. Sweden.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H., 2003. Open Innovation: the New Imperative for Creating and Profiting from Technology. Harvard Business School Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Christensen, J., Olsen, M. &amp; Kjaer, J., 2005. The industrial dynamics of Open Innovation—Evidence from the transformation of consumer electronics. Research Policy, 34(10), pp. 1533–1549.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Dunne, P. &amp; Braddon, D., 2008. Economic Impact of Military R&amp;D, Bristol: University of he west of England.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Fabricio Jr, R. D. S. et al., 2015. Strengthening of Open Innovation Model: using startups and technology parks. IFAC-PapersOnLine, 48(3), pp. 14-20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Fagerberg, J., 2004. Innovation: A Guide to the Literature. Oxford Handbook of Innovation. Oxford University press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Godin, B., 2010. Innovation Studies: The Invention of a Specialty (Part I), Quebec.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Greenwood, D., 2010. Collaborate to Innovate: innovative capacity index for effective open innovation,  University of Meryland.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Guichard, R., 2005. Suggested Repositioning of Defence R&amp;D within the French system of Innovation. Technovation, Volume 25, pp. 195–201.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Healey, P., 2001. Managing European Technology: Defence and Competitiveness Issues (METDAC), London: European Commission.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Hung, K. P. &amp; Chou, C., 2013. The impact of open innovation on firm performance: The moderating effects of internal R&amp;D and environmental turbulence. Technovation, 33(10), pp. 368-380.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Kline, S. j. &amp; Rosenberg, N., 1986. An Overview of Innovation, in The Positive Sum Strategy: Harnessing Technology for Economic Growth. Washington DC: National Academy Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Lee, K. R., 2006. Performance and sources of industrial innovation in Korea. In: B. A. Lundvall, P. Intarakumnerd &amp; J. Vang, eds. Innovation System, in Asian Innovation Systems in Transition. Edward Elgar Pub, pp. 178–199.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B. A., 1985. Product Innovation and User-Producer Interaction, Industrial Development. Aalborg University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B. A., 2002. National systems of production , innovation and competence building. Research Policy, 31(2), pp. 213–231.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B. A., 2005. National innovation systems - Analytical concept and development tool. Industry and Innovation, 14(1), pp. 95-119.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B. A., 2009. Handbook of Innovation Systems and Developing Countries: Building Domestic Capabilities in a Global Setting. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Maclaurin, W. R., 1949. Invention and Innovation in the Radio Industry. New York: Macmillan.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Malerba, F., 1999. Technological entry and diversification in Europe, the United States and Japan, in The Organization of Economic Innovation in Europe. Cambridge University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Mowery, D., 2012. Defense-Related R&amp;D, A Model for Grand Challenge. Research Policy, 41(10), pp. 1703-1715.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson, R. R., 1993. National Innovation Systems: A Comparative Analysis. New York: Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson, R. R. &amp; Nelson, K., 2003. Technology , institutions , and innovation systems. Research Policy, Volume 31, pp. 265–272.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Niosi, J. B. &amp; Manseau, A., 2000. Canada’s National System of Innovation. McGill-Quenn’s University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>OECD, 1998. Productivity and Job Creation: Best Policy Practices,  s.n.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>OECD, 1999. Managing National Innovation Systems, Paris: OECD Publishing service.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Oyelaran, B. &amp; Rasiah, R., 2009. Uneven Paths of Development Innovation and Learning in Asia and Africa. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar Publishing Limited.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Porter, M. E., 2001. Clusters of Innovation: Regional Foundations of US. Washington: Harvard Business.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Rogers, E. M., 1983. Diffusion of Innovations. Third ed ed. New York: The Free Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Saebi, T. &amp; Foss, N. J., 2015. Business models for open innovation: Matching heterogeneous open innovation strategies with business model dimensions. European Management Journal, 33(3), pp. 201-213.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, K., 2000. Innovation as a systemic phenomenon: Rethinking the role of policy. Enterprise and Innovation Management Studies, 1(1), pp. 73–83.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Taylor, B., 2007. Innovation Strategy: Creating a new environment for innovation within the defense supply chain. London: Ministry of defence.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Tidd, J., Bessant, J. &amp; Pavitt, K., 2005. Managing Innovation: Integrating Technological, Market and Organizational Change. 3rd edition ed. John Wiley.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Viotti, E. B., 2002. National Learning Systems: A new approach on technological change in late industrializing economies and evidences from the cases of Brazil and South Korea. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, Volume 69, pp. 653–680.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, C. H., Chang, C. H. &amp; Shen, G. C., 2015. The effect of inbound open innovation on firm performance: Evidence from high-tech industry. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Volume 99, pp. 222-230.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Whitley, R. D., 2001. National innovation systems. In: International Encyclopedia of the Social Behavior Sciences. Elsevier, pp. 10303-10309.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Wong, P. K. &amp; Singh, A., 2008. From technology adopter to innovator: Singapore.. In: C. Edquist &amp; L. Hommen, eds. Small Country Innovation Systems: Globalization, Change and Policy in Asia and Europe. Cheltenham: Edward EIgar Publishing Limited.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>الیاسی، م.، 1392. نقش و جایگاه علوم و فناوری دفاعی در قدرت ملی و ارائه الگوی بهره‌گیری از آن در کاربردهای غیرنظامی. مرکز تحقیقات راهبردی ستاد کل نیروهای مسلح.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>ریاحی، پ. و قاضی نوری، س.، 1392. مقدمه‌ای بر نظام نوآوری (رویکردی گسترده). مرکز نشر دانشگاهی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>سرمد، ز.، بازرگان، ع. و حجازی، ا.، 1383. روش‌های تحقیق در علوم رفتاری. تهران: انتشارات آگاه.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>سکاران، ا.، 1381. روش‌های تحقیق در مدیریت. مرکز آموزش مدیریت دولتی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>طبائیان، س. ک.، 1390. طراحی مدل نوآوری صنعت هوایی کشور، تهران: دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>کیوی، ر. و کامپنهود، ل.، 1373. روش تحقیق در علوم اجتماعی. انتشارات فرهنگ معاصر.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>محمدی، م.، سلیمی، س.، بوشهری، ع. و نظری زاده، ف.، 1390. مروری بر نظام نوآوری دفاعی پنج کشور. تهران: انتشارات موسسه آموزشی تحقیقاتی صنایع دفاعی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>محمدی، م.، 1390. مروری بر نظام نوآوری دفاعی پنج کشور.. تهران: انتشارات سمت.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Balaguer, A. et al., 2008. the rise and growth of a policy-driven economy: Taiwan. In: C. Edquist &amp; L. Hommen, eds. Small Country Innovation Systems: Globalization, Change and Policy in Asia and Europe. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar Publishing Limited, pp. 31–70.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Bergek, A. &amp; Jacobsson, S., 2003. The Emergence of a Growth Industry : A Comparative Analysis of the German , Dutch and Swedish Wind Turbine Industries. In: Change, Transformation and Development. Berlin: Physica Verlag HD.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Bitard, P., Edquist, C. &amp; Hommen, L., 2008. Reconsidering the paradox of high R&amp;D input and low innovation: Sweden. In: Small Country Innovation Systems: Globalization, Change and Policy in Asia and Europe. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar Publishing Limited, pp. 237–280.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Bryman, A., 1989. Research methods and organization studies. London: Unwin Hyman Ltd.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Chaminade, C. &amp; Edquist, C., 2005. From theory to practice: the use of systems of innovation approach in innovation policy. Sweden.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Chesbrough, H., 2003. Open Innovation: the New Imperative for Creating and Profiting from Technology. Harvard Business School Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Christensen, J., Olsen, M. &amp; Kjaer, J., 2005. The industrial dynamics of Open Innovation—Evidence from the transformation of consumer electronics. Research Policy, 34(10), pp. 1533–1549.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Dunne, P. &amp; Braddon, D., 2008. Economic Impact of Military R&amp;D, Bristol: University of he west of England.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Elyasi, M., 2013. The role and place of defense science and technology in national power and the provision of a model for utilizing it in civilian applications. A Glance at Center for Strategic Defence Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Fabricio Jr, R. D. S. et al., 2015. Strengthening of Open Innovation Model: using startups and technology parks. IFAC-PapersOnLine, 48(3), pp. 14-20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Fagerberg, J., 2004. Innovation: A Guide to the Literature. Oxford Handbook of Innovation. Oxford University press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Godin, B., 2010. Innovation Studies: The Invention of a Specialty (Part I), Quebec.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Greenwood, D., 2010. Collaborate to Innovate: innovative capacity index for effective open innovation,  University of Meryland.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Guichard, R., 2005. Suggested Repositioning of Defence R&amp;D within the French system of Innovation. Technovation, Volume 25, pp. 195–201.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Healey, P., 2001. Managing European Technology: Defence and Competitiveness Issues (METDAC), London: European Commission.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Hung, K. P. &amp; Chou, C., 2013. The impact of open innovation on firm performance: The moderating effects of internal R&amp;D and environmental turbulence. Technovation, 33(10), pp. 368-380.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Kline, S. j. &amp; Rosenberg, N., 1986. An Overview of Innovation, in The Positive Sum Strategy: Harnessing Technology for Economic Growth. Washington DC: National Academy Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Lee, K. R., 2006. Performance and sources of industrial innovation in Korea. In: B. A. Lundvall, P. Intarakumnerd &amp; J. Vang, eds. Innovation System, in Asian Innovation Systems in Transition. Edward Elgar Pub, pp. 178–199.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B. A., 1985. Product Innovation and User-Producer Interaction, Industrial Development. Aalborg University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B. A., 2002. National systems of production , innovation and competence building. Research Policy, 31(2), pp. 213–231.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B. A., 2005. National innovation systems - Analytical concept and development tool. Industry and Innovation, 14(1), pp. 95-119.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Lundvall, B. A., 2009. Handbook of Innovation Systems and Developing Countries: Building Domestic Capabilities in a Global Setting. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>Maclaurin, W. R., 1949. Invention and Innovation in the Radio Industry. New York: Macmillan.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation>Malerba, F., 1999. Technological entry and diversification in Europe, the United States and Japan, in The Organization of Economic Innovation in Europe. Cambridge University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammadi, M.,  Salimi, S., Boushehri, As. &amp;  Nazarzadeh, F. 2011. A Review of the Five-Country Defense Innovation System. Research Institute for Defense Industries.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Mohammadi, M., 2011. A Review of the Five-Country Defense Innovation System. Tehran: The Organization for Researching and Composing University Textbooks in the Humanities (SAMT).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Mowery, D., 2012. Defense-Related R&amp;D, A Model for Grand Challenge. Research Policy, 41(10), pp. 1703-1715.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson, R. R., 1993. National Innovation Systems: A Comparative Analysis. New York: Oxford University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Nelson, R. R. &amp; Nelson, K., 2003. Technology , institutions , and innovation systems. Research Policy, Volume 31, pp. 265–272.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Niosi, J. B. &amp; Manseau, A., 2000. Canada’s National System of Innovation. McGill-Quenn’s University Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>OECD, 1998. Productivity and Job Creation: Best Policy Practices,  s.n.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>OECD, 1999. Managing National Innovation Systems, Paris: OECD Publishing service.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Oyelaran, B. &amp; Rasiah, R., 2009. Uneven Paths of Development Innovation and Learning in Asia and Africa. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar Publishing Limited.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Porter, M. E., 2001. Clusters of Innovation: Regional Foundations of US. Washington: Harvard Business.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Quivy, R. &amp; Campenhoudt, L. V., 2009. Manuel recherche en sciences socials. Farhang-Moaser Publications.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Riyahi, B. &amp; Ghazi Noori, S., 2013. Introduction to the Innovation System (Wide Approach). University Publication Center.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Rogers, E. M., 1983. Diffusion of Innovations. Third ed ed. New York: The Free Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Saebi, T. &amp; Foss, N. J., 2015. Business models for open innovation: Matching heterogeneous open innovation strategies with business model dimensions. European Management Journal, 33(3), pp. 201-213.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Sarmad, z., bazargan, As. &amp; Hjazi, A., 2004. Research Methods in Behavioral Sciences. Tehran: Agah Publication.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Sekaran, U.,2002. Research methods for busihess: a skill - building approach. Governmental Management Training Center.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, K., 2000. Innovation as a systemic phenomenon: Rethinking the role of policy. Enterprise and Innovation Management Studies, 1(1), pp. 73–83.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Tabaein, S. K., 2011. Designing the Air Industry Industry Innovation Model. Tehran: Allameh Tabatabaei University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Taylor, B., 2007. Innovation Strategy: Creating a new environment for innovation within the defense supply chain. London: Ministry of defence.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Tidd, J., Bessant, J. &amp; Pavitt, K., 2005. Managing Innovation: Integrating Technological, Market and Organizational Change. 3rd edition ed. John Wiley.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Viotti, E. B., 2002. National Learning Systems: A new approach on technological change in late industrializing economies and evidences from the cases of Brazil and South Korea. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, Volume 69, pp. 653–680.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Wang, C. H., Chang, C. H. &amp; Shen, G. C., 2015. The effect of inbound open innovation on firm performance: Evidence from high-tech industry. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Volume 99, pp. 222-230.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Whitley, R. D., 2001. National innovation systems. In: International Encyclopedia of the Social Behavior Sciences. Elsevier, pp. 10303-10309.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Wong, P. K. &amp; Singh, A., 2008. From technology adopter to innovator: Singapore.. In: C. Edquist &amp; L. Hommen, eds. Small Country Innovation Systems: Globalization, Change and Policy in Asia and Europe. Cheltenham: Edward EIgar Publishing Limited.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14827_6edd67f8f2faa5d7f76a7b8831637576.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تاثیر جهت گیری های راهبردی بر عملکرد شرکت های مستقر در پارک علم و فناوری خراسان به واسطه نوآوری سازمانی</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>رحیم نیا</surname>
			            <given-names>فریبرز</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2">
			          <name>
			            <surname>سجاد</surname>
			            <given-names>عاطفه</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2015</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>4</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>87</fpage>
			      <lpage>114</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>09</day>
			          <month>02</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>13</day>
			          <month>09</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2015, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2015</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14827.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14827.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>با توجه به نقش شرکت‌های کوچک و متوسط در پیشبرد اهداف اقتصادی و اجتماعی کشور و همچنین از طرفی مطرح شدن اقتصاد دانش‌بنیان، لزوم توجه به عملکرد شرکت‌‌های کوچک و متوسط دانش‌بنیان بیش از پیش احساس می‌شود. در این شرکت‌ها به دلیل ماهیتی که دارند، نوآوری برای تضمین بقای آن‌ها در بازار نقش حیاتی دارد؛ بنابراین در این پژوهش ابتدا تاثیر سه مولفه بازارگرایی، گرایش به کارآفرینی و گرایش به یادگیری بر نوآوری سازمانی و سپس تاثیر نوآوری سازمانی بر عملکرد شرکت‌های مستقر در پارک علم‌وفناوری خراسان بررسی شد. برای این منظور از 143 شرکت مستقر، 90 شرکت به عنوان نمونه انتخاب شدند. برای جمع‌آوری داده‌ها از ابزار پرسش‌نامه استفاده شد. حاصل تجزیه و تحلیل‌ها که با استفاده از نرم‌افزار SPSS و SMARTPLS انجام شد نشان داد که گرایش به کارآفرینی بر نوآوری سازمانی و عملکرد سازمانی تاثیر دارد و نقش میانجی‌گری کامل نوآوری سازمانی تایید شد؛ از طرفی مشخص گردید بازارگرایی، تاثیر مستقیم بر عملکرد ندارد بلکه از طریق نقش واسطه نوآوری سازمانی این رابطه تایید می‌شود، یعنی نوآوری سازمان نقش میانجی‌گری جزئی در این رابطه دارد؛ رابطه گرایش به یادگیری بر عملکرد نیز با نقش میانجی گری جزئی نوآوری تایید شد.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>جهت گیری راهبردی</kwd>
						<kwd>بازارگرایی</kwd>
						<kwd>گرایش به کارآفرینی</kwd>
						<kwd>گرایش به یادگیری</kwd>
						<kwd>نوآوری سازمانی</kwd>
						<kwd>عملکرد سازمانی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Alegre, J. &amp; Chiva, R., 2013. Linking Entrepreneurial Orientation and Firm Performance: The Role of Organizational Learning Capability and Innovation Performance. Journal of Small Business Management, 51(4), pp. 491–507.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Altuntas, semercioz &amp; Eregezc, 2013. Linking strategic and market orientations to organizational performance: the role of innovation in private healthcare organizations. Social and Behavioral Sciences, 99(6), pp. 413 – 419.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Artz, K., Norman, PP., Hatfield, D. &amp; Cardinal, L., 2010. A longitudinal study of the impact of r&amp;d, patents, and product innovation on firm performance. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 27(5), pp. 725-740.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Augusto, M. &amp; Coelho, F., 2009. Market orientation and new-to-the-world products: exploring the moderating effects of innovativeness, competitive strength, and en-vironmental forces.. Industrial Marketing Management, 38(1), pp. 94– 108.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Auh, S. &amp; Menguc, B., 2007. Performance implication of the direct and moderating effects of centralization and formalization on customer orientation. Industrial Marketing Management, 36(8), pp. 1022-1034.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Awang, A., Ariffin Ahmad, Z., Said Asghar, A. &amp; Anwar Subari, K., 2010. Entrepreneurial orientation among bumiputera small and medium agrobased enterprises (BSMAEs) in West Malaysia: Policy implication in Malaysia. International Journal of Business and Management, 5(6), pp. 130-143.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Baker, W. E. &amp; Sinkula, J. M., 1999. The synergetic effect of market orientation and learning orientation on organizational performance. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, 27(4), pp. 411−427.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Baker, W. E. &amp; Sinkula, J. M., 2009. The Complementary Effects of Market Orientation and Entrepreneurial Orientation on Profitability in Small Business. Journal of Small Business Management, 47(4), pp. 443–464.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Bapuji, H. &amp; Crossan, M., 2004. From questions to answers: reviewing organizationallearning research. Management Learning, 35(4), pp. 397- 417.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Barksdale, H. &amp; Darden, W., 1971. Marketing attitudes toward the marketing concept. Journal of Marketing, 35(4), pp. 29-36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Bing, L. &amp; Zhengping, F., 2011. Relationship between Strategic Orientation and Organizational Performance in Born Global: A Critical Review. International Journal of Business and Management, 6(3), pp. 109-115.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, Y.-S., Ming-Ji , J. L. &amp; Chang, C.-H., 2009. The positive effects of relationship learning and absorptive capacity on innovation performance and competitive advantage in industrial markets. Industrial Marketing Management, Volume 38, pp. 152–158.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Covin, J. &amp; Slevin, D., 1991. A conceptual model of entrepreneurship as firm behavior. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice, 16(1), pp. 7-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Cuu Long, H., 2013. The Relationship among Learning Orientation, Market OrientatioEntrepreneurial Orientation, and Firm Performance of Vietnam Marketing Communications Firms. Philippine Management Review, Volume 20, pp. 37‐46.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Davis, J. L., Greg Bell, R., Tyge Payne, G. &amp; Kreiser, PP. M., 2010. Entrepreneurial orientation and firm performance: the moderating role of managerial power. American Journal of Business, 25(2), pp. 41-54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Deshpande, R., Farley, J. U. &amp; Webster, F. E., 1993. Corporate culture customer orientation, and innovativeness in Japanese firms: A quadrat analysis. Journal of Marketing, 57(1), pp. 23–37.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Dess, G. &amp; Robinson, R. J., 1984. Measuring organizational performance in the absence of objective measures. Strategic Management Journal, 5(265-273).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Gokus, o., 2008. Configuration of market oriented culture, organization structure and business strategy types and their performance implication in service organization,  Old Dominion University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Greenley, G., 2000. Market orientation on business profitability : a balance replication. journal of business research, 48(1), pp. 69-73.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Gunday, G., Ulusoy, G., Kilic, K. &amp; Alpkan, L., 2011. Effects of innovation types on firm performance. International Journal of Production economics, 133(2), pp. 662-676.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Han, J. K., Kim, N. &amp; Srivastava, R. K., 1998. Market orientation and organizational performance: Is innovation a missing link?. Journal of Marketing, 62(4), pp. 30-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Hine, D. &amp; Ryan, N., 1999. Small service firms — Creating value through innovation. Managing Service Quality, 9(6), pp. 411−422.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Hughes, M. &amp; Morgan, R., 2007. Deconstructing the Relationship between Entrepreneurial Orientation and Business Performance at the Embryonic Stage of Firm Growth. Industrial Marketing Management , 36(5), pp. 651-661.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Hunt, S. &amp; Morgan, R., 1995. The comparative advantage Theory of Capitalism. Journal of Marketing, Volume 59, pp. 1-15.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Hurley, R. F. &amp; Hult, T., 1998. Innovation, market orientation, and organizational learning: An integration and empirical examination. Journal of Marketing, 62(3), pp. 42–54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>Jacob, M., Hellstrom, T., Adler, N. &amp; Norrgren, F., 2000. From sponsorship to partnership in academy–industry relation. R&amp;D Management, 30(3), pp. 255-262.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Jantunen, A., Nummela, N., Puumalainen, K. &amp; Saarenketo, S., 2008. Strategic orientations of born globals - Do they really matter?.. Journal of World Business, 43(2), pp. 158-170.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Jimenez-Jimenez, D., Sanz - Valle, R. &amp; Hernandez-Espallardo, M., 2008. Fostering Innovation: The role of market orientation and organizationallearning.European Journal of Innovation Management 11(3): 389-412.. European Journal of Innovation Management, 11(3), pp. 389-412.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Johne, A., 1999. Successful market innovation. European Journal of Innovation Management, 2(1), pp. 6−11.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Kandemir, D. &amp; Hult, G. T. M., 2005. A Conceptualization of an Organizational Learning Culture in International Joint Ventures. Industrial Marketing Management, 34(5), pp. 430-439.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Keh, H. T. N. T. T. M. &amp;. N. H. PP., 2007. The effects of entrepreneurial orientation and marketing information on the performance of SMEs. Journal of Business Venturing, 22(4), pp. 592‐611.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Keskin, 2006. Market orientation, learning orientation, and innovation capabilities in SMEs, An extended model. European Journal of Innovation Management, 9(4), pp. 396-417.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Khalili, S., Nejad, h. &amp; Fazel, A., 2013. The influence of entrepreneurial orientation on innovative performance Study of a petrochemical company in Iran. Journal of Knowledge-based Innovation in China, 5(3), pp. 262-278.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Kohli, A. &amp; Jaworski, B., 1990. Market orientation: The Construct, Research Propositions, and Managerial Application. Journal of Marketing, Volume 54, pp. 1-18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Kohli, A., Jaworski, B. &amp; Kumar, A., 1993. MARKOR: A Measure of Market orientation. Journal of Marketing Research, Volume 30, pp. 467-477.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Langerak, F., 2003. An appraisal of research on the predictive power of market orientation. European Management Journal, 21(4).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Lin, C., Peng, C. &amp; Kao, D., 2008. The innovativeness effect of market orientation and learning orientation on business performance. International Journal of Manpower, 29(8), pp. 752-772.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Li, Y. H., Huang, J. &amp; Tsai, M. T., 2009. Entrepreneurial orientation and firm performance: The role of knowledge creation process. Industrial Marketing Management, 38(4), pp. 440–449.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Lucas, B. &amp; Ferrell, O., 2000. The effects of market orientation on product innovation. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, 28(2), pp. 239-47.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Lumpkin, G. &amp; Dess, G., 1996. Enriching the Entrepreneurial Orientation Construct. The Academy of Management Review, Volume 21, pp. 605-606.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Matsuno, K. &amp; Mentzer, J. T., 2000. The Effects of Strategy Type on the Market Orientacion–performance Relationshipp. Journal of Marketing, 64(4), pp. 1 –16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Mavondo, F. C. J. &amp; Stewart, J., 2005. Learning orientation and market orientation: relationship with innovation, human resource practices and performance. European Journal of Marketing, 39(11/12), pp. 1235–1263.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Naldi, L., Nordqvist, M., Sjoberg, K. &amp; Wiklund, J., 2007. Entrepreneurial orientation, risk taking, and performance in family firms. Family businesss review, 20(1), pp. 997-1017.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Narver, J. C., Slater, S. F. &amp; MacLachlan, D. L., 2004. Responsive and proactive market orientation and new-product success. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 21(5), pp. 334-347.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Narver, J. C., Slater, S. F. &amp; Tietje, B., 1998. Creating a Market Orientation. Journal of Market Focused Management, Volume 2, pp. 225-241.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Narver, J. &amp; Slater, S., 1990. The Effect of a Market Orientation on Business Profitability. Journal of Marketing , 54(4), pp. 20-35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Özsahin, M., Zehir, C. &amp; Acar, A., 2011. Linking leadership style to firm performance: the mediating effect of the learning orientation. Procedia Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume 24, pp. 1546–1559.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Parkman, I. D., Holloway, S. S. &amp; Sebastiao, H., 2012. Creative industries: aligning entrepreneurial orientation and innovation capacity. Journal of Research in Marketing and Entrepreneurship, 14(1), pp. 95-114.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Rahab, 2012. Innovativeness Model of Small and Medium Enterprises Based On Market Orientation and Learning Orientation: Testing Moderating Effect of Business Operation Mode. Procedia Economics and Finance, Volume 4, pp. 97 – 109.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Raju, PP. S., Lonial, S. C. &amp; Crum, M. D., 2011. Market orientation in the context of SMEs: A conceptual framework. Journal of Business Research, pp. Article in Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Rauch, A., Wiklund, J., Lumpkin, G. &amp; Frese, M., 2009. Entrepreneurial orientation and business performance: An assessment of past research and suggestions for the future. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice, 33(3), pp. 761–787.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Rhee, J., Park, T. &amp; Lee, D., 2010. Drivers of innovativeness and performance for innovative SMEs in South Korea: Mediation of learning orientation. Journal of Technovation, 30(1), pp. 65–75.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Rodoula, H. &amp; Tsiotdou, T., 2010. Delineating the effect of market orientation on services performance: a component-wise approach. Service Industries Journal, 30(3), pp. 375- 403.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Sandvik, I. L. &amp; Sandvik, K., 2003. The impact of market orientation on product innovativeness and business performance. International Journal of Research in Marketing, 20(4), pp. 355−376.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Slater, S. &amp; Narver, J., 1994. Does Competitive Environment Moderate the Market Orientation Performance Relationship?. Journal of Marketing, 58(1), pp. 46-55.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Suliyanto &amp; Rahab , 2012. The Role of Market Orientation and Learning Orientation in Improving Innovativeness and Performance of Small and Medium Enterprises. Asian Social Science Journal, 8(1), pp. 134-145.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Suliyanto &amp; Rahab, 2012. The Role of Market Orientation and Learning Orientation in Improving Innovativeness and Performance of Small and Medium Enterprises. Asian Social Science Journal, 8(1), pp. 134-145.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Theodosiou, M., Kehagias, J. &amp; Evangelia , K., 2012. Strategic orientations, marketing capabilities and firm performance: An empirical. Industrial Marketing Management, pp. 1-13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Tsiotsou, R., 2010. Delineating the effect of market orientation on services performance: a component-wise approach. The Service Industries Journal, 30(3), pp. 375- 403.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Tushman, M. &amp; Nadler, D., 1986. Organizing for innovation. California Management Review, 28(3), pp. 74-92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Venkatraman, N. &amp; Ramanujam, V., 1986. Measurement of business performance in strategy research: A comparison of approaches. Academy of Management Review, 11(4), pp. 801-814.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>Wiklund, J. &amp; Shepherd, D., 2005. Entrepreneurial orientation and small business performance: A configurational approach. Journal of Business Venturing, 20(1), pp. 71–79.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Wright, PP., Kroll, M., Pray, B. &amp; Lado, A., 1995. Strategic orientations, competitive advantage and business performance. Journal of Business Research, 33(2), pp. 143-51.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Zahra, S. &amp; Covin, J., 1995. Contextual influences on the corporate entrepreneurship performance relationship: A longitudinal analysis. Journal of Business Venturing, 10(1), pp. 43-58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Zhou, K. Z., Yim, C. K. &amp; Tse, D. K., 2005. The effects of strategic orientations on technology and market based breakthrough innovations. Journal of Marketing, 69(2), pp. 42–60.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>ایمانی پور، ن. و زیودار، م.، 1387. بررسی رابطه گرایش به کارآفرینانی شرکتی و عملکرد ، مطالعه موردی : نمایندگی‌های فروش شرکت سهامی بیمه ایران در شهر تهران. توسعه کارآفرینی، (2) 1، صص. 11-34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>عباس زاده، ح.، درویش، ح.، الوانی، س. م. و صالحی، ج.، 1390. الگوی استراتژی گرایش به کارآفرینی در نظام بانکی ایران. مجله مطالعات مدیریت راهبردی، شماره 7، صص. 99 - 116.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>ملاحسینی، ع. و فتحی، ف.، 1388. متغیرهای موثر بر الگوی نوآوری در شرکت‌های متوسط و کوچک شهر کرمان. دو فصلنامه برنامه و بودجه، (1) 14، صص. 59 – 74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>موتمنی، ع.، حسین آبادی، م. و همتی، ا.، 1391. ارزیابی نرخ موفقیت واحدهای فناور مستقر در پارک‌ها و مراکز رشد علم‌وفناوری. فصلنامه تخصصی پارک‌ها و مراکز رشد،(32) 8، صص. 40-32.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>مهارتی، ی. و طباطبایی، ح.، 1391. بررسی و تحلیل تاثیر گرایش به بازار از دیدگاه فرهنگی و رفتاری بر عملکرد بانک‌های دولتی. فصلنامه چشم‌انداز مدیریت بازرگانی، (10) 5، صص. 25-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>میرقربانی گنجی، س. م.، 1392. انتقال فناوری راهکاری موثر در توسعه‌ی صنایع کوچک و متوسط. ماهنامه مدیریت صنعت هوشمند، شماره 4، صص. 19 – 23.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R72">
			<label>72</label>
			<element-citation>هومن، ح. ع.، 1387. مدل‌یابی معدلات ساختاری به کمک نرم‌افزار لیزرل. تهران: سمت.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R73">
			<label>73</label>
			<element-citation> _||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R74">
			<label>74</label>
			<element-citation>Abaszadeh, H., Darvish, H., Alvani, S. M. &amp; Salehi, J., 2011. The Model of Entrepreneurial Orientation Strategy in Banking Industry of Iran. Journal of Strategic Management Studies, Volume (7), pp.99-116.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R75">
			<label>75</label>
			<element-citation>Alegre, J. &amp; Chiva, R., 2013. Linking Entrepreneurial Orientation and Firm Performance: The Role of Organizational Learning Capability and Innovation Performance. Journal of Small Business Management, 51(4), pp. 491–507.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R76">
			<label>76</label>
			<element-citation>Altuntas, semercioz &amp; Eregezc, 2013. Linking strategic and market orientations to organizational performance: the role of innovation in private healthcare organizations. Social and Behavioral Sciences, 99(6), pp. 413 – 419.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R77">
			<label>77</label>
			<element-citation>Artz, K., Norman, PP., Hatfield, D. &amp; Cardinal, L., 2010. A longitudinal study of the impact of r&amp;d, patents, and product innovation on firm performance. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 27(5), pp. 725-740.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R78">
			<label>78</label>
			<element-citation>Augusto, M. &amp; Coelho, F., 2009. Market orientation and new-to-the-world products: exploring the moderating effects of innovativeness, competitive strength, and en-vironmental forces.. Industrial Marketing Management, 38(1), pp. 94– 108.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R79">
			<label>79</label>
			<element-citation>Auh, S. &amp; Menguc, B., 2007. Performance implication of the direct and moderating effects of centralization and formalization on customer orientation. Industrial Marketing Management, 36(8), pp. 1022-1034.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R80">
			<label>80</label>
			<element-citation>Awang, A., Ariffin Ahmad, Z., Said Asghar, A. &amp; Anwar Subari, K., 2010. Entrepreneurial orientation among bumiputera small and medium agrobased enterprises (BSMAEs) in West Malaysia: Policy implication in Malaysia. International Journal of Business and Management, 5(6), pp. 130-143.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R81">
			<label>81</label>
			<element-citation>Baker, W. E. &amp; Sinkula, J. M., 1999. The synergetic effect of market orientation and learning orientation on organizational performance. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, 27(4), pp. 411−427.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R82">
			<label>82</label>
			<element-citation>Baker, W. E. &amp; Sinkula, J. M., 2009. The Complementary Effects of Market Orientation and Entrepreneurial Orientation on Profitability in Small Business. Journal of Small Business Management, 47(4), pp. 443–464.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R83">
			<label>83</label>
			<element-citation>Bapuji, H. &amp; Crossan, M., 2004. From questions to answers: reviewing organizationallearning research. Management Learning, 35(4), pp. 397- 417.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R84">
			<label>84</label>
			<element-citation>Barksdale, H. &amp; Darden, W., 1971. Marketing attitudes toward the marketing concept. Journal of Marketing, 35(4), pp. 29-36.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R85">
			<label>85</label>
			<element-citation>Bing, L. &amp; Zhengping, F., 2011. Relationship between Strategic Orientation and Organizational Performance in Born Global: A Critical Review. International Journal of Business and Management, 6(3), pp. 109-115.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R86">
			<label>86</label>
			<element-citation>Chen, Y.-S., Ming-Ji , J. L. &amp; Chang, C.-H., 2009. The positive effects of relationship learning and absorptive capacity on innovation performance and competitive advantage in industrial markets. Industrial Marketing Management, Volume 38, pp. 152–158.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R87">
			<label>87</label>
			<element-citation>Covin, J. &amp; Slevin, D., 1991. A conceptual model of entrepreneurship as firm behavior. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice, 16(1), pp. 7-25.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R88">
			<label>88</label>
			<element-citation>Cuu Long, H., 2013. The Relationship among Learning Orientation, Market OrientatioEntrepreneurial Orientation, and Firm Performance of Vietnam Marketing Communications Firms. Philippine Management Review, Volume 20, pp. 37‐46.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R89">
			<label>89</label>
			<element-citation>Davis, J. L., Greg Bell, R., Tyge Payne, G. &amp; Kreiser, PP. M., 2010. Entrepreneurial orientation and firm performance: the moderating role of managerial power. American Journal of Business, 25(2), pp. 41-54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R90">
			<label>90</label>
			<element-citation>Deshpande, R., Farley, J. U. &amp; Webster, F. E., 1993. Corporate culture customer orientation, and innovativeness in Japanese firms: A quadrat analysis. Journal of Marketing, 57(1), pp. 23–37.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R91">
			<label>91</label>
			<element-citation>Dess, G. &amp; Robinson, R. J., 1984. Measuring organizational performance in the absence of objective measures. Strategic Management Journal, 5(265-273).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R92">
			<label>92</label>
			<element-citation>Gokus, o., 2008. Configuration of market oriented culture, organization structure and business strategy types and their performance implication in service organization,  Old Dominion University.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R93">
			<label>93</label>
			<element-citation>Greenley, G., 2000. Market orientation on business profitability : a balance replication. journal of business research, 48(1), pp. 69-73.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R94">
			<label>94</label>
			<element-citation>Gunday, G., Ulusoy, G., Kilic, K. &amp; Alpkan, L., 2011. Effects of innovation types on firm performance. International Journal of Production economics, 133(2), pp. 662-676.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R95">
			<label>95</label>
			<element-citation>Imanipour, N. &amp; Zivdar, M., 2008. Studying the Relationship Between Corporate Entrepreneurship Orientation and Performance Iran Insurance Company Agencies in Tehran). Journal of Entrepreneurship Development, 1(2), pp. 11-34.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R96">
			<label>96</label>
			<element-citation>Han, J. K., Kim, N. &amp; Srivastava, R. K., 1998. Market orientation and organizational performance: Is innovation a missing link?. Journal of Marketing, 62(4), pp. 30-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R97">
			<label>97</label>
			<element-citation>Hine, D. &amp; Ryan, N., 1999. Small service firms — Creating value through innovation. Managing Service Quality, 9(6), pp. 411−422.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R98">
			<label>98</label>
			<element-citation>Hughes, M. &amp; Morgan, R., 2007. Deconstructing the Relationship between Entrepreneurial Orientation and Business Performance at the Embryonic Stage of Firm Growth. Industrial Marketing Management , 36(5), pp. 651-661.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R99">
			<label>99</label>
			<element-citation>Houman, H. As., 2008. Structural Simulation Modeling Using Laser Software .Tehran: Samt.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R100">
			<label>100</label>
			<element-citation>Hunt, S. &amp; Morgan, R., 1995. The comparative advantage Theory of Capitalism. Journal of Marketing, Volume 59, pp. 1-15.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R101">
			<label>101</label>
			<element-citation>Hurley, R. F. &amp; Hult, T., 1998. Innovation, market orientation, and organizational learning: An integration and empirical examination. Journal of Marketing, 62(3), pp. 42–54.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R102">
			<label>102</label>
			<element-citation>Jacob, M., Hellstrom, T., Adler, N. &amp; Norrgren, F., 2000. From sponsorship to partnership in academy–industry relation. R&amp;D Management, 30(3), pp. 255-262.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R103">
			<label>103</label>
			<element-citation>Jantunen, A., Nummela, N., Puumalainen, K. &amp; Saarenketo, S., 2008. Strategic orientations of born globals - Do they really matter?.. Journal of World Business, 43(2), pp. 158-170.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R104">
			<label>104</label>
			<element-citation>Jimenez-Jimenez, D., Sanz - Valle, R. &amp; Hernandez-Espallardo, M., 2008. Fostering Innovation: The role of market orientation and organizationallearning.European Journal of Innovation Management 11(3): 389-412.. European Journal of Innovation Management, 11(3), pp. 389-412.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R105">
			<label>105</label>
			<element-citation>Johne, A., 1999. Successful market innovation. European Journal of Innovation Management, 2(1), pp. 6−11.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R106">
			<label>106</label>
			<element-citation>Kandemir, D. &amp; Hult, G. T. M., 2005. A Conceptualization of an Organizational Learning Culture in International Joint Ventures. Industrial Marketing Management, 34(5), pp. 430-439.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R107">
			<label>107</label>
			<element-citation>Keh, H. T. N. T. T. M. &amp;. N. H. PP., 2007. The effects of entrepreneurial orientation and marketing information on the performance of SMEs. Journal of Business Venturing, 22(4), pp. 592‐611.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R108">
			<label>108</label>
			<element-citation>Keskin, 2006. Market orientation, learning orientation, and innovation capabilities in SMEs, An extended model. European Journal of Innovation Management, 9(4), pp. 396-417.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R109">
			<label>109</label>
			<element-citation>Khalili, S., Nejad, h. &amp; Fazel, A., 2013. The influence of entrepreneurial orientation on innovative performance Study of a petrochemical company in Iran. Journal of Knowledge-based Innovation in China, 5(3), pp. 262-278.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R110">
			<label>110</label>
			<element-citation>Kohli, A. &amp; Jaworski, B., 1990. Market orientation: The Construct, Research Propositions, and Managerial Application. Journal of Marketing, Volume 54, pp. 1-18.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R111">
			<label>111</label>
			<element-citation>Kohli, A., Jaworski, B. &amp; Kumar, A., 1993. MARKOR: A Measure of Market orientation. Journal of Marketing Research, Volume 30, pp. 467-477.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R112">
			<label>112</label>
			<element-citation>Langerak, F., 2003. An appraisal of research on the predictive power of market orientation. European Management Journal, 21(4).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R113">
			<label>113</label>
			<element-citation>Lin, C., Peng, C. &amp; Kao, D., 2008. The innovativeness effect of market orientation and learning orientation on business performance. International Journal of Manpower, 29(8), pp. 752-772.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R114">
			<label>114</label>
			<element-citation>Li, Y. H., Huang, J. &amp; Tsai, M. T., 2009. Entrepreneurial orientation and firm performance: The role of knowledge creation process. Industrial Marketing Management, 38(4), pp. 440–449.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R115">
			<label>115</label>
			<element-citation>Lucas, B. &amp; Ferrell, O., 2000. The effects of market orientation on product innovation. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, 28(2), pp. 239-47.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R116">
			<label>116</label>
			<element-citation>Lumpkin, G. &amp; Dess, G., 1996. Enriching the Entrepreneurial Orientation Construct. The Academy of Management Review, Volume 21, pp. 605-606.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R117">
			<label>117</label>
			<element-citation>Matsuno, K. &amp; Mentzer, J. T., 2000. The Effects of Strategy Type on the Market Orientacion–performance Relationshipp. Journal of Marketing, 64(4), pp. 1 –16.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R118">
			<label>118</label>
			<element-citation>Mavondo, F. C. J. &amp; Stewart, J., 2005. Learning orientation and market orientation: relationship with innovation, human resource practices and performance. European Journal of Marketing, 39(11/12), pp. 1235–1263.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R119">
			<label>119</label>
			<element-citation>Maharati, Y. &amp; Tabatabaei, H., 2012. Investigating and analyzing the impact of market orientation from the cultural and behavioral point of view on the performance of government banks. Journal of Business Management, 5(10), pp. 25-45.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R120">
			<label>120</label>
			<element-citation>Molahosseini, As. &amp; Fathi, F., 2009. Variables Effective on the Innovation Model in Small and Medium Enterprises (SME’s) of Kerman-Iran. The Journal of Planning and Budgeting, 14(1), pp.59-74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R121">
			<label>121</label>
			<element-citation>Motamani, As., Hossein Abadi, M. &amp; Hemati, A., 2012. Evaluation of the Success Rate of Tenants in Science and  Technology Parks and Icubators. journal of science and technology parks &amp; incubators, 8(32), pp. 32-40.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R122">
			<label>122</label>
			<element-citation>Mirghorbani Ganji, S. M., 2013. Technology transfer is an effective solution for the development of small and medium industries. Intelligent Industry Management Monthly, Volume(4), pp. 19-23.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R123">
			<label>123</label>
			<element-citation>Naldi, L., Nordqvist, M., Sjoberg, K. &amp; Wiklund, J., 2007. Entrepreneurial orientation, risk taking, and performance in family firms. Family businesss review, 20(1), pp. 997-1017.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R124">
			<label>124</label>
			<element-citation>Narver, J. C., Slater, S. F. &amp; MacLachlan, D. L., 2004. Responsive and proactive market orientation and new-product success. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 21(5), pp. 334-347.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R125">
			<label>125</label>
			<element-citation>Narver, J. C., Slater, S. F. &amp; Tietje, B., 1998. Creating a Market Orientation. Journal of Market Focused Management, Volume 2, pp. 225-241.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R126">
			<label>126</label>
			<element-citation>Narver, J. &amp; Slater, S., 1990. The Effect of a Market Orientation on Business Profitability. Journal of Marketing , 54(4), pp. 20-35.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R127">
			<label>127</label>
			<element-citation>Özsahin, M., Zehir, C. &amp; Acar, A., 2011. Linking leadership style to firm performance: the mediating effect of the learning orientation. Procedia Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume 24, pp. 1546–1559.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R128">
			<label>128</label>
			<element-citation>Parkman, I. D., Holloway, S. S. &amp; Sebastiao, H., 2012. Creative industries: aligning entrepreneurial orientation and innovation capacity. Journal of Research in Marketing and Entrepreneurship, 14(1), pp. 95-114.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R129">
			<label>129</label>
			<element-citation>Rahab, 2012. Innovativeness Model of Small and Medium Enterprises Based On Market Orientation and Learning Orientation: Testing Moderating Effect of Business Operation Mode. Procedia Economics and Finance, Volume 4, pp. 97 – 109.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R130">
			<label>130</label>
			<element-citation>Raju, PP. S., Lonial, S. C. &amp; Crum, M. D., 2011. Market orientation in the context of SMEs: A conceptual framework. Journal of Business Research, pp. Article in Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R131">
			<label>131</label>
			<element-citation>Rauch, A., Wiklund, J., Lumpkin, G. &amp; Frese, M., 2009. Entrepreneurial orientation and business performance: An assessment of past research and suggestions for the future. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice, 33(3), pp. 761–787.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R132">
			<label>132</label>
			<element-citation>Rhee, J., Park, T. &amp; Lee, D., 2010. Drivers of innovativeness and performance for innovative SMEs in South Korea: Mediation of learning orientation. Journal of Technovation, 30(1), pp. 65–75.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R133">
			<label>133</label>
			<element-citation>Rodoula, H. &amp; Tsiotdou, T., 2010. Delineating the effect of market orientation on services performance: a component-wise approach. Service Industries Journal, 30(3), pp. 375- 403.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R134">
			<label>134</label>
			<element-citation>Sandvik, I. L. &amp; Sandvik, K., 2003. The impact of market orientation on product innovativeness and business performance. International Journal of Research in Marketing, 20(4), pp. 355−376.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R135">
			<label>135</label>
			<element-citation>Slater, S. &amp; Narver, J., 1994. Does Competitive Environment Moderate the Market Orientation Performance Relationship?. Journal of Marketing, 58(1), pp. 46-55.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R136">
			<label>136</label>
			<element-citation>Suliyanto &amp; Rahab , 2012. The Role of Market Orientation and Learning Orientation in Improving Innovativeness and Performance of Small and Medium Enterprises. Asian Social Science Journal, 8(1), pp. 134-145.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R137">
			<label>137</label>
			<element-citation>Suliyanto &amp; Rahab, 2012. The Role of Market Orientation and Learning Orientation in Improving Innovativeness and Performance of Small and Medium Enterprises. Asian Social Science Journal, 8(1), pp. 134-145.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R138">
			<label>138</label>
			<element-citation>Theodosiou, M., Kehagias, J. &amp; Evangelia , K., 2012. Strategic orientations, marketing capabilities and firm performance: An empirical. Industrial Marketing Management, pp. 1-13.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R139">
			<label>139</label>
			<element-citation>Tsiotsou, R., 2010. Delineating the effect of market orientation on services performance: a component-wise approach. The Service Industries Journal, 30(3), pp. 375- 403.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R140">
			<label>140</label>
			<element-citation>Tushman, M. &amp; Nadler, D., 1986. Organizing for innovation. California Management Review, 28(3), pp. 74-92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R141">
			<label>141</label>
			<element-citation>Venkatraman, N. &amp; Ramanujam, V., 1986. Measurement of business performance in strategy research: A comparison of approaches. Academy of Management Review, 11(4), pp. 801-814.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R142">
			<label>142</label>
			<element-citation>Wiklund, J. &amp; Shepherd, D., 2005. Entrepreneurial orientation and small business performance: A configurational approach. Journal of Business Venturing, 20(1), pp. 71–79.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R143">
			<label>143</label>
			<element-citation>Wright, PP., Kroll, M., Pray, B. &amp; Lado, A., 1995. Strategic orientations, competitive advantage and business performance. Journal of Business Research, 33(2), pp. 143-51.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R144">
			<label>144</label>
			<element-citation>Zahra, S. &amp; Covin, J., 1995. Contextual influences on the corporate entrepreneurship performance relationship: A longitudinal analysis. Journal of Business Venturing, 10(1), pp. 43-58.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R145">
			<label>145</label>
			<element-citation>Zhou, K. Z., Yim, C. K. &amp; Tse, D. K., 2005. The effects of strategic orientations on technology and market based breakthrough innovations. Journal of Marketing, 69(2), pp. 42–60.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14828_310788e6c4bdc82ca11b2524daad9861.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>نوآوری اجتماعی: کنکاشی بر مفهوم سازی مبتنی بر تحلیل محتوای تعاریف</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>مبین دهکردی</surname>
			            <given-names>علی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>کشتکار هرانکی</surname>
			            <given-names>مهران</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه عالی دفاع ملی</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2015</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>4</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>115</fpage>
			      <lpage>134</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>31</day>
			          <month>05</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>23</day>
			          <month>11</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2015, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2015</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14828.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14828.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>امروزه نوآوری اجتماعی به‌عنوان یک موضوع مهم و حیاتی در جوامع مطرح است. با این حال، مطالعه ادبیات موضوع نشان می‌دهد یکپارچگی چندانی میان نویسندگان مختلف وجود نداشته و طیف وسیع و گسترده‌ای از تفسیرها و تعریف‌ها در مورد آن ارائه شده است. در این شرایط، واکاوی تعریف‌های موجود و ارائه تعریفی واضح، روشن، یکپارچه و جامع از نوآوری اجتماعی ضرورتی اجتناب‌ناپذیر است که می‌تواند به برداشت و درک مشترک و منطقی از آن کمک نماید. برای این منظور، با مراجعه به اسناد و مدارک معتبر قابل‌دسترس، تعداد 100 تعریف ارائه‌شده مراکز علمی و تحقیقاتی معتبر و نویسندگان مختلف در مورد نوآوری اجتماعی بر اساس سه دسته کلی معیار «هدف»، «تمرکز» و «ماهیت» جمع‌آوری گردید. به‌منظور شناخت مفاهیم تشکیل‌دهنده، ابعاد و مؤلفه‌های تاثیرگذار، از روش تحلیل محتوا استفاده شد. در ادامه به‌منظور اعتبارسنجی مفاهیم استخراج‌شده، از روش پانل دلفی با حضور تعدادی از صاحب‌نظران و خبرگان استفاده شد. در پایان، یافته‌های پژوهش در قالب 7 گزاره شامل «ایده کالا و خدمات عمومی»؛ «مدلی از حکمرانی»؛ «مدلی از مدیریت سازمانی»؛ «معطوف به اهداف اجتماعی»؛ «کارآفرینی اجتماعی»؛ «تغییر نهادی»؛ و «تحول اجتماعی» برای بیان مفهوم نوآوری اجتماعی ارائه گردید.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>نوآوری</kwd>
						<kwd>نوآوری اجتماعی</kwd>
						<kwd>تحلیل محتوا</kwd>
						<kwd>دلفی</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation>Biggs, R., Westley, F. R., &amp; Carpenter, S.R., 2010. Navigating the back loop: fostering social innovation and transformation in ecosystem management. Ecology and Society, 15(2).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Dedijer, S., 1984. Social innovations for development. Oxford Science- and Technology-related Social innovations in UNCSTD National Papers. In Carl-Göran Hedén, Alexander King (Eds.): New York [etc.]: Pergamon Press, pp. 57–92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Dees, J. &amp; Anderson, B., 2006. Framing a Theory of Social Entrepreneurship: Building on Two Schools of Practice and Thought. In: Research on Social Entrepreneurship: Understanding and Contributing to an Emerging Field. Association for Research on Non-proft Organizations and Voluntary Action (ARNOVA).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Elo, S. &amp; Kyng¨s, H., 2008. The qualitative content analysis process. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 62(1), pp. 107–115.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Fathian, M., 2007. Application of Delphi Technique for Development of E-Readiness Assessment Model: A Study on Small and Medium Enterprises of Iran. IRMA International Conference.  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Goldsmith, S., 2010. The Power of Social Innovation: How civic entrepreneurs ignite community networks for good. Jossey-Bass, San Francisco, CA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Grice, J.C., Davies, A., Patrik, R. &amp; Norman, W., 2012. Defining social innovation. The Young Foundation. Available at: www. Youngfoundation.org</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Hahn, J. &amp; Andor, L., 2013. Guide to social innovation. European Commission.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Hamalainen, T.J. &amp; Heiskala, R., 2007. Social Innovations, Institutional Change and Economic Performance. Cheltenham, U.K. and Northampton, Mass: Elgar in association with Sitra, the Finnish Innovation Fund.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Hamerlinck, Laurens.R.E.(2010). Social Innovation, Beyond the hype, Tilburg School of Social and Behavioral Sciences, 2010.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Hochgerner, J., 2009. Innovation processes in the dynamics of social change. ZSI – Centre for Social Innovation, Vienna, In Jibi Loudin, Klaus Schuch (ed.), 2009. Innovation Cultures.  Challenge and Learning Strategy. Prague: Filosofia; pp. 17-45</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Hochgerner, J., 2012. New Combinations of Social Practices in the Knowledge Society. In: H. W. Franz, J. Hochgerner &amp; J. Howaldt, eds. Challenge Social Innovation. Berlin: Springer-Verlag, pp. 87-104.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Howaldt, J., 2012. Social Innovation and Workplace Innovation in Germany. Second International Wellbeing at Work Conference.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Howaldt, J. &amp; Kopp, R., 2012. Shaping social innovation by social research. In: Franz, Hans-Werner; Hochgerner, Josef; Howaldt, Jürgen (Hrsg.): Challenge social innovation, pp. 43-55, Heidelberg: Springer Verlag.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Howaldt, J. &amp; Schwarz, M., 2010. Social innovation: concepts, research fields and international trends. 1st ed. Aachen: IMA/ZLW, Available at: http://www.sfsdortmund.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Hubert, A. et al. 2010. Empowering people, driving change: Social innovation in the   European Union, BEPA (Bureau of European Policy Advisers) (Ed.), Brussels. Available at:  http://ec.europa.eu/bepa/pdf/publications_pdf/social_innovation.pdf.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Hsieh, H. F. &amp; Shannon, S. E., 2005. Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qualitative Health Research, 15(9), pp. 1277-1288.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Kennedy, H.P., 2004. Enhancing Delphi research: methods and results. J Adv Nurs. 45(5), pp. 504-11.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Krippendorff, k., 2004. Content Analysis – An Introduction to its Methodology. SAGE Publication</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>Llie, G.E., During, R., 2012. An analysis of social innovation discourses on Europe, Concepts and Strateies of Social innovation, Availabe at: https://webgate.ec.europa.eu /socialinnovationeurope /en/magazine/context/highlights /analysis-social-innovation-discourses-europe</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>Martinelli, F., 2012. Social Innovation or Social Exclusion? Innovating Social Service in the Context of a Retrenching Welfare State. In Franz, H., Hochgerner, J., Howaldt, J., (Eds.), Challenge Social Innovation. Berlin: Springer-Verlag, pp.169-180.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>Menzel, H.C. &amp; Aaltio, I.,&amp; Ulijn, J.M., 2007. On the way to creativity: Engineers as intrapreneurs in organizations. Technovation, 27 (12), pp. 732–743.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>Moulaert, F., &amp; Lille, F., 2007. Social innovation, governance and community building (SINGOCOM), EU Research on Social Sciences and Humanities. Available at: http://cordis.europa.eu/documents/documentlibrary/100123951EN6.pdf</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>Mulgan, G., Tucker, S., Rushanara, A. &amp; Sanders, B., 2007. Social Innovation. What it is, why it matters and how it can be accelerated. Oxford Said Business School Skoll Centre for Social Entrepreneurship.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>Murray, R., Caulier-Grice; Mulgan, G., 2010. The Open Book of Social Innovation, the Young Foundation &amp; NESTA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>OECD, 2010. Social Entrepreneurship and Social Innovation, in: SMEs, Entrepreneurship and Innovation.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>Osburg, T., Schmidpeter, 2010. Social Innovation: Que Vadis? , Tilburg School of Social and Behavioral Sciences.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>Phills, J.A., Deiglmeier, K., Miller, Dale, T. (2008). Rediscovering Social Innovation. In Stanford Social Innovation Review 6 (4), pp. 34–43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Poll, E. &amp; Ville, S., 2009. Social innovation: Buzz word or enduring term?. School of Economics, University of Wollongong, The Journal of Socio-Economics 38(6),pp. 878–885.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation>Porter, M. &amp; Kramer, M., 2011. Shared Value: How to reinvent capitalism - and unleash a wave of innovation and growth. Harvard Business Review, 89(1/2), pp. 62-77.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Rader, s., 2007. Qualitative Methods of Data Analysis, Swiss- Federal Institute of Technology. Zurich.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Rüede, D. &amp; Lurtz, K., 2012. Maps the various meanings of social innovation: Towards a differentiated understanding of an emerging concept, EBS Business School, Research Paper Series 12-03.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Social Innovation eXchange (SIX), 2010. Study on Social Innovation, Young Foundation. Available at:http://youngfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Study-on-Social-Innovation-for-the-Bureau-of-European-Policy-Advisors-March-2010.pdf</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Young Foundation. (2012). Social Innovation Overview: A deliverable of the project TEPSIE. European Commission – 7th Framework Programme, Brussels: European Commission, DG Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Zapf, W., 1991. The role of innovations in modernization theory. International Review of Sociology, 1(3), pp. 83–94.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>مبینی دهکردی، علی و کشتکار، مهران.1393. بررسی تاثیر مدل سه شاخگی بر نوآوری اجتماعی (مطالعه موردی یک شرکت وابسته به صنایع خودروسازی).فصلنامه مدیریت نوآوری، (4) 3، صص 75-57._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation> Biggs, R., Westley, F. R., &amp; Carpenter, S.R., 2010. Navigating the back loop: fostering social innovation and transformation in ecosystem management. Ecology and Society, 15(2).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Dedijer, S., 1984. Social innovations for development. Oxford Science- and Technology-related Social innovations in UNCSTD National Papers. In Carl-Göran Hedén, Alexander King (Eds.): New York [etc.]: Pergamon Press, pp. 57–92.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Dees, J. &amp; Anderson, B., 2006. Framing a Theory of Social Entrepreneurship: Building on Two Schools of Practice and Thought. In: Research on Social Entrepreneurship: Understanding and Contributing to an Emerging Field. Association for Research on Non-proft Organizations and Voluntary Action (ARNOVA).</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Elo, S. &amp; Kyng¨s, H., 2008. The qualitative content analysis process. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 62(1), pp. 107–115.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Fathian, M., 2007. Application of Delphi Technique for Development of E-Readiness Assessment Model: A Study on Small and Medium Enterprises of Iran. IRMA International Conference.  </element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Goldsmith, S., 2010. The Power of Social Innovation: How civic entrepreneurs ignite community networks for good. Jossey-Bass, San Francisco, CA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Grice, J.C., Davies, A., Patrik, R. &amp; Norman, W., 2012. Defining social innovation. The Young Foundation. Available at: www. Youngfoundation.org</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Hahn, J. &amp; Andor, L., 2013. Guide to social innovation. European Commission.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Hamalainen, T.J. &amp; Heiskala, R., 2007. Social Innovations, Institutional Change and Economic Performance. Cheltenham, U.K. and Northampton, Mass: Elgar in association with Sitra, the Finnish Innovation Fund.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Hamerlinck, Laurens.R.E.(2010). Social Innovation, Beyond the hype, Tilburg School of Social and Behavioral Sciences, 2010.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Hochgerner, J., 2009. Innovation processes in the dynamics of social change. ZSI – Centre for Social Innovation, Vienna, In Jibi Loudin, Klaus Schuch (ed.), 2009. Innovation Cultures.  Challenge and Learning Strategy. Prague: Filosofia; pp. 17-45</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Hochgerner, J., 2012. New Combinations of Social Practices in the Knowledge Society. In: H. W. Franz, J. Hochgerner &amp; J. Howaldt, eds. Challenge Social Innovation. Berlin: Springer-Verlag, pp. 87-104.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Howaldt, J., 2012. Social Innovation and Workplace Innovation in Germany. Second International Wellbeing at Work Conference.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Howaldt, J. &amp; Kopp, R., 2012. Shaping social innovation by social research. In: Franz, Hans-Werner; Hochgerner, Josef; Howaldt, Jürgen (Hrsg.): Challenge social innovation, pp. 43-55, Heidelberg: Springer Verlag.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Howaldt, J. &amp; Schwarz, M., 2010. Social innovation: concepts, research fields and international trends. 1st ed. Aachen: IMA/ZLW, Available at: http://www.sfsdortmund.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Hubert, A. et al. 2010. Empowering people, driving change: Social innovation in the   European Union, BEPA (Bureau of European Policy Advisers) (Ed.), Brussels. Available at:  http://ec.europa.eu/bepa/pdf/publications_pdf/social_innovation.pdf.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Hsieh, H. F. &amp; Shannon, S. E., 2005. Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qualitative Health Research, 15(9), pp. 1277-1288.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Kennedy, H.P., 2004. Enhancing Delphi research: methods and results. J Adv Nurs. 45(5), pp. 504-11.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Krippendorff, k., 2004. Content Analysis – An Introduction to its Methodology. SAGE Publication</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Llie, G.E., During, R., 2012. An analysis of social innovation discourses on Europe, Concepts and Strateies of Social innovation, Availabe at: https://webgate.ec.europa.eu /socialinnovationeurope /en/magazine/context/highlights /analysis-social-innovation-discourses-europe</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R57">
			<label>57</label>
			<element-citation>Martinelli, F., 2012. Social Innovation or Social Exclusion? Innovating Social Service in the Context of a Retrenching Welfare State. In Franz, H., Hochgerner, J., Howaldt, J., (Eds.), Challenge Social Innovation. Berlin: Springer-Verlag, pp.169-180.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R58">
			<label>58</label>
			<element-citation>Menzel, H.C. &amp; Aaltio, I.,&amp; Ulijn, J.M., 2007. On the way to creativity: Engineers as intrapreneurs in organizations. Technovation, 27 (12), pp. 732–743. Mobini Dehkordi, A. &amp; Keshtkar, M., 2014. Analyzing the Effects of Three-Dimensional Model on Social Innovation: A Case Study of a Company in Iran's Automotive Industry. Innovation Management Journal , 3 (4), pp. 57-75.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R59">
			<label>59</label>
			<element-citation>Moulaert, F., &amp; Lille, F., 2007. Social innovation, governance and community building (SINGOCOM), EU Research on Social Sciences and Humanities. Available at: http://cordis.europa.eu/documents/documentlibrary/100123951EN6.pdf</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R60">
			<label>60</label>
			<element-citation>Mulgan, G., Tucker, S., Rushanara, A. &amp; Sanders, B., 2007. Social Innovation. What it is, why it matters and how it can be accelerated. Oxford Said Business School Skoll Centre for Social Entrepreneurship.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R61">
			<label>61</label>
			<element-citation>Murray, R., Caulier-Grice; Mulgan, G., 2010. The Open Book of Social Innovation, the Young Foundation &amp; NESTA.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R62">
			<label>62</label>
			<element-citation>OECD, 2010. Social Entrepreneurship and Social Innovation, in: SMEs, Entrepreneurship and Innovation.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R63">
			<label>63</label>
			<element-citation>Osburg, T., Schmidpeter, 2010. Social Innovation: Que Vadis? , Tilburg School of Social and Behavioral Sciences.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R64">
			<label>64</label>
			<element-citation>Phills, J.A., Deiglmeier, K., Miller, Dale, T. (2008). Rediscovering Social Innovation. In Stanford Social Innovation Review 6 (4), pp. 34–43.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R65">
			<label>65</label>
			<element-citation>Poll, E. &amp; Ville, S., 2009. Social innovation: Buzz word or enduring term?. School of Economics, University of Wollongong, The Journal of Socio-Economics 38(6),pp. 878–885.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R66">
			<label>66</label>
			<element-citation>Porter, M. &amp; Kramer, M., 2011. Shared Value: How to reinvent capitalism - and unleash a wave of innovation and growth. Harvard Business Review, 89(1/2), pp. 62-77.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R67">
			<label>67</label>
			<element-citation>Rader, s., 2007. Qualitative Methods of Data Analysis, Swiss- Federal Institute of Technology. Zurich.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R68">
			<label>68</label>
			<element-citation>Rüede, D. &amp; Lurtz, K., 2012. Maps the various meanings of social innovation: Towards a differentiated understanding of an emerging concept, EBS Business School, Research Paper Series 12-03.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R69">
			<label>69</label>
			<element-citation>Social Innovation eXchange (SIX), 2010. Study on Social Innovation, Young Foundation. Available at:http://youngfoundation.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Study-on-Social-Innovation-for-the-Bureau-of-European-Policy-Advisors-March-2010.pdf</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R70">
			<label>70</label>
			<element-citation>Young Foundation. (2012). Social Innovation Overview: A deliverable of the project TEPSIE. European Commission – 7th Framework Programme, Brussels: European Commission, DG Research.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R71">
			<label>71</label>
			<element-citation>Zapf, W., 1991. The role of innovations in modernization theory. International Review of Sociology, 1(3), pp. 83–94.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>
<article article-type="مقاله پژوهشی" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
			  <front>
			    <journal-meta>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="pmc"></journal-id>
			      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">Iranian Association for Management of Technology</journal-id>
			    	<journal-title-group>
				      <journal-title>مدیریت نوآوری</journal-title>
			    	</journal-title-group>
			      <issn pub-type="ppub">2322-5386</issn>
			      <publisher>
			        <publisher-name>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher-name>
			      </publisher>
			    </journal-meta>
			    <article-meta>
 			      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">138</article-id>
			      <article-id pub-id-type="doi"></article-id>		
			      <ext-link xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14835_6fb55f8b0625af6750300bd8d5705187.pdf"/>		
			      <article-categories>
			        <subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
			          		<subject>مقاله پژوهشی</subject>
			        	</subj-group>
			      </article-categories>
			      <title-group>
			        <article-title>تاثیر سلامت سازمانی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی، نقش میانجی: جو خلاقیت</article-title>
			        
			      </title-group>
			      
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c1">
			          <name>
			            <surname>نصراصفهانی</surname>
			            <given-names>علی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه اصفهان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c2" corresp="yes">
			          <name>
			            <surname>فرخی</surname>
			            <given-names>مجتبی</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه اصفهان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c3">
			          <name>
			            <surname>امیری</surname>
			            <given-names>زینب</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>دانشگاه لرستان</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			       <contrib-group>
			       <contrib contrib-type="author" id="c4">
			          <name>
			            <surname>سلحشوری</surname>
			            <given-names>روح الله</given-names>
			          </name>
					  <aff>پردیس البرز دانشگاه تهران</aff>
			        </contrib>
			       </contrib-group>
			      <pub-date pub-type="ppub">
			        <day>01</day>
			        <month>09</month>
			        <year>2015</year>
			      </pub-date>
			      <volume>4</volume>
			      <issue>2</issue>
			      <fpage>135</fpage>
			      <lpage>153</lpage>
			      <history>
			        <date date-type="received">
			          <day>07</day>
			          <month>12</month>
			          <year>2014</year>
			        </date>
			        <date date-type="accepted">
			          <day>11</day>
			          <month>10</month>
			          <year>2015</year>
			        </date>
			      </history>
			      <permissions>
			      	<copyright-statement>Copyright &#x000a9; 2015, Iranian Association for Management of Technology. </copyright-statement>	
			        <copyright-year>2015</copyright-year>
			      </permissions>
			       <self-uri xlink:href="http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14835.html">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14835.html</self-uri> 		
			      <abstract>
			        <p>مفهوم سلامتی در یک سازمان توجه را به شرایطی جلب می‌کند که رشد و توسعه سازمان را تسهیل می‌نماید و یا موجب پویایی‌های سازمانی می‌شود. سلامت سازمانی تنها شامل توانایی سازمان برای انجام وظایف به طور موثر نیست، بلکه شامل توانایی سازمان برای رشد و بهبود مداوم است. هدف این پژوهش بررسی تاثیر سلامت سازمانی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی با متغیر میانجی جو خلاقیت می‌باشد. پژوهش حاضر از لحاظ ماهیت و روش توصیفی- پیمایشی و از لحاظ هدف از نوع کاربردی است. جامعه آماری پژوهش شامل280 نفر، کارکنان شرکت سرمایه‌گذاری صنایع شیمیایی ایران می‌باشد. برای‌ جمع‌آوری اطلاعات از ابزار پرسش‌نامه استفاده شد. جهت آزمون فرضیه‌های پژوهش مدل‌یابی معادلات ‌ساختاری با استفاده از نرم‌افزار SMART-PLS  انجام شد. نتایج حاصل از پژوهش نشان داد که سلامت سازمانی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی با شدت (414/0)، سلامت سازمانی بر جو خلاقیت با شدت (822/0) و همچنین جو خلاقیت بر کارآفرینی سازمانی با شدت (563/0) تاثیر دارد و در نهایت جو خلاقیت به‌عنوان میانجی در تاثیر سلامت سازمانی بر کارآفرینی سازمانی با شدت (462/0) تاثیرگذار است.</p>
			      </abstract>
					<kwd-group kwd-group-type="author">
						<kwd>سازمان</kwd>
						<kwd>جو سازمانی</kwd>
						<kwd>کارآفرینی</kwd>
						<kwd>شرکت سرمایه گذاری صنایع شیمیایی ایران</kwd>
					</kwd-group>
			    </article-meta>
			  </front>
<back>
	<ref-list>
		<ref id="R1">
			<label>1</label>
			<element-citation> Akbaba, S., 1999. Organizational Health of Secondary School in Turkey. Association of Behavioral and Social Sciences Journal, Volume 2, pp. 217-233.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R2">
			<label>2</label>
			<element-citation>Andreu, T., David, U. &amp; Marta, P., 2014. Culture and innovation: The moderating effect of cultural values on corporate entrepreneurship. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Issue 88, pp. 360-369.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R3">
			<label>3</label>
			<element-citation>Apostolos, D. &amp; Zaridis, D., 2014. Entrepreneurship and SME›s Organizational Structure. Elements of a Successful Business. Social and Behavioral Sciences, Issue 148, pp. 463-467.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R4">
			<label>4</label>
			<element-citation>Augusto, J., Helena, M. &amp; Gonçalves, V., 2013. Social value and organizational performance in non-profit social organizations: Social entrepreneurship, leadership, and socioeconomic context effects. Journal of Business Research, 66(10), pp. 2139-2146.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R5">
			<label>5</label>
			<element-citation>Bahar, O., Türker, O. &amp; Timo, L., 2014. Trip-focused organizational safety climate: Investigating the relationships with errors, violations and positive driver behaviours in professional driving.. Transportation Research Part F: Traffic Psychology and Behaviour, Issue 26, pp. 361-369.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R6">
			<label>6</label>
			<element-citation>Hosseini, N. &amp; Sadeghi, T., 2011. Investigating the Relationship Between the Eight Dimension of Organiziation Climate With Occupational Stress and Creativity in Administrative Employee. Iranian Quarterly of Education Strategis, 1(2), pp. 52-60.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R7">
			<label>7</label>
			<element-citation>Irfaner, S. &amp; Ercetin, S., 2008. Organizational Cleaner Catfish. World Applide Sciences Journal, 3(4), pp. 396-648.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R8">
			<label>8</label>
			<element-citation>Lee, C., Chun-Liang, C. &amp; Shu, H., 2014. The Influence of School Organizational Health and Occupational Burnout on Self-perceived Health Status of Primary School Teachers. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Issue 116, pp. 985-989.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R9">
			<label>9</label>
			<element-citation>Lina, G. &amp; Asta, S., 2012. Leadership role implementing knowledge transfer in creative organization: how does it work. Social and Behavioral Sciences, Issue 41, pp. 15-22.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R10">
			<label>10</label>
			<element-citation>Luthans, F., 2008. Organizational behavior. New york: McGraw Hill Book company.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R11">
			<label>11</label>
			<element-citation>Manuel, J., Francisco, J. &amp; Félix, A., 2009. Exploring the impact of individualism and uncertainty avoidance in Web-based electronic learning: An empirical analysis in European higher education. Computers &amp; Education, Volume 52, p. 588–598.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R12">
			<label>12</label>
			<element-citation>Patrick, L., Yorio, D. &amp; Willmer, M., 2015. Health and safety management systems through a multilevel and strategic management perspective: Theoretical and empirical considerations. Safety Science, Volume 72, pp. 221-228.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R13">
			<label>13</label>
			<element-citation>Ramdass, M. &amp; Theodore, L., 2012. Towards a Model for Research on the Effect of School Organizational Health Factors on Paimary School performance in Trinidad and Tobago. International Journal of Educational Development, 32(4), pp. 91-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R14">
			<label>14</label>
			<element-citation>Sabanci, A., 2011. The Effect of Teachers Stress on educational Organizations Health. International Journal of Business and Social Science, 2(1), pp. 91-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R15">
			<label>15</label>
			<element-citation>Sarri, S., Bakouros, D. &amp; Petridou, M., 2010. Stimulating creativity: Individual procedures. New York: Academic Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R16">
			<label>16</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, M., Yango, D. &amp; Ferd, Z., 2014. Relationship between knowledge management and organizational health and employee entrepreneurship. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Issue 112, pp. 56-69.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R17">
			<label>17</label>
			<element-citation>Yukthamarani, P., Roselina, A. S. &amp; Raja, S., 2013. The Impact of Organizational Climate on Employee›s Work Passion and Organizational Commitment. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume 107, pp. 88-95.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R18">
			<label>18</label>
			<element-citation>Zahed-Babelan, A. &amp; Moenikia, M., 2010. A study of simple and multiple relations between organizational health and faculty trust in female high schools. Social and Behavioral Sciences, 2(2), pp. 1532-1536.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R19">
			<label>19</label>
			<element-citation>Zenovia, C., 2011. Entrepreneurship Versus Entrepreneurship. Review of International Comparative Management, 12(5), pp. 971-976.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R20">
			<label>20</label>
			<element-citation>اکبری، م. و غیره، 1392. بررسی رابطه‌ی سلامت سازمانی با کارآفرینی سازمانی (مورد مطالعه: دانشگاه تهران)،. مدیریت دولتی، 5(1)، صص. 1-20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R21">
			<label>21</label>
			<element-citation>بهرامیان، 1389. بررسی نقش کارآفرینی سازمانی و سلامت روانی در کارآفرینی سازمانی در صنایع کوچک فسا، شیراز: دانشکده علوم انسانی دانشگاه پیام نور، استان فارس.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R22">
			<label>22</label>
			<element-citation>پرداختچی، م. و شفیع زاده، ح.، 1385. درآمدی برکارآفرینی سازمانی. تهران: نشر ارسباران.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R23">
			<label>23</label>
			<element-citation>حسن بیگی، م.، 1389. ارائه مدل عوامل کلیدی موفقیت مدیریت دانش به منظور افزایش خلاقیت و یادگیری سازمانی در شرکت فرودگاه‌های کشور، دانشگاه پیام نور.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R24">
			<label>24</label>
			<element-citation>رضایی، ر. ا. و حسینی، س.، 1392. طراحی مدل معادلات ساختاری توسعة کارآفرینی سازمانی در تعاونی‌های توسعة روستایی استان زنجان. فصلنامه توسعه کارآفرینی، (4) 6، صص. 57-74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R25">
			<label>25</label>
			<element-citation>شائمی برزکی، ع.، امیری، ز. و فرخی، م.، 1391. تحلیل موانع کارآفرینی سازمانی. خوانسار.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R26">
			<label>26</label>
			<element-citation>عبدالله زاده، م.، 1392. تحلیل تاثیر سلامت سازمانی بر یادگیری سازمانی.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R27">
			<label>27</label>
			<element-citation>گلستان هاشمی، س. و احمدی، ع. ح.، 1384. مبانی علم کارآفرینی (دانش مهندسی کارآفرینی). اصفهان: انتشارات جهاددانشگاهی واحدصنعتی اصفهان.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R28">
			<label>28</label>
			<element-citation>ناظم، ف.، کریم زاده، ص. و قادری، ا.، 1389. بررسی رابطه بین مدیریت دانش و سلامت سازمانی با کارآفرینی کارکنان در سازمان تأمین اجتماعی. فصلنامه پژوهش اجتماعی، (9) 3، صص. 89-115._||_</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R29">
			<label>29</label>
			<element-citation>Abdolazadeh, M., 2013. Analysis of organizational health impact on organizational learning.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R30">
			<label>30</label>
			<element-citation> Akbaba, S., 1999. Organizational Health of Secondary School in Turkey. Association of Behavioral and Social Sciences Journal, Volume 2, pp. 217-233.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R31">
			<label>31</label>
			<element-citation>Akbari, M. &amp; Etc. 2013. Investigating the relationship between organizational health and organizational entrepreneurship (Case study: Tehran University). governmental management, 5 (1), pp. 1-20.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R32">
			<label>32</label>
			<element-citation>Andreu, T., David, U. &amp; Marta, P., 2014. Culture and innovation: The moderating effect of cultural values on corporate entrepreneurship. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Issue 88, pp. 360-369.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R33">
			<label>33</label>
			<element-citation>Apostolos, D. &amp; Zaridis, D., 2014. Entrepreneurship and SME›s Organizational Structure. Elements of a Successful Business. Social and Behavioral Sciences, Issue 148, pp. 463-467.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R34">
			<label>34</label>
			<element-citation>Augusto, J., Helena, M. &amp; Gonçalves, V., 2013. Social value and organizational performance in non-profit social organizations: Social entrepreneurship, leadership, and socioeconomic context effects. Journal of Business Research, 66(10), pp. 2139-2146.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R35">
			<label>35</label>
			<element-citation>Bahramian, 2010. The Role of Organizational Entrepreneurship and Mental Health in Organizational Entrepreneurship in Fasa Small Industries.Shiraz: Faculty of Humanities, Payame Noor University, Fars province.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R36">
			<label>36</label>
			<element-citation>Bahar, O., Türker, O. &amp; Timo, L., 2014. Trip-focused organizational safety climate: Investigating the relationships with errors, violations and positive driver behaviours in professional driving.. Transportation Research Part F: Traffic Psychology and Behaviour, Issue 26, pp. 361-369.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R37">
			<label>37</label>
			<element-citation>Golestan Hashemi, S. &amp; Ahmadi, As. H., 2005. The Basics of Entrepreneurship Science (Entrepreneurship Engineering Knowledge). Isfahan: Isfahan University of Technology Publication Center.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R38">
			<label>38</label>
			<element-citation>Hasan Beigi, M., 2010. Provide a model of key factors for the success of KM to enhance creativity and organizational learning at the company's airports. Payam Noor university.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R39">
			<label>39</label>
			<element-citation>Hosseini, N. &amp; Sadeghi, T., 2011. Investigating the Relationship Between the Eight Dimension of Organiziation Climate With Occupational Stress and Creativity in Administrative Employee. Iranian Quarterly of Education Strategis, 1(2), pp. 52-60.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R40">
			<label>40</label>
			<element-citation>Irfaner, S. &amp; Ercetin, S., 2008. Organizational Cleaner Catfish. World Applide Sciences Journal, 3(4), pp. 396-648.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R41">
			<label>41</label>
			<element-citation>Lee, C., Chun-Liang, C. &amp; Shu, H., 2014. The Influence of School Organizational Health and Occupational Burnout on Self-perceived Health Status of Primary School Teachers. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Issue 116, pp. 985-989.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R42">
			<label>42</label>
			<element-citation>Lina, G. &amp; Asta, S., 2012. Leadership role implementing knowledge transfer in creative organization: how does it work. Social and Behavioral Sciences, Issue 41, pp. 15-22.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R43">
			<label>43</label>
			<element-citation>Luthans, F., 2008. Organizational behavior. New york: McGraw Hill Book company.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R44">
			<label>44</label>
			<element-citation>Manuel, J., Francisco, J. &amp; Félix, A., 2009. Exploring the impact of individualism and uncertainty avoidance in Web-based electronic learning: An empirical analysis in European higher education. Computers &amp; Education, Volume 52, p. 588–598.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R45">
			<label>45</label>
			<element-citation>Nazem, F., Karimzadeh, S. &amp; Ghaderi, A., 2010. Survey on the Relationship Between Knowledge Management, Organizational Health With Personnel Entrepreneurship in Social Security Organization of Iran. Social Research Quarterly, 3 (9), pp. 89-115.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R46">
			<label>46</label>
			<element-citation>Patrick, L., Yorio, D. &amp; Willmer, M., 2015. Health and safety management systems through a multilevel and strategic management perspective: Theoretical and empirical considerations. Safety Science, Volume 72, pp. 221-228.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R47">
			<label>47</label>
			<element-citation>Pardakhtchi, M. &amp; Shafi Zadeh, H., 2006. Income for organizational creativity. Tehran: Arasbaran Publishing.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R48">
			<label>48</label>
			<element-citation>Ramdass, M. &amp; Theodore, L., 2012. Towards a Model for Research on the Effect of School Organizational Health Factors on Paimary School performance in Trinidad and Tobago. International Journal of Educational Development, 32(4), pp. 91-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R49">
			<label>49</label>
			<element-citation>Rezaei, R. A. &amp; Hosseini, S., 2013. Designing the Structural Equation Model of Organizational Entrepreneurship Development in Rural Development Cooperatives of Zanjan Province. Journal of Entrepreneurship Development, 6(4), pp. 57-74.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R50">
			<label>50</label>
			<element-citation>Sabanci, A., 2011. The Effect of Teachers Stress on educational Organizations Health. International Journal of Business and Social Science, 2(1), pp. 91-100.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R51">
			<label>51</label>
			<element-citation>Sarri, S., Bakouros, D. &amp; Petridou, M., 2010. Stimulating creativity: Individual procedures. New York: Academic Press.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R52">
			<label>52</label>
			<element-citation>Shaemi Barzaki, As., Amiri, Z. &amp; Farokhi, M., 2012. Analyzing organizational entrepreneurship barriers. Khansar.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R53">
			<label>53</label>
			<element-citation>Smith, M., Yango, D. &amp; Ferd, Z., 2014. Relationship between knowledge management and organizational health and employee entrepreneurship. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Issue 112, pp. 56-69.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R54">
			<label>54</label>
			<element-citation>Yukthamarani, P., Roselina, A. S. &amp; Raja, S., 2013. The Impact of Organizational Climate on Employee›s Work Passion and Organizational Commitment. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume 107, pp. 88-95.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R55">
			<label>55</label>
			<element-citation>Zahed-Babelan, A. &amp; Moenikia, M., 2010. A study of simple and multiple relations between organizational health and faculty trust in female high schools. Social and Behavioral Sciences, 2(2), pp. 1532-1536.</element-citation>
		</ref>
		<ref id="R56">
			<label>56</label>
			<element-citation>Zenovia, C., 2011. Entrepreneurship Versus Entrepreneurship. Review of International Comparative Management, 12(5), pp. 971-976.</element-citation>
		</ref>
	</ref-list>
		</back>
</article>