<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing a Decision-Making System to Prioritize Appropriate Knowledge Management Technologies in Insurance Companies</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی سیستم تصمیم گیری جهت اولویت بندی فناوری های مناسب مدیریت دانش در شرکت های بیمه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>101</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>122</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14669</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهام</FirstName>
					<LastName>فلاح</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسن زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>آمنه</FirstName>
					<LastName>خدیور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه الزهرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهنام</FirstName>
					<LastName>مولوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد نجف آباد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays knowledge management is an important element of organizations to gain competitive advantage, and one of the most important aspects of which is information technology. Due to the increasing growth in information technology field, insurance companies require an appropriate technology for knowledge management in their organizations. That is why choosing the right technology in knowledge management process is important. In this paper, by using criteria from the literature and using the analytic hierarchy process (AHP), the technologies of each stage of knowledge management of 4 Iranian insurance companies are compared with each other with the help of the Expert Choice software. The data needed for the study is gathered by two questionnaires, the first one aiming to determine the meaningfulness of the selection criteria and technologies of each KM processes, and the second to determine and prioritize the weight of the criteria. The results of the comparison of knowledge management technologies based on the 12 criteria demonstrate that knowledge-base technology in the knowledge acquisition process, technology education systems in the knowledge-sharing process, knowledge map technology in the knowledge organizing process, and enterprise resource planning system technology in the knowledge application process of the insurance companies have the highest priorities. Finally, the &quot;decision-making software&quot; designed to help the employees of the insurance companies select an appropriate technology for each stage of knowledge management by using the C# programming language.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;امروزه مدیریت دانش به عنوان یکی از عناصر کلیدی سازمان&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها برای کسب مزیت رقابتی محسوب می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;شود و یکی از مهم&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ترین ابعاد آن فناوری اطلاعات می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;باشد. با توجه به رشد روز افزون فناوری اطلاعات و نیاز شرکت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های بیمه به استفاده از فناوری برای مدیریت دانش سازمانی، مساله انتخاب فناوری مناسب در فرآیندهای مدیریت دانش از اهمیت ویژه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای برخوردار است. در این مقاله با استفاده از معیارهای شناسایی شده از ادبیات موضوع و فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی، فناوری&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های هر مرحله از فرآیندهای مدیریت دانش در شرکت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های  بیمه ایران، ملت، البرز و سینا با استفاده از نرم&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;افزار &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expert Choice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;با یکدیگر مقایسه شدند. داده&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های مورد نیاز پژوهش، با استفاده از دو پرسش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;نامه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها جمع&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;آوری شد. پرسش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;نامه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها اول برای تعیین معناداری معیارهای انتخاب و فناوری&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های هر یک از فرآیندهای مدیریت دانش و پرسش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;نامه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها دوم برای اولویت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;بندی و تعیین وزن شاخص&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها مورد استفاده قرار گرفت.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; نتیجه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های حاصل از مقایسه فناوری&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های مدیریت دانش براساس 12 معیار انتخاب شده، نشان می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;دهد که فناوری پایگاه دانش در فرآیند کسب دانش، فناوری نظام&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های آموزشی در فرآیند تسهیم دانش، فناوری نقشه دانش در فرآیند سازماندهی دانش و در نهایت فناوری نظام برنامه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ریزی منابع سازمان در فرآیند کاربرد دانش در شرکت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های بیمه دارای بیشترین اولویت بوده&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;اند. در پایان این مقاله، نرم&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;افزار تصمیم&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;گیری طراحی شده جهت کمک به کارکنان شرکت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های بیمه در انتخاب فناوری مناسب برای هر یک از فرآیندهای مدیریت دانش تشریح شده است. &lt;/strong&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فناوری‌های مدیریت دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیستم تصمیم‌گیری انتخاب فناوری مدریت دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرکت‌های بیمه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14669_50daf59874137af7cbec004f033ac24a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
