<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Factors Affecting the Success of the Biotechnology Accelerators in Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>عوامل مؤثر بر موفقیت شتاب دهنده های حوزه زیست فناوری در ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>95</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>112</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">86886</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>گودرزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>نقی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احسان</FirstName>
					<LastName>بیگلر</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>24</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Accelerators are a relatively new type of institutions which support entrepreneurial ecosystem across the world that rapidly grows and they offer the necessary services to startups in the early stages of their development. The emergence of this phenomenon has opened up a new path in front of the entrepreneurs and in a short period of time, the startups have developed very quickly. Identifying success factors of accelerators can minimize failure of the startups. &lt;br /&gt; The determinants of success in the field of biotechnology accelerators, has shaped the main question of this research. After reviewing literature, interviewing with managers and experts in the field of biotechnology, twenty factors have been identified. After designing the questionnaire and distributing it among selected statistical sample, by using Binomial test, the important success factors have been identified. Some factors such as strategic intent of accelerator for development and teams’ support, teams’ investigaton criteria of ideas and capabilities, presented services to the teams, training programs, accessibility to market, customer and investor networks through and after the accelerating program.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ظهور پدیده شتابدهنده ها مسیری نوین پیش روی کارآفرینان و کسب‌و‌کارهای نوپا گذاشته است. ویژگی های خاص حوزه زیست فناوری و همچنین جدید بودن مفهوم شتابدهنده ها در ایران، شناخت عوامل موفقیت این موسسات را ضروری می نماید. در فرایند انجام این پژوهش، بیست عامل کلیدی موفقیت در حوزه مورد نظر با مطالعه پژوهش های پیشین و مصاحبه های صورت گرفته با مدیران و خبرگان شتاب دهنده های زیست فناوری که می تواند باعث موفقیت شتاب دهنده ها شود، شناسایی گردید. پس از طراحی پرسشنامه و توزیع آن بین نمونه منتخب و جمع آوری نظرات، با استفاده از آزمون دوجمله ای تعداد یازده عامل مهم در چهار مرحله آگاهی، انتخاب و ثبت‏نام، برنامه شتابدهی و در نهایت روز نمایش شناسایی گردید. عواملی همچون اهداف استراتژیک شتاب دهنده برای توسعه و حمایت از تیم ها، معیارهای بررسی تیم ها بر اساس ایده، توانایی و جذابیت توسط شتاب دهنده، خدمات ارائه شده توسط شتاب دهنده به تیم ها، نحوه اجرای برنامه آموزش و میزان انعطاف پذیری آن نسبت به زمان استقرار تیم ها، دسترسی شتاب دهنده به شبکه بازارها، مشتریان و سرمایه گذاران در طول برنامه شتابدهی و عامل دسترسی به شبکه سرمایه گذاران برای تزریق سرمایه بعد از پایان برنامه به تیم های خروجی برخی از عوامل مهم را شکل می دهند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شتاب دهنده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زیست فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عامل موفقیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مرکز رشد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرکت نوپا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86886_a7b338d8129ce6c5699ad8a659a21886.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
