<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1396</YEAR>
<VOL>6</VOL>
<NO>1</NO>
<MOSALSAL>19</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>160</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>سرمقاله: راهکارهای بهبود ضریب تاثیر مقالات علمی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Improving Impact of Research Papers</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>سرمقاله حاضر، به نویسندگان می­ گوید که چگونه ضریب تاثیر مقاله خود را به میزان چشمگیری بهبود بخشند. اگرچه این سرمقاله، به طور خاص برای نشریه تکنویشن  نوشته شده، اما بسیاری از نکات مطرح شده در آن، برای سایر نشریات نیز مفید و قابل استفاده هستند. با وجود اینکه ارزش علمی هر مقاله، منحصر به فرد می باشد، اما بهترین راه نشان دادن این ارزش به مخاطبان، برای همه مقاله ها یکسان است و این سرمقاله تلاش دارد تا چنین روشی را معرفی کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>-</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>6</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بنیادی نائینی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bonyadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>bonyadi.naeini@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حامد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اسفندی</Family>
						<NameE>Hamed</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Esfandi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Linton, J.D. 2012.How to Get Your Papers Rejected (or not). Technovation, 32(1), pp.6-8.##Linton, J.D. 2009. Reviewing: the Unsung Heroes of Excellent Journals and Publications. Technovation, 29(1), pp.1–4.##Sun, H. &amp; Linton, J.D. 2014. Structuring Papers for Success: Making Your Paper More Like a High Impactpaper than a Deskreject. Technovation, 34(10), pp. 571–573.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>رویکردی زمینه محور به چالش های انتقال فناوری در قراردادهای بین المللی تجاری در ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Technology Transfer Challenges in Iran&#039;s International Commercial Contracts based on a thematic Approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>فناوری عاملی کلیدی در تجارت بین­المللی است. بنگاه­های اقتصادی تلاش می­کنند تا از طرق مختلف به فناوری­های مزیت­ساز دست یابند. یکی از راه های مورد توجه شرکت­های فعال در کشورهای درحال توسعه، انتقال فناوری است. بسیاری از پروژه­های انتقال فناوری در جهت تحقق اهداف دانشی مدنظر خود با چالش­های جدی مواجه هستند. این پژوهش تلاش دارد تا با رویکردی زمینه­محور به شناسایی و تبیین چالش­های انتقال فناوری در قراردادهای بزرگ تجاری ایران بپردازد. با توجه به اهمیت درک عمیق چالش­های مذکور و وابستگی آن به بستر و زمینه مورد تحلیل، از روش تحلیل تم به­منظور آنالیز مصاحبه­های عمیق  صورت گرفته با 10 نفر از خبرگان صنعتی و علمی استفاده شد. پس از کدگذاری یافته­های پژوهش 18 چالش در قالب چهار گروه اصلی طبقه­بندی گردیدند. لزوم نگاه جامع به همه ابعاد موثر بر انتقال فناوری و همچنین توجه ویژه به بستر و محیط ایران بخشی از یافته­های اصلی پژوهش بودند. در بعد واگذارنده فناوری، عدم تمایل به دلایل اقتصادی، سیاسی و پروژه­ای، در بعد گیرنده فناوری، ظرفیت جذب پایین شرکت های ایرانی، در بعد محیط و فرآیند انتقال، عدم ثبات اقتصادی و در بعد محتوای مورد انتقال، ماهیت متفاوت فناوری­ها بخشی از مهمترین چالش­های انتقال فناوری در پروژه­های بزرگ تجاری بودند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> Technology is one of the main determinants of international trade. Firms try to acquire beneficial technologies through different ways. One of these ways, regarded by active firms in developing countries, is technology transfer. However, many technology transfer projects have confronted with different serious challenges toward their knowledge goals realization. This research tries to identify and explain these technology transfer challenges in Iran&#039;s important commercial contracts with a thematic analysis approach. regarding the importance of deep understanding of aforementioned  challenges and its dependence on the analyzed field, we used thematic analysis in order to analyze deep interviews of 10 industrial and scientific experts . After coding the results,  18 challenges have been classified into four main groups. The necessity of having comprehensive approach to different aspects of technology transfer and considering the special context and circumstance of Iran are some of the main results. As well, unwillingness to technology transfer due to economic, political, and project based reasons related to the factor of technology transferor factor, low absorptive capacity of Iranian firms related to technology transferee factor, lack of economic sustainability related to context factor and finally different nature of technologies related to content factor were introduced as the main challenges of technology transfer in important commercial projects in Iran. </CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>19</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نقی زاده</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Naghizadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیات علمی دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیات علمی دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mohamadnaghizadeh@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امینی</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Amini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rezaamini_ie@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سارا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نوری</Family>
						<NameE>Sara</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nouri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>nouri.work@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انتقال فناوری بین المللی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قراردادهای تجاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ظرفیت جذب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رویکرد زمینه محور</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Adidam,  P. T.,  Banerjee, M., Shukla, P. 2012Competitive intelligence and firm’s performance in emerging markets: an exploratory study in India, Journal of Business &amp; Industrial Marketing, 27(3), pp. 42–254##Adidam, P. Sampada, G and Kejriwal, S , 2009. Cross-cultural competitive Intelligence Strategies, Marketing Intelligence &amp; Planning, 27 (5), pp. 666-680.##Agnihotri, R. and Rapp, A. 2011. Perspectives on competitive intelligence within business: a tactical tool for sales-people to gain a competitive advantage”, The Marketing Review, 11(4), pp. 363-380.##Alon, I., Higgins, M.2005. Global Leadeship Success Trough Emotional &amp;  Cultural intelligence,  Bussiness Horizons, 48, pp. 501-512.##Bartes, F. 2015. Defining a basis for the new concept of competitive intelligence, Acta Universitatis Agriculturae et Silviculturae Mendelianae Brunensis, 62(6), pp. 1233-1242.##Benny, D.J. 2013, Industrial Espionage: Developing a Counterespionage Program, Crc Press, Boca Raton, FL.##Bose, R. 2008. Competitive intelligence process and tools for intelligence analysis, Industrial Management &amp; Data Systems, 108(4), pp. 510-528.##Cacciolatti, L.A. and Fearne, A. 2013. Marketing intelligence in SMEs: implications for the industry and policy makers, Marketing Intelligence &amp; Planning, 31(1), pp. 4-26.##Calof, J.2017. Reflections on the Canadian Government in competitive intelligence , Programs and Impacts, Foresight, 19 (1), pp.31-47.##Chen, H. and Das, S.R. 2010. Business and market intelligence 2.0”, Part 2, IEEE Intelligent Systems, 25 (2), pp.74-78.##Cheng, CH. &amp; Hsue, Y. 2002. Evaluating the best mail battle tank using fuzzy decision theory. European Journal of Operational Research, 142 (1), pp. 174-186.##Des champs, J. P. And Ranganath Nayak, P. 1995. Product Juggernauts: How Companies Mobilize to Generate A Stream of Market Winner. Harvard Business Press.##Gabber, H, 2007. competitive intelligence topology analyze for improved plan operation, Industrial Management and Data Systems, 107(2), pp. 198-236.##Gabber, H, 2007. competitive intelligence topology analyze for improved plan operation, Industrial Management and Data systems, 107(2), pp. 198-236.##Halt, G.B. Jr, Fesnak, R., Donch, J.C. and Stiles, A.R. 2014, Intellectual Property in Consumer Electronics, Software and Technology Startups, Springer, New York.##He, W., Shen, J., Tian, X., Li, Y., Akula, V.,  Gongjun Yan, G., and Tao, R. 2015. Gaining competitive intelligence from social media data: Evidence from two largest retail chains in the world, Industrial Management &amp; Data Systems, 115 (9), pp.1622-1636##Hsiu-Fang, H. Sieh &amp; Shannon, S. E. 2005. Three Approaches  to Qualitative Content Analysis. Qualitative Health Research, 15(9), pp. 1277-1288.##Jenster, P., Soilen, K. 2009. Market Intelligence Building Strategic Insight. (1st ed.) Copenhagen, Denmark: Copenhagen Business School Press.##Johns, P, Van Doren, D, 2010. Competitive intelligence in service marketing A new approach with practical application, Marketing Intelligence &amp; Planning, 28 (5), pp. 551-570.##Jonathan L. Calof, Sheila Wright, 2008. “Competitive intelligence: A practitioner, academic and interdisciplinary perspective”, European Journal of Marketing, Vol. 42 Issue: 7/8, pp.717-730.##Juhari, M and Stephens, K. 2006. Tracing the Origins of Competitive Intelligence Throughout History, Journal of Competitive Intelligence and Management, 3(4), pp. 61-82.##Kahaner, L. 1996. Competitive Intelligence: How to Gather,  Analyze, and Use Information to Move your Business to the Top, 1sted., Simon &amp; Schuster, New York.##Kotler, P. and Keller, K.L. 2012. Marketing Management, 14 edn, Pearson, Upper Saddle River, NJ.##Liebowitz, J. 2007. Strategic Intelligence, an informa Business Intelligence, Competitive Intelligence, and Knowledge Management, Auerbach Publications is an imprint of the Taylor &amp; Francis Group, Boca Raton   New York.##Luu T. T. 2013b. Knowledge sharing and competitive intelligence, Marketing Intelligence &amp; Planning, 32 (3), pp. 269-292.##Luu, T. T. 2013a. Competitive intelligence and other levers of brand performance. Journal of Strategic Marketing, 21, pp. 217–239.##Luu, T. T. 2016. Organisational ambidexterity and supply chain agility: the mediating role of external knowledge sharing and moderating role of competitive intelligence, International Journal of Logistics Research and Applications, 19(6), pp. 583-603##Nasri, W. and Zarai, M. 2013. Key success factors for developing competitive intelligence in organisation, American Journal of Business and Management, 2(3), pp. 239-244.##Nazari. M., Shahngian. B., Salmantahery. F and Ziaei. 2015. The Impact of Individual Characteristics on the Creation of Marketing  Intelligence,  Case Study: Manufacturing Organization in Isfahan, Journal UMP Social Sciences and Technology Management, 3(3), pp. 213-218.##Polit, D. Beck, C. Hungler, B.P. 2001. Essentials of nursing research: methods, appraisal, and utilization. 5th ed. New York: Lippincott.##Qiu, T. 2008.Scanning for competitive intelligence: a managerial perspective, European Journal of Marketing, 42(7/8), pp. 814-835.##Rapp, A., Agnihotri, R., Baker, T.L. et al. J. of the Acad. Mark. Sci. 2015. Competitive intelligence collection and use by sales and service representatives: how managers’ recognition and autonomy moderate individual performance, Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, 43(3), pp 357–374.##Ross, P., McGowan, C. and Styger, L. 2012. A comparison of theory and practice in market intelligence gathering for Australian micro businesses and SMEs, 19th International Business Research Conference: Research for Re-thinking, Social Science Research Network, pp. 1-17.##Rouach, D., and Santi, P.2001. Competitive intelligence adds value: Five Intelligence Attitudes , European Management journal, 19(5), pp. 200-224.##Saayman, A.  Pienaar, J. Pelsmacker, P.  Viviers, W.  Cuyvers, L. Muller, M  &amp;  Jegers,M , 2008.Competitive intelligence: construct exploration, validation and  equivalence, Adlib Proceedings: New Information  Perspectives  , 60 (4), pp. 383-411.##Shujahat, M.,  Hussain, S., Javed, S., Malik, M. I.,  Thurasamy, R., and Ali, J.2017. “Strategic management model with lens of knowledge management and competitive intelligence: A review approach”, VINE Journal of Information and Knowledge Management Systems, 47(1), pp.55-93.##Tuan, L. T.2015. Entrepreneurial orientation and competitive intelligence: cultural intelligence as a moderator, Journal of Research in Marketing and Entrepreneurship, 17 (2), pp. 212 – 228.##Venter, P. and Rensburg, M. J. V. 2014. The Relashionship Between  marketing Intelligence and strategic  marketing, SAJEMS, 17(4), pp. 440-456.##Wilkinson, D. and Birmingham, P. 2003. Using Research Instruments: A Guide for Researchers. London: Routledge.##Yap, C. S., Rashid, M. Z. A., Sapuan, D. A. 2013. Perceived Environmental Uncertainty and Competitive Intelligence Practices”, The Journal of Information and Knowledge Management Systems, Vol. 43 (4), pp. 462 – 481.##yuan, T. and Chen, P. 2012. Data Mining Applications in E-Government Information Security. Procedia Engineering, 29, pp. 235–240.##حبیبی، آ.، ایزدیار، ص. و سرافرازی، ا.، 1393. تصمیم‌گیری چند معیاره فازی. کتیبه گیل، رشت.##حسن پور، ی.1392. توسعه صادرات کالاهای با فناوری بالا: سیاست‌ها و اقدامات، موسسه مطالعات و پژوهش‌های بازرگانی، تهران.##خاشعی، و. و هرندی، ع.1394. بررسی نقش هوش فرهنگی در ارتقاء هوشمندی رقابتی، پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی، دوره 5، شماره 1، صص. 1-18.##رضایی دولت آبادی، ح.،  زینلی، ز.، و  شکرچی زاده، ز.، 1390. بررسی میزان تاثیر هوشمندی رقابتی در ایجاد مزیت رقابتی، مجله چشم انداز مدیریت بازرگانی، دوره 10، شماره 5، صص 9-25.##رونقی، م. ح. و رونقی م. 1393. ارائه مدل بلوغ هوشمندی کسب و کار در بین سازمان‌های ایرانی. فصلنامه رشد و فناوری، سال دهم، شماره 38، صص. 38-44.##سیاه سرانی کجوری، م.،  1396. طراحی و تبیین الگوی هوشمندی رقابتی در راستای صادرات پایدار محصولات دانش بنیان، رساله دوره‌ی دکتری مدیریت بازاریابی بین‌الملل، دانشگاه سمنان.##طبرسا، غ. و نظری پور، ا.، 1392. بررسی عوامل موثر بر ارتقاء هوشمندی انسانی-ساختاری در سازمان های دانش بنیان. پژوهشهای مدیریت در ایران، شماره 1، دوره 17، صص. 111-131.##طبرسا، غ.، رضائیان، ع. و نظری پور، ام.، 1391. طراحی و تبیین مدل هوشمندی رقابتی مبنتی بر هوشمندی سازمانی در سازمان‌های دانش بنیان. پژوهشنامه مدیریت اجرایی، سال چهارم، شماره 7، صص. 37-57.##مصلح، ع.، بحرینی زاده، م.، دوکوهکی، س. 1394. بررسی تاثیرهوش رقابتی بر نوآوری در شرکت‌های دانش بنیان شیراز ، پژوهش‌نامه مدیریت تحول، سال هفتم، شماره 31، صص. 18-41.##مصلح، ع.، بحرینی زاده، م.، دوکوهکی، س. 1394. بررسی تاثیرهوش رقابتی بر نوآوری در شرکتهای دانشبنیان شیراز ، پژوهش نامه مدیریت تحول، سال هفتم، شماره 31، صص. 18-41.##نهاوندیان، م. و افقهی، ب. 1393. عوامل موثر بر توسعه صادرات خدمات با فناوری بالا در جمهوری اسلامی ایران، پژوهشنامه اقتصادی (رشد و توسعه پایدار)، سال چهاردهم، شماره چهارم، صص. 23-56.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>مفهوم‌پردازی و ‌اولویت‌بندی مولفه‌های هوشمندی رقابتی در شرکتهای دانش بنیان: پژوهش ترکیبی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Conceptualization and Prioritization of Competitive Intelligence Components at Knowledge-based Companies: Mixed method Study</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>شناسایی مشکلات شرکتهای دانش‌بنیان به دلیل جایگاه ویژه آنها در اقتصاد کشور از اهمیت ویژه‌ای برخوردار است، با وجود افزایش ارزش صادرات محصولات دانش‌بنیان، این شرکتها از دو مشکل عمده عرصه‌های سرمایه‌گذاری و صادرات ناپایدار رنج می‌برند، موضوعی که رقابتمندی این شرکتها را با مشکل مواجه کرده و نیاز به کنکاش و جستجوی بیشتری دارد. هدف پژوهش حاضر مفهوم‌پردازی و اولویت‌بندی مولفه‌های هوشمندی در شرکتهای دانش‌بنیان از طریق رویکرد ترکیبی است. بر این اساس پژوهش حاضر از نظر هدف اکتشافی و از نوع آمیخته و از نظر نتیجه کاربردی است. در گام اول پژوهش به منظور دستیابی به اهداف پژوهش، با استفاده از روش تحلیل محتوا و از طریق مصاحبه‌های عمیق نیمه ساختاریافته با فعالان شرکتهای دانش‌بنیان (متخصصان، مدیران شرکتها و مسئولین مرتبط)، 95 کد به عنوان مفاهیم هوشمندی رقابتی در شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان استخراج و با توجه به قرابت معنایی در 10 مولفه دسته‌بندی شدند. در گام دوم از طریق نمونه‌گیری نظری 12 خبره انتخاب و نظرات آنها از طریق پرسشنامه‌ای با طیف لیکرت 5 درجه‌ای جمع‌آوری و داده‌ها از طریق تکنیک دلفی فازی مورد تحلیل قرار گرفت. نتایج پژوهش در دو مرحله نظرسنجی از خبرگان منجر به شناسایی هشت مولفه اصلی هوشمندی رقبا، هوشمندی مالی، هوشمندی بازار، هوشمندی فنی، هوشمندی مدیریتی، هوشمندی قانونی، هوشمندی انسانی و هوشمندی سیاسی جهت کسب هوشمندی رقابتی در شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Identifying the problems of Knowledge-based companies is important because of their special position in country&#039;s economy, despite of the increasing export value of Knowledge-based products, these companies suffer from two main problems, areas of investment and unsustainable export, the issues that have challenged the competitiveness of these companies; it is an issue that needs to be explored further. The aim of this study was to conceptualize and Prioritize the intelligence components in knowledge-based companies through a mixed method approach. The present study aimed to explore the mixed and the functional result. The first step in research in order to achieve the objectives, is using semi-structured content analysis and interviews with activist’s knowledge-based companies (professionals, managers and relevant officials), 95 code as intelligent concepts competitive knowledge-based mining companies and 10 components were classified according to semantic relationships. At the second step, 12 experts were selected to extract their views by theoretical sampling  through a 5-point Likert-scale questionnaire then analyzed the data collected through Fuzzy Delphi technique. The results of study led to the identification of eight main components of  competitors intelligence, financial intelligence, market intelligence, technical intelligence,  management intelligence, regulatory intelligence, human intelligence and political intelligence, in order to gain competitive intelligence in the knowledge-based companies.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>21</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>44</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سیاه سرانی کجوری</Family>
						<NameE>mohammad ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>siahsarani kojouri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازاریابی بین الملل- دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اداری; دانشگاه سمنان-ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازاریابی بین الملل-</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m_sarani@semnan.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عظیم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زارعی</Family>
						<NameE>Azim</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zarei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار گروه مدیریت- دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اداری- دانشگاه سمنان- ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار گروه مدیریت- دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a_zarei@semnan.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مرتضی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ملکی مین باش رزگاه</Family>
						<NameE>Morteza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Maleki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مدیریت- دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت و علوم اداری- دانشگاه سمنان-ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مدیریت- دانشکده اقتصاد، مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m_maleki@sun.semnan.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عادل</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آذر</Family>
						<NameE>Adel</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Azar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد گروه مدیریت- دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد- دانشگاه تربیت مدرس- ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد گروه مدیریت- دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد-</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>azara@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>داود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فیض</Family>
						<NameE>Davod</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Feiz</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه سمنان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه سمنان</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>feiz1353@semnan.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شرکتهای دانش ‌بنیان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هوشمندی رقابتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Adenfelt, Maria, Lagerström, Katarina. 2006. Enabling knowledge creation and sharing in transnational projects. International Journal of Project Management. 24(3), pp. 191-198.##Back, A., Von Krogh, G., Seufert، A., Enkel, E.، Raimann, J.، Vassiliadis, S.، Wicki, Y. 2005. Putting knowledge networks into action: Methodology, Development, Maintenance.##‏Bstieler, L. 2006. Trust Formation in Collaborative New Product Development. J. Prod. Innov. Manag. Volume (23), pp. 56–72.##‏Chrislip، D.D. &amp; Larson، C.E. 1994. Collaborative leadership. San Franc.##Choi, Byounggu, Lee, Heeseok. 2002. Knowledge management strategy and its link to knowledge creation process. Expert Systems with applications. 23(3), pp.  173–187.##‏De Luca, L.M.، Atuahene-Gima, K. 2007. Market knowledge dimensions and cross-functional collaboration: Examining the different routes to product innovation performance. J. Mark. Volume  (71)، pp. 95–112.##‏Ettlie, J.E. 1995. Product-Process Development Integration in Manufacturing. Manag. Sci. Volume (41), pp. 1224–1237.##‏Frishammar, J., Lichtenthaler, U.، Rundquist,J. 2012. Identifying technology commercialization opportunities: The importance of integrating product development knowledge. J. Prod. Innov. Manag. Volume (29), pp. 573–589.##‏Jolly, V.K. 1997. Commercializing New Technologies - Getting from Mind to Market. Innov. Manag. Policy Pract. Volume (1), pp. 1–30.##‏Lank, E. 2006. Collaborative Advantage: How Organizations Win by Working together. Palgrave Macmillan New York, NY.##‏Lin,Y.,Wang,Y., Kung, L. 2015. Influences of Cross-functional Collaboration and Knowledge Creation on Technology Commercialization: Evidence from High-tech Industries. Ind. Mark. Manag. Volume (49), pp. 128–138.##Lin, Yichen, Wang, Yichuan, Kung,LeeAnn. 2015. Influences of Cross-Functional Collaboration and Knowledge Creation on Technology Commercialization: Evidence from High-tech Industries. Industrial Marketing Management.Indmarman.##McAdam, Rodney. 2004. Knowledge Creation and Idea Generation: a Critical Quality Perspective. Technovation. 24(9), pp. 697–705.##‏Nonaka, I. 1994. A dynamic theory of organizational knowledge creation. Organ. Sci. Volume (5), pp. 14–37.##‏Nonaka, I.، Toyama, R.، Konno، N. 2000. SECI، Ba and Leadership: a Unified Model of Dynamic Knowledge Creation. Long Range Plann. Volume (33)، pp. 5–34.##‏Robbins, S.P.,Judge,T.A. 2013. Organizational Behavior.##‏Rooney, J.A., Gottlieb,B.H. 2007. Development and initial validation of a measure of supportive and unsupportive managerial behaviors. J. Vocat. Behav. Volume (71)، pp. 186–203.##‏Singh, K. 1996. Survival of Businesses using Collaborative Relationships to Commercialize Complex Goods. Strateg. Manag. J. Volume (17), pp. 169–195.##‏Teece, D.J. 1998. Capturing Value from Knowlegde Assets : The New Economy، Markets for Know-How، and intangible Assets. Calif. Manage. Rev. Volume (40), pp. 55–79.##‏Zahra, S.A.,Nielsen, A.P. 2002. Sources of Capabilities, Integration and Technology Commercialization. Strateg. Manag. J. Volume (23), pp. 377–398.##Kimberley, C. 2013. Building Collaborative Relationships in the Workplace. Onedesk.##بحرکانی، حسین. 1392. بررسی رابطه رفتارهای حمایتی و غیرحمایتی مدیر و خشنودی شغلی با هویت سازمانی کارکنان سازمان-های دولتی شهرستان هندیجان (کارشناسی ارشد). دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی ‌واحد مرودشت - دانشکده علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی.##‏بیگلری، آرزو. 1394. بررسی رابطه بین اعتماد سازمانی، انتقال دانش، خلق دانش و نوآوری سازمانی (مطالعه موردی: بیمه آسیا) (کارشناسی ارشد). دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکزی - دانشکده مدیریت.##پاک‌نیت، مریم.، انصاری، رضا.، شاهین، آرش.، 1395، تحلیل تاثیر توانمندی‌های نوآوری فناورانه بر تجاری‌سازی فناوری و عملکرد شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان استان اصفهان، مدیریت نوآوری، دوره 5، شماره 3، صص.59-84.##‏حاجی‌زاده‌، ابراهیم.، اصغری، محمد. 1390. روش‌ها و تحلیل‌های آماری با نگاه به روش تحقیق در علوم زیستی و بهداشتی (به همراه راهنمای SPSS). جهاد‌دانشگاهی، واحد تهران، تهران.##‏حسن زاده، محمد.، اسکندری، فائزه. 1390. ارزیابی رابط کاربر نرم‌افزارهای علوم اسلامی شهر قم، ارزیابی‌های مرکز. مرکز تحقیقات کامپیوتری علوم اسلامی، قم.##حسن‌زاده، ریحانه، سماواتیان، حسین، نوری، ابوالقاسم، حسینی، مهرداد. 1391. رابطه بین رفتارهای حمایتی مدیران و توانمندسازی با میل به ماندن در سازمان بهداشت و درمان صنعت نفت اصفهان. تحقیقات نظام سلامت. (7)8، صص 1206–1215.##خیراندیش، مهدی، خدایی، ارشیا، و محمدی، علیرضا. 2015. مدل جامع عوامل مؤثر بر کارتیمی اثربخش در بستر سازمان و مقیاس های سنجش آن. مطالعات رفتار سازمانی. (3)4، صص.60–31.##‏دانایی‌فرد، حسن.، الوانی، سید.مهدی.، آذر، عادل. 1394. روش‌شناسی پژوهش‌کمی در مدیریت: رویکرد جامع. صفار.##‏درودی، هما. 1392. رفتار در سازمان‌ها (درک و مدیریت‌کردن افراد در محیط کار): مفاهیم، نظریه‌ها و کاربردها. یاد عارف، تهران.##راب‍ی‍ن‍ز، ‏استیون پی. 1388. تئوری سازمان: ساختار و طرح سازمانی. (ترجمه سید مهدی الوانی‌، و حسن دانائی‌فرد). تهران: صفار (تاریخ انتشار به زبان اصلی1943).##رابینز، استیون پی. 1379. مدیریت رفتار سازمانی. ویرایش دوم. (ترجمه علی پارسائیان و محمد اعرابی). تهران: دفتر پژوهش‌های فرهنگی (تاریخ انتشار به زبان اصلی 1943).##رابینز، ‏استیون پی ، جاج، تیم. 1388. رفتار سازمانی. (ترجمه مهدی زارع). تهران ‏: نص. 311 (تاریخ انتشار به زبان اصلی1943).##رضایی، دولت‌آبادی حسین، شهبازی، غلامرضا، و دهقانی، اناری فرشید. 1391. بررسی ارتباط حمایت سازمانی و مدیریتی و تعهد سازمانی نیروهای کارمند و نظامی پلیس (مورد مطالعه: نیروهای پلیس شهر اصفهان). پژوهش‌های راهبردی امنیت و نظم اجتماعی. (1)1، ص. 59.##‏رحیمی‌العظیم پور، فریبا. 1393. بررسی رابطه بین سبک‌های مدیریت حمایتی و غیرحمایتی با نوآوری سازمانی و عملکرد شغلی کارکنان شرکت نفت و گاز آغاجاری (کارشناسی ارشد). دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی ‌واحد مرودشت - دانشکده علوم تربیتی و روانشناسی.##شلدون راس.1392. مبانی احتمال. مترجمان:احمد پارسیان، علی همدانی، تهران: انتشارات شیخ بهایی.##طبرسا، غلامعلی، حاتمی، سکینه، و ابدالی، رقیه. 1391. تبیین ارتباط هوش سازمانی و خلق دانش (مورد مطالعه: کارکنان یک شرکت صنعتی). پژوهش نامه مدیریت تحول (پژوهش‌نامه مدیریت). (7)4، ص.110.##‏محمدداوودی، امیرحسین.، پژوهش، ش. 1394. ارزیابی مدل رهبری مشترک در تیم خلق دانش در اعضای هیات علمی دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه. رهیافتی نو در مدیریت آموزشی. دوره 6، ص. 123.##میرکمالی، سیدمحمد، حیات، علی اصغر، و اسمی، کرامت. 1390. رابطه خلاقیت سازمانی با ساختار ارگانیکی و مکانیکی مدارس: مطالعه موردی مدارس متوسطه. مدیریت و برنامه‌ریزی در نظام‌های آموزشی. (7)4، ص. 28.##کلانتری، اسماعیل، میگون‌پوری، محمدرضا، و یدالهی فارسی، جهانگیر. 1394. مطالعه عوامل سازمانی تأثیرگذار بر راهبرد تجاری-سازی تحقیقات دانشگاهی (مطالعه موردی: فناوری نانو). مدیریت فرهنگ سازمانی. (2)13،صص. 415–435.##گرگانی، نسیم، و نادری، مسعود. 1393. تجاری‌سازی موفق علم و فناوری: نیازها. ارائه شده در دومین کنفرانس بین‌المللی تجاری سازی فناوری، پارک علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران.##‏ممقانی، علیرضا.، سرمدسعیدی، سهیل.، کارباران‌زادقدیم.محمدرضا. 1390. شناسایی و رتبه‌بندی عوامل کلیدی موثر در توسعه محصول جدید در گروه خودروسازی سایپا با رویکرد AHP. مطالعات مدیریت صنعتی. دوره 8، 167.##ناصحی‌فر، وحید، حبیبی، بدرآبادی محبوبه، و حبیبی بدرآبادی، علی. 1389. عوامل ساختاری موثر بر نوآوری و خلق دانش در سازمان ها (مطالعه موردی سازمان امور مالیاتی کشور). پژوهشنامه مالیات. دوره جدید - 18(مسلسل 57)، 123.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تأثیر همکاری متقابل کارکردی بر عملکرد تجاری‌سازی فناوری با توجه به نقش خلق دانش و حمایت مدیریت ارشد</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Influences of Cross-functional Collaboration on Technology Commercialization Function Regarding the Role of Knowledge Creation and Support  of Superior Management</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>حفظ مزیت رقابتی و بقاء سازمانی در گرو حفظ و تقویت تجاری‌سازی فناوری است. هدف اصلی این پژوهش بررسی رابطه بین همکاری‌متقابل کارکردی، خلق دانش، حمایت مدیریت‌ارشد و تجاری‌سازی فناوری در شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان می‌باشد. پژوهش حاضر بر اساس هدف، کاربردی و روش آن توصیفی-تحلیلی است که با رویکرد پیمایشی انجام‌گرفته است. جامعه آماری پژوهش 122 شرکت دانش‌بنیان‌  مستقر در پارک علم وفناوری پردیس می‌باشد. تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌ها با استفاده از معادلات‌ساختاری و نرم‌افزار SmartPLS انجام‌گرفته است. طبق یافته‌های حاصل از این پژوهش، بین متغیر همکاری‌متقابل کارکردی و تجاری‌سازی فناوری رابطه مثبت و معنی‌دار وجود دارد و خلق دانش میانجی‌گراین رابطه است و حمایت مدیریت ‌ارشد نیز رابطه مذکور را به‌طور مثبت تعدیل می‌کند. در انتها با توجه به نتایج پژوهش پیشنهادهایی ارائه ‌شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Maintaining competitive advantage and organizational survival depends on maintaining and strengthening the commercialization of technology. The main objective of this study is to investigate the relationship between cross-functional collaboration, knowledge creation, superior management support and commercialization of technology in knowledge-based companies. The aim of the current study is practical and it is an descriptive-analytic survey which is conducted by a metrical approach. The Statistical Society were 122  knowledge-based companies located in the area of Pardis science and technology park. A questionnaire was used to collect data and structural equation modeling and data analysis methods were used by SmartPLS to analyze the data. According to the results of this study, there was positive and significant relationship between the variable cross-functional cooperation and technology commercialization   and knowledge creation mediate this relationship and superior management support also equates the aforementioned relationship positively. Finally, according to the results suggestions are presented.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>45</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>72</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>هما</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>درودی</Family>
						<NameE>Homa</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Doroudi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، زنجان ، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، زنجان ، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>homa_doroudi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مسعود</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شرف پور</Family>
						<NameE>Masoud</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sharafpour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، زنجان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، زنجان، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>msharafpour@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>همکاری متقابل کارکردی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خلق دانش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تجاری‌سازی فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>حمایت مدیریت ارشد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Athayde, R., 2009. Measuring enterprise potential in young people. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice, 33(2), pp. 481-500.##Autio, E., Keeley, R., Klofsten, M. &amp; Ulfstedt, T., 1997. Entrepreneurial intent among students: testing an intent model in Asia, Scandinavia and USA. Wellesley, Babson College.##Bandura, A., 1986. Social Foundations of Thought and Action: a Social Cognitive Theory. NJ: Prentice-Hall.##Baron, R., 1998. Cognitive mechanisms in entrepreneurship: why and when entrepreneurs think differently than other People. Journal of Business Venturing, 13(3), pp. 275-294.##Baron, R. A., 2004. The cognitive perspective: A valuable tool for answering entrepreneurship’s basic – why questions. Journal of Business Venturing, 19(2), pp. 221-239.##Baron, R. A. &amp; Ensley, M. D., 2006. Opportunity recognition as the detection of meaningful patterns: evidence from comparisons of novice and experienced entrepreneurs. Management Science, 52(9), pp. 1331-1344.##Basadur, M., Taggar, S. &amp; Pringle, P., 1999. Improving the measurement of divergent thinking attitudes in organizations. Journal of Creativity Research, Volume 33, pp. 75-111.##Baum, J. R. &amp; Locke, E. A., 2004. The relationship of entrepreneurial traits, skill, and motivation to subsequent venture growth. Journal of Applied Psychology, 89(4), pp. 587-598.##Beghetto, R. A. &amp; Kaufman, J. C., 2015. Promise and pitfalls in differentiating amongst the Cs of creativity. Creativity Research Journal, 27(2), pp. 240-241.##Brorström, B., 2002. The world’s richest municipality: The importance of institutions for municipal development. Journal of Economic Issues , 36(1), pp. 55-78.##Busenitz, L., 1996. Research on entrepreneurial alertness: sampling, measurement, and theoretical issues. Journal of Small Business Management, 34(4), pp. 35-44.##Chaston, I. &amp; Sadler‐Smith, E., 2012. Entrepreneurial cognition, entrepreneurial orientation and firm capability in the creative industries. British Journal of Management, 23(3), pp. 415-432.##Chen, C. C., Greene, P. G. &amp; Crick, A., 1998. Does entrepreneurial self-efficacy distinguish entrepreneurs from managers?. Journal of business venturing, 13(4), pp. 295-316.##Cheng, Y. C. &amp; Tam, W., 1997. Multi-models of quality in education. Quality Assurance in Education, 5(1), pp. 22-31.##Cheong Cheng, Y. &amp; Ming Tam, W., 1997. Multi-models of quality in education. Quality assurance in Education, 5(1), pp. 22-31.##Cohen-Kdoshay, O. &amp; Meiran, N., 2007. The representation of instructions in working memory leads to autonomous response activation: evidence from the first trials in the flanker paradigm. Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology (Colchester), 60(8), pp. 1140-1154.##Cohen, M. D. &amp; Axelrod, R., 2000. Harnessing Complexity: Organizational Implications of a Scientific Frontier. Simon and Schuster.##Cope, J. &amp; Pittaway, L., 2007. Entrepreneurship education: a systematic review of the evidence. International Small Business Journal, 25(5), pp. 479-510.##DeTienne, D. &amp; Chandler, G., 2004. Opportunity identification and its role in the entrepreneurial classroom: a pedagogical approach and empirical test. Academy of Management Learning &amp; Education, 3(3), pp. 242-257.##Dewett, T., 2004. Employee creativity and the role of risk. European Journal of Innovation Management, 7(4), pp. 257-266.##Drucker, P. F. &amp; Noel, J. L., 1986. Innovation and Entrepreneurship: practices and principles. The Journal of Continuing Higher Education, 34(1), pp. 22-23.##Dweck, C., 2008. Mindset: The New Psychology of Success. New York: Ballantine.##Dweck, C. S. &amp; Leggett, E. L., 1988. A social-cognitive approach to motivation and personality. Psychological review, 95(2), pp. 256-273.##Ertuna, Z. &amp; Gurel, E., 2011. The moderating role of higher education on entrepreneurship. Education+Training, 53(5), pp. 387-402.##Fayolle, A., Gailly, B. &amp; Lassas-Clerc, N., 2006. Assessing the impact of entrepreneurship education programmes: a new methodology. Journal of European industrial training, 30(9), pp. 701-720.##Freitas, A. L., Gollwitzer, P. &amp; Trope, Y., 2004. The influence of abstract and concrete mindsets on anticipating and guiding others’ self-regulatory efforts. Journal of Experimental Social Psychology, 40(6), pp. 739-752.##Gaglio, C. M. &amp; Katz, J. A., 2001. The psychological basis of opportunity identification: Entrepreneurial alertness. Small business economics, 16(2), pp. 95-111.##Galloway, L. &amp; Brown, W., 2002. Entrepreneurship education at university: a driver in the creation of high growth firms?. Education+ Training, 44(8/9), pp. 398-405.##Gefen, D. &amp; Straub, D., 2005. A practical guide to factorial validity using PLS-Graph: Tutorial and annotated example. Communications of the Association for Information systems, 16(1), p. 5.##Gimeno, J., Folta, T., Cooper, A. &amp; Woo, C., 1997. Survival of the fittest? Entrepreneurial human capital and the persistence of underperforming firms. Administrative Science Quarterly, 42(4), pp. 750-783.##Gollwitzer, P. M., 1990. Action phases and mind-sets. Handbook of motivation and cognition: Foundations of social behavior, Volume 2, pp. 53-92.##Gorman, G., Hanlon, D. &amp; King, W., 1997. Some research perspectives on entrepreneurship education, enterprise education and education for small business management: a ten-year literature review. International small business journal, 15(3), pp. 56-77.##Hannon, P., 2007. Enterprise for all? The fragility of enterprise provision across England’s HEIs. Journal of Small Business and Enterprise Development, 14(2), pp. 183-210.##Haynie, J. M., Shephered, D., Mosakowski, E. P. &amp; Earley, C., 2010. A situated metacognitive model of the entrepreneurial mindset. Journal of Business Venturing, Volume 25, pp. 217-229.##Heinonen, J., Hytti, U. &amp; Stenholm, P., 2011. The role of creativity in opportunity search and business idea creation. Education+Training, 53(8/9), pp. 659-672.##Hennessey, B. &amp; Amabile, T., 2010. Creativity. Annual Review of Psychology, Volume 61, pp. 569-598.##Henry, C., Hill, F. &amp; Leitch, C., 2004. The effectiveness of training for new business creation – a longitudinal study. International Small Business Journal, 22(3), pp. 249-271.##Humphrey, G., 1951. Thinking: an introduction to its experimental psychology.##Ireland, R. D., Hitt, M. A. &amp; Sirmon, D. G., 2003. A model of strategic entrepreneurship: The construct and its dimensions. Journal of management, 29(6), pp. 963-989.##Kaish, S. &amp; Gilad, B., 1991. Characteristics of opportunities search of entrepreneurs versus executives: sources, interests, general alertness. Journal of Business Venturing, 6(1), pp. 5-61.##Karwowski, M., 2009. I’m creative, but am I creative? Similarities and differences between self-evaluated small and big-C creativity in Poland. Korean Journal of Thinking and Problem Solving, 19(2), pp. 7-26.##Karwowski, M., 2014. Creative mindsets: Measurement, correlates, consequences. Psychology of Aesthetics, Creativity, and the Arts, 8(1), pp. 62-70.##Kaufman, J. C., 2016. Creativity 101 (2nd ed.). New York: Springer.##Kaufman, J. C. &amp; Beghetto, R. A., 2013. In praise of Clark Kent: Creative metacognition and the importance of teaching kids when (not) to be creative. Roeper Review, 35(3), pp. 155-165.##Kimberly, J. R. &amp; Evanisko, M. J., 1981. Organizational innovation: The influence of individual, organizational, and contextual factors on hospital adoption of technological and administrative innovations. Academy of management journal, 24(4), pp. 689-713.##Kirzner, I., 1973. Competition and Entrepreneurship. Chicago, IL: University of Chicago Press.##Kirzner, I., 1979. Perception, Opportunity, and Profit, Studies in the Theory of Entrepreneurship. Chicago, IL: University of Chicago Press.##Kirzner, I., 1999. Creativity and/or alertness: a reconsideration of the Schumpeterian entrepreneur. Review of Austrian Economics, 11(1/2), pp. 5-17.##Kirzner, I. M., 2009. The alert and creative entrepreneur: A clarification. Small Business Economics, 32(2), pp. 145-152.##Koontz, H., O’Donnell, C. &amp; Weihrich, H., 1980. Management (7th ed.). Tokyo: McGraw-Hill.##Krauss, S., Frese, M., Friedrich, C. &amp; Unger, J., 2005. Entrepreneurial orientation: a psychological model of success among southern African small business owners. European Journal of Work and Organizational Psychology , 14(3), pp. 315-328.##Kuratako, D., 2006. A Tribute to 50 years of Excellence in Entrepreneurship and Small Business. Journal of Small Business Management, 44(3), pp. 483-492.##Langowitz, N. S. &amp; Allen, I. E., 2010. Small Business Leadership: Does Being the Founder Matter?. Journal of Small Business &amp; Entrepreneurship, 23(1), pp. 53-63.##Liu, L., Mynderse, J. A., Gerhart, A. L. &amp; Arslan, S., 2015. Fostering the entrepreneurial mindset in the junior and senior mechanical engineering curriculum with a multi-course problem-based learning experience IEEE, pp. 1-5.##Madjar, N., Oldham, G. R. &amp; Pratt, M. G., 2002. There’s no place like home? The contributions of work and nonwork creativity support to employees’ creative performance. The Academy of Management Journal, 45(4), pp. 757-767.##Mahmood, A. &amp; Cheng, M., 2005. E-entrepreneurship in knowledge economy: implications for the Asia-Pacific economies. The Business Review, Cambridge, 4(1), pp. 153-160.##Martin, B., McNally, J. &amp; Kay, M., 2013. Examining the formation of human capital in entrepreneurship: a meta-analysis of entrepreneurship education outcomes. Journal of Business Venturing, 28(2), pp. 211-224.##Mathisen, J. &amp; Arnulf, J., 2013. Competing mindsets in entrepreneurship: The cost of doubt The International. Journal of Management Education , 11(3), p. 132–141.##Mathur, P., Block, L. &amp; Yucel-Aybat, O., 2014. The effects of goal progress cues: An implicit theory perspective. Journal of Consumer Psychology, 24(4), pp. 484-496.##Matlay, H., 2008. The impact of entrepreneurship education on entrepreneurial outcomes. Journal of Small Business and Enterprise Development, 15(2), pp. 382-396.##McGrath, R. G. &amp; MacMillan, I. C., 2000. The entrepreneurial mindset: Strategies for continuously creating opportunity in an age of uncertainty. Harvard Business Press.##McMullen, J. S. &amp; Shepherd, D. A., 2006. Entrepreneurial action and the role of uncertainty in the theory of the entrepreneur. Academy of Management review, 31(1), pp. 132-152.##Meyer, G. D. &amp; Heppard, K. A., 2000. Entrepreneurship as strategy: Competing on the entrepreneurial edge. pp. 101-114.##Miles, G., Heppard, K. A., Miles, R. E. &amp; Snow, C. C., 2000. Entrepreneurial strategies. Entrepreneurship as strategy. Competing on the entrepreneurial edge, pp. 101-114.##Morris, M. H., Kuratko, D. F. &amp; Schindehutte, M., 2001. Towards integration: understanding entrepreneurship through frameworks. The international journal of entrepreneurship and innovation, 2(1), pp. 35-49.##Mueller, S. L. &amp; Thomas, A. S., 2001. Culture and entrepreneurial potential: A nine country study of locus of control and innovativeness. Journal of business venturing, 16(1), pp. 51-75.##Munoz, C. A., Mosey, S. &amp; Binks, M., 2011. Developing opportunity-identification capabilities in the classroom: visual evidence for changing mental frames. Academy of Management Learning &amp; Education, 10(2), pp. 277–295.##Naudé, W., 2011. Entrepreneurship and Economic Development. Palgrave Macmillan: Basingstoke.##Neck, C. &amp; Houghton, J. D., 2006. Two decades of self-leadership theory and research.. Journal of Manage.rial Psychology, 21(4), pp. 270–295.##Neck, C. P. &amp; Manz, C. C., 1996. Thought self-leadership: the impact of mental strategies training on em.ployee cognition, behavior, and affect. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 17(5), pp. 445–467.##Neck, H. &amp; Greene, P., 2011. Entrepreneurship education: known worlds and new frontiers. Journal of Small .Business Management, 49(1), pp. 55-70.##Oosterbeek, H., Van Praag, M. &amp; Ijsselstein, A., 2010. The impact of entrepreneurship education on entre.preneurship skills and motivation. European economic review, 54(3), pp. 442-454.##.Osborne, J., 2008. Best Practices in Quantitative Methods. Sage.##Puente-Diaz, R., Maier, M. A., Brem, A. &amp; Cavazos-Arroyo, J., 2016. Generalizability of the four C model of creativity: A cross-cultural examination of creative perception. Psychology of Aesthetics, Creativity, and the Arts, 10(1), pp. 14-20.##Rhodes, M., 1961. An analysis of creativity. The Phi Delta Kappan, 42(7), pp. 305-310.##Schumpeter, J. A., 1961. The theory of economic development: An inquiry into profits, capital, credit, interest, and the business cycle.:Harvard University Press..##Sevincer, A. T., Kluge, L. &amp; Oettingen, G., 2014. Implicit theories and motivational focus: Desired future versus present reality. Motivation and Emotion, 38(1), pp. 36-46.##Shane, S., 2012. Reflections on the 2010 AMR decade award: delivering on the promise of entrepreneurship as a field of research. Academy of Management Review, 37(1), pp. 10-20.##Shane, S., Nicolaoum, N., Cherkas, L. &amp; Spector, T. D., 2010. Do openness to experience and recognizing opportunities have the same genetic source?. Human Resource Management, 49(2), pp. 291–303.##Shane, S. &amp; Venkataraman, S., 2000. The promise of entrepreneurship as a field of research. Academy of management review, 25(1), pp. 217-226.##Short, J. C., Ketchen, D. J., Shook, C. L. &amp; Ireland, R. D., 2010. The concept of opportunity in entrepreneurship research: past accomplishments and future challenges. Journal of Management, 36(1), pp. 40–65.##Skinner, B. F., 1978. Reflections on behaviorism and society.##Solesvik, M., Westhead, P., Matlay, H. &amp; Parsyak, N., 2013. Entrepreneurial assets and mindsets: benefit from university entrepreneurship education investment. Education+ Training, 55(8/9), pp. 748-762.##Solomon, G., Duffy, S. &amp; Tarabishy, A., 2002. The state of entrepreneurship education in the United States: a nationwide survey and analysis. International Journal of Entrepreneurship Education, 1(1), pp. 65-86.##Souitaris, V., Zerbinati, S. &amp; Al-Lahan, A., 2007. Do entrepreneurship programmes raise entrepreneurial intention of science and engineering students? The effect of learning, inspiration and resources. Journal of Business Venturing, 22(4), pp. 566-591.##Tang, J., Kacmar, K. &amp; Busenitz, L., 2012. Entrepreneurial alertness in the pursuit of new opportunities. Journal of Business Venturing, 27(1), pp. 77-94.##Thagard, P., 2006. Hot Thought: Mechanisms and Applications of Emotional Cognition. MIT Press.##Thompson, J., 1999. The world of the entrepreneur – a new perspective. Journal of Workplace Learning: Employee Counselling Today, 11(6), pp. 209-224.##Timmons, J., 1999. New Venture Creation – Entrepreneurship for the 21st century. New York: Irwin McGraw-Hill.##Tuggle, C., 2002. Encouraging Entrepreneurial Endeavors in Established Enterprise. Texas A&amp;M University, Department of Management.##Udwadia, F. E., 1990. Creativity and innovation in organizations: Two models and managerial implications. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 38(1), pp. 65-80.##Uy, M. A. et al., 2015. Proactivity, adaptability and boundaryless career attitudes: The mediating role of entrepreneurial alertness.. Journal of Vocational Behavior, Volume 86, pp. 115-123.##van Gelderen, M. et al., 2008. Explaining entrepreneurial intentions by the means of the theory of planned behaviour. Career Development International, 13(6), pp. 538-559.##Von Graevenitz, G., Harhoff, D. &amp; Weber, R., 2010. The effects of entrepreneurship education. Journal of Economic Behavior &amp; Organization, 76(1), pp. 90-112.##Wadeson, N., 2006. Cognitive aspects of entrepreneurship: decision-making and attitudes to risk. In: M. Casson, B. Yeung, A. Basu &amp; N. Wadeson, eds. The Oxford handbook of entrepreneurship. OUP.##Walter, S., Parboteeah, K. &amp; Walter, A., 2013. University departments and selfemployment intentions of business students: a cross-level analysis. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice, 37(2), pp. 175-200.##Whetten, D. A. &amp; Cameron, K. S., 1983. Management skill training: A needed addition to the management curriculum. Exchange: The Organizational Behavior Teaching Journal, 8(2), pp. 10-15.##Yang, S.-J. &amp; Chandra, Y., 2009. Agent based simulation in entrepreneurial research. Academy of Management Chicago.##Yeager, D. S. &amp; Dweck, C. S., 2012. Mindsets that promote resilience: When students believe that personal characteristics can be developed. Educational Psychologist, 47(4), pp. 302-314.##Zhao, H., Seibert, S. &amp; Hills, G., 2005. The mediating role of self-efficacy in the development of entrepreneurial intentions. Journal of applied psychology, 90(6), pp. 1265-1272.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر آموزش کارآفرینی بر دستگاه فکری کارآفرینانه: نقش میانجی خلاقیت و هوشیاری کارآفرینانه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Effect of Entrepreneurship Training on Entrepreneurial Mindset: Mediating Role of Creativity and Entrepreneurial Alertness. (Organizations of MOD)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی تأثیر آموزش کارآفرینی بر دستگاه فکری کارآفرینانه با توجه به نقش میانجی خلاقیت و هوشیاری کارآفرینانه است. جامعه آماری این پژوهش، مدیران ارشد 140 شرکت راهبردی کشور است که از این میان، 105 شرکت به عنوان نمونه مورد بررسی قرار گرفته‌اند. ابزار اصلی گردآوری داده‌ها، پرسشنامه است که سطح روایی و پایایی آن، برای تمامی سازه‌ها مورد قبول بوده است. به منظور تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها ، از روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری و نرم‌افزار لیزرل استفاده شده است. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که آموزش کارآفرینی و خلاقیت بر دستگاه فکری کارآفرینانه بی‌تأثیر است، اما آموزش کارآفرینی بر خلاقیت و هوشیاری تأثیر دارد. همچنین، هوشیاری نقش میانجی را در رابطه‌ی آموزش کارآفرینی و دستگاه فکری کارآفرینانه ایفا می‌کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>This study aims to investigate the impact of entrepreneurship training on entrepreneurial mindset according to mediating role of creativity and entrepreneurial alertness. By Cochrane formula, 105 companies from 140 organizations of Ministry of Defence (MOD) have been selected randomly. The main tool for collecting data is questionnaire, which its level of validity and reliability has been acceptable for all structures. To analyze the data, structural simulating equations and Lisrel software is used. Results show that entrepreneurship training and creativity on the entrepreneurship mindset system is not effective, but entrepreneurship training on creativity and awareness is effective. Also, awareness plays the role of mediator in the relationship of entrepreneurship training and entrepreneurship mindset system.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>73</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>100</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدجواد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نائیجی</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Javad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>naeiji</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی،تهران،ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی،تهران،ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m_naeiji@sbu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ابراهیم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ابراهیمی</Family>
						<NameE>Ebrahim</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ebrahimi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه شهید بهشتی، تهران، ایران.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ebm.ebrahimi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آموزش کارآفرینی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خلاقیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هوشیاری کارآفرینانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>دستگاه فکری کارآفرینانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Athayde, R., 2009. Measuring enterprise potential in young people. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice,##33(2), pp. 481-500.##Autio, E., Keeley, R., Klofsten, M. &amp; Ulfstedt, T., 1997. Entrepreneurial intent among students: testing an##intent model in Asia, Scandinavia and USA. Wellesley, Babson College.##Bandura, A., 1986. Social Foundations of Thought and Action: a Social Cognitive Theory. NJ: Prentice-Hall.##Baron, R., 1998. Cognitive mechanisms in entrepreneurship: why and when entrepreneurs think differently##than other People. Journal of Business Venturing, 13(3), pp. 275-294.##Baron, R. A., 2004. The cognitive perspective: A valuable tool for answering entrepreneurship’s basic – why##questions. Journal of Business Venturing, 19(2), pp. 221-239.##Baron, R. A. &amp; Ensley, M. D., 2006. Opportunity recognition as the detection of meaningful patterns:##evidence from comparisons of novice and experienced entrepreneurs. Management Science, 52(9), pp.##1331-1344.##Basadur, M., Taggar, S. &amp; Pringle, P., 1999. Improving the measurement of divergent thinking attitudes in##organizations. Journal of Creativity Research, Volume 33, pp. 75-111.##Baum, J. R. &amp; Locke, E. A., 2004. The relationship of entrepreneurial traits, skill, and motivation to subsequent##venture growth. Journal of Applied Psychology, 89(4), pp. 587-598.##Beghetto, R. A. &amp; Kaufman, J. C., 2015. Promise and pitfalls in differentiating amongst the Cs of creativity.##Creativity Research Journal, 27(2), pp. 240-241.##Brorström, B., 2002. The world’s richest municipality: The importance of institutions for municipal development.##Journal of Economic Issues , 36(1), pp. 55-78.##Busenitz, L., 1996. Research on entrepreneurial alertness: sampling, measurement, and theoretical issues.##Journal of Small Business Management, 34(4), pp. 35-44.##Chaston, I. &amp; Sadler‐Smith, E., 2012. Entrepreneurial cognition, entrepreneurial orientation and firm capability##in the creative industries. British Journal of Management, 23(3), pp. 415-432.##Chen, C. C., Greene, P. G. &amp; Crick, A., 1998. Does entrepreneurial self-efficacy distinguish entrepreneurs##from managers?. Journal of business venturing, 13(4), pp. 295-316.##Cheng, Y. C. &amp; Tam, W., 1997. Multi-models of quality in education. Quality Assurance in Education, 5(1),##pp. 22-31.##Cheong Cheng, Y. &amp; Ming Tam, W., 1997. Multi-models of quality in education. Quality assurance in Education,##5(1), pp. 22-31.##Cohen-Kdoshay, O. &amp; Meiran, N., 2007. The representation of instructions in working memory leads to##autonomous response activation: evidence from the first trials in the flanker paradigm. Quarterly Journal of##Experimental Psychology (Colchester), 60(8), pp. 1140-1154.##Cohen, M. D. &amp; Axelrod, R., 2000. Harnessing Complexity: Organizational Implications of a Scientific##Frontier. Simon and Schuster.##Cope, J. &amp; Pittaway, L., 2007. Entrepreneurship education: a systematic review of the evidence. International##Small Business Journal, 25(5), pp. 479-510.##DeTienne, D. &amp; Chandler, G., 2004. Opportunity identification and its role in the entrepreneurial classroom:##a pedagogical approach and empirical test. Academy of Management Learning &amp; Education, 3(3), pp. 242-##Dewett, T., 2004. Employee creativity and the role of risk. European Journal of Innovation Management,##7(4), pp. 257-266.##Drucker, P. F. &amp; Noel, J. L., 1986. Innovation and Entrepreneurship: practices and principles. The Journal of##Continuing Higher Education, 34(1), pp. 22-23.##Dweck, C., 2008. Mindset: The New Psychology of Success. New York: Ballantine.##Dweck, C. S. &amp; Leggett, E. L., 1988. A social-cognitive approach to motivation and personality. Psychological##review, 95(2), pp. 256-273.##Ertuna, Z. &amp; Gurel, E., 2011. The moderating role of higher education on entrepreneurship. Education+Training,##53(5), pp. 387-402.##Fayolle, A., Gailly, B. &amp; Lassas-Clerc, N., 2006. Assessing the impact of entrepreneurship education programmes:##a new methodology. Journal of European industrial training, 30(9), pp. 701-720.##Freitas, A. L., Gollwitzer, P. &amp; Trope, Y., 2004. The influence of abstract and concrete mindsets on anticipating##and guiding others’ self-regulatory efforts. Journal of Experimental Social Psychology, 40(6), pp.##Gaglio, C. M. &amp; Katz, J. A., 2001. The psychological basis of opportunity identification: Entrepreneurial##alertness. Small business economics, 16(2), pp. 95-111.##Galloway, L. &amp; Brown, W., 2002. Entrepreneurship education at university: a driver in the creation of high##growth firms?. Education+ Training, 44(8/9), pp. 398-405.##Gefen, D. &amp; Straub, D., 2005. A practical guide to factorial validity using PLS-Graph: Tutorial and annotated##example. Communications of the Association for Information systems, 16(1), p. 5.##Gimeno, J., Folta, T., Cooper, A. &amp; Woo, C., 1997. Survival of the fittest? Entrepreneurial human capital and##the persistence of underperforming firms. Administrative Science Quarterly, 42(4), pp. 750-783.##Gollwitzer, P. M., 1990. Action phases and mind-sets. Handbook of motivation and cognition: Foundations##of social behavior, Volume 2, pp. 53-92.##Gorman, G., Hanlon, D. &amp; King, W., 1997. Some research perspectives on entrepreneurship education, enterprise##education and education for small business management: a ten-year literature review. International##small business journal, 15(3), pp. 56-77.##Hannon, P., 2007. Enterprise for all? The fragility of enterprise provision across England’s HEIs. Journal of##Small Business and Enterprise Development, 14(2), pp. 183-210.##Haynie, J. M., Shephered, D., Mosakowski, E. P. &amp; Earley, C., 2010. A situated metacognitive model of the##entrepreneurial mindset. Journal of Business Venturing, Volume 25, pp. 217-229.##Heinonen, J., Hytti, U. &amp; Stenholm, P., 2011. The role of creativity in opportunity search and business idea##creation. Education+Training, 53(8/9), pp. 659-672.##Hennessey, B. &amp; Amabile, T., 2010. Creativity. Annual Review of Psychology, Volume 61, pp. 569-598.##Henry, C., Hill, F. &amp; Leitch, C., 2004. The effectiveness of training for new business creation – a longitudinal##study. International Small Business Journal, 22(3), pp. 249-271.##Humphrey, G., 1951. Thinking: an introduction to its experimental psychology.##Ireland, R. D., Hitt, M. A. &amp; Sirmon, D. G., 2003. A model of strategic entrepreneurship: The construct and##its dimensions. Journal of management, 29(6), pp. 963-989.##Kaish, S. &amp; Gilad, B., 1991. Characteristics of opportunities search of entrepreneurs versus executives:##sources, interests, general alertness. Journal of Business Venturing, 6(1), pp. 5-61.##Karwowski, M., 2009. I’m creative, but am I creative? Similarities and differences between self-evaluated##small and big-C creativity in Poland. Korean Journal of Thinking and Problem Solving, 19(2), pp. 7-26.##Karwowski, M., 2014. Creative mindsets: Measurement, correlates, consequences. Psychology of Aesthetics,##Creativity, and the Arts, 8(1), pp. 62-70.##Kaufman, J. C., 2016. Creativity 101 (2nd ed.). New York: Springer.##Kaufman, J. C. &amp; Beghetto, R. A., 2013. In praise of Clark Kent: Creative metacognition and the importance##of teaching kids when (not) to be creative. Roeper Review, 35(3), pp. 155-165.##Kimberly, J. R. &amp; Evanisko, M. J., 1981. Organizational innovation: The influence of individual, organizational,##and contextual factors on hospital adoption of technological and administrative innovations. Academy##of management journal, 24(4), pp. 689-713.##Kirzner, I., 1973. Competition and Entrepreneurship. Chicago, IL: University of Chicago Press.##Kirzner, I., 1979. Perception, Opportunity, and Profit, Studies in the Theory of Entrepreneurship. Chicago,##IL: University of Chicago Press.##Kirzner, I., 1999. Creativity and/or alertness: a reconsideration of the Schumpeterian entrepreneur. Review##of Austrian Economics, 11(1/2), pp. 5-17.##Kirzner, I. M., 2009. The alert and creative entrepreneur: A clarification. Small Business Economics, 32(2),##pp. 145-152.##Koontz, H., O’Donnell, C. &amp; Weihrich, H., 1980. Management (7th ed.). Tokyo: McGraw-Hill.##Krauss, S., Frese, M., Friedrich, C. &amp; Unger, J., 2005. Entrepreneurial orientation: a psychological model##of success among southern African small business owners. European Journal of Work and Organizational##Psychology , 14(3), pp. 315-328.##Kuratako, D., 2006. A Tribute to 50 years of Excellence in Entrepreneurship and Small Business. Journal of##Small Business Management, 44(3), pp. 483-492.##Langowitz, N. S. &amp; Allen, I. E., 2010. Small Business Leadership: Does Being the Founder Matter?. Journal##of Small Business &amp; Entrepreneurship, 23(1), pp. 53-63.##Liu, L., Mynderse, J. A., Gerhart, A. L. &amp; Arslan, S., 2015. Fostering the entrepreneurial mindset in the junior##and senior mechanical engineering curriculum with a multi-course problem-based learning experience##IEEE, pp. 1-5.##Madjar, N., Oldham, G. R. &amp; Pratt, M. G., 2002. There’s no place like home? The contributions of work##and nonwork creativity support to employees’ creative performance. The Academy of Management Journal,##45(4), pp. 757-767.##Mahmood, A. &amp; Cheng, M., 2005. E-entrepreneurship in knowledge economy: implications for the Asia-Pacific##economies. The Business Review, Cambridge, 4(1), pp. 153-160.##Martin, B., McNally, J. &amp; Kay, M., 2013. Examining the formation of human capital in entrepreneurship: a##meta-analysis of entrepreneurship education outcomes. Journal of Business Venturing, 28(2), pp. 211-224.##Mathisen, J. &amp; Arnulf, J., 2013. Competing mindsets in entrepreneurship: The cost of doubt The International.##Journal of Management Education , 11(3), p. 132–141.##Mathur, P., Block, L. &amp; Yucel-Aybat, O., 2014. The effects of goal progress cues: An implicit theory perspective.##Journal of Consumer Psychology, 24(4), pp. 484-496.##Matlay, H., 2008. The impact of entrepreneurship education on entrepreneurial outcomes. Journal of Small##Business and Enterprise Development, 15(2), pp. 382-396.##McGrath, R. G. &amp; MacMillan, I. C., 2000. The entrepreneurial mindset: Strategies for continuously creating##opportunity in an age of uncertainty. Harvard Business Press.##McMullen, J. S. &amp; Shepherd, D. A., 2006. Entrepreneurial action and the role of uncertainty in the theory of##the entrepreneur. Academy of Management review, 31(1), pp. 132-152.##Meyer, G. D. &amp; Heppard, K. A., 2000. Entrepreneurship as strategy: Competing on the entrepreneurial edge.##pp. 101-114.##Miles, G., Heppard, K. A., Miles, R. E. &amp; Snow, C. C., 2000. Entrepreneurial strategies. Entrepreneurship as##strategy. Competing on the entrepreneurial edge, pp. 101-114.##Morris, M. H., Kuratko, D. F. &amp; Schindehutte, M., 2001. Towards integration: understanding entrepreneurship##through frameworks. The international journal of entrepreneurship and innovation, 2(1), pp. 35-49.##Mueller, S. L. &amp; Thomas, A. S., 2001. Culture and entrepreneurial potential: A nine country study of locus of##control and innovativeness. Journal of business venturing, 16(1), pp. 51-75.##Munoz, C. A., Mosey, S. &amp; Binks, M., 2011. Developing opportunity-identification capabilities in the classroom:##visual evidence for changing mental frames. Academy of Management Learning &amp; Education, 10(2),##p. 277–295.##Naudé, W., 2011. Entrepreneurship and Economic Development. Palgrave Macmillan: Basingstoke.##Neck, C. &amp; Houghton, J. D., 2006. Two decades of self-leadership theory and research.. Journal of Manage.##rial Psychology, 21(4), p. 270–295.##Neck, C. P. &amp; Manz, C. C., 1996. Thought self-leadership: the impact of mental strategies training on##em.ployee cognition, behavior, and affect. Journal of Organizational Behavior, 17(5), p. 445–467.##Neck, H. &amp; Greene, P., 2011. Entrepreneurship education: known worlds and new frontiers. Journal of Small##.Business Management, 49(1), pp. 55-70.##Oosterbeek, H., Van Praag, M. &amp; Ijsselstein, A., 2010. The impact of entrepreneurship education on entre.##preneurship skills and motivation. European economic review, 54(3), pp. 442-454.##.Osborne, J., 2008. Best Practices in Quantitative Methods. Sage.##Puente-Diaz, R., Maier, M. A., Brem, A. &amp; Cavazos-Arroyo, J., 2016. Generalizability of the four C model##of creativity: A cross-cultural examination of creative perception. Psychology of Aesthetics, Creativity, and##the Arts, 10(1), pp. 14-20.##Rhodes, M., 1961. An analysis of creativity. The Phi Delta Kappan, 42(7), pp. 305-310.##Schumpeter, J. A., 1961. The theory of economic development: An inquiry into profits, capital, credit, interest,##and the business cycle.:Harvard University Press..##Sevincer, A. T., Kluge, L. &amp; Oettingen, G., 2014. Implicit theories and motivational focus: Desired future##versus present reality. Motivation and Emotion, 38(1), pp. 36-46.##Shane, S., 2012. Reflections on the 2010 AMR decade award: delivering on the promise of entrepreneurship##as a field of research. Academy of Management Review, 37(1), pp. 10-20.##Shane, S., Nicolaoum, N., Cherkas, L. &amp; Spector, T. D., 2010. Do openness to experience and recognizing##opportunities have the same genetic source?. Human Resource Management, 49(2), p. 291–303.##Shane, S. &amp; Venkataraman, S., 2000. The promise of entrepreneurship as a field of research. Academy of##management review, 25(1), pp. 217-226.##Short, J. C., Ketchen, D. J., Shook, C. L. &amp; Ireland, R. D., 2010. The concept of opportunity in entrepreneurship##research: past accomplishments and future challenges. Journal of Management, 36(1), p. 40–65.##Skinner, B. F., 1978. Reflections on behaviorism and society.##Solesvik, M., Westhead, P., Matlay, H. &amp; Parsyak, N., 2013. Entrepreneurial assets and mindsets: benefit##from university entrepreneurship education investment. Education+ Training, 55(8/9), pp. 748-762.##Solomon, G., Duffy, S. &amp; Tarabishy, A., 2002. The state of entrepreneurship education in the United States: a##nationwide survey and analysis. International Journal of Entrepreneurship Education, 1(1), pp. 65-86.##Souitaris, V., Zerbinati, S. &amp; Al-Lahan, A., 2007. Do entrepreneurship programmes raise entrepreneurial##intention of science and engineering students? The effect of learning, inspiration and resources. Journal of##Business Venturing, 22(4), pp. 566-591.##Tang, J., Kacmar, K. &amp; Busenitz, L., 2012. Entrepreneurial alertness in the pursuit of new opportunities.##Journal of Business Venturing, 27(1), pp. 77-94.##Thagard, P., 2006. Hot Thought: Mechanisms and Applications of Emotional Cognition. MIT Press.##Thompson, J., 1999. The world of the entrepreneur – a new perspective. Journal of Workplace Learning:##Employee Counselling Today, 11(6), pp. 209-224.##Timmons, J., 1999. New Venture Creation – Entrepreneurship for the 21st century. New York: Irwin Mc-##Graw-Hill.##Tuggle, C., 2002. Encouraging Entrepreneurial Endeavors in Established Enterprise. Texas A&amp;M University,##Department of Management.##Udwadia, F. E., 1990. Creativity and innovation in organizations: Two models and managerial implications.##Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 38(1), pp. 65-80.##Uy, M. A. et al., 2015. Proactivity, adaptability and boundaryless career attitudes: The mediating role of##entrepreneurial alertness.. Journal of Vocational Behavior, Volume 86, pp. 115-123.##van Gelderen, M. et al., 2008. Explaining entrepreneurial intentions by the means of the theory of planned##behaviour. Career Development International, 13(6), pp. 538-559.##Von Graevenitz, G., Harhoff, D. &amp; Weber, R., 2010. The effects of entrepreneurship education. Journal of##Economic Behavior &amp; Organization, 76(1), pp. 90-112.##Wadeson, N., 2006. Cognitive aspects of entrepreneurship: decision-making and attitudes to risk. In: M.##Casson, B. Yeung, A. Basu &amp; N. Wadeson, eds. The Oxford handbook of entrepreneurship. OUP.##Walter, S., Parboteeah, K. &amp; Walter, A., 2013. University departments and selfemployment intentions of##business students: a cross-level analysis. Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice, 37(2), pp. 175-200.##Whetten, D. A. &amp; Cameron, K. S., 1983. Management skill training: A needed addition to the management##curriculum. Exchange: The Organizational Behavior Teaching Journal, 8(2), pp. 10-15.##Yang, S.-J. &amp; Chandra, Y., 2009. Agent based simulation in entrepreneurial research. Academy of Management##Yeager, D. S. &amp; Dweck, C. S., 2012. Mindsets that promote resilience: When students believe that personal##characteristics can be developed. Educational Psychologist, 47(4), pp. 302-314.##Zhao, H., Seibert, S. &amp; Hills, G., 2005. The mediating role of self-efficacy in the development of entrepreneurial##intentions. Journal of applied psychology, 90(6), pp. 1265-1272.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی نقش سرمایه فکری بر روی رفتار نوآورانه با تأکید بر نقش میانجیگری اشتراک دانش (مورد مطالعه: پژوهشکده هوا خورشید)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the Effect of Intellectual Capital on Innovative Behavior through the Role of Knowledge Sharing as a Mediator (Case of Sun-Air Research Institute)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در سازمان‌های پژوهشی، حفظ بقا منوط به نوآوری است. با توجه به تغییرات محیطی، این‌گونه سازمان‌ها نیازمند پرورش نوآوری وخلاقیت هستند. در اقتصاد مبتنی بر دانش، رفتارهای نوآورانه به‌عنوان کلید نوآوری، نقش به‌سزایی در خلق ارزش‌های سازمانی دارند و این مسأله در حوزة سازمان‌های تحقیقاتی وابسته به صنایع دفاع با توجه به نوع فعالیت، حائز اهمیت است. هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی نقش واسط اشتراک دانش در تأثیر اجزای سرمایة فکری بر رفتار نوآورانه در میان کارکنان یکی از مجموعه‌های تحقیقاتی وابسته به وزارت دفاع می‌باشد. برای سنجش متغیرهای پژوهش از پرسشنامه‌ای شامل 25 پرسش استفاده شد. این پرسشنامه، میان 80 نفر از کارکنان سازمان مورد مطالعه توزیع گردید و داده‌ها با روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری تجزیه و شدند. نتایج پژوهش، وجود رابطه میان بعد انسانی سرمایة فکری و رفتار نوآورانه از طریق بعد تجربة برگزیدة اشتراک دانش و همچنین بعد ساختاری سرمایة فکری بر رفتار نوآورانه از طریق نقش میانجی، دو بعد رفتار اشتراک دانش را تأیید می‌کند . در ادامه با توجه به اهمیت نوآوری در این سازمان‌ها و به منظور تقویت آن، بازگشت به میدان و مصاحبه‌های کیفی انجام گرفت و عوامل تأثیرگذار بر متغیرها و ارتباط سیستمی آنها شناسایی شد تا با استفاده از این نتایج و ارائة پیشنهادهای کاربردی بتوان سازمان را در جهت تقویت این روابط یاری نمود. نتایج تحلیل سیستمی بیان‌گر نقش مهم خلاقیت فردی  و لزوم توجه به آن، در جهت تقویت روابط موجود است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Research organizations survival depends on innovation. Considering the variability and unpredictability of environmental changes, these organizations desperately need to foster innovation and creativity. In the knowledge-based economy, innovative behavior plays a significant role in creating and enhancing organizational values and this matter in research facilities of the Department of Defense with respect to their activity field is significant. The aim of this study is to design and fit a model of the relationship between intellectual capital components and innovative behavior with regard to the interventionist behavior role of knowledge sharing among employees who work in research facilities of the Department of Defense. A questionnaire included 25 questions to measure variables were used. The questionnaire was distributed among 80 employees of the studied organizations. In order to analyze data, structural equation modeling was used. The result of this research proves the relationship between intellectual capital human dimension and innovative behavior by best practices sharing and also structural dimension of intellectual capital and both dimensions of knowledge sharing behavior. In the following, Considering the importance of innovation in the organization and to strengthen its return to the field and qualitative interviews were conducted also factors influencing variables and the systematic relationships between these factors and variables were identified in order for the organization to improve them. System analysis results indicate the important role of individual creativity.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>101</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>134</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خوراکیان</Family>
						<NameE>Alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khorakian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.khorakian@um.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نگار</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کدخدا</Family>
						<NameE>Negar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kadkhoda</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>negarkadkhoda@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>بهاره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ملازاده یزدانی</Family>
						<NameE>Bahareh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Molazadeh Yazdani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد، مشهد، ایران.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>bahar.3443@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایه فکری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رفتار اشتراک دانش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رفتار نوآورانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایه انسانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سرمایه ساختاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ahmed Al-Dujaili, M. A. 2012. Influence of Intellectual Capital in the Organizational Innovation. International Journal of Innovation, Management and Technology, 3(2), pp. 128-135.##Alavi, M. lidner, D. 2001. Review: KM and KMS: conceptual foundations and research issues, MIS quarterly, 25(1), pp. 107-136.##Amabile, T. M. 1988. A model of creativity and innovation in organizations. Research in Organizational Behavior, Volume (10), pp. 123–167.##Beodker, C. Guthrie, J. Cuganesan, S. 2005. The strategic significance of human capital information in annual reporting. Journal of Human Resource Costing and Accounting, 8(2), pp. 7-22.##Bontis, N. (1998). Intellectual capital: an exploratory study that develops measures and models. Management Decision, 36(2), pp. 63-76.##Bontis, N. Keow, W. C. C. Richardson, S. (2000). Intellectual capital and Business performance in Malaysian Industries. Journal of Intellectual capital, 1(1), pp. 85-100.##Boulton, R. Libert, B. Samek, S. 2000. A business model for the new economy. Journal of Business Strategy, 21, 29-35.##Darren, G. Mallery, P. 2003. SPSS for windows step by step: A Simple Guide and Reference, 11.0 Update. Third Adition.##Davis, D. Morris, M. Allen, J. 1991. Perceived Environmental Turbulence and Its Effect on Selected Entrepreneurship, Marketing and Organizational Characteristics in Industrial Firms. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, 19(1),  pp. 43-51.##De Jong, J. &amp; Den Hartog, D. 2010. “Measuring Innovative Work Behaviour”, Creativity and Innovation Management, 19(1), pp. 23-36.##Delgado-Verde, M. Martı´n-de Castro, G. Navas-Lo´pez, J. E. 2011. Organizational knowledge assets and innovation capability. Journal of Intellectual Capital, 12(1), pp. 5-19.##Fornel, C. Lacker, D. 1981. Evaluating structural equation models with unobservable variables and measurement error: Algebra and statistic. Journal of Marketing Research, Volume (28), pp. 39-50.##Fukuyama, F. 1995, Trust: The Social Virtues &amp; the Creation of Prosperity, the Free Press, New York.##Gogan, Luminita Maria. Duran, Dan Cristian. Draghici, Anca. 2016. Structural capital-A proposed measurement model. 2nd GLOBAL CONFERENCE on BUSINESS, ECONOMICS, MANAGEMENT and TOURISM, 30-31 October 2014, Prague, Czech Republic##Huang, J.W. Li, Y.H. 2009.The mediating effect of knowledge management on social interaction and innovation performance. International Journal of Manpower, 30(3), pp. 285 - 301##Huy, Q. N. Bagozzi, R. P. Boss, W. Sguera, F. 2010. Affective enablers of knowledge sharing in a high performance hospital. Ann Arbor, 1001, 48109-1234.##Janssen, O. 2000. Job demands, perceptions of effort reward fairness and innovative work behavior. Journal of Occupational and organizational psychology, 73(3), pp. 287-302.##Johnston, R. Douglas, B. J. 2013. The Power of Strategy Innovation: A New Way of Linking Creativity and Strategic Planning To Discover Great Business Opportunity.##Jurczak, J. 2008. Intellectual Capital Measurement Methods. Institute of Organization and Managment in Industry ORGMAS. 1(1), pp. 37-45.##Karagiannis, D. Nemetz, M. 2009. A method for comprehensive intellectual capital management and reporting: The case of BOC Information Systems. Journal of Intellectual Capital, 10(1), pp. 93 – 108.##Lee, J. N. Kim, Y. G. 1999. Effect of partnership quality on IS outsourcing succes. Journal of Management information systems, 15(4), 29-61.##Liljander, K. Polsa, P. Van Riel, A. 2009. Modeling consumer responses to an apparel store band: Store image as a risk reducer. Journal of retailing and Consumer Services, 16, pp. 281- 290.##Magner, N. Welker, R. B. Campbell, T. L. 1996. Testing a model of cognitive budgetary participation processes in a latent variable structural equations framework. Accounting and Business Research, 27(1), pp. 41-50.##Marr, B. 2008. Impacting Future Value: How to Manage your Intellectual Capital. Society of Management Accountants of Canada, pp. 1-34.##Matos da Silva, F. Aperecide de Araujo Querido, E. Barbosa de Moraes, M. 2016. Innovation development Process in s, all and medium technology-based companies. Innovation and management review, pp. 176-189.##McAdam, R. Armstrong, G.  Kelly, B. 1998. Investigation of the relationship between total quality and innovation: A research study involving small organizations. European Journal of Innovation Management, 1(3), pp. 139-147##Meritum Project. 2002. Guideline for Managing and Reporting on intangibles (Intellectual Capital Report).Madrid, Airtel-Vodafone Foundation, pp. 1- 28.##Mura, M., Lettieri E., Spiller, N. &amp; Radaelli, G. 2012. Intellectual Capital and Innovative Work Behaviour: Openning the Black Box, International Journal of Engineering Business Management, 4(39), pp. 1-10.##Mura, M. Lettieri, E. Radaelli, G. Spiller, N. 2013. Promoting professional› Innovative Behaviour through Knowledge Sharing: the moderating role of Social Capital. Journal of Knowledge Management, 17(4).##Musiolik, J., Markard, J., &amp; Hekkert, M. P. 2012. Networks and network resources in technological innovation systems: Towards a conceptual framework for system building.Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 79(6), pp. 1032–1048.##Nelson, D. L. Cooper, C. L. 2007. Positive organizational behavior: An inclusive view. Positive organizational behavior, pp. 3-8.##Nunnally, J. C. 1978. Psychometric theory (2nd Ed.). New York: McGraw-Hill, pp. 460-469.##Obeso I., Cho S. S., Antonelli F., Houle S., Ko J. H., Strafella A. S. 2013. Effect of continuous theta burst stimulation of the right pre-SMA on cerebral blood flow changes during response inhibition. Brain Stimul, pp. 769-76.##Ornek, Ali Sahin. Ayas, Siyret. 2015. The Relationship between Intellectual Capital, Innovative work behavior and Bussiness Performance Reflection. Social and Behavioral science. pp. 1387-1395.##Peng, T. Roos, G. (2007). Intellectual capital and performance indicators: Taiwanese healthcare sector, Journal of Intellectual Capital, 8(3). pp. 538 - 556.##Radaelli, G. Lettieri, E. Mura, M. Spiller, N. (2014). Knowledge Sharing and Innovative Work Behaviour in Healthcare. Creativity and Innovation Management, 23(4), pp. 400–414.##Roos, G. Roos, J. 1997. Measuring Your Company’s Intellectual Performance. Long Range Planning, 30(3), pp. 413-426.##Rose, S. Barrons, J. 2005. The Effect of Disclosing Intellectual Capital on the Internal and External Finacial Statements’Users, Paper no. 24##Scott, W. E. Bruce, R. A. 1994. Determinants of innovative behavior: A path model of individual innovation in the workplace. Academy of Management Journal, Volume (37), pp. 580-607.##Serenko, A. and Bontis, N. 2009, Global Ranking of Knowledge Management and Intellectual Capital Academic Journals, Journal of Knowledge Management, 13(1), pp. 307-326.##Sulistiyani, Rina. Harwiki, Wiwiek. 2016. How SMEs Build Innovation Capability Based on Knowledge Sharing Behavior? Phenomenological Approach. 3rd Global Conference on Business and Social Sciences (GCBSS-2016) on “Contemporary Issues in Management and Social Sciences Research”, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, pp. 741-747.##Sullivan, J. H. 2000. Valuing Intangible Companies: an Intellectual Capital Approach. Journal of Intellectual Capital. 1(4), pp. 328- 340.##Van De Ven, A. H. 1986. Central problems in the management of innovation. Management science, Volume (32), pp. 590–607.##Van den Hoof, B. Ridder, D. Jan, A. 2004. Knowledge Sharing in Context: The Influence of Organizational Commitment. Journal of Knowledge Management, 8(6), pp. 117-130.##Wen, W. S. 2010. Linking Bayesian networks and PLS path modeling for causal analysis. Export Systems with Applications, Volume(37), pp. 134-139.##West, M.A. 2002, Sparkling fountains or stagnant ponds: An integrative model of creativity and innovation implementation in work groups. Applied Psychology: An International Review. Volume(51), pp. 355–387.##Yousefi, S; Moradi, M., &amp; Tishevarz, M. 2010. Role of organizational commitment in knowledge sharing. Human Development; Volume(30), pp. 23-36.##Zerenler, M., Hasiloglu, B., and Sezgin, M. 2008. Intellectual Capital and Innovation Performance: Empirical Evidence in the Turkish Automotive Supplier. Journal Oftechnology Management, 3(4), pp.31-40.##Zhang, J, Faeran, S. 2004.The Nature of Knowledge and It›s Influence on Knowledgesharing Practice: Experiences from Building the MACROS System in: Proceeding of the 38th Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences. Retrieved April 22##آزاده دل، م. فرحبد، ف. اوشک سرایی، م. صالحی کرد آبادی، س. رسا، ع. 1391. بهبود رفتارهای نوآورانه کارگران از طریق مولفه های مدیریت دانش در شرکت های تولیدی. چهارمین کنفرانس ملی مهندسی مدیریت نوآوری ایران. صص. 1-14.##پهلوانیان، ح. 1391. سرمایه فکری دارایی پنهان برای برتری در رقابت. ماهنامه مهندسی مدیریت. صص. 64-67.##تیموری، ا. نورعلی، ع. ولی زاره، ن. 1371. پویایی سیتم، رویکردی کاربردی برای مسائل مدیریتی. دانشگاه علم و صنعت ایران، چاپ دوم.##جوانمرد، م. راست خدیو، م. 1393. بررسی رابطه بین مدیریت دانش و سرمایه های فکری ناجا. فصلنامه دانش انتظامی مازندران. دوره پنجم بهار، صص.64-80.##جهانگیر، م. خوراکیان، ع. لگزان، م. 1395. بررسی تأثیر تعلق خاطر کاری بر رفتار نوآورانه با نقش میانجی به‌اشتراک‌گذاری خطاها. نشریه مدیریت نوآوری، (1)5، صص. 29-52.##چوپانی، ح. زارع خلیلی، م. قاسمی، ع. غلام زاده، ح. 1391. بررسی رابطه بین سرمایه فکری با نوآوری سازمانی (مطالعه موردی: شرکت سهامی بیمه توسعه). ابتکار و خلاقیت در علوم انسانی، (1)2، صص. 28-56.##حسن زارعی، م. 1373. خلاقیت و نوآوری. مجله دانش مدیریت، 24، صص. 59-66.##خاتمیان فر، پ. پریرخ، م. 1386. بررسی وضعیت و بسترهای به اشتراک گذاری دانش در سازمان کتابخانه های آستان قدس رضوی (در انطباق با الگوی نوناکا و تاکه اوچی). فصلنامه کتابداری آستان قدس رضوی، (4)10. ص177.##رهنورد، ف. فتحی لیواری، ر. روشن دل اربطانی، ط. 1393. شناسایی عوامل کلیدی موفقیت در اجرای راهبردهای سازمانی: مطالعه موردی مرکز صدا و سیمای آذربایجان شرقی. مدیریت بهره وری، صص. 75-94.##سید نقوی، ع. بحرالعلوم، محمد مهدی. 1387. تبیین زیرساخت های مدیریت دانش با استفاده از مدل های فرهنگ و رهبری سازمانی، مطالعات مدیریت بهبود و تحول، صص. 87-104.##صالحی، ع. دانایی فرد، ح.  1394. بررسی نقش تسهیم دانش در رابطه میان اجزای سرمایه فکری و رفتار نوآورانه .نشریات عملی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس،(1)5، صص. 109-128.##طوطی فر طهرانپور، م. ضیاء، ب. 1393. تأثیر سرمایه فکری بر نوآوری کسب وکارهای کوچک ورزشی استان تهران. مجلات علمی دانشگاه تهران،(2)7، صص. 181-199.##قزل، ع. رمضان، م. زاهدی، م. ر. 1392. ارائه چارچوب مفهومی برای اندازه گیری سرمایه ساختاری در دانشگاه. فصلنامه رشد فناوری، (37)10، صص. 53-63.##معظم باباشیخعلی، ز. کریمی، ف. کریمی، س. 1392. رابطه ساده و چندگانه بین سرمایه فکری و نوآوری سازمانی در اعضای هیأت‌علمی دانشگاه علوم پزشکی اصفهان. مجله آموزش در علوم پزشکی، (7)14. صص. 616-625.##مهدوی مزده، م. ضرغامی، ح. 1389. خلاقیت و نوآوری رمز دستیابی به راهبرد‌های رقابتی اثربخش در هزاره سوم: ارائه مدل مفهومی تعدیل یافته راهبرد-های رقابتی پورتر بر مبنای نوآوری. پنجمین کنفرانس بین المللی مدیریت راهبردی.##نصرالهی، ز. طاهری دمنه، م. دامکی، ع. م.  1388. نقش خلاقیت و نوآوری در رشد اقتصادی، دومین کنفرانس ملی خلاقیت شناسی و TRIZ##نوری بروجردی، پ. محمودی، م. هارون کلایی، ک. 1389. سنجش مدلهای کمی ارزیابی سرمایه فکری با استفاده از متغیرهای مالی. مجله حسابداری مدیریت، (5)3. صص. 31-43.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی تأثیر مدیریت دانش مشتری بر عوامل کلیدی موفقیت و عملکرد توسعه محصول جدید در حوزه فناوری صنعتی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Impact Analysis of Customer Knowledge Management (CKM) on the Critical Success Factors (CSFs)  and New Product Development Performance in Field of Industrial Technology</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>نوآوری باز متکی به منابع دانش خارج از سازمان نظیر دانش مشتری است و تاکنون در حوزه تحقیقات فناوری صنعتی به دانش مشتری توجه نشده است. همچنین، نرخ شکست محصولات فناوری صنعتی بالاست. هدف تحقیق، بررسی تأثیر مدیریت دانش مشتری بر عوامل کلیدی موفقیت محصول جدید در فناوری صنعتی و عملکرد محصول جدید است. تحقیق از نوع توصیفی و پیمایشی است. با بررسی ادبیات موضوع، مدل مفهومی و فرضیه‌ها ارائه شد. سپس برای سنجش آن‌ها پرسشنامه‌ای طراحی و پس از اعمال نظر خبرگان، توسط مشتریان محصولات فناوری صنعتی تکمیل شد. اعضای نمونه از میان مشتریان محصولات جدید این حوزه و به روش طبقه‌ای نسبتی و تصادفی انتخاب شدند. تجزیه و تحلیل نتایج آزمون فرضیه‌ها از طریق روش‌های همبستگی و معادلات ساختاری نشان داد که، مدیریت دانش مشتری (شامل سه بعد دانش «از»، «درباره» و «برای» مشتری) با عملکرد توسعه محصول جدید، و عوامل کلیدی موفقیت محصول جدید با عملکرد آن رابطه مثبت و معناداری دارد. همچنین، رابطة دانش «از» و دانش «درباره» مشتری با عوامل کلیدی موفقیت محصول جدید تأیید اما دانش «برای» مشتری تأیید نشد. یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد، بکارگیری مدیریت دانش مشتری در توسعه محصول جدید حوزه فناوری صنعتی اثرگذاری زیادی در موفقیت و ارتقای عملکرد این محصولات دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Open innovation relies on external knowledge sources such as customers, and Customer knowledge has been neglected in researches about Iranian Defense Industry. In addition, new product failure rate is high in defense industries. This study aims to investigate the impact of Customer Knowledge Management (CKM) on the Critical Success Factors (CSFs) of New Product Development and New Product Development (NPD) performance. This is a metrical and descriptive study. Considering the literature of the study, conceptual models and the hypothesis were presented. Then, in order to evaluate the models and the hypothesis, a questionnaire was designed in order to get elite&#039;s opinions about users of defense products. Using relative categorized method, the sample members were selected among the users of new defense products. The analysis of the data through Structural Equation Modeling (SEM) showed that there is a positive and significant correlation between customer knowledge management (knowledge from, about and for customer) with performance of the new product development and critical sources factors. Also the relation between the knowledge “from and the knowledge “about” with critical Success factors was confirmed, but the knowledge “for” customers was not confirmed. The results show that applying customer management knowledge in the process of developing new defense products has a great impact on successes and performance promotion of new product.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>135</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>164</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شایسته</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shayeste</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه آزاد علوم تحقیقات، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه آزاد علوم تحقیقات، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>kiarash.shayan@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جلیلیان</Family>
						<NameE>Hosein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jalilian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>h.jalilian70@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>ابوطالب</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شفقت</Family>
						<NameE>Abootaleb</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shafaghat</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دکتری مدیریت سیاست گذاری علم و فناوری دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دکتری مدیریت سیاست گذاری علم و فناوری دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email></Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت دانش؛ دانش مشتری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>محصول جدید</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فناوری صنعتی مقیاس</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abramson, G.,1999. All Along the Watchtower, CIO Enterprise, Section 2, pp. 24-34.##Al-Ghassani, A., Kamara, J., Anumba, C. and Carrillo, P., 2004. An innovative approach to identifying knowledge management problems, Engineering, Construction and Architectural Management, 11(5), pp. 349-357.##Blosch, M., 2000. Customer knowledge. Knowledge and Process Management. 7(4): 265 -268.##Booz, A., Hamilton. 1982. New Product Management for 1980s. Booz Allen &amp; Hamilton Inc, New York.##Brown, S.L., K.M. Eisenhardt. 1995. Product Development: Past Research, Present Findings, and Future Directions. Acad. Management Rev. Volume (20), pp. 343–378.##Bose R., Sugumaran V., 2003. Application of Knowledge Management Technology in Customer Relationship Management. Knowledge and Process Management, 10(1), pp. 3-17.##Bullen, C. V., &amp; Rockart, j. F. 1981. A primer on critical success factors. Cambridge, MA: Center for information Systems Research MIT.##Campbell, A. J., 2003. Creating Customer Knowledge Competence: Managing Customer Relationship Management Programs Strategically.  Industrial Marketing Management, 32(5), pp. 375-383.##Chan, S.L., Ip, W.H., 2011. A dynamic decision support system to predict the value of customer for new product development. Decision Support Systems, Volume (52), pp. 178–188.##Chen, J., Zhu, Z., and Xie, H.Y. 2004.  Measuring Intellectual Capital: A New Model and Empirical Study. Journal of Intellectual Capital, 5(1), pp. 195-207.##Chesbrough, H., 2003. Open Innovation: The New Imperative for Creating and Profiting from Technology, Boston: Harvard Business School Press.##Cooper, R.G., 1990. Stage-gate systems: a new tool for managing new products , Business Horizons, Available at: www. Stage-gate systems.co.##Cooper, R. G.1997. The dimensions of industrial new product success and failure, Journal of Marketing; 43(3). 93-103.##Cooper, R.G. Edgett, S.J. Kleinschmidt, E.J., 2004. Benchmarking Best NPD Part 1, Research-Technology Management, 47(1), pp. 31-43.##Davenport, T. H., Harris, J., G. and Kohli, A. K. 2001. How Do They Know Their Customers So Well? Sloan Management Review, 42 (1), pp. 63-73.##Day, G.S., 2000.Managing Market Relationships.Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, Volume(289), pp. 24-30.##Desouza, K., Awazu, Y. 2005. What do they know? Business Strategy Review, spring, pp.42-45.##Dous, M., Kolbe , L., Salomann , H. and Brenner , W. 2005. Knowledge Management Capabilities in CRM Knowledge Management Capabilites: Making Knowledge for, from and about Customers Work. In Proceedings of the eleventh Americas conference on information systems Omaha. NE, USA.##Drummond, G., Ensor, J., 2001.  Strategic Marketing Planning and Control. 2nd Ed. Butterworth-Heinemann.##Feng, T., Tian, J. 2005. Customer Knowledge Management and Condition Analysis of Successful CKM Implementation. Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Machine Learning and Cybernetics. Guanghou, August. 18-21.##Garcia, M., &amp; Annabi, H.2002. Customer Knowledge Management. Journal  of Operational Research Society. p.53.##Garrido-Moreno, A. and Padilla-Meléndez, A. 2011. Analyzing the Impact of Knowledge Managementon CRM Success: The Mediating Effects of Organizational Factors. International Journal of Information Management, 31 (6), pp.437-444##Gebert, H., Geib, M., Kolbe, L. and Brenner, W. 2003. Knowledge-enabled Customer Relationship Management: Integrating Customer Relationship Management and Knowledge Management Concepts. Journal of Knowledge Management, 7 (5), pp. 107-123##Gebert, H., Geib, M., Kolbe, L., &amp; Riempp, G., 2002, Towards customer knowledge management: integrating customer relationship management and knowledge management concepts, Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Electronic Business, pp. 286-98.##Gibbert M., Leibold M., Probst G., 2002, Five Styles of Customer Knowledge Management, and How Smart Companies Use them to Create Value. European Management Journal, 20(5).##Gonzalez, F.J.M., Palacios, T.M.B.,2002. The Effect of New Product Development Techniques on New Product Success in Spanish Firms, Industrial Marketing Management, Volume (31), pp.261-271.##Green, D.H. Barclay, D.W. Ryans, A.B., 1995. Entry Strategy and Long-Term Performance: Conceptualization and Empirical Examination, Journal of Marketing, 59(4), pp. 1-16.##Gruner, K. E., &amp; Homburg, C., 2000.  Does Customer Interaction Enhance New Product Success? Journal of Business Research, 49(1), pp. 1-14.##Guo, Y. c., 2007. Researches on know ledge-Enabled customer Relationship management in Electric Power Enterprises. Internal Journal of Business and Management.##Jashapara, A., 2004. Knowledge Management: An Integrated Approach. Prentice Hall, pp. 18-24.##Kanter, R., 1998. When a thousand flowers bloom: Structural, collective and social conditions for innovation in organizations, Research in Organizational Behavior, 10, JAI Press,Greenwich, CT, pp.169.##Khalil, T., 2000. Management of technology McGraw-Hill.##Kohlbacher, F., 2008. Knowledge-based marketing: building and sustaining competitive advantage through knowledge co-creation. Int. J. Management and Decision Making, 9(6).##Kotler, P., and Armstrang, G., 2015.  Marketing Principles. 16th Edition.##Kridan, A.B., Goulding, J.S., 2006. A case study on Knowledge Management implementation in banking sector, The Journal of Information and Knowledge Management Systems, 36 (2), pp.211-222.##Lee, M., Dohyeong, N., 1994. Determinants of Technical Success in Product Development when Innovative Radicalness is Considered. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 11(1). pp. 62-68.##Lin, Y., Su, H.-Y. &amp; Chien, S.,2006. A Knowledge-enabled Procedure for Customer Relationship Management. Industrial Marketing Management, Volume (35), pp. 446-456##Maital, S. and Sehadri, D., 2007. Innovation management Sage publications.##McNally, R.C. Akdeniz, M.B. Calantone, R.J., 2011. New Product Development Processes and New Product Profitability: Exploring the Mediating Role of Speed to Market and Product Quality  Journal of Product Innovation Management, 28(1), pp. 63-77.##Morel, L. and Boly, V., 2006. Innovation process evaluation : From self -assessment to detailed technological audit.##Morris, L., 2006. permanent innovation Oxford university press.##MU,Y., Peny,G., Tan,Y. 2007. New product development in Chinese enterprise key successes factors managerial prospective. International Journal of Emerging Marketing, 2(2), pp. 723-143.##Murillo G., Annabi H.2002. Customer Knowledge Management. Journal of the Operational Research Society, Volume (53), pp. 875-84.##Ozer, M., 2006. New product development in Asia: An introduction to the special issu. Industrial Marketing Management, Volume (35), pp. 252–261.##Parry, M. E., &amp; Song, X.M., 1994. Identifying new product successes in China, Journal of Product Innovation, 11(1). pp. 15-30.##Poolton, J., Barclay, I. 1998. New Product Development from Past Research to Future Applications. Industrial Marketing Management, 27(3), 197-212.##Quinn, R. E. 1985. The Transformation of Organization Culture. Sabe,.##Quintas, P., Lefrere, P, &amp; Jones, G.,1997. Knowledge Management: A Strategy Agenda, Journal of Long Range Planning, 30(3), p. 385.##Radfar, R., Rezaei-Malek, N., 2012.  Improving Performance of Customer Relationship Management##through Applying Knowledge Management. International Journal of Management Business Research, 2 (2), pp. 136- 150.##Rainey, L. D., 2005. Product Innovation: Leading Change through Integrated Product Development. Cambridge University Press, New York.##Rezvani, Z., 2009.  New Product Development based on Customer Knowledge Management, Master s thesis, Lulea University of Technology, Department of Business Administration and Social Sciences.##Rockart, J.F., 1979.  Chief Executives Define Their Own Data Needs. Harvard Business Review, 57(2), pp. 238-241.##Roper, S. Du, J. Love, J.H., 2008. Modeling the Innovation Value Chain, Research Policy, 37(6/7),  pp.961-977.##Rollins M., Halinen A., 2005.  Customer Knowledge Management Competence: Towards a Theoretical Framework. In Proceedings of the 38th Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences;pp. 1–10.##Rowley J.,2002. Eight Enhancing Questions for Customer Knowledge Management in e-Business. Journal of Knowledge Management; 6(5), pp.500-511.##Sakhaee, N., Shahbaznezhad H., ShamiZanjani M., 2009.  A Comprehensive Model for Customer Knowledge Management Mechanisms. Available at SSRN 2660769, 2012.##Sakrani, H., Bogue, j., Butt, T., 2013. New Prouct Development and Customer Knowledge Management in Pakistan Firms: an Exploratory Study of Processes and Activities. Available at http://pakacademicsearch.com/journals/516/4/14.##Saraph, J. V., Benson, P. G., and Schroeder, R. G., 1989.  An Instrument for Measuring the Critical Factors of Quality Management. Decision Sciences, 20(4).##Schmidt, J.B. and Calantone, R.J., 2002. Escalation of Commitment During New Product Development, Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, 30(2), pp.103-118.##Shami Zanjani M., Rouzbehani R., Dabbagh H., 2008. Proposing a Conceptual Model of Customer Knowledge Management: A Study of CKM Tools in British Dotcoms. International Journal of Social, Behavioral, Educational, Economic, Business and Industrial Engineering, 2(2).##Sofianti, T.D., Suryadi, K., Govindaraju, R., Prihartono, B., 2010. Customer Knowledge Co-creation Process in New Product Development, Proceedings of the World Congress on Engineering. Vol I WCE 2010, June 30 - July 2, 2010, London, U.K.##Su C. T., Chen Y. H., Sha D. Y. 2006. Linking Innovative Product Development with Customer Knowledge: A Data-mining Approach. Technovation, 26(7), pp.784–795.##Sveiby, K. E. 1997.  The New Organizational Wealth, Managing and Measuring Knowledge-Based Assets. Berrett-Koehler Publishers Inc.##Tonsu, C. &amp; Chen, C. 2006. Linking Invasive Product Development with Customer Knowledge: A Data- mining Approach, www.emeraldinsight.com##Taylor, a., &amp; Greve, H., 2006. Superman or the fantastic four? Knowledge combination and experience in innovative team. Academy of Management Journal, Volume (49), pp.23-40.##Von Hippel, E. A.1976. Has a customer already developed your next product?. Working papers from Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), Sloan School of Management.##Twiss, B., 1986. Managing Technological Innovation 3th Edition, London: Longman-Pitman.##Willaert, S.S.A., Graaf, R.D. and Minderhoud, S.,1998. Collaborative Engineering: A Case Study of Concurrent Engineering in a Wider Context, Journal of Engineering and Technology Management, 15(1), pp. 87-109.##ابراهیمیان، ب.، کاملی، ب.، 1395، رابطه مدیریت دانش و خلاقیت کارکنان و ارائه راهکارهای آن (مطالعه موردی در یک سازمان دفاعی)، مطالعات مدیریت بر آموزش نظامی، سال نهم، شماره دوم.##اقدسی، م.، رنجبرفرد، م.، 1388. سنجش سطح بلوغ مدیریت دانش مشتری در شرکت‌های بیمه ایران، فصلنامه صنعت بیمه، سال بیست و چهارم، شماره 1 و 2، صص. 24-3.##امیری اقطاعی، ر.، تیمورپور، ب.، 1391. طراحی مدل ساختاری مدیریت دانش مشتری بانک با استفاده از مدل‌سازی ساختاری مسیری، پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی، دوره 4، شماره 3، صص.22-1.##امینی، آ.، انعامی علمداری، س.، 1389. مدیریت دانش و راهبرد نوآوری در سازمان‌های دفاعی، فصلنامه تخصصی علوم سیاسی، شماره دهم، صص. 90-73.##برادران قهفرحی، پ.، زعفریان، ر.، مهدوی،م.، 1389. بکارگیری فناوری دومنظوره در فرآیند توسعه محصول جدید صنایع دفاعی، اولین کنفرانس سالانه مدیریت، نوآوری و کارآفرینی##‌برزین‌پور، ف.، اخوان، پ.، قمی، ح.، 1393. شناسایی، اولویت‌بندی و سنجش میزان استفاده از ابزارهای مناسب مدیریت دانش در فرآیندهای دانشی دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)، شماره 55، سال یازدهم، صص. 71-47.##جعفری خانشیر، س.، رادفر، ر.، حسنوی، ر.، 1391. تبیین کارکردهای مدیریت فناوری در توسعه محصول جدید با روش تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی، نشریه علمی- پژوهشی مدیریت نوآوری، شماره 1، صص. 60-41.##جلال‌پور، ح.، 1393. بومی سازی چرخه مدیریت دانش در سازمان‌های نظامی- دفاعی (مطالعه موردی ستاد فرماندهی نیروی زمینی ارتش جمهوری اسلامی ایران)، کنفرانس ملی مدیریت و فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات.##حاجی‌کرمی، ع.، منصوریان، ت.، 1391. بررسی و تبیین مدیریت دانش مشتری در بهبود عملکرد سازمانی. کاوش‌های مدیریت بازرگانی، سال چهارم، شماره 8، صص. 92-75.##‌حورعلی، م.، منتظری، ع. و الیاسی، م.، 1394. شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی اصول مورد نیاز برای بهبود فضای نوآوری بنگاه‌های دفاعی ایران با رویکرد نوآوری باز، نشریه علمی- پژوهشی مدیریت نوآوری، سال چهارم، شماره 2، صص. 86-57.##خزائی، س.، 1384. ترجمه و گزارش مدیریت دانش در عرصه نظامی، موسسه آموزشی و تحقیقاتی صنایع دفاعی، مرکز آینده‌پژوهی علوم و فناوری دفاعی، معاونت اطلاع‌رسانی و خدمات علمی.##دادور، س.، منطقی، م. و باقری، ا. 1394. ارائه مدلی مشتمل بر عامل‌های کلیدی موفقیت برای همکاری میان دانشگاه‌ها و صنایع دفاعی کشور، نشریه علمی- پژوهشی مدیریت نوآوری، سال چهارم، شماره 1، صص. 52-25.##دانش‌کهن، ح.، الیاسی، م.، پیله‌وری، ن. و طباطبایی بافقی، س.، 1394. بررسی و اولویت‌بندی عوامل کلیدی موفقیت نوآوری در صنعت پهباد ایران، نشریه علمی- پژوهشی مدیریت نوآوری، سال چهارم، شماره 4، صص. 130-107.##دهقانی پوده، ح.، اخوان، پیمان.، حسینی خوش، سید مهدی.، 1392. افزایش موفقیت توسعه محصول جدید مبتنی بر رویکرد نوآوری باز (مطالعه موردی در یک سازمان پژوهشی). نشریه مدیریت نوآوری، سال دوم، شماره 2. صص. 68-45.##دیواندری، ع.، محمدیان، م.، شامی زنجانی، م.، عابدی، ا.، 1393. تدوین و تبیین چارچوب استقرار مدیریت دانش مشتری در بانک‌های تجاری خصوصی ایران. مدیریت بازرگانی، دوره6، شماره 1، صص. 66-41.##رضایی، ب.، خیراندیش، م.، 1392. تأثیر شایستگی‌های اجتماعی افسران بر موفقیت مدیریت دانش، فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی، شماره 49، سال سیزدهم، صص. 106-79.##رضائی، م.، کراری، ح.، مصطفوی، ل.، 1387. مدیریت دانش در توسعه محصول جدید، هفتمین همایش مراکز تحقیق و توسعه صنایع و معادن.##رضوانی، ح.، رشیدایی آبندانسری، ا.، 1392. بررسی مهمترین عوامل درون و برون سازمانی مؤثر بر عملکرد محصول جدید در صنایع غذایی، فصلنامه علمی- پژوهشی تحقیقات بازاریابی نوین، شماره 10، صص. 58-39.##سازمان صنایع دفاع ایران.، 1392. نظامنامه مدیریت پروژه.##‌سری‌نیواسان، ن. س.، نارایانا، و.، 2009. مدیریت نوآوری صنعتی (مفاهیم و اقدامات)، ترجمه کیانا، و.، ملکی‌فر، ع.، بوشهری، ع.، وحیدی مطلق، و.، مؤسسه آموزشی تحقیقاتی صنایع دفاعی.##سعیدا اردکانی، س.، طالعی‌فر، ر.، حاتمی‌نسب، س.، محمدی، ف، 1390. بررسی و رتبه‌بندی عوامل و مولفه‌های توسعه محصول جدید (مطالعه دیدگاه مدیران SMEs واقعی در صنایع غذایی و آشامیدنی استان فارس)، تحقیقات بازاریابی نوین، سال اول، شماره اول، صص 126-101.##سلطانی، م.، نیکوکار، غ.، دارابی، د.، 1393. انتخاب مدل مناسب مدیریت دانش برای یکی از سازمان‌های تحقیقاتی نظامی، مدیریت بازرگانی، دوره 6، شماره 3، صص. 554-535.##‌سهرابی، ب.، دارمی، ه. 1390. مدیریت دانش، تهران، انتشارات سمت، صص. 58-67.##سیدحسینی، س.، ایرانبان، سیدجواد.، 1383. راهبرد توسعه محصول جدید: رویکردها و یافته‌ها، دانش مدیریت، شماره 64، صص. 105-81.##سیدنقوی، م.، خانی پردنجانی، س.، علیزاده، ح.، 1391. سرمایه‌های فکری و مدیریت دانش: پژوهشی در سازمان‌های دانش‌بنیان، نشریه علمی- ترویجی منابع انسانی ناجا، سال هفتم، شماره 30، صص. 158-131.##شامی زنجانی، م.، نجف‌لو، ف.، 1390. ارائه چارچوب مفهومی برای نوع‌شناسی دانش مشتری، مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دوره 3، شماره 9، صص. 189-163.##شلینگ، ملیسا. ا.، 1387. مدیریت استراتژیک نوآورى تکنولوژی ”، چاپ اول، ترجمه محمد اعرابى و محمد تقى زاده مطلق، . تهران: دفتر پژوهش‌هاى فرهنگى.##شهلائی، ن.، 1390. ارائه الگوی مناسب شکل‌گیری سازمان‌های یادگیرنده در ارتش جمهوری اسلامی ایران، فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی، سال یازدهم، شماره 41، صص. 42-11.##صادقی، منصور.، صادقی، علیرضا.، 1392. تحلیل مدل عوامل برون‌سازمانی مؤثر در توسعه نوآوری سازمان‌های پژوهشی صنعتی، نشریه مدیریت نوآوری، سال دوم، شماره 1. صص. 20-1.##طالبی، ک.، سلیمی ترکمانی، م.، زارع، هادی.، 1389، شناسایی و اولویت‌بندی عوامل اساسی موفقیت در توسعه محصول جدید در کسب و کارهای کوچک و متوسط مستقر در پارک علم و فناوری تهران، فصلنامه اقتصاد و تجارت نوین، شماره‌های 19 و 20، صص 100-83.##عارفی‌نیا، ج.، 1391. بررسی و مقایسه مدل‌های مدیریت دانش و ارائه یک مدل تلفیقی جهت مدیریت دانش پلیسی، دانش انتظامی، خراسان رضوی، صص. 188-153.##عبدی، ف.، 1389. بررسی رابطه بین دو دسته عوامل سازمانی (ساختار و فرهنگ) با مدیریت دانش در دانشگاه افسری امام علی(ع)، فصلنامه مدیریت نظامی، شماره 39، صص. 130-109.##عصاری، م.، حسینی شکیب، م.، خمسه، ع.، 1394. رتبه‌بندی عوامل کلیدی موفقیت توسعه محصول جدید و ارائه راهکارهای بهبود در صنایع دفاعی، کنفرانس بین‌المللی اقتصاد، حسابداری، مدیریت و علوم اجتماعی.##فرهنگی، ع.، میرا، س.، 1390. ارائه الگوی مفهومی کسب بازخور مشتریان در رویکرد مدیریت دانش مشتریان، مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دوره 3، شماره 9، صص. 138-107.##فیروزشاهی، م.، نورنگ، ا.، احمدوند، ع.، تربتی، ا.، ارسنجانی، م.، 1391. ارائه الگویی فرآیندی- عملیاتی به منظور اجرای نظام مدیریت دانش در سازمان‌های دفاعی- نظامی، فصلنامه راهبرد دفاعی، سال دهم، شماره 36، صص. 139-105.##کاتلر، فیلیپ.ف.، آرمسترانگ، گری.، 1395. اصول بازاریابی، ترجمه فروزنده، بهمن. اصفهان، انتشارات آموخته##کاظمی، ر. م.، خوانساری شامخ، ن.، حسین‌پور، د.، 1394، عوامل حیاتی موفقیت توسعه محصول جدید در صنعت پوشاک، مطالعات مدیریت ورزشی، شماره 34، صص. 36-17.##کزازی، ا.، طباطبائیان، س.، امیری، مقصود. و شیرازی شایسته، م.، 1393. بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر شکل‌گیری و توسعه خوشه بالگرد کشور، نشریه علمی- پژوهشی مدیریت نوآوری، سال سوم، شماره 1، صص. 45-23.##مانیان، ا.، اصغری‌زاده، ع.، و دهقان بنادکی،م. 1390. نقش مدیریت دانش در عملکرد فرآیند توسعه محصول جدید (پژوهشی پیرامون شرکت‌های SME صنعت نرم‌افزار استان یزد)، مدیریت فناوری اطلاعات، دوره 3 شماره 8، صص. 150-133.##محمدی فاتح، ا.، جوکار، ع.، 1390، استقرار مدیریت دانش در نیروهای مسلح؛ ارائه موردکاوی تطبیقی از صنایع هوافضای کشورهای دیگر، مدیریت نظامی، شماره 44، سال یازدهم‌، صص. 158-123.##محمدی فاتح، ا.، شرفی‌نژاد، ن.، دهبان، ا.، 1393. چرخه مدیریت دانش در سازمان‌ها، تهران، موسسه کتاب مهربان نشر##مرکز مدیریت دانش ودجا.، 1393. نظام‌نامه مدیریت دانش دفاعی، صص. 21-20.##موسی‌خانی، م.، حقیقی،م.، ترک‌زاده، س.، 1391. ارائه مدلی جهت کسب وفاداری مشتری با استفاده از مدیریت دانش مشتری در صنعت بانکداری کشور، مدیریت بازرگانی، دوره 4، شماره 12.##مینایی، ح.، حاجیانی، ا.، دهقان بوده، ح.، جعفرزاده‌پوز، ف.، 1393. ارزیابی اثر فرآیندهای مدیریت دانش در فعالیت‌های دیپلماسی دفاعی جمهوری اسلامی ایران، نشریه راهبرد، شماره 70، سال بیست و سوم، صص. 60-39.##نظری زاده، ف.، 1391. مدل‌ها و عوامل موفقیت نوآوری، موسسه آموزشی و تحقیقاتی صنایع دفاعی.##ونوس، د.، روستا، ا.، ابراهیمی، ع.، 1393. مدیریت بازاریابی، انتشارات سمت.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				