<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1398</YEAR>
<VOL>8</VOL>
<NO>2</NO>
<MOSALSAL>28</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>200</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>آزادی اقتصادی و فعالیت های کارآفرینانه نوآورانه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Economic Freedom and Innovative Entrepreneurial Activity</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف از انجام تحقیق حاضر، بررسی تأثیر آزادی اقتصادی بر سطح فعالیت های کارآفرینانه در 17 کشور نوآوری محور، طی سال های 2005 تا 2014، می باشد. در این پژوهش از داده های استاندارد آزادی اقتصادی موسسه فریزر، و داده های کارآفرینی دیده بان جهانی کارآفرینی، استفاده گردید و داده ها پانلی در محیط نرم افزار Eveiws9 و Stata14، به روش تخمین حداقل مربعات تعمیم یافته و حداقل مربعات معمولی تجزیه و تحلیل شد. نتایج بدست آمده از این پژوهش، نشان می دهد، آزادی اقتصادی رابطه معناداری با سطح فعالیت های کارآفرینانه دارد و از بین شاخص های مورد بررسی، بیش ترین میزان تأثیر بر سطح فعالیت کارآفرینانه نوآورانه در 17 کشور نوآوری محور، توسط شاخص آزادی تجارت خارجی، تنظیم قوانین و مقررات و امنیت حقوق مالکیت برآورد شده است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effect of economic freedom on the level of entrepreneurial activity in 17 innovative countries, from 2005 to 2014. In this study, we used the standard Fraser Economic Freedom Data and Entrepreneurship Global Monitor Entrepreneurship data. The panel data was analyzed in the Eviews9 and Stata14 software environment by generalized least squares estimation and ordinary least squares. The results of this research show that economic freedom has a significant relation with the level of entrepreneurial activity Among the indicators surveyed, the most impact on the level of innovative entrepreneurial activity in 17 innovative countries has been estimated by the Foreign Trade Freedom Index, regulation of rules and regulations, and security of property rights.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>20</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شهین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بهور</Family>
						<NameE>Shahin</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Behvar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت کارآفرینی، دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناسی ارشد مدیریت کارآفرینی، دانشگاه رازی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>s.behvar94@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نادر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نادری</Family>
						<NameE>Nader</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Naderi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار گروه مدیریت و کارآفرینی دانشگاه رازی،ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار گروه مدیریت و کارآفرینی دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>n.naderi@razi.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شهرام</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فتاحی</Family>
						<NameE>Shahram</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Fattahi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار و عضو هیئت‌علمی گروه اقتصاد دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار و عضو هیئت‌علمی گروه اقتصاد دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sh_fatahi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آزادی اقتصادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کسب و کارهای کارآفرینانه نوآورانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aghion, P., &amp; Howitt, P., 1992. A model of growth through creative destruction. Econometrica, 60(2), pp. 323-352.##Anokhin, S., &amp; Schulze, W. S., 2009. Entrepreneurship, innovation, and corruption. Journal of business venturing, 24(5), pp. 465-476.‏##Baumol, W., 1993. Entrepreneurship, management, and the structure of payoffs. Cambridge: MIT Press.##Bradley. S.W and Klein. P.G.,2016. Institutions, Economic Freedom, and Entrepreneurship: The Contribution of Management Scholarship. Academy of Management Executive 30(3), pp. 211-221.##Chari, M. D. &amp; Dixit, J., 2015. Business groups and entrepreneurship in developing countries after reforms, Journal of Business Research, 68(6), pp. 1359- 1366.##Dereli, D. D., 2015. Innovation management in global competition and competitive advantage. Procedia-Social and behavioral sciences, Volume (195), pp. 1365-1370.‏##Dutz, M.A., Ordover, J.A. &amp; Willig, R.D.,2000. Entrepreneurship, access policy and economic development: lessons from industrial organization, European Economic Review, 44 (4), pp. 739-747.##Doran.J, McCarthy.N, O’Connor.M .,2018. The role of entrepreneurship in stimulating  economic growth in developed and developingcountries. Cogent Economics &amp; Finance (2018), Volume (6), 1442093##Friedman, M., 1962. Capitalism and freedom. Chicago: University of Chicago Press.##Friedman, B. A., 2011. The relationship between governance effectiveness and entrepreneurship, International Journal of Humanities and Social Science, 1(17), pp. 221- 225.##Ferreira, J. J., Fayolle, A., Fernandes, C., &amp; Raposo, M.,2017. Effects of Schumpeterian and Kirznerian entrepreneurship on economic growth: Panel data evidence. Entrepreneurship &amp; Regional Development, Volume (29), pp. 27–50. https://doi.org/10.1080/08985626.2016.1255431.##Henrekson, Magnus., 2005. Entrepreneurship: A Weak Link in the Welfare State? Industrial and Corporate Change 14 (3), pp. 437-467.##Hernán Herrera-Echeverri, Jerry Haar, Juan Benavides Estévez-Bretón., 2013. Foreign direct investment, institutional quality, economic freedom and entrepreneurship in emerging markets. Journal of Business Research Volume (73), pp. 11-20.##Hidalgo, A., &amp; Albors, J., 2008. Innovation management techniques and tools: a review from theory and practice. R&amp;d Management, 38(2), 113-127.‏##Global Entrepreneurship Monitor., 2017. Total early-stage Entrepreneurial Activity (TEA). Data retrieved August 20, 2014, from: Key Indicators. http://www.gemconsortium.org/Data.##Johnson.S &amp; McMillan. J &amp; Woodruff. CH., 2002.  American Economic Association. The American Economic Review, Vol. 92, No. 5, pp. 1335-1356.##Kahn, K. B., 2018. Understanding innovation. Business Horizons, 61(3), 453-460.‏##Kuckertz. A, Berger. E.S.C, Mpeqa.A.,2016.The more the merrier? Economic freedom and entrepreneurial activity. Journal of Business Research. 69(4):1288-1293 · April 2016.##McMullen, J. S., Bagby, D. &amp; Palich, L. E., 2008. Economic freedom and the motivation to engage in entrepreneurial action, Entrepreneurship Theory and Practice, 32(5): 875- 895.##Reynolds Paul D. and Curtin Richard T.,2008. BusinessCreation in the United State: Panel Study of Entreprenurial.##Segerstrom, P.S, Anent, T.C.A., &amp; Dinopoulos, E., 1990. A Schumpeterian model of the product life cycle. American Economic Review, 80 (5), pp. 1077-1091.##Sobel, R. S., Clark, J. R. &amp; Lee, D. R., 2007. Freedom, barriers to entry, entrepreneurship, and economic progress, The Review of Austrian Economics, 20(4), pp. 221- 236.##Schumpeter, J.A. ,1911. The theory of economic development. Cambridge: Harvard University Press.## Schumpeter, J.A. ,1942. Capitalism, socialism, and democracy. London: Harper Perennial.##Stam, E., &amp; Nooteboom, B.,2011. 26 Entrepreneurship, innovation and institutions. Handbook of research on innovation and entrepreneurship, 421.‏##Wiseman, T., &amp; Young, A. T., 2013. Economic Freedom, Entrepreneurship, &amp; Income Levels: Some US State-Level Empirics. American Journal of Entrepreneurship, 6(1).‏##Wikhamn, W., 2019. Innovation, sustainable HRM and customer satisfaction. International Journal of Hospitality Management, Volume (76), pp. 102-110.‏##جعفری صمیمی، احمد، آملی دیوا، کبری.،1389. بررسیرابطهآزادسازیاقتصادیباکاراییدولتدرکشورهایمنطقهخاورمیانهوشمالافریقا، فصلنامه پژوهشنامه اقتصادی، سال دهم، شماره چهارم، صص 15-37.##حافظ نیا، محمدرضا.،1380. مقدمه­ایبرروشتحقیقدرعلومانسانی، تهران، انتشارات سمت.##حیرانی، حسین، قدسی­پور، سیدحسن، باقری­مقدم، ناصر، کریمیان، حسن.،1393. تحلیل پویای کارکردی-ساختاری توسعه فناوری در چارچوب نظام نوآوری فناورانه؛ موردمطالعه: فناوری تولید هم‌زمان برق و حرارت، فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه فناوری، دوره دوم، شماره 2، صص 49-80.##خلیلی­عراقی، سیدمنصور، گودرزی­فراهانی، یزدان.،1392. حقوق مالکیت فکری بر رشد اقتصادی، دوفصلنامه دانشنامه حقوق اقتصادی (دانش و توسعه سابق)، دوره جدید سال نوزدهم، شماره 4، صص 1-27.##زالی، محمدرضا، رضوی، سیدمصطفی، یدالهی، جهانگیر و کردنائیج، اسدالله.،1389. ارزیابیوضعیتکارآفرینیدرایران، چاپ اول، تهران، مؤسسه کار و تأمین اجتماعی.##مرکز پژوهش مجلس شورای اسلامی.، 1390. بررسی و نقد شاخص­های جهانی آزادی اقتصادی(بنیاد هریتیج و موسسه فریزر). تهران.##میرجلیلی، سیدحسین.،1386. آموزه­های مکتب تاریخی برای تحلیل اقتصاد ایران، فصلنامه پژوهشنامه اقتصادی، شماره 26، صص 43-76.##هاشم­زاده، ابراهیم؛ حاجی­حسینی، حجت­الله؛ رادفر، رضا؛ ملک­زاده، کرامت.،1393. عوامل مؤثر در ایجاد توانمندی­های نوآوری (مطالعه موردی یک مرکز پژوهشی صنعت هوایی در ایران). فصلنامه مدیریت نوآوری، سال سوم، شماره 1، صص 75-100.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>ارائه چارچوب نهادی برای افزایش اثربخشی نقش دولت و بخش عمومی در ارتقای توان فناورانه تولیدات داخلی: مطالعه موردی قانون حداکثر استفاده از توان داخل</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Proposing an Institutional Framework to Increase the Effectiveness of Government and Public’s role in enhancing Technological Capacity of Internal Productions: A Case Study of the Maximal use of internal capabilities law</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>تجربه جهانی نشان می‌دهد که سیاست‌گذاران توسعه چه در کشورهای درحال‌توسعه و چه در کشورهای توسعه‌یافته همواره از اهرم بازار داخلی برای ارتقای توانمندی فناورانه کشورهای خود به‌عنوان یک ابزار سیاستی مهم و اثربخش استفاده نموده‌اند. در ایران نیز مهم‌ترین سیاست این حوزه، قانون حداکثر استفاده از توان داخل بوده است که علیرغم اصلاح نسخه اولیه در سال 1391 به نظر می‌رسد نتوانسته است نتایج اثربخشی برای اقتصاد کشور داشته باشد. در این پژوهش با بررسی پیشینه اجرای این قانون و قوانین و مقررات مرتبط و مصاحبه اولیه با کارشناسان، شش مقوله نهادی اصلی تأثیرگذار در توسعه توان داخل شناسایی و با استفاده از روش مصاحبه گروه متمرکز و تحلیل محتوای مباحثات و مصاحبه‌های انجام‌شده در شش جلسه، چارچوب نهادی توسعه توانمندی داخلی پیشنهاد شد. بر اساس تحلیل‌های انجام‌شده مهم‌ترین نواقص نهادی در کاهش اثربخشی اجرای قانون حداکثر استفاده از توان داخل، با مقولاتی نظیر اهمیت بیشتر ارجاع کامل کار به‌طرف ایرانی و الزام به ارتقای توانمندی فناورانه آن، نبود نظام تأمین مالی مقید، نبود تنظیم‌گری بخشی متناسب با اهداف توسعه توانمندی و عدم استفاده دستگاه‌های اجرایی کشور از تجمیع تقاضای عمومی برای افزایش قدرت چانه‌زنی مرتبط است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Global experience has shown that policymakers in both developing and developed countries have always used the leverage of the domestic market to enhance their country&#039;s technological capability as an important and effective policy instrument. In Iran, the most important policy in this area is the law of “maximal use of internal capabilities”, which despite the modification of the initial version in 2012, seems to have failed to have effectiveness for the economy of the country. In this study, by reviewing the history of the implementation of this law, related laws and regulations, and initial interview with experts, six main institutional categories were identified. Using the method of focus group and analyzing the content of the discussions and interviews conducted in six sessions, the institutional framework for increasing effectiveness of this kind of laws was proposed. According to the analysis, the most important institutional deficiencies in reducing the effectiveness of the law, were some issues like: the importance of a full project to Iranian companies and forcing them to improve its technological capability, the lack of a system of financing, the lack of sectoral innovation policy and regulation and lack of aggregation of public demand for increasing bargaining power.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>21</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>47</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>میثم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نریمانی</Family>
						<NameE>Meysam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Narimani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت‌علمی پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت‌علمی پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری، تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>narimani.meysam@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>الیاسی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Elyasi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی (ره)، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>elyasi.atu@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عطارپور</Family>
						<NameE>MohammadReza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Attarpour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی (ره)، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکترای مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشگاه علامه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>attarpour.mailbox@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل نهادی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خرید دولت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توسعه توانمندی فناورانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قانون حداکثر استفاده از توان داخل</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گروه متمرکز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Acheampong, T., Ashong, M. and Svanikier, V.C., 2016. An assessment of local-content policies in oil and gas producing countries. The Journal of World Energy Law &amp; Business, 9(4), pp.282-302.##Anderson, G. and Arsenault, N., 2005. Fundamentals of educational research. Routledge.##Arrowsmith, S., 2003. Transparency in government procurement: The objectives of regulation and the boundaries of the World Trade Organization. Journal of World Trade, 37(2), pp.283-303.##Blind, K., 2012. The influence of regulations on innovation: A quantitative assessment for OECD countries. Research Policy, 41(2), pp.391-400.##Campbell, J.W., 2017. Public Procurement Policy in South Korea: Approaches to Sustainable Development and Anti-Corruption. In The Experience of Democracy and Bureaucracy in South Korea (pp. 159-179). Emerald Publishing Limited.##Krueger, R.A., 2014. Focus groups: A practical guide for applied research. Sage publications.##Asiago, B., 2017. Rules of Engagement: A Review of Regulatory Instruments Designed to Promote and Secure Local Content Requirements in the Oil and Gas Sector. Resources, 6(3), p.46.##Denscombe, M., 2014. The good research guide: for small-scale social research projects. McGraw-Hill Education (UK).##Edler, J. and Georghiou, L., 2007. Public procurement and innovation—Resurrecting the demand side. Research policy, 36(7), pp.949-963.##Edquist, C., 2015. Innovation-related public procurement as a demand-oriented innovation policy instrument (No. 2015/28). Lund University, CIRCLE-Center for Innovation, Research and Competences in the Learning Economy.##Edquist, C. and Zabala-Iturriagagoitia, J.M., 2012. Public Procurement for Innovation as mission-oriented innovation policy. Research policy, 41(10), pp.1757-1769.##Erridge, A., 2007. Public procurement, public value and the Northern Ireland unemployment pilot project. Public Administration, 85(4), pp.1023-1043.##Evenett, S.J., 2004. International disciplines on government procurement: A review of economic analyses and their implications.##Fenster, G., 2003. Multilateral Talks on Transparency in Government Procurement.##Flynn, A., 2018. Investigating the implementation of SME-friendly policy in public procurement. Policy Studies, 39(4), pp.422-443.##Georghiou, L., Edler, J., Uyarra, E. and Yeow, J., 2014. Policy instruments for public procurement of innovation: Choice, design and assessment. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 86, pp.1-12.##Kale, D. and Little, S., 2007. From imitation to innovation: The evolution of R&amp;D capabilities and learning processes in the Indian pharmaceutical industry. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 19(5), pp.589-609.##Kattel, R. and Lember, V., 2010. Public procurement as an industrial policy tool: an option for developing countries?. Journal of public procurement, 10(3), pp.368-404.##Keulemans, S. and Van de Walle, S., 2017. Cost-effectiveness, domestic favouritism and sustainability in public procurement: A comparative study of public preferences. International Journal of Public Sector Management, 30(4), pp.328-341.##Khan, M.E. and Manderson, L., 1992. Focus groups in tropical diseases research. Health policy and planning, 7(1), pp.56-66.##Khor, M., 2003. Mainstreaming development in trade and finance: a key to global partnership. Development Policy Journal, 3, pp.127-150.##Korinek, J. and Ramdoo, I., 2017. Local content policies in mineral-exporting countries.##Lee, T.J., 2004. Technological learning by national R&amp;D: the case of Korea in CANDU-type nuclear fuel. Technovation, 24(4), pp.287-297.##Morettini, S., 2011. Public procurement and secondary policies in EU and global administrative law. In Global Administrative Law and EU Administrative Law (pp. 187-209). Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg.##Mu, Q. and Lee, K., 2005. Knowledge diffusion, market segmentation and technological catch-up: The case of the telecommunication industry in China. Research policy, 34(6), pp.759-783.##Naegelen, F. and Mougeot, M., 1998. Discriminatory public procurement policy and cost reduction incentives. Journal of Public Economics, 67(3), pp.349-367.##Oecd, G.O.V., 2017. Government at a Glance. Organization For Economic.##Oecd, G.O.V. 2016. The economic impact of local content requirements. Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development. Retrieved from https://www.oecd.org/tad/policynotes/economic-impact-local-content-requirements.pdf##Oecd, G.O.V, OECD in Figures, OECD, Paris.##Patton, M.Q., 1990. Qualitative evaluation and research methods. SAGE Publications, inc.##Preuss, L., 2011. On the contribution of public procurement to entrepreneurship and small business policy. Entrepreneurship &amp; Regional Development, 23(9-10), pp.787-814.##Rainey, H. G. 2014. Understanding and managing public organization (5th edEd.). San Francisco: Jossey-Bass; Pfeiffer Imprints, Wiley.##Raymond, J., 2008. Benchmarking in public procurement. Benchmarking: An International Journal, 15(6), pp.782-793.##Ruttan, V.W., 2006. Is war necessary for economic growth?:? militaryMilitary procurement and technology development. Oxford University Press.##Singh, A., 2002. Competition and competition policy in emerging markets: international and developmental dimensions. London: Edward Elgar.##Ssennoga, F., 2006. Examining discriminatory procurement practices in developing countries. Journal of Public Procurement, 6(3), pp.218-249.##Walker, H., Miemczyk, J., Johnsen, T. and Spencer, R., 2012. Sustainable procurement: Past, present and future.##Waluszewski, A., Baraldi, E. and Ciabuschi, F., 2018. Increase Development and Decrease Use! Innovation Controversies Caused by Antimicrobial Resistance. In Controversies in Healthcare Innovation (pp. 309-339). Palgrave Macmillan, London.##Wint, A.G., 1998. The role of government in enhancing the competitiveness of developing economies: Selective functional intervention in the Caribbean. International Journal of Public Sector Management, 11(4), pp.281-299.##ابراهیمی, ن. قاسمی مقدم, س. 1397. بررسی الزامات قانونی استفاده از توان داخل در صنعت بالادستی نفت‌وگاز. پژوهش حقوق عمومی. 20(59), 64-96.##بی‌تعب، ع. یقطین، ع. حسینی، م. اصغری، ا. مامی غفاری، اب. روستاآزاد، س. یقطین، م، 1389، ملزومات افزایش حجم ساخت داخل در پروژه‌ها. چاپ اول، تهران: نشر راهدان.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>سنجش کارایی نوآوری شرکت‌های چهار صنعت پیشرفته منتخب ایران، با استفاده از مدل جمعی تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Measuring Innovation Efficiency in the firms of Four High-tech Industries in Iran, Using Slack-Based DEA Model</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>امروزه بحث سیاست‌گذاری مبتنی بر شواهد و داده محور در زمینه نوآوری، روزبه‌روز اهمیت گسترده‌تری می‌یابد؛ لذا دانشمندان به این موضوع دست‌یافته‌اند که تا زمانی که داده‌های خرد و متقن از سطح شرکت‌ها، به‌منظور سنجش نوآوری آن‌ها جمع‌آوری نشده و مورد تحلیل قرار نگیرد، نمی‌توان انتظار تدوین سیاست‌های کارا و اثربخش را داشت. یکی از مهم‌ترین روش‌های سنجش نوآوری، سنجش کارایی آن است. تاکنون کارایی نوآوری، چه در سطح کلان، ملی و یا خرد و شرکت‌ها، موردسنجش قرارگرفته است ولی مدلی که با استفاده از آن بتوان پیشنهادهای بهبود برای شاخص‌های ورودی و خروجی ارائه نمود، به کار گرفته نشده است. در این پژوهش ابتدا بر مبنای ادبیات موضوع و داده‌های موجود، به‌منظور محاسبه کارایی نوآوری، شاخص‌های ورودی و خروجی مشخص شدند، سپس بر مبنای داده‌های جمع‌آوری‌شده در اولین پیمایش نوآوری ایران، کارایی نوآوری شرکت‌های چهار صنعت پیشرفته نانوتکنولوژی، بیوتکنولوژی، تولید محصولات الکترونیک، میکروالکترونیک و مخابراتی و هوافضا، با استفاده از مدل جمعی تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها، بررسی شد؛ علاوه براین نقش و اهمیت اندازه شرکت‌ها در کارایی آن‌ها مورد تحلیل قرار گرفت. نتایج حاصل از این پژوهش نشان داد که 23.72% از شرکت‌های نانوتکنولوژی، 20% از شرکت‌های تولید محصولات الکترونیک؛ میکروالکترونیک و مخابراتی، 18.33% از شرکت‌های حوزه بیوتکنولوژی و 18.18% از شرکت‌های صنعت هوافضا کارا شده‌اند. علاوه بر نوع صنعت، اندازه آن‌ها نیز تأثیر جدی در کارا بودن یا کارا نبودن شرکت‌ها داشته است؛ بدین ترتیب که در صنایع نانوتکنولوژی و هوافضا هر چه اندازه شرکت‌ها بزرگ‌تر می‌شود، درصد کمتری از آنان کارا هستند. حال‌آنکه در صنعت تولید محصولات الکترونیک؛ میکروالکترونیک و مخابراتی، درصد شرکت‌های کارای با اندازه بین 10 تا 50 نفر بیشتر از شرکت‌های با اندازه کمتر از 10 نفر و شرکت‌های با اندازه بیشتر از 50 نفر است. در صنعت بیوتکنولوژی نیز روندی کاملاً متفاوت با روند نانوتکنولوژی و هوافضا دیده می‌شود به‌این‌ترتیب که هر چه اندازه شرکت‌ها بزرگ‌تر می‌شود، درصد کارایی آن‌ها نیز افزایش می‌یابد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Nowadays, evidence-based and data-based policymaking is taken into consideration in policymaking, so policymakers understand that until they don’t analyze micro data from firms, they could not form efficient and effective policies. One of the most important ways to measuring innovation is measuring its efficency. Measuring innovation efficeincy in macro level is more usual than micro level. In this paper, first, on the basis of previous reseaches, input and output indicators were identified. Then based on first Irarnian innovation survey data, innovation efficiency of four sectors (Nanotechnology. Biotechnology, Electronic, micro electronic and Telecomunication and Aerospace) firms were calculated and analysed, using Slack based DEA model. Finally, results show that 23.27% of nanotechnology firms, 20% of Electronic, micro electronic and Telecomunication, 18.33% of Biotechnology and 18.18% of Aerospace firms were efficent. In addition, the size of the firms in each sector were effective in firms efficiency.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>49</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>76</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امیرعلی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کریمی</Family>
						<NameE>AmirAli</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Karimi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>پژوهشگر، پژوهشکده سیاست‌گذاری دانشگاه صنعتی شریف، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>پژوهشگر، پژوهشکده سیاست‌گذاری دانشگاه صنعتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.karimi@sharif.edu</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ملکی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Maleki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت‌علمی پژوهشکده سیاست‌گذاری دانشگاه صنعتی شریف، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت‌علمی پژوهشکده سیاست‌گذاری دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>a.maleki@sharif.edu</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>اسماعیل</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>عبدی</Family>
						<NameE>Esmaeel</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Abdi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>پژوهشگر، پژوهشکده سیاست‌گذاری دانشگاه صنعتی شریف، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>پژوهشگر، پژوهشکده سیاست‌گذاری دانشگاه صنعتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>abdi@sharif.edu</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارایی نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدل جمعی تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نانوتکنولوژی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>بیوتکنولوژی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>محصولات الکترونیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>میکروالکترونیک و مخابراتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>هوافضا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اندازه شرکت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abbasi, F., Hajihoseini, H. &amp; Haukka, S. 2011. Use of virtual index for measuring efficiency of innovation systems: a cross-country study. International Journal of Technology Management &amp; Sustainable Development, 9(3), pp. 195-212.##Adam, F. 2014. Measuring national innovation performance: the Innovation Union Scoreboard revisited, Springer.##Afzal, M. N. I. 2014. An empirical investigation of the National Innovation System (NIS) using Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA) and the TOBIT model. International Review of Applied Economics, 28(4), pp. 507-523.##Arundel, A. Innovation scoreboards: Promises, pitfalls and policy applications. Conference of Innovation and Enterprise Creation: Statistics and Indicators, 2001.##Cai, Y. 2011. Factors affecting the efficiency of the BRICSs&#039; national innovation systems: A comparative study based on DEA and Panel Data Analysis. Economics Discussion paper.##Cook, W. D. &amp; Seiford, L. M. 2009. Data envelopment analysis (DEA)–Thirty years on. European journal of operational research, 192(1), pp. 1-17.##Cruz-cazares, C., Bayona-Saez, C. &amp; Garcia-Marco, T. 2013. You can’t manage right what you can’t measure well: Technological innovation efficiency. Research Policy, 42(6-7), pp. 1239-1250##Diaz-Balteiro, L., Herruzo, A. C., Martinez, M. &amp; Gonzalez-Pachon, J. 2006. An analysis of productive efficiency and innovation activity using DEA: An application to Spain&#039;s wood-based industry. Forest Policy and Economics, 8(7), pp. 762-773.##Dzemydaite, G., Dzemyda, I. &amp; Galiniene, B. 2016. The efficiency of regional innovation systems in new member states of the European Union: a nonparametric DEA approach. Economics and business, 28(1), pp. 83-89.##EARL, L. 2006. National innovation, indicators and policy, Edward Elgar Publishing.##Feng, F., Wang, B., Zou, Y. &amp; Du, Y. 2013. A New Internet DEA Structure: Measurementof Chinese R&amp;D Innovation Efficiency in High Technology Industry. International Journal of Business and Management, 8(21), p. 32.##Guan, J. &amp; Chen, K. 2012. Modeling the relative efficiency of national innovation systems. Research policy, 41(1),pp. 102-115.##Hsu, Y. 2011. Cross national comparison of innovation efficiency and policy application. African Journal of Business Management, 5(4), pp. 1378-1387.##Junwen 2016. A Research on the Evaluation of the Operating Efficiency and Innovation Efficiency of China’s Development Zones Based on Panel Data. Canadian Social Science, 12,pp. 13-19.##Mogha, S. K., Yadav, S. P. &amp; Singh, S. 2015. Slack based measure of efficiencies of public sector hospitals in Uttarakhand (India). Benchmarking: An International Journal, 22(7), pp. 1229-1246.##Revilla, E., Sarkis, J. &amp; Modrego, A. 2003. Evaluating performance of public–private research collaborations: A DEA analysis. Journal of the Operational Research Society, 54(2), pp. 165-174.##Xu, X. &amp; QI, L. 2015. Evaluation Research of Innovation Efficiency of the Equipment Manufacturing Industry Based On Super Efficiency DEA and Malmquist Index. International Journal of Hybrid Information Technology, 8(4), pp. 27-34.##دانش کهن، ح. الیاسی، م. پیله‌وری، ن. و طباطبایی بافقی، س. م.، 1394. بررسی و اولویت‌بندی عوامل کلیدی موفقیت نوآوری در صنعت پهپاد ایران. مدیریت نوآوری (4)4، صص. 107-130.##رحیمی راد، ز. یحیی زاده فر، م. میرعمادی، ط. و مدهوشی، م.، 1396. تحلیل نظام نوآوری فناورانه سیستم‌های خورشیدی فتوولتاییک در ایران. مدیریت نوآوری، 6(4)، صص 1-28.##پاکزادبناب، ب. طباطباییان، س.ح.، 1385. بررسی سیستم‌های سنجش نوآوری و ارائه چارچوبی برای سنجش نوآوری در ایران. پژوهش‌های مدیریت در ایران، 10(1)، صص. 161-190.##مهرگان، م.، 1391 . تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها مدل‌های کمی در ارزیابی عملکرد سازمان‌ها. نشر کتاب دانشگاه، صص. 99-120##میرغفوری، س.ح. شفیعی‌رودپشتی، م. ندافی، غ.، 1390. مقایسه و رتبه‌بندی عملکرد مالی شرکت‌های مخابرات استانی با رویکرد مدل جمعی تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها و روش کارایی متقاطع. فرآیند مدیریت و توسعه، 24(2)، صص.103-128.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تحلیل چالش‌های راهبری شبکه‌های رسمی همکاری علم و فناوری : مطالعه پنج شبکه منتخب در ایران</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Analysis of the challenges of orchestrating formal collaborative networks of science and technology: (Case Study: Selected Networks in Iran)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>علی‌رغم تحقیقات انجام‌شده در زمینه شبکه‌های همکاری علم و فناوری(STCNs)، چالش‌های مدیریت این شبکه‌ها کمتر مورد بررسی قرار‌گرفته است. در این مطالعه، 5 شبکه همکاری ایجاد شده توسط نهادهای دولتی در بین سال‌های 1379 تا 1397 در ایران، در زمینه آزمایشگاه‌های فناوری‌های راهبردی، آزمایشگاه‌های علمی، بیوتکنولوژی، پزشکی مولکولی و داروهای گیاهی، مطالعه شده است. در این مقاله با مرور نظام‌مند تحقیقات انجام شده، 41 چالش‌ راهبری شبکه‌های رسمی همکاری علم و فناوری در ایران در سطح تحلیل شبکه شناسایی شد. سپس پرسشنامه محقق ساخته تدوین و در بین مطلعین 5 شبکه همکاری منتخب که جزء فعالترین شبکه های رسمی همکاری در حوزه علم و فناوری در ایران بودند توزیع گردید. برای تحلیل ها از تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی و تحلیل عوامل اصلی و چرخش واریماکس استفاده شد. از 41 شاخص شناسایی شده، 19 شاخص بار عاملی زیر 0.5 داشته و از تحلیل ها حذف و 22 شاخص در مرحله دوم و پس از چرخش، در 6 طبقه قرار گرفتند. با توجه به خصوصیات شاخص ها در طبقات، 6 عنوان برای طبقات نامگذاری گردید: 1-عضو گیری(دوشاخص)، 2-ساختار شبکه(6 شاخص)، 3- موقعیت شبکه(3 شاخص)، 4-جریان دانش(3 شاخص)، 5- صیانت پذیری(3 شاخص) و 6- پایداری(5 شاخص). در پایان نیز محدودیت های تحقیق ارائه شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Although science and technology collaborative networks (STCNs) have been studied and investigated for quite a while, the challenges of orchestrating these networks have received insignificant attention. In this paper, five collaborative networks in the field of strategic technologies laboratories, scientific laboratories, biotechnology, molecular medicine, and herbal medicine, established by the government agency in Iran in the years 2000-2018, were studied. In this paper, with systematic review of research, 41 challenges of the orchestrating formal collaborative networks of science and technology in Iran were identified at the level of network analysis. A researcher-made questionnaire was developed and distributed among the knowledgeable 5 selected collaborative networks, which were among the most active formal collaborative networks of science and technology in Iran. For analyzes, exploratory factor analysis and analysis of main factors and varimax rotation were used. Of the 41 indicators identified, 19 factor indexes were below 0.5 and excluded from the analysis, and 22 indicators in the second stage and after the rotation were classified in 6 categories. According to the characteristics of the indicators in the classes, 6 titles were named for the classes: 1- membership (2 indicators), 2- network structure (6 indicators), 3- network position (3 indicators), 4- knowledge mobility (3 indicators), 5- appropriability (3 indicators) and 6- Stability (5 indicators). In the end, research limitations were also presented.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>77</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>102</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شهابی</Family>
						<NameE>ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>shahabi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری رشته مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری رشته مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>shahabi_63@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عادل</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>آذر</Family>
						<NameE>Adel</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Azar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، گروه مدیریت، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد- دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، گروه مدیریت، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد-</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>azara@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رادفر</Family>
						<NameE>reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>radfar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، واحد</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>radfar@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اسدی فرد</Family>
						<NameE>Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Asadifard</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری ریاست جمهوری، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری ریاست</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>reza_asadifard@tsi.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبکه‌های رسمی همکاری علم و فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>راهبری شبکه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چالش‌های راهبری شبکه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل عاملی اکتشافی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aarikka-Stenroos, A., Ritala, V., 2017. Network management in the era of ecosystems: Systematic review and management framework, Industrial Marketing Management, 67(1), pp. 23-36.##Agranoff, R., 2006. Inside Collaborative Networks: Ten Lessons for Public Managers, Public Administration Review, 66(1), pp. 56–65##Agranoff, R. McGuire. M., 2001. Big Questions in Public Network Management Research, Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory, 11(3), pp. 295–326.##Agranoff, R., 2007. Managing Within Networks: Adding Value to Public Organizations. Washington, DC: Georgetown University Press.##Alter, C. J. Hage. 1993. Organizations Working Together. Beverly Hills, CA: Sage.##Asadifard, R., Tabatabaeian, S.H, Bamdad Sofi, J., Taghva, M.R., 2017. A model for investigating the stability factors in formal science and technology collaborative networks: A case study of Iran, Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, 122(1), pp. 139-150.##Bache, I. M. Flinders. 2004. Conclusions and Implications, in I. Bache and M. Flinders(eds), Multi-level Governance. Oxford: Oxford University Press.##Batterink, MH, Wubben, EFM, Klerkx L, Omta S.W.F. 2010. Orchestrating innovation networks: the case of innovation brokers in the agri-food sector, Enterpren Reg Dev, 22(1), pp. 47–76.##Belussi F., Arcangeli F., 1998. A typology of networks: flexible and evolutionary firms, Research policy, 27(1), PP. 415-428.##Bizzi, L., Langley, A., 2012, Studying processes in and around networks, Industrial Marketing Management, 41(2), PP 224-234.##Carlsson, B., Jacobsson, S., 1997. In search of useful public policies: key lessons and issues for policy makers. In: Carlsson, B., (Ed.), Technological Systems and Industrial Dynamics, Kluwer Academic Publishers, Dordrecht.##Carvalho, L. Goodyear, P, 2018. Design, learning networks and service innovation, Design Studies, 55(1), pp 27-53.##Ceglie, G., Dini, M., 1999. SME Cluster and Network Development in Developing Countries: The Experience of UNlDO, United Nations Industrial Development Organization (UNlDO).##Chen, B., 2008. Assessing Inter-organizational Networks for Public Service Delivery: A Process-Perceived Effectiveness Framework’, Public Performance and Management Review, 31(3), pp. 348–63.##Chituc C.M., Cesar T., Americo A., 2008. Interoperability in collaborative networks: Independent and industry-specific initiatives – The case of the footwear industry; The Journal of Computers in Industry: ACM. 59 (7), pp.741-757.##Dal Molin, M., Masella, C., 2016. From Fragmentation to Comprehensiveness in Network Governance, Public Organization Review, 16(4), pp. 493–508.##Danilovic M. Winroth M., 2005. A tentative framework for analyzing integration in collaborative Manufacturing network settings: a Cass study, Journal of Engineering and Technology Management, 22(1), pp. 141-58.##Dhanaraj, CH., Parkhe, A., 2006. Orchestrating innovation networks, Academy of Management Review, 31(3), pp 659–669.##Dyer, JH, Nobeoka K., 2000. Creating and managing a high-performance knowledge-sharing network: the Toyota case. Strat Manag, 21(3), pp. 345–367.##Jurian, E., Klijn. E., 2007. Trust in complex decision-making networks: A theoretical and empirical explanation. Administration &amp; Society, 39(1), pp. 25–50.##Gardet, E., Mothe, C., 2012. SME dependence and coordination in innovation networks, Journal of Small Business and Enterprise Development, 19(2), pp. 263-280.##Gibb, J., Sune, A., Albers, S., 2017. Network learning: Episodes of interorganizational learning towards a collective performance goal, European Management Journal, 35(1), pp 15-25.##Haugen Gausdal, A., Ragnhild Nilsen, E., 2011. Orchestrating Innovative SME Networks. The Case of Health Innovation, Springer Science Business Media, LLC , J Knowl Econ, 2(1), pp. 586–600.##Hakansson, H., Havila, V., Pedersen, A. 1999. Learning in Networks, Industrial Marketing Management, 28(5), PP. 443-452.##Hakansson, H., Ford, D. 2002. How should companies interact in business networks? Journal of Business Research, 55(1), PP. 133–39.##Hakansson, H., Eriksson, A.-K. 1993. Getting Innovations Out of Supplier Networks. Journal of Business-to-Business Marketing, 1(1), PP. 3–34##Hines, P., 1994. Creating World Class Suppliers: Unlocking Mutual Competitive Advantage, (Pitman Publishing: London)##Hou, Y., D.P. Moynihan and P.W. Ingraham. 2003. ‘Capacity, Management, and Performance: Exploring the Links’, American Review of Public Administration, 33 (3), pp. 295–315.##Hu, Y., Sørensen, OJ. 2012. Open Innovation in Networks: Specifying Orchestration Capability for SMEs, Ledelse &amp; Erhvervsoekonomi, 77(2), pp. 7-24.##Hurmelinna-Laukkanen, P., Olander, H., Blomqvist, K., Panfilii, V., 2012. Orchestrating R&amp;D networks: Absorptive capacity, network stability, and innovation appropriability, European Management Journal, 30(1), PP. 552– 563.##Human, Sherrie E., Keith G. Provan. 2000. Legitimacy building in the evolution of small-firm networks: A comparative study of success and demise. Administrative Science Quarterly, 45(1), PP. 327–65.##Hurmelinna-Laukkanen, P., Natti, S., 2017. Orchestrator types, roles and capabilities – A framework for innovation networks, Industrial Marketing Management, Industrial Marketing Management, 74, pp.65-78.##Jackson, D.L. 2003. Revisiting sample size and number of parameter estimates: Some support for the N:q hypothesis. Structural Equation Modeling, 10.##Kickert, W.J.M., Klijn, E.H. Koppenjan, J.F.M., 1997. Managing Complex Policy Networks, London: Sage.##Kleindorfer, P.R., Wind, Y. 2009 , The Network Challenge Strategy, Profit, and Risk in an Interlinked World, Upper Saddle River, N.J. :  Wharton School Pub.##Klerkx, L., Aarts, N., 2013. The interaction of multiple champions in orchestrating innovation networks: Conflicts and complementarities, Technovation, 33(1), pp193–210.##Klijn, E. H., Edelenbos, J., Steijn, B. 2010. Trust in governance networks: its impact on outcomes.Administration and Society, 42(2), pp 193–221.##Klein Woolthuis, R., Lankhuizen, M., Gilsing, V. 2005. A system failure framework for innovation policy design, Technovation 25(1), pp. 609–619.##Koppenjan, J.F.M. E.-H. Klijn. 2004. Managing Uncertainties in Networks. London: Routledge.## Lianga, X., Liu, A. M.M., 2018. The evolution of government sponsored collaboration network and its impact on innovation: A bibliometric analysis in the Chinese solar PV sector, Research Policy, 47(7), pp1295-1308.##Leven, P., Holmströma, J., Mathiassen, L., 2014. Managing research and innovation networks: Evidence from a govrnment ponsored cross-industry program, Research Policy 43 (1), pp 156– 168.##Mankevich, V., 2014. Managing Innovation Networks Exploring Coopetition Dynamics in Innovation Ecosystems, Master thesis, UMEA universitet, Department of informatics, IT Management.##Marsh, D. Smith, M., 2000. Understanding Policy Networks: Towards a Dialectical Approach, Political Studies, 48, 1, 4–21.##McEvily, B, Zaheer, A., 2004. Architects of trust: The role of network facilitators in geographical clusters. In Trust and distrust in organizations, ed. R. Kramer and K. Cook, pp. 189–213. New York: Russell Sage Foundation.##McGuire, M, Agranoff, R., 2011.The limitations of public management networks, Public Administration, 89 (2), pp 265-284.##Milwood P.A. Roehl W.S., 2018. Orchestration of innovation networks in collaborative settings, International Journal of Contemporary Hospitality Management 30 (6), pp. 2562-2582##Möller, K. Halinen, A., 1999, Business Relationships and networks: Managerial Challenge of Network Era, Industrial Marketing Management, 28(1), pp. 413-427.##Provan, K., G. Kenis, P. 2008. Modes of Network Governance: Structure, Management, and Effectiveness, Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory, 18(2), pp. 229-252.##Provan, K.G., Milward, H.B., 1995. A preliminary theory of inter-organizational network effectiveness: A comparative study of four community mental health systems, administrative science quarterly, 40(1), pp. 1-33.##Riemer, K. Klein, S., 2006, Network management framework, In: S. Klein and A. Poulymenakou (eds.), Managing dynamic networks, pp. 17-66, Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg.##Powell, W.W., Koput, K.W., Smith-Doerr, L., 1996. Interorganizational collaboration and the locusof innovation: networks of learning in biotechnology. Administrative Science Quarterly, 41(1), PP.116–45.##Rampersad G., Quester, P., Troshani, I., 2010. Managing innovation networks: Exploratory evidence from ICT, biotechnology and nanotechnology networks, Industrial Marketing Management 39(1), pp 793–805.##Ren, J., Li, T. 2010. Network Management, Handbook of Technology Management.##Rhodes, R.A.W. 2000. ‘The Governance Narrative: Key Findings and Lesson from the ESRC’s Whitehall Programmeme’, Public Administration, 78(2), PP. 345–63.##Rhodes, R.A.W. 1997 Understanding Governance: Policy Networks, Governance, Reflexivity and Accountability. Buckingham: Open University Press.##Schudrich, W, Auerbach, C., Liu, J., Fernandes, G., Mc Gowan, B., Claiborne, N., 2012. Factors Impacting Intention to Leave In Social Workers and Child Care Workers Employed at Voluntary Agencies. Children and Youth Services Review, 34(1), PP. 84-90.##Sørensen, E. J. Torfing. 2007. Theoretical Approaches to Democratic Network Governance’, in E. Sørensen and J. Torfing (Eds), Theories of Democratic Network Governance. London: Palgrave Macmillan, pp. 233–46.##Suchman, C., 1995. Managing legitimacy: Strategic and institutional approaches. Academy of Management Review, 20(1), PP. 571–610.##Thompson, G.F. 2003. Between Markets and Hierarchies: The Logic and Limits of Network Forms of Organization. Oxford: Oxford University Press.##Uzzi, B. 1997. Social structure and competition in interfirm networks: the paradox of embeddedness, Adm. Sci. Q. 42(1), pp 35–67.##Van Raaij, D., 2006. Norms Network Members Use: An Alternative Perspective for Indicating Network Success or Failure, International Public Management Journal, 9(3), pp. 249-270##Weiner, Bryan J., Weiner BJ, Alexander JA.1998. The challenges of governingpublic-private community health partnerships. Health Care Management Review, 23(2), PP. 39–55.##Wixted, B., Holbrook, J., 2008. Conceptual Issues in the Evaluation of Formal Research Networks, CPROST Report 2008-01, Available from: http://www.sfu.ca/cprost /docs/wixtedholbrook08-1.pdf## Xu, F., Shi, J.,  Chen, X., Chow, K.P. 2013. A Three-Dimensional Evaluation Model for Network Management System, Procedia Computer Science, 17(1), pp 888-892.##اسدی‌فرد. ر، 1390. مدلی برای شکل‌گیری شبکه‌های پایدار همکاری علم و فناوری در ایران، پایان‌نامه دکتری، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی.##اسدی‌فرد. ر، چوخاچی زاده مقدم. ا، گودرزی. م، 1395. الگویی برای دسته‌بندی و مطالعه عوامل مؤثر بر موفقیت شبکه‌های همکاری بین‌المللی، نشریه علمی پژوهشی مدیریت نوآوری، سال پنجم، شماره 1، صص129-150.##تید. ج، بسنت. ج، 1391. مدیریت نوآوری، یکپارچه‌سازی تغییرات فناورانه، بازار و سازمان، ترجمه آراستی، محمدرضا و همکاران، جلد اول، انتشارات رسا.##محمدی. م، حمیدی. م، محمودی. ب، جوادی. س، 1393. شناسایی، تحلیل و دسته‌بندی عوامل مؤثر بر شکل‌گیری شبکه‌های نوآوری در شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان( مطالعه موردی پارک علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران)، نشریه علمی پژوهشی مدیریت نوآوری، سال سوم، شماره 4، صص 1-24.##نیلفروشان، ه، آراستی. م، 1392. فرآیند شکست ضعیف شبکه‌های نوآوری مهندسی‌شده در مرحله راه‌اندازی، مطالعه موردی صنعت گاز ایران، سیاست علم و فناوری، سال ششم، شماره 2، ص77-93.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>تحلیلی بر توسعه فناوری پهپاد در ایران با تاکید بر رویکرد مدیریت راهبردی جاویژه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>An analysis of the development of UAV technology in Iran with an emphasis on the strategic niche management approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>لازمه سیاست‌گذاری درست در هر فرایند گذار فناورانه‌ای، تحلیل وضعیت کنونی آن با تمرکز بر نقاط ضعف و قوت و زمینه‌های شکست آن است. مقاله پیش رو در پی تحلیل پویایی فرایندهای گذار فناوری پهپاد در ایران، به‌عنوان یکی از اولویتهای دفاعی کشور، است. لذا نخست با اتکا به مبانی نظری پژوهش، پرسش‌نامه‌ای برای ارزیابی سه فرایند توسعه جاویژه‌های فناوری شامل تبیین انتظارات و چشم‌انداز، شبکه‌سازی و یادگیری و 13 مولفه زیرمجموعه آنها، طراحی شد. در ادامه با ابزار پیمایش، وضعیت کنونی فرایندهای یادشده در توسعه جاویژه فناوری پهپاد در ایران ارزیابی و نقاط ضعف و قوت مولفه‌های زیرمجموعه آنها تعیین گردید و مشخص شد که هر سه فرایند در سطح رو به ضعیف قرار دارند. البته وضعیت فرایند «تبیین انتظارات و چشم‌انداز» تا حدی بهتر است. همچنین مولفه‌های «توجه به جنبه‌های غیرفنی»، «تعاملات و مشارکت بازیگران در قالب شبکه» و «فضای یادگیری و سطح رقابت» ضعیف‌ترین مولفه‌ها و «سطح نوآورانه و بلندپروازانه بودن انتظارات و چشم‌انداز»، «سطح قدرت لابی بازیگران و تشکیل ائتلافهای حامی» و «کیفیت و کمیت یادگیری»، قو‌ی‌ترین مولفه‌های فرایندی شناخته شدند. سپس با برگزاری پنلی از خبرگان، تحلیل کیفی درباره وضعیت فرایندهای یادشده و تعامل آنها با یکدیگر صورت گرفت. در پایان مشخص شد که این رویکرد کاربردپذیری خوبی برای تحلیل توسعه فناوریهای نوظهور دفاعی دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The need for policy-making in any technological transition is to analyze its current situation. This paper is about the development processes of UAV technological niche in Iran. Therefore, first, based on theoretical foundations of the research, a questionnaire was developed for evaluating three development processes of technological niche, including &quot;expectations and vision articulation&quot;, &quot;network building&quot; and &quot;learning&quot;. Next, with the surveying tool, the current situation of the processes mentioned in the development of the UAV technological niche in Iran was evaluated and the strengths and weaknesses of their components were determined. It was found that all three processes are at a weak level. Of course, the status of the process of &quot;expectations and vision articulation&quot; is somewhat better. Also, the components of &quot;attention to non-technical aspects&quot;, &quot;interactions and participation of actors in the form of network&quot; and &quot;learning environment and the level of competition&quot;, the weakest components and the &quot;level of innovative of expectations and vision&quot;, &quot;the level of actors&#039; lobbying power&quot;, &quot;the formation of advocative coalitions&quot;, and &quot;the quality and quantity of learning&quot;, the strongest components were recognized. Then, with a panel of experts, a qualitative analysis of the status of these processes took place. In the end, it became clear that it is a good applicable approach for analyzing the development of emerging defense technologies</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>103</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>128</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بهارلو</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Baharloo</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری، پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوریهای نوین، سازمان پژوهشهای علمی و صنعتی ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری، پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوریهای</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.baharloo@irost.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>طاهره</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>میرعمادی</Family>
						<NameE>Tahere</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mir emadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوریهای نوین، سازمان پژوهشهای علمی و صنعتی ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوریهای نوین،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>tamiremadi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>الیاسی</Family>
						<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Elyasi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>elyasi.atu@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علیرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بوشهری</Family>
						<NameE>alireza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>boushehri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، مرکز پژوهشی مدیریت و فناوریهای نرم، دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، مرکز پژوهشی مدیریت و فناوریهای</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>arb1148@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>گذار فناورانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت راهبردی جاویژه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تبیین انتظارات و چشم‌انداز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبکه‌سازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>یادگیری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فناوری پهپاد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aghion, P., David, P. &amp; Foray, D., 2009. Science, Technology and Innovation for Economic Growth: Linking Policy Research and Practice in “STIG Systems”. Research Policy, 38(4), pp. 681-693.##Cooper, T. &amp; Bishop, F., 2016. Iran-Iraq War in the Air, 1980-1988. s.l.:s.n.##Development, Concepts and Doctrine Centre, 2014. Global Strategic Trends: Out to 2045, Fifth Ed.. UK: Ministry of Defense.##Farrell, T. &amp; Terriff, T., 2002. the Sources of Military Change: Culture, Politics, Technology. s.l.:Lynne Reinner Publishers.##Geels, F.W., 2002. Technological Transitions as Evolutionary Reconfiguration Processes: a Multilevel Perspective and a Case Study. Research Policy 31(89), pp. 1257-1274.##Geels, F.W., 2005. Technological Transitions and System Innovations: A Co-evolutionary and Socio-Technical Analysis. Cheltenham: Edward Elgar.##Geels, F. &amp; Schot, J., 2007. Typology of Sociotechnical Transition Pathways. Research Policy, 36(3), pp. 399-417.##Gundlach, J., 2012. Designing Unmanned Aircraft Systems: A Comprehensive Approach. Virginia: American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, Inc..##Hillman, K., Nilsson, M., Rickne, A. &amp; Magnusson, T., 2011. Fostering Sustainable Technologies: a Framework for Analysing the Governance of Innovation. systems Science and Public Policy, 38(5), pp. 403-415.##Hoogma, R., 2000. Exploiting Technological Niches: Strategies for Experimental Introduction of Electric Vehicles, s.l.: Twente University Press.##Hoogma, R., Kemp, R., Schot, J. &amp; Truffer, B., 2002. Experimenting for Sustainable Transport: The Approach of Strategic Niche Management. London and New York: Spon Press.##Jacobsson, S. &amp; Bergek, A., 2011. Innovation System Analyses and Sustainability Transitions: Contributions and Suggestions for Research. Enviromental Innovation and Societal Transitions 1, pp. 41-57.##Kemp, R.; Rip, A.; Schot, J., 2001. Constructing Transition Paths through the Management of Niches, in R. Garud and P. Karnøe (eds), Path Dependence and Creation. London: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates.##Kemp, R.; Schot, J.; Hoogma, R., 1998. Regime Shifts to Sustainability through Processes of Niche Formation: the Approach of Strategic Niche Management. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 10(2), pp. 175-195.##Kendel, F. &amp; Winnefeld, J. A., 2013. Unmanned Systems Integrated Roadmap FY2013-2038. USA: Departmant of Defense.##Markard, J.; Truffer, B., 2012. Sustainability transitions: an Emerging Field of Research and Its Prospects. Research Policy, 41(6), p. 955–967.##Markard, J. &amp; Truffer, B., 2008. Technological innovation systems and the multi-level perspective: Towards an integrated framework. Research Policy 37, pp. 596-615.##Raven, R. P., 2005. Strategic Niche Management for Biomass: A comparative study on the experimental introduction of bioenergy technologies in the Netherlands and Denmark, s.l.: Technische Universiteit Eindhoven.##Rip, A. &amp; Kemp, R., 1998. Technological Change, in S. Rayner, E.L. Malone (eds), Human Choice and Climate Change, Vol. 2.. Columbus, OH: Battelle Press.##Rotmans, J., Kemp, R. &amp; Van Asselt, M., 2001. More Evolution than Revolution: Transition Management in Public Policy. Foresight, 3(1), pp. 15-31.##Schot, J. &amp; Geels, F., 2008. Strategic Niche Management and Sustainable Innovation Journeys: Theory, Findings, Research agenda, and Policy. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management 20(5), p. 537–54.##Smith, A. &amp; Raven, R., 2012. What is Protective Space? Reconsidering Niches in Transition to Sustainability. Research Policy 41, pp. 1025-1036.##Sterrenberg, L. et al., 2013. Low-Carbon Transition through System Innovation: Theoretical Notions and Application, s.l.: Pioneers into Practice Mentoring Programme, Regional Innovation Implementation Community (RIC).##Tarikhi, P., Ashrafi, M. &amp; Abbasi, M., 2014. Iran&#039;s Aerospace Tecnology. In: Science and Innovation in Iran. s.l.:Palgrave McMillan.##UVS-info, 2017. Remotely Piloted Aircraft Systems: The Global Perspective (2016/2017), 14th Edition. [Online]##Available at: https://rps-info.com/publications/2016-rpas-yearbook-flipping-book/##[Accessed 2017].##Weber, M., Hoogma, R., Lane, B. &amp; Schot, J., 1999. Experimenting with Sustainable Transport Innovations : a Workbook for Strategic Niche Management. s.l.:Seville/Enschede: Universiteit Twente.##Wieczorek, A. J. &amp; Hekkert, M. P., 2012. Systemic instruments for systemic innovation problems: A framework for policy makers and innovation scholars. Science and Public Policy, 39(1), pp. 74-87.##Yin, R. K., 2002. Case Study Research: Design and Methods. s.l.:Sage Publishing.##بهارلو, مهدی, 1391. سند توسعه هوافضا- بخش هوایی- زیربخش پهپاد, تهران: ستاد توسعه هوافضا.##بهارلو, م., میرعمادی, ط., الیاسی, م. &amp; بوشهری, ع., 1397. تحلیل و تبیین ساختاری- کارکردی نظام نوآوری فناورانه پهپاد در ایران. مدیریت توسعه فناوری، 6 (1), pp. 42-72.##ستاد توسعه هوافضا, 1391. سند جامع توسعه هوافضای کشور, تهران: معاونت علمی و فناوری ریاست جمهوری.##علی‌بابایی, غ., 1385. تاریخ نیروی هوایی ایران. تهران: انتشارات آشیان.##مجلس شورای اسلامی, 1396. قانون برنامه پنجساله ششم توسعه جمهوری اسلامی ایران (مصوب 14/12/1395 مجلس شورای اسلامی). [درون خطی]##Available at: https://shenasname.ir/1391-09-30-20-01-30/tosee/plan6/3579##[دستیابی در 21 10 1396].##مستند داستان مهاجر. 1391. [فیلم] با کارگردانی گروه تلویزیونی ثریا. مکان نشر نامشخص: مؤلف نامعلوم##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نگاشت عوامل مؤثر بر خلق پتنت با رویکرد فرا ترکیب</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Mapping the Patent Creation Affecting Factors Using Meta-Synthesis Method</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>اهمیت یافتن مباحث مربوط به تولید فناوری و سرمایه‌گذاری‌های صورت گرفته، نیازمند نتایجی ملموس در حوزه انتشار دانش کاربردی خلق‌شده باقابلیت تجاری‌سازی و انتقال آن به بازار مصرف در قالب خلق پتنت می‌باشد. بااین‌وجود در مطالعات صورت گرفته چارچوب یکپارچه‌ای از روابط بین عوامل مؤثر بر خلق پتنت مشاهده نمی‌شود. لذا هدف این پژوهش، شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر خلق پتنت و تبیین نحوه ارتباط این عوامل می‌باشد. در این پژوهش کیفی تلاش شده با استفاده از شیوه فراترکیب و مرور نظام‌مند، مهم‌ترین عوامل مؤثر بر خلق پتنت بررسی و استخراج گردد. درنهایت با کدگذاری در قالب واحدهای معنایی و کدهای مفهومی نسبت به ترسیم ارتباطات بین آن‌ها اقدام شده است. براساس نتایج حاصل‌شده، مدیریت دانش، خدمات مدیریت فناوری، مدیریت فرآیندهای ثبت اختراع، فعالیت‌های تحقیق و توسعه و تعاملات بین‌المللی در تحقیق و توسعه، بیشترین نقش را در ایجاد تعادل بین مفاهیم مؤثر بر خلق پتنت دارد. چنین مطالعه‌ای با معرفی عوامل تأثیرگذار بر خلق پتنت به شیوه‌ای نظام‌مند نه‌تنها به شناخت مهم‌ترین عوامل موجود این حوزه کمک خواهد کرد بلکه با مشخص کردن نحوه ارتباط هر یک، برای سیاست‌گذاران در جهت تشخیص اثربخش‌ترین سیاست‌های ارتقای نوآوری، بستر لازم برای خلق پتنت را در پی دارد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The importance of technology creating and investments requires tangible results in the area of the dissemination of applied knowledge created with the commercialization capability and transferring it to the market in the form of patent. However, there is no studies suggested the integrated framework for patent creation affecting factors. The purpose of this research is to identify the factors affecting the creation of patents and to explain how these factors are interconnected. This qualitative research, attempts to explore and extract the most important factors influencing the creation of patents using systematic review and meta-synthesis method. Finally, by extracting and encoding factors in the form of semantic codes and conceptual codes try to mapping the relation between them. Based on the results, the knowledge management, technology management services, patenting processes management, research and development activities and international interactions in research and development have the greatest role in balancing the patent creation affecting the factors. Such a study, will not only help recognizing the most important factors in this area by introducing the patent creation factors in a systematic method, but also, help policymakers to identify the most effective policies to promote innovation, Which improve the context for patent creating.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>129</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>166</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>فرهنگ نژاد</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad Ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Farhangnejad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری سیاست‌گذاری علم و فناوری، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری سیاست‌گذاری علم و فناوری، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mafarhang@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شعبان</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>الهی</Family>
						<NameE>Shaban</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Elahi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه تربیت مدرس،ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>elahi@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید سپهر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قاضی نوری</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Sepehr</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ghazinoory</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه تربیت مدرس، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ghazinoory@modares.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مجیدپور</Family>
						<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Majidpour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشکده مدیریت، علم و فناوری دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشکده مدیریت، علم و فناوری</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>majidpour.mehdi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>خلق پتنت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>علم و فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظام نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فراترکیب</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مرور نظام‌مند</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Acharya, V. and Xu, Z., 2017. Financial dependence and innovation: The case of public versus private firms. Journal of Financial Economics, 124(2), pp.223-243.##Agrawal, A.K., 2001. University‐to‐industry knowledge transfer: Literature review and unanswered questions. International Journal of management reviews, 3(4), pp.285-302.##Alletto, A., Bruccoleri, M., Mazzola, E. and Ramanathan, U., 2017. Collaboration experience in the supply chain of knowledge and patent development. Production Planning &amp; Control, 28(6-8), pp.574-586.##Ambrammal, S.K. and Sharma, R., 2014. R&amp;D and patenting by firms in India in high-and medium-high-technology industries. Journal of Chinese Economic and Business Studies, 12(2), pp.181-207.##Ang, J.S., Cheng, Y. and Wu, C., 2014. Does enforcement of intellectual property rights matter in China? Evidence from financing and investment choices in the high-tech industry. Review of Economics and Statistics, 96(2), pp.332-348.##Arora, A. and Ceccagnoli, M., 2006. Patent protection, complementary assets, and firms’ incentives for technology licensing. Management Science, 52(2), pp.293-308.##Arqué-Castells, P., Cartaxo, R.M., García-Quevedo, J. and Godinho, M.M., 2016. Royalty sharing, effort and invention in universities: Evidence from Portugal and Spain. Research Policy, 45(9), pp.1858-1872.##Arundel, A. and Kabla, I., 1998. What percentage of innovations are patented? Empirical estimates for European firms. Research policy, 27(2), pp.127-141.##Athreye, S. and Cantwell, J., 2007. Creating competition? Globalisation and the emergence of new technology producers. Research Policy, 36(2), pp.209-226.##Azagra-Caro, J.M. and Consoli, D., 2016. Knowledge flows, the influence of national R&amp;D structure and the moderating role of public–private cooperation. The Journal of Technology Transfer, 41(1), pp.152-172.##Baldini, N. 2006. University patenting and licensing activity: a review of the literature. Research Evaluation, England, vol. 15, No. 3, pp. 197–207.##Barros, H.M., 2015. Exploring the use of patents in a weak institutional environment: The effects of innovation partnerships, firm ownership, and new management practices. Technovation, 45, pp.63-77.##Baumeister, R.F. and Leary, M.R., 1997. Writing narrative literature reviews. Review of general psychology, 1(3), pp.311-320.##Bench, S. and Day, T., 2010. The user experience of critical care discharge: a meta-synthesis of qualitative research. International journal of nursing studies, 47(4), pp.487-499.##Bercovitz, J. and Feldman, M., 2011. The mechanisms of collaboration in inventive teams: Composition, social networks, and geography. Research Policy, 40(1), pp.81-93.##Berry, H., 2014. Global integration and innovation: multicountry knowledge generation within MNC s. Strategic Management Journal, 35(6), pp.869-890.##Bertoni, F. and Tykvová, T., 2015. Does governmental venture capital spur invention and innovation? Evidence from young European biotech companies. Research Policy, 44(4), pp.925-935.##Blind, K., Edler, J., Frietsch, R. and Schmoch, U., 2006. Motives to patent: Empirical evidence from Germany. Research Policy, 35(5), pp.655-672.##Brander, J.A. and Zhang, W., 2017. Employee relations and innovation: an empirical analysis using patent data. Economics of Innovation and New Technology, 26(4), pp.368-384.##Bush, V. 1945. Science: The endless frontier. Transactions of the Kansas Academy of Science (1903-), 48(3), 231-264.##Calderini, M., Franzoni, C. and Vezzulli, A., 2007. If star scientists do not patent: The effect of productivity, basicness and impact on the decision to patent in the academic world. Research Policy, 36(3), pp.303-319.##Chai, S. and Shih, W., 2016. Bridging science and technology through academic–industry partnerships. Research Policy, 45(1), pp.148-158.##Chang, Y.C., Yang, P.Y. and Chen, M.H., 2009. The determinants of academic research commercial performance: Towards an organizational ambidexterity perspective. Research Policy, 38(6), pp.936-946.##Chellaraj, G., Maskus, K.E. and Mattoo, A., 2004. The contribution of skilled immigration and international graduate students to US innovation. World Bank Policy Research Working Paper, 3588.##Clarysse, B., Tartari, V. and Salter, A., 2011. The impact of entrepreneurial capacity, experience and organizational support on academic entrepreneurship. Research policy, 40(8), pp.1084-1093.##Coriat, B. and Orsi, F., 2002. Establishing a new intellectual property rights regime in the United States: Origins, content and problems. Research policy, 31(8-9), pp.1491-1507.##Coriat, B., &amp; Orsi, F. 2002. Establishing a new intellectual property rights regime in the United States: Origins, content and problems. Research policy. 31(8), 1491-1507.##Coupe, T., 2003. Science is golden: academic R&amp;D and university patents. The Journal of Technology Transfer, 28(1), pp.31-46.##Creswell, J., 2010. W. 2007. Qualitative inquiry and research design: Choosing among five approaches, 2.##Czarnitzki, D. and Lopes-Bento, C., 2014. Innovation subsidies: Does the funding source matter for innovation intensity and performance? Empirical evidence from Germany. Industry and Innovation, 21(5), pp.380-409.##Czarnitzki, D., Glänzel, W. and Hussinger, K., 2009. Heterogeneity of patenting activity and its implications for scientific research. Research Policy, 38(1), pp.26-34.##Delgado, M., Porter, M.E. and Stern, S., 2014. Clusters, convergence, and economic performance. Research policy, 43(10), pp.1785-1799.##Dey, S., 2016. Does a strong patent regime discourage innovation? Economics of Innovation and New Technology, 25(5), pp.485-502.##Di Cagno, D., Fabrizi, A. and Meliciani, V., 2014. The impact of participation in European joint research projects on knowledge creation and economic growth. The Journal of Technology Transfer, 39(6), pp.836-858.##Dutt, B. 2006. International Collaboration in Patenting: A case study of contributions of Indian inventors.##Eberhardt, M., Helmers, C. and Yu, Z., 2016. What can explain the Chinese patent explosion? Oxford Economic Papers, 69(1), pp.239-262.##Erikson, T., Knockaert, M. and Der Foo, M., 2015. Enterprising scientists: The shaping role of norms, experience and scientific productivity. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 99, pp.211-221.##Ernst, H., 2003. Patent information for strategic technology management. World patent information, 25(3), pp.233-242.##Fabrizi, A., Guarini, G. and Meliciani, V., 2016. Public knowledge partnerships in European research projects and knowledge creation across R&amp;D institutional sectors. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 28(9), pp.1056-1072.##Fabrizio, K.R. and Di Minin, A., 2008. Commercializing the laboratory: Faculty patenting and the open science environment. Research Policy, 37(5), pp.914-931.##Fabrizio, K.R., Poczter, S. and Zelner, B.A., 2017. Does innovation policy attract international competition? Evidence from energy storage. Research Policy, 46(6), pp.1106-1117.##Fini, R., Lacetera, N. and Shane, S., 2010. Inside or outside the IP system? Business creation in academia. Research Policy, 39(8), pp.1060-1069.##Freeman, L.C., 1978. Centrality in social networks conceptual clarification. Social networks, 1(3), pp.215-239.##Friedman, J. and Silberman, J., 2003. University technology transfer: do incentives, management, and location matter? The Journal of technology transfer, 28(1), pp.17-30.##Fuentes Solís, R. and Ferrada Rubio, S., 2016. Technological innovation in Chilean firms: An empirical study based on patents [Innovación Tecnológica en Empresas Chilenas: Un Estudio Empírico Basado en Patentes]. Journal of technology management &amp; innovation, 11(4), pp.56-64.##Furman, J.L., Porter, M.E. and Stern, S., 2002. The determinants of national innovative capacity. Research policy, 31(6), pp.899-933.##GAO, L., Yang, L.L. and Zhang, J.H., 2016. Corporate patents, R&amp;D success, and tax avoidance. Review of Quantitative Finance and Accounting, 47(4), pp.1063-1096.##García-Muiña, F.E. and González-Sánchez, R., 2017. Absorptive routines and international patent performance. BRQ Business Research Quarterly, 20(2), pp.96-111.##German-Soto, V. and Flores, L.G., 2015. A standardized coefficients model to analyze the regional patents activity: Evidence from the Mexican states. Journal of the Knowledge Economy, 6(1), pp.72-89.##Gerybadze, A. and Merk, S., 2014. Globalisation of R&amp;D and host-country patenting of multinational corporations in emerging countries. International Journal of Technology Management, 64(2-4), pp.148-179.##Geuna, A. and Rossi, F., 2011. Changes to university IPR regulations in Europe and the impact on academic patenting. Research Policy, 40(8), pp.1068-1076.##Ghazinoory, S., Abdi, M., &amp; Bagheri, S. K. 2010. Promoting nanotechnology patenting: a new experience in national innovation system of Iran. Journal of Intellectual Property Rights, 15(6), 464-73.##Ghazinoory, S., Yazdi, F. S., &amp; Soltani, A. M. 2012. Iran and Nanotechnology: A New Experience of on Time Entry. In making it to the Forefront .pp. 85-108. Springer New York.##Glaser, B.G., 1992. Basics of grounded theory analysis: Emergence vs forcing. Sociology press.##Göktepe-Hulten, D. and Mahagaonkar, P., 2010. Inventing and patenting activities of scientists: in the expectation of money or reputation? The Journal of Technology Transfer, 35(4), pp.401-423.##Grimaldi, R., Kenney, M., Siegel, D.S. and Wright, M., 2011. 30 years after Bayh–Dole: Reassessing academic entrepreneurship. Research Policy, 40(8), pp.1045-1057.##Grimm, H.M. and Jaenicke, J., 2015. Testing the causal relationship between academic patenting and scientific publishing in Germany: Crowding-out or reinforcement? The Journal of Technology Transfer, 40(3), pp.512-535.##Guan, J. and Pang, L., 2017. Industry specific effects on innovation performance in China. China Economic Review, 44, pp.125-137.##Guerzoni, M., Aldridge, T.T., Audretsch, D.B. and Desai, S., 2014. A new industry creation and originality: Insight from the funding sources of university patents. Research Policy, 43(10), pp.1697-1706.##Guo, D., Guo, Y. and Jiang, K., 2016. Government-subsidized R&amp;D and firm innovation: Evidence from China. Research policy, 45(6), pp.1129-1144.##Henderson, R., Jaffe, A.B. and Trajtenberg, M., 1998. Universities as a source of commercial technology: a detailed analysis of university patenting, 1965–1988. Review of Economics and statistics, 80(1), pp.119-127.##Huang, K.G.L., Geng, X. and Wang, H., 2017. Institutional regime shift in intellectual property rights and innovation strategies of firms in China. Organization Science, 28(2), pp.355-377.##Huang, W.L., Feeney, M.K. and Welch, E.W., 2011. Organizational and individual determinants of patent production of academic scientists and engineers in the United States. Science and Public Policy, 38(6), pp.463-479.##Huelsbeck M., &amp; E., Lehmann. 2006. German University Patenting and Licensing: Legally Prescribed Incentives and Institutional Determinants of University-Industry-Technology-Transfer, in University of Augsburg, Department of Business Administration Chair of Management and Organisation.##Huyghe, A. and Knockaert, M., 2015. The influence of organizational culture and climate on entrepreneurial intentions among research scientists. The Journal of Technology Transfer, 40(1), pp.138-160.##Jacobsen, C.B. and Andersen, L.B., 2014. Performance management in the public sector: Does it decrease or increase innovation and performance? International Journal of Public Administration, 37(14), pp.1011-1023.##Jones, C. I. 2005. Growth and ideas. Handbook of economic growth, 1, 1063-1111.##Jongwanich, J., Kohpaiboon, A. and Yang, C.H., 2014. Science park, triple helix, and regional innovative capacity: province-level evidence from China. Journal of the Asia Pacific Economy, 19(2), pp.333-352.##Kammoun, O. and Rahmouni, M., 2014. Appropriation Instruments and Innovation Activities: Evidence from Tunisian Firms. International Journal of Innovation and Technology Management, 11(06), p.1450046.##Kandasamy, W.V. and Smarandache, F., 2003. Fuzzy cognitive maps and neutrosophic cognitive maps. Infinite Study.##Kim, C. and Song, J., 2007. Creating new technology through alliances: An empirical investigation of joint patents. Technovation, 27(8), pp.461-470.##Kolympiris, C. and Klein, P.G., 2017. The effects of academic incubators on university innovation. Strategic Entrepreneurship Journal, 11(2), pp.145-170.##Landis, J.R. and Koch, G.G., 1977. The measurement of observer agreement for categorical data. biometrics, pp.159-174.##Landry, R., Amara, N., Rherrad, I., 2006. Why are some university researchers more likely to create spin-offs than others? Evidence from Canadian universities. Research Policy, 35, 1599–1615.##Laplume, A.O., Xavier-Oliveira, E., Dass, P. and Thakur, R., 2015. The organizational advantage in early inventing and patenting: Empirical evidence from interference proceedings. Technovation, 43, pp.40-48.##Lee, J. and Stuen, E., 2016. University reputation and technology commercialization: evidence from nanoscale science. The Journal of Technology Transfer, 41(3), pp.586-609.##Leung, L., 2015. Validity, reliability, and generalizability in qualitative research. Journal of family medicine and primary care, 4(3), p.324.##Leydesdorff, L. 2008. The delineation of nanoscience and nanotechnology in terms of journals and patents: A most recent update. Scientometrics, 76(1), 159-167.##Leydesdorff, L., &amp; Zhou, P. 2007. Nanotechnology as a field of science: Its delineation in terms of journals and patents. Scientometrics, 70(3), 693-713.##Long, C. 2002. Patent signals. The University of Chicago Law Review, 625-679.##Maresch, D., Fink, M. and Harms, R., 2016. When patents matter: The impact of competition and patent age on the performance contribution of intellectual property rights protection. Technovation, 57, pp.14-20.##Medina-Molotla, N., Thorsteinsdóttir, H., Frixione, E. and Kuri-Harcuch, W., 2017. Some factors limiting transfer of biotechnology research for health care at Cinvestav: A Mexican scientific center. Technology in Society, 48, pp.1-10.##Meyer, M., 2006. Are patenting scientists the better scholars? An exploratory comparison of inventor-authors with their non-inventing peers in nano-science and technology. Research Policy, 35(10), pp.1646-1662.##Minguillo, D. and Thelwall, M., 2015. Which are the best innovation support infrastructures for universities? Evidence from R&amp;D output and commercial activities. Scientometrics, 102(1), pp.1057-1081.##Mowery, D.C. and Ziedonis, A.A., 2002. Academic patent quality and quantity before and after the Bayh–Dole act in the United States. Research Policy, 31(3), pp.399-418.##Mueller, P., 2006. Exploring the knowledge filter: how entrepreneurship and university–industry relationships drive economic growth. Research Policy, 35 (10), 1499–1508.##Mukherjee, A., Singh, M. and Žaldokas, A., 2017. Do corporate taxes hinder innovation?. Journal of Financial Economics, 124(1), pp.195-221.##Nard, C.A., 2010. Legal forms and the common law of patents. BUL Rev., 90, p.51.##Nikzad, R., 2014. Canadian worldwide patent activity: An industrial level analysis. World Patent Information, 38, pp.12-18.##Pakes, A., &amp; Griliches, Z. 1980. Patents and R&amp;D at the firm level: A first report. Economics letters, 5(4), 377-381.##Pammolli, F. and Rossi, M.A., 2005. Intellectual property, technological regimes and market dynamics. Economia e Politica Industriale Paper, (2).##Pammolli, F., &amp; Rossi, M. A. 2005. Intellectual property, technological regimes and market dynamics.##Peters, M., Schneider, M., Griesshaber, T. and Hoffmann, V.H., 2012. The impact of technology-push and demand-pull policies on technical change–Does the locus of policies matter? Research Policy, 41(8), pp.1296-1308.##Prud&#039;homme, D., 2017. Utility model patent regime “strength” and technological development: Experiences of China and other East Asian latecomers. China Economic Review, 42, pp.50-73.##Rafferty, M., 2008. The Bayh–Dole Act and university research and development. Research Policy, 37(1), pp.29-40.##Rizzo, U. and Ramaciotti, L., 2014. The determinants of academic patenting by Italian universities. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 26(4), pp.469-483.##Romano, M., Del Giudice, M. and Nicotra, M., 2014. Knowledge creation and exploitation in Italian universities: the role of internal policies for patent activity. Journal of Knowledge Management, 18(5), pp.952-970.##Saini, M. and Shlonsky, A., 2012. Systematic synthesis of qualitative research. OUP USA.##Samila, S. and Sorenson, O., 2010. Venture capital as a catalyst to commercialization. Research Policy, 39(10), pp.1348-1360.##Sandelowski, M. and Barroso, J., 2006. Handbook for synthesizing qualitative research. Springer Publishing Company.##Sarkissian, A., 2008. Intellectual property rights for developing countries: Lessons from Iran. Technovation, 28(11), pp.786-798.##Scherer, F.M., 1983. The propensity to patent. International Journal of industrial organization, 1(1), pp.107-128.##Schleich, J., Walz, R. and Ragwitz, M., 2017. Effects of policies on patenting in wind-power technologies. Energy Policy, 108, pp.684-695.##Schmookler, A. B. 1993. The illusion of choice: how the market economy shapes our destiny: SUNY Press.##Schumpeter, J. A. 1934. The theory of economic development: An inquiry into profits, capital, credit, interest, and the business cycle (Vol. 55): Transaction publishers.##Shane, S., 2004. Encouraging university entrepreneurship? The effect of the Bayh-Dole Act on university patenting in the United States. Journal of Business Venturing, 19(1), pp.127-151.##Shane, S.A., 1992. Why do some societies invent more than others? Journal of Business Venturing, 7(1), pp.29-46.##Shapiro, D., Tang, Y., Wang, M. and Zhang, W., 2017. Monetary incentives and innovation in Chinese SMEs. Asian Business &amp; Management, 16(3), pp.130-157.##Shi, Y. and Guan, J., 2016. Small-world network effects on innovation: evidences from nanotechnology patenting. Journal of Nanoparticle Research, 18(11), p.329.##Singh, A., Wong, P.K. and Ho, Y.P., 2015. The role of universities in the national innovation systems of China and the East Asian NIEs: An exploratory analysis of publications and patenting data. Asian Journal of Technology Innovation, 23(2), pp.140-156.##Solow, R. M. 1956. A contribution to the theory of economic growth. The quarterly journal of economics, 70(1), 65-94.##Somaya, D., Williamson, I.O. and Zhang, X., 2007. Combining patent law expertise with R&amp;D for patenting performance. Organization Science, 18(6), pp.922-937.##Stek, P.E. and van Geenhuizen, M.S., 2015. Measuring the dynamics of an innovation system using patent data: a case study of South Korea, 2001–2010. Quality &amp; Quantity, 49(4), pp.1325-1343.##Stek, P.E. and van Geenhuizen, M.S., 2016. The influence of international research interaction on national innovation performance: A bibliometric approach. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 110, pp.61-70.##Sterzi, V. and Lawson, C., 2014. The role of early career factors in the formation of serial academic inventors (No. hal-01135599).##Sun, Y., 2003. Determinants of foreign patents in China. World Patent Information, 25(1), pp.27-37.##Suzuki, J., Tsukada, N. and Goto, A., 2015. Role of public research institutes in Japan’s national innovation system: Case study of AIST, RIKEN and JAXA. Science, Technology and Society, 20(2), pp.133-160.##Tahmooresnejad, L. and Beaudry, C., 2015. Does government funding have the same impact on academic publications and patents? The case of nanotechnology in Canada. International Journal of Innovation Management, 19(03), p.1540001.##Takalo, T. and Kanniainen, V., 2000. Do patents slow down technological progress? Real options in research, patenting, and market introduction. International Journal of Industrial Organization, 18(7), pp.1105-1127.##Thursby, J.G. and Kemp, S., 2002. Growth and productive efficiency of university intellectual property licensing. Research policy, 31(1), pp.109-124.##Thursby, J.G. and Thursby, M.C., 2003. Industry/university licensing: Characteristics, concerns and issues from the perspective of the buyer. The Journal of Technology Transfer, 28(3-4), pp.207-213.##Thursby, J.G., Jensen, R. and Thursby, M.C., 2001. Objectives, characteristics and outcomes of university licensing: A survey of major US universities. The journal of Technology transfer, 26(1-2), pp.59-72.##Tseng, C.Y. and Pai, D.C., 2014. Knowledge search, spillover and creation capability in India&#039;s pharmaceutical industry. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 26(2), pp.207-222.##Vermont, S., 2006. Independent invention as a defense to patent infringement. Mich. L. Rev., 105, p.475.##Verspagen, B., 2006. University research, intellectual property rights and European innovation systems. Journal of Economic surveys, 20(4), pp.607-632.##Walsh, J.P. and Huang, H., 2014. Local context, academic entrepreneurship and open science: Publication secrecy and commercial activity among Japanese and US scientists. Research Policy, 43(2), pp.245-260.##Walsh, J.P., Lee, Y.N. and Jung, T., 2016. Win, lose or draw? The fate of patented inventions. Research Policy, 45(7), pp.1362-1373.##Walsh, J.P., Lee, Y.N. and Nagaoka, S., 2016. Openness and innovation in the US: Collaboration form, idea generation and implementation. Research Policy, 45(8), pp.1660-1671.##Wang, N. and Hagedoorn, J., 2014. The lag structure of the relationship between patenting and internal R&amp;D revisited. Research Policy, 43(8), pp.1275-1285.##Westmore, B., 2014. Policy incentives for private innovation and maximising the returns. OECD Journal: Economic Studies, 2013(1), pp.121-163.##WIPO, 2010. World Intellectual Property Indicators.##Wu, Y., Welch, E.W. and Huang, W.L., 2015. Commercialization of university inventions: Individual and institutional factors affecting licensing of university patents. Technovation, 36, pp.12-25.##Zhang, G. and Zhou, J., 2016. The effects of forward and reverse engineering on firm innovation performance in the stages of technology catch-up: An empirical study of China. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 104, pp.212-222.##Zhou, W., Li, Y., Hsieh, C.J., Chang, K.C., Kiang, Y.J. and Ken, Y., 2016. Research Performance and University–Industry–Government Funding Sources in Taiwan’s Technological and Vocational Universities. Innovation, 18(3), pp.340-351.##Zucker, L.G., Darby, M.R., Furner, J., Liu, R.C. and Ma, H., 2007. Minerva unbound: Knowledge stocks, knowledge flows and new knowledge production. Research Policy, 36(6), pp.850-863.##الهی، شعبان.، خالدی، آرمان.، مجیدپور، مهدی.، اسدی فر، رضا.، 1397. چارچوب تحلیلی زیست‌بوم همکاری‌های فناورانه بین شرکت‌های بزرگ و شرکت‌های کوچک فناوری محور. مدیریت نوآوری، 7 (1)، 1-32.##امیری، سعید.، نیک کام، نادر.، صاحبی نژاد، مجید. 1387. بررسی آماری وضعیت تولید فناوری و ثبت اختراعات مرتبط با فناوری نانو در کشورهای مختلف. سیاست علم و فناوری، 1 (3)، صفحات 1-11.##باقری، سیدکامران.، سمندرعلی اشتهاردی، مژگان.، پیمانخواه، صادق. شفیعی، لیلا. 1392. نگاهی تحلیلی به پراکندگی جغرافیایی اختراعات در ایران.‎ سیاست علم و فناوری، 5 (3). صفحات 17-25.##باقری، سیدکامران.، کبریایی، مریم.، عزیزی مرادپور، حمید. 1391. دسترسی عمومی به اطلاعات اختراع در ایران: چرایی و چگونگی. رشد فناوری، 8 (30). صفحات 57- 64.##بیگدلی، زاهد.، صراطی شیرازی، منصوره. 1394. تحلیل پیوند علم و فناوری بامطالعه استنادی پروانه‌های ثبت اختراع ایرانی در طول سال‌های 2009-2013. فصلنامه مطالعات ملی کتابداری و سازمان‌دهی اطلاعات، 26 (2)، صفحات 65-76.‎##حبیب پور، کرم.، صفری، رضا. 1391. راهنمای جامع کاربرد SPSS در تحقیقات پیمایشی (تحلیل داده های کمی)، نشر لویه، متفکران، تهران.##حبیبا، سعید.، بهادری، زهرا. 1393. اختراعات نانو فناوری و احراز شرایط جدید بودن. نانو مقیاس، 1 (2)، صفحات 109-118.##شاکری، عباس.، ابراهیمی سالاری، تقی. 1388. اثر مخارج تحقیق و توسعه بر اختراعات و رشد اقتصادی (تحلیل مقایسه‌ای بین کشورهای درحال‌توسعه و توسعه‌یافته)، دانش و توسعه، 16 (29). صفحات 88-125.##عباسی نژاد، حسین.، گودرزی فراهانی، یزدان.، قیاسی، محمدحسین. 1393. تأثیر حمایت از حقوق مالکیت فکری و حق اختراع بر رشد اقتصادی ایران. پژوهش‌های اقتصادی، 14 (1)، صفحات 27-58.##عبدخدا، هیوا.، نوروزی، علیرضا.، راوند، سامان. 1390. تحلیل موضوعی پروانه‌های ثبت اختراع مخترعان ایرانی در پایگاه‌های بین‌المللی ثبت اختراع در فاصله سال‌های 2011-1976. بیاورد سلامت، 5(5)، صفحات 42-51.##عبدلی، قهرمان. 1386. نظام ملی نوآوری، ابداعات و جهش اقتصادی. پژوهش‌های اقتصادی ایران. 9 (31). صفحات 103-126.##عرفان منش، محمدحسین.، عباسی محمود.، زاهدی، مهدی. 1394. استفاده از اختراع ثبت‌شده در تحقیقات آزمایشگاهی (مطالعه تطبیقی). مجله علمی-پژوهشی اخلاق زیستی, 5 (17), صفحه 169-199.##علایی آرانی، محمد. 1388. مطالعۀ رابطۀ میان پروانه‌های ثبت اختراع و تولیدات علمی مخترعان ایرانی. پایان‌نامه برای اخذ درجه کارشناسی ارشد. دانشکده علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه تهران.##علایی آرانی، محمد.، نقشینه، نادر. 1388. تحلیلی بر وضعیت پروانه‌های ثبت اختراع ایرانی در اداره‌های چهارگانه ثبت اختراع. تحقیقات اطلاع‌رسانی و کتابخانه‌های عمومی (پیام کتابخانه)، 15 (4). صفحات 167-184.##علائی آرانی، محمد.، نقشینه، نادر.، طاهری، سید مهدی. 1390. شاخص‌های خروجی علم و فنّاوری در جمهوری اسلامی ایران: مطالعه موردی رابطه میان پروانه‌های ثبت اختراع و تولیدات علمی مخترعان ایرانی. پژوهشنامه پردازش و مدیریت اطلاعات (علوم و فناوری اطلاعات)، 27 (4)، صفحات 1033-1053.##علم خواه، حسن. مرادی، زهرا. 1392. راﻫﻨﻤﺎی ﻛﺎرﺑﺮدی ﻛﻠﻴﺎت ﻣﺎﻟﻜﻴﺖ ﻓﻜﺮی، اﺻﻮل ﺛﺒت اﺧﺘﺮاع و ﻣﺮور ﭘﺘﻨت. نشر ستایش حقیقت، تهران، چاپ اول.##قاضی نوری، سید سپهر.، قاضی نوری، سید سروش. 1387. استخراج راهکارهای اصلاح نظام ملی نوآوری ایران با تکیه‌بر مطالعه تطبیقی کشورهای منتخب. سیاست علم و فناوری، 1 (1)، صفحات 64-80.##محسنی کیاسری، مصطفی.، محمدی، مهدی.، جعفر نژاد، احمد.، مختارزاده، نیما.، اسدی فرد، رضا. 1396. دسته‌بندی ابزارهای سیاست نوآوری تقاضامحور با استفاده از رویکرد فراترکیب. مدیریت نوآوری، 6 (2)، 109-138##نقی زاده، رضا.، الهی، شعبان.، منطقی، منوچهر.، قاضی نوری، سید سپهر. 1393. فراترکیب مدل‌های نوآوری منطقه‌ای مروری بر سال‌های 2013-1990. مدیریت نوآوری، 3 (4)، 25-56.##نوروزی، ناصر.، الهی، شعبان.، حسن‌زاده، علیرضا.، حاجی حسینی، حجت‌الله. 1393. ارائه چارچوبی از ابزارهای سیاستی علم و فناوری، با استفاده از رویکرد فراترکیب. مدیریت نوآوری، 3 (2)، 103-124.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				