<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1397</YEAR>
<VOL>7</VOL>
<NO>4</NO>
<MOSALSAL>26</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>200</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>بررسی قابلیت‌های شرکتهای کوچک و متوسط فناور در شکل‌گیری و تداوم همکاری‌های فناورانه : مطالعه‌ای چند موردی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Investigating the capabilities of the  SME firms in the formation and continuation of technological collaborations: a multi case study</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>امروزه توسعه همکاری‌های فناورانه یکی از راهکارهای مهم جهت توسعه منابع، قابلیت‌ها و کسب مزیت رقابتی در میان سازمان‌ها محسوب می‌شود. این نوع از همکاری‌ها در میان شرکت‌های کوچک و متوسط فناوری به جهت ایجاد تاثیرات چشمگیر بر موفقیت آنها از اهمیت بیشتری برخوردار است. یکی از بستر‌های مهم جهت ایجاد و تداوم همکاری‌ها ایجاد قابلیت‌های لازم جهت ورود و بهره‌برداری از این همکاری‌ها است. در این مقاله تلاش شده است تا بر اساس مطالعه چند موردی، قابلیت‌های متفاوت چند بنگاه فناور کوچک و متوسط فناور از طریق انجام مصاحبه با مدیران شرکت‌ها و طرف‌های همکاری و مطالعه اسناد و مشاهده و به کمک تحلیل تم به مورد بررس قرار گرفت. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که قابلیت‌های مورد نیاز در همکاری فناورانه در بنگاه‌ها شامل چهار دسته قابلیت‌های شکل‌گیری و تداوم همکاری، قابلیت‌های پشتیبان محصول/خدمت فناورانه، قابلیت‌های پشتیبان بهره‌برداری از محصول/خدمت همکاری و قابلیت‌های یکسان و مکمل جهت هم‌افزایی از طریق همکاری است که مجموعه‌ای از قابلیت‌ها بر اساس نوع همکاری و هدف آن در این مجموعه‌ها قرار می‌گیرد. این قابلیت‌ها بستر شکل‌گیری و تداوم همکاری‌ها و همچنین میزان بهره‌برداری و نتیجه بر آمده از همکاری‌ها برای بنگاه محسوب می‌گردد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Today, the development of technological collaboration is one of the important strategies for developing resources, capabilities and gaining competitive advantage among organizations. This kind of collaboration among small and SME firms is important for creating significant effects on their success. One of the important pillars to create and maintain partnerships is to create the necessary capabilities to enter and use these collaborations. In this paper, we have tried to examine the various capabilities of several SME technology companies through interviews with corporate executives and partners, and studying documents and observation and by analyzing the theme, based on a few case studies. The results show that the capabilities required in collaborative technology in firms include four types of interoperability and continuity capabilities, product / service support capabilities, product / service collaboration support capabilities, and the same or complementary capabilities for collaboration that a set of The capabilities are based on the type of collaboration and its purpose in these sets. These capabilities are the basis for the formation and continuity of cooperation as well as the amount of operation and the result of cooperation for the firm.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>25</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صمیمی</Family>
						<NameE>ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>samimi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت تکنولوژی دانشگاه تهران،ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت تکنولوژی دانشگاه تهران،ایران.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ali.samimi.s@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید سروش</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قاضی نوری</Family>
						<NameE>soroush</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>ghazinoori</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی،تهران،ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی،تهران،ایران.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ghazinoori@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>هاشم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>معزز</Family>
						<NameE>Hashem</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moazzez</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار دانشگاه تهران ،ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار دانشگاه تهران ،ایران.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>h.moazzez@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کشمیری</Family>
						<NameE>Mehdi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Keshmiri</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان،ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه صنعتی اصفهان،ایران.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mehdi.keshmiri@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>همکاری فناورانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قابلیت‌های همکاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شکل‌گیری همکاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تداوم همکاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ahuja, G., 2000. Collaboration networks, structural holes, and innovation: A longitudinal study‏. Administrative science quarterly, 45(3), pp. 425-455.##Andreu, R. &amp; Ciborra, 1996. Organisational learning and core capabilities development: the role of IT. The Journal of Strategic Information Systems, 5(2), pp. 111-127.##Annand, B. &amp; Khanna, T., 2000. Do firms learn to create value? The case of alliances. Strategic Management Journal, 21(1), pp. 295-315.##Barney, J. B. &amp; Clark, D. N., 2007. Resource-based theory: Creating and sustaining competitive advantage‏. :Oxford University Press on Demand.##Bayona, C., Garcı́a-Marco, T. &amp; Huerta, E., 2001. Firms’ motivations for cooperative R&amp;D: an empirical analysis of Spanish firms. Research Policy, 30(8), pp. 1289-1307.##Birkinshaw, J. &amp; Fey, C. F., 2005. External sources of knowledge, governance mode, and R&amp;D performance. Journal of Management, 31(4), pp. 597–621.##Blomqvist, K., Hummelinna-Laukanen, p., Nummella, N. &amp; Saarenketo, S., 2008. The role of trust and contracts in the internationalization of technology-intensive Born Globals. Journal of Engineering and Technology Management, 25(1), pp. 123-135.##Cagliano, R., Chiesa, V. &amp; Manzini, R., 2000. Differences and similarities in managing technological collaborations in research, development and manufacturing: a case study. Cagliano, R., Chiesa, V., &amp; Manzini, R. Engineering and Technology Management, 17(2), pp. 193–224.##Caloghirou, Y., Kastelli, I. &amp; Tsakanikas, A., 2004. Internal capabilities and external knowledge sources: complements or substitutes for innovative performance?‏. Technovation, 24(1), pp. 29-39.##Capaldo, A., 2007. Network structure and innovation: The leveraging of a dual network as a distinctive relational capability‏. Strategic management journal, 28(6), pp. 585-608.##Capaldo, A., 2007. Network structure and innovation: The leveraging of a dual network as a distinctive relational capability. Strategic management journal, 28(6), pp. 585-608.##Carr, A. S. &amp; Pearson, J. N., 1999. Strategically managed buyer–supplier relationships and performance outcomes‏. Journal of operations management, 17(5), pp. 497-519.##Cassiman, B., Di Guardo, M. C. &amp; Valentini, G., 2009. Organising R&amp;D projects to profit from innovation: Insights from co-opetition ‏. Long Range Planning, 42(2), pp. 216-233.##Chiesa, V., 2001. R&amp;D strategy and organisation: Managing technical change in dynamic contexts. World Scientific., 5(1).##Das, K. T. &amp; Teng, B.-S., 2000. A resource-based theory of strategic alliances. Journal of management, 26(1), pp. 31-61.##De Man, A. P. &amp; Duysters, G., 2005. Collaboration and innovation: a review of the effects of mergers, acquisitions and alliances on innovation Technovation, 25(12), pp. 1377-1387.##Deeds, L. D., De Carolis, D. &amp; Coombs, J., 1999. Deeds, D.L., De CDynamic capabilities and new produc development in high technology ventures: An empirical analysis of new biotechnologyfirms. Journal of Business Venturing, 15(3), pp. 211–229.##Dodgson, M., 1992. The future for technological collaboration. Futures, 24(5), pp. 459-470.##Dollinger, M., 1995. Entrepreneurship: Strategies and Resources.  Boston: Irwin.##Draulans, J., de Man, P. A. &amp; Volberda, W. H., 2003. Building alliance capability: management techniques for superior alliance performance.. Long Range Planning, 36(2), pp. 151–166.##Duysters, G., Kok, G. &amp; Vaandrager, M., 1999. Crafting successful strategic technology partnerships. R&amp;D Management,, 29(4), pp. 343-351.##Duysters, G., 2012. Do firms learn to manage alliance portfolio diversity? The diversity‐performance relationship and the moderating effects of experience and capability. European Management Review, 9(3), pp. 139-152.##Ettlie, E. J. &amp; Pavlou, A. P., 2006. Technology-based new product development partnerships. Decision Sciences, 37(2), pp. 117 – 147.##Faems, D., Janssens, M. &amp; Van Looy, B., 2010. Managing the Co‐operation–Competition Dilemma in R&amp;D Alliances: A Multiple Case Study in the Advanced Materials Industry. Creativity and Innovation Management, 19(1), pp. 3-22.##Felin, T. &amp; Foss, N., 2011. The endogenous origins of experience, routines, and organizational capabilities. the poverty of stimulus, 7(1), pp. 231-256.##Feller, J., Parhankangas, A., Smeds, A. &amp; Jaatine, 2013. How companies learn to collaborate: Emergence of improved inter-organizational processes in R&amp;D alliances. Organization Studies, 34(3), pp. 313-343.##Fernández-Olmos, M., &amp; Ramírez-Alesón, M , M. &amp; Ramírez-Alesón, M., 2017. How internal and external factors influence the dynamics of SME technology collaboration networks over time. Technovation, 64(1), pp. 16-27.##Fernández-Olmos, M. &amp; Ramírez-Alesón, M., 2017. How internal and external factors influence the dynamics of SME technology collaboration networks over time‏. Technovation, 64(1), pp. 16-27.##Ferreira, J. J., Fernandes, I. C., Alves, H. &amp; Rapo, L. M., 2015. . Drivers of innovation strategies: testing the Tidd and Bessant (2009) model. Journal of Business Research, 68(7), pp. 1395–1403.##Forrest, J. E. &amp; Martin, M. J., 1992. Strategic alliances between large and small research intensive organizations: experiences in the biotechnology industry‏. R&amp;D Management, 22(1), pp. 041-054.##Gray, B., 1989. The pathways of my research: A journey of personal engagement and change. The Journal of Applied Behavioral Science, 25(4), pp. 383-398.##Gulati, R., 1998. Alliances and networks. Strategic Management Journal, 9(4), pp. 293–317.##Gulati, R., 1999. Network location and learning: The influence of network resources and firm capabilities on alliance formation.. Strategic Management Journal, 20(1), pp. 397-420.##Haeussler, C. &amp; Matthew, H. J., 2014. Strategic alliances: Trading ownership for capabilities. Journal of Economics and Management Strategy, 23(1), pp. 178-203.##Hagedoorn, J. &amp; Duysters, G., 2002. External sources of innovative capabilities: the preferences for strategic alliances or mergers and acquisitions‏. Journal of management studies, 39(2), pp. 167-188.##Hagedoorn, J., Roijakkers, N. &amp; Van Kranenburg, H., 2006. Inter‐Firm R&amp;D Networks: the Importance of Strategic Network Capabilities for High‐Tech Partnership Formation‏. British Journal of Management, 17(1), pp. 39-53.##Hagerdoon, J. &amp; Schakenraad, J., 1994. The effect of strategic technology alliances on company performance‏. Strategic management journal, 15(4), pp. 291-309.##Hax, A. C. &amp; Majluf, N. S., 1996. The strategy concept and process: a pragmatic approach‏. Upper Saddle River, NJ: Prentice Hall.##Heimeriks, H. K., Duysters, G. &amp; Vanhaverbeke, W., 2007. Learning mechanisms and differential performance in alliance portfolios. Strategic organization, 5(4), pp. 373-408.##Heimeriks, K., Klijn, E. &amp; Reuer, J., 2009. Building capabilities for alliance portfolios. Long Range Planning, 42(1), pp. 96–114..##Hitt, A. M., Ireland, D. R. &amp; Hoskisson, E. R., 2012. Strategic management cases: competitiveness and globalization‏. 10 South-Western: Cengage Learning.##Hoffmann, H. W. &amp; Schlosser, R., 2001. Success factors of strategic alliances in small and medium-sized enterprises An empirical survey. Long range planning, 34(3), pp. 357-381.##Ingham, M. &amp; Mothe, C., 1998. How to learn in R&amp;D partnerships?. R&amp;D Management, 28(4), pp. 249-261.##Ireland, D. R., Hitt,, M. A. &amp; Vaidyanath, D., 2002. Alliance management as a source of competitive advantage. Journal of Management, 28(1), pp. 413-446.##Johnson, J. L., Sohi, R. S. &amp; Grewal, R., 2004. The role of relational knowledge stores in interfirm partnering. Journal of Marketing, 68(1), pp. 21–36.##Kalaignanam, K., Shankar, V. &amp; Varadarajan, R., 2007. Asymmetric new product development alliances: win-win or win-lose partnerships?‏. Management Science, 53(3), pp. 357-374.##Kale, P., Dyer, J. H. &amp; Singh, H., 2002. Alliance capability, stock market response, and long‐term alliance success: the role of the alliance function‏. Strategic management journal, 23(8), pp. 747-767.##Kale, P. &amp; Singh, H., 2007. Building firm capabilities through learning: The role of the alliance learning process in alliance capability and firm-level alliance success. Strategic Management Journal, 28(10), pp. 981–1000.##Katila, R. &amp; Mang, P. Y., 2003. Exploiting technological opportunities: the timing of collaborations. Research policy, 32(2), pp. 317-332.##Ketchen, D. J., Ireland, R. D. &amp; Snow, C. C., 2007. Strategic entrepreneurship,collaborative innovation, and wealth creation. Strategic Entrepreneurship Journal, 4(1), pp. 371–385.##Kilubi, I., 2016. Strategic technology partnering capabilities: A systematic review of the empirical evidence over two decades. Journal of Strategy and Management, 9(2), pp. 216-255.##Kohtamäki,, M., Rabetino, M. &amp; Möller, k., 2018. Alliance capabilities: A systematic review and future research directions‏. Industrial Marketing Management, 68(1), pp. 188-201.##Kohtamäk, M., Partanen, i. M., Parida, J. &amp; Wincent, V., 2013. Non-linear relationship between industrial service offering and sales growth: The moderating role of network capabilities. Industrial Marketing Management, 42(8), pp. 1374–1385.##Kraaijenbrink, J., Spender, J. &amp; Groen, A. J., 2010. The resource-based view: a review and assessment of its critiques. Journal of management, 36(1), pp. 349-372.##Lambe, C. J., Spekman, R. E. &amp; Hunt, S. D., 2002. Alliance competence, resources, and alliance success: Conceptualization, measurement, and initial test.. Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, 30(2), p. 141–158.##Lanctot, A. &amp; Swan, K. S., 2000. Technology acquisition strategy in an internationally competitive environment. Journal of International Management, 6(3), pp. 187-215.##Lee, C., Lee, K. &amp; Pennings, J. M., 2001. Internal capabilities, external networks, and performance: a study on technology‐based ventures. Strategic management journal, 22(6-7), pp. 615-640.##Lee, G. A., 1998. Negotiating Technology Acquisition: getting the tools you need to succeed., Working Paper, Nanyang Technology University..##Li, H., Meng, L., Wang, Q. &amp; Zhou, L. A., 2008. Political connections, financing and firm performance: Evidence from Chinese private firms. Journal of development economics, 87(2), pp. 283-299.##Long, C. &amp; Vickers-Koch, M., 1995. Using core capabilities to create competitive advantage‏. Organizational dynamics, 24(1), pp. 7-22.##Lorenzoni, G. &amp; Lipparini, A., 1999. The leveraging of interfirm relationships as a distinctive organizational capability: a longitudinal study.. StrategiC Management Journal, 20(1), pp. 317-338.##Malik, k., 2002. Aiding the technology manager: A conceptual model for intra-firm technology transfer. Technovation, 22(7), pp. 427–436.##Miotti, L. &amp; Sachwald, F., 2003. Co-operative R&amp;D: why and with whom?: An integrated framework of analysis. ‏. Research policy, 32(8), pp. 1481-1499.##Mitrega, M., Forkmann, S., Ramos, C. &amp; Henneberg, S. C., 2012. Networking capability in business relationships—Concept and scale development. ‏. Industrial Marketing Management, 41(5), pp. 739-751.##Mowery, D. C., 1998. The relationship between intrafirm and contractual forms of industrial research in American manufacturing. Explorations in Economic history,, 20(4), pp. 351–374.##Mowery, D. C., Oxley, J. E. &amp; Silverman, B. S., 1996. Strategic alliances and interfirm knowledge transfer‏. Strategic management journal, 17(2), pp. 77-91.##Mueller, C. &amp; Herstatt, C., 2000. Interfirm cooperation: a brief overview of current theoretical findings and issues for future research. International Journal of Human Resources Development and Management, 1(1), pp. 48-67.##Narula, R. &amp; Duysters, G., 2004. Globalisation and trends in international R&amp;D alliances. ‏. Journal of International management, 10(2), pp. 199-218.##Noseleit, F. &amp; De Faria, P., 2013. Complementarities of internal R&amp;D and alliances withdifferent partner types. Journal of Business Research, 66(10), pp. 2000–2006.##Nummela, N., 2003. Looking through a prism—multiple perspectives to commitment to international R&amp;D collaboration.. The Journal of High Technology Management Research, 14(1), pp. 135-148..##Patel, P. C., Kohtamäk, M., Parida, V. &amp; Wincent, J., 2015. Entrepreneurial orientation‐as‐experimentation and firm performance: The enabling role of absorptive capacity‏. Strategic Management Journal, 36(11), pp. 1739-1749.##Pennings, J. M. &amp; Harianto, F., 1992. Technological networking and innovation implementation‏. Organization Science, 3(3), pp. 356-382.##Phelps, C. C., 2010. A longitudinal study of the influence of alliance network structure and composition on firm exploratory innovation. Academy of Management Journal, 53(4), pp. 890–913.##Phene, A. &amp; Tallman, S., 2012. Complexity, context and governance in biotechnology alliances. Journal of International Business Studies, 43(1), pp. 61-83.##Porter, M., 1980. Techniques for analyzing industries and competitors. Competitive Strategy‏. New York:##Porter, M. E., 1985. Technology and competitive advantage. Journal of business strategy, 5(3), pp. 60-78.##poulsen, B., 2014. Strategic collaboration: Key Success Factors, Stakeholder workshop: Stimulating Emerging Industries through a Large-Scale Demonstrator Approach, European Commission.##Powell, W. W., Koput, K. W. &amp; Smith-Doerr, L., 1996. Interorganizational collaboration and the locus of innovation: Networks of learning in biotechnology. Administrative science quarterly, pp. 116-145.##Priem, R. L. &amp; Butler, J. E., 2001. Is the resource-based “view” a useful perspective for strategic management research?. Academy of management review, 26(1), pp. 22-40.##Reuer, J. &amp; Zollo, M., 2000. Managing governance adaptations in strategic alliances ‏. European management journal, 18(2), pp. 164-172.##Ritala,, p. &amp; Hurmelinna-Laukkanen, p., 2009. What&#039;s in it for me? Creating and appropriating value in innovation-related coopetition‏. Technovation, 29(12), pp. 819-828.##Ritter, T., Wilkinson, I. F. &amp; Johnston, W. J., 2004. Managing in complex business networks. Industrial Marketing Management, 33(3), pp. 175–183.##Rivera, J. M., 2003. Behavioral antecedents and strategic outcomes of inter-organizational collaborative capabilities‏, Concordia: Doctoral dissertation, Concordia University.##Rothaermel, F. T., 2001. Incumbent&#039;s advantage through exploiting complementary assets via interfirm cooperation. ‏. Strategic management journal, 22((6-7)), pp. 687-699.##Rothaermel, F. T. &amp; Deeds, D. L., 2006. Alliance type, alliance experience and alliance management capability in high-technology ventures‏. Journal of business venturing, 21(4), pp. 429-460.##Rothaermel, F. T. &amp; Hess, A. M., 2007. Building dynamic capabilities: Innovation driven by individual-, firm-, and network-level effects‏. Organization science, 18(6), pp. 898-921.##Sampson, R. C., 2007. R&amp;D alliances and firm performance: The impact of technological diversity and alliance organization on innovation. Academy of Management Journal, 50(2), pp. 364-386.##Santangelo, G. D., 2000. Corporate strategic technological partnerships in the Europeaninformation and communications technology industry. Research Policy, 29(9), pp. 1015–1031.##Santos, C., Abubakar, P. S., Barros, A. C. &amp; Gods, 2016. The role of organizational networks in the development of technological capabilities.. EUROMA.##Sarkar, M., Aulakh, P. S. &amp; Madhok, A., 2009. Process capabilities and value generation in alliance portfolios. Organization Science, 20(1), pp. 583-600.##Saxton, T., 1997. The effects of partner and relationship characteristics on alliance outcomes. The Academy of Management Journal, 40(2), pp. 443-461.##Schilke, O. &amp; Goerzen, A., 2010. Alliance management capability: an investigation of the construct and its measurement. Journal of Management, 36(5), pp. 1192-1219.##Schreiner, M., Kale, P. &amp; Corsten, D., 2009. What really is alliance management capability and how does it impact alliance outcomes and success?. Strategic Management Journal, 30(1), pp. 1395-1419.##Schulze, A., Brojerdi, G. &amp; von Krogh, G., 2014. Those Who Know, Do. Those who understand, teach. Disseminative capability and knowledge transfer in the automotive industry. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 31(1), pp. 79–97.##Siu, W. S. &amp; Bao, Q., 2008. Network strategies of small Chinese high‐technology firms: a qualitative study‏. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 25(1), pp. 79-102.##Sivadas, E. &amp; Dwyer, F. R., 2000. An examination of organizational factors influencing new product success in internal and alliance-based processes. Journal of Marketing, 64(1), p. 31–49.##Spekman, R. E., Isabella, L. A. &amp; MacAvoy, T. C., 2000. Alliance competence: Maximizing the value of your partnerships.:John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Tidd, J., 2014. Conjoint innovation: building a bridge between innovation and entrepreneurship. International Journal of Innovation Management, 18(1).##Tidd, J., Bessant, J. R. &amp; Pavitt, K., 1997. Managing innovation: integrating technological, market and organizational change. 4:Chichester: Wiley..##Trott, P., Cordey-Hayes, M. &amp; Seaton, R. F., 1995. Inward technology transfer as an interactive process‏. Technovation, 15(1), pp. 25-43.##Tsai, K. H. &amp; Wang, J. C., 2009. External technology sourcing and innovation performance in LMT sectors. Research Policy,, 38(3), p. 518–526.##Un, C. A., Cuervo‐Cazurra, A. &amp; Asakawa, K., 2010. R&amp;D collaborations and product innovation. ‏. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 27(5), pp. 673-689.##Utterback, J. M. &amp; Afuah, A. N., 1998. The dynamic ‘diamond’: a technological innovation perspective. Economics of Innovation and New Technology, 6(2-3), pp. 183-200..##Van de Vrande, V., Vanhaverbeke, W. &amp; Duysters, G., 2011. Technology in‐sourcing and the creation of pioneering technologies. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 28(6), pp. 974-987.##Vilkamo, T. &amp; Keil, T., 2003. Strategic technology partnering in high-velocity environments—lessons from a case study.. Technovation, 23(3), pp. 193-204.##Wang, G., Dou, w., Zhu, W. &amp; Zhou, N., 2015. The effects of firm capabilities on externalcollaboration and performance: the moderating role of market turbulence. Journal of Business Research, 68(9), p. 1928–1936.##Wang, J. &amp; Rajagopalan, N., 2015. Alliance capabilities: review and research agenda. Journal of management, 41(1), pp. 236-260.##Wang, L. &amp; Zajac, E. J., 2007. Alliance or acquisition? A dyadic perspective on interfirm resource combinations. Strategic Management Journal, 28(1), pp. 1291-1317.##Wang, Y. &amp; Rajagopalan, N., 2015. Alliance capabilities: Review and research agenda.. Journal of Management, 41(1), p. 236–260.##Wassmer, U., 2010. Alliance portfolios: A review and research agenda. Journal of Management, 36(1), p. 141–171.##Wittmann, C. M., Hunt, S. D. &amp; Arnett, D. B., 2009. Explaining alliance success: Competences, resources, relational factors, and resource-advantage theory. Industrial Marketing Management, 38(7), p. 743–756.##Zhang, J. &amp; Baden‐Fuller, C., 2010. The influence of technological knowledge base and organizational structure on technology collaboration‏. Journal of Management Studies, 47(4), pp. 679-704.##Zineldin, M. &amp; Dodourova, M., 2005. Motivation, achievements and failure of strategic alliances: the case of Swedish auto-manufacturers in Russia‏. European Business Review, 17(5), pp. 460-470.##اسدی فر, ر., خوشنویس, ی. &amp; خالدی , آ., 1397. بزرگ مریخی، کوچک ونوسی: چالشهای همکاری فناورانه بین شرکت های نوپا و شرکت های بزرگ در ایران. تهران: موسسه خدماتی فرهنگی رسا.##آراستی, م., مدرس یزدی, م. &amp; دلاوری, م., 1387. ارائه مدلی جامع برای انتخاب روش مناسب انتقال فناوری. مجله علمی و پژوهشی شریف, 43(1), صص 145-153.##باقری, ا. &amp; بوشهری, ع., 1392. مدل سازی عوامل موثر بر دستاوردهای همکاری های فناورانه: مورد کاوی همکاری های فناورانه نانوفناوری در ایران. مدیریت نوآوری, 2(1), صص 113-140.##چایلد, ج., فالکر, د. &amp; تالمن, ت., 1394. راهبرد مشارکت: مدیریت اتحادها، شبکه‌ها و سرمایه‌گذاری‌های مشترک. 1 تدوین تهران: نشر هزاره ققنوس.##گرنت, ر., 1394. مدیریت استراتژیک با رویکردی امروزی. 2 تدوین تهران: انتشارات آریا قلم.##هداوند, م., 1385. قراردادهای انتقال تکنولوژی. ماهنامه تدبیر, 16(4), صص 36-41.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>کاوشی در توانمندسازهای ساخت محصولات پیچیده؛ شناسایی، اولویت‌بندی و تعیین روابط میان قابلیت‌های مورد نیاز در ساخت‌وتولید محصولات و سیستم‌های پیچیده (COPS)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Exploration of Enablers for Complex Product Manufacturing; Identify, Prioritize and and Determine the Intermediate Relationships of Required Capabilities in Manufacturing of Complex Product Systems (COPS)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>محصولات و سیستم‌های پیچیده (COPS) نقش مهمی در صنعت، اقتصاد و فناوری کشورها ایفا می‌کنند. از طرفی دشواری توسعه و ساخت این محصولات به دلیل پیچیدگی فراوان و نیازمندی به دانش عمیق و سطح بالا ، سازمان‌ها را با چالش‌هایی روبرو نموده است. سازمان‌ها برای موفقیت در ساخت این محصولات احتیاج به شناخت عمیق قابلیت‌های موردنیاز دارند. به همین منظور پژوهش فعلی صورت گرفت تا از طرفی قابلیت‌ها و توانمندسازهای موردنیاز برای ساخت‌و تولید محصولات پیچیده را شناسایی نماید و از طرف دیگر به تجزیه و تحلیل روابط علی معلولی میان توانمندسازها بپردازد. تعیین اهمیت این عوامل جهت برنامه‌ریزی دقیق سازمان نیز هدف دیگر این پژوهش بوده است. به این منظور با استفاده از مطالعات کتابخانه‌ای و مصاحبه‌های نیمه‌ساختاریافته قابلیت‌های مذکور شناسایی و با توزیع پرسشنامه‌ اعتبارسنجی شد. نهایتاً 10 قابلیت اصلی و 46 مولفه فرعی شناسایی و تائید شدند. در مرحله بعدی روابط فی‌مابین عوامل مذکور با استفاده از روش مدلسازی ساختاری تفسیری (ISM) تعیین و در چهار سطح افرازبندی شدند. به منظور تعیین اوزان و رتبه‌بندی عوامل نیز از ر تحلیل شبکه‌ای (ANP) استفاده شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان می‌دهد قابلیت‌های شبکه‌سازی، مدیریت‌پروژه‌های کلان، یکپارچه‌سازی و تعاملات در سطوح کلان از مهم‌ترین عوامل موثر در ساخت محصولات پیچیده بوده و تاثیرات زیربنایی بر سایر عوامل دارند. در پایان پس از ارائه جمع‌بندی، پیشنهاداتی برای پژوهش‌های آتی بیان شد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Complex product systems (COPS) play an important role in industry, economics and technology of countries. On the other hand,Due to the complexity and the need for in depth and high level knowledge; organizations face challenges in Manufacturing and developing these products.To succeed in manufacturing of these products, organizations need to recognize the required capabilities.Therefore, the current research was conducted to identify the capabilities and enablers needed to manufacturing complex products And analyzes the causal relationships between these enablers.The other purpose of this study was to determine the importance of these factors for the accurate planning in the organization.For this purpose, with using the library studies and semi-structured interviews, the mentioned capabilities were identified and then validated by distributing the questionnaire. Eventually, 10 main factors and 46 sub-factors were identified. In the next step, with using Interpretative Structural Modeling (ISM) method , the relationships between these factors were determined and partitioned into four levels.Then ANP was used to determine the weights and ranking of factors.The research results show that networking capabilities, projects management, system integration and interactions at macro levels are the most important factors in manufacturing complex products and have underlying impacts on other factors. at the end of paper, after concluding the content, some suggestions were proposed for future research.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>26</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>50</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کریمی گوارشکی</Family>
						<NameE>mohammad hosein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>karimi gavareshki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار و عضو هیئت‌علمی گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار و عضو هیئت‌علمی گروه مهندسی صنایع،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mh_karimi@aut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جعفر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>قیدرخلجانی</Family>
						<NameE>Jafar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Gheidar-Kheljani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار و عضو هیئت‌علمی گروه مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار و عضو هیئت‌علمی گروه مهندسی صنایع،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>kheljani@aut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>پوریا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کریمی</Family>
						<NameE>Pourya</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Karimy</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مهندسی صنایع، دانشگاه صنعتی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>pourya.karimy@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>محصولات و سیستم‌های پیچیده (COPS)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قابلیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساخت‌وتولید</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ISM</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ANP</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Anderson, D. M. 2014. Design for manufacturability: how to use concurrent engineering to rapidly develop low-cost, high-quality products for lean production: CRC press.##Blanchard, B. S., &amp; Blyler, J. E. 2016. System Engineering Management: John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Chen, J., Tong, L. and Ngai, E.W., 2007. Inter-organizational knowledge management in complex products and systems: Challenges and an exploratory framework. Journal of Technology Management in China, 2(2), pp.134-144.##DAU. 2010. Defense acquisition guidebook. Defense Acquisition University.##Davies, A. and Brady, T., 2000. Organisational capabilities and learning in complex product systems: towards repeatable solutions. Research policy, 29(7-8), pp.931-953.##Davies, A., Brady, T., Prencipe, A. and Hobday, M., 2011. Innovation in complex products and systems: implications for project-based organizing. In Project-Based Organizing and Strategic Management (pp. 3-26). Emerald Group Publishing Limited.##Davies, A. and Hobday, M., 2005. The business of projects: managing innovation in complex products and systems. Cambridge University Press.##DOD. 2012. Defense Manufacturing Management Guide for Program Managers. United States: United States Department of Defense.##Hardstone, G.A.P., 2004. Capabilities, structures and strategies re-examined: incumbent firms and the emergence of complex product systems (CoPS) in mature industries. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 16(2), pp.173-196.##Hobday, M., Davies, A. and Prencipe, A., 2005. Systems integration: a core capability of the modern corporation. Industrial and corporate change, 14(6), pp.1109-1143.##Hobday, M. and Rush, H., 1999. Technology management in complex product systems (CoPS)-ten questions answered. International Journal of Technology Management, 17(6), pp.618-638.##Igel, B. and Wei, Z., 2002. A framework to analyse the competence to innovate complex product systems in the stored program control switchboard industry. International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Innovation Management, 2(6), pp.537-556.##Kiamehr, M., 2017. Paths of technological capability building in complex capital goods: The case of hydro electricity generation systems in Iran. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 122, pp.215-230.##Kiamehr, M., Hobday, M. and Hamedi, M., 2015. Latecomer firm strategies in complex product systems (CoPS): The case of Iran’s thermal electricity generation systems. Research Policy, 44(6), pp.1240-1251.##Kiamehr, M., Hobday, M. and Kermanshah, A., 2013. Latecomer systems integration capability in complex capital goods: the case of Iran’s electricity generation systems. Industrial and corporate change, 23(3), pp.689-716.##Kossiakoff, A., Sweet, W.N., Seymour, S.J. and Biemer, S.M., 2011. Systems engineering principles and practice (Vol. 83). John Wiley &amp; Sons.##Lee, J.J. and Yoon, H., 2015. A comparative study of technological learning and organizational capability development in complex products systems: Distinctive paths of three latecomers in military aircraft industry. Research Policy, 44(7), pp.1296-1313.##Li, M., Liu, H. and Zhou, J., 2018. G-SECI model-based knowledge creation for CoPS innovation: the role of grey knowledge. Journal of Knowledge Management, 22(4), pp.887-911.##Madni, A.M. and Sievers, M., 2014. Systems integration: Key perspectives, experiences, and challenges. Systems Engineering, 17(1), pp.37-51.##Majidpour, M., 2016. Technological catch-up in complex product systems. Journal of Engineering and Technology Management, 41, pp.92-105.##Modrak, V. 2018. Mass customized manufacturing: theoretical concepts and practical approaches.##Naghizadeh, M., Manteghi, M., Ranga, M., &amp; Naghizadeh, R. 2016. Managing integration in complex product systems: The experience of the IR-150 aircraft design program. Technological Forecasting and Social Change.##Ngai, E.W., Jin, C. and Liang, T., 2008. A qualitative study of inter‐organizational knowledge management in complex products and systems development. R&amp;d Management, 38(4), pp.421-440.##Nightingale, P., 2000. The product–process–organisation relationship in complex development projects. Research Policy, 29(7-8), pp.913-930.##Oshri, I. and Newell, S., 2005. Component sharing in complex products and systems: challenges, solutions, and practical implications. IEEE transactions on engineering management, 52(4), pp.509-521.##Park, T.Y., 2012. How a latecomer succeeded in a complex product system industry: three case studies in the Korean telecommunication systems. Industrial and corporate change, 22(2), pp.363-396.##Park, T.Y. and Ji, I., 2015. From mass production to complex production: case of the Korean telecom equipment sector. Asia-Pacific Journal of Accounting &amp; Economics, 22(1), pp.78-102.##Park, T.Y. and Kim, J.Y., 2014. The capabilities required for being successful in complex product systems: case study of Korean e-government. Asian Journal of Technology Innovation, 22(2), pp.268-285.##Patanakul, P., Kwak, Y.H., Zwikael, O. and Liu, M., 2016. What impacts the performance of large-scale government projects? International Journal of Project Management, 34(3), pp.452-466.##Prencipe, A., 2000. Breadth and depth of technological capabilities in CoPS: the case of the aircraft engine control system. Research policy, 29(7-8), pp.895-911.##Priest, J. and Sanchez, J., 2012. Product development and design for manufacturing: a collaborative approach to producibility and reliability. CRC Press.##Ren, Y.T. and Yeo, K.T., 2006. Research challenges on complex product systems (CoPS) innovation. Journal of the Chinese Institute of Industrial Engineers, 23(6), pp.519-529.##Safdari Ranjbar, M., Park, T. Y., &amp; Kiamehr, M. (2018). What happened to complex product systems literature over the last two decades: progresses so far and path ahead. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 30(8), 948-966.##Su, J. and Liu, J., 2012. Effective dynamic capabilities in complex product systems: experiences of local Chinese firm. Journal of Knowledge-based Innovation in China, 4(3), pp.174-188.##Thomassen, M. K., &amp; Alfnes, E. 2017. Mass customization challenges of engineer-to-order manufacturing Managing Complexity (pp. 27-39): Springer.##Ulrich, K. T., &amp; Eppinger, S. D. 2008. Product design and development (4ed.): Tata McGraw-Hill Education.##Wei, Z., &amp; Igel, B. 2010. Competence to manage innovation in complex product systems.##Zhang, L., Lam, W., &amp; Hu, H. 2013. Complex product and system, catch-up, and sectoral system of innovation: a case study of leading medical device companies in China. International Journal of Technological Learning, Innovation and Development, 6(3), 283-302.##الیاسی، م.، شفیعی، م.، 1393. شبکه‌های نوآوری در محصولات با سیستم‌های پیچیده. دوفصلنامه توسعه فنّاوری صنعتی (23)، 39-31.##حافظ‌نیا، م.، 1393. روش‌های تحقیق در علوم انسانی. تهران: سمت.##حسینی، س.ع.، محمدی، م.، و حاجی‌حسینی، ح.، 1395. عوامل حیاتی موفقیت نوآوری در محصولات و سیستم‌های پیچیده (CoPS)؛ مطالعه موردی: پروژه بالگرد ملی سازمان صنایع هوایی. فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه فناوری، 4(1)، 159-186.##صفدری‌رنجبر، م.، قیدرخلجانی، ج.، طهماسبی، س.، توکلی، غ.، 1395-الف. قابلیت‌های کلیدی برای نوآوری و توسعه محصولات و سامانه‌های پیچیده دفاعی. فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه فناوری، 4(1)، 133-158.##صفدری‌رنجبر، م.، رحمان‌سرشت، ح.، منطقی، م.، قاضی‌نوری، س.س.، 1395-ب. پیشران‌های کسب و ایجاد قابلیت‌های فناورانه ساخت محصولات و سامانه‌های پیچیده در بنگاه‌های متأخر: مطالعه موردی شرکت توربوکمپرسور نفت (OTC). مدیریت نوآوری، 5(3)، 1-26.##صفدری‌رنجبر، م.، رحمان‌سرشت، ح.، منطقی، م.، قاضی‌نوری، س.س.، 1395-پ. الگوی ساخت و انباشت قابلیت‌های فناورانه تولید محصولات و سامانه‌های پیچیده در کشورهای درحال‌توسعه: مطالعه موردی شرکت توربوکمپرسور نفت. فصلنامه مدیریت توسعه فناوری، 4(3)، 9-38.##طلایی، ح.، عالم‌تبریز، ا.، فارسیجانی، ح.، 1396. تحلیل توانمندسازهای سیستم تولید انعطاف‌پذیر با رویکردهای مدل‌سازی ساختاری تفسیری و فرایند رتبه‌بندی تفسیری. مطالعات مدیریت صنعتی، 15(44)، 1-26.##مؤمنی، م.، 1393. مباحث نوین تحقیق در عملیات (ویرایش سوم). تهران: مؤلف.##مؤمنی، م.، فعال‌قیومی، ع.، 1389. تحلیل‌های آماری با استفاده از spss. تهران: کتاب نو.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>قابلیت‌های استراتژیک در صنعت نفت و گاز: مطالعه‌ای در بخش میان‌دستی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Strategic Capabilities in the Oil and Gas Industry: A Study in the Midstream Sector</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>نظریه‌های مختلفی پیرامون چگونگی دستیابی به مزیت رقابتی توسط محققان و اندیشمندان مدیریت استراتژیک مطرح شده است و دیدگاه قابلیت‌های پویا که ارتباط نزدیکی میان کسب مزیت رقابتی و قابلیت‌های سازمانی قائل است، یکی از روشن‌ترین نظریاتی است که درباره مزیت رقابتی در دنیای امروز کسب‌وکار ارائه شده است. پژوهش حاضر در همین راستا و با تکیه بر دیدگاه قابلیت‌های پویا، با رویکردی اکتشافی و کیفی به شناسایی و تحلیل قابلیت‌هایی اختصاص دارد که رقابت‌پذیری و دستیابی به مزیت رقابتی را در بخش میان‌دستی زنجیره ارزش صنعت نفت و گاز تحت تأثیر قرار می‌دهند. برای تحقق این هدف، داده‌هایی از 21 مصاحبه نیمه‌ساختاریافته با مدیران ارشد 6 پالایشگاه که به روش هدفمند انتخاب شده بودند، گردآوری و داده‌های حاصل از این مصاحبه‌ها پس از تلفیق با نظرات چند تن از خبرگان، با روش تحلیل مضمون مورد ارزیابی قرار گرفتند. یافته‌های این پژوهش نشان می‌دهد دستیابی به مزیت رقابتی در بخش میان‌دستی صنعت نفت و گاز ریشه در دو قابلیت درون‌نگرِ ارزش‌افزایی و بهره‌وری (کیفی‌سازی فرآورده‌ها، کارایی عملیاتی و قابلیت فناورانه)، و قابلیت برون‌نگرِ پایداری استراتژیک کسب‌وکار (توسعه کسب‌وکار، گرایش بازار و پایداری زنجیره تأمین) دارد. این نتیجه نشان‌دهنده اهمیت رویکرد متوازن برای دستیابی به مزیت رقابتی در صنعت نفت و گاز است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Different theories are presented by strategic management scholars and thinkers to explain how to achieve a competitive advantage, and dynamic capability theory which believed that gaining a competitive advantage is closely linked with organizational capabilities; is one of the clearest theories about competitive advantage in today&#039;s business world. In this regard, current research, based on dynamic capability view, employs a qualitative and explorative approach to identify and analyze of capabilities which influence the competitiveness and gaining competitive advantage in the midstream sector of oil and gas industry. In order to achieve this goal, data were gathered through 21 semi-structured interviews with top level managers of 6 refineries, integrated with comments of some experts, and analyzed by theme analysis method. Findings showed that gaining competitive advantage in the midstream of oil and gas industry rooted in both of inward capability of productivity and value-addition (products qualification, operational efficiency and technological capability) and outward capability of business strategic sustainability (business development, market orientation and sustainability of supply chain). This result reveals the importance of balanced approach in gaining competitive advantage in the oil and gas industry.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>51</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>80</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جلالی</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jalali</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کاندیدای دکتری سیاست‌گذاری بازرگانی، دانشکدۀ مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کاندیدای دکتری سیاست‌گذاری بازرگانی، دانشکدۀ</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>jalali.sh@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>شهرام</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>خلیل نژاد</Family>
						<NameE>Shahram</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Khalil Nezhad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sh.khalilnezhad@atu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عماد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>گل محمدی</Family>
						<NameE>emad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>golmohammadi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>مدرس، دانشگاه علمی کاربردی استان ایلام، مرکز پارسیان (ایلام1)، ایلام، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>مدرس، دانشگاه علمی کاربردی استان ایلام، مرکز</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>emadg818@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>&quot;قابلیت‌های استراتژیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظریه قابلیت پویا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مزیت رقابتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تحلیل مضمون</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>صنعت نفت و گاز &quot;</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Accenture, 2011. Achieving High Performance in the Energy Industry. Accessed on January 2019 on http://accenture.com##Ambrosini, V., Bowman, C., Collier, N., 2009. Dynamic capabilities: An exploration of how firms renew their resource base, British Journal of Management, 20, pp. 9-24.##Amit, R., Shoemaker, P.J.H., 1993. Strategic assets and organizational rent, Strategic Management Journal, 14(1), 33–46.##Augier, M., Teece, D. J., 2009. Dynamic capabilities and the role of managers in business strategy and economic performance, Organization Science, 20(2), pp. 410-421.##Barney, J. B., &amp; Arikan, A. M., 2001. The Resource-Based View: Origins and Implications, The Blackwell Handbook of Strategic Management, pp.124-188.##Barney, J.B., 1991. Firm resources and sustained competitive advantage, Journal of Management, 17(1). pp. 99–120.##Collis, D. J., 1994. Research note: how valuable are organizational capabilities, Strategic Management Journal, 15(8), pp. 143–152.##Crook, T.R., Ketchen, D.J., Combs, J.G.,Todd, S.Y., 2008. Strategic resources and performance: a meta-analysis, Strategic Management Journal, 29(11), pp. 1141-1154.##Cruz-Ros, S., Cruz, T.F.G. and Pérez-Cabañero, C., 2010. Marketing capabilities, stakeholders’ satisfaction, and performance. Service Business, 4(3-4), pp.209-223.##Day, G. S., 1990. Market Driven Strategy: Processes For Creating Value, New York: Free Press.##Deloitte Center for Energy Solutions, 2018. Outlook on Oil &amp; Gas. Accessed online on December 2018.##Eggers, J.P. and Kaplan, S., 2013. Cognition and capabilities: A multi-level perspective. Academy of Management Annals, 7(1), pp.295-340.##Eisenhardt, K.M., 1989. Building theories from case study research. Academy of Management Review, 14(4), pp. 532-550.##Feiler, P., and Teece, D., 2014. Case study, dynamic capabilities and upstream strategy: Supermajor EXP. Energy Strategy Reviews, 3, pp. 14-20.##Garcia, R., Lessard, D., and Singh, A., 2014. Strategic partnering in oil and gas: A capabilities perspective. Energy Strategy Reviews, 3, 21-29.##Grant, R. M., 2010, Contemporary Strategy Analysis, John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd. 7th ed.##Guba, E.G., Lincoln, Y.S., 1994. Competing paradigms in qualitative research, In Denzin, N.K. and Lincoln, Y.S. (Eds), Handbook of Qualitative Research, (pp. 105-117), Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.##Helfat, C. E., Peteraf, M. A., 2015. Managerial cognitive capabilities and the micro foundations of dynamic capabilities. Strategic Management Journal, 36(6)pp.831-850.##Helfat, C.E. and Martin, J.A., 2015. Dynamic managerial capabilities: Review and assessment of managerial impact on strategic change. Journal of Management, 41(5), pp.1281-1312.##Helfat, C.E. and Peteraf, M.A., 2003. The dynamic resource‐based view: Capability lifecycles. Strategic Management Journal, 24(10), pp.997-1010.##Helfat, C.E. and Winter, S.G., 2011. Untangling dynamic and operational capabilities: Strategy for the (N) ever‐changing world. Strategic Management Journal, 32(11), pp.1243-1250.##Inan, G.G. and Bititci, U.S., 2015. Understanding organizational capabilities and dynamic capabilities in the context of micro enterprises: a research agenda. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 210, pp.310-319.##International Energy Agency, 2018. Key World Energy Trends. Accessed online on IEA website on March 2019.##International Standard Organization, 2018. ISO/DIS 20815:2018: Petroleum, Petrochemical and Natural Gas Industries - Production Assurance and Reliability Management. Accessed November 2018.##Jalali, S.H., 2017. How alliance partner characteristics can affect performance? An empirical evidence from emerging economies context. International Journal of Strategic Business Alliances, 6(1-2), pp.1-17.##Kozlowski, S. W. J., Klein, K. J., 2000. A multilevel approach to theory and research in organizations: Contextual, temporal, and emergent processes. In K. J. Klein &amp; S. W. J. Kozlowski (Eds.), Multilevel Theory, Research, and Methods in Organizations: Foundations, Extensions, and New Directions (pp. 3-90). San Francisco: Jossey-Bass.##KPMG, 2015. Building the Midstream Company of the Future: The Reemergence of North America’s Midstream Sector. Accessed on February 2018 on http://kpmg.com##KPMG, 2016. The Reemergence of North America’s Midstream Sector. Accessed on February 2018 on http://kpmg.com##Lichtenstein, B.M.B. and Brush, C.G., 2001. How do “resource bundles” develop and change in new ventures? A dynamic model and longitudinal exploration. Entrepreneurship theory and practice, 25(3), pp.37-58.##Madhok, A., 1997.Cost, value and foreign market entry mode: the transaction and the firm, Strategic Management Journal, 18 pp. 39-61.##Makanga, J.B., 2011. Strategic Capabilities as a Source of Competitive Advantage in The Five Star Hotels in Nairobi Kenya. Unpublished MBA Dissertation, School of Business, University of Nairobi.##Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries, 2018.World Oil Outlook. Geneva, OPEC Secretariat Publishing.##Penrose, E.T., 1959. The Theory of the Growth of the Firm, Wiley, New York, NY.##Peteraf, M.A., 1993. The cornerstones of competitive advantage: a resource‐based view. Strategic Management Journal, 14(3), pp.179-191.##PWC, 2017. New Energy Futures: Perspectives on the Transmission of the Oil and Gas Sector. Accessed online on March 2019.##Shuen, A., Feiler, P. F., &amp; Teece, D. J., 2014. Dynamic capabilities in the upstream oil and gas sector: Managing next generation competition. Energy Strategy Reviews, 3, pp. 5-13.##Sirmon, D.G., Hitt, M.A., Ireland, R.D., Gilbert, B.A., 2011. Resource orchestration to create competitive advantage breadth, depth, and life cycle effects. Journal of Management, 37(5), pp. 1390-1412.##Teece, D.J., 2018, Business models and dynamic capabilities. Long Range Planning, 51, 40-49.##Teece, D.J., Pisano, G., Shuen, A., 1997. Dynamic capabilities and strategic management. Strategic Manag Journal. 18 (7), 509-533.##Wenerferlt, B., 1984. A resource-based view of the firm, Strategic Management Journal, 5(2), pp. 171-80.##Winter, S.G., 2003. Understanding dynamic capabilities. Strategic Management Journal, 24(10), pp.991-995.##Winter, S.G., 2012. Capabilities: Their origins and ancestry, Journal of Management Studies, 49(8), pp.1402-1406.##Zahra, S. A., Sapienza, H. J., Davidsson, P., 2006. Entrepreneurship and dynamic capabilities: A review, model and research agenda, Journal of Management Studies, 43, pp. 917–955.##حمیدی‌زاده.م. ر.، حسین‌زاده شهری. م.، 1385. طراحی مدل شناسایی، ارزیابی و تعیین قابلیت‌های استراتژیک: پژوهشی در شرکت ایران‌خودرو، علوم مدیریت ایران، دوره اول. شماره4. صص1-28.##روملت، ر.، 1395. استراتژی خوب استراتژی بد، ترجمه بابک وطن‌دوست، آریانا قلم، تهران چاپ دوم.##شاه‌حسینی، م.ع.، رنجبر، م.ه.، کیماسی، م.، 1395. شناسایی و ترکیب قابلیت‌های سازمانی در موفقیت رقابتی صنعت نوشیدنی، چشم‌انداز مدیریت بازرگانی، شماره 25. صص 51-67.##عابدی جعفری،ح.، تسلیمی، م. س.، فقیهی، ا.، شیخ‌زاده، م.، 1390. تحلیل مضمون و شبکه مضامین: روشی ساده و کارآمد برای تبیین الگوهای موجود در داده‌های کیفی، اندیشه مدیریت راهبردی، سال پنجم، شماره دوم، شماره پیاپی10، صص151-198.##لافلی، ای.جی.، مارتین، راجر.، 1393.بازی برد راه‌کارهای دستیابی به استراتژی برد. ترجمه سیدحسین جلالی، آریانا قلم،تهران.##مرکز مطالعات زنجیره ارزش در صنعت نفت و گاز، 1395. توصیف وضعیت صنعت پالایش نفت و میعانات گازی کشور، گزارش 101.##ولیان، ح.، کوشکی جهرمی، ع.، بودلائی، ح.، 1396. طراحی مدل رویکرد قابلیت‌های سازمانی مبتنی بر تئوری نقاط مرجع استراتژیک. پژوهش‌های مدیریت راهبردی، سال بیست و سوم، شماره 65،صص131-151.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نقش سیستم مدیریت دانش و نوآوری باز در توسعه ظرفیت نوآوری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Role of knowledge management system and open innovation in developing innovation capacity</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی نقش میانجی­گری نوآوری باز در تأثیر سیستم مدیریت دانش بر ظرفیت نوآوری است. جامعه آماری شامل مدیران شرکت‌های فعال در شهرک صنعتی شماره 2 و نیز شرکت‌های مستقر در پارک علم و فناوری شهر کرمان به تعداد 177 شرکت می­باشد. روش تحقیق ازنظر هدف، کاربردی و ازنظر روش گردآوری داده‌ها، توصیفی - پیمایشی است. ابزار اصلی گردآوری داده‌ها، پرسشنامه است که سطح روایی و پایایی آن، برای تمامی سازه‌ها اندازه‌گیری و تائید شد. پس از تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌ها با استفاده از معادلات ساختاری در قالب نرم‌افزار Amos مشخص شد که سیستم مدیریت دانش بر نوآوری باز و ظرفیت نوآوری تأثیر دارد. همچنین؛ نوآوری باز، تأثیر سیستم مدیریت دانش بر ظرفیت نوآوری را میانجی‌گری می‌کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The purpose of the study was to investigating the role of open innovation in the effect of knowledge management system on innovation capacity. The study population which was an applied and descriptive-survey research was composed of 177 managers of Companies in Industrial Town No. 2 &amp; companies in Kerman Science and Technology Park. The questionnaire was used to collect data.Validity and reliability of the questionnaire were verified and confirmed. After data analysis by Spss &amp; Amos, findings suggested that: knowledge management system had effect on open innovation andinnovation capacity. Also, the impact of knowledge management system on innovation capacity was mediated by open innovation.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>81</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>110</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مهدیه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نگارستانی</Family>
						<NameE>Mahdieh</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Negarestani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت اجرایی، دانشگاه جامع علمی کاربردی، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت اجرایی، دانشگاه جامع</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mnegarestani82@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیستم مدیریت دانش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ظرفیت نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نوآوری باز</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ahn, J.M., et al., 2016. Beyond absorptive capacity in open innovation process: the relationships between openness, capacities and firm performance. Technology Analysis &amp; Strategic Management, 28 (9), pp. 1009-1028.##Alavi, M., Leidner, D.E., 2001. Review: knowledge management and knowledge management systems: conceptual foundations and research issues.MISQ.pp.107–136.##Aloini, D., Pellegrini, L., Lazzarotti, V. and Manzini, R., 2015. Technological strategy, open innovation and innovation performance: evidences on the basis of a structural-equationmodel approach. Meas. Bus. Excell. 19 (3), pp.22–41.##Amirkhanpour, M., Vrontis, D. and Thrassou, A., 2014. Mobile marketing: a contemporary strategic perspective.  International Journal of Technology Marketing 9(3), pp.252-269.##Argote, L., Ingram, P., 2000. Knowledge transfer: a basis for competitive advantage in firms. Organ. Behav. Hum. Decis. Process. 82 (1), pp.150–169.##Ashok, M., Narula, R., Martinez-Noya, A., 2016. How do collaboration and investments in knowledge management affect process innovation in services? Journal of Knowledge Management, Vol. 20 Iss 5 pp. 1004 – 1024.##Bafoutsou, G., Mentzas, G., 2002. Review and functional classification of collaborative systems. Int. J. Inf. Manag. 22 (4), pp.281–305.##Berchicci, L., 2013. Towards an open R&amp;D system: internal R&amp;D investment, external knowledge acquisition and innovative performance. Res. Policy 42 (1), pp.117–127.##Bresciani, S., 2010. Innovation within firms: a survey in the Piedmont area. Int. J. Qual. Innov. 1 (2), pp.138–152.##Boly, V., Morel, L. and Renaud, J., 2003. Towards a Constructivist Approach to Technological Innovation Management: An Overview of the Phenomena in French SME’s. in International Handbook on Innovation, Elsevier Sciences, pp. 790-803.##Bresciani, S., Thrassou, A. and Vrontis, D., 2013. Change through innovation in family businesses: evidence from an Italian sample. World Rev. Entrep. Manag. Sustain. Dev. 9 (2), pp. 195–215.##Carayannis, E.G., Rogers, E.M., Kurihara, K. and Allbritton, M.M., 1998. High-technology spinoffs from government R&amp;D laboratories and research universities. Technovation 18 (1), pp. 1–11.##Chebbi H., Yahiaoui, D., Vrontis, D. and Thrassou, A., 2015. Building Multi-Unit Ambidextrous Organizations – A Transformative Framework, Human Resource Management, 54.##Chesbrough, H., 2004. Managing open innovation. Res. Technol. Manag. 47(1), 23.##Chesbrough, H., Crowther, A. K., 2006. Beyond high tech: early adopters of open innovation in other industries, R&amp;D Management, 36(3). pp. 229-236.##Chin, W. W., 1998. The partial least squares approach for structural equation modeling. In G. A. Marcoulides (Ed.), Methodology for business and management. Modern methods for business research, pp. 295-336.##Cohen, W.M., Levinthal, D.A., 1990. Absorptive capacity: a new perspective on learning and innovation. Adm. Sci. Q. pp.128–152.##Cooke, P., 2007. Regional innovation, entrepreneurship and talent systems, International Journal of entrepreneurship and Innovation Management, 7(2), pp. 101-120.##Darroch, J., 2005. Knowledge management, innovation and firm performance. J. Knowledge management. 9 (3), pp.101–115.##Davenport, T.H., Prusak, L., 1998.Working Knowledge: How Organizations Manage What They Know. Harvard Business Press.##Del Giudice, M., Della Peruta, M.R., 2016. The impact of IT-based knowledge management systems on internal venturing and innovation: a structural equation modeling approach to corporate performance, Journal of Knowledge Management, 20(3), pp.484-498.##Felin, T., Zenger, T., 2013. Closed or open innovation? Problem solving and the governance choice, Research Policy. V43 (5), pp. 914-925.##Ferraris, A., Santoro, G. and Dezi, L., 2017. How MNC’s subsidiaries may improve their innovative performance? The role of external sources and knowledge management capabilities, Journal of Knowledge Management, 21 (3), pp.540-552.##Ferreras-Méndez, J.L., Fernández-Mesa, A. and Alegre, J., 2016. The Relationship between Knowledge Search Strategies and Absorptive Capacity: a Deeper Look Technovation. Technovation, (54), pp. 48-61.##Foss, N.J., Laursen, K. and Pedersen, T., 2011. Linking customer interaction and innovation: the mediating role of new organizational practices, Organization Science, 22(4), pp. 980-999.##Garud, R., Nayyar, P.R., 1994. Transformative capacity: continual structuring by intertemporal technology transfer. Strateg. Manag. J. 15 (5), pp.365–385.##Grant, R.M., 1996. Toward a knowledge-based theory of the firm. Strateg. Manag. J. 17 (S2), pp.109–122.##Gulati, R., 1999. Network location and learning: the influence of network resources and firm capabilities on alliance formation. Strateg. Manag. J. 20 (5), pp.397–420.##Ichijo, K., Von Krogh, G. and Nonaka, I., 1998. Knowledge enablers. Knowing in Firms: Understanding, Managing and Measuring Knowledge, pp. 173–203.##Jung, D., Chow C. and Wu A., 2003. The Role Transformational Leadership in Enhancing Organizational Innovation: Hypotheses and Some Preliminary Findings, Leadership Quarterly, pp. 525-544.##Kale, P., Singh, H., 2007. Building firm capabilities through learning: the role of the alliance learning process in alliance capability and firm-level alliance success. Strateg.Manag. J. 28 (10), pp.981–1000.##Khilji, S.E., Mroczkowski, T. and Bernstein, B., 2006. Frominvention to innovation: toward developing an integrated innovation model for biotech firms*. J. Prod. Innov. Manag. 23 (6), pp.528–540.##King, W.R., Marks, P.V., 2008. Motivating knowledge sharing through a knowledge management system. Omega 36 (1), pp.131–146.##Koc, T., &amp; Ceylan, C., 2007. Factors Impacting the Innovative Capacity in Large Scale Companies. Technovation, 27, pp.105–114.##Laursen, K., Salter, A., 2006. Open for innovation: the role of openness in explaining innovation performance among UK manufacturing firms. Strateg. Manag. J. 27 (2), pp.131–150.##Lee, H., Choi, B., 2003. Knowledge management enablers, processes, and organizational performance: an integrative view and empirical examination. J. Manag. Inf. Syst. 20 (1), pp.179–228.##Lichtenthaler, U., Lichtenthaler, E., 2009. A capability-based framework for open innovation: complementing absorptive capacity. J. Manag. Stud. 46 (8), pp.1315–1338.##Lim, K., 2004. The relationship between research and innovation in the semiconductor and pharmaceutical industries, Research Policy (33), pp. 287–321.##Lopez-Nicolas, C., Soto-Acosta, P., 2010. Analyzing ICT adoption and use effects on knowledge creation: an empirical investigation in SMEs. Int. J. Inf. Manag. 30(6), pp.521–528.##Lopes, C.M., Scavarda A., Fernando, A.L., TavaresThomé, A.M. and RoeheVaccaro, G.L, 2017. An analysis of the interplay between organizational sustainability, knowledge management, and open innovation, Journal of Cleaner Production Volume 142(1), pp. 476-488.##Malhotra, Y., 2000. Knowledge management for e-business performance: advancing information strategy to “internet time”. Inf. Strateg. 16 (4), pp.5–16.##Martinez-Conesa, I., Soto-Acosta, P. and Carayannis, E.G., 2017. On the path towards open innovation: assessing the role of knowledge management capability and environmental dynamism in SMEs, Journal of Knowledge Management, 21(3), pp.553-570.##Merono-Cerdan, A.L., Soto-Acosta, P. and López-Nicolás, C., 2007. Analyzing collaborative technologies&#039; effect on performance through intranet use orientations. J. Enterp. Inf. Manag. 21 (1), pp.39–51.##Morel, L. &amp; Boly, V., 2005. Mastering the Innovativeness Potential: results of an expert consultation?, REAd – Special Issue Nº. 42.##Nonaka, I., 1994. A dynamic theory of organizational knowledge creation. Organ. Sci. 5 (1), pp.14–37.##Park, D. Krishnan, H.A., 2001. Supplier Selection Practices among Small Firms in the United States: Testing Three Models, Journal of small business anagement (93)3, pp. 259-271.##Porter, A.L., 2007. Tech Mining to Drive Open Innovation, Proceedings of the First International Conference on Technology Innovation, Risk Management and Supply Chain Management, pp.1-13.##Prajogo, D. I., Ahmed, P. K., 2006. Relationships between Innovation Stimulus, Innovation Capacity, and Innovation Performance. R&amp;D Management, 36(5), pp. 499-515.##Santoro, G., Vrontis, D., Thrassou, A. and Dezi, L., 2017. The Internet of Things: Building a knowledge management system for open innovation and knowledge management capacity, J. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, 136, pp. 347-354.##Santoro, G., Ferraris, A., Giacosa, E. and Giovando, G., 2016. How SMEs engage in open innovation: a survey. J. Knowl. Econ, pp.1–14.##Marques, C.S., Ferreira, J., 2009. SME Innovative Capacity, Competitive Advantage and Performance in a Traditional Industrial Ragion of Portugal, Journal of Technology Management &amp; Innovation. 4(4). Pp.53-68.##Smith, E.A., 2001. The role of tacit and explicit knowledge in the workplace. J. knowledge management. 5 (4), pp.311–321.##Soto-Acosta, P., MeroñO-Cerdan, A.L., 2008. Analyzing e-business value creation from a resource-based perspective. Int. J. Inf. Manag. 28 (1), pp.49–60.##Stata, R., Almond, P., 1989. Organizational learning: the key to management innovation. Train. Dev. Sourcebook 2, pp.31–42.##Su, C.T., Yung-Hsin, C. and Sha, D.Y., 2006. Linking innovative product development with customer knowledge: a data-mining approach, Technovation (26), pp.784–795.##Thrassou, A., Vrontis, D., Chebbi, H. and Yahiaoui, D., 2012. A preliminary strategic marketing framework for new product development. J. Trans. Manage. 17 (1), pp. 21–44.##Trejo, J.M., Gutiérrez, J.S. and Guzman, G.M., 2015.  The customer knowledge management and innovation, Contaduríay Administración, 61(3), pp. 456-477.##Vanhaverbeke, W., Cloodt, M., 2014. Theories of the firm and open innovation. New Frontiers in Open Innovation. Oxford University Press, Oxford.##Vrontis, D., Thrassou, A., Chebbi, H. and Yahiaoui, D., 2012. Transcending innovativeness towards strategic reflexivity. Qual. Mark. Res. Int. J. 15 (4), pp. 420–437.##Wang, C.H., Chang, C.H. and Shen, G.C., 2015. The effect of inbound open innovation on firm performance: evidence from high-tech industry. Technol. Forecast. Soc. Chang. 99, pp. 222–230.##Yeh, Y.J., Lai, S.Q. and Ho, C.T., 2006. Knowledge management enablers: a case study. Ind. Manag. Data Syst. 106 (6), pp.793–810.##Zobel, A.K., 2016. Benefiting from open innovation: a multidimensional model of absorptive capacity. Journal of Product Innovation Managmant, 34(3), pp. 269-288.##اسماعیل‌پور، رضا؛ دوستدار، محمد و طاهر پرور، نسترن، 1395، مدیریت دانش مشتری و نقش آن در نوآوری مستمر و عملکرد برتر (مطالعه  موردی: بانک‌های خصوصی سطح استان گیلان)، نشریه مدیریت بازرگانی، دوره 8، شماره 1،صص 28-1.##آراستی، محمدرضا؛ کرمی پور، آزیتا و قریشی، بابک، 1388، شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر ظرفیت نوآوری بنگاه‌های اقتصادی: مطالعه موردی شرکت‌های خودکارسازی صنعتی ایران، فصلنامه علوم مدیریت ایران، سال چهارم، شماره 15،صص 1-30.##پور اشراف، علی، 1393، بررسی ارتباط میان ابعاد مدیریت دانش با نوآوری مطالعه موردی: آموزشگاه‌های آزاد استان تهران، پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه جامع علمی کاربردی.##جاوید، غزاله. باقری نژاد، جعفر، 1391، ارتباط فرایند نوآوری باز و توانمندی جذب بنگاه‌ها. فصلنامه تخصصی پارک‌ها و مراکز رشد، سال هشتم، شماره 31، صص 53-61.##عرب حجی، مهرداد، 1394، بررسی تأثیر جذب دانش مشتری بر نوآوری سازمانی (مطالعه موردی شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان) پایان‌نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی ‌واحد شاهرود.##فرزانه، محمد؛ روح‌بخش، هاجر و بذرافشان، مجتبی، 1395، نقش واسطه‌ای مدیریت دانش در ارتباط میان رهبری تحول‌آفرین و نوآوری سازمانی، فصلنامه رسالت مدیریت دولتی، دوره 7، شماره 3، صص 31-15.##صنوبر، ناصر؛ سلمانی، بهزاد؛ تجویدی، مینا، 1390، تأثیر محرک‌های نوآوری بر ظرفیت نوآوری شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان، فصلنامه علمی پژوهشی سیاست علم و فناوری، سال چهارم، شماره 2،صص 91-107.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>نقش منابع سازمانی و قابلیت نوآوری در خلق مزیت رقابتی شرکت های دانش بنیان نوپا با تعدیل گری عملکرد تجاری سازی فناوری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>The Role of Organizational Resources and Innovation Capability in Creating the Competitive Advantage of Knowledge Based Companies: The moderating role of Technology Commercialization Performance</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>شرکت های دانش بنیان می توانند از طریق به کارگیری بهره ور از منابع سازمانی و ارتقا پیوسته قابلیت نوآوری به مزیت رقابتی دست یابند. مهم است که بدانیم عملکرد تجاری سازی فناوری به عنوان مهم ترین مرحله مدیریت فناوری، چقدر می تواند تاثیر منابع سازمانی و قابلیت نوآوری بر مزیت رقابتی را تعدیل کند. هدف پژوهش حاضر مطالعه تاثیر منابع سازمانی و قابلیت نوآوری بر مزیت رقابتی شرکت‌های‌ دانش‌بنیان‌ نوپا با در نظر گرفتن متغیر تعدیل گر عملکرد تجاری سازی فناوری است. ابـزار گردآوری داده ها پرسشنامه استاندارد بوده و جامعه آماری پژوهش حاضر 166 شرکت دانش بنیان نوپا مستقر در مراکز رشد می باشند که از میان 166 مدیر ارشد آن ها، تعداد نمونـه بـا اسـتفاده از فرمول کوکران و با توجه به اطمینان از برگشت پرسشـنامه کـافی128 نفـر تعیـین شـد، کـه در نهایت 117 پرسشنامه به روش نمونه گیری طبقه ای تصادفی ساده برای تحلیل جمع آوری گردید. پژوهش حاضر از لحاظ هدف کاربردی، روش آن توصیفی و از نوع پیمایشی می باشد، که نتایج به‌صورت‌ مدل‌سازی‌ معادلات‌ساختاری‌ و به‌روش‌ حداقل‌ مربعات‌ جزئی‌(به‌وسیله نرم‌افزارSmart PLS) استخراج‌ شده‌ است. یافته‌ها‌ نشان‌ می‌دهند که منابع سازمانی و قابلیت نوآوری بر مزیت رقابتی شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان نوپا‌ تاثیر مثبت و معناداری دارند. همچنین عملکرد تجاری سازی فناوری، تاثیر منابع سازمانی و قابلیت نوآوری بر مزیت رقابتی را تعدیل می کند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>knowledge-based companies can achieve competitive advantage through employing productivity from organizational resources and continuously upgrading innovation capability. In this regard, it is important to understand how the technology commercialization performance as the most important stage in technology management can moderating the impact of innovation capability and organizational resources on competitive advantage. Therefore, the purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of innovation capability and organizational resources on the competitive advantage of startup companies by considering the moderating variable of technology commercialization performance. The statistical population of This study was 166 top managers in growth stage of centers of growth of science and technology parks and the sample size was selected according to Cochran&#039;s formula by stratified random sampling method to ensure the retum of number of 128 respondents was completed. Finally, 117 questionnaires were collected and entered into the analysis stage. The present research is applied in a practical, descriptive and survey-oriented way. The results are extracted by structural equations modeling using partial least squares (by Smart PLS software). The findings show that innovation capabilitiy and organizational resources are effective on the competitive advantage of Knowledge Based Companies, as well as the moderating role of the technology commercialization performance in the impact of innovation capabilities and organizational resources on the competitive advantage.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>11</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>130</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شیرازی</Family>
						<NameE>Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Shirazi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشکده مدیریت و اقتصاد، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت تکنولوژی، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hossein.shirazi63@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>غلامرضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>هاشم زاده خوراسگانی</Family>
						<NameE>Gholamreza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hashemzadeh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار و عضو هیئت علمی گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد جنوب، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار و عضو هیئت علمی گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>gh_hashemzadeh@azad.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رادفر</Family>
						<NameE>reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>radfar</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد و عضو هیئت علمی گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد و عضو هیئت علمی گروه مدیریت، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>radfar@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>تقی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ترابی</Family>
						<NameE>Taghi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Torabi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار و عضو هیئت علمی گروه اقتصاد، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد علوم و تحقیقات، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار و عضو هیئت علمی گروه اقتصاد، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ttttorabi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>&quot;منابع سازمانی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قابلیت های نوآورانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عملکرد تجاری سازی فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مزیت رقابتی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شرکت های دانش بنیان نوپا&quot;</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>ATUAHENE-GIMA, K. &amp; LI, H. 2004. Strategic decision comprehensiveness and new product development outcomes in new technology ventures. Academy of Management Journal, Volum(47), pp. 583-597.##CACCIOLATTI, L. &amp; LEE, S. H. 2016. Revisiting the relationship between marketing capabilities and firm performance: The moderating role of market orientation, marketing strategy and organisational power. Journal of Business Research, Volum(69), pp. 5597-5610.##CAMISÓN, C. &amp; VILLAR-LÓPEZ, A. 2014. Organizational innovation as an enabler of technological innovation capabilities and firm performance. Journal of business research, Volum(67), pp. 2891-2902.##CHEN, C.-J. 2009. Technology commercialization, incubator and venture capital, and new venture performance. Journal of Business research, Volum(62), pp. 93-103.##CHEW, D. A., YAN, S. &amp; CHEAH, C. Y. 2008. Core capability and competitive strategy for construction SMEs in China. Chinese Management Studies, Volum(2), pp. 203-214.##CLULOW, V., GERSTMAN, J. &amp; BARRY, C. 2003. The resource-based view and sustainable competitive advantage: the case of a financial services firm. Journal of European Industrial Training, Volum(27), pp. 220-232.##DISTANONT, A. &amp; KHONGMALAI, O. 2018. The role of innovation in creating a competitive advantage. Kasetsart Journal of Social Sciences.##HAGEDOORN, J. &amp; CLOODT, M. 2003. Measuring innovative performance: is there an advantage in using multiple indicators? Research policy, Volum(32), pp. 1365-1379.##HANEDA, S. &amp; ITO, K. 2018. Organizational and human resource management and innovation: Which management practices are linked to product and/or process innovation? Research Policy, Volum(47), pp. 194-208.##JEYAVELU, S. 2007. Organizational identity and sustainable competitive advantage: combining resource based view and configuration approach.##KEEGAN, W. J. &amp; SCHLEGELMILCH, B. B. 2001. Global marketing management: A European perspective, Pearson education.##KHALIL, T. 2000. Management of technology: The key to competitiveness and wealth creation: McGraw-Hill Science. Engineering &amp; Mathematics.##KIM, S. K., LEE, B. G., PARK, B. S. &amp; OH, K. S. 2011. The effect of R&amp;D, technology commercialization capabilities and innovation performance. Technological and Economic Development of Economy, Volum(17), pp.  563-578.##LEE, J.-S. &amp; HSIEH, C.-J. 2010. A research in relating entrepreneurship, marketing capability, innovative capability and sustained competitive advantage. Journal of Business &amp; Economics Research, Volume(8), pp. 109-119.##LI, Y., LI*, L., LIU, Y. &amp; WANG, L. 2005. Linking management control system with product development and process decisions to cope with environment complexity. International Journal of Production Research, Volume(43), pp. 2577-2591.##LIN, Y., WANG, Y. &amp; KUNG, L. 2015. Influences of cross-functional collaboration and knowledge creation on technology commercialization: Evidence from high-tech industries. Industrial marketing management, Volum(49),pp.  128-138.##LUMPKIN, G. T. &amp; DESS, G. G. 1996. Clarifying the entrepreneurial orientation construct and linking it to performance. Academy of management Review, Volum(21), pp. 135-172.##NAJAFI-TAVANI, S., NAJAFI-TAVANI, Z., NAUDÉ, P., OGHAZI, P. &amp; ZEYNALOO, E. 2018. How collaborative innovation networks affect new product performance: Product innovation capability, process innovation capability, and absorptive capacity. Industrial Marketing Management.##PORTER, M. E. &amp; TEISBERG, E. O. 2004. Redefining competition in health care. Harvard business review, pp. 64-77.##REAMER, A. 2003. Technology transfer and commercialization: their role in economic development. www. eda. gov/PDF/eda_ttc. pdf.##ROMIJN, H. &amp; ALBALADEJO, M. 2002. Determinants of innovation capability in small electronics and software firms in southeast England. Research policy, Volum(31), pp. 1053-1067.##SADRI, G. &amp; LEES, B. 2001. Developing corporate culture as a competitive advantage. Journal of Management Development, Volum(20), pp. 853-859.##SARANGA, H., GEORGE, R., BEINE, J. &amp; ARNOLD, U. 2018. Resource configurations, product development capability, and competitive advantage: An empirical analysis of their evolution. Journal of Business Research, Volume(85), pp. 32-50.##SIGERA, I. &amp; CAHOON, S. 2018. Processes Adopted to Integrate Intangible Resources in Global Acquisitions among Container Lines: Perceptions of Acquirer and Acquired. The Asian Journal of Shipping and Logistics, Volume(34), pp. 1-11.##TEECE, D. J. 2009. Dynamic capabilities and strategic management: Organizing for innovation and growth, Oxford University Press on Demand.##TEECE, D. J., PISANO, G. &amp; SHUEN, A. 1997. Dynamic capabilities and strategic management. Strategic management journal, Volum(18), pp. 509-533.##ZAHRA, S. A. &amp; NIELSEN, A. P. 2002. Sources of capabilities, integration and technology commercialization. Strategic Management Journal, Volum(23), pp. 377-398.##ZHANG, M. &amp; HARTLEY, J. L. 2018. Guanxi, IT systems, and innovation capability: The moderating role of proactiveness. Journal of Business Research, Volum(90), pp. 75-86.##پاک نیت،م، انصاری،ر و شاهین،آ،1395. تحلیل تاثیر توانمندی های نوآوری فناورانه بر تجاری سازی فناوری و عملکرد شرکت های دانش بنیان استان اصفهان، نشریه مدیریت نوآوری، شماره3، صص59-84.##زندحسامی، ح و آشتیانی­پور،ز، 1392. تحلیل چگونگی تاثیر قابلیت‎های نوآوری‎های فناورانه بر رقابت پذیری شرکت‎های کوچک و متوسط، نشریه مدیریت نوآوری، شماره 2، صص 1-24.##حسین‌زاده‌شهری،م و شاهینی،ص،1397. تاثیر قابلیت پویا و قابلیت نوآوری بر مزیت رقابتی، نشریه کاوش­های مدیریت بازرگانی، شماره 19، صص123-141.##حقیقی کفاش،م، حاجی پور،ب، مظلومی، ن و مومنی، م،1390. مدل‌سازی قابلیت نوآوری سازمانی، فصلنامه علمی ـ پژوهشی مدیریت سازمان های دولتی، شماره 3، صص31-42.##خورشید،ص و نوجوان،ص،1394. تحلیل رقابت جویی و انتخاب استراتژی رقابتی مبتنی بر مدل نیروهای رقابتی پورتر، تحلیل سلسله مراتبی فازی و تحلیل پوششی داده، مطالعات مدیریت صنعتی، شماره11، صص61-97.##خیاطیان،م.ص، طباطبائیان،س.ح، امیری،م و الیاسی،م، 1393. تحلیلی بر عوامل مؤثر بر رشد و پایداری شرکت های دانش بنیان در ایران. نشریه نوآوری و ارزش آفرینی، شماره 6، صص 57-74.##هاشم­زاده،ا، حاجی حسینی،ر، رادفر،ر و ملک­زاده،ک،1393. عوامل مؤثر در ایجاد توانمندی­های نوآوری (مطالعه موردی یک مرکز پژوهشی صنعت هوایی در ایران)، مدیریت نوآوری، شماره3، صص75-100.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>آینده نگاری تاثیر فناوریهای همگرا بر سیاستهای دولت در قابلیت آفرینی نوآورانه</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A Foresight on the Impact of Convergent Technologies on Public Policies for Innovative capability Building</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>مطالعه حاضر تلاش دارد تا نقش و کارکرد دولت در قابلیت‌آفرینی نوآورانه را تحت تأثیر جریان همگرایی فناورانه مورد تحلیلی آینده-نگرانه قرار دهد. رویکرد این تحقیق، کیفی و توصیفی بوده و در آن از استراتژی‌های تحلیل ریخت‌شناختی و سناریوسازی استفاده شده است؛ بدین صورت که رایج‌ترین سازوکارهای حمایت دولت از فرایند تقویت قابلیت نوآورانه شناسایی و در قالب مدلی ارائه و به صورت موازی، مهمترین دستاوردهای حاصل از کاربرد فناوری‌های همگرا نیز بر اساس یکی از مدل‌های معتبر استخراج شده است. سپس با تشکیل نشست خبرگان و اجرای تکنیک تحلیل ریخت‌شناختی، شدت تاثیرگذاری جریان همگرایی فناورانه بر هرکدام از سازوکارهای حمایتی مورد برآورد قرار گرفته و با اجرای تکنیک سناریوسازی، سه سناریوی بدیل از آینده نقش دولت در قابلیت نوآوری تحت تاثیر فناوریهای همگرا (شامل سناریوهای حداقلی، میانه و حداکثری) طراحی شده است. نتایج تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که با بهره‌گیری هوشمندانه از ظرفیت‌های انقلابی فناوری‌های همگرا می‌توان آینده مطلوب از نقش دولت در توسعه قابلیت نوآورانه را زمینه‌سازی نمود و این جایگاه را در مقایسه با شرایط فعلی به شدت تکامل بخشید.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The present study attempts to introduce the role and function of the government in innovative capability building under the influence of the technological convergence flow as a foresight study and introduce the predictable futures of convergent technologies (NBIC). The approach of this research is qualitative and descriptive and has been used in morphological and scenario-building strategies. Thus, the most common mechanisms of public support in the process of innovation capability enhancement are identified and modeled; in parallel, the most important achievements of convergent technologies are derived from one of the valid models. Then, the intensity of the impacts of technological convergence on each aspect of governmental support is estimated through expert panel &amp; morphological analysis techniques. Finally, by implementing the scenario-building technique, three alternative scenarios of the future (including minimal, moderate, and maximum scenarios) are designed. The results show that by utilizing intelligently the revolutionary capacities of convergent technologies, the governments can establish the desirable future of the role of governance in development of innovative capabilities, and this position can be evolved strongly compared to the current situation.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>131</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>160</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>هدایت</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>کارگر شورکی</Family>
						<NameE>Hedayat</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Kargar Shouroki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت، دانشگاه یزد، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت، دانشگاه یزد، ایران.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hkargar@stu.yazd.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید حبیب اله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>میرغفوری</Family>
						<NameE>seyed Habibollah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mirghafoori</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشیار بخش مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه یزد، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشیار بخش مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه یزد، ایران.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mirghafoori@yazd.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سلطانی</Family>
						<NameE>Ali Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Soltani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار، پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار، پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری، ایران.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>soltani@tsi.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حبیب</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>زارع</Family>
						<NameE>Habib</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Zare</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استادیار بخش مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه یزد، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استادیار بخش مدیریت صنعتی، دانشگاه یزد، ایران.</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>zarehabib@yazd.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>قابلیت نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سیاستهای دولت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>همگرایی فناورانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>فناوری‌های همگرا</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>انبیک (شزان)</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>سناریوسازی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Aegerter, A. and Benziger, A., 2015. Study the effect of internet on the human abilities in future. International Journal of Advanced and Applied Sciences, 2(5), pp.1-5.##Alexe, C. and Alexe, C., 2016. The Importance of the Dimensions of the Innovation Management in Evaluating the Innovation Capability of the Firms in the Machine Building Industry in Romania. Procedia Technology, Volume(22), pp.999-1005.##Aryanto, R., Fontana, A. and Afiff, A., 2015. Strategic Human Resource Management, Innovation Capability and Performance: An Empirical Study in Indonesia Software Industry. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume(211), pp.874–879.##Bayarçelik, E., Taşel, F. and Apak, S., 2014. A Research on Determining Innovation Factors for SMEs. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume(150), pp.202–211.##Beckert, B., Blümel, C., Friedewald, M. and Thielmann, A., 2008. Converging technologies and their impact on the social sciences and humanities (CONTECS). Germany, Karlsruhe: Fraunhofer Institute for Systems and Innovation Research.##Cai, S., 2011. The age of synthesis: From cognitive science to converging technologies and hereafter. Chinese Science Bulletin, 56(6), pp.465–475.##Clarkson, G. and Dekorte, D., 2006. The Problem of Patent Thickets in Convergent Technologies. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 1093(1), pp.180–200.##Cobb, M. and Gano, G., 2012. Evaluating Structured Deliberations about Emerging Technologies: Post-Process Participant Evaluation. International Journal of Emerging Technologies and Society, Volume(10), pp.96-110.##Dhewanto, W., Prasetio, E., Ratnaningtyas, S., Herliana, S., Chaerudin, R., Ainaa, Q., Bayuningrat, R. and Rachmawaty, E., 2012. Moderating Effect of Cluster on Firm’s Innovation Capability and Business Performance: A Conceptual Framework. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume(65), pp.867-872.##Edler, J. and Georghiou, L., 2007. Public procurement and innovation—Resurrecting the demand side. Research Policy, Volume(36), pp. 949–963.##Edwards-Schachter, M., 2018. The nature and variety of innovation. International Journal of Innovation Studies, 2(2), pp.65–79.##Farrokhi H., GhodratiToostani I., Farasatkhah M. and Ekhtiari H., 2014. Sustainable Development of Cognitive Science and Technology Ecosystem; an Overview to the “Human Brain Project” as a Functioning Sample. Basic and Clinical Neuroscience, 5(1), pp.4-10.##Georghiou, L., Edler, J., Uyarra, E. and Yeow, J., 2014. Policy instruments for public procurement of innovation: Choice, design and assessment. Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, Volume(86), pp. 1-12.##Ghazinoory, S. and Hajishirzi, R., 2012. Using Actor-Network Theory to identify the role of IT in cognitive science in Iran. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume(32), pp.153-162.##Hayat, E., Liyanage, C., Haigh, R. and Amaratunga, D., 2018. Development of Research and Innovation Capacity Index of HEIs on Disaster Resilience Related Studies. Procedia Engineering, Volume(212), pp.1249–1256.##Hermans, F., Geerling-Eiff, F., Potters, J. and Klerkx, L., 2018. Public-private partnerships as systemic agricultural innovation policy instruments – Assessing their contribution to innovation system function dynamics. NJAS - Wageningen Journal of Life Sciences. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.njas.2018.10.001##Ince, H., Imamoglu, S. and Turkcan, H., 2016. The Effect of Technological Innovation Capabilities and Absorptive Capacity on Firm Innovativeness: A Conceptual Framework. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume(235), pp.764-770.##Jian, C. and Zhi-guo, L., 2012. Improve Technological Innovation Capability of Enterprises in Hebei Province by Absorbing Innovation Resources from Beijing and Tianjin. Procedia Engineering, Volume(29), pp.1501-1505.##Kastenhofer, K., 2010. Do we need a specific kind of technoscience assessment? Taking the convergence of science and technology seriously. Poiesis and Praxis, 7(1-2), pp.37-54.##Kim, M. and Kim, C., 2012. On A Patent Analysis Method for Technological Convergence. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume(40), pp.657–663.##Kim, P., 2012. A Study on the Identification of Cutting-Edge ICT-Based Converging Technologies. ETRI Journal, 34(4), pp.602–612.##Lawson, B. and Samson, D., 2001. Developing Innovation Capability in Organisations: A Dynamic Capabilities Approach. International Journal of Innovation Management, 5(3), pp.377-400.##Matyushenko I. and Khaustova V., 2015. Modern Trands on Bioeconomy Development in The World: The Introduction of NBIC-technologies in Biomedicine. IJBRITISH, 2(2), pp.103-118.##McIntosh, D., 2008. The Transhuman Security Dilemma. Journal of Evolution and Technology, 21(2), pp.32-48.##Obwegeser, N. and Müller, S.D., 2018. Innovation and public procurement: Terminology, concepts, and Applications. Technovation, 74-75, pp.1-17.##Rajapathirana, R. and Hui, Y., 2018. Relationship between innovation capability, innovation type, and firm performance. Journal of Innovation and Knowledge, 3(1), pp.44-55.##Roco, M., 2007. Possibilities for global governance of converging technologies. Journal of Nanoparticle Research, 10(1), pp.11-29.##Scupola, A. and Zanfei, A., 2016. Governance and innovation in public sector services: The case of the digital library. Government Information Quarterly, Volume(33), pp. 237–249.##Simatupang, T. and Widjaja, F., 2012. Benchmarking of Innovation Capability in the Digital Industry. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume(65), pp.948-954.##Sulistiyani, R. and Harwiki, W., 2016. How SMEs Build Innovation Capability Based on Knowledge Sharing Behavior? Phenomenological Approach. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume(219), pp.741-747.##Sulistyo, H. and Siyamtinah, 2016. Innovation capability of SMEs through entrepreneurship, marketing capability, relational capital and empowerment. Asia Pacific Management Review, 21(4), pp.196-203.##Swierstra, T., Boenink, M., Walhout, B. and Van Est, R., 2009. Converging Technologies, Shifting Boundaries. NanoEthics, 3(3), pp.213-216.##Tello-Gamarra, J. and Zawislak, P., 2013. Transactional capability: Innovation&#039;s missing link. Journal of Economics Finance and Administrative Science, 18(34), pp.2-8.##Turner, J., Klerkx, L., White, T., Nelson, T., Everett-Hincks, J., Mackay, A. and Botha, N., 2017. Unpacking systemic innovation capacity as strategic ambidexterity: How projects dynamically configure capabilities for agricultural innovation. Land Use Policy, Volume(68), pp.503-523.##Wang, J., 2018. Innovation and government intervention: A comparison of Singapore and Hong Kong. Research Policy, 47(2), pp.399-412.##Wei-li, C. and Cai-jie, W., 2012. Study of the Construction of Assessment System on Regional Innovation Capacity in Knowledge Management. Procedia Engineering, Volume(29), pp.1830-1834.##Xue, C. and Xu, Y., 2017. Influence Factor Analysis of Enterprise IT Innovation Capacity Based on System Dynamics. Procedia Engineering, Volume(174), pp.232-239.##Yeşil, S., Koska, A. and Büyükbeşe, T., 2013. Knowledge Sharing Process, Innovation Capability and Innovation Performance: An Empirical Study. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume(75), pp.217-225.##Zawislak, P., Cherubini Alves, A., Tello-Gamarra, J., Barbieux, D. and Reichert, F., 2012. Innovation Capability: From Technology Development to Transaction Capability. Journal of technology management and innovation, 7(2), pp.14-27.##Zehir, C., Köle, M. and Yıldız, H., 2015. The Mediating Role of Innovation Capability on Market Orientation and Export Performance: An Implementation on SMEs in Turkey. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, Volume(207), pp.700-708.##Zhen, H., 2011. Research on the Evaluation of China&#039;s Provincial Eco-Innovation Capability. Energy Procedia, Volume(5), pp.647-653.##فرتاش، ک.، الیاسی، م.، قاضی نوری، س. و طباطبائیان، س.، 1396. یادگیری سیاستی در سیاست‌های توسعه فناوری و نوآوری ایران. مدیریت نوآوری، 6 (2)، صص 1-30.##مجیدپور، م.، و نامداریان، ل.، 1394. شناسایی موانع اجرای اسناد سیاست علم و فناوری کشور. مدیریت نوآوری، 4 (4)، صص 31-60.##محسنی کیاسری، م.، محمدی، م.، جعفرنژاد، ا.، مختارزاده، ن. و اسدی فرد، ر.، 1396. دسته‌بندی ابزارهای سیاست نوآوری تقاضامحور با استفاده از رویکرد فراترکیب. مدیریت نوآوری، 6 (2)، صص 109-138.##محمدی، م.، الیاسی، م.، تقوی­فرد، م.، حاجی حسینی، ح. و دلاور، ع.، 1391. مدل‌سازی شکل‌گیری نظام نوآوری فناورانه در بخش زیست‌فناوری ایران با استفاده از مدل یابی معادلات ساختاری. مدیریت نوآوری، 1 (1)، صص  21-40.##نامداریان، ل.، حسن­زاده، ع. و مجیدپور، م.، 1393. ارزیابی تأثیر آینده­نگاری برسیاست­گذاری علم، فناوری و نوآوری. مدیریت نوآوری، 3 (2)، صص 73-102.##نامداریان، ل.، حسن­زاده، ع.، الهی، ش. و مجیدپور، م.، 1392. چارچوبی برای هم‌راستایی آینده‌نگاری انطباقی با سیاست­گذاری مبتنی بر شواهد علم، فناوری و نوآوری. مدیریت نوآوری، 2 (1)، صص 21-50.##نوروزی، ن.، الهی، ش.، حسن­زاده، ع.، و حاجی حسینی، ح.، 1393. ارائه چارچوبی از ابزارهای سیاستی علم و فناوری، با استفاده از رویکرد فراترکیب. مدیریت نوآوری، 3 (2)، صص 103-124.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				