<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Modeling the Formation of Technological Innovation System in Iran&#039;s Biotechnology Sector Using Structural Equation Modeling</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مدلسازى شکل گیرى نظام نوآورى فناورانه در بخش زیست فناورى ایران با استفاده از مدل یابی معادلات ساختارى</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>40</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>21</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14593</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده علوم و فنون دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>الیاسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد تقی</FirstName>
					<LastName>تقوی فرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حجت الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاجی حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عطیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>دلاور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>17</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The main objective of this study is to provide a model for the formation of emerging technological innovation system in Iran&#039;s biotechnology sector. In this study which uses qualitative and quantitative methods, the historical development of the formation of this sector is analyzed, taking the functional approach of Technological Innovation System (TIS) concept. Using historical data mapping, the evolution of different functions and activities is charted in this paper. By conducting factor analysis and structural equation modeling on 103 questionnaires, the functions and activities of the conceptual model are confirmed and the causal relationships between different functions are mapped. Based on the results, 7 functions and several activities are identified for the formation of emerging technological innovation systems in Iran. The results indicate that the government has a key role through influencing the functions, such as directing research and innovation, institutionalization and legalization. Therefore, the government&#039;s functions and activities are the main drivers of the formation and development of these sectors in Iran, and also simultaneous development of knowledge and market capacities facilitate the process.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با توجه به اهمیت روزافزون فناورى‌هاى نوظهور مانند نانوفناورى، زیست‌فناورى و فناورى اطلاعات و ارتباطات، در این تحقیق سعى شد نحوه شکل گیرى و رشد بخش زیست‌فناورى ایران با استفاده از رویکرد کارکردى نظام نوآورى فناورانه، مورد بررسى و تحلیل قرار گیرد. براى این منظور با بهرهگیرى از فن &quot; نگاشت تاریخى دادهها&quot; و مصاحبه با برخى از فعالان بخش زیست فناورى و بررسى و تحلیل محتواى اسناد و فعالیتهاى انجام شده در آن، تحلیل کیفى بر نحوه شکل‌گیرى تاریخى آن در کشور انجام شد. بر اساس نتایج این تحلیل و مبانى نظرى تحقیق، مدل اولیهاى براى شکلگیرى کارکردهاى نظام نوآورى در این بخش مشتمل بر 15 فرضیه براى مسیر تاثیرگذارى کارکردها طراحى گردید. در ادامه، با انجام تحلیلى بر 103 پرسشنامه جمع آورى شده از خبرگان بخش زیست فناورى، پس از آزمون سازههاى مدل به روش تحلیل عاملى، مدل و مسیر تاثیرگذارى کارکردهاى مختلف بر یکدیگر با کمک مدلیابى ساختارى استخراج شد. نتایج این تحقیق نشان داد که نقش دولت در شکلگیرى کارکردهاى نهادینه سازى و قانونمندسازى، هدایت فصلنامه علمى - پژوهشى تحقیقات و نوآورى، نقشى کلیدى بوده که باعث شکلگیرى بقیه کارکردهاى نظام نوآورى زیست فناورى در ایران شده است. البته وجود ظرفیتها و پتانسیلهاى دانشى و بازارى اولیه، باعث شکلگیرى دو مسیر تقویت طرف تقاضا و طرف عرضه شده است و لذا، این مسیر شکلگیرى تحت عنوان &quot;موتور شکلگیرى حمایت دولت و ظرفیتهاى دانشى و بازارى&quot; نامگذارى گردید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام نوآوری فناورانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فاز شکلگیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بخش زیستفناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل معادلات ساختاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14593_4ea4fb81497da0fddb7cfc75f0ddfdd8.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
