<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Enhancing New Product Development Success Based on Open Innovation Approach: A Case Study of a Research Organization</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و اولویت بندی اصول مورد نیاز برای بهبود فضای نوآوری بنگاه های دفاعی ایران با رویکرد باز</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>57</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>86</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14826</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>حورعلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>منتظری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>الیاسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The literature of innovation, innovation management, open innovation at firm level, tremendous changes in firm&#039;s environment and firm&#039;s tough competitive situation points to the need for taking an open approach to maximizing firms&#039; value-added by combining firms internal and external capabilities. In this study, we propose some essential principles for opening Iran&#039;s defense firms&#039; innovation process. By reviewing the literature, 21 principles for improving firms&#039; innovation are extracted, and then increased to 25 principles by conducting exploratory interviews with related experts. After that, an initial questionnaire is designed, and its internal consistency is confirmed by the contribution of 50 experts and by computing the Cronbach&#039;s alpha. Its validity is also confirmed by the experts&#039; views. The extracted principles are clustered by principal component analysis (PCA), factor loading with eigenvalue&gt;1, and varimax matrix with absolute value of factor loading &gt;0.6. The final questionnaire is designed by Likert-scale and answered by 245 defense innovation experts, and analyzed by LISREL software. The results show that defense firms must design and implement an open integrated process firstly, then implement the associated infrastructure systems with open approach for supporting this innovation process. Creating suitable organizational context is in the third priority because of its time-consuming nature.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">رویکردهای جدید به نوآوری در سطح بنگاه و همچنین تغییرات شدید محیطی و فضای رقابتی حاکم بر فعالیت بنگاه‌های تولیدی، استفاده از رویکرد نوآوری باز را اجتناب‌ناپذیر کرده است. پژوهش حاضر با هدف پیشنهاد اصولی برای باز شدن فضای نوآوری در سطح بنگاه‌های دفاعی ایران انجام شد. در این راستا، پس از مرور ادبیات، 21 اصل برای بکارگیری رویکرد باز در سطح بنگاه‌ها استخراج شد و با مصاحبه‌های اکتشافی با خبرگان، به 25 اصل افزایش یافت و سپس پرسش‌نامه‌ای برای دسته‌بندی این اصول، طراحی گردید. بر اساس نظرات خبرگان، اصول پیشنهادی با استفاده از تحلیل مولفه‌های اصلی و محاسبه بارهای عاملی با مقادیر ویژه بزرگتر از یک و استفاده از چرخش متعامد به روش واریماکس با مقادیر بار مطلق عاملی بزرگتر از 6/0، در سه دسته‌بندی کلی با عنوان اصول مورد نیاز برای ایجاد نظام‌های زیرساختی نوآوری در سطح بنگاه با رویکرد باز، اصول مورد نیاز برای اجرای فرآیند نوآوری در سطح بنگاه با رویکرد باز و اصول مورد نیاز برای ایجاد فضای سازمانی مناسب نوآوری باز  قرار گرفت. در ادامه پرسش‌نامه اصلی طراحی و به خبرگان نوآوری دفاعی سپرده شد و داده‌های حاصل توسط نرم‌افزار لیزرل تحلیل گردید. نتایج نشان داد که برای بازشدن فضای نوآوری بنگاه‌های دفاعی ایران، باید ابتدا فرآیند یکپارچه مدیریت نوآوری باز، طراحی شود و استقرار یابد. سپس نظام‌های زیرساختی مناسب برای فرآیند نوآوری در سطح بنگاه مستقر و در نهایت فضای سازمانی مناسب برای نوآوری، باز شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری باز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بنگاه دفاعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظامهای زیرساختی مناسب برای نوآوری باز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرآیند یکپارچه نوآوری باز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فضای سازمانی مناسب نوآوری باز</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14826_bf7bd2eb6c96840c28e3073e305eb00e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
