<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Meta-synthesis of success factors for commercialize of products with advanced technology</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>فراترکیب عوامل موفقیت تجاری‌سازی محصولات با فناوری پیشرفته</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>19</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>54</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">46945</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهمن</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاجی پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت بازرگانی دانشگاه شهید بهشتی تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>موتمنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت صنعتی دانشگاه شهید بهشتی تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدامیرحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>طیبی ابوالحسنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت اجرایی دانشگاه شهید بهشتی تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>09</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of the main reasons for the rapid development of technology in developed countries is attention to commercialization process of research and technological ideas that countries. Aim of this research according to important role of commercialization in the advancement of Industrial and economic any society, is quality combining in the area of commercialization from previous studies have been carried out. For this purpose, with utilize meta-synthesis approach in this study is to analyze the results and findings of other researchers. With comprehensive studies have been done about success factors for commercialize of products with advanced in scientific databases of Internal and foreign, eventually, 118 articles were identified. Results classified on 3 dimensions (individual, organizational and environmental factors), 19 components (individual manager&#039;s mind, individual manager&#039;s character, manager&#039;s inter-personal abilities, general conditions, experience, human resources, financial resources, technical ability, production ability, marketing and sales abilities, ability of absorption and project management, strategic abilities, organizational absorption capacity, competitors, supporting institutions, infrastructure, social factors, legal factors, political, economic and technological factors) and 99 indices.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از دلایل اصلی توسعه سریع فناوری در کشورهای توسعه یافته صنعتی، توجه به فرایند تجاری‌سازی نتایج تحقیقات پژوهشی و ایده‌های فناورانه آن کشورها بوده است. پژوهش حاضر با توجه به نقش مهمی که فرآیند تجاری‌سازی در اعتلای صنعتی و اقتصادی هر جامعه دارد، با هدف ترکیب کیفی نتایج پژوهش‌های صورت گرفته در حوزه تجاری‌سازی و تحلیل جامع آن‌ها، انجام شده است. بدین منظور با به کارگیری رویکرد فراترکیب و شیوه تحلیل تم در این پژوهش، به تجزیه و تحلیل نتایج و یافته‌های محققان قبلی پرداخته و با بررسی‌های جامع صورت گرفته پیرامون عوامل موفقیت تجاری‌سازی محصولات با فناوری پیشرفته در پایگاه‌های علمی معتبر داخلی و خارجی، تعداد 118 مقاله در این خصوص شناسایی شدند. درنهایت عوامل موفقیت در 3 بعد اصلی (فردی، سازمانی و عوامل محیطی)، 19 مولفه (فردی ذهن مدیر، فردی شخصیتی مدیر، بین‌فردی مدیر، شرایط عمومی، تجربه، منابع انسانی، منابع مالی، توانمندی فنی، توانمندی تولید، توانمندی بازاریابی و فروش، توانمندی جذب و مدیریت پروژه، توانمندی‌های استراتژیک، ظرفیت جذب سازمانی، رقبا، نهادهای حمایتی، زیرساخت، عوامل اجتماعی، عوامل قانونی و دیگرعوامل سیاسی اقتصادی و فناوری) و 99 شاخص شناسایی، طبقه‌بندی و تحلیل شدند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تجاری‌سازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">موفقیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراترکیب</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_46945_696969ee9c576d783010eb363673b747.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
