<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Role of knowledge management system and open innovation in developing innovation capacity</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نقش سیستم مدیریت دانش و نوآوری باز در توسعه ظرفیت نوآوری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>81</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>110</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">90186</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>نگارستانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت اجرایی، دانشگاه جامع علمی کاربردی، ایران.</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2800-5431</Identifier>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of the study was to investigating the role of open innovation in the effect of knowledge management system on innovation capacity. The study population which was an applied and descriptive-survey research was composed of 177 managers of Companies in Industrial Town No. 2 &amp; companies in Kerman Science and Technology Park. The questionnaire was used to collect data.Validity and reliability of the questionnaire were verified and confirmed. After data analysis by Spss &amp; Amos, findings suggested that: knowledge management system had effect on open innovation andinnovation capacity. Also, the impact of knowledge management system on innovation capacity was mediated by open innovation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی نقش میانجی­گری نوآوری باز در تأثیر سیستم مدیریت دانش بر ظرفیت نوآوری است. جامعه آماری شامل مدیران شرکت‌های فعال در شهرک صنعتی شماره 2 و نیز شرکت‌های مستقر در پارک علم و فناوری شهر کرمان به تعداد 177 شرکت می­باشد. روش تحقیق ازنظر هدف، کاربردی و ازنظر روش گردآوری داده‌ها، توصیفی - پیمایشی است. ابزار اصلی گردآوری داده‌ها، پرسشنامه است که سطح روایی و پایایی آن، برای تمامی سازه‌ها اندازه‌گیری و تائید شد. پس از تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌ها با استفاده از معادلات ساختاری در قالب نرم‌افزار Amos مشخص شد که سیستم مدیریت دانش بر نوآوری باز و ظرفیت نوآوری تأثیر دارد. همچنین؛ نوآوری باز، تأثیر سیستم مدیریت دانش بر ظرفیت نوآوری را میانجی‌گری می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیستم مدیریت دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ظرفیت نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری باز</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_90186_f1450565ab2b48169db5855d6a6c4523.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
