<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Windows of opportunity for catch up in nanofibers technology in Iran from a sectoral systems of innovation perspective</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>پنجره فرصت‌های همپایی فناوری نانوالیاف در ایران از منظر نظام بخشی نوآوری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>28</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">87695</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عماد</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدوند</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری / دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1564-2754</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>سلامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حبیب الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>طباطبائیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جهانیار</FirstName>
					<LastName>بامداد صوفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract> 
Iran has experienced an evident progress on the path of catch up in nanofibers technology. This qualitative case study has analyzed the catch up process in this technology. The sectoral systems of innovation approach was used as the theoretical framework for the study. The effects of the technological regime, market regime, government policies and foreign sanctions on windows of opportunity in this sector has been explored. The study shows that: &lt;br /&gt;High technological opportunities, low appropriateness and low cumulativeness of nanofibers technology make this sector appropriate for a turbulent flow of innovators. &lt;br /&gt;Various and large local markets for nanofiber products can help domestic firms to build necessary capabilities for entering the foreign markets. However brand loyalty in one segment of the market and traditional players in another segment are two main market barriers for nanofibers development in Iran. &lt;br /&gt;Foreign sanctions against Iran on one hand have limited the financial transactions between Iranian and foreign firms. On the other hand, the sanctions have limited the entrance of foreign companies into Iran’s market. &lt;br /&gt;Government support programs for manufacturers of nanotechnology equipment had a crucial role in the success of the domestic firms in Entry Stage of the catch up cycle.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt; یکی از فناوری‌هایی که طی دو دهۀ گذشته توسعه مشهودی در ایران داشته و در مسیر همپایی پیش رفته است، فناوری نانو الیاف است. این پژوهش به دنبال یافتن پنجره فرصت‌های همپایی فناوری و تحلیل چگونگی تأثیرگذاری آن‌ها در بخش ذکرشده است. بدین منظور از رویکرد کیفی و راهبرد مطالعۀ موردی استفاده شده است. همچنین از چارچوب نظام بخشی نوآوری به‌عنوان مبنای نظری تحلیل‌ها استفاده شده است. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که رژیم فناوری نانو الیاف، بازارهای داخلی متنوع و بزرگ، تحریم‌های خارجی و برنامه‌های حمایتی دولت، نقش مؤثری در همپایی شرکت‌های فعال در این حوزه از فناوری دارند. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همپایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پنجره فرصت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رژیم فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رژیم بازار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نانوالیاف</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام بخشی نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_87695_ba49c3cc8b7bb08e93dab0c3931a8b8b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
