<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Impact of External Contextual Factors on Open Innovation Adoption with an Emphasis on Sectorial Characteristics: Evidences from Iran's Advanced Materials Firms]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mashayekh, Javad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tabatabaeian, Seyed Habibollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Amiri, Maghsoud]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shokrieh, Mahmood Mehrdad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Open Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Developing countries]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[advanced materials]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[case study]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Over the past decade, open innovation has been of interest to several researchers as one of the innovation management theories. These researchers believe that the adoption and efficacy of this approach are influenced by different internal and external contingencies to firms. Sector or industry contextual properties and institutional environment conditions are among those external contingencies affecting open innovation in firms. Advanced materials sector, as a pillar of knowledge-based economy, has been less studied by innovation management scholars. In addition, a review of the literature indicates a lack of in-depth research on the adoption and efficacy of open innovation in the context of developing countries, especially in Iran. Having identified these research gaps, this study uses qualitative approach based on multiple case studies to examine open innovation among advanced materials firms in Iran. The results of this study confirms the prevalence of open innovation among the firms in this sector, reflecting the dominance of inbound open innovation strategy using financial and non-financial methods. The studied firms use open innovation strategies to overcome both technical and market challenges. Although they face several challenges in their open innovation practices, the expansion of higher education and research, and the spread of the internet are among the factors facilitating the adoption of open innovation among Iranian firms.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_40457_d24b723e7e493618f127b22962c8fd5d.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Collective Action and Institutional and Technological Change: A Case Study of Iran Bio-Pharmaceutical Industry]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hamidimotlagh, Roohollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Isaai, Mohammad Taghi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Yamin, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Babaee, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Kermanshah, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[collective action]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[institutional change]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Practice]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[institutional entrepreneur]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[There is a wide range of evidence emphasizing the role of collective action in the process of institutional change. Collective collaboration as well as individualistic profit-seeking activities of entrepreneurs are two complementary wings of institutional and technical change in innovation systems. In this paper, based on empirical evidence from Iran bio-pharmaceutical sector, we develop a framework to link the institutional change of innovation systems to practices and institutional entrepreneurs (IEs). Then we use the framework to see to what extent IEs' practices are collective. We analyze institutional change as a shift from supplier-dominated governmental firms to science-based private firms. After that, we analyze four practices as mainly influential practices with institutional change effects, and finally we elaborate on IEs who are actively involved in directing the practices. Our analysis shows that in all the practices, collective action has been influential. We also find that there is a network of entrepreneurs involved in all the practices. These IEs are from both governmental and non-governmental organizations and play formal as well as informal roles in directing the practices. Our analysis criticizes both government-centric and individualistic views of institutional and technical change in catching up on innovation systems.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_38885_9bde542c38838516ccf91c0ff4ca4e45.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Designing an Institutional Compatibility Ex-Ante Assessment Procedure for Science and Technology Policies]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Noroozi, Naser]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Elahi, Shaban]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hajihoseini, Hojatolah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hasanzadeh, Alireza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[science and technology policies]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Policy-making]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[ex-ante evaluation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[institution]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[institutional compatibility]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[It is essential to consider policy assessment in policy cycle. However, ex-ante evaluation has been rarely reviewed in the policy evaluation literature. In this paper, a five-phase process of ex-ante evaluation of science and technology policies in policy cycle using grounded theory is offered. For this purpose, through the literature review, ten keywords are searched for, and finally 50 selected texts are selected for open and axial coding. After that, by structured interviews with experts, the process of ex-ante evaluation of institutional compatibility is extracted. The first step of the process is classifying the policy options. In the second step, Crucial Institutional Aspects (CIA) are identified in the policy cycle context. By determining some indicators, the third step measures these CIAs. The forth step analyzes the policy impacts, and in the fifth, these analyses are used to modify policy instruments with regards to the target institutions. This suggested process is a new subject and provides a tool for policy makers to conduct ex-ante evaluation of policies.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_38498_43469fbb74235cbbfbe667a0f295e676.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Ranking Venture Capital Business Plans by Data Envelopment Analysis Method: A Case Study of an Iranian venture capital company]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ahsanizadeh, Saman]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Pishvaee, Mir Saman]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Karimi, Amir Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ranking]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Venture Capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Data Envelopment Analysis (DEA)]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cross efficiency]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[VIKOR]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[of Hatef Company Evaluation in venture capital industry is one of the most challenging issues from practitioners' and researchers' points of view. Limited time of evaluation, lack of financial data especially from ventures, heuristics and biases in evaluating and some other issues differentiate venture capital evaluation process from other investment methods. Also the speed and accuracy of evaluation are two key success factors for venture capitalists. In this paper, we attempt to overcome some of evaluation challenges by using several mathematical methods including data envelopment analysis (DEA), cross efficiency and VIKOR through decreasing screening time, reducing biased effects and enabling group decision-making with variety of weights. This method does not need any weights as they are calculated within the model. For the purpose of this study, some interviews are conducted and domestic criteria are extracted. The performance of the proposed model is investigated with the aid of the Hatef Company case study. Thereafter, we present a group of domestic criteria, and a standard and mathematical method to support decision-making without any needs for criteria weights or normalization. The results derived from the model are similar to the experts' opinions about the best project, but there are not adequate data to compare the ranking of another project with the experts' opinions.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_41314_6c8fcedbb3184cb32b725ec571bf6a68.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Model of Decision-Making for New Venture Creation: A Grounded Theory Approach]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Zivdar, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Imanipour, Narges]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Talebi, Kambeiz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hosseini, Seyed Rasul]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2016]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Entrepreneurship]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[new venture creation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Decision-making]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[non-teleological approach]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The decision-making process of entrepreneurs is not appropriately explicable by means of teleological approach. Through a non-teleological approach and employing a grounded theory research design, this study aims to explore a process of new venture creation decision-making in a sample of nascent entrepreneurs in Iranian high-tech businesses. The data collection is conducted through qualitative event-based interviews with 20 nascent entrepreneurs of the research theoretical sample. The analysis of the gathered data is done by three integrated procedures of open, axial and selective coding. The results determine six categories as the constituent elements of the studied process. These categories are "entrepreneur’s characteristics and background", "specific contextual conditions", "general contextual conditions", "entrepreneurial orientation and competency", "identification, evaluation and empowerment" and "venture creation decision". Propositions concerning the relationships between the categories lead to the development of a model of new venture creation decision-making in the sample. Moreover, the studied process is explained by the story line of the substantive grounded theory.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_38499_2058b0692f86494c7d57ac1204bcde0d.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Role of Technology Management Capability in Defense New Product Development Process (The Empirical Findings)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Fartash, Kiarash]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohseni Kiasari, Mostafa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sadabadi, Aliasghar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2023]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[technology]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[technology management capability]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[defense new product development processes]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The main purpose of defense new product development (NPD) process is to transform different ideas to a product or a system that fulfill some needs. NPD process consists of six phases: idea development; concept development; problem definition and planning; engineering and production design and development; validation; and pre-commercialization and market launch. In this paper, we discuss the role of technology management and its related capabilities in new defense products and systems acquisition process and in each of the six phases, and discuss the role of technology management and its important and essential tools in each phase. For understanding this relationship, after interviews with the experts of defense industries, first the tools associated with technology management used at different phases are identified, and then a Fuzzy seven-scaled questionnaire is designed for data gathering. The data are analyzed using Fuzzy Delphi Technique. The results show that technology management, as one of the most important tools in defense new products development process, is more influential in initial phases. As we go through the NPD process, the role of technology management becomes less influential. The role of technology management, as a supporting tool in NPD process, is significant, and in this paper we aim to comprehensively cover this role. Finally, by using Fuzzy logic 14 processes and 8 tools associated with technology management are identified and analyzed.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_39221_9f198311f7530758749e8fd105d7bd7e.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>