<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The analytical framework of the ecosystem of technological collaboration between large and small technology oriented companies]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Elahi, Shaban]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[khaledi, Arman]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Majidpour, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Asadifard, Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2018]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technological collaboration]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Systematic literature review]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Meta synthesis]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[According to the competitive environment of the business over the last few decades, large companies despite access to financial resources and distribution channels, face with bureaucracy, inefficiency and inertia, in contrast small technology-oriented companies with the flexibility and high innovation capability face with resource shortages And lack of access to the market. Therefore, both large and small companies need to work together to maintain their competitive position and survival. However, technological collaboration between companies is a complex subject that a comprehensive review of which requires a systematic approach. In this regard, an ecosystem approach can be used to analyze and explain the process of technological collaboration between the two groups of companies. To this end, using a systematic literature review method to develop an appropriate framework for the analysis of the ecosystem of technological collaboration and 605 documents were searched in valid databases, after which 63 of them were identified as valid documents. Subsequently, the selected documents were examined and coded using the Meta synthesis method. Finally, the codes extracted are as follows: five categories, one category about the characteristics of the ecosystem, and four others refer to the categories to be considered in the ecosystem analysis. These categories include life cycle, analysis dimensions, roles and institutions in the technological collaboration ecosystem]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_61839_b5ef8b178282022a6a1a0b9bb4b2e150.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Structural-functional analysis of the Rotary Wing Technological Innovation System in Iran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mir emadi, Tahere]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Baharloo, Mahdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Behzadirad, Maryam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2018]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rotary Wing]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technological Innovation System]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[structural analysis]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Functional Analysis]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The purpose of this paper is to analyze the current status of the Rotary Wing's Technology Innovation System (RWTIS) in Iran and identify its weaknesses and problems. For this purpose, a structural-functional approach has been used in evaluating innovation systems. The structural configuration of the system was studied and studied using six helicopter experts, in four dimensions of the actors, their interactions, institutions, and technology (its infrastructure). The presence of a strong network in the supply and demand segment of the public-defense and weak interactions of the private sector, policy-making and facilitators, and civilian demand were recognized as characteristics of the RWTIS’s structure in Iran. To assess the status of the functions of the system, the survey tool was used and it was found that the overall condition of the functions is in the weak and, of course, the functions of "knowledge diffusion" and "resource mobilization" are the weakest functions of this system. The weakness of the knowledge diffusion function is due to factors such as the level of participation and low competition of actors, and the space of diffusion of knowledge and technology. Regarding the mobilization of resources, the lack of financial resources and non-appropriate distribution of them in line with the needs and objectives of the system was identified as the main causes of the weakness.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81030_221e8a9288bac400f1d3958b084eec87.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Comparative Study of Development Strategies in A High Tech Industry Through Text Mining of Policy Documents]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Talafi, Mojtaba]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shojaei, Mohammad Hosain]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Taheri, Sayyed Amin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2018]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Policy analysis]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lesson Drawing]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Text Mining]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Co-word Analysis]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Aerospace Industry]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The present study seeks to apply Lesson drawing process for analyzing aerospace industry (AI) policies in nine regions/countries and learning from them. This analysis has been carried out by applying the methodology of text mining to policy documents of AI and the two related policy areas, i.e. science, technology and innovation, and defense. The study comprises the regions/countries of the EU,UK,USA,Brazil,Turkey,the Zionist regime,Russia,Japan-Korea,and India-Pakistan. After analyzing the frequency of words, drawing the co-occurrence network of words and clustering this network for all policy documents, the co-occurrence networks for each of the nine countries/regions are separately mapped and analyzed; then the most important policy points are extracted. Finally, the most important lessons learned for AI policy Analysis in the Islamic Republic of Iran are presented. Orientation towards applied research and application of researches; the interaction of government, industry and universities; the integration of policies and programs; the application of science and technology diplomacy capacities; the optimal use of resources; accurate planning for future innovations and technologies; the development of training programs;special attention to space observation services; the creation of aerospace clusters and the use of regional capacities; the diversification of financing sources; the localization of products and systems in developing countries; and a systematic approach to science,Technology and Innovation policy are lessons learned from the analyzed policy documents in this study.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81031_397c415428d80057dde22db05bb6e790.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Identification and clustering modes of learning and innovation in high technology and medium technology firms]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sohrabi, Somayeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohammadi, Mahdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2018]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[STI]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[DUI]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Clustering]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Learning modes]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Latent Classs Analysis]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Today,Regarding to the importance of innovation, organizations are trying to promote it to gain competitive advantage and market share. In such circumstances, organizational learning capabilities can be the best way to achieve this success and take advantage of opportunities and creating innovation in different forms. In this regard, different modes of learning and innovation is important. In this article has been tried by identification and clustering of learning modes in 728 firms active in high-tech(ICT) and medium-tech (Oil&amp;Gas, Automotive parts manufacturer) industry in Iran as a developing country to help development policies making and innovation capabilities improvement. Therefore, by defining appropriate indicators to assess learning modes by latent class method,four clusters of 1-Average DUI+STI, 2-DUI, 3-Strong(STI+DUI) 4-Moderate STI, have been recognized. Finally, the effect of the above modes on the performance of firms with logistic regression, analysed and identified So as a result we found organizations with combined STI+DUI, have achieved more success in financial growth,export and innovation.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_69190_89c048dea5e60f2c23700a19369246fb.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A new service development (NSD) pattern in Iranian mobile operators]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[hasani parsa, majid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Elyasi, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tabatabaeian, Seyed Habibollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hanafizadeh, Payam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2018]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[New service development]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mobile Operators]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Multiple Case Study]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[process model]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Iran]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Today, with the ever-increasing share of services in the economies of the countries, New Service Development (NSD) has become crucial for service providers. Despite this importance, there are not enough studies on the patterns of new service development in some service industries (such as mobile operators) in Iran. The purpose of this study is to investigate the patterns of new service development in Iranian mobile operators. In the first stage of this research, new service development patterns were studied in the literature and the conceptual model of new service development was extracted. Since the NSD process varies in each sector and country under the specific circumstances of that sector and country; at a later stage, a multiple case study has been conducted and the initial model of new service development was extracted from them. In the final stage, proposed model of new service development in Iranian mobile operators has been presented.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81020_9c0a309751b612bd1430b02c068eefb6.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The impact of high-tech industries’ featurs on technological innovation and product performance in the defense industry]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[mehrabi, somayeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[mahmoodzadeh, ebrahim]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[boushehri, alireza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[ramezan, majid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2018]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[High-tech industries]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Product Performance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[product innovation capability]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[process innovation capability]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[High-tech defense organizations, due to specific features, require more attention to capabilities, including technological innovation (product and Process innovation). Therefore, in this research, the impact of the features of high-tech industrie’s featurs on the product and process innovation capabilities is examined. Because the importance of product performance in the defense industries, its impact on the industry's characteristics has been studied. The research methodology is exploratory and descriptive in terms of purpose, and is applied in terms of achievement. In order to design the model and extract some of the variables of the model's dimensions in defense organizations on Iran's high-tech industries,th interview method was used. The Delphi method was used to validate the model. In order to test the model with real data, the required information was collected in the form of a questionnaire from 58 organizations of electronics defense industry. PLS-SEM used to analyse the data. Results have been shown that the featurs of the high-tech industries have a great impact on the product and process innovation and defense product performance. The findings lead managers to empower the organization in the field of product and process innovation capabilities and take advantage of the high-tech industrie’s features as an opportunity, not a threat.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_81028_70d1ce7e67a5cdbeab075de9fedef68c.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>