<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Examining Knowledge-sharing Behavior in a High-Tech Firm Based on the Theory of Planned Behavior</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی رفتار تسهیم دانش کارکنان در یک سازمان با فناوری پیشرفته مبتنی بر نظریه رفتار برنامه ریزی شده</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>61</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>80</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">15361</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدمهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی سرخوش</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پیمان</FirstName>
					<LastName>اخوان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>کیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>امین پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Employees&#039; knowledge-sharing is a key to achieve sustainable competitive advantage in current dynamic economy, especially in high-tech firms. Effective knowledge-sharing among employees can considerably affect the time, cost and quality of research and development activities in such organizations. Therefore, this paper is aimed at examining how to form knowledge-sharing behavior in a high-tech firm based on the theory of planned behavior (TPB). To do so, after reviewing the literature on knowledge-sharing determining factors, TPB is explained. Then, the conceptual model and research hypotheses are discussed. A descriptive-survey method is used and a questionnaire developed for gathering data. Also, partial least squares (PLS) method is used to test the research hypotheses. The results of analyzing data gathered from the statistical population show that attitude toward knowledge-sharing, subjective norms, and perceived behavioral control have significant positive effects on knowledge-sharing intention. Additionally, the research findings indicate that knowledge-sharing intention and perceived behavioral control significantly influence knowledge-sharing behavior. Finally, some practical implications are offered for knowledge management practitioners to foster employees&#039; knowledge-sharing, and some suggestions for future works to overcome current research shortcomings.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;تسهیم دانش بین کارکنان، مؤلفه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای کلیدی برای دستیابی به مزیت رقابتی پایدار در اقتصاد پویای کنونی و به ویژه در سازمان&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های با فناوری پیشرفته می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;باشد. تسهیم دانش اثربخش میان کارکنان می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;تواند به طور قابل ملاحظه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای بر زمان، هزینه و کیفیت فعالیت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های تحقیق&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;وتوسعه در چنین سازمان&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;هایی تاثیر بگذارد. پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی نحوه شکل&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;گیری رفتار تسهیم دانش در یک سازمان با فناوری پیشرفته مبتنی بر نظریه رفتار برنامه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ریزی&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;شده انجام شد. برای این منظور ضمن مرور ادبیات، عوامل مؤثر بر رفتار تسهیم دانش استخراج &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;و مدل مفهومی و فرضیه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های پژوهش طراحی گردید. روش این پژوهش، از نوع توصیفی ـ پیمایشی و ابزار گردآوری اطلاعات پرسش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;نامه بوده است. برای آزمون فرضیه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها، از روش حداقل مجذورات جزئی (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PLS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;) استفاده شد. نتایج تجزیه و تحلیل 112 داده گردآوری شده از جامعه آماری، اثر مثبت و معنادار نگرش نسبت به تسهیم دانش، هنجارهای ذهنی و کنترل رفتاری درک&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;شده بر قصد تسهیم دانش را تایید نمود. علاوه بر این، نتایج پژوهش، از اثر مثبت و معنادار قصد تسهیم دانش و کنترل رفتاری درک&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;شده بر رفتار تسهیم دانش حمایت کرد. در نهایت با توجه به یافته&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها، توصیه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;هایی برای شاغلان حرفه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای حوزه مدیریت دانش به منظور ترغیب تسهیم دانش میان کارکنان به همراه پیشنهادهایی برای محققان آتی جهت پوشش شکاف&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های پژوهش حاضر ارائه گردید.&lt;/strong&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تسهیم دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظریه رفتار برنامه ریزی شده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هنجارهای ذهنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کنترل رفتاری درک شده</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_15361_e543218463bec635194ae6e2ed76c068.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
