<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Reviewing and Rating Factors Affecting the Mechanism of Open Innovation Approach in Iran's Aviation Industry</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hosein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khosropour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Kamran</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Feizi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allameh Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Kamal</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tabaian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malek Ashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Network communication is a fundamental pillar of innovation-based economy. Meanwhile, using the concept of knowledge networking, open innovation approach tries to create an interactive relationship between science and industry actors to exchange ideas, technology and knowledge within a network to shorten the course of development and innovation in organizations. Considering Hafkesbrink and Schroll&#039;s &quot;Organizational Competences for Open Innovation Model&quot;, this paper tries to investigate open innovation strategies of Iran&#039;s aviation industry and to identify its implementation challenges. Here, we use survey method to collect data from 66 experts in air transport aviation maintenance agencies, and the data collection tool is a standard questionnaire. A T-test is used to examine the status of each variable, and the fuzzy TOPSIS method to rank factors influencing open innovation approach. The results clearly show that the factor of networking capability, from collaborative capabilities dimension; and the factors of identifying innovative opportunities, and understanding and exchanging, from absorptive capacity, are in undesirable conditions, but the rest of the factors have acceptable conditions. The affecting factors are also rated by fuzzy TOPSIS method, and the results show that the factors of understanding and exchanging, identifying innovative opportunities, and networking capabilities are the most important ones, and the factors of the specific designing of structure and process, outside-to-inside and vice versa cooperation, and internal cooperation are less important.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>26</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14665_7f7c3e2aa01835cfa7d5cd5c111751db.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Analysis of the Role of Techno-Market in Creating and Strengthening Innovation in Organizations</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kamali</namePart>
				<affiliation>دانشگاه</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Masoud</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Science and Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The increasing importance of technology has lead to the introduction of different mechanisms for its development, transfer, diffusion and deployment. Techno-market is one of the most important mechanisms in our country, which has attracted considerable attention in recent years. This article tries to explain how mediating institutions such as techno-market can promote innovation in organizations, and uses structural equations modeling (SEM). To do so, we first review the techno-market mechanisms and the indicators related to innovation performance, innovation stimuli and innovation capacity. Model processing is done using partial least squares (PLS) approach in the SmartPLS software. By means of a questionnaire, the opinions of experts in the field of technology management are extracted as the input to analyze the relationships. The results of the model processing indicate that techno-market with the defined functions has no direct effects on innovation performance and its major impact is on innovation stimuli and innovation capacity.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>27</start>
					<end>52</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14666_f53a420fe163acb344dfc4b3172a6ec0.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Factors Affecting the Success of International Technology Transfer Projects with the support of a Facilitator Organization</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Taghva</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allame Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Habibolah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tabatabaeian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allame Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Jashid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Salehi Sadaghiani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allame Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Kamal</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Allame Tabataba’i University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The relationship between the success factors of international technology transfer projects is one of the major research areas of technology management. The literature mostly focuses on the effects of recipient, resource, environment, technology nature, transfer method, etc. In this paper, besides these factors, the role of technology transfer facilitator is also investigated. This study is an applied research, using survey method as its strategy along with the review of archival documents through a mixed method of qualitative and quantitative approaches. The list of success factors and criteria are extracted from the literature using focus groups, and a conceptual framework for the success of international technology transfer projects is designed with respect to the facilitator qualifications. The data from 191 projects are gathered through interviews and the review of existing documents. The partial least squares method is used to analyze the abnormal data in the SmartPLS software. The results show that &quot;the readiness of facilitator organization&quot; has the major impact, with &quot;the readiness of recipient for technology absorption&quot; and &quot;technology exchangeability&quot; ranking respectively the next. The results also indicate that &quot;the readiness of resource for technology transfer&quot; has no significant effect on projects success.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>53</start>
					<end>80</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14667_9ff4c3c9d6fa13659c8edf839dc5e31f.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Model for Designing Communities of Practice based on Organizational Variables</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abdolla</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jassbi</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Science &amp; Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jasbi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Islamic Azad University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mostafa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jafari</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Science &amp; Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Peyman</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Akhavan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Malekashtar University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Morteza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Piri</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Science &amp; Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Communities of practice (CoP) are tools for exchanging best practices and a chance for increasing the level of individual and organizational learning. Developing these social structures has become a fundamental strategy for improving innovation process. Researchers and practitioners of knowledge management believe that managing CoPs in alignment with organizational goals will have favorable results for organization. Reviewing previous studies and experiences reveals that the relationships between organizational variables and CoPs designing and managing have not been investigated properly; that is the development of communities of practice has only been investigated as independent from organizational variables. This study aims to investigate the relationships between organizational variables and CoPs&#039; design elements, applying fuzzy method in the context of an industrial and strategic organization. The data is gathered through interviews with and questionnaires distributed among 11 experts in the aforementioned organization. The results show that 17 organizational variables have effects on 13 CoPs designing elements. Furthermore, the conceptual model of this study besides providing a pattern for managers to evaluate and select CoPs, clearly confirms the relationship between organizational variables and CoPs designing elements.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>81</start>
					<end>100</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14668_c687c5e212b0dbb653605fbc08023d8c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Designing a Decision-Making System to Prioritize Appropriate Knowledge Management Technologies in Insurance Companies</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Elham</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fallah</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Alireza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hasan Zade</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ameneh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Khadivar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Alzahra University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Behnam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Molavi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Islamic Azad University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Nowadays knowledge management is an important element of organizations to gain competitive advantage, and one of the most important aspects of which is information technology. Due to the increasing growth in information technology field, insurance companies require an appropriate technology for knowledge management in their organizations. That is why choosing the right technology in knowledge management process is important. In this paper, by using criteria from the literature and using the analytic hierarchy process (AHP), the technologies of each stage of knowledge management of 4 Iranian insurance companies are compared with each other with the help of the Expert Choice software. The data needed for the study is gathered by two questionnaires, the first one aiming to determine the meaningfulness of the selection criteria and technologies of each KM processes, and the second to determine and prioritize the weight of the criteria. The results of the comparison of knowledge management technologies based on the 12 criteria demonstrate that knowledge-base technology in the knowledge acquisition process, technology education systems in the knowledge-sharing process, knowledge map technology in the knowledge organizing process, and enterprise resource planning system technology in the knowledge application process of the insurance companies have the highest priorities. Finally, the &quot;decision-making software&quot; designed to help the employees of the insurance companies select an appropriate technology for each stage of knowledge management by using the C# programming language.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>101</start>
					<end>122</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14669_50daf59874137af7cbec004f033ac24a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Selecting a Knowledge Management Strategy in a Research-Industrial Laboratory based on Dynamic Strategy</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Behnam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Molavi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Islamic Azad University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Farshid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghanbarpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.s in EMBA.  Knowledge Manager Hesa Company</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ansari</namePart>
				<affiliation>University of Isfahan</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Selecting an appropriate knowledge management strategy ensures that knowledge management system will be implemented successfully. Considering organizational factors and the dynamic nature of knowledge in organization, there is a need for choosing a dynamic knowledge management strategy. This study tries to select a knowledge management strategy in a research-industrial lab by focusing on dynamic approach to knowledge management strategizing. To this end, the most important factors affecting knowledge management strategizing are extracted from the related literature. The factors include organizational culture, business strategy, organizational structure, organizational knowledge level, human resources strategy, and the maturity of information technology system. By analyzing organizational culture, business strategy and organizational structure, the boundaries of the codification and personalization of knowledge management strategy are determined. Then, by measuring the level of knowledge creation processes according to Nonaka&#039;s model in the lab and evaluating the current human resources strategy and information technology, the final strategy is selected in order to balance the organization&#039;s tacit and explicit knowledge. Thus, the selected strategy is a dynamic knowledge management strategy. The results show that personalization strategy is the main and codification strategy is the complimentary strategy in the lab.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>2</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>123</start>
					<end>146</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14670_6d2b86618b62d03f37d00c92b628901b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>