<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>5</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing and Devising a Suitable Innovation Sample for I.R.I Army According to Supreme Leaders Statements</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی و تبیین الگوی مناسب ﻧﻮآوری در ارتش ﺑﺮ مبنای تدابیر فرمانده کل قوا (ﻣﺪ ﻇﻠﻪ)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>101</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>124</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">46947</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امید</FirstName>
					<LastName>اردلان</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه افسری امام علی)ع(، تهران، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>الوانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>هیات علمی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>شهلائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشگاه فرماندهی و ستاد آجا، تهران، ایران.</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of this study was derived from a project that was in the army, define and design a suitable model for innovation in the army of the Islamic Republic is based on the supreme leader. This research is based on the purpose and nature of the exploratory study based on applied research achievements.A survey, documents related to the speech of the Leader of the Revolution and the number 106 Commanders and deputies education, research and university faculty members are military officers.109 lectures, the numbers of holiness, through content analysis, 67 items were extracted. Using factor analysis, finally presented in the form of 12. In this study, data collection tools for documents and questionnaires were used The use of library and field required data have been collected.The results show that the appropriate model based on innovation and creativity in the military commands of the supreme leader is a model that contains Individual aspects (scientific power, scientific courage, motivation), organizational aspects (goals and strategies based on science, organizational structure, organizational culture and climate, technology, equipment, systems, human resources, education and research system) And dimensions bureau (Basiji spirit and thinking, knowledge and faith) is.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از این تحقیق که برگرفته از پروژه ای است که در سطح ارتش انجام گرفته، طراحی و تبیین الگوی مناسب نوآوری علمی در ارتش ج.ا.ا بر اساس فرمایشات مقام معظم رهبری است. اﻳﻦ ﺗﺤﻘﻴﻖ ﺑﺮ ﻣﺒﻨﺎی هدف و ﻣﺎﻫﻴﺖ ﺗﺤﻘﻴﻖ از ﻧﻮع اﻛﺘﺸﺎﻓﻲ و ﺑﺮ ﻣﺒﻨﺎی دﺳﺘﺎورد ﺗﺤﻘﻴﻖ ﻧﻴﺰ ﻛﺎرﺑﺮدی اﺳﺖ. ﺟﺎﻣﻌﺔ آﻣﺎری ﺗﺤﻘﻴﻖ، اﺳﻨﺎد و ﻣﺪارک ﻣﺮﺗﺒﻂ ﺑﺎ ﺳﺨﻨﺮاﻧﻲ های رهبر انقلاب و ﻧﻴﺰ تعداد 106 نفر از فرماندهان و معاونان آموزش و پژوهش و اعضای هیات علمی دانشگاه های افسری ارتش می باشند. با بررسی تعداد 109 سخنرانی معظم له، از طریق روش تحلیل محتوا 67 گویه استخراج شد. سپس با استفاده از روش تحلیل عاملی، در نهایت در قالب 12 عامل ارائه گردید. در اﻳﻦ ﺗﺤﻘﻴﻖ ﺑﺮای ﮔﺮدآوری اﻃﻼﻋﺎت از اﺑﺰارﻫﺎی اﺳﻨﺎد و ﻣﺪارک و ﭘﺮﺳﺶ ﻧﺎﻣﻪ اﺳﺘﻔﺎده ﮔﺮدﻳﺪه ﻛﻪ ﺑﺎ اﺳﺘﻔﺎده از روش ﻫﺎی ﻛﺘﺎﺑﺨﺎﻧﻪ ای و ﻣﻴﺪاﻧﻲ داده ﻫﺎی ﻣﻮرد ﻧﻴﺎز ﮔﺮدآوری ﺷﺪه اﻧﺪ. ﻧﺘﺎﻳﺞ ﺗﺤﻘﻴﻖ ﻧﺸﺎن ﻣﻲ دﻫﺪ ﻛﻪ ﻣﺪل ﻣﻨﺎﺳﺐ ﻧﻮآوری در ارﺗﺶ ﺑﺮ اﺳﺎس ﻓﺮﻣﺎﻳﺸﺎت رهبر انقلاب ﻣﺪﻟﻲ اﺳﺖ ﻛﻪ در ﺑﺮﮔﻴﺮﻧﺪة اﺑﻌﺎد ﻓﺮدی(قدرت علمی، جرات علمی، انگیزش)، اﺑﻌﺎد ﺳﺎزﻣﺎﻧﻲ(اﻫﺪاف و راﻫﺒﺮد بر مبنای تولید علم، ﺳﺎﺧﺘﺎر ﺳﺎزﻣﺎﻧﻲ، ﻓﺮﻫﻨﮓ و جو ﺳﺎزﻣﺎﻧﻲ، ﻓﻨﺎوری و تجهیزات، ﻧﻈﺎم ﻣﻨﺎﺑﻊ اﻧﺴﺎﻧﻲ، ﻧﻈﺎم آﻣﻮزشی و نظام پژوهشی) و اﺑﻌﺎد مکتبی(روحیه و تفکر بسیجی، معرفت و ایمان) اﺳﺖ.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خلاقیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نوآوری علمی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارتش ج.ا.ا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_46947_525b5268e002746cfc03391ad0cbda65.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
