<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Policy Learning in Iran's Technology and Innovation Development 
(The Study of Third, Fourth and Fifth Development Plan regulations)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Fartash, Kiarash]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Elyasi, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghazinoori, Seyyed Soroush]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tabatabeian, Seyyed Habibollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Policy learning]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Learning]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[National development plan]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Technology and innovation development policies]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Over the time, policy change and learning play a significant role in national decision making and improving transparency of policy situations. On this basis, current paper has concentrated on Iran's national development plans, as the major national mid-term developmental policies, to investigate policy learning and its mechanisms in the most crucial policy attempts to develop technology and innovation (T&amp;I). Analyzing five past development plans led to selection of third to fifth plans, which have more coherent and integrated approach to T&amp;I development by including a dedicated section in this regard, as suitable case studies for this paper. After content analysis of relevant policy documents in addition to conducting eighteen interviews with key policy actors of development planning process related to T&amp;I articles, sixteen major policy issues were extracted in which direct implications are apparent in at least two investigated plans. Dominant share of policy learning belongs to political and technical learning with eight and seven frequencies respectively. Dominancy of political learning, as the most irrelevant type of policy learning, reflects low maturity of learning in T&amp;I policy actors in Iran. Furthermore, this indicates superficial commitment of high level politicians to the most fundamental T&amp;I policy objectives, which haven't fulfilled yet without any sign of sufficient attempts to meet defined objectives. Technical and conceptual learning (with seven and five occurrences) refer to relatively successful policy endeavours that are being tried to be improved or continued, usually by low and mid-level policy actors. Two key cases of identified social learning unveil effective role of public media and policy experts to widen and strengthen the discourse on innovation and knowledge-based development. Resulted social learning has brought mentioned discourse to the attention and commitments of high level politicians. Our findings contribute to more detailed recognition of Iran's T&amp;I policy environment in the past two decades as well as decision making in near future.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60171_04c1aeac65a26c5420e2c7af5d324c0a.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Effect of Regulatory Policies on the Innovation Capability of Iranian Pharmaceutical Companies]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Soltanzadeh, Javad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Elyasi, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bamdad Soufi, Jahanyar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Kazazi, Abolfazl]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Regulatory Policies]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Government Intervention Assessment]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Policy Tools]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation Capability]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Micro-Foundation]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Many scholars focus on the effects of policies that make response to market failures and systems. To understand behaviour of the firm as a result of government interventions, they have tried to develop the concept of Behavioural Additionality (BA) in Innovation Policy Assessment. This research emphasis on the Innovation Capability and its Micro-Foundation as indicators of the firms behaviour that received less attention by scholars. Therefore, we attempt to evaluate the effects of three regulatory policies (Generic plan, Pricing system and Tariff system) on innovative behaviour (Innovation capability and Performance) in Iranian pharmaceutical companies. This study is a cross-sectional study which uses Multi-Case study strategy and cognitive-analytic tool, the effect of regulatory policies on three levels of five policy objectives (Market Expansion, Availability Enhancement, Quality Promotion, R&amp;D Motivation, and Value Chain Improvement), Micro-Foundation of Innovation Capability (Innovation Intelligence, Decision Making, Combination, and Governance) and Innovative Performance (Product and Process). Also, using the sensitivity analysis of the effects of the following 26 scenarios, the three levels of the component have been considered. The results show that although these policies are aimed at policy goals of Market Expansion, Availability Enhancement, and Value Chain Improvement, as well as on the process innovation, they have been able to create patterns in the innovation and management intelligence of firms, but their negative effects on Quality Promotion, R&amp;D Motivation as well as product innovation.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60172_c4cdfd2c7a29f20bd937d21911a4b6c0.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Exploring the Goals and Enablers of Participating in the Platform Ecosystem from the Supply-Side Innovators’ Perspective in Software Industry: Small Companies in Tehran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Yarmohammadi, Maryam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rezvani, Mehran]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Alborzi, Mahmood]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Enablers]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Supply side innovators]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Platform ecosystem]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Supply-side innovators play an important role in the success of a platform and in increasing the number of its users. This paper takes on the perspective of the innovators and looks the goals they have in mind when participating in the platform ecosystem and the factors that enable this participation. This research is comprised of small Iranian companies in the software industry. This paper uses a qualitative approach and utilizes a multiple case study method. Data is collectd using 42 semi-structured interviews with 26 small companies that develop Android/ IOS- based applications. Secondary information, including news and interviews published in web concerning the innovation of the companies, is utilized as well, in order to supplement the interviews. The collected data is analyzed based on the qualitative content analysis method in the open coding and axial coding stages. The findings indicate that, the supply-side innovators’ goals in platform ecosystem participation, are as follows:, customer access, customer accountability, business expansion,credit increase, cost savings, and focus on innovation. Resource sharing, platform leadership, rules and regulations competency, maturity of investors and business partners are also, from the innovators' perspective, identified as the main factors that enable the participation.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60176_78c3d8ae784ca4215d86762daee94f31.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Fitness of Product Innovation Level and Brand Change: A Survey on Customers of Cleaning and Hygiene Products]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Gharibi, Jalil]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nazemi, Neda]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[product innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[substantial innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[gradual innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[new trademark]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[trademark development]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[primary acceptors]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Selecting a proper attitude for choosing a trademark is an important factor in succeeding new products. The purpose of this study is to answer this question: What are the costumer's criteria for choosing new products according to its trademark? In this paper, comments of 385 costumers of washing and hygienic products who usually go to shopping stores of Tehran gathered based on the metrical attitude. Results show that primary acceptors prefer the substantial technical innovations with new trademarks and current products with current trademarks. But about the more gradual innovations (having minor differences with older products), they do not demonstrate a unique pattern. But about other acceptors, current products with their present trademarks are more rational. They also accept the gradual innovation with both introducing new trademarks and current trademarks. But about more substantial innovations, there are rather dispersed patterns around two opposite options of current trademarks and the new one. In this paper, the reasons for these patterns that are concluded from collecting qualitative date and also somewhat could help explain the existing causes of these patterns.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60173_3d463691029462a5d93a813e65a72ac6.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Classification of Demand-based Innovation Policy Tools Using Meta-synthesis Approach]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohseni Kiasari, Mostafa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohammadi, Mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Jafarnejad, Ahmad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Garousi Mokhtarzadeh, Nima]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Asadifard, Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Demand-driven innovation policy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Policy Tools]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[MetaSynthesis]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Demand-driven innovation policy is a relatively new field of study in the science and technology policy that researchers have less attention but has been a growing issue recently. Demand-driven innovation policy is a set of public measures to boost demand for innovation, improvement of the conditions for perception of innovation or improvement of demand articulation in order to encourage and disseminate innovation. This paper seeks to provide a new classification of policy tools introduced in the related studies by using of meta-synthesis method. So, 252 articles have been found from official academic sites and have been investigated according to meta-synthesis method which 105 articles have been selected to be analysed. Analyses of articles and the meta-synthesis results indicate that the innovation demand-side stimulation tools can be categorized in three main categories from the perspective that which applicant is concerned. These three categories are: policies that stimulate the government demand (B2G), policies that stimulate the private demand (B2C), and policies that stimulate the large businesses demand (B2B). The analysis of this study shows that in the first category, the quantity of the articles and introduced tools is relatively very high. Also in the third category fewer studies have been carried out in which practical and detailed tools have not been presented. So there is a research gap in third category that needs to be investigated more by researchers.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60175_cf8651aeea01a5d6df300d7fff3741e7.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The role of R&amp;D Expenditure among Factors Influencing Labor Productivity; (A Case Study of Iran and the Selected Business Partners)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[najafi, zahra]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[azarbaijani, karim]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Labour productivity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[R&D expenditure]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Human capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[life expectancy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[data panel method]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Increasing the level of productivity factors of production is one of the most important components influencing the growth and development of economies of all countries. In addition, based on theories of endogenous economic growth, internal R&amp;D activities as an indicator of the level of innovation lead to more efficient use of existing resources and the absorption of advanced foreign technology in the production of goods and services' business and, finally, the productivity of production improvement is upgraded. Considering the importance of the issue, this research attempts to investigate the contributing factors of efficiency of Iranian workforce and their selected commercial partners during the year 2004 to 2014 using Pan-Data method. The results indicate that life expectancy and human capital variables with the coefficient of 30.74 and 0.19 have the highest and the lowest impact on the productivity index of the workforce. Also, the R&amp;D expenditure variable with a coefficient of 1.71 has a positive effect on labour productivity, although, according to the important position of this variable, little attention has been paid to it.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_60174_d732e36b4d2fc00893877aa11dd1d441.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>