<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An analysis of a Model for External Organizational Factors Influencing Innovation Development in Industrial-Research Organizations</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل مدل عوامل برون سازمانی موثردرتوسعه نوآوری سازمان های پژوهشی صنعتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>20</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14616</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منصور</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه امام حسین(ع)</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه امام حسین (ع)</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study intends to identify the constituent elements of &quot;a model for external factors influencing innovation development&quot;, to identify relations among the main elements, and lastly to design a comprehensive structure of a model for external factors influencing innovation development in research organizations. To design a theoretical framework for the model, using the relevant literature and library research, and conducting exploratory interviews, we extract the factors effective on innovation development in research organizations, and then evaluate them by survey research methodology and questionnaires. The data of the study are collected by using questionnaires distributed among 300 subjects, and then each major component of the conceptual model is analyzed. The structural equation model and LISREL software are used to evaluate the causal relations between the components of the conceptual model. Based on the findings, &quot;competitive intelligence&quot; is the most influential factor (through dominating emerging technologies space, absorbing and transferring knowledge from organization&#039;s external environment elements, forecasting before competitors, reaching future before customers, and predicting market changes). The next important influential factors include taking advantage of &quot;science &amp; research centers&quot; (through benchmarking, outsourcing, and idea absorption); and considering the &quot;customers&quot; (through investigations based on customer needs and their participation in all design processes and innovation, and getting customers&#039; satisfaction).</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این پژوهش با هدف شناخت ارکان تشکیل دهنده «مدل عوامل برون سازمانی موثر بر توسعه نوآوری»، شناسائی روابط ارکان اصلی با یکدیگر و طراحی ساختار جامع مدل عوامل برون سازمانی موثر بر توسعه نوآوری در سازمان‌های پژوهشی انجام شد. برای تدوین چارچوب نظری مدل پژوهش، پس از انجام مطالعات کتابخانه ای و اجرای مصاحبه های اکتشافی، مؤلفه های موثر بر توسعه نوآوری در سازمان‌های پژوهشی استخراج و از طریق روش پژوهش پیمایشی ارزیابی گردید. داده‌ها از طریق توزیع پرسش‌نامه بین 300 نفر از افراد جامعه آماری، جمع آوری و هر کدام از مؤلفه های اصلی مدل، مورد سنجش قرار گرفت. جهت بررسی روابط علّی میان مؤلفه‌ها از مدل معادلات ساختاری و نرم افزار LISREL استفاده شد. بر اساس یافته های پژوهش، مؤلفه «هوشمندی رقابتی» (از طریق تسلط بر فضای فناوری‌های در حال ظهور، جذب و انتقال دانش، درک آینده قبل از رقیب ها، رسیدن به آینده قبل از مشتری و پیش بینی تغییرات بازار) تأثیرگذارترین عامل و پس از آن بهره گیری از «مراکز علمی و پژوهشی» (با الگویابی، برون سپاری و جذب ایده) و در کنار آن مؤلفه «مشتریان» (از طریق انجام پژوهش بر اساس نیاز مشتری و مشارکت دادن وی در کلیه فرآیندهای طراحی و خلق نوآوری و همچنین کسب رضایت مشتری) عوامل مهم بعدی موثر بر توسعه نوآوری در سازمان‌های پژوهشی بودند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توسعه نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هوشمندی رقابتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشتری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مراکز علمی و پژوهشی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_14616_f23b1edbb43a3367f4497bccd630edd7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
