<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Influences of Cross-functional Collaboration on Technology Commercialization Function Regarding the Role of Knowledge Creation and Support  of Superior Management</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر همکاری متقابل کارکردی بر عملکرد تجاری‌سازی فناوری با توجه به نقش خلق دانش و حمایت مدیریت ارشد</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>45</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>72</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">57420</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>هما</FirstName>
					<LastName>درودی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، زنجان ، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسعود</FirstName>
					<LastName>شرف پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، زنجان، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>14</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Maintaining competitive advantage and organizational survival depends on maintaining and strengthening the commercialization of technology. The main objective of this study is to investigate the relationship between cross-functional collaboration, knowledge creation, superior management support and commercialization of technology in knowledge-based companies. The aim of the current study is practical and it is an descriptive-analytic survey which is conducted by a metrical approach. The Statistical Society were 122  knowledge-based companies located in the area of Pardis science and technology park. A questionnaire was used to collect data and structural equation modeling and data analysis methods were used by SmartPLS to analyze the data. According to the results of this study, there was positive and significant relationship between the variable cross-functional cooperation and technology commercialization   and knowledge creation mediate this relationship and superior management support also equates the aforementioned relationship positively. Finally, according to the results suggestions are presented.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">حفظ مزیت رقابتی و بقاء سازمانی در گرو حفظ و تقویت تجاری‌سازی فناوری است. هدف اصلی این پژوهش بررسی رابطه بین همکاری‌متقابل کارکردی، خلق دانش، حمایت مدیریت‌ارشد و تجاری‌سازی فناوری در شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان می‌باشد. پژوهش حاضر بر اساس هدف، کاربردی و روش آن توصیفی-تحلیلی است که با رویکرد پیمایشی انجام‌گرفته است. جامعه آماری پژوهش 122 شرکت دانش‌بنیان‌  مستقر در پارک علم وفناوری پردیس می‌باشد. تجزیه‌وتحلیل داده‌ها با استفاده از معادلات‌ساختاری و نرم‌افزار SmartPLS انجام‌گرفته است. طبق یافته‌های حاصل از این پژوهش، بین متغیر همکاری‌متقابل کارکردی و تجاری‌سازی فناوری رابطه مثبت و معنی‌دار وجود دارد و خلق دانش میانجی‌گراین رابطه است و حمایت مدیریت ‌ارشد نیز رابطه مذکور را به‌طور مثبت تعدیل می‌کند. در انتها با توجه به نتایج پژوهش پیشنهادهایی ارائه ‌شده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همکاری متقابل کارکردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خلق دانش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تجاری‌سازی فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حمایت مدیریت ارشد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_57420_7e56ce4f35a424126f516a286a9b961c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
