<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<XML>
		<JOURNAL>
<YEAR>1397</YEAR>
<VOL>7</VOL>
<NO>3</NO>
<MOSALSAL>25</MOSALSAL>
<PAGE_NO>200</PAGE_NO>
<ARTICLES>


				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>پنجره فرصت‌های همپایی فناوری نانوالیاف در ایران از منظر نظام بخشی نوآوری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Windows of opportunity for catch up in nanofibers technology in Iran from a sectoral systems of innovation perspective</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> یکی از فناوری‌هایی که طی دو دهۀ گذشته توسعه مشهودی در ایران داشته و در مسیر همپایی پیش رفته است، فناوری نانو الیاف است. این پژوهش به دنبال یافتن پنجره فرصت‌های همپایی فناوری و تحلیل چگونگی تأثیرگذاری آن‌ها در بخش ذکرشده است. بدین منظور از رویکرد کیفی و راهبرد مطالعۀ موردی استفاده شده است. همچنین از چارچوب نظام بخشی نوآوری به‌عنوان مبنای نظری تحلیل‌ها استفاده شده است. یافته‌های پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که رژیم فناوری نانو الیاف، بازارهای داخلی متنوع و بزرگ، تحریم‌های خارجی و برنامه‌های حمایتی دولت، نقش مؤثری در همپایی شرکت‌های فعال در این حوزه از فناوری دارند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT> 
Iran has experienced an evident progress on the path of catch up in nanofibers technology. This qualitative case study has analyzed the catch up process in this technology. The sectoral systems of innovation approach was used as the theoretical framework for the study. The effects of the technological regime, market regime, government policies and foreign sanctions on windows of opportunity in this sector has been explored. The study shows that: High technological opportunities, low appropriateness and low cumulativeness of nanofibers technology make this sector appropriate for a turbulent flow of innovators. Various and large local markets for nanofiber products can help domestic firms to build necessary capabilities for entering the foreign markets. However brand loyalty in one segment of the market and traditional players in another segment are two main market barriers for nanofibers development in Iran. Foreign sanctions against Iran on one hand have limited the financial transactions between Iranian and foreign firms. On the other hand, the sanctions have limited the entrance of foreign companies into Iran’s market. Government support programs for manufacturers of nanotechnology equipment had a crucial role in the success of the domestic firms in Entry Stage of the catch up cycle.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>1</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>28</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>عماد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>احمدوند</Family>
						<NameE>Emad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Ahmadvand</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری / دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری / دانشگاه علامه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>eahmadvand@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>رضا</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سلامی</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Reza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Salami</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>rz_salami@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>حبیب الله</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>طباطبائیان</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Habiboallah</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Tabatabaeian</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>tabatabaeian@atu.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>جهانیار</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>بامداد صوفی</Family>
						<NameE>Jahanyar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Bamdad Soofi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران، ایران.</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی، تهران،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>bamdadsoofi@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>همپایی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پنجره فرصت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رژیم فناوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>رژیم بازار</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نانوالیاف</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>نظام بخشی نوآوری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ahmadvand, E., Salami, S.R., Soofi, J.B. and Tabatabaeian, S.H. 2018. Catch-up process in nanotechnology start-ups: The case of an Iranian electrospinning firm. Technology in Society.##Amsden, A. 1989. Asia&#039;s next giant : South Korea and late industrialization: Oxford University Press.##Breschi, S. and Malerba, F. 1997. Sectoral innovation systems: technological regimes, Schumpeterian dynamics, and spatial boundaries. Systems of innovation: Technologies, institutions and organizations, pp. 130-156.##Breschi, S. Malerba, F. and Orsenigo, L. 2000. Technological regimes and Schumpeterian patterns of innovation. The Economic Journal, 110(463), pp. 388-410.##Fagerberg, J. and Godinho, M.M. 2005. Innovation and catching-up. The Oxford Handbook of Innovation. Oxford University Press, New York, pp. 514-543.##Fan, P. and Watanabe, C. 2006. Promoting industrial development through technology policy: Lessons from Japan and China. Technology in Society, 28(3), pp. 303-320.##FARIDI, M.R. Naderi, N. and KOOCHAKI, J.A. 2016. Needleless electrospinning apparatus. Google Patents.##Hobday, M. 1995. East Asian latecomer firms: learning the technology of electronics. World Development ,23(7), pp. 1171-1193.##Kang, H. and Song, J. 2017. Innovation and recurring shifts in industrial leadership: Three phases of change and persistence in the camera industry. Research Policy, 46(2), pp. 376-387.##Kannan, B. Cha, H. and Hosie, I.C. 2016. Electrospinning Commercial Applications, Challenges and Opportunities. In S. Fakirov ed. Nano-size Polymers: Preparation, Properties, Applications. Cham, Springer International Publishing. pp. 309-342.##Khademhosseini, A. Parak, W.J. and Weiss, P.S. 2016. Nanoscience and Nanotechnology around the World. ACS nano 10(5) 4883-4884.##Kiamehr, M. Hobday, M. and Hamedi, M. 2015. Latecomer firm strategies in complex product systems (CoPS): The case of Iran’s thermal electricity generation systems. Research Policy, 44(6), pp. 1240-1251.##Kim, J.Y. Park, T.Y. and Lee, K. 2013. Catch-up by indigenous firms in the software industry and the role of the government in China: A sectoral system of innovation (SSI) perspective. Eurasian Business Review, 3(1), pp. 100-120.##Kim, L. 1980. Stages of development of industrial technology in a developing country: a model. Research Policy, 9(3), pp. 254-277.##Kim, L. 1997. Imitation to innovation: The dynamics of Korea&#039;s technological learning: Harvard Business Press.##Kim, L. 1998. Crisis construction and organizational learning: Capability building in catching-up at Hyundai Motor. Organization science, 9(4), pp. 506-521.##Lee, J. 1996. Technology imports and R&amp;D efforts of Korean manufacturing firms. Journal of Development Economics, 50(1), pp. 197-210.##Lee, K. Gao, X. and Li, X. 2017. Industrial catch-up in China: a sectoral systems of innovation perspective. Cambridge Journal of Regions, Economy and Society, 10(1), pp. 59-76.##Lee, K. and Lim, C. 2001. Technological regimes, catching-up and leapfrogging: findings from the Korean industries. Research Policy, 30(3), pp. 459-483.##Lee, K. and Malerba, F. 2016. Catch-up cycles and changes in industrial leadership: Windows of opportunity and responses of firms and countries in the evolution of sectoral systems. Research Policy.##LF Nascimento, M. et al. 2015. A literature investigation about electrospinning and nanofibers: historical trends, current status and future challenges. Recent patents on nanotechnology, 9(2), pp. 76-85.##Li, Z. and Wang, C. 2013. One-dimensional nanostructures: electrospinning technique and unique nanofibers: Springer.##Majidpour, M. 2011. The Dynamics of Technological Catching-up: The Case of Iran&#039;s Gas Turbine Industry. University of Sussex.##Majidpour, M. 2016a. International technology transfer and the dynamics of complementarity: A new approach. Technological Forecasting and Social Change.##Majidpour, M. 2016b. Technological catch-up in complex product systems. Journal of Engineering and Technology Management, Volume(41), pp. 92-105.##Malerba, F. 2002. Sectoral systems of innovation and production. Research Policy, 31(2), pp. 247-264.##Malerba, F. and Nelson, R. 2008. Catching up in different sectoral systems. Globelics working paper series.##Marlerba, F. and Orsenigo, L. 1993. Technological Regimes and firm behavior. Industrial and Corporate Change, 2(1), pp. 45-66.##Mathews, J. 1995. High-Technology Industrialization in East Asia: The Case of the Semiconductor Industry in East Asia (Taipei: Chung-Hua Institute for Economic Research).##Mathews, J.A. 2002. Competitive advantages of the latecomer firm: A resource-based account of industrial catch-up strategies. Asia Pacific Journal of Management, 19(4), pp. 467-488.##Mazzoleni, R. and Nelson, R.R. 2007. Public research institutions and economic catch-up. Research Policy, 36(10), pp. 1512-1528.##Mirzaei, E. Majidi, R.F. Sarkar, S. and Rezayat, S.M. 2015. Electro spun nanofibrous wound dressing and a method of synthesizing the same. Google Patents.##Mohammadzadehmoghadam, S. et al. 2016. Electrospinning: Current Status and Future Trends. In S. Fakirov ed. Nano-size Polymers: Preparation, Properties, Applications. Cham, Springer International Publishing. pp. 89-154.##Mu, Q. and Lee, K. 2005. Knowledge diffusion, market segmentation and technological catch-up: The case of the telecommunication industry in China. Research Policy, 34(6), pp. 759-783.##Niosi, J. and Reid, S.E. 2007. Biotechnology and nanotechnology: science-based enabling technologies as windows of opportunity for LDCs? World Development ,35(3), pp. 426-438.##Perez, C. and Soete, L. 1988. Catching up in technology: entry barriers and windows of opportunity. Technical change and economic theory, pp. 458-479.##Radošević, S. 1999. International Technology Transfer and Catch-up in Economic Development: Edward Elgar.##Ramakrishna, S. 2005. An introduction to electrospinning and nanofibers: World Scientific.##Ramani, S.V. Chowdhury, N. Coronini, R. and Reid, S.E. 2011. On India&#039;s plunge into Nanotechnology: What are good ways to catch-up? UNU-MERIT Working Paper Series(2011-020).##Roco, M.C. Mirkin, C.A. and Hersam, M.C. 2011. Nanotechnology research directions for societal needs in 2020: summary of international study. Journal of Nanoparticle Research, 13(3), pp. 897-919.##Sarkar, K. et al. 2010. Electrospinning to forcespinning™. Materials Today, 13(11), pp. 12-14.##Shin, J.S. 2016. Dynamic catch-up strategy, capability expansion and changing windows of opportunity in the memory industry. Research Policy.##StatNanao. 2018. StatNano [online]. Available at: http://statnano.com/strategicplans [Accessed 2018/03/15 2018].##Thavasi, V. Singh, G. and Ramakrishna, S. 2008. Electrospun nanofibers in energy and environmental applications. Energy &amp; Environmental Science, 1(2), pp. 205-221.##Tomaszewski, W. and Szadkowski, M. 2005. Investigation of electrospinning with the use of a multi-jet electrospinning head. Fibres and Textiles in Eastern Europe, 13(4), p. 22.##Wong, P.K. 1999. National innovation systems for rapid technological catch-up: An analytical framework and a comparative analysis of Korea, Taiwan, and Singapore. DRUID Summer Conference held in Rebild.##Yin, R.K. 2014. Case study research: Design and methods Fifth edition: Sage publications.##Zhang, Z. Jin, J. and Guo, M. 2017. Catch-up in nanotechnology industry in China from the aspect of process-based innovation. Asian Journal of Technology Innovation, pp.  1-18.##توانیر. 1395، روند ۱۰ ساله صنعت برق ایران از 1384 تا 1394. آمار تفصیلی صنعت برق ایران.##حسنی، سیدحمزه، قافله باشی، سیدمجتبی و رفیعی، سعیدحسین. 1395. داستان نانو تافته: انتشارات بسیج دانشجویی دانشگاه امام صادق.##ستاد فناوری نانو. 1386. گزارش عملکرد سند راهبرد آینده.##ستاد فناوری نانو. 1390. گزارش عملکرد سند راهبرد آینده.##ستاد فناوری نانو.1391a. راهبرد آینده: راهبرد ده‌ساله توسعه فناوری نانو در جمهوری اسلامی ایران- سند تکمیلی سوم. ستاد ویژه توسعه فناوری نانو.##ستاد فناوری نانو. 1391b. گزارش عملکرد سند راهبرد آینده.##ستاد فناوری نانو. 1392. گزارش عملکرد سند راهبرد آینده.##ستاد فناوری نانو. 1393. گزارش عملکرد سند راهبرد آینده.##ستاد فناوری نانو. 1394. گزارش عملکرد سند راهبرد آینده.##ستاد فناوری نانو. 1395a. گزارش عملکرد سند راهبرد آینده.##ستاد فناوری نانو. 1395b. محصولات فناوری نانو ساخت ایران-ویرایش سوم: ستاد ویژه توسعه فناوری نانو.##شبکه چهار سیما. 1395. صفرتا صد؛ فناوران نانومقیاس. صفرتا صد. 17 دقیقه.##شرکت ملی صنایع پتروشیمی. 1396. عملکرد صنعت پتروشیمی [online]: روابط عمومی شرکت ملی صنایع پتروشیمی. Available at: http://www.nipna.ir/fa/newsagency/15053/ [Accessed June 13 2017].##فروندی، محمدجواد... 1392. سخنرانی مدیر طراحی شرکت بهران فیلتر در مجمع اقتصاد نانو [online]. Available at: http://news.nano.ir/1/447401395.##فریدی مجیدی، رضا. 1387. مصاحبه با ماهنامه فناوری نانو.##معاونت علمی و فناوری. 1395a. نمایشگاه تجهیزات و مواد آزمایشگاهی ساخت ایران، دستورالعمل ارزیابی فنی محصولات [online]. Available at: http://iranlabexpo.ir/index.php?ctrl=page&amp;id=13011395.##معاونت علمی و فناوری. 1395b. نمایشگاه تجهیزات و مواد آزمایشگاهی ساخت ایران، لیست محصولات [online]. Available at: http://iranlabexpo.ir/index.php?ctrl=products&amp;lang=11396.##موسسه خدمات فناوری تا بازار ایرانیان 1395. جهش 1؛ فناوران نانومقیاس. جهش. 40 دقیقه.##موسسه خدمات فناوری تا بازار ایرانیان. 1396. خدمات به شرکت‌های فناوری نانو [online]. Available at: http://tmsc.ir/index.php?ctrl=static_page&amp;lang=1&amp;id=2336&amp;section_id=351396.##هیئت دولت. 1396. سند گسترش کاربرد فناوری نانو در افق 1404##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>چارچوب طراحی سازمان در اتحادهای استراتژیک بین‌المللی مبتنی بر فناوری</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Presenting a Framework of Organization Design in Technology-based International Strategic Alliances</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>اتحادهای استراتژیک به‌تدریج سهم قابل‌توجهی از پژوهش‌های دانشگاهی در حوزه مدیریت استراتژیک و تصمیم‌های مدیران بنگاه‌های تجاری را به خود اختصاص داده‌اند. علیرغم این اقبال روزافزون، نرخ شکست اتحادهای استراتژیک همچنان بسیار زیاد است و پیشینه نظری اصلی‌ترین علت این نرخ شکست را در الگوی اداره و سازمان‌دهی اتحادها می‌داند. پژوهش حاضر با درنظرگرفتن اهمیت مسئله ساختار و خلأ نظری پیرامون آن، به بررسی اقتضائات و ویژگی‌های ساختار اتحادهای استراتژیک بین‌المللی مبتنی بر فناوری پرداخته است. نتایج حاصل از این پژوهش که با استراتژی مورد کاوی چندگانه به انجام رسیده است، سه نوع ساختار پارلمانی، تکنوکراتیک و کمیته‌ای را از یکدیگر تفکیک کرده و اقتضائات لازم برای به‌کارگیری کارآمد هر یک را مشخص ساخته است. در شرایطی که تمرکز عمودی زیاد و تمرکز افقی کم باشد، ساختار پارلمانی بیشترین اثربخشی را دارد و اگر تمرکز عمودی کم و تمرکز افقی زیاد باشد، ساختار تکنوکراتیک کارآمدتر است. این دو ساختار در دو سر یک طیف قرار می‌گیرند که هر نقطه میان آن‌ها، بستر مساعدی برای به‌کارگیری ساختار کمیته‌ای است.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Strategic alliances have gained considerable attention, both among strategic management researches and across managerial decisions in business companies. Despite of this popularity, the failure rate of strategic alliances is high and theoretical literature has being sought the reason in governance mechanism and organizational design of alliances. With considering the importance of this issue and theoretical gap about it, current research devoted to the requirements and specifications of the structure of technology-based international strategic alliances. Findings from this multiple case study research are distinguished three designs and theirs requirements for effective application: parliamentary, technocratic and committee. In high vertical centralization-low horizontal centralization situation, the parliamentary form has most effectiveness; and in low vertical centralization-high horizontal centralization, the technocratic form is best suited. These forms are on a spectrum in which, any points between extremes, is a favourable place for applying of committee-based structure.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>29</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>50</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید حسین</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جلالی</Family>
						<NameE>S. Hossein</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Jalali</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>jalali.seyedhossein@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>طهمورث</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسنقلی پور</Family>
						<NameE>Tahmoores</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Hasangholipour</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>استاد، مدیریت، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکده مدیریت، دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>استاد، مدیریت، گروه مدیریت بازرگانی، دانشکده</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>thyasory@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اتحادهای استراتژیک</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>طراحی سازمان</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ساختار اتحاد</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>اتحادهای فناوری‌محور</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Abdi, M., &amp; Aulakh, P. S., 2017. Locus of uncertainty and the relationship between contractual and relational governance in cross-border interfirm relationships, Journal of Management, 43(3), pp.771-803.##Adegbesan, J. A., &amp; Higgins, M. J., 2011. The intra‐alliance division of value created through collaboration, Strategic Management Journal, 32(2), pp.187-211.##Albers, S., 2010. Configurations of alliance governance systems, Schmalenbach Business Review, 62(3), pp. 204-233.##Albers, S., Wohlgezogen, F., &amp; Zajac, E. J., 2016. Strategic alliance structures: An organization design perspective, Journal of Management, 42(3), pp.582-614.##Aulakh, P. S., &amp; Gençtürk, F. E., 2008. Contract formalization and governance of exporter–importer relationships, Journal of Management Studies, 45(3), pp.457-479.##Cao, Z., &amp; Lumineau, F., 2015. Revisiting the interplay between contractual and relational governance: A qualitative and meta-analytic investigation, Journal of Operations Management, 33, pp.15-42.##Castañer, X., Mulotte, L., Garrette, B., &amp; Dussauge, P., 2014. Governance mode vs. governance fit: Performance implications of make‐or‐ally choices for product innovation in the worldwide aircraft industry 1942–2000, Strategic Management Journal, 35(9), pp.1386-1397.##Cavusgil, S. T., Deligonul, S., &amp; Zhang, C., 2004. Curbing foreign distributor opportunism: An examination of trust, contracts, and the legal environment in international channel relationships, Journal of International Marketing, 12(2), pp.7-27.##Chen, h., &amp; Chen, T.j., 2003. Governance structure in strategic alliance: Transaction cost versus resource based perspective, Journal of World Business, 38(1), pp.1-14.##Contractor, F. J., &amp; Reuer, J. J., 2014. Structuring and governing alliances: New directions for research, Global Strategy Journal, 4(4), pp.241-256.##Creswell, J. W., 1998. Qualitative Inquiry and Research Design: Choosing among Five Tradition, Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.##Das, T. K., &amp; Teng, B. S., 1996. Risk types and inter‐firm alliance structures, Journal of Management Studies, 33(6), pp.827-843.##Davis, J. P., &amp; Eisenhardt, K. M., 2011. Rotating leadership and collaborative innovation: Recombination processes in symbiotic relationships, Administrative Science Quarterly, 56(2), pp.159-201.##Doz, Y. L., &amp; Hamel, G., 1998. Alliance Advantage: The Art of Creating Value Through Partnering, Boston: Harvard Business School Press.##Eisenhardt, K.M., &amp; Graebner, M.E., 2007. Theory building from cases: Opportunities and challenges, Academy of Management Journal, 50(1), pp.25-32.##Faems, D., Janssens, M., Madhok, A., &amp; Looy, B. V., 2008. Toward an integrative perspective on alliance governance: Connecting contract design, trust dynamics, and contract application, Academy of Management Journal, 51(6), pp.1053-1078.##Ferguson, R. J., Paulin, M., &amp; Bergeron, J., 2005. Contractual governance, relational governance, and the performance of interfirm service exchanges: The influence of boundary-spanner closeness, Journal of the Academy of Marketing Science, 33(2), pp.217-234.##Guba, E.G., &amp; Lincoln, Y.S., 1994. Competing Paradigms in Qualitative Research, In Denzin, N.K. and Lincoln, Y.S. (Eds), Handbook of Qualitative Research, pp.105-117, Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.##Gulati, R., &amp; Singh, H., 1998. The architecture of cooperation: Managing coordination costs and appropriation concerns in strategic alliances, Administrative Science Quarterly, 43, pp.781-814.##Hoetker, G., &amp; Mellewigt, T., 2009. Choice and performance of governance mechanisms: matching alliance governance to asset type, Strategic Management Journal, 30(10), pp.1025-1044.##Ireland, R. D., Hitt, M. A., &amp; Vaidyanath, D., 2002. Alliance management as a source of competitive advantage, Journal of Management, 28(3), pp.413-446.##Jalali, S.H., 2017. How alliance partner characteristics can affect performance? An empirical evidence from emerging economies context, International Journal of Strategic Business Alliances, 6(1-2), pp.1-17.##Klijn, E., Reuer, J. J., Buckley, P. J., &amp; Glaister, K. W., 2010. Combinations of partners&#039; joint venture formation motives, European Business Review, 22(6), pp.576-590##Krishnan, R., Geyskens, I., &amp; Steenkamp, J. B. E., 2016. The effectiveness of contractual and trust‐based governance in strategic alliances under behavioral and environmental uncertainty, Strategic Management Journal, 37(12), pp.2521-2542.##Lavie, D., Haunschild, P. R., &amp; Khanna, P., 2012. Organizational differences, relational mechanisms, and alliance performance, Strategic Management Journal, 33(13), pp.1453-1479.##Lawrence, P. R., &amp; Lorsch, J. W., 1967. Differentiation and integration in complex organizations, Administrative Science Quarterly, 12(1), pp.1-47.##Li, J., Zhou, C., &amp; Zajac, E. J., 2009. Control, collaboration, and productivity in international joint ventures: Theory and evidence, Strategic Management Journal, 30(8), pp.865-884.##Lin, H., &amp; Darnall, N., 2015. Strategic alliance formation and structural configuration, Journal of Business Ethics, 127(3), pp.549-564.##Lincoln, Y., &amp; Guba, E., 1985. Naturalistic Inquiry, Beverly Hills, CA: Sage.##Lumineau, F., &amp; Malhotra, D., 2011. Shadow of the contract: How contract structure shapes interfirm dispute resolution, Strategic Management Journal, 32(5), pp.532-555.##Mayer, K. J., &amp; Argyres, N. S., 2004. Learning to contract: Evidence from the personal computer industry, Organization Science, 15(4), pp.394-410.##Mohr, A. T., &amp; Puck, J., 2013. Revisiting the trust-performance link in strategic alliances, Management International Review, 53(2), pp.269-289.##Nielsen, B.B., &amp; Gudergan, S., 2012. Exploration and exploitation fit and performance in international strategic alliances, International Business Review, 21(4), pp.558-574.##Reuer, J. J., &amp; Arino, A., 2007. Strategic alliance contracts: Dimensions and determinants of contractual complexity, Strategic Management Journal, 28(3), pp.313-330.##Schilke, O., &amp; Cook, K. S., 2015. Sources of alliance partner trustworthiness: Integrating calculative and relational perspectives, Strategic Management Journal, 36(2), pp.276-297.##Stake, R. E., 1995. The Art of Case Study Research, Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.##Suchman, M. C., 2003. The contract as social artifact, Law &amp; Society Review, 37(1), pp.91-142.##Teng, B. S., &amp; Das, T. K., 2008. Governance structure choice in strategic alliances: The roles of alliance objectives, alliance management experience, and international partners, Management Decision, 46(5), pp.725-742.##Wang, L., &amp; Zajac, E. J., 2007. Alliance or acquisition? A dyadic perspective on interfirm resource combinations, Strategic Management Journal, 28(13), pp.1291-1317.##Welch, C., Piekkari, R., Plakoyiannaki, E., &amp; Paavilainen-Mäntymäki, E., 2011. Theorising from case studies: Towards a pluralist future for international business research, Journal of International Business Studies, 42(5), pp.740-762.##Yin, R.K., 2003. Case Study Research: Design and Methods, 3rd ed. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.##Zhou, K. Z., &amp; Xu, D., 2012. How foreign firms curtail local supplier opportunism in China: Detailed contracts, centralized control, and relational governance, Journal of International Business Studies, 43(7), pp.677-692.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>عوامل کلیدی موفقیت پروژه‌های طراحی‌محصول با رویکرد جمع‌سپاری در صنعت فناوری اطلاعات</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Identifying and prioritizing Critical Success Factors of product design in IT industry with Crowdsourcing Approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>جمع‌سپاری یکی از راهبردهای همکاری در نوآوری باز است که با بهره‌گیری از امکانات فناوری اطلاعات (IT) بستری را برای حضور فعال جمعیت‌های آنلاین در فعالیت‌های مختلف شرکت‌ها نظیر طراحی‌محصول فراهم کرده‌است. با این حال تعداد پروژه‌هایی که در این حوزه به نتایج قابل قبول نرسیده و کارایی لازم را نداشته‌اند نیز کم نبوده‌است. این پژوهش درصدد شناسایی و تعیین اولویت برای شاخص‌های موفقیت در جمع‌سپاریطراحی‌محصول و بهبود آن بوده‌است. این تحقیق از نوع تحقیقات آمیخته است که در قسمت کیفی، تحلیل مضمون و در قسمت کمی با روش توصیفی پیمایشی صورت گرفته‌است. جامعه تحقیق شامل تمام کارشناسان،نخبگان و متخصصان حوزه جمع‌سپاری بود، در همین راستا ابتدا با استفاده از ادبیات پیشین تعدادی عوامل استخراج شد سپس به کمک مصاحبه با ۱۰ نفر از کارشناسان،مدیران سازمان‌هایی که تجربه استفاده از جمع‌سپاری را در طراحی‌محصول داشته‌اند، در مجموع ۳۶ عامل حیاتی برای موفقیت جمع‌سپاری مورد شناسایی قرار گرفت که با روش دلفی غربالسازی شدند و  به کمک روش بهترین-بدترین (BWM) اولویت‌بندی شدند. از میان ابعاد چهارگانه جمع‌سپاری به ترتیب «مشارکت‌کنندگان»، «سیستم IT»، «مدیریت سازمان» و «کارمندان» و نیز در میان عوامل این ابعاد، «کیفیت عملکرد مشارکت‌کنندگان»، «کیفیت سیستم IT»، «فرآیند کنترل و نظارت» و «کارآیی کارمندان» به ترتیب دارای بیشترین اهمیت بودند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>Crowdsourcing is one of the new cooperative strategiesin open innovation that Using Information Technology (IT) facilities, provides a platform for active online crowds in various activities of companies such as product design. However, in this area, there were not too many projects which have achieved acceptable results. Therefore, this research attempts to identify and prioritize success factors of crowdsourcing in product design and improvement. the type of research is mixed method. The method of analysis for qualitative section is based on content analysis and for quantitative part is based on descriptive survey. Data were collected from experts and specialists in the field of crowdsourcing. Hence, several factors has been extracted from previous studies, then 36 main success factors has been recognized through interviewing approximately ten managers who are experienced in crowdsourcing for product design. The factors were assayed by Delphi method and final dimensions and factors were weighed by experts using best worth method. The study prioritized the quadruple dimensions of crowdsourcing as follows: contributors, IT system, organization management and employees. Among the factors of mentioned dimensions, “contributors operation quality”, “quality of IT System”, “control and supervision process” and “employees efficiency” are the most important ones, respectively.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>51</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>84</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>مرتضی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>سلطانی</Family>
						<NameE>Morteza</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Soltani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیات علمی دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mortezasoltanee@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>میثم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شفیعی رودپشتی</Family>
						<NameE>maysam</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>shafiei</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیت علمی دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیت علمی دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>maysam.shafiee@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید جاوید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>حسینی</Family>
						<NameE>s.javid</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>hosseini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانش آموخته مدیریت بازرگانی دانشگاه تهران پردیس فارابی</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانش آموخته مدیریت بازرگانی دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>j.hosseini@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>جمع‌سپاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>طراحی‌محصول</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>صنعت it</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>عوامل کلیدی موفقیت</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>روش دلفی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تکنیک BWM</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Archak, N., 2010, April. Money, glory and cheap talk: analyzing strategic behavior of contestants in simultaneous crowdsourcing contests on TopCoder. com. In Proceedings of the 19th international conference on World wide web (pp. 21-30). ACM.##Atakan, S.S., Bagozzi, R.P. and Yoon, C., 2014. Consumer participation in the design and realization stages of production: How self-production shapes consumer evaluations and relationships to products. International journal of research in marketing, 31(4), pp.395-408.##Bayus, B.L., 2013. Crowdsourcing new product ideas over time: An analysis of the Dell IdeaStorm community. Management science, 59(1), pp.226-244.##Bouras, C., Igglesis, V., Kapoulas, V. and Tsiatsos, T., 2005. A web-based virtual community. International Journal of Web Based Communities, 1(2), pp.127-139.##Brabham, D.C., 2008. Crowdsourcing as a model for problem solving: An introduction and cases. Convergence, 14(1), pp.75-90.##Brabham, D.C., 2010. Crowdsourcing as a model for problem solving: leveraging the collective intelligence of online communities for public good. The University of Utah.##Buecheler, T., Sieg, J.H., Füchslin, R.M. and Pfeifer, R., 2010. Crowdsourcing, open innovation and collective intelligence in the scientific method: a research agenda and operational framework. In The 12th International Conference on the Synthesis and Simulation of Living Systems, Odense, Denmark, 19–23 August 2010 (pp. 679-686). MIT Press.##Cannon, J.P. and Homburg, C., 2001. Buyer-supplier relationships and customer firm costs. Journal of Marketing, 65(1), pp.29-43.##Dawson, R. and ByngHall, S., 2011. Getting Results from Crowds - The Definitive Guide to Using Crowds to Grow Your Business. 1st ed. San Francisco: Advanced Human Technologie.##Djelassi, S. and Decoopman, I., 2013. Customers&#039; participation in product development through crowdsourcing: Issues and implications. Industrial Marketing Management, 42(5), pp.683-692.##Enkel, E., Gassmann, O. and Chesbrough, H., 2009. Open R&amp;D and open innovation: exploring the phenomenon. R&amp;d Management, 39(4), pp.311-316.##Fink, A., Kosecoff, J., Chassin, M. and Brook, R.H., 1984. Consensus methods: characteristics and guidelines for use. American journal of public health, 74(9), pp.979-983.##Füller, J., Bartl, M., Ernst, H. and Mühlbacher, H., 2006. Community based innovation: How to integrate members of virtual communities into new product development. Electronic Commerce Research, 6(1), pp.57-73.##Gatautis, R. and Vitkauskaite, E., 2014. Crowdsourcing application in marketing activities. Procedia-Social and Behavioral Sciences, 110, pp.1243-1250.##Gefen, D., Gefen, G. and Carmel, E., 2016. How project description length and expected duration affect bidding and project success in crowdsourcing software development. Journal of Systems and Software, 116, pp.75-84.##Hippel, E.V. and Krogh, G.V., 2003. Open source software and the “private-collective” innovation model: Issues for organization science. Organization science, 14(2), pp.209-223.##Hoek, J.F.S., 2014. Crowdsourcing for Innovation: An overview of the success factors and challenges of the broadcast search process (Bachelor&#039;s thesis).##Howe, J., 2006. The rise of crowdsourcing. Wired magazine, 14(6), pp.1-4.##Huang, S.W. and Fu, W.T., 2013, April. Don&#039;t hide in the crowd!: increasing social transparency between peer workers improves crowdsourcing outcomes. In Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems(pp. 621-630). ACM.##Jaakkola, H., 2017. The Influence of Cultural Factors on Crowdsource Product Designing. Information Modelling and Knowledge Bases XXVIII, 292, p.334.##Kuijpers, M.J.M., 2013. Crowdsourcing Critical Success Factors in SME’s: Towards a Successful Implementation Model.##Kuppuswamy, V. and Bayus, B.L., 2015. Crowdfunding creative ideas: The dynamics of project backers in Kickstarter (UNC Kenan-Flagler Research Paper No. 2013-15). Available at: SSRN http://papers. ssrn. com/sol3/papers. cfm.##Laasonen, J.A., 2014. Value Creation in Crowd-Business: Developing a Framework for Successful Implementation of Crowdsourcing Initiatives.##Lee, C.Y. and Glass, J., 2011. A transcription task for crowdsourcing with automatic quality control. In Twelfth Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association, pp.3041-3044.##Li, Z. and Hongjuan, Z., 2011, June. Research of crowdsourcing model based on case study. In Service Systems and Service Management (ICSSSM), 2011 8th International Conference on (pp. 1-5). IEEE.##Liu, T.X., Yang, J., Adamic, L.A. and Chen, Y., 2014. Crowdsourcing with all-pay auctions: a field experiment on taskcn. Management Science, 60(8), pp.2020-2037.##Menguc, B., Auh, S. and Yannopoulos, P., 2014. Customer and supplier involvement in design: The moderating role of incremental and radical innovation capability. Journal of Product Innovation Management, 31(2), pp.313-328.##Mukherji, S., 2012. A framework for managing customer knowledge in retail industry. IIMB Management Review, 24(2), pp.95-103.##Nishikawa, H., Schreier, M. and Ogawa, S., 2013. User-generated versus designer-generated products: A performance assessment at Muji. International Journal of Research in Marketing, 30(2), pp.160-167.##Piller, F., 2010. Open innovation with customers: crowdsourcing and co-creation at Threadless, available at: http://ssrn.com/abstract¼1688018 (accessed 5 October 2010).##Rezaei, J., 2015. Best-worst multi-criteria decision-making method. Omega, 53, pp.49-57.##Romanczuk, G.E., Willy, C. and Bischoff, J.E., 2017. Critical success factors for crowdsourcing with virtual environments to unlock innovation. Defense AR Journal, 24(2), p.334.##Sharma, A., 2010. Crowdsourcing Critical Success Factor Model: Strategies to harness the collective intelligence of the crowd. London School of Economics (LSE), London, pp.1-22.##Tajedin, H. and Nevo, D., 2013, May. Determinants of success in crowdsourcing software development. In Proceedings of the 2013 annual conference on Computers and people research(pp. 173-178). ACM.##Walter, T. and Back, A., 2011. Towards measuring crowdsourcing success: An empirical study on effects of external factors in online idea contest.Institute of Information Management, University of St. Gallen##Whitla, P., 2009. Crowdsourcing and its application in marketing activities. Contemporary Management Research, 5(1), pp.15-28.##Williams, P.L. and Webb, C., 1994. The Delphi technique: a methodological discussion. Journal of advanced nursing, 19(1), pp.180-186.##Yang, J., Adamic, L.A. and Ackerman, M.S., 2008, July. Crowdsourcing and knowledge sharing: strategic user behavior on taskcn. In Proceedings of the 9th ACM conference on Electronic commerce (pp. 246-255). ACM.##Yoo, J., Lee, K. and Choi, M., 2013. Crowdsourcing for device manufacturers in the convergent media industry. Communications &amp; Strategies, No. 89, 1st Quarter 2013, pp. 73-93.##Zott, C., Amit, R. and Massa, L., 2011. The business model: recent developments and future research. Journal of management, 37(4), pp.1019-1042.##Zwikael, O., Pathak, R.D., Singh, G. and Ahmed, S., 2014. The moderating effect of risk on the relationship between planning and success. International Journal of Project Management, 32(3), pp.435-441.##آذر،ع. و ، مومنی، م. ، ۱۳۹۵. آمار و کاربرد آن در مدیریت-جلد دوم-تحلیل آماری. تهران : انتشارات سازمان مطالعه و تدوین کتب علوم انسانی دانشگاه‌ها (سمت).##جوادی خسرقی، ه.، ۱۳۹۲. شناسایی فاکتورهای اثرگذار بر عملکرد جمع کاران در پلتفرم‌های جمع‌سپاری. پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد. دانشگاه صنعتی خواجه نصیر الدین طوسی. دانشکده مهندسی صنایع.##حبیبی، آ. ، ایزدیار، ص. ، سرافرازی، ا. ، ۱۳۹۳. تصمیم‌گیری چندمعیاره فازی. تهران: انتشارات کتیبه گیل.##شفیعی، س. ، ۱۳۹۶. عوامل موثر بر مشارکت الکترونیک مشتریان در جمع‌سپاری و ارتقای عملکرد شرکت؛مطالعه موردی: مدیران بازاریابی شهر اصفهان. تحقیقات بازاریابی نوین،(۷)۲،صص۱۱۵-۱۳۴.##قدسی پور، ح. ، ۱۳۹۵. فرآیند تحلیل سلسله مراتبی. تهران: دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر.##قوامی عادل، م. ، ۱۳۹۴. عوامل کلیدی موفقیت به‌کارگیری جمع‌سپاری در توسعه محصول جدید. پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد. دانشگاه الزهرا(س).دانشکده اقتصاد و حسابداری.##مهرگان، م. ، ۱۳۸۳. پژوهش عملیاتی پیشرفته. تهران: انتشارات کتاب دانشگاهی.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>چالش های شکل دهی شبکه همکاری مهندسی شده (مطالعه موردی شبکه همکاری شرکت پویندگان راه سعادت)</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Identifying and analyzing challenges of forming of the engineered collaboration network
(a Case study of collaboration network of Poyandeghan Rah Saadat)</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>در سالیان گذشته مطالعات بسیاری بر روی شبکه‌های همکاری انجام‌شده، بااین‌وجود روند تکامل و آفرینش شبکه، در تعداد کمی از تحقیقات موردتوجه قرارگرفته است. در این میان شناسایی و تحلیل جامع چالش‌های موجود در روند تشکیل شبکه، باهدف حل آن‌ها و پایدارسازی شبکه از اهمیت بسیاری برخوردار است. در این پژوهش یک شبکه همکاری فعال در زمینه تجهیزات پزشکی که در سال ۱۳۸۸ هسته اولیه آن به‌صورت مهندسی‌شده ایجاد گردید و متشکل از اعضای متنوع می‌باشد، موردمطالعه قرار گرفت. حضور اعضای متنوع در شبکه، زمینه‌ساز بروز چالش‌های مختلف است و امکان ارائه تحلیل مقایسه‌ای بین آن‌ها را به وجود می‌آورد. جهت تجزیه‌وتحلیل‌ فرآیندمحور و غنی اطلاعات جمع‌آوری‌شده از مصاحبه‌های عمیق و اسناد پشتیبان، از رویکرد کیفی و مطالعه موردی استفاده شد. درنهایت ضمن تحلیل ساختار و چارچوب شبکه، 4 مدل همکاری و 28 چالش مختلف در شبکه شناسایی گردید و چالش­های شناسایی‌شده (بر اساس وجود و یا عدم وجود آن‌ها در هر یک از 4 مدل همکاری شناسایی‌شده) به 7 دسته، تقسیم‌بندی گردیدند و مورد تحلیل قرار گرفتند.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>In recent years, many studies have been conducted on collaboration networks, however, the process of evolution and network creation has been considered in a small number of studies. In this context, comprehensive identification and analysis of the challenges in the network forming process are important in order to solve them and to stabilize the network. In this research, an active collaboration network in the field of medical equipment that engineered by a Hub in 2009 and consisting of a large company, a small and medium-sized company, two subcontractors, three universities, a start-up, an accelerator and a venture capital fund, was studied. The presence of diverse members in the network is the basis for the emergence of various challenges and allows for a comparative analysis between them. For process-centric and rich analyze of information that gathered from deep interviews and supporting documents, a qualitative approach and case study were used. Finally, after analyzing the structure and framework of the network, 4 collaboration models and 28 different challenges were identified in the network, and in order to provide an analysis, those 28 different challenges (based on their existence or absence in each of the 4 identified collaboration models) divided into 7 categories and analyzed</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>85</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>112</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>هاشم</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>معزز</Family>
						<NameE>Hashem</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Moazzez</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تهران، تهران، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>h.moazzez@ut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>ترابی خرق</Family>
						<NameE>Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Torabi Khargh</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>دانشگاه تهران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>دانشگاه تهران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>m.torabi1390@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>هادی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>نیلفروشان</Family>
						<NameE>Hadi</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Nilforoushan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>پژوهشکده مطالعات بنیادین علم و فناوری ، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی ، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>پژوهشکده مطالعات بنیادین علم و فناوری ، دانشگاه</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>hadinil@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سید محمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>صاحبکار خراسانی</Family>
						<NameE>Seyed Mohammad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Sahebkar Khorasani</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>پژوهشکده مطالعات فناوری، تهران، ایران</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>sahebkar@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>همکاری فناورانه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شبکه همکاری مهندسی شده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>شکل دهی شبکه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>چالش‌های همکاری</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>تجهیزات پزشکی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مطالعه موردی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Akdoğan, A.A. &amp; Cingšz, A., 2012. An Empirical Study on Determining the Attitudes of Small and Medium Sized Businesses (SMEs) Related to Coopetition. Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences, 58, pp.252–258.##Al-Tabbaa, O. &amp; Ankrah, S., 2016. Social capital to facilitate ‘engineered’ university–industry collaboration for technology transfer: A dynamic perspective. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 104, pp.1–15.##Ansari, M.F., Kharb, R.K., Luthra, S., Shimmi, S.L. &amp; Chatterji, S., 2013. Analysis of barriers to implement solar power installations in India using interpretive structural modeling technique. Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews, 27, pp.163–174.##Asadifard, R., Tabatabaeian, S.H., Sofi, J.B. &amp; Taghva, M.R., 2017. A model for investigating the stability factors in formal science and technology collaborative networks: A case study of Iran. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 122, pp.139–150.##Birkinshaw, J., Bessant, J. &amp; Delbridge, R., 2007. Finding, Forming, and Performing: Creating Networks for Discontinuous Innovation. California Management Review, 49(3), pp.67–84.##Boyatzis, R.E., 1998. Transforming qualitative information: Thematic analysis and code development. sage.##Chang, S.-H., 2017. The technology networks and development trends of university-industry collaborative patents. Technological Forecasting and Social Change,118, pp.107–113.##Chen, K., 2017. Do research institutes benefit from their network positions in research collaboration networks with industries or / and universities ? Technovation, (October), pp.1–20.##COY, S.P., SHIPLEY, M.F., OMER, K. &amp; KHAN, R.N.A., 2007. FACTORS CONTRIBUTORY TO SUCCESS: A STUDY OF PAKISTAN’S SMALL BUSINESS OWNERS. Journal of Developmental Entrepreneurship, 12(02), pp.181–198.##Creswell, J.W., 1998. Qualitative inquiry and research design: Choosing among five traditions. thousand oaks, ca: Sage.##Darabi, F. &amp; Clark, M., 2012. Developing business school/SMEs collaboration: the role of trust. International Journal of Entrepreneurial Behavior &amp; Research, 18(4), pp.477–493.##Etemad, H., Wright, R.W. &amp; Dana, L.P., 2001. Symbiotic international business networks: collaboration between small and large firms. Thunderbird International Business Review, 43(4), pp.481–499.##Evans, P. &amp; Wolf, B., 2005. Collaboration Rules. Harvard Business Review, (JULY–AUGUST).##Fernández-Olmos, M. &amp; Ramírez-Alesón, M., 2017. How internal and external factors influence the dynamics of SME technology collaboration networks over time. Technovation, 64–65(July 2016), pp.16–27.##Fiaz, M. &amp; Naiding, Y., 2012. Exploring the Barriers to R&amp;D Collaborations: A Challenge for Industry and Faculty for Sustainable U-I Collaboration Growth. International Journal of U- &amp; E-Service, Science &amp; Technology, 5(2), pp.1–15.##Fung, H.-N. &amp; Wong, C.-Y., 2017. Scientific collaboration in indigenous knowledge in context: Insights from publication and co-publication network analysis. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 117, pp.57–69.##Hanna, V. &amp; Walsh, K., 2008. Interfirm Cooperation among Small Manufacturing Firms. International Small Business Journal, 26(3), pp.299–321.##Hemetsberger, A. &amp; Reinhardt, C., 2009. Collective Development in Open-Source Communities: An Activity Theoretical Perspective on Successful Online Collaboration. Organization Studies, 30(9), pp.987–1008.##Hoang, H. &amp; Antoncic, B., 2003. Network-based research in entrepreneurship. Journal of Business Venturing, 18(2), pp.165–187.##Hyötyläinen, R., Valkokari, K. &amp; Kalliokoski, P., 2011. Renewal Through Co-Creation in Business Networks. The Open Source Business Resource, (October 2016), pp.29–37.##Inkpen, A.C. &amp; Tsang, E.W.K., 2005. SOCIAL CAPITAL, NETWORKS, AND KNOWLEDGE TRANSFER. Academy of Management Review, 30(1), pp.146–165.##Jack, S.L., 2010. Approaches to studying networks: Implications and outcomes. Journal of Business Venturing, 25(1), pp.120–137.##Johanson, M. &amp; Lundberg, H., 2011. Network Strategies for Regional Growth. London: Palgrave Macmillan UK.##Kapucu, N. &amp; Garayev, V., 2013. Designing, Managing, and Sustaining Functionally Collaborative Emergency Management Networks. The American Review of Public Administration, 43(3), pp.312–330.##Karlsson, J., Booth, S. &amp; Odenrick, P., 2007. Academics’ Strategies and Obstacles in Achieving Collaboration between Universities and SMEs. Tertiary Education and Management, 13(3), pp.187–201.##Kshetri, N. &amp; Schiopu, A., 2007. Government Policy, Continental Collaboration and the Diffusion of Open Source Software in China, Japan, &amp; South Korea. Journal of Asia-Pacific Business, 8(1), pp.61–77.##Lindman, J. &amp; Rajala, R., 2012. How Open Source Has Changed the Software Industry : Perspectives from Open Source Entrepreneurs. technology Innovation Management Review, (January), pp.5–11.##Mohr, J. &amp; Spekman, R., 2016. Characteristics of Partnership Success : Partnership Attributes , Communication Behavior , and Conflict Resolution Techniques Author ( s ): Jakki Mohr and Robert Spekman Published by : Wiley Stable URL : http://www.jstor.org/stable/2486868 Accessed : 13-0. Strategic Management Journal, 15(2), pp.135–152.##Muegge, S., 2013. Platforms , Communities , and Business Ecosystems : Lessons Learned about Technology Entrepreneurship in an Interconnected World Platforms , Communities , and Business Ecosystems. Technology Innovation Management Review, (February), pp.5–15.##Muscio, A., 2007. THE IMPACT OF ABSORPTIVE CAPACITY ON SMEs’ COLLABORATION. Economics of Innovation and New Technology, 16(8), pp.653–668.##Nan, N. &amp; Kumar, S., 2013. Joint effect of team structure and software architecture in open source software development. IEEE Transactions on Engineering Management, 60(3), pp.592–603.##Provan, K.G., Fish, A., Sydow, J. &amp; Fish, A., 2007. Interorganizational Networks at the Network Level A Review of the Empirical Literature on Whole Networks. Journal of Management, 33(3), pp.479–516.##Rajalo, S. &amp; Vadi, M., 2017. University-industry innovation collaboration: Reconceptualization. Technovation, 62–63(April), pp.42–54.##Ramesh, A., Banwet, D.K. &amp; Shankar, R., 2010. Modeling the barriers of supply chain collaboration. Journal of Modelling in Management, 5(2), pp.176–193##Richbell, S.M., 2006. Owner-managers and Business Planning in the Small Firm. International Small Business Journal, 24(5), pp.496–514.##Riemer, K. &amp; Klein, S., n.d. Network Management Framework. In: Managing Dynamic Networks. Berlin/Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag, pp.17–66.##Sarker, S., Sarker, S. &amp; Schneider, C., 2009. Seeing Remote Team Members as Leaders: A Study of US-Scandinavian Teams. IEEE Transactions on Professional Communication, 52(1), pp.75–94.##Scaringella, L. &amp; Burtschell, F., 2017. The challenges of radical innovation in Iran: Knowledge transfer and absorptive capacity highlights — Evidence from a joint venture in the construction sector. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, 122, pp.151–169.##Schøtt, T. &amp; Jensen, K.W., 2016. Firms’ innovation benefiting from networking and institutional support: A global analysis of national and firm effects. Research Policy, 45(6), pp.1233–1246.##Shalbaf, R., Behnam, H. &amp; Jelveh Moghadam, H., 2015. Monitoring depth of anesthesia using combination of EEG measure and hemodynamic variables. Cognitive Neurodynamics, 9(1), pp.41–51.##Shalbaf, R., Behnam, H., Sleigh, J.W., Steyn-Ross, A. &amp; Voss, L.J., 2013. Monitoring the depth of anesthesia using entropy features and an artificial neural network. Journal of Neuroscience Methods, 218(1), pp.17–24.##Shalbaf, R., Mehrnam, A.H. &amp; Behnam, H., 2014. Depth of anesthesia indicator using combination of complexity and frequency measures. In: 2014 21th Iranian Conference on Biomedical Engineering (ICBME). IEEE, pp.156–160.##Shamsuzzoha, A., Kankaanpaa, T., Carneiro, L.M., Almeida, R., Chiodi, A. &amp; Fornasiero, R., 2013. Dynamic and collaborative business networks in the fashion industry. International Journal of Computer Integrated Manufacturing, 26(1–2), pp.125–139.##Shane, S. &amp; Venkataraman, S., 2000. The Promise of Enterpreneurship as a Field of Research. The Academy of Management Review, 25(1), p.217.##Skerrett, I., 2011. Best Practices in Multi-Vendor Open Source Communities. Open Source Business Resource, (January 2011), pp.11–15.##Smith, D., Alshaikh, A., Bojan, R., Kak, A. &amp; Kohe, J.M., 2014. Overcoming Barriers to Collaboration in an Open Source Ecosystem. Technology Innovation Management Review, 4(January), pp.18–27.##Strauss, A. &amp; Corbin, J., 1998. Basics of qualitative research: Procedures and techniques for developing grounded theory. ed: Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.##Tidd, J. &amp; Bessant, J., 2009. Managing innovation integrating technological, market and organizational change. John Wiley and Sons Ltd. John Wiley and Sons Ltd.##Tsai, K.H., 2009. Collaborative networks and product innovation performance: Toward a contingency perspective. Research Policy, 38(5), pp.765–778.##TURRINI, A., CRISTOFOLI, D., FROSINI, F. &amp; NASI, G., 2009. NETWORKING LITERATURE ABOUT DETERMINANTS OF NETWORK EFFECTIVENESS. Public Administration, 88(2), pp.528–550.##Vangen, S. &amp; Huxham, C., 2003. Nurturing Collaborative Relations. The Journal of Applied Behavioral Science, 39(1), pp.5–31.##Verschoore, J.R. &amp; Balestrin, A., 2011. Outcomes in Small-Firm Networks: A Quantitative Study in the Southern Brazilian Context.##Wang, H., Peverelli, P.J. &amp; Bossink, B.A.G., 2014. The development of asymmetric trust in cooperation between large firms and SMEs: Insights from china. Group Decision and Negotiation, 24(5), pp.925–947.##Yih‐Tong Sun, P. &amp; Scott, J.L., 2005. An investigation of barriers to knowledge transfer. Journal of Knowledge Management, 9(2), pp.75–90.##Yin, R.K., 2009. Case Study Research: Design and Methods. Applied Social Research Methods. SAGE Publications.##اسدی فرد, ر.، چوخانی زاده مقدم, ا. و گودرزی, م.، 1395. الگویی برای دسته‌بندی و مطالعه عوامل مؤثر بر موفقیت شبکه‌های همکاری بین‌المللی. مدیریت نوآوری، دوره 5، شماره 1، صص 150-129.##محمدی, م.، حمیدی, م.، محمودی, ب. و جوادی, س.، 1393. شناسایی، تحلیل و دسته‌بندی عوامل مؤثر بر شکل‌گیری شبکه‌های نوآوری در شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان (مطالعه موردی پارک علم و فناوری دانشگاه تهران). مدیریت نوآوری، دوره 3، شماره 4، صص 24-1.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>الگویی برای توسعه آینده بنیان مدیریت دانش؛ مورد پژوهی در شرکت ملی صنایع پتروشیمی</TitleF>
				<TitleE>A model for future-based knowledge management development; research study in the National Petrochemical Company</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>سرعت تغییرات، رقابت‌، مشتریان آگاه و نوآوری‌ها، چالش‌های آینده و عدم قطعیت‌های جدی پیش‌روی سازمان‌ها است که ضرورت کارآمد­سازی مدیریت دانش و سازگاری آن با شرایط آینده را اثبات می‌کند. چنانچه در مسیر تعالی مدیریت دانش در یک سازمان، فاقد نگاه آینده‌اندیش باشیم، اقدامات توسعه‌ای مدیریت دانش مضاف بر ناتوانی در حل مسئله، نفعی بر پایه نیازهای دانشی آینده نخواهد داشت. در این تحقیق پژوهشگران با موردپژوهش شرکت ملی صنایع پتروشیمی، به نحوه پیوند آینده‌پژوهی با سیر بلوغ مدیریت دانش پرداخته‌اند که نوآوری آن متکی بر ترکیب و کاربست روش‌های آینده‌پژوهی در مسیر کارآمد سازی نظام مدیریت دانش سازمانی است. در این مسیر، مصاحبه، پرسشنامه و مرور ادبیات برای گردآوری داده‌ها صورت گرفته و از منطق تحلیل چارچوب، پنل‌ و گروه‌ متمرکز حول چالش‌های آینده مدیریت دانش شرکت ملی صنایع پتروشیمی به‌عنوان ابزارهای تجزیه‌وتحلیل استفاده‌شده است. با شکستن روش‌های آینده‌پژوهی به بن‌مایه‌های کارکردی آن‌ها، درنهایت مدلی برای توسعه آینده بنیان مدیریت دانش سازمانی به‌عنوان خروجی پیشنهادشده است. اثر بلندمدت این مدل (متشکل از سه مرحله آسیب‌شناسی و نیازسنجی، تدوین راهبردهای دانشی و برنامه‌ریزی عملیاتی در توسعه مدیریت دانش)، ارزش‌آفرینی راهبردهای دانشی مطابق با وضعیت کلیدی آینده و همگرا شدن مقاصد مدیریت دانش با راهبردهای کلان و چشم‌انداز سازمان است. درنتیجه تکامل‌یافتگی و بلوغ مدیریت دانش همواره از منظر آینده استمرار می‌یابد.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The pace of change, competition, informed customers and innovations makes to future challenges and uncertainties. So the efficiency of knowledge management (KM) and its adaptability to the future condition is necessary. If we don’t have a perspective on the organizational KM performance,not only the KM development activities will not be able to solve current problems, but also cannot benefit based on future knowledge needs. In this research, researchers by study on the National Petrochemical Company (NPC) have focused on how to integrate KM maturity to futures studies (FS), whose innovation relies on the combination and application of FS methods in this direction. Interviews, questionnaire and library studies were used for data collection. Using the logic of framework analysis, panels and focus groups on the future challenges of NPC KM result to break functional FS methods. Finally, a model for developing future-based KM has been proposed which consists of three stages: pathology and needs assessment, making knowledge base strategies and operational planning. The effect of this model is the value creation of knowledge strategies in accordance with the key state of the future (activity environment) and the convergence of macro strategies and the vision of organization with the objectives of knowledge management, which results in the evolution of the maturity level of KM from the perspective of the future.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>113</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>142</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>احمد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>برومند کاخکی</Family>
						<NameE>Ahmad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Borumand Kakhki</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده چشم‌انداز و آینده‌پژوهی
دانشجوی دکتری آینده‌پژوهی، مرکز تحقیقات سیاست علمی کشور،تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده چشم‌انداز و آینده‌پژوهی
دانشجوی</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>aborumandk70@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>نیلوفر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>رادنژاد</Family>
						<NameE>Niloofar</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Radnezhad</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده چشم‌انداز و آینده‌پژوهی،
کارشناس ارشد مهندسی آینده‌پژوهی، دانشکده مدیریت، علم و فناوری دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر (پلی تکنیک تهران)</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>پژوهشگر پژوهشکده چشم‌انداز و آینده‌پژوهی،
کارشناس</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>n.rad2010@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>امیر ناصر</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>اخوان</Family>
						<NameE>Amir Naser</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Akhavan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی دانشکده مدیریت، علم و فناوری دانشگاه صنعتی امیرکبیر (پلی تکنیک تهران)، تهران، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی دانشکده مدیریت، علم و فناوری</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>akhavan@aut.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>محمدجواد</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>مستوفی</Family>
						<NameE>MohammadJavad</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>Mostofi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت فناوری، دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی، تهران ، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت فناوری، دانشکده مدیریت</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>mohamostofi@gmail.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>توسعه</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>آینده</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت دانش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>الگو</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پتروشیمی</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Ackerman, M. 1994. Definitional and contextual issues in organizational and group memories. Proceedings of the Twenty Seventh Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences, pp. 191-200.##Akhavan, P., Zahedi, M., &amp; Hoseini, S. 2014. A conceptual framework to address barriers to knowledge management in project-based organizations. Education, Business and Society: Contemporary Middle Eastern Issues, 7(2), pp. 98-119.##Anthony, R. 1965. Planning and Control Systems: A Framework for Analysis. Cambridge MA: Harvard University Press.##Asan, S. S., &amp; Umut, A. 2007. Qualitative Cross-impact analysis with time consideration. Technological Forecasting and Social Change, Volume (74), pp. 627-644.##C. Vorakulpipat، و Y. Rezgui.2006. From Knowledge Sharing to Value Creation: Three Generations of Knowledge Management. The IEEE International Engineering Management Conference. Salvador.##Davenport, T. H. 2006. Strategic Management in the Innovation Economy. John Wiely &amp; Sons.##Davenport, T. H., &amp; Prusak, L. 1997. Information ecology, Mastering the Information and Knowledge Environment. New York: Oxford University Press.##Edwards, J. 2011. A Process View of Knowledge Management: It Ain’t What you do, it’s the way That you do it. The Electronic Journal of Knowledge Management, 9(4), pp. 297-306.##Edwards, J. S. 2009. Business Processes and Knowledge Management (Vol. 1). Hershey, PA: IGI Global.##Ehms, K., &amp; Langen, M. 2010. Holistic Development of Knowledge Management with KMMM. Munich, Germany: Siemens AG, Corporate Technology Knowledge Management &amp; Business Transformation.##Fahey , L., &amp; Prusak, L. 1998. The Eleven Deadliest Sins of Knowledge Management . California Management Review, 40(3), pp. 265-276.##Hough , J. R., &amp; White, M. A. 2004. Scanning actions and environmental dynamism: gathering information for strategic decision making,. Management Decision, 42(6),pp. 781-793.##Ian Miles. 2002. Appraisal of Alternative Method and Procedures for Producing Regional Foresight. Brussels: Europian Commission.##IEA. 2014. Energy Technology Roadmaps, a guide to development and implementation. Paris: International Energy Agency.##Inayatullah, S. 2008. Six pillars: futures thinking for transforming. foresight, 10(1),pp. 4-21.##J. A. Vorosi . 2003. Genrix Foresight Prosess Framework. Forsight , 5(3).##Jafari, M., &amp; Akhavan, P. 2007. Essential Changes for Knowledge Management Establishment in a Country: a Macro Perspective. European Business Review Journal, 19(1), pp. 89-110.##Kaplan, R., &amp; Norton, D. 2008. Exwcution Premium. Boston: Harvard Business School Press.##Kemp, R., &amp; Martens, P. 2007. Sustainable development: how to manage something that is subjective and never can be achieved? Sustain Sci Pract Policy, Volume (3), pp. 5-14.##Khatibian, N., Hasan Gholoi Pour, T., &amp; Abedi Jafari, H. 2010. Measurement of knowledge management maturity level within organizations. Business Strategy Series, 11(1), pp. 54-70.##Lee, H., &amp; Choi, B. 2003. Knowledge Management Enablers, Processes and Organizational Performance. An Integrative View and Empirical Examination. Journal of Management Information Systems, 20(1), pp. 179-228.##Lin, C., Wua, J.-C., &amp; Yen, D. C. 2012. Exploring barriers to knowledge flow at different knowledge management maturity stages. Information &amp; Management, Volume (49), pp. 10-23.##Meihami, B., &amp; Meihami, H. 2014. Knowledge Management a way to gain a competitive advantage in firms (evidence of manufacturing companies). International Letters of Social and Humanistic Sciences, Volume (3), pp. 80-91.##Pöppelbuß, J., &amp; Röglinger, M. 2011. What makes a useful maturity model? A framework of general design principles for maturity models and its demonstration in business process management. ECIS 2011 Proceedings, Paper 28. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/ecis2011/28##Popper, R. 2008. How are foresight methods selected? foresight, 10(6), pp. 62-89.##Quist, J. 2007. Backcasting for a Sustainable Future: the Impact After Ten Years. Delft NL: Eburon.##Rezgui, Y., Hopfe, C. J., &amp; Vorakulpipat, C. 2010. Generations of knowledge management in the architecture, engineering and construction industry: An evolutionary perspective. Advanced Engineering Informatics, Volume (24), pp. 219-228.##Serna M., E. 2015. Maturity model of transdisciplinary knowledge management. International Journal of Information Management,Volume (35), pp. 647-654.##Teece, D. 1998. Capturing Value from Knowledge Assets: The New Economy, Markets, for Know-How, and Intangible Assets. California Management Review, 40(3), pp. 55-79.##Thomsen, E. B., &amp; Lumbye, T. 2012. How to facilitate knowledge collaboration – developing next practice. In Innovation Through Knowledge Transfer 2012 (pp. 103-114). Berlin: Springer Berlin Heidelberg.##Tong, C., Wah Tak, W., &amp; Wong, A. 2014. The Impact of Knowledge Sharing on the Relationship between Organizational Culture and Job Satisfaction: The Perception of Information Communication and Technology (ICT) Practitioners in Hong Kong. International Journal of Human Resource Studies, 5(1), pp. 19-47.##Tuomi, I. 2002. The Future of Knowledge Management. Lifelong Learning in Europe (LLinE), 7(2), pp. 69-79.##Van der Steen, M., &amp; et al. 2011. Integrating futures studies with organizational development: design options for the scenario project RWS2020. Futures, 43(3), pp. 337–347.##Vorakulpipat, C., &amp; Rezgui, Y. 2007. Value Creation: The next generation of Knowledge Management. IRMA International Conference.##Wickramasinghe, N., &amp; Lubitz, D. V. 2007. Knowledge-based Enterprise: Theories and Fundamentals. Idea Group Publishing.##Wiek, A., &amp; Iwaniec, D. 2013. Quality criteria for visions and visioning in sustainability science. Japan: Springer. doi:10.1007/s11625-013-0208-6##Wiig, K. M. 1997. Knowledge Management: Where Did It Come From and Where Will It Go? Expert Systems With Applications, 13(1).##Xue Zhang، Shaheen Majid، و Schubert Foo. 2010. Environmental scanning: An application of information literacy skills at the workplace. Journal of Information Science, 36(6),719-732.##لمپرت، ر. ج. 1385. برنامه‌ریزی پابرجا برای یک قرن. (و. وحیدی مطلق، مترجم) تهران: اندیشکده صنعت و فناوری.##افرازه، ع. 1387. مدیریت دانش (مفاهیم مدل‌ها، اندازه‌گیری و پیاده‌سازی). تهران: مؤلف.##امین مقدم، ع., و ستوده ریاضی، م. 1384. ارائه مدلی برای توسعه مدیریت دانش در سازمان‌های تحقیقاتی با رویکرد استفاده مؤثر از فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات. پنجمین همایش مراکز تحقیق و توسعه صنایع و معادن. تهران: انجمن تخصصی مراکز تحقیق و توسعه صنایع و معادن.##بازرگان، ع. 1382. روش اقدام پژوهی. تهران: انتشارات پژوهشکده تعلیم و تربیت وزارت آموزش‌وپرورش.##برومند کاخکی، ا., و اخوان، ا. 1397. چالش‌ها و الزامات توسعه مدیریت دانش در شرکت ملی صنایع پتروشیمی (افق ایران 1404). مدیریت منابع انسانی در صنعت نفت، 9(35)،صص 187-212.##بنیاد توسعه فردا. 1395. دستنامه آینده‌پژوهی. تهران: فرهنگستان علوم پزشکی جمهوری اسلامی ایران.##بهنام مولوی و همکاران. 1392. تدوین راهبرد مدیریت دانش در یک آزمایشگاه تحقیقاتی- صنعتی با بهره‌گیری از رویکرد پویا. مدیریت نوآوری،صص 123-146.##تحلیل لایه لایه‌ای علت‌ها؛ نظریه و موردکاوی‌های یک روش‌شناسی یکپارچه و متحول‌ساز. 1388. تهران: مرکز آینده‌پژوهی علوم و فناوری دفاعی.##جاودانی، ن و همکاران. 1388. مدل‌های ارزیابی سطح بلوغ مدیریت دانش. همایش مدیریت تکنولوژی و نوآوری دانشگاه پیام نور. گرمسار.##خاکی, غ. 1390. موردپژوهی؛ فرایندی برای نظریه‌پردازی بر اساس دانش پنهان منابع انسانی (مورد: صنعت آب و برق). دوفصلنامه پژوهش‌های مدیریت منابع انسانی دانشگاه جامع امام حسین (ع)، 3(1)،صص 27-52.##خاکی، غ. 1392. روش تحقیق مورد پژوهی. تهران: نشر فوژان.##خسروانی، ا. 1392. نسل جدید مدیریت دانش (KM2) مجله الکترونیکی مطالعات مدیریت دانش، 14،صص 5-10.##راسل، ب. 1381. علم و دین. (ر. مشایخی، مترجم) تهران: انتشارات کتاب‌فروشی دهخدا.##ربیعی، ع و پرهیزگار, م. 1390. استراتژی‌های مدیریت دانش. تهران.##زارع میرک آباد، ع. 1390. بررسی مبانی معرفت‌شناختی آینده‌پژوهی اسلامی و بررسی تأثیرات آن بر روش‌های آینده‌پژوهی. تهران: دانشگاه جامع امام حسین. بازیابی از پایگاه اینترنتی آینده‌پژوهی.##سهرابی، ب. رئیسی وانانی، ا و علیدوستی, س. 1389. ارائه مدلی کاربردی برای سنجش بلوغ مدیریت دانش در صنعت نرم‌افزار. سیاست علم و فناوری، 3(1)،صص 63-79.##سیف الهی و. 1381. راهنمای اقدام پژوهی در آموزش‌وپرورش. رشت: انتشارات گیلان.##شیخ‌زاده, م. 1385. مدیریت دانش: کاربردها و چالش‌ها. ماهنامه صنعت خودرو.##عبادی، غ. 1387. روش تحقیق اقدام پژوهی. مدارس کارآمد (3)،صص 71-73.##عرب زوزنی، م و همکاران. 1393. درک مفهوم آلفای کرونباخ: ضرورتی برای انجام مطالعات پژوهشی اصیل. مجله ایرانی آموزش در علوم پزشکی، 9(14)،صص 831-832.##عباس فام، ه. 1392. روش‌های پیش‌بینی در مدیریت و مطالعات آینده‌پژوهی. دومین همایش ملی آینده‌پژوهی. تهران.##عطاری، م. طاعتی، م. علمداری، ش و بهرامی, م. 1393. روش‌های آینده‌نگاری. تهران: نشر رویش.##علی احمدی، ع. برزین پور، ف و کرمی, م. 1387. مقایسه الگوهای بلوغ مدیریت دانش. تدبیر، 201،صص 21-27.##قدمی، م. 1393. مدیریت دانایی استراتژیک با تمرکز بر زندگی و فرهنگ اجتماعی و سازمانی. تهران: انتشارات تیسا.##کارگروه واژه‌گزینی تخصصی آینده‌پژوهی. 1389. واژه‌های آینده‌پژوهی (1). تهران: انتشارات فرهنگستان زبان و ادب فارسی.##نادری منش، م و همکاران. 1388. آینده‌نگاری فناوری اطلاعات در ایران 1404. تهران: مرکز تحقیقات سیاست علمی کشور.##ناظمی اشنی, ا و قدیری, ر. 1385. آینده‌نگاری از مفهوم تا اجرا. تهران: مرکز صنایع نوین.##نامداریان، ل و همکاران. 1393. ارزیابی تأثیر آینده‌نگاری بر سیاست‌گذاری علم، فناوری و نوآوری. مدیریت نوآوری، 3(2)،صص 73-102.##نبی پور، ا. 1390. آینده‌نگاری فناوری؛ ابزاری برای توسعه پایدار جامع. بوشهر: دانشگاه علوم پزشکی خدمات بهداشتی و درمانی بوشهر.##نظافتی، ن. 1392. رویکردی نوین برای مدیریت دانش سازمان‌های نسل 2.0. مجله الکترونیکی مطالعات مدیریت دانش، 14،صص 3-4.##نیک پیما، ن و همکاران. 1392. تحلیل چارچوب؛ شیوه‌ای برای تحلیل داده‌های کیفی. پایش, 13(1)،صص 41-50.##یار احمد زهی، م و سیدزاده, س. 1392. شناسایی عوامل کلیدی مؤثر بر آینده منابع انسانی در سازمان‌های دولتی. دومین همایش ملی آینده‌پژوهی. تهران.##یوسفی، س. مرادی، م و[1] تیشه ورز دائم، م. 1389. نقش تعهد سازمانی کارکنان در تسهیم دانش. دوماهنامه توسعه انسانی پلیس، 7(30)،صص 23-36.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE>
				<ARTICLE>
				<TitleF>شناسایی سیاستهای بهبود ظرفیت جذب دانش و تاثیر آنها بر عملکرد سازمانی با رویکرد پویایی شناسی سیستم</TitleF>
				<TitleE>Identifying the policies for improving the knowledge absorption  capacity and their effects on organizational performance : A System Dynamics Approach</TitleE>
				<TitleLang_ID>1</TitleLang_ID>
				<ABSTRACTS>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>1</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>هدف از این پژوهش شناسایی سیاستهای تاثیرگذار بر بهبود ظرفیت جذب دانش در سازمان و سنجش میزان تاثیر آنها بر عملکرد سازمان می باشد. به این منظور با استفاده از روش شناسی پویایی شناسی سیستمها ابتدا متغیرهای مربوطه شناسایی شده و سپس با ساخت مدل حالت-جریان امکان شبیه سازی سیستم برقرار می شود. پژوهش حاضر یک طرح کاربردی برای نظام تصمیم گیری سازمان فراهم می کند که سطح دانش کسب شده، دانش منتشر شده، دانش مورد استفاده و بخشی از دانشی که از سازمان خارج میشود را در گذر زمان اندازه گیری می کند. طبق نتایج مدل حاضر، بهترین سیاست برای افزایش سطح دانش مورد استفاده در سازمان ،ترکیب سه سیاست افزایش ساعات آموزش، آموزش و متخصص کردن مصاحبه کنندگان و افزایش درصد مصاحبه شوندگان بازنشسته است که میتواند سطح دانش مورد استفاده را در حالت بهینه نگه دار. این پژوهش با شبیه سازی سیستم مدیریت دانش سازمان یک سیستم پشتیبان تصمیم گیری در زمینه مدیریت دانش ارائه کرده است به گونه ای که با اعمال سیاستهای مختلف در این سیستم و مقایسه آثار آن بهترین سیاست اتخاذ می گردد. پژوهش حاضر منجر به تولید ابزاری برای نظام تصمیم گیری سازمان شده است که سطح دانش کسب شده، دانش منتشر شده، دانش مورد استفاده و دانشی که از سازمان خارج می شود را در گذر زمان اندازه گیری می کند</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
					<ABSTRACT>
						<Language_ID>2</Language_ID>
						<CONTENT>The purpose of this research is to investigate the policies which are most effective on the knowledge absorption capacity and then their effects on organizational performance. In this study we use Balanced Score Card(BSC) as our performance measurement structure. In order to be able to measure the effects of each policy and also their combinations, A system dynamics methodology is applied through which the main variables of the system and its boundaries are identifies. After testing all sections of the model and also the whole model through various validity tests, three separate policies including increased training hours, the competency of interviewers and increased proportion of retired employees been interviewed are performed by a simulation tool by which a stock &amp; Flow model is made during the modeling process. According to the results the best policy for improving absorptive knowledge capacity and hence the organizational performance is a combination of all above mentioned policies. This study leads to a kind of decision support system through which managers in different levels would be able to simulate their potentially effective policies to see if they are actually effective on organizational performance or not. This study is a novel research which combines system dynamics with BSC in the field of knowledge absorption capacity in the organization.</CONTENT>
					</ABSTRACT>
				</ABSTRACTS>
				<PAGES>
					<PAGE>
						<FPAGE>143</FPAGE>
						<TPAGE>168</TPAGE>
					</PAGE>
				</PAGES>
	
				<AUTHORS><AUTHOR>
						<Name>سعید</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>جهانیان</Family>
						<NameE>saeed</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>jahanyan</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>عضو هیئت علمی گروه مدیریت، دانشکده علوم اداری واقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان، اصفهان، ایران</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>عضو هیئت علمی گروه مدیریت، دانشکده علوم اداری</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>s.jahanyan@ase.ui.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>فائزه</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>امینی</Family>
						<NameE>faeze</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>amini</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مدیریت، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مدیریت، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>faeze.amini@yahoo.com</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR><AUTHOR>
						<Name>علی</Name>
						<MidName></MidName>		
						<Family>شائمی برزکی</Family>
						<NameE>ali</NameE>
						<MidNameE></MidNameE>		
						<FamilyE>shaemi</FamilyE>
						<Organizations>
							<Organization>گروه مدیریت، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد، دانشگاه اصفهان</Organization>
						</Organizations>
						<Universities>
							<University>گروه مدیریت، دانشکده علوم اداری و اقتصاد،</University>
						</Universities>
						<Countries>
							<Country>ایران</Country>
						</Countries>
						<EMAILS>
							<Email>ali.shaemi@ase.ui.ac.ir</Email>			
						</EMAILS>
					</AUTHOR></AUTHORS>
				<KEYWORDS>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>مدیریت دانش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>ظرفیت جذب دانش</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>کارت امتیازی متوازن</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD>
					<KEYWORD>
						<KeyText>پویایی شناسی سیستم</KeyText>
					</KEYWORD></KEYWORDS>
				<REFRENCES>
				<REFRENCE>
				<REF>Alavi, M. and Leidner, D.,1999. Knowledge management systems: Emerging views and practices from the##field. Proceedings of the 32nd Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences.##Barna, Z.,2002. Knowledge Management: A Critical E-Business Strategic Factor, San Diego State University:##Unpublished Masters Thesis.##Barnabè, F., 2012. A “system dynamics based Balanced Scorecard” to support strategic decision making.##International Journal of Productivity and Performance Management, Volume (605), pp. 446-473.##Bhirud, S.; Rodrigues, L. and Desai, P.,2005. A case study In Indian software subsidiary. Journal of Knowledge##Management Practice, Volume (22), pp. 83-90.##Borges.M., Foss.M.N &amp; Lyngsie.J.,2018. The “human side” of open innovation: The role of Employee diversity##in firm-level openness. Research Policy, Volume (47), pp. 218-231.##Cepeda-Carrión, G., Cegarra-Navarro, J. and Jimenez-Jimenez, D.,2012. The effect of absorptive capacity##on innovativeness: Context and information systems capability as catalysts. British Journal of Management,##Volume (231), pp. 110–129.##Chen, J., Chen, Y., &amp; Vanhaverbeke, W., 2011. The influence of scope, depth, and orientation of external##technology sources on the innovative performance of Chinese firms. Technovation, 3(18), pp. 362–373.##Cohen, W. and Levinthal, D.,1990, Absorptive capacity: A new perspective on learning and innovation.##Administrative Science Quarterly, Volume (351), pp. 128-152.##De Zubielqui, G. C., Jones, J., &amp; Lester, L., 2016. Knowledge inflows from market-and science-based actors,##absorptive capacity. Innovation and performance – A study of SMEs. International Journal of Innovation##Management, Volume (206), pp. 1–31.##D’Souza, D. and Kulkarni, S.,2015, A framework and model for absorptive capacity in a dynamic multi-firm##environment. International Journal of Production Economics, Volume (167), pp. 50–62.##Egbetokun, A. A., 2015. The more the merrier? Network portfolio size and innovation performance in Nigerian##firms. Technovation, Volume (43–44), pp. 17–28.##Enderson, R. and Clark, K.,1990. Architectural innovation: The reconfiguration of existing product technologies##and the failure of established firms. Administrative Science Quarterly, Volume (351), pp. 9-30.##Escribano, A.; Fosfuri, A. and Tribo, J.,2006. Managing external knowledge flows: The moderating role of##absorptive capacity. Research Policy,Volume (381), pp. 96-105.##Ferreira.J and Teixeira.A.,2018. Open Innovation and Knowledge for Fostering Business Ecosystems, Journal##of Innovation &amp; Knowlede, In Press: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jik.2018.10.002##Flatten, T.; Adams, D. and Brettel, M.,2015. Fostering absorptive capacity through leadership: A cross-cul166##tural analysis. Journal of World Business, Volume (503),pp. 519–534.##Flatten, T.; Engelen, A.; Zahra, S. and Brettel, M.,2011.A measure of absorptive capacity: scale development##and validation. European Management Journal. Volume (292), pp. 98–116.##Gebauer, H., Worch, H. andTruffer, B.,2012. Absorptive capacity, learning processes and combinative capabilities##as determinants of strategic innovation. European management Journal, Volume (301), pp. 57–73.##Gesing, J., Antons, D., Piening, E. P., Rese, M., &amp; Salge, T. O. , 2015. Joining forces or going it alone? On##the interplay among external collaboration partner types, inter firm governance modes, and internal R&amp;D.##Journal of Product Innovation Management, Volume (323), pp. 424–440.##Hackett, B., 2000. Beyond knowledge management: New ways to work and learn. New York: The Conference##Hagemeister, M.; Rodríguez-Castellanos, A., 2010. Organisational capacity to absorb external R&amp;D: Industrial##differences in assessing intellectual capital drivers. Knowledge Management Research &amp; Practice.##Volume (28), pp. 102-111.##Heiden, P.; Pohl, C.; Mansor, S. and Genderen, J.,2015. The role of education and training in absorptive##capacity of international technology transfer in the aerospace sector. Journal of Progress in Aerospace Sciences,##Volume (78), pp. 42–54.##Jahanyan. S and Moshabbaki.A.,2011. Factors influencing on knowledge sharing behavior in organizations.##International Journal of Internet and Enterprise Management, Volume (73), pp. 217-236.##Jahanyan. S, Azar.A and DanaeeFard.H.,2012. Utilizing multi aspectual understanding as a framework for##ERP success evaluation. Journal of Enterprise Information Management, Volume (255), pp. 479-504.##Jennex, M. and Olfman, L.,2000. Development recommendations for knowledge management/organizational##memory systems, Proceedings of the Information Systems Development Conference 2000, pp. 209-222.##Kaplan, R., &amp; Norton, D. ,1996. Linking the Balanced Scorecard to strategy. California Management Review,##39(1), pp. 53–79.##Krogh, G.; Ichijo, K. and Nonaka, I., 2000. Enabling knowledge creation: How to unlock the mystery of tacit##knowledge and release the power of innovation, Oxford University Press.##Levinson, N. and Asahi, M.,1995. Cross-national alliances and interorganizational learning. Organizational##Dynamics, Volume (242), pp. 50-63.##Love, J. H., Roper, S., &amp; Bryson, J. R. ,2011. Openness, knowledge, innovation and growth in UK business##services. Research Policy, Volume (4010), pp. 1438–1452.##Manteghi.M, Toloie. A and Moshiri.B., 2014. An Evaluation of the Success Factors of Open Innovation##Intermediaries: A Case Study of Nanotechnology Companies Network. Quarterly Journal of Innovation##Management, Volume (22), pp. 25-44.##Mariano , S. and Christian, W., 2015. The construct of absorptive capacity in knowledge management and##intellectual capital research: Content and text analyses. Journal of Knowledge Management, Volume (192),##pp. 372-400.##Maslach, D., 2016. Change and Persistence with Failed Technological Innovation. Strategic Management##Journal, Volume (37), pp. 714–723.##Mathew, A., &amp; Rodrigues, L., 2012. Human Factors &amp; Knowledge Management: A System Dynamics##Based Analysis, Available at: http://www. ResearchGate.com.##Minbaeva, D.; Pedersen, T.; Bjorkman, I.; Fey, C. and Park, H.,2003, MNC Knowledge Transfer, Subsidiary##Absorptive Capacity, and HRM. Journal of International Business Studies, Volume (451), pp. 38–51.##Murovec, M. and Prodan, I.,2009. Absorptive capacity and Its determinants, and influence on innovation##output: Cross-calcural validation of structural model. Technovation, Volume (2912), pp. 859–872.##Nitzsche, P., Wirtz, B. W., &amp; Goettel, V. ,2016. Innovation success in the context of inbound open innovation.##International Journal of Innovation Management, Volume (202).##O’Dell, C.; Hasanali, F.; Hubert, C.; Lopez, K.; Odem, P. and Raybourn, C.,2000. Successful KM implementation:##A study of best-practice organizations, Berlin: Springer-Verlag.##Praest Knudsen, M., &amp; Bøtker Mortensen, T., 2011. Some immediate but negative effects of openness on##product development performance. Technovation, Volume (311), pp. 54–64.##Rass, M., Dumbach, M., Danzinger, F., Bullinger, A. C., &amp; Moeslein, K. M., 2013.Open innovation and firm##performance: The mediating role of social capital. Creativity and Innovation Management, Volume (222),##pp. 177–194.##Ribière, V. and Tuggle, F. ,2005. The role of organizational trust in knowledge management tools and technology##use and success. International Journal of Knowledge Management, Volume (11), pp. 67-85.##Sage, A. and Rouse, W.,1999. Information systems frontiers in knowledge management. Information Systems##Frontiers, Volume (13), pp. 205–219.##Shi, T. and Gill, R.,2005. Developing effective policies for the sustainable development of ecological agriculture##in China: The case study of Jinshan County with a systems dynamics model. Ecological Economics,##Volume (532), pp. 223–642.##Spithoven, A., Frantzen, D., &amp; Clarysse, B., 2010. Heterogeneous firm-level effects of knowledge exchanges##on product innovation: Differences between dynamic and lagging product innovators. Journal of Product##Innovation Management, Volume (273), pp. 362–381.##Spithoven, A.; Clarysse, B. And Knockaert, M.,2011. Building absorptive capacity to organise inbound open##innovation in traditional industries. Technovation, Volume (31), pp. 10-21.##Sterman, J.,2000. Business dynamics: Systems thinking and modeling for a complex World, McGraw-Hill.##Suh, Y., &amp; Kim, M. S., 2012. Effects of SME collaboration on R&amp;D in the service sector in open innovation.##Innovation: Management. Policy and Practice, Volume (143), pp. 349–362.##Tou.Y.,Watanabe.G.,Moriya.K &amp; Neittaanmaki.P.,2019. Harnessing soft innovation resources leads to neo##open innovation. Technology in Society, In Press: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.techsoc.2019.01.007.##Tsinopoulos.C., Yan.J &amp; Sousa.G.M.,2018.Abandoning innovation activities and performance: The moderating##role of openness. Research Policy, Volume (48), pp. 1399 -1411.##Villar, C.; Alegre, J. and Pla-Barber, J.,2013. Exploring the role of knowledge management practices on##exports: A dynamic capabilities view. International Business Review, Volume (231), pp. 38–44.##Yu, S.; kim, Y. and Kim, M.,2004. Linking organizational knowledge management drivers to knowledge##management performance: An exploratory study. 37th Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences.##Zack, M.; McKeen, J. and Singh, S.,2009. Knowledge management and organizational performance: An##exploratory analysis. Journal of Knowledge Management, Volume (136), pp. 392-409.##Zahra, S., &amp; George, G., 2002. Absorptive capacity: A review, reconceptualization, and extension. Academy##of Management Review, Volume (272), pp. 185–203.##مرادی، محمود؛ عبداللهیان، فرزانه و صفردوست، عطیه. 1391 . بررسی نقش ظرفیت جذب دانش بر رابطه بین یادگیری از خطاهای سازمانی و نوآوری سازمانی. مطالعات مدیریت بهبود و تحول، ( 69 ) 22 ، صص. 121 - 149 .##حاجی کریمی، عباسعلی و حاجی پور، بهمن. 1387 ، طراحی مدل انداز هگیری ظرفیت جذب دانش: مطالعه موردی صنایع دارویی کشور، فصلنامه پژوهش و برنامه ریزی در آموزش عالی، ( 1) 14 ، صص. 51 - 71 .##آزاد، سید محسن و قدسی پور، سید حسن، 1396 ، مد لسازی و سیاس تگذاری نظام نوآوری فنی-بخشی در صنعت پتروشیمی با رویکرد پویای یشناسی سیست مها، فصلنامه مدیریت نوآوری، ( 4) 6، صص. 29 - 62 .##رحمانی فرد، گلمان. 1393 . شبی هسازی عملکرد زنجیره تامین با استفاده از تکنیک سیستم داینامیک مطالعه موردی شرکت کاله. پایان نامه کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه علوم و فنون مازندران.##موسوی حقیقی، محمد هاشم و تاجیک، مهدی، 1393 ، شبیه سازی فرآیند اشاعه محصولات نوین با رویکرد پویایی های سیستم، فصلنامه مدیریت نوآوری، ( 3) 3، صص. 77 - 99 .##آذر, ع., و خدپور, ا. 1389 . کاربرد رویکرد سیستم داینامیک در فرآیند ره نگاری و سیاست گذاری آموزش عالی. فصلنامه علمی-پژوهشی سیاست علم و فناوری, سال دوم، شماره-4.##</REF>
						</REFRENCE>
					</REFRENCES>
			</ARTICLE></ARTICLES>
</JOURNAL>

				</XML>
				