<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Looking at the concept and dimensions of science and technology diplomacy: 
A meta-synthesis approach]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Norouzi, Effat]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[mashayekh, javad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[mohseni, mostafa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2018]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Science and Technology Diplomacy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Conceptual Framework]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[interdisciplinary]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Meta-Synthesis]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Coding]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In spite of the widespread attention of politicians and scholars in the field of science and technology diplomacy in recent years, it seems there is no consensus on this interdisciplinary concept. Naturally, understanding a concept and its constituent parts is necessary for deal with it wisely. In this paper, it has been attempted to provide a conceptual framework for the configuration of the science and technology diplomacy, using the meta-synthesis approach and the systematic analysis of scientific literature in this field. For this purpose, identifying 120 related sources and conducting the necessary methodological steps, 58 sources were finally analyzed. Meta-synthesis on previous studies shows that the developed academic concepts about science and technology diplomacy can be classified under the four main pillars including the what (nature), the why (purpose), the how (implementation considerations), and the which (outcomes and effects). Additionally, more details of the identified dimensions were extracted as subcategories. For example, the implications of science and technology diplomacy consist of sub-categories of diplomacy and foreign policy, science and technology, economics, security, and soft power. These different dimensions of science and technology diplomacy will provide scholars with a platform for the development of academic literature based on proposed dimensions and will provide policy makers and decision makers with a reasonable logic to begin planning and evaluating actions taken.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86887_8eb7ef190e60f49413e147728948ee23.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Interaction between Organizational Silence and Innovation in Public Sector Organizations:A Study on Knowledge Workers of Humanities faculties in Tehran Province]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Noruzi, khalil]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sadeghikia, Mohammad Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2018]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Public Sector]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[organizational silence]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[knowledge workers]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Innovation deals with information and its success stops responding to the optimal and interactive flow of information and communication. Meanwhile, what disrupts the flow of knowledge and information is organizational silence. Organizational silence is a phenomenon in which employees deliberately refrain from comments, criticisms, suggestions and, in general, the sharing of hidden and hidden knowledge and information. This research seeks to identify as one of the most important barriers to innovation in public sector organizations the main aspects of the silence of knowledge workers in Tehran's School of Humanities. The present research is purpose-oriented, applied and methodically based on the methodology of foundation data. The statistical population of the research is the knowledge workers of the Faculties of Humanities of Tehran province and sampling has been done to saturation data. In this research, after identification of types of silence in the organization, the factors of silence, the consequences and strategies of reducing silence as the main dimensions of organizational silence of knowledge workers, a narrative on avoiding the breakdown of organizational silence and failing to move towards innovation in faculty Humanities.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86885_df5cd4e0d2913fdf04f84f6bd17f19eb.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Investigating the Impact of Human Resources Management Functions on Creativity, Product Innovation and Process Innovation (Case Study: Knowledge-Based Companies Based in Science and Technology Park of University of Tehran)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Taheriattar, Ghazaleh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[rostamlou, reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2018]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Human Resources Management Functions]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[employee creativity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[product innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[process innovation]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The creativity of staff has a significant impact on organizational innovation and survival. The good performance of the organization in the field of innovation can maintain the competitive advantage and growth of the organization. An organization looking for creativity and innovation should not overlook the importance and impact of human resource management function on organization innovation. In this research, we used a sample of 107 knowledge-based companies from Tehran University of Science and Technology Park to investigate the relationship between human resource management function with employee creativity, product innovation and process innovation. The present research is based on the purpose of applied research and is a survey-descriptive research data collection. Data collection was done through a questionnaire. reliability of the questionnaires was confirmed by calculating the Cronbach's alpha coefficient and composite reliability (CR) and validity of the questionnaires by calculating the convergent and divergent validity criteria, which is specific to the structural equation modeling. Also, for analyzing aggregated data, Structural Equation Method has been used with using Smart PLS software. The results of this study showed that HRM practices have a direct and positive effect on employees' creativity and employees' creativity have a direct and positive effect on product and process innovation. Also, the mediator role of Employees creativity in the impact of HRM practices on product innovation and process innovation was confirmed.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86890_bd57eb79c59aafc532a1a73d43a02840.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Identifying The Dimensions and Causes of Decline In Satisfaction Of Knowledge-Based Companies In Collaboration With The Fund's From The Perspective Of Executives And Policy Makers: A Case Study Of Innovation And Prosperity Fund]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Naghizadeh, Reza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hajari, mahdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[basavand, sajedeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2018]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[knowledge-based firms]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[fund's]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[National innovation and prosperity fund]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Decline in Satisfaction]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Since the concept of knowledge-based economy emerged, the knowledge-based firms, as a main driver of economic growth and development, has become more important. Therefore, identifying and solving their challenges is important too. One of the main challenges of knowledge-based firms is providing their essential funding which need different mechanisms because of their different nature from other enterprises. Understanding the importance of these firms funding, increase the importance of financing funds in technology such as the Innovation and Prosperity Fund. Thus the interaction knowledge-based firms with financial funding and increasing their satisfaction from getting services tailored to their needs has become one of the policy issues for financing funds in innovation area. In this regard, in this research, the affecting factors on reducing satisfaction of knowledge-based firms in cooperation with the Innovation and Prosperity Fund from the viewpoint of the executives and policymakers are identifiead and analyzed based on quantitative and qualitative combination methodology and focusing on the case study research strategy. In the first step, 18 factors that affect on reducing satisfaction of knowledge-based firms in cooperation with national financial funds were identified and classified in 6 categories. After that, based on case study research strategy, these factors are examined in the Innovation and Prosperity Fund and a framework, which shows the affecting factors on reducing satisfaction of knowledge-based firms in cooperation with the Innovation and Prosperity Fund from the viewpoint of the executives and policymakers , is presented.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86889_ecdda8d4491cd0cf830e6af75100f6b0.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Factors Affecting the Success of the Biotechnology Accelerators in Iran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Goudarzi, mehdi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Naghi zadeh, Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[biglar, ehsan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2018]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Accelerator]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Biotechnology]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Incubators]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Success Factor]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Startup]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Accelerators are a relatively new type of institutions which support entrepreneurial ecosystem across the world that rapidly grows and they offer the necessary services to startups in the early stages of their development. The emergence of this phenomenon has opened up a new path in front of the entrepreneurs and in a short period of time, the startups have developed very quickly. Identifying success factors of accelerators can minimize failure of the startups.  The determinants of success in the field of biotechnology accelerators, has shaped the main question of this research. After reviewing literature, interviewing with managers and experts in the field of biotechnology, twenty factors have been identified. After designing the questionnaire and distributing it among selected statistical sample, by using Binomial test, the important success factors have been identified. Some factors such as strategic intent of accelerator for development and teams’ support, teams’ investigaton criteria of ideas and capabilities, presented services to the teams, training programs, accessibility to market, customer and investor networks through and after the accelerating program.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86886_a7b338d8129ce6c5699ad8a659a21886.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Strategies for setting up a platform business within the banking and payment industry]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Kayyal, Kazem]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Albadvi, Amir]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[Iranian Association for Management of Technology]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2018]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Open Innovation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[platform]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Platform business]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[strategy]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In recent decades, the need for innovation on the one hand and the high cost of innovation, on the other hand, led businesses to use open innovation approaches more than before. One of the implementation models of this approach is to turn the business into a platform business which has attracted a lot of research in recent years. However, there is a need for research into the main strategies of the platform business in Iran with its own specific economic conditions. In addition, in any particular industry, given the specific characteristics of that industry, these strategies can vary. The purpose of this research is to provide practical strategies for setting up a platform business in Iran. In this research, after reviewing various articles in the field of platform business, the collected data from semi-structured interviews and archival sources were analyzed using the grounded theory method. In this Research, the banking and payment industry was selected as the case study according to the characteristics of this research. Banks can create a platform business using five main strategies: "providing service to a limited number of customers", "create a public platform", "join an existing platform", "participation in the creation and management of a platform" and "investment".]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/article_86989_71cb8640d39f3916db64ba1693b5d58a.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[http://www.nowavari.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Innovation Management Journal]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>