<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Analysis on Technological Innovation System Regarding Iranian Bio-Products 
(Focused on Human Vaccines)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Vahid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Marandi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D. Candidate / Department of Technology Management, Science  and Research Branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyyed Habibollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tabatabaeian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor / Department of Management, Faculty of Management and Accounting, Allameh Tabatabaei University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parivash</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jafari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor / Department of Educational administration, Science and Research branch, Islamic Azad University, Tehran, Iran,</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Morteza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azarnoosh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor / Pasteur institute of IRAN, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Regarding strategic importance of biotechnology in world’s economy, Iran has made investments in this field since twenty years ago which resulted in several achievements. This paper is going to analyze the domestic efforts in Biotech industry and the quality of innovation system evolution, focusing on vaccine production, based on seven innovation key functions introduced by Bergek, et al. (2007). The importance of Biotech industry, its market condition and a brief history of domestic human vaccine production is presented. After addressing the necessity for the country to enter in this high-tech industry, which was commenced with technology transfer project for production of HB vaccine, the functions of its innovation system will be investigated and the results will be discussed by historical data mapping method. Situation of domestic vaccine production innovation system with regard to the blocking and inducement mechanisms at functional level will be analyzed by Delphi method and policy making issues will be pointed out finally. Accordingly to inhibit 8 blocking mechanisms and stimulate 3 inducement mechanisms, 6 political issues were recommended.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>26</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_65122_60e2f8f99c35af3796804ad8738971b2.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Hybrid Framework for Evaluating New Service Development Performance in Healthcare Industry</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Jalil</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Heidari Dehvi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty Member, Faculty of Management, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Navid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Master of management of technology, Faculty of management, university of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Developing a framework to evaluate New Service Development performance, besides usefulness for evaluation of the success of NSD programs, can be helpful to identify strengths and weaknesses of improvement projects. Current paper aims to develop a framework to evaluate NSD performance by ISM and ANP. Extracted criteria finalized by experts and categorized in BSC framework. Because of internal communication among criteria, this model was evaluated by interpretive structural modelling (ISM) and modelled in 5 levels. Next, the analytic network process (ANP) approach was applied to weighting this criterion. Finally, New Service Development performance of Moheb-e Mehr Hospital as the case of current study was evaluated by this proposed model.The results indicate that the brand value and attraction of customers are the most important criteria for NSD performance. Moheb-e Mehr Hospital overall performance score was 54 points out of 100 points. So NSD performance of Moheb-e Mehr Hospital is moderate to high level. Finally, a framework proposed to help the aforementioned hospital in which could adjust the performance policies relative to the gained points along with developing actions in New Service Development performance domain.  </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>27</start>
					<end>52</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_61121_75db28ca2a15a0cdd06fce34473e411b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Role of Absorptive Capacity in Effectiveness of International Technology Transfer: Investigation of Part Suppliers in EF7 Project</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Majidpour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Research Associate, Faculty of Management, Science and Technology
Amirkabir University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Arman</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">khaledi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shohreh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nasri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Saber</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty of Management and Economics, Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Minaee</namePart>
				<affiliation>Faculty of Management and Economics, Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In era of knowledge and technology, the completive advantage of companies depends on their knowledge assets and their capabilities to absorb external technologies rather than their physical assets. The ultimate aim of current research is to investigate the influence of dimensions of absorptive capacity in success of international technology transfer process for the Iranian National Engine (EF7) project by elaborating the manufacturing companies which accompany the project. Therefore, four hypotheses are proposed and tested in five manufacturing companies namely, STYM, Laton, IMPC, Mashad Washer and Fara Sanat, those which engaged in the project. Also the model was analyzed through regression and variance methods by data gathered from the five aforementioned companies. The results show that the level of absorptive capacity of companies significantly affects the effectiveness of technology transfer in so called project; companies having higher level of absorptive capacity before starting the project were able to achieve a higher level of technological capabilities after ending the project.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>53</start>
					<end>80</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_65091_a1502639a1400a5f54842d8ac654a0fc.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Pathology of Technology Transfer Methods in the Food and Beverage Industry through applying CIPP Model</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Gholamreza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Haseli</namePart>
				<affiliation>Master Student of School of industrial engineering and management,Shahrood University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Saeed</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hakami Nasab</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Faculty of Industrial Engineering and Management, Shahrood University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Aliakbar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hasani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Faculty of Industrial Engineering and Management, Shahrood University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The food and beverage industry are important industrial entities which have essential role in the developing of economies mainly in developing countries.  A major problem existed in this industry can be attributed to the weaknesses of technology transfer to this industry. Therefore, in current research, authors aim at studying the pathology of technology transfer methods in Iran&#039;s food and beverage industry using CIPP model. To do so, fuzzy BWM and ELECTRE methods have been used to determine the relative importance of identified criteria and to rank the technology transfer methods in the food and beverage industry. Having evaluated the processes of implementing CIPP model and founding incompatibility in utilizing methods of technology transfer, industry experts proposed the solutions for removing obstacles. The research results indicate that food and beverage industries in Iran unlike some other industries do not have the ability to invest in technology transfer in the ways of internal development. Also, some of the most important solutions introduced by the experts in order to select the appropriate technology transfer methods are: effective communication management with intermediary companies, the use of expert managers in the field of technology management and considering effective native factors at the industry.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>81</start>
					<end>112</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_61122_401e1eadac54f5701ad04fa7bbf4551f.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Mitigating Agency Problems in Venture Capital Contracting in Different Stage of Iranian Entrepreneurial Firms Growth</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehrnaz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Heidari Soureshjani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Department of Industrial and System Engineering, Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parastoo</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Faculty of Industrial and Systems Engineering, Tarbiat Modares University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The purpose of current study is to find practical solutions in venture capital (VC) contracting according to entrepreneurial firm’s stage of growth. In venture capital (VC) contracting, Information asymmetry and conflict of interest causes lots of challenges between VC and entrepreneurs that will be investigate based on agency theory, then suggest diverse control and motivational mechanisms to mitigate agency problems. The factor affects on firm’s taking adequate strategies is its growth rate, because the firms needs and characteristics varies during stages so the problems change with the growth. Using grounded theory approach, authors tried to find different solutions which VCs usually use by semi-structured interviews and data gathering. Data analysis using open and axial coding shows the contracting approach varies due to changes of business developing factors, improving entrepreneur’s abilities and risks type in different stages of firm growth. Also business environment such as market, government’s intervention, legal shortcomings and cultural infrastructure affects the contracting approach as well.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>113</start>
					<end>140</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_65090_82de139e296a7334f09dcbc756ad62af.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Impediments to Adoption of Agricultural Technologies in Regions with Water Shortage from the Viewpoint of Farmers: The Case of Drip Irrigation in SALMAS</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Pooria</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Choobchian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Sharif University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kiamehr</namePart>
				<affiliation>Graduate School of Management and Economics, Sharif University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Maleki</namePart>
				<affiliation>Institute for Research in Science, Technology and Industry Policies, Sharif University of Technology</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Regarding water crises in the world it is necessary to change and reform agricultural methods in order to increase efficacy.  Although it seems that farmers in some regions do not accept new technologies due to some problems. To address these problems, drip irrigation technology was investigated in Salmas near to zone Lake Urumia. Despite the government supports, the adoption of drip irrigation technologies in the SALMAS region is even lower than its neighbouring regions with less shortage of water crises. Through a qualitative, exploratory research based on the literature of technology adoption, this paper tries to uncover the reasons behind this lower than expected level of adoption among farmers. The findings suggest that farmers in the southern parts of the region suffer from insecurities that are caused by ethnic diversity of the local communities. The farmers in the western part, however, prefer having a pretty field over consuming less water. The implications for theories and practice are outlined.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Innovation Management Journal</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>Iranian Association for Management of Technology</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2322-5386</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>6</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>141</start>
					<end>168</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">http://www.nowavari.ir/article_65123_cfb39457290e9b33f28d16fadd469066.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>