<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Comparative Study of Innovation Modes and HR Configurations in Knowledge-Based Firms in Science and Technology Parks</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی انطباقی سبک نوآوری و سبک مدیریت منابع انسانی در شرکت های دانش بنیان مستقر در پارک های علم و فناوری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>22</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14844</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>وجه الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>قربانی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>راحله</FirstName>
					<LastName>منتظر</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میرعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>سیدنقوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داوود</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسین پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت و حسابداری دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Human capital is one of the most important factors for innovation in companies. In this paper, we focus on two characteristics of human capital, i.e. uniqueness and value creation, to conduct a comparative study on the modes of innovation and human resource (HR) configurations in knowledge-based firms located in Pardis Technology Park and the University of Tehran Science and Technology Park. Managing human capital in innovative companies needs a set of HR practices suitable for work force characteristics and special aims of firm. In this study, we try to answer the question: Do knowledge-based firms choose their HR configuration according to their human capital characteristics and innovation mode? This study is a descriptive survey, with questionnaire as data collecting tool. We perform confirmatory factor analysis to assess the construct validity and model verification, and use binominal test to assess the level of coordination between the modes. In the first stage, the maximum level of coordination is identified between productivity-based HR system and market-oriented innovation, and in the next stage, the maximum coordination is between collaborative HR system and science-based innovation mode. Also, the average of value creation scores higher than uniqueness.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سرمایه انسانی یک شرکت از مهمترین عوامل نوآوری محسوب می‌شود. در این پژوهش با تمرکز بر‌ دو ویژگی منحصر‌به‌فردی و ارزش‌آفرینی سرمایه انسانی،‌ به بررسی انطباقی ‌سبک نوآوری با سبک کارکردهای منابع انسانی در شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان مستقر در دو پارک علم وفناوری پردیس و دانشگاه تهران پرداخته شد. مدیریت سرمایه‌های انسانی شرکت‌های نوآور، نیازمند بکارگیری مجموعه‌ای از کارکردهای مدیریت منابع انسانی متناسب با ویژگی‌های کارکنان و اهداف ویژه شرکت می‌باشد. پژوهش حاضر بدنبال پاسخ به این سوال است که آیا شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان بر مبنای نوع و ویژگی‌های سرمایه انسانی ‌و منطبق با سبک نوآوری خود، سبک کارکردهای منابع انسانی خود را انتخاب می‌نمایند؟ برای این منظور پس از مرور ادبیات، 46 شرکت مستقر در دو پارک فناوری پردیس و دانشگاه تهران، مورد بررسی قرار گرفتند. برای گردآوری داده‌ها از ابزار پرسش‌نامه استفاده شد. در ادامه، پس از تحلیل داده‌ها با روش تحلیل عاملی تاییدی و تایید مدل، میزان هماهنگی میان سبک‌ها با استفاده از آزمون دو جمله‌ای مورد بررسی قرار گرفت. بیشترین میزان انطباق، میان سبک نوآوری ‌بازارمحور و سبک مدیریت منابع انسانی بهره‌وری و پس از آن میان سبک نوآوری علم‌محور و سبک‌مدیریت منابع انسانی همکاری مشاهده شد. ویژگی ارزش‌آفرینی سرمایه انسانی در شرکت‌های دانش‌بنیان دارای میانگین بالاتری نسبت به ویژگی منحصربه‌فردی بود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منحصر به فردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش راهبردی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سبک نوآوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سبک مدیریت منابع انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هماهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل عاملی تاییدی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Formation Factors of Technological Spillovers Resulted from Foreign Direct Investment in Iran&#039;s Free Trade Zone</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی عوامل شکل گیری سرریزهای فناورانه حاصل از سرمایه گذاری مستقیم خارجی در مناطق آزاد ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>23</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>46</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14857</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهیار</FirstName>
					<LastName>خادم</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه آزاد واحد علوم و تحقیقات تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یگانه سادات</FirstName>
					<LastName>موسوی جهرمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه پیام نور واحد تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Technological spillover at micro-level has always been one of the main works of foreign direct investment. In this paper, we study spillovers and their determining factors in free trade zones. According to the conditions of Iran&#039;s free trade zones, technological spillovers in the form of vertical links are chosen as dependent variable and the factors determining technological spillovers, including research and development activities, the presence of qualified and skilled human resources, access to information and communication technologies, and centers for scientific and technical service are selected as independent variables. Due to the limited number of statistical samples, i.e. foreign investor companies in Iran&#039;s free trade zones, the method of partial least squares (PLS) is used to test the hypotheses. The results show that all these determinant factors have positive and significant impacts on promotion of vertical links in Iran&#039;s free trade zones.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سرریزهای فناورانه، همواره به عنوان یکی از مهمترین آثار سرمایه‌گذاری مستقیم خارجی در سطح اقتصاد خرد مطرح بوده است. در پژوهش حاضر تلاش شده است تا موضوع ایجاد سرریزها و عوامل تعیین‌کننده آن‌ها در مناطق آزاد مورد مطالعه قرار بگیرد. با توجه به شرایط مناطق آزاد ایران، سرریز فناورانه در قالب پیوندهای عمودی به عنوان متغیر وابسته پژوهش و عوامل موثر بر سرریز فناورانه شامل انجام فعالیت‏ های تحقیق‌وتوسعه، وجود نیروی انسانی متخصص و ماهر، دسترسی به فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات، و وجود مراکز ارائه خدمات علمی و فنی به عنوان متغیرهای مستقل انتخاب شدند. جامعه پژوهش را کارشناسان شاغل در شرکت‏های سرمایه‌گذار خارجی در مناطق آزاد ایران تشکیل دادند. ابزار جمع‌آوری داده‌ها، پرسش‌نامه بود و روش حداقل مجذورات جزیی برای آزمون فرضیه‌ها به‌کارگرفته شد. نتایج نشان دادند که تمامی عوامل یادشده بر ارتقاء پیوندهای عمودی در مناطق آزاد کشور تاثیر مثبت و معنا‏داری دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه گذاری مستقیم خارجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرریزهای فناورانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل موثر بر سرریز فناورانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مناطق آزاد ایران</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش PLS</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Designing a Capability-Based Model for Defense Need Assessment and Proposing a List of Defense Capability Components for Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>طراحی الگوی نیازسنجی قابلیت محور در حوزه دفاعی و پیشنهاد فهرستی از عناصر قابلیت برای کشور</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>47</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>74</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14901</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیامک</FirstName>
					<LastName>عزیززاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فشارکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیامک</FirstName>
					<LastName>طهماسبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سید محمد جواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>غضنفری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرتوک زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه صنعتی مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>15</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, need assessment is one of the most important inputs to defense acquisition systems in the world. Due to the dynamic, complex and uncertain nature of future environments, the classic approach of need assessment (threat-based) is not effective anymore, therefore, some countries have recently changed their approach from threat-based to capability-based. Using threat-based approach and lack of an integrated and comprehensive model for need assessment impose high costs on defense sector of our country. This study is aimed to present a comprehensive capability-based model for need assessment and extract likely capability components of the country. For this purpose, defensive information related to need assessment of the United States, Australia, Britain and Canada are collected, interpreted, compared and analyzed. Then, their need assessment models are investigated qualitatively by meta-synthesismethod, and finally a capability-based need assessment model is presented for defense field. Also, a list of capability components of the country is proposed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;امروزه، نیازسنجی به عنوان یکی از ورودی&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های اصلی نظام اکتساب دفاعی در جهان مطرح است که کشورها آن را مبنای برنامه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ریزی&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها، در پیش گرفتن یک رویکرد و تصمیم&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;گیری&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های خود جهت ارائه راه حل برای مقابله با دشمن قرار می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;دهند. با توجه به پویایی، پیچیدگی و عدم قطعیت محیط&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های آینده، دیگر رویکرد سنتی به نیازسنجی (تهدیدمحوری)، چندان موثر نیست. عدم استفاده از یک الگوی یکپارچه و جامع نیازسنجی و مبتنی بودن رویکرد فعلی بر تهدیدمحوری، موجب شده است تا اثربخشی فعالیت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های دفاعی کشور به قیمت هزینه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های هنگفت میسر باشد. این پژوهش با هدف طراحی یک الگوی جامع نیازسنجی مبتنی بر قابلیت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;محوری و استخراج عناصر احتمالی قابلیت کشور انجام شده است. برای این منظور، ابتدا با روش مطالعه تطبیقی نظام&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های نیازسنجی دفاعی کشورهای آمریکا، استرالیا، انگلستان و کانادا مورد بررسی و مقایسه قرار گرفت، سپس با استفاده از روش «فراترکیب» ضمن بررسی کیفی الگوهای استخراج شده، از نقاط قوت آنها استفاده شد و یک الگوی نیازسنجی قابلیت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;محور برای کشور طراحی گردید. در ادامه الگوی طراحی شده با استفاده از روش گروه کانونی مورد اصلاح و اعتبارسنجی قرار گرفت. همچنین عناصر قابلیت کشورهای مختلف استخراج گردید و با استفاده از الگوی هفت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;اس مکینزی و نظریه قابلیت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های پویا، تحلیل شد. نتایج نشان داد که این عناصر به لحاظ ماهیت، از جنس قابلیت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های پویا هستند و بر 5 حوزه «سیستم»، «راهبرد»، «کارکنان»، «مهارت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها» و «سبک مدیریت و رهبری» تمرکز دارند. در پایان فهرستی از عناصر قابلیت برای کشور پیشنهاد گردید.&lt;/strong&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام اکتساب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام نیازسنجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویکرد قابلیت محور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رویکرد تهدیدمحور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روش فراترکیب</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying Factors Affecting the Successful Transfer of Nanotechnology</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزیابی و اولویت بندی مولفه های موثر بر انتقال موفق نانوفناوری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>75</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>96</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14903</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>اکبری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>مهرابی فیروزآباد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>مبین دهکردی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>For successful technology transfer, identifying Industry needs, required technologies, technological resources, transfer methods and its factors are necessary. The purpose of this study is to evaluate and prioritize factors affecting the successful transfer of nanotechnology as an issue concerning the development of Iran. We use an exploratory mixed method in this study and the statistical samples of the qualitative phase are academic and industrial experts of nanotechnology, selected with purposeful sampling until theoretical saturation point is reached. The samples of quantitative PHASE are 83 experts selected by simple random sampling. A semi-structured interview is conducted in the qualitative phase and a questionnaire in the quantitative phase. The collected data are analyzed by SPSS 18 software. According to the results, effective components include knowledge, organizational, technological, communicational, training human resources, and understanding physical environment. These factors have different significances in the receiver and provider organizations. Technological, organizational, knowledge, communicational, training human resources and understanding physical environment components have the highest priorities in the receiver organization, and technological, organizational, communicational, knowledge, understanding physical environment and training human resources have the highest in the provider organization.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;انتقال موفق فناوری، نیازمند شناسایی اهداف صنعت موردنظر، فناوری&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های مورد&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;نیاز، منابع فناورانه، روش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های انتقال و عوامل موثر در آن، نحوه جذب و توسعه آن دارد و انجام هر یک از اینها نیازمند به&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;کارگیری متخصصان مربوط است. بدون استفاده از کارشناسان متخصص در این زمینه، معمولاً انتقال فناوری موردنظر، ناقص و نامناسب و با فاصله از هدف اولیه صورت می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;گیرد. پژوهش حاضر با هدف ارزیابی و اولویت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;بندی مولفه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های موثر بر انتقال موفق نانوفناوری انجام شد. نمونة آماری در بخش کیفی ،خبرگان دانشگاهی و صنعتی نانوفناوری بودند، روش پژوهش از نوع آمیخته اکتشافی بود و به روش پیمایشی انجام شد. نمونة آماری در بخش کمّی، فعالان حوزه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; نانوفناوری در شهر تهران بودند که با روش نمونه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;گیری تصادفی ساده 83 تن از آن&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها انتخاب شدند. ابزار بخش کیفی، مصاحبه عمیق نیمه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ساختارمند و ابزار بخش کمی، پرسش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;نامه بود. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها از نرم&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;افزار &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPSS18&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; استفاده شد. نتایج نشان داد که عوامل دانشی، سازمانی، فناورانه، ارتباطی، آموزش نیروی انسانی و شناخت محیط فیزیکی، مهم&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ترین مولفه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های موثر بر انتقال موفق نانوفناوری هستند. این عوامل در سازمان گیرنده و دهنده فناوری، اهمیت متفاوتی دارند. عوامل فناورانه، سازمانی، دانشی، ارتباطی، آموزش نیروی انسانی و شناخت محیط فیزیکی اولویت&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های اول را در سازمان گیرنده به خود اختصاص دادند و عوامل فناورانه، سازمانی، ارتباطی، دانشی، شناخت محیط فیزیکی و آموزش نیروی انسانی در سازمان دهنده دارای بیشترین اولولیت بودند.&lt;/strong&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرآیند انتقال فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نانوفناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انتقال موفق فناوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل مقایسه ای مداوم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کدگذاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the Role of Talent Management in Organization&#039;s Intellectual Capital Development: A Case Study of Iran&#039;s PANHA</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی نقش مدیریت استعداد در توسعه سرمایه فکری سازمان (مورد مطالعه: سازمان پشتیبانی و نوسازی بالگردهای ایران- پنها)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>97</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>118</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14904</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>داود</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسین پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منوچهر</FirstName>
					<LastName>منطقی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه مالک اشتر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سحر</FirstName>
					<LastName>ملک محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study is to investigate the role of talent management in Iranian Helicopter Support and Renewal Company (PANHA) intellectual capital development. This study is based on a main hypothesis and three sub-hypothesis which measure the effects of talent management on three intellectual capital factors, including human capital, relational structural capital and organizational structural capital. A sample consisted of 158 individuals (118 talented staff, and 40 deputies and experts of the organization) is selected and analyzed by inferential statistics using descriptive-surveyed research approach. The data is collected using questionnaires. For data analysis, first, we assess the base validity of all indicators using confirmatory factor analysis, and then the research hypotheses are examined by fitted model and structural equations model. The research findings indicate that talent management has positive and meaningful effect on intellectual capital of PANHA. Among the three components of intellectual capital, talent management has also positive and meaningful effect on the two components of human capital and relational structural capital, but has no impact on organizational structural capital.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;هدف از این پژوهش بررسی نقش مدیریت استعداد در توسعه سرمایه فکری سازمان پنها می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;باشد. این پژوهش بر مبنای یک فرضیه اصلی و سه فرضیه فرعی بنا شده است که تاثیر مدیریت استعداد را بر سه مولفه سرمایه فکری شامل سرمایه انسانی، سرمایه ساختاری رابطه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای و سرمایه ساختاری سازمانی می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;سنجد. با استفاده از روش توصیفی- پیمایشی نمونه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای متشکل از 158 نفر (118 نفر از کارکنان بااستعداد و 40 نفر از معاونان و کارشناسان سازمان) انتخاب شد و با استفاده از آمار استنباطی مورد تجزیه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;وتحلیل قرار گرفت. ابزار جمع&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;آوری داده&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها، پرسش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;نامه بود. برای تحلیل داده&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها، ابتدا با استفاده از تحلیل عاملی تأییدی، روایی سازه تمام شاخص&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های مورد مطالعه محاسبه شد و سپس با استفاده از مدل برازش شده و مدل معادلات ساختاری، فرضیه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های پژوهش مورد آزمون قرار گرفت. یافته&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های پژوهش، نشان می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;دهد که مدیریت استعداد بر سرمایه فکری سازمان پنها تاثیر مثبت و معناداری دارد و از میان سه مولفه سرمایه فکری بر دو مولفه سرمایه انسانی و سرمایه ساختاری رابطه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای نیز تاثیر مثبت و معنادار دارد اما تاثیری بر سرمایه ساختاری سازمانی ندارد. &lt;/strong&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت استعداد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه فکری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه ساختاری رابطهای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه ساختاری سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سازمان پشتیبانی و نوسازی بالگردهای ایران</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName></PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>مدیریت نوآوری</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2322-5386</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Presenting a Model for Analyzing the Risks of Strategic and Technological Alliances</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائه مدلی برای تحلیل ریسک اتحادهای راهبردی و فناورانه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>119</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>140</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">14905</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نیما</FirstName>
					<LastName>مختارزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشکده مدیریت دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شاپور</FirstName>
					<LastName>کرامت</LastName>
<Affiliation>مدیریت فناوری پردیس البرز دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Technological alliance is an intelligence solution to obtaining the strategic goals of firms. While the trend of this type of collaboration is increasing, the failure rate is still high. The high rate of risk is due to the nature of internal cooperation of organizations in technological alliance. Most analytical methods and models consider the sources of risk in alliance process in two types: relational and functional risks. In this paper, the resources of risk are identified in the phases of strategic alliance process based on the literature. Then the level of importance of differenr phases of alliance and their influence on the success of alliance is weighted in a checklist by expert panel through Delphi technique. The method used in this study is design science with method output and design precision strategy using two Delphi panel rounds. The results show that risk factors in each phases of alliance are not the same and also the same risk factors in different phases of alliance process do not have the same weights. The aim of this paper is to present a flexible, dynamic and reliable method for alliance risk assessment, including identification, analysis and evaluation of risk resources. Proposing a structured method that can predict and estimate the level of risk for each phase of alliance based on the opinions of the employees and stakeholders of two sides of alliance is a significant result of this study.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">&lt;strong&gt;اتحادهای فناورانه، راه حل هوشمندانه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای برای دستیابی به اهداف راهبردی یک بنگاه در دنیای در حال تغییر کنونی است. با وجود روند رو به افزایش این نوع همکاری&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها، نرخ شکست در آن&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها همچنان بالاست. ماهیت همکاری درون&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;سازمانی در اتحادها، دلیل بالا بودن ریسک در آن&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;باشد. بیشتر روش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها و مدل&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;های تحلیلی، منابع ریسک در طول فرآیند اتحاد را بصورت ایستا و در دو نوع نسبی و کارکردی در نظر می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;گیرند. در پژوهش حاضر، با انجام مطالعات کتابخانه&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ای، منابع ریسک در مراحل فرآیند اتحاد راهبردی شناسایی شدند. به دلیل متفاوت بودن ضریب اهمیت هر یک از عوامل ریسک در اتحادهای مختلف، میزان اهمیت و همچنین درجه تاثیر مرحله اتحاد در موفقیت اتحاد، توسط خبرگان وزن&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;دهی شدند. بر اساس نتایج، عوامل ریسک در هر مرحله از فرآیند اتحاد، یکسان نیست و حتی عوامل ریسک مشابه در مراحل فرآیند اتحاد نیز دارای وزن یکسان نیستند. هدف از انجام این پژوهش، ارائه روشی پویا، انعطاف&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;پذیر و دقیق جهت ارزیابی ریسک اتحاد شامل شناسایی، سنجش و تحلیل منابع ریسک در طول یک اتحاد می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;باشد. نوع پژوهش، توصیفی است و اجرای آن در دو مرحله، شامل جمع&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;آوری داده&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ها و نیز استفاده از نظر خبرگان جهت روایی پژوهش انجام شده است. دستیابی به روشی ساختاریافته که با نظرات کارکنان و ذی&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;نفعان دو طرف اتحاد، قادر به پیش&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;گویی و تخمین میزان ریسک آن به تفکیک هریک از مراحل اتحاد می&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‌&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;باشد، مهمترین دستاورد پژوهش حاضر است.&lt;/strong&gt;</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ریسک اتحادها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">راهبردهای فناورانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شکست اتحادها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوی تحلیل ریسک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
