<add><doc><field name="journal_id">10014</field><field name="abstract">Rumor is one of the factors which has always been hidden from the eyes and attention of the organization and its managers and its importance in crisis because of mental and emotional communication in the organization is ignored. Gossip and disperse it among the indicators that can measure the degree of healthy relationships within the organization. The goal of present study was to investigate the effects of organizational rumor on the performance of SOUT pars gas complex employees using a descriptive survey method. The statistical universe of this study was consisted of all ۵ refinery-administrative staff, operation management. The number of participants in total was ۲۳۰۰ persons. A classified random sampling method and a sample size proportional to statistical population have been selected. Then using Cochran formula from ۲۳۰۰ persons, ۳۳۰ persons were chosen. In order to collect data from the participants, a questionnaire were distributed among them. After collecting some advices from supervisors and faculty advisors and also opinions of some professors at University and then applying their views on the questionnaire, at first stage important questions about the impact of organizational rumors on job performance were identified including spirit of distrust, the pressure on the employees from the administration, worry and anxiety, decreased productivity, lack of job security for personnel of SPGC. After providing the questionnaire at the second stage, the responses collected based on the sample space. Then the data were collected from the responses. This data were analyzed using several tests including correlation, Friedman test, T test with two independent groups, variance analysis and also using ۱۶ SPSS software. Some important results are as follows: There is a direct relationship between gossip and decreased job performance and the coefficient of determination obtained indicates that ۳۰ percent of the variation can be explained by a drop in job performance by the rumors. Significant differences were seen in the opinions of the staff on the effect of organizational rumors on employees' performance according to work experience and work place. work experience and workplace provide significant difference on the above scores. However, the difference between scores measured based on age. edgucation level and marital status are not significant</field></doc></add>