<add><doc><field name="journal_id">10042</field><field name="abstract">To recognize the strengths and weaknesses and level of organization’s achievement to better quality and better performance, Use of organizational excellence models for assessment the organization’s Performance is effective. The purpose of this research is assessment of Tehran municipality’s human resources management based on the EFQM model. 

This research is a Survey with descriptive and Cross-sectional method that assess the organizational excellence of Tehran municipality from the perspective of human resources managers of it in ۱۹۹۳. The Statistic society of the research was included ۳۰ persons of human resources managers that selected by census method. The Standard questionnaire of EFQM model that has ۵۰ questions was distributed to collecting data. The questions have been customized according to the requirements of Tehran municipality. The validity was measured by the use of experts opinions, and its reliability was measured by Cronbach's alpha that was confirmed ۰٫۸۸. Data was described and analyzed using descriptive statistics, t-test and ANOVA test group. In this assessment, HR managers of Tehran municipality devoted to the evaluation of ۸۵/۶۰۹ points, Enablers areas ۳۴/۲۹۶ points and field results were ۵۱/۳۱۱ points. Each of the nine percentage points, respectively according to the questionnaire approach are as follows: Leadership ۴۰/۶۳ percent, policy making ۶۳/۶۷٪, and ۷۰/۶۲٪ of staff resources, ۹۰/۴۰ percent, ۷۱/۶۱ percent processes, customer results ۹۰/۵۹ percent, ۰۸/۶۰ percent of the staff, ۸۳/۶۶٪ of the population and ۵/۶۴ of the business. The results indicate that the evaluation model described is an appropriate tool to identify strengths and improve the performance of Tehran Municipality. Obviously the better implementation of programs and the pursuit of excellence, is made possible by continued cooperation. Also the results showed that between Work experience in the field of human resource managers and their evaluation criteria in the municipality of Tehran and between different regions and municipalities education and human resource management assessment of the quality criteria in Tehran municipality, there was no significant difference.</field></doc></add>