<add><doc><field name="journal_id">10042</field><field name="abstract">Today, competitiveness has become one of the most applied concepts in regional and urban studies. The reason, why much attention has been devoted to this concept is the changes in the world economy, demographical changes of countries, changes in social structures and activities. This research aimed to conduct a spatial analysis of competitiveness of Iran provinces based on educational factors. In terms of scope, this research is an applied study and in terms of nature and research method is descriptive analytic one. ۷۵ factor from education section of national population and housing consensus of ۱۳۹۰ (۲۰۱۱) have selected and analyzed. For analyzing Coefficient of Variant (C. V) , VIKOR and geographically weighted regression in the Arc GIS were used. The research findings indicate inappropriate distribution in the educational factors between provinces of Iran. Totally, ۴۶٪ of educational factors distributed in unsuitable way, and Sistan and Baluchestan, Kurdistan and Ilam provinces are in most inequality but in turn, West Azerbaijan, Isfahan and East Azerbaijan are in the good situation. Final results shows that, in terms of educational competitiveness, Tehran province is in the first level, Razavi Khorasan, Khuzestan, Fars, Isfahan, East Azerbaijan, Kerman, Mazanderan provinces are placed in the second level, and in the third level Gilan, Sistan and Baluchestan, West Azerbaijan, Lorestan, Hormozgan, Golestan, Kermanshah, Hamadan, Markazi, Kurdistan, Alborz, Qazvin, Ardebil, Kohgiluyeh and Boyer-Ahmad, Boushehr, Yazd, Chaharmahal and Bakhtiari, Zanjan, Semnan, South Khorasan, Qom, Ilam and North Khorasan provinces are located. Overall conclusions indicate that development situations of Iran provinces in terms of educational factors are not in good consistent with concepts of social and spatial justice and required bottom-up approach and decentralized planning. Moreover, economic growth depends on establishment of performance-oriented education system. </field></doc></add>