<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Image of Unveiling and Forced Unveiling, the Status of the Picture of Unveiling in the Second Pahlavi Era</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>عصر تصویر بی حجابی و بی حجابی اجباری بررسی وضعیت تصویر بی حجابی در دورۀ پهلوی دوم</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>339</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>358</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68852</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2018.262289.1007458</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>قائمی نیک</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری جامعه‌شناسی نظری‌ـ فرهنگی از دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طیبه</FirstName>
					<LastName>نجفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگر مرکز مطالعات زنان دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>There are two different viewpoints on the approach of the Iranian society to the phenomena of veiling, especially female veiling. The first is the resistance of Muslim Iranians to the forced unveiling (kashf-e hejab) in Reza Pahlavi`s monarchy and the second, according to some opinions, is reaction Iranian people to the forced veiling or law of veiling in the Islamic Republic era. In the first era, under the influence of Reza Pahlavi’s Western Modernization, unveiling is considered to be imposed, and in the second era, veiling. However, between the two periods, there is a 37 years period of Mohammad Reza Pahlavi. Despite of continuity of the forced unveiling policies, this era has been less analyzed. Unlike Reza Pahlavi`s period, forced unveiling not only was not directly in the real social scene, but also, it was disseminated through media and to influence the unconscious mind of social actors. Furthermore, since the 1960s, these policies have been linked to the plan for development of capitalism. In the present study, &quot;the image of unveiling&quot; has been used to express the pictorial feature of unveiling. In the West, the unveiling picture of men or women`s organs was expanded under the development of music and cinema industry, after World War II. Before that time, revealing of the images of feminine or masculine bodies was limited, or at least, wasn’t the symbol of modernity, progress and personality. In the present research, the Critical Theory of Frankfort School and methodological of Culture Industry which was formulated in the second half of the twentieth century, has been employed to investigate the status of the picture of unveiling and the influence of the policies of the second Pahlavi on that. It can be concluded that, the attention to the pictorial feature of unveiling that began from the second Pahlavi`s era can explain superficial contradiction of the two opinions on Iranian reaction to veiling. With the continuation of media images during the Islamic Republic era, it seems necessary to make further researches on the contrast of veiling picture-unveiling picture.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">دربارۀ مواجهۀ جامعۀ ایران با پدیدۀ حجاب (به‌خصوص حجاب زنانه)، دو دیدگاه به‌ظاهر متفاوت وجود دارد؛ اول مقاومت مردم در برابر بی‏حجابی اجباری (کشف حجاب) در دورۀ رضاخان پهلوی و دوم مطابق با برخی از دیدگاه‌ها، واکنش به حجاب اجباری یا قانون حجاب در دورۀ جمهوری اسلامی. در دورۀ اول، در ذیل سیاست‏های «تجدد آمرانۀ» غربی، بی‏حجابی و در دورۀ دوم حجاب امری تحمیلی محسوب می‏شود. بین این دو دوره، حکومت 37 سالۀ پهلوی دوم قرار دارد که به‏رغم استمرار سیاست‏های تحمیل بی‏حجابی، کمتر مورد تحلیل قرار گرفته است. تحمیل بی‏حجابی در این دوره، برخلاف دورۀ پهلوی اول، مستقیماً در صحنۀ واقعی اجتماعی نبود، بلکه از طریق گسترش تصاویر رسانه‏ای و تبلیغاتی و تأثیر بر ناخودآگاه ذهن کنشگران اجتماعی صورت گرفت. به‏علاوه، این سیاست‏ها از دهۀ 1340 با طرح توسعۀ سرمایه‏داری پیوند ‏خورد. در این مقاله، برای بیان ویژگی تصویری بی‏حجابی، از تعبیر «تصویر بی‏حجابی» استفاده شده است. این تصویر از اندام زنانه یا مردانه عمدتاً تحت تأثیر صنایع سینما و موسیقی پس از جنگ جهانی دوم گسترش یافت. پیش از آن، آشکار‌شدنِ تصاویر بی‏حجاب از اندام زنانه یا مردانه چندان رایج نبود  یا حداقل نشانۀ تجدد، ترقی و شخصیت تلقی نمی‏شد. در مقالۀ حاضر، با استفاده از نظریۀ انتقادی مکتب فرانکفورت و چارچوب روشی صنعت فرهنگ، که در نیمۀ دوم قرن بیستم صورت‏بندی شد، به بررسی وضعیت تصویر بی‏حجابی و تأثیر سیاست‏های پهلوی دوم بر آن خواهیم پرداخت. در نتیجه‏گیری، اولاً اشاره خواهیم کرد که توجه به ویژگی تصویری تحمیل بی‏حجابی، که از دورۀ پهلوی دوم شروع شد، می‏تواند دو دیدگاه به‌ظاهر متضاد دربارۀ واکنش جامعۀ ایران به حجاب را توضیح دهد. ثانیاً، با توجه به استمرار تصاویر رسانه‏ا‏ی در دورۀ جمهوری اسلامی، پژوهش دربارۀ منازعۀ تصویر باحجاب‌ـ تصویر بی‏حجاب ضرورت دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بی‏حجابی اجباری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پهلوی دوم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصویر بی‏حجابی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حجاب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صنعت فرهنگ</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study of Cultural Conceptualization of Marriage and Childbearing among Women in Tehran: with a Cognitive Sociolinguistics Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی مفهوم‌سازی فرهنگی ازدواج و فرزندآوری در میان زنان شهر تهران: با رویکرد جامعه شناسی زبانی-شناختی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>359</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>377</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68853</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2018.247109.1007322</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیلیا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نرسسیانس</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مردم‏ شناسی، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>فیاض</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مردم‏ شناسی، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>اردبیلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مردم ‏شناسی، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Recent studies in the field of cognitive science on conceptual metaphor indicated that metaphor is not merely a linguistic phenomenon but it is essentially a conceptual-experimental process that constructs our mental world and is a means that reflects the origin of the cognitive structures of human thought. By examining the metaphorical conceptualization of marriage and childbearing widely used in Persian everyday language, the present study seeks to demonstrate how the study of conceptual metaphors, within the framework of sociolinguistics, can help us get a better understanding of collective representations and cultural cognition. To achieve this goal, the present study is to utilize ethnographic strategy and semi-structured interview from twenty married women between the ages of 50-70 in Tehran, has gained some common metaphors in the conceptualization of marriage and childbearing. Subsequently, based on the premises of Conceptual Metaphor Theory, these metaphors are analyzed qualitatively. The results show that such conceptual mappings bear theoretical significance for the study of metaphor in identifying collective representation and cultural cognition and help us to get a deeper understanding of cultural understanding of the concepts in a community.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تحقیقات اخیر در حوزة علوم‏شناختی دربارة استعارۀ مفهومی نشان داده‏اند که استعاره صرفاً یک پدیدة زبانی نیست، بلکه اساساً فرایندی مفهومی‏ـ تجربی است که جهان ذهنی ما را ساخت‌مند می‏کند و ابزاری است که منعکس‏کنندة منشأ ساختارهای شناختی تفکر انسان است. پژوهش حاضر بر آن است با بررسی مفهوم‏سازی‏های استعاری ازدواج و فرزند،که در کاربردهای زبان فارسی روزمره به‏وفور دیده می‏شوند، نشان دهد که چگونه بررسی استعاره‏های مفهومی در چارچوب زبان‏شناسی اجتماعی‏ـ شناختی می‏تواند ما را در درک بهتر بازنمایی‏های جمعی و شناخت فرهنگی ازدواج و فرزندآوری یاری رساند. برای رسیدن به این هدف، پژوهش حاضر با استفاده از راهبرد قوم‏نگاری و فن مصاحبه‏‏های نیمه‏ساخت‏یافته از زنان متأهل دارای فرزند، بین سنین 50 تا 70 سالِ ساکن شهر تهران، استعاره‏های رایج در مفهوم‏سازی ازدواج و فرزند را به‏دست آورده و در ادامه با تکیه بر نظریة استعاره‏های مفهومی، آن‌ها را مورد تحلیل کیفی قرار داده است. نتایج نشان می‏دهند که استعاره‏های به‏دست‏آمده در بررسی بازنمایی جمعی و شناخت فرهنگی مفهوم ازدواج و فرزند معنادارند و به ما کمک می‏کنند به درک عمیقی از فهم فرهنگی این مفاهیم در جامعه دست یابیم.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ازدواج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استعارة مفهومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‏شناسی اجتماعی‏ـ شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شناخت فرهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرزندآوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Scenarios for the Presence of Iranian Women in Politics in 2017-2027, a Futuristic Study</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سناریوهای پیش روی حضور زنان ایرانی در عرصۀ سیاست 1396ـ1406 یک بررسی آینده‌پژوهانه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>379</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>396</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68854</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2018.250405.1007362</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فرهاد</FirstName>
					<LastName>درویشی سه‌تلانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه علوم سیاسی، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه بین‌المللی امام خمینی(ره) قزوین</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>همتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری علوم سیاسی، گرایش جامعه‌شناسی سیاسی، دانشکدة علوم اداری و اقتصادی، دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Participation and political activity of women in political history of Iran has been appeared in different ways. The issue has played a significant role in the course of Iran&#039;s historical changes and certainly will also be influential in future of its political participation. This paper as an applied research type, depending on a descriptive-survey method, attempts to explore the women&#039;s participation trend in Iran&#039;s politics in the next decade. In this research, using an open questionnaire, we asked the professors and experts about the indicators of Iranian women&#039;s activity in politics and analyzed the responses by the obtained items using inductive content analysis method. The results have been classified in seven categories including Individual-psychological, political, social, cultural, economic, and communication indicators and institutional features. Then, based on the Schwarz Steps for scenario, we have extracted triple dimensions from the seven categoriesincluding Quadruple Scenarios of the Future of Iranian Women in Politics, low impact of women&#039;s presence, institutional change and formation of a secular pattern of participation in Iran, leading women by creating equal political, economic opportunities, and removing social cultural failures,  promoting the current status of women&#039;s participation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مشارکت و فعالیت سیاسی زنان در تاریخ سیاسی ایران به شیوه‌های مختلف انجام پذیرفته است؛ موضوعی که نقشی درخور توجه در سیر تحولات تاریخی ایران داشته و بدیهی است در آیندة مشارکت سیاسی این کشور نیز تأثیرگذار خواهد بود. مقالة حاضر، که از نوع تحقیقات کاربردی است، با اتکا بر روشی توصیفی‌ـ پیمایشی در صدد است به این پرسش پاسخ گوید که روند حضور زنان در عرصة سیاست ایران در دهة آینده چگونه خواهد بود؟ در این پژوهش، ابتدا با استفاده از پرسش‌نامة باز، از استادان و صاحب‌نظران در‌خصوص شاخص‌های فعالیت‌های زنان ایرانی در عرصة سیاست نظر‌سنجی به عمل آمد و گویه‌های به‌دست‌آمده با استفاده از روش تحلیل محتوای استقرایی در 7 مقوله شاخص‌های فردی‌ـ روان‌شناختی، سیاسی، اجتماعی، فرهنگی، اقتصادی، ارتباطی و ویژگی‌های نهادی طبقه‌بندی شد. در ادامه، بر‌اساس گام‌های سناریونگاری شوارتز، ابعاد سه‌گانة مستخرج از 7 مقولة یادشده، سناریوهای چهارگانة آیندة فعالیت زنان ایرانی در عرصة سیاست‌ـ یعنی سناریوی اول: حضور کمرنگ و کم‌اثر زنان؛ سناریوی دوم: تحول نهادی و شکل‌گیری الگوی سکولار مشارکت در ایران؛ سناریوی سوم: پیشتازی زنان با ایجاد فرصت‌های برابر سیاسی، اقتصادی و رفع نارسایی‌های فرهنگی اجتماعی؛ سناریوی چهارم: ارتقای وضع فعلی مشارکت زنان‌ـ تدوین شدند. بررسی‌های انجام‌شده نشان می‌دهند که نمی‌توان روند ده سال آیندة فعالیت زنان در عرصة سیاست را حضوری صرفاً کمرنگ و کم‌اثر دانست، بلکه رشد تدریجی مشارکت آنان محتمل و مطابق با واقع خواهد بود. در‌نهایت، چنین به نظر می‌رسد که با اتکا بر توضیحاتی که در ارتباط با هر‌یک از سناریوها ارائه شد، ظهور و بروز سناریوی چهارم محتمل‌ترین گزینه خواهد بود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آینده‌پژوهی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل محتوا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سناریونگاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشارکت سیاسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Identifying and Leveling the Barriers to Women&#039;s Promotion in Managerial Posts in Iranian Educational System based on Interpretative Structural Modeling</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناسایی و سطح‌بندی موانع ارتقای مدیریتی زنان در نظام آموزش و پرورش مبتنی بر مدل‌سازی ساختاری تفسیری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>397</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>414</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68855</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2018.253973.1007393</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>میمنت</FirstName>
					<LastName>عابدینی بلترک</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشکدة علوم انسانی و اجتماعی، دانشگاه مازندران، بابلسر</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیروس</FirstName>
					<LastName>منصوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت‌علمی گروه علوم تربیتی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، اردکان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>05</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this study is to identify the barriers to women&#039;s promotion in management position in Iranian educational system based on Interpretative Structural Modeling. The research method in present study is to identify the factors for categorizing based on qualitative approach as a case study. The participants of the study are consisted of faculty members of Iranian Universities and then among them, 13 faculty members were selected as research sample based on purposeful sampling.  To assess the validity of the questionnaire, a content validity criterion was used. The questionnaire was originally reviewed by the experts of the women researches after the final amendments. The data collection tool was a self-interactive questionnaire (ISM) and content validity was confirmed by specialists. The results showed that 10 factors are considered as the factors affecting the barriers to women&#039;s promotion in managerial positions in Iranian educational system. Also, factor analysis showed that this model has 8 levels ranged from the deepest and most influential to the most surface. The eighth level of the model was the norms based on religious traditionalism that is as the deepest level of the model. The seventh level of the model is dominance of patriarchal culture and also stereotypical attitude toward women&#039;s management. The sixth level of the model is the unwritten gender discrimination. The fifth level is dismissal of women&#039;s management by employees, and women&#039;s inability to deal violently and not risk-taking. The fourth level of the model is the lack of self-confidence and self-esteem of women. The third level is Job conflict with family duties. The second level is the disapproving women&#039;s responsibility for management and finally the first level is lack of suitability in employment.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف پژوهش حاضر شناسایی و سطح‏بندی موانع ارتقای مدیریتی زنان در نظام آموزش و پرورش است. روش پژوهش، مطالعة موردی است و به منظور تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها از تکنیک مدل‌سازی ساختاری تفسیری برای سطح‏بندی موانع و دسته‏بندی آن‌ها استفاده شد. جامعة آماری پژوهش را اعضای هیئت‌علمی دانشگاه‏ها تشکیل می‏‏دهند که از بین آن‌ها 13 نفر به‌عنوان نمونة پژوهش به شیوة هدفمند انتخاب شدند. ابزار گرد‏آوری داده‏ها پرسش‌نامة خود‏تعاملی محقق‏ساخته بود. به منظور سنجش و ارزیابی روایی پرسش‌نامه از ملاک روایی محتوایی استفاده شد. بدین صورت که پرسش‌نامه در ابتدا از سوی متخصصان حوزة زنان بررسی و پس از اصلاحات عوامل نهایی تدوین شد. نتایج پژوهش نشان داد که 10 عامل به‌عنوان موانع نهایی مؤثر بر عدم ارتقای مدیریتی زنان در نظام آموزش و پرورش به حساب می‏آیند. همچنین، تحلیل حاصل از داده‌ها به سطح‏بندی مدل به 8 سطح منجر شد. سطح هشتم مدل شامل هنجارهای مبتنی بر سنت‏گرایی‌اند. سطح هفتم شامل غلبة فرهنگ مردسالاری و نگرش کلیشه‏ای به مدیریت زنان است. تبعیض‏های جنسیتی نانوشته به‌عنوان سطح ششم مدل به حساب می‏آید. عامل‏های نپذیرفتن مدیریت زنان از سوی کارکنان و همچنین ناتوانی زنان در برخورد قهر‏آمیز و ریسک‏ناپذیری مشترکاً به‌منزلة سطح پنجم مدل به حساب می‏آیند. نداشتن خودباوری و اعتمادبه‌نفس زنان به‌منزلة سطح چهارم مدل و تعارض شغلی با وظایف خانوادگی نیز به‌منزلة سطح سوم مدل به‌دست آمد. همچنین، عامل‏های نپذیرفتن مسئولیت مدیریتی از سوی زنان به‌منزلة سطح دوم و عدم شایسته‏گزینی به‌منزلة سطح اول است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارتقای مدیریتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل‌سازی ساختاری تفسیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">موانع توسعة زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظام آموزش و پرورش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Patterns of Sex Differences in Mortality in Iran, 2006-2015</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>الگوی تفاوت جنسی مرگ‏ و میر در ایران طی سال‏های 1385ـ1394</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>415</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>438</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68856</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2018.262595.1007462</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>عسکری ندوشن</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار جمعیت‌شناسی دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>ساسانی‌پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری جمعیت‌شناسی دانشگاه یزد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجید</FirstName>
					<LastName>کوششی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار جمعیت‌شناسی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اردشیر</FirstName>
					<LastName>خسروی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار وزارت بهداشت درمان و آموزش پزشکی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The different life cycles and lifestyles of men and women in human society have always led to significant gender differences in the mortality. So far, the studies on the gender gap in mortality are mostly carried out in western countries, and it is under research in Iran. The present study examines the patterns of cause-by-age gender gap in mortality in Iran over the last decades. Data of this research were adopted from the Ministry of Health and Medical Education and have been used after evaluation by the modified Brass-Trussell method and the Bennett-Horrurichi method. The findings show that the gap in life expectancy between male and female was about 3.5 years in 2006. This value is decreased to 2.9 and 3.0 years in 2011 and 2015, respectively. During the study period, about 80% of the gender gap in mortality was due to mortality differences between male and female aged 20-64 years old. The unintentional events in all three periods played a dominant role in the mortality of sex differences, but its share has declined significantly over time, with its contribution from 60% to around 42% between 2006 and 2015. By contrast, during this period, the role of cardiovascular disease has increased from 9% to 20% in explaining the mortality gap and the role of cancer rose from 10% to 15%. Examining the sex differences in death causes, in addition to showing the capacity to reduce men death, can be used to identify the critical points of women mortality by age and cause. By focusing on health planning and disease prevention in a specific direction, the sex differences in mortality can be decreased and also the life expectancy increased for both m,en and women.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">چرخة عمر و سبک زندگی متفاوت مرد و زن در جمعیت‏های انسانی همواره تفاوت‏های جنسیتی مهمی را در مرگ دو جنس پدید آورده است. مطالعة حاضر، الگوهای علت‌ـ سن شکاف جنسی مرگ‏ومیر در ایران و روند تحولات آن را در ایران طی یک دهة اخیر بررسی می‏کند. داده‏های مطالعه، از سامانة ثبت وزارت بهداشت، درمان و آموزش پزشکی اخذ شده و پس از ارزیابی و تصحیح به روش تعدیل‌شده براس‌ـ تراسل و روش بنت‌ـ هوریوشی مورد استفاده قرار گرفته است. یافته‌ها نشان می‏دهد تفاوت جنسی امید زندگی در سال 1385 حدود 5&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;3 سال بوده که در سال 1390 به 9&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;2 سال کاهش یافته و سپس با اندکی افزایش در سال 1394 به 3 سال رسیده است. در طول دورة مطالعه‌شده، حدود 80 درصد از تفاوت جنسی مرگ‏ومیر مربوط به تفاوت‏های مرگ‏ومیر مردان و زنان در سنین 20 تا 64 سالگی بوده است. حوادث غیرعمدی در هر سه دوره نقشی مسلط در شکاف جنسی مرگ‏ومیر داشتند، اما سهم آن در طول زمان کاهش یافته و از 60 درصد به حدود 42 درصد در فاصلۀ سال‏های 1385 تا 1394 رسیده است. درمقابل، در این دوره، نقش بیماری‏های قلبی عروقی در تبیین فزونی امید زندگی زنان نسبت به مردان، از 9 درصد به 20 درصد و نقش سرطان‏ها از 10 درصد به 15 درصد افزایش یافته است. مطالعة تفاوت جنسی در علل مرگ‏ومیر می‏تواند ضمن نشان‌دادن ظرفیت‏های کاهش مرگ‏ومیر مردان، به شناسایی نقاط بحرانی مرگ‏ومیر زنان بر‌حسب علت و سن نیز کمک کند. بر این مبنا، می‏توان با تمرکز برنامه‏ریزی‏های بهداشتی و پیشگیری از بیماری‏ها در جهت مشخص، تفاوت جنسی مرگ‏ومیر را کاهش داد و درضمن، امید زندگی در هر دو جنس را بهبود بخشید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">امید زندگی در بدو تولد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنس</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بیماری‏های قلبی عروقی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حوادث غیرعمدی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرطان‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Relationship between Board Gender Diversity and Internal Control Weaknesses</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی ارتباط بین حضور زنان در هیئت‌مدیره و ضعف کنترل داخلی، شواهدی از شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>439</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>456</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68857</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2018.259908.1007441</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یاسر</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضائی پیته‌نوئی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار حسابداری، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8025-3555</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خدیجه</FirstName>
					<LastName>محسنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد حسابداری، واحد بندر گز، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today, sustainable development relies on empowerment of women, as social scientists have always emphasized on the elimination of gender barriers as a prerequisite for the realization of economic and social development. Accordingly, the main purpose of this research is to investigate the relationship between Board Gender Diversity and Internal Control Weaknesses in companies admitted to the Tehran Stock Exchange. To test the research hypotheses, financial information of the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange was used between 2012 and 2016. Thus, after applying the limitations in this study, a final sample of 87 companies was selected. In this study, the Board Gender Diversity as independent variable and Internal Control Weaknesses are dependent variables of the research. After measuring the variables of the research, multivariate linear regression analysis was used to test the research hypotheses. Statistical tests were performed using the Eviews econometric software and the statistical data compilation technique. The results obtained from the test indicate that there is a significant relationship between Board Gender Diversity and Internal Control Weaknesses. In other words, the presence of women on the board reduces the company&#039;s internal control weaknesses.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه، توسعة پایدار بر توانمندسازی زنان تکیه دارد؛ به‌طوری‌که اندیشمندان اجتماعی همواره بر رفع موانع جنسیتی به‌منزلة لازمة تحقق توسعة اقتصادی و اجتماعی تأکید کرده‌اند. بر این اساس، هدف اصلی تحقیق حاضر بررسی ارتباط بین جنسیت هیئت‌مدیره و ضعف کنترل داخلی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است. در این مطالعه، جنسیت هیئت‌مدیره به‌منزلة متغیر مستقل و ضعف کنترل داخلی متغیر وابسته پژوهش است. برای آزمون فرضیه‌های تحقیق از اطلاعات مالی شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در فاصلة زمانی بین سال‌های 1391 تا 1395 استفاده شده است. به‌طوری‌که پس از اعمال محدودیت‌های مورد نظر در این تحقیق، نمونة نهایی متشکل از 87 شرکت انتخاب شدند. پس از اندازه‌گیری متغیرهای تحقیق از تجزیه و تحلیل رگرسیون خطی چند‌متغیره و تکنیک آماری داده‌های ترکیبی برای آزمون فرضیة‌ تحقیق استفاده شد. نتایج به‌دست‌آمده از آزمون فرضیه‌ حاکی از آن است که بین جنسیت هیئت‌مدیره و ضعف کنترل داخلی شرکت‌ها رابطة منفی معناداری وجود دارد. به ‌عبارت دیگر، حضور زنان در هیئت‌مدیره ضعف کنترل داخلی شرکت را کاهش می‌دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضعف کنترل داخلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گزارش حسابرسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هیئت‌مدیره</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Vulnerability of Women to Natural Disasters: A Social Construct</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آسیب‌پذیری زنان در سوانح طبیعی: یک برساختۀ اجتماعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>457</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>481</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68858</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2018.251698.1007376</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کرم</FirstName>
					<LastName>حبیب‌پور گتابی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار جامعه‏ شناسی دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present study uses feminist and critical theories to study the vulnerability of women in natural disasters in order to optimize the management of natural disaster risk with the aim of reducing their vulnerability. This research has a quantitative methodology using survey. Among 384 men and women aged 15-65 in Gorgan and Kerman provinces, we selected some people based on cluster and proportional stratification sampling methods. The results showed that the most important areas of vulnerability of women in natural disasters were lack of security, lack of employment, lack or weakness of education in the field of natural disasters, cultural problems or the traditional thinking patterns of men about women, no belief in women&#039;s participation in disasters. Meanwhile, the most important contexts of women&#039;s vulnerability to natural disasters were, as compared to men, the potential and background of women emotional and psychological vulnerability.  The social conditions are defined for women in the society and the lack of respect for women&#039;s rights by the society and authorities; the physical vulnerability of women; and the preservation of Hijab at the time of the disaster. The findings imply that the natural disasters are intrinsically social phenomena rooted from a social structure or system. Hence, vulnerability of women to natural disasters can be traced back to a construction and the consequence of social structures and semantic systems, which makes the division in the roles of men and women that, produces and reproduces this vulnerability.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقالة حاضر با تلفیقی از نظریه‏های برساخت‏گرایی اجتماعی و فمنیستی به بررسی کمّ‏وکیف آسیب‏پذیری زنان در سوانح طبیعی به منظور مدیریت بهینة ریسک سوانح طبیعی با هدف کاهش میزان آسیب‏پذیری آنان می‏پردازد. روش‏شناسی تحقیق کمی و روش آن پیمایشی بوده است که بین 768 نفر از زنان و مردان 15 تا 65 سالة دو شهر گرگان و کرمان براساس شیوه‏های نمونه‏گیری خوشه‏ای، طبقه‏بندی متناسب و تصادفی نظام‏مند انجام شده است. نتایج نشان داد که حوزه‏های مهم آسیب‏پذیری زنان در سوانح طبیعی عبارت بودند از: فقدان امنیت، فقدان اشتغال، فقدان یا ضعف آموزش در زمینة سوانح طبیعی و مشکلات فرهنگی یا انگاره‏های تفکر سنتی مردان درخصوص زنان و باورنداشتن به مشارکت زنان در سوانح. همچنین، دلایل مهم آسیب‏پذیری زنان در سوانح طبیعی، در مقایسه با مردان، عبارت بودند از: پتانسیل و زمینة آسیب‏پذیری بیشتر روحی و روانی زنان (به دلیل عاطفی‏بودن، داشتن ترس و اضطراب و...)، شرایط اجتماعی تعریف‏شده برای زنان در جامعه و رعایت‌نکردن حقوق زنان از طرف جامعه و مسئولان، آسیب‏پذیری جسمانی و فیزیکی زنان و حفظ حجاب در زمان وقوع سوانح و... . دلالت یافته‏ها بر آن است که سوانح طبیعی ذاتاً پدیده‏های اجتماعی‏اند و در ساختار یا نظام اجتماعی ریشه دارند. از‌این‌رو، آسیب‏پذیری زنان در سوانح طبیعی را می‏توان به‌منزلة امری برساختی و نتیجة ساختارهای اجتماعی و نظام‏های معنایی آن دانست که تفکیک نقشی زن و مرد موجب تولید و بازتولید این آسیب‏پذیری می‏شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آسیب‏ پذیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سوانح طبیعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت ریسک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
