<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Women’s sports and its meaningful implications</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ورزش زنان و دلالت های معنایی آن</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>309</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>334</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56334</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2015.56334</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امید</FirstName>
					<LastName>قادرزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار جامعه‌شناسی دانشگاه کردستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیده چیمن</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد جامعه‌شناسی دانشگاه کردستان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The origins of sports traditionally dates back to its practice encouraged by religion, custom or militancy, and, therefore, was considered a wholly masculine practice. Due to the inextricable link between sports and body management, nowadays, leisure and health have transcended their meaning beyond a certain gender and, consequently, sports has become a wholly ordinary practice for women. To attain an insight into the women’s experience and understanding of sports, this research conducted a semi-structural interview with 30 samples of women with sports experience, using a Grounded Theory method. The results show that the practice of sports by women is chiefly due to their concern about the maintenance of symmetry in the spatial-locative context and body fitness.Incidentally, striving for equality, maintaining an idealistic view of the body as a facilitating element, and the widespread broadcast of sports and its popularization have also been contributing factors.The meaningful implications of women’s appreciation of sports include their consciousness towards sports (sports as a functional identity), deconstruction of the social strata, body symmetry and pleasure. The research concludes that sports has offered women social acceptance, the opportunity to rethink and transcend physical and psychological well-being.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در مقایسه با گذشته، که ورزش در ذیل ابعاد آیینی، مذهبی و جنگاوری معنا پیدا می‏کرد و امری مردانه تلقی می‏شد، امروزه، به دلیل پیوند عمیق با مدیریت بدن، فراغت و سلامت، ورزش ماهیتی فراجنسیتی به‏ خود گرفته و به بخشی از زندگی روزمره بین زنان مبدل شده است. در پژوهش حاضر، به قصد راه بُردن به تجربه و درک زنان از ورزش، به روش نظریة مبنایی با 30 نمونة زن دارای تجربة فعالیت ورزشی مصاحبۀ نیمه‏ساخت‌یافته به‌عمل آمد. نتایج پژوهش بیانگر آن است که زنان به‌دلیل تناسب بافت فضایی و مکانی و ترس از افتادگی بدن به ورزش روی می‏آورند. در این میان، فهم برابری‌طلبانه از جنسیت، ایده‏آل‌نگری بدن به‌مثابة زمینۀ تسهیل‏گر و رسانه‏ای‌شدن و فراگیری ورزش به‌منزلة شرایط مداخله‏گر عمل کرده‏اند. بازسازی معنایی تجربه و درک زنان از ورزش بر آگاهانه‌بودن ورزش (ورزش به‌مثابة هویت نقشی)، واسازی رده‏بندی‏های اجتماعی، تناسب اندام و لذت‌طلبی دلالت دارد. بر‌اساس مطالعة حاضر، ورزش برای بانوان کسب پذیرش اجتماعی، بازاندیشی و ارتقای سلامت جسمی و روانی در پی داشته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایده‏آل‌نگری بدن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سلامت جسمی و روانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراگیری ورزش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ورزش زنان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The sources of social exclusion and  happiness in female-headed households</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>منابع مطرودساز، طرد اجتماعی و احساس شادمانی زنان سرپرست خانوار</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>335</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>356</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56335</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2015.56335</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>منصوره اعظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>آزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه جامعه‏ شناسی دانشگاه الزهرا(س)</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>تافته</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد جامعه‏ شناسی دانشگاه الزهرا(س)</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This research is aimed at measuring the happiness of the women who conduct a family in Tehran and identifying the causes and background of such happiness and also the causes of ostracism and the ways it affects their happiness. This is an explorative survey. For this purpose,  30 women were selected through snowball sampling and the data was collected through interview and then a survey was conducted with the population of 180. The interviews demonstrated that: factors such as deprivation from basic needs and SENSE OF DISCRIMINATION have excluded these women from the society and that is why they feel being discriminated and less happy. . Based on regression equation, about 70 percent of the changes in terms of happiness of the female heads in Tehran is because of  lack of fairness, social ostracism and SENSE OF DISCRIMINATION and also lack of effective provision of basic needs which faint away their happiness. Based on path analysis equation, social ostracism is the strongest factor, which negatively affects their happiness directly and indirectly. Lack of fairness comes next in terms of direct effects. Sense of discrimination and effective provision of the basic needs are  other factors that affect their happiness respectively.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با هدف اندازه‏گیری میزان احساس شادمانی زنان سرپرست خانوار تهران و همچنین شناسایی منابع طرد و محرومیت اجتماعی این جمعیت و مکانیزم اثرگذاری آن بر شادمانی آن‏ها صورت گرفته است. روش پژوهش در این تحقیق، اکتشافی‌ـ پیمایشی است. بدین‌منظور، ابتدا نمونه‏ای 30‌نفری از زنان سرپرست خانوار تهران به روش نمونه‏گیری گلوله‏برفی انتخاب و داده‏ها با تکنیک مصاحبه جمع‏آوری شده است. سپس پیمایش با نمونة 180‌نفری و روش نمونه‏گیری دردسترس و تکنیک پرسش‌نامه اجرا شده است. نتایج حاصل از مصاحبه‏ها نشان داد: مجموعه ‌عواملی مثل محرومیت از نیازهای اساسی و احساس نابرابری، دست به دست هم داده و زمینۀ طرد و محرومیت اجتماعی زنان سرپرست خانوار را فراهم کرده و از طریق و به‌واسطۀ ایجاد این طرد و محرومیت، احساس بی‏انصافی در این قشر از زنان شکل گرفته است؛ در‌نتیجه این وضعیت باعث کاهش احساس شادمانی در زندگی آن‏ها شده است. طبق معادلة رگرسیون نزدیک به 70درصد از کل تغییرات میزان احساس شادمانی در بین زنان سرپرست خانوار تهران از سوی متغیرهای احساس بی‏انصافی، طرد اجتماعی و احساس نابرابری پیش‏بینی می‏شود. در‌نهایت، طبق معادلة تحلیل مسیر، متغیر طرد اجتماعی قوی‏ترین و مهم‏ترین قدرت پیش‏بینی‏کننده نسبت به مابقی عوامل تأثیرگذار بر احساس شادمانی زنان سرپرست خانوار است که به صورت مستقیم و غیرمستقیم بر شادمانی این قشر از زنان تأثیر منفی داشته است. در مرتبة بعدی، به ترتیب احساس بی‏انصافی و احساس نابرابری به‌صورت مستقیم و عدم پاسخ‌گویی مؤثر به نیازهای اساسی به صورت غیرمستقیم بر احساس شادمانی این جمعیت تأثیر منفی گذاشته‏ است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">احساس بی‏انصافی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">احساس شادمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">احساس نابرابری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان سرپرست خانوار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طرد اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The effective determinants in willingness to cesarean section (The case of pregnant women in Tehran)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تعیین‌کننده‌های موثر بر تمایل به سزارین (مطالعۀ موردی: زنان باردار شهر تهران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>357</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>376</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56336</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2015.56336</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خلیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>علی محمدزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار رشتة مدیریت خدمات بهداشتی و درمانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران شمال، رئیس مرکز تحقیقات سیاست‌گذاری اقتصاد سلامت</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پریوش</FirstName>
					<LastName>افرادی اسبقرانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت خدمات بهداشتی و درمانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تهران شمال</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Based on statistical evidence, rate of cesarean   in Iran is quite high ranking Iran  the second country in the world; in terms of the highest cesarean rates,  various parameters affect  decision of  delivery mode  in pregnant women. One way to reduce caesarean sections is to identify these factors and their impacts. The aim of this study is to identify factors affecting willingness to cesarean section in pregnant women and the correlation between them to reduce the willingness to C-section. This study was examined in a cross-sectional way by means of stochastic and available selection procedure, within the second half of 2014, on pregnant women who live in Tehran. In the semi-structured survey with the answer package (5 point Likert scale), five effective factors to predict   willingness to cesarean were examined  including psychological, environmental and socio-cultural factors, as well as conditions and outcomes of childbirth;  structural equation modeling (SEM) method and Amossoftware were utilized in order to confirm the parameters. Among the 5 factors affecting willingness to cesarean section in pregnant women, &quot;fear of natural childbirth&quot;  related to psychological factors and the component &quot;Not to put pressure on the baby&#039;s head&quot; and &quot;no shoulder dislocation  other physical damages” caused by Caesarean section related to the consequences of childbirth, have the greatest impact. Also the results of this study demonstrated that the highest and lowest correlations are related to conditions and consequences and socio-cultural and psychological factors respectively. Therefore, we can help pregnant women to recognize their capabilities and overcome their fear of pain by improving the level of pregnant women’s awareness and using natural vaginal delivery techniques with lower pain.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">براساس شواهد آماری نرخ سزارین در ایران بسیار بالاست. پارامترهای گوناگون در تصمیم‌گیری زنان باردار دربارۀ انتخاب روش زایمان تأثیر دارند. پژوهش حاضر با هدف شناسایی عوامل تأثیرگذار بر میزان تمایل به سزارین در زنان باردار و میزان همبستگی بین این عوامل به منظور کمک به کاهش تمایل به سزارین انجام شده است. این مطالعه به صورت مقطعی در بین زنان باردار ساکن شهر تهران و به روش انتخاب تصادفی و در دسترس انجام شد. در پرسش‌نامۀ محقق‌ساخته، پنج عامل تأثیرگذار در پیش‌بینی تمایل به سزارین شامل: عوامل روان‌شناختی، محیطی، اجتماعی‌ـ فرهنگی، شرایط و پیامدهای زایمان، بررسی شده و برای تأیید مؤلفه‌ها از روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری و نرم‌افزار آموس بهره گرفته شده است. در بین 5 مؤلفۀ یادشده، «ترس از زایمان طبیعی» مربوط به عوامل روان‌شناختی و مؤلفۀ «تحت فشار قرار نگرفتن سر نوزاد» و «عدم دررفتگی شانه یا وارد آمدن سایر آسیب‌های جسمی به نوزاد» در روش سزارین مربوط به پیامدهای زایمان، بیشترین تأثیر را داشته‌اند. همچنین، عوامل مربوط به «شرایط زایمان» و «پیامدهای زایمان» بیشترین همبستگی و کمترین همبستگی مربوط به عوامل «روان‌شناختی» و «اجتماعی‌ـ فرهنگی» را داشت. بنابراین، با ارتقای سطح آگاهی زنان باردار از مراحل بارداری و زایمان و استفاده از تکنیک‌های زایمان طبیعی با درد کمتر، می‌توان به بهبود شناخت زنان باردار از توانمندی‌های خود و غلبۀ آن‌ها بر ترس کمک کرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تمایل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زایمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان باردار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سزارین</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Effect of Glass Cliff on work engagement with the  mediator role of organizational silence (Case study of female staff of Bu-Ali University of Hamedan)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تاثیر صخره شیشه ای بر اشتیاق شغلی با نقش میانجی سکوت سازمانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>377</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>398</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56337</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2015.56337</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فخرالسادات</FirstName>
					<LastName>نصیری ولیک نبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیارگروه علوم تربیتی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>اردلان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیارگروه علوم تربیتی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رقیه</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهشتی راد</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت آموزشی دانشگاه بوعلی سینا همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>31</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The current study aims to examine the  effect of Glass Cliff on work engagement with the mediator roe of organizational silence. The statistical population consists of all formal staff of women in Bu-Ali University of hamedan, totally 88,   among which 52  were selected by stratified random sampling method. Data were gathered through three questionnaires, the glass cliff, organizational silence and work engagement. The validity of the questionnaires was determined based on viewpoints of experts in management and educational sciences. The combined reliability of questionnaires was measured by Dillon-Goldstein coefficient and Average Variance Extracted. The combined reliability of both  questionnaires was more than 0.7 and Average Variance Extracted was more than 0.5. The data after collecting were analyzed by Excel, VisualPLS and SmartPLS, Pearson test and with Self-test system, Q&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Stone- Geisser index and Goodness of fit index. The results indicate that the direct effect of the glass cliff on job engagement is negative and significant, but the direct effect of these variables on organizational silence is significant and positive. Also, an effect of organizational silence on work engagement is negative and significant. Indirect effect of glass cliff on work engagement with mediating role of organizational silence is negative and significant.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی تأثیر صخرة شیشه‌ای بر اشتیاق شغلی با نقش میانجی سکوت سازمانی صورت گرفته است. جامعة آماری شامل کلیة کارکنان رسمی زن دانشگاه بوعلی سینای همدان به تعداد 88 نفر است که با روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی ساده، 52 نفر به‌عنوان نمونه جهت مطالعه انتخاب شده‌اند. برای گردآوری داده‌های پژوهش از سه پرسش‌نامة صخرة شیشه‌ای، سکوت سازمانی و اشتیاق شغلی استفاده شده است. برای روایی پرسش‌نامه‌ها از متخصصان علوم تربیتی و مدیریت بهره گرفته شده و برای بررسی قابلیت اعتماد ترکیبی هر‌یک از سازه‌ها از ضریب دیلون‌ـ گلداشتاین (&lt;sub&gt;c&lt;/sub&gt;ρ) و میانگین واریانس استخراج‌شده، استفاده شده است. شاخص‌های پایایی ترکیبی هر دو پرسش‌نامه بیشتر از 7&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 و میانگین واریانس استخراج‌شدة آن‌ها نیز بیشتر از 5&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0به دست آمد. داده‌های پژوهش با استفاده از نرم‌افزارهای Excel، SPSS، VisualPLS و SmartPLS و با آزمون پیرسون، مدل‌یابی معادلات ساختاری به روش Partial Least Square (PLS) آزمون خودگردان‌سازی، شاخص Q&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; Stone&lt;em&gt;-&lt;/em&gt;Geisser و شاخص نیکویی برازش تحلیل شدند. نتایج به‌دست‌آمده گویای آن بود که اثر مستقیم صخرة شیشه‌ای بر اشتیاق شغلی منفی و معنادار است، اما اثر مستقیم این متغیر بر سکوت سازمانی مثبت و معنادار است. همچنین، اثر سکوت سازمانی بر اشتیاق شغلی نیز منفی و معنادار است. اثر غیر‌مستقیم صخرة شیشه‌ای بر روی اشتیاق شغلی با میانجی‌گری سکوت سازمانی منفی و معنادار است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتیاق شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سکوت سازمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صخرة شیشه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارکنان زن</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Women entering  male jobs: causes and consequences Qualitative exploration of experts’ views</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ورود زنان به مشاغل مردانه: دلایل و پیامدها واکاوی کیفی آرای کارشناسان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>399</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>424</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56338</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2015.56338</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اسماعیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>بلالی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه جامعه‌شناسی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینای همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مونس</FirstName>
					<LastName>سیاح</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیده فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>محبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مسائل اجتماعی ایران دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Gender as one of the social and cultural determinant factors, affects many dimensions of women including their occupation and can affect  the types of male and female jobs. Nowadays, gender segregation of jobs in Iran is gradually being removed. Nevertheless, social policy making in this subject needs scientific studies. It seems necessary to take advantage of qualitative methods. In this qualitative study using focus group discussions, views of  19 women and family experts  about the phenomenon of women presence in occupations and its reasons were questioned and discussed. The findings and thematic analysis showed three types of views including: supporters,  opponents and intermediate. Individual and communicative capability elevation, economic and social justice realization are mensioned as positive implications of women entering  male jobs. In some experts’ views, seperation of women jobs prevents their talent development, strengthens gender beliefs in society and economic-gender imbalance. But opponents of women entering  male jobs see this entrance as equivalent to women distancing from women world, identity and personality imbalance, physical and mental exhaustion, reduction of marriage opportunity, sexual and ethical insecurity and male social reactions.   </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">جنسیت، به‌منزلة یکی از عناصر تعیین‌کنندة فرهنگی و اجتماعی، بسیاری از ابعاد حیات جمعی زنان همچون اشتغال آنان را تحت‌تأثیر قرار می‌دهد و می‌تواند بر نوع مشاغل زنان و مردان در جامعه تأثیر‌گذار باشد. امروزه، جداسازی جنسیتی مشاغل در ایران به‌تدریج در حال برداشته شدن است، اما سیاست‌گذاری اجتماعی در مورد این موضوع نیازمند مطالعات علمی است. از‌این‌رو، در این مطالعه با استفاده از روش کیفی و بحث گروهی متمرکز، دیدگاه‌های 19 نفر از کارشناسان مسائل زنان و خانواده دربارة پدیدة «ورود زنان به مشاغل مردانه» و دلایل آن، مورد پرسش و بحث قرار گرفته است. یافته‌های حاصل از تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها به روش تحلیل تماتیک نشان داد مشارکت‌کنندگان در مورد این پدیده دیدگاه‌های پیامدگرای مثبت‌گرا، پیامدگرای منفی‌گرا و تلفیقی داشتند. تعالی توانایی‌های فردی و ارتباطی زنان و تحقق عدالت اقتصادی و اجتماعی از دلالت‌های مثبت ورود زنان به مشاغل مردانه ذکر شده‌اند. همچنین، جداسازی مشاغل زنان مانع پرورش استعدادهای آن‌ها، تقویت باورهای جنسیتی در جامعه و عدم تعادل اقتصادی‌ـ جنسیتی قلمداد شده است. اما پیامدگرایان منفی‌گرا ورود زنان به مشاغل مردانه را مترادف فاصله‌گیری زنان از دنیای زنانه، عدم تعادل هویتی و شخصیتی، فرسودگی جسمی و روانی، کاهش فرصت ازدواج، ناامنی اخلاقی و جنسی برای زنان درگیر در این مشاغل و بازخوردهای اجتماعی مردانه دانسته‌اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتغال زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جداسازی جنسیتی مشاغل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشاغل زنانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشاغل مردانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مطالعة کیفی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Gender analysis of the impact of family upbringing on the democratic attitudes</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل جنسیتی تأثیر تربیت خانوادگی بر ایستارهای دموکراتیک (مطالعۀ موردی: شهر اصفهان)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>425</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>438</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56339</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2015.56339</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمودرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>رهبرقاضی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم سیاسی دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیدجواد</FirstName>
					<LastName>امام جمعه زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه علوم سیاسی دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>عارفیان جزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد گروه علوم سیاسی دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>18</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Humans, since their creation, have experienced different political systems. In addition, it seems that the training in families is the key to open the future; therefore, it is expected that the family system of each human society nurtures and trains future humans and prepares the present generation for the future. The task of families is to empower all members of a society to develop their hidden potentials and provide grounds for realizing them in humans and also to empower the society in identifying its creativities and potentials. Accordingly, deep political advancement and development in societies for attaining determined aims far from radicalism, particularly in the domains of societies and politics, will not be possible without paying attention to the family structure and training methods dominant over this structure. The objective of the present study is to investigate the effect of different upbringing methods in families from democratic perspectives among male and female citizens of the City of Isfahan in 2015. By dividing upbringing methods into three types of authoritative, tyrannical, and easygoing , the results indicate that authoritative methods with the coefficient of 49.0 causes the increase in the democratic perspectives, but tyrannical methods with an coefficient of -18.0 causes a decrease in democratic perspectives among citizens. In addition, other findings indicate that although the results of the research among men are consistent with the general results of the research, tyrannical methods have no significant correlation with democratic perspectives among the studied women.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">بشر، از اوان پیدایش تا کنون، نظام های سیاسی مختلفی را تجربه کرده است. اما در این میان هیچ نظامی تاکنون به اندازة نظام‏های دموکراتیک جایگاه ویژه‌ای نداشته است. از سوی دیگر، به نظر می‏رسد پیشرفت و توسعة عمیق سیاسی در جوامع در جهت رسیدن به اهداف تعیین‌شده، که از هر‌گونه افراط و تفریط به دور باشد، خصوصاَ در عرصة اجتماع و سیاست، بدون توجه به ساختار خانواده و روش‌های تربیتی حاکم در آن‌ها میسر نخواهد بود. حال، هدف این پژوهش بررسی تأثیر روش‏های تربیتی مختلف در درون خانواده‏ها بر روی ایستارهای دموکراتیک در بین شهروندان مرد و زن شهر اصفهان در سال 1394 است. با تقسیم روش‏های تربیتی به سه نوع شیوه‏های مقتدرانه، مستبدانه و سهل‏گیرانه، نتایج نشان می‏دهد که روش‏های مقتدرانه با ضریب 49&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 باعث افزایش ایستارهای دموکراتیک می‏شود، اما روش‏های مستبدانه با ضریب 18&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0- باعث کاهش ایستارهای دموکراتیک در بین شهروندان می‏شود. از سوی دیگر، یافته‏ها نشان می‏دهد که هر‌چند بین مردان هر دو شیوة تربیتی مستبدانه و مقتدرانه با ایستارهای دموکراتیک آن‌ها ارتباط داشتند، بین زنان، فقط روش تربیتی مقتدرانه بر روی ایستارهای دموکراسی‏خواهی آنان تأثیر می‏گذاشت و باعث افزایش این نوع ایستارها در بین آنان می‏شد. سرانجام، نتایج نشان می‏دهد که روش سهل‏انگارانه تأثیری در افزایش یا کاهش ایستارهای دموکراتیک ندارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایستارهای دموکراتیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تربیت سهل‌انگارانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تربیت مستبدانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تربیت مقتدرانه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigating the role of women in rural animal husbandry production system (attitude, motives, and barriers  of participation) in Charuymaq County/Iran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی نقش زنان روستایی در نظام بهره ‏برداری دامپروری روستایی (نگرش، انگیزه و موانع مشارکت) درشهرستان چاراویماق</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>439</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>453</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56340</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2015.56340</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>شمس</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی، گروه ترویج، ارتباطات و توسعة روستایی، دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نازیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نبی زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد توسعة روستایی دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>شعبانعلی فمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار ترویج و توسعة روستایی، دانشکدة اقتصاد و توسعة کشاورزی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Any economic development planning of rural regions needs an initial investigation of rural women&#039;s role in the production system, hence the purpose of this descriptive- survey study was to investigate rural women&#039;s role in animal husbandry activities. The statistical population consisted of all rural families (N=6571) in Charuymaq county among which 135 were selected through a multistage randomised sampling method based on Cochran&#039;s sampling formula. The research tool was a researcher-constructed questionnaire the  validity of which was verified by a panel of experts in the related field and to check its reliability, a Cronbach&#039;s Alpha coefficient was computed which was higher than 0.7 for composite constructs. The results showed that majority of women (60.7%) had a neutral attitude toward animal husbandry activities. Hard nature of animal activities was the most important barrier of women&#039;s participation.  Preparing households food requirements (self-consumption) and feeling responsibile toward household were the most intrinsic and extrinsic motives of women regarding their participation, respectively. The majority of women had a low level of mass media information usage and TV was the first source of their information  gathering. Women had the highest participation in milking and processing and the least in grazing the animals.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هرگونه برنامه‏ریزی با هدف توسعة اقتصادی جوامع روستایی نیازمند شناخت اولیة جایگاه و نقش زنان روستایی در نظام بهره‏برداری روستایی است. از‌این‌رو،این تحقیق توصیفی‌ـ پیمایشی با هدف بررسی نقش زنان روستایی در نظام دامپروری روستایی انجام گرفت. جامعة آماری شامل ۶ هزار ۵۷۱ نفر خانوار روستایی شهرستان چاروایماق بود که با استفاده از فرمول کوکران ۱۳۵ نفر از زنان روستایی از طریق نمونه‏گیری چند‌مرحله‌ای تصادفی انتخاب و مطالعه شدند. ابزار تحقیق پرسش‌نامة محقق‌ساخته‏ای بود که روایی آن از طریق متخصصان موضوعی تأیید و از طریق پیش‌آزمون و محاسبة ضریب آلفای کرونباخ بالاتر از 7&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 برای شاخص‏های ترکیبی مناسب تشخیص داده شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد که ۷&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;۶۰ درصد زنان روستایی نگرشی خنثی (میانه) در‌خصوص مشارکت در فعالیت‌های دامپروری داشتند. سنگین و سخت بودن کارهای دامپروری مهم‌ترین مانع مشارکت از دید زنان بود. تأمین مواد غذایی مورد نیاز مهم‏ترین انگیزة بیرونی و احساس مسئولیت در قبال خانواده مهم‏ترین انگیزة درونی زنان برای مشارکت در فعالیت‌های دامپروری محسوب می‏شد. بیشتر زنان به میزان کمی از رسانه‏های جمعی اطلاعات دریافت می‏کردند و مهم‌ترین منبع اطلاعاتی آن‌ها تلویزیون بود. زنان بیشترین مشارکت را در فعالیت‌های شیردوشی و فرآوری و کمترین مشارکت را در فعالیت‌های مربوط به چرا داشتند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انگیزه و نگرش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دامپروری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان روستایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شهرستان چاراویماق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نقش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>English Abstracts</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>چکیده های انگلیسی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>1</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>7</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56721</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2015.56721</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract></Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA"></OtherAbstract>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
