<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[First Pages]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_58515_89d98c06e5091ca15adb97ddff474739.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Conservative views and the effect of gender gaps (Case study: Students of University of Isfahan)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Rahbarghazi, Mahhmoodreza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Masoudnia, Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Sadeghi Naghdali, zahra]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[cultural views]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[economic views]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[gender gaps]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[political views]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Women]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Investigations and studies in 1960’s and 1970’s indicate that in some political, cultural, and economic issues, as well as party identity, men think differently from women so that women have relatively strong conservative tendencies. But new findings indicate that since 1980’s women’s degree of conservatism has degreased. The main objective of the present study is to investigate the existence or inexistence of such differences among groups of women and men in the studied population. To do so, the research population includes all students of universities of in Isfahan City. From among them, 914 participants were selected using the cluster sampling method. The results of this research indicate that women in cultural and political domains are more conservative than men. But in economic issues, men supported free markets and privatizing the economy more than women. This issue indicates that women have less economic conservative tendencies than men. In addition, investigating findings more closely show that the effect size between the gender variable and conservative components are moderate only in terms of cultural conservatism, and in the rest of hypotheses, the effect size was small. Therefore, it can be concluded that except for cultural domains in which there are relatively profound gaps among men and women, in other domains of the society, these gender gaps have been relatively degreasing and fading.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_58130_12430a7b053c4fa1e5ed9b85dc45fcf5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2015.58130]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Qualitative content analysis of elementary textbooks based on gender orientation]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Marzooghi, Rahmatallah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mansoori, Sirus]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[elementary]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Gender]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Personality characteristics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[professional role]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[social and political patterns]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[textbooks]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The aim of this study was the content analysis of elementary textbooks based on gender orientation. Method of research was qualitative content analysis. Statistical population was textbooks of the elementary. Statistical sample of research includes Heavenly gifts (Hediehaye Asmani), social studies, and Persian books. Components of the study were including personality characteristics, political and social patterns and professional roles. Results showed that women have emotional and the subordinate role and men have intellectual personality characteristics and directive. Relation to job roles, men had jobs outside the home and women were in jobs related to nursing home or maximum of teaching and nursing role. About the social and political patterns as well as men in the form of social and political leadership patterns, the peacemakers and owners but in contrast, the pattern for women embodied in the form of the mother and the husband.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_58131_2f19ceaa61af3332d0f2308c9926a30e.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2015.58131]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Representation of women in Iranian newspapers (Kayhan, Iran and Shargh Newspapers)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Naderi, Ahmad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ghashami, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Iran Newspaper]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Kayhan Newspaper]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[photos]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Representation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Semiotics]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Shargh Newspaper]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Women]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Women as half of human societies have different roles in different areas of social life. So content analysis of the media is necessary in the about of women. This study uses two methods: content analysis and semiotics. So content analyzed a statistical week from the first six months of 1393 Kayhan, Iran and Shargh Newspapers. Then by using semiotics, printed images of women in these newspapers were analyzed. Number of Iran Newspaper writings was about one and half. The newspaper press releases about one and a half equal Shargh Newspaper writings. The number of Shargh Newspaper writings was twice equal of the Keyhan Newspaper. Iran Newspaper in front-page headlines and photographs of the position of women is better than the two other daily newspapers. In semiotics of women, representation of Iranian women in comparison with foreign women is not suitable and in front page and internal pages images of Iran Newspaper, reflection of foreign women were better than Iranian women. Of course, we can be considered the approach of Shargh Newspaper in intermediate in which images of foreign and Iranian women have been reflected suitable. Anyway, images of Iranian womens in Shargh were better than other two daily newspapers.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_58132_4378b834d3955b48d6d4aec9b9e007f7.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2015.58132]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Representation the nature of power among women's principals: Developing a theoretical framework]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Gholami, Khalil]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shirbagi, Naser]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hosseini, Delsuz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[educational administration]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Empowerment]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[power relationship]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Women Studies]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The present research investigated the nature of power among women's principals in order to develop a theoretical framework. Relying on critical epistemology and qualitative approach, we used grounded theory to study the problem. Using a purposeful and theoretical sampling, we selected women and men's principals as well as the men whose spouses were employed in schools. We collected data with semi-structured interview. The interviews were transcribed verbatim and after three stage of coding, institutional discrimination was considered as core category. In addition, political, cultural and mental structures were considered as casual conditions affected the core category. Family- official responsibilities, educational context and media were found to be the mediating factors that affected the hegemony of masculinity in society. The women enhanced a kind of epistemic hope in order to empower themselves and struggle with these hegemonic conditions.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_58133_f1942effc4f3d5a64cf2d4be5ab20f6f.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2015.58133]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[An investigation of relationship between religiosity, social and cultural capital and loneliness in Shiraz: A comparison between employed and nonemployed women]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Soroush, Maryam]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Adibi Parsa, Pegah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Employed Women]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Loneliness]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Religiosity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[social and cultural capital]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The objective of this article was to investigate the relationship between capitals, religiosity and loneliness among women in Shiraz, Iran. Using survey method, we chose 413 women between 19 to 65 years of age by cluster random sampling. Findings showed that being religious decrease emotional loneliness and more cultural and social capital decrease social loneliness. Employed women enjoyed more education and social capital in comparison to nonemployed ones and felt much less social loneliness. Emotional loneliness was not significantly different in two groups. Findings suggest that employment has many advantages for women. Employed women are more empowered so that they have more social and cultural capitals and they will not suffer of social loneliness especially when they come to age.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_58134_5bce392ab7d26c3b402e4d3387211ad5.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2015.58134]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[investigating factors related to rural womens’ participation in family poultry activities in Maragheh County]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[shams, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Razmi, Halimeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shahir, Mohammad- Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[family poultry]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Maragheh County]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[participation level]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[rural women]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[    Production of family poultry is one of the activities which women in the villages participate and several factors effect on their participation in these activities. The purpose of this descriptive- correlational study was to investigate factors related to the participation level of rural women in family poultry activities. The Statistical population consisted all rural households in Maragheh County (N=22564) which 224 of them were selected based on Cochran sampling formula and using multi-stage randomized sampling method. The research tool was a researcher-constructed questionnaire whose validity verified by a panel of experts in the related field and to check its reliability. A pretest conducted and Cronbach's Alpha coefficient were higher than 0.7 for different parts of the questionnaire. The results showed that all family members are involved in family poultry activities, but the participation of women was higher than other family members. On average, women participated 77.35 percent in activities and incubator related activity and nesting activities had lower and higher rate of participation, respectively. The participation level of women had a negative meaningful correlation with their age, education, husband's education, households’ numbers, the size of poultry folk and their knowledge but a positive meaningful correlation with their attitudes and women's share of income gaining from poultry and products selling.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_58135_70eb95bccdbcc85cb8c7f762e031822b.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2015.58135]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Compare married and single women teachers of social anxiety and psychological]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Azadmanesh, Seyed Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mostafapour, chyman]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ahmadipour, Luqman]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[prolongation of celibacy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Psychological capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[social anxiety]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Today, marriage is one of the main challenges in Iranian society. Youth for various reasons attempt to avoid marriage and the phenomenon of delay in age at marriage not as a problem but as a problem of social and personal problems. The current study aims to investigate the effects of prolongation of celibacy period on social anxiety and psychological capital of female teachers in Boukan. As causal-comparative study (after an event), the population consisted of two groups of married and unmarried female teachers aged 45 to 25 years in 1393 were 94 school year. Married between the two groups of teachers (80) and single (80) and a total of 160 people were randomly chosen. The data of psychological capital questionnaire Mk‌Gy (2011) and social phobia list Conover and colleagues (2000) were used. Multivariate analysis of variance indicated a significant difference between two groups of female teachers aged 25 to 45 years old, married and single social anxiety and the psychological capital. So, it can be concluded that married people more than single people are above the psychological level of capital, and less social anxiety.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_58136_2249d501d68888a6abfed449bb298075.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2015.58136]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[English Abstracts]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2015]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_58516_0b032ebeb83fc4a10d79fe1441200364.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>