<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Study On Socio- Cultural Barriers of Women&#039;s Participation in Sports Case study: 20-40 year-old female athletes and non-athletes in Hamedan province</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>موانع فرهنگی- اجتماعی مشارکت زنان در فعالیت‌های ورزشی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>147</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>163</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22496</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اسداله</FirstName>
					<LastName>نقدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اسماعیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>بلالی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکده اقتصاد و علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پروین</FirstName>
					<LastName>ایمانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد جامعه شناسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In today&#039;s world, women&#039;s participation in social activities is considered as a measure of their social and civil rights. However, there are challenges to such participation. This research aims to investigate these socio-cultural obstacles, comparing athletic and non-athletic women. 
The present study examines women&#039;s sports participation as a form of behavior which includes Fishbein and Ajzen theories, social learning theory, cultural capital, Bem&#039;s feministic theories, Chaftez theory and also Chu&#039;s theory, through survey and data gathering technique of questionnaire. 
A t-test was run for independent samples along with logistic regression proportional to research theories to compare the two groups. 200 non-athletic and 50 athletic women were selected a statistical society of 106404 women aged 20 to 40 residing in Hamedan Province. 
The results show that athletic women enjoy a greater economic, social and cultural status and a more comprehensive social protection. Moreover, the families of athletic women have more positive attitude towards life than non-athletes. Accordingly, athletic women demonstrate a significantly lower acceptance rate for cliché beliefs in comparison to non – athletic women. However, the results also reveal that in terms of perceived usefulness, there is no significant difference between these two groups. 
Generally, cultural capital and individual inclination are two influential variables in the probability of women participating in sports</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه مشارکت زنان در فعالیت‌های مختلف اجتماعی بخشی از حقوق اجتماعی آنان تلقی می‌شود، اما موانع فرهنگی و اجتماعی بسیاری در این زمینه وجود دارد. مشارکت زنان در ورزش به دلیل تأثیرات آن بر سلامت جامعه دارای اهمیت بسیاری است. در اینجا برای مطالعه مشارکت زنان در ورزش از مدلی که ترکیبی از نظریه‌های فیش باین و آیزن، نظریه یادگیری اجتماعی، سرمایه فرهنگی و نیز نظریه‌های بم، چافتز و چو استفاده شده است. روش تحقیق پیمایشی و تکنیک جمع‌آوری داده‌ها از طریق پرسشنامه بوده و از آزمون تی گروه‌های مستقل و رگرسیون لجستیک استفاده شده است. حجم نمونه 200 نفر از زنان غیر ورزشکار به صورت نمونه‌گیری خوشه‌ای چند مرحله‌ای از جامعه آماری 106404 نفری زنان 40- 20 ساله شهر همدان و یک گروه 50 نفری از زنان ورزشکار بر اساس نمونه‌گیری تصادفی ساده انتخاب شده‌اند. نتایج نشان‌گر پایگاه اقتصادی اجتماعی بالاتر، میزان سرمایه فرهنگی، تمایل فردی و حمایت اجتماعی بیشتر از زنان ورزشکار نسبت به زنان غیر ورزشکار است. نگرش خانواده زنان ورزشکار،مثبت‌تر و میزان پذیرش باورهای قالبی به طور معنی‌داری کمتر از زنان غیر ورزشکار است. اما از نظر سودمندی ادراک شده تفاوت معنی‌داری بین دو گروه وجود ندارد. نتایج رگرسیون لجستیک نشان داد که متغیر‌های سرمایه فرهنگی و تمایل فردی دو متغیر تأثیر‌گذار بر احتمال مشارکت ورزشی است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حمایت اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه فرهنگی.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فعالیت ورزشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کلیشه‌های جنسیتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_22496_4faa2c03b6525e71a9ff44aff882e39d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
