<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Cohort Analysis of Women&#039;s Attitude towards Value of Children  in Semnan Province</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل کوهورتی (نسلی) نگرش زنان دربارۀ ارزش فرزند در استان سمنان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>229</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>250</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">52357</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2014.52357</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حجیه بی بی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رازقی نصرآباد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مؤسسۀ مطالعات و مدیریت جامع و تخصصی جمعیت کشور</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0990-9689</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسن</FirstName>
					<LastName>سرایی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد دانشکدۀ علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this paper is to investigate the differences in value of children between the 1960s, 1970s, after 1980 birth cohort, and identifying the factors affecting. The data for this study are drawn from a survey in Semnan province in 2012. Information is related to 405 married women aged 15-49 years. The result shows that the highest score of the children value belonged to the 1960 birth cohort. Protect, emotional and family continuity value in childbearing are characteristics of this cohort. In contrast, emphasis on the economic costs and lost opportunity costs, emotional and psychological benefits to children are characteristics of the 1980 birth cohorts. Based on this study, in line with the socio- economical changes, significant changes in childbearing attitude have emerged in three cohorts. Nevertheless, the 1960 birth cohort more than any other generation produces modern childbearing values and behaviors gives great importance to childbearing and because of the emotional value of children, one of the goals of younger cohort is childbearing. Multiple classification analysis showed that by controlling the effect of factors related to modernization and individual characteristics of respondents, the mean score of value of children within cohort changes. A more percent of the differences between the cohorts are affected by education variable. After entering these variables are considerably reduced the intensity of relationship between value of children and birth cohort. But, the differences in the value of children in three cohorts are still significant.
 </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف از این مقاله، بررسی تفاوت‏های ارزش فرزند در سه کوهورت (هم‏دوره) تولد دهه‏های 1340، 1350 و 1360 به بعد و شناسایی عوامل مؤثر بر آن است. به منظور دستیابی به اهداف تحقیق، از داده‏های طرح پیمایشی«شمار فرزندان موجود و فرزندان ایده‏آل و شکاف میان آن‏ها در سه استان منتخب در سال 1391» استفاده شده است. روش نمونه‏گیری در این طرح ترکیبی از روش‏های نمونه‏گیری طبقه‏ای چند‏مرحله‏ای و نمونه‏گیری تصادفی سیستماتیک بوده است. جامعة آماری 405 زن ازدواج‏کرده ساکن استان سمنان است. یافته‏های مطالعه نشان می‏دهد که متولدان هم‏دورۀ دهۀ 1340 بالاترین ارزش را به فرزند می‏دهند. ارزش فرزند به جهت منافع حمایتی، عاطفی، و تداوم و پیوستگی خانواده از ویژگی‏های‏ این هم‏دوره است. کمترین نمرۀ ارزش فرزند، متعلق به متولدان سال‏های 1360 به بعد است. تأکید بر هزینه‏های اقتصادی و هزینۀ فرصت از‏دست‏رفته و اهمیت زیاد به منافع عاطفی و روانی فرزندان از ویژگی‏های‏ متولدان هم‏دورۀ 1360 به بعد است. بر‏اساس این مطالعه، ملازم با تغییرات اجتماعی، تغییرات محسوسی در زمینۀ ارزش فرزند در سه نسل پدید آمده است. با‏این‏حال، متولدان هم‏دورۀ 1360 به بعد نیز، که بیش از هر نسل دیگر ارزش‏ها و رفتارهای مدرن فرزندآوری را تولید می‏کند، به کارکرد عاطفی فرزندان اهمیت می‏دهند و فرزندآوری یکی از اهداف و ارزش‏های آن‏هاست. نتایج تحلیل طبقه‏بندی چندگانه نشان داد که با کنترل عوامل مرتبط با نوسازی و برخی ویژگی‏های جمعیتی افراد، میانگین ارزش فرزند در بین سه هم‏دوره تغییر می‏کند. بخش زیادی از تفاوت بین هم‏دوره‏ها تحت‏تأثیر متغیر تحصیلات است. با ورود این متغیر، شدت رابطۀ ارزش فرزند و هم‏دوره به‏طور درخور توجهی کم می‏شود. با‏این‏حال، تفاوت در میانگین ارزش فرزند در دوره‏های مختلف، همچنان به لحاظ آماری معنادار باقی می‏ماند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش فرزند</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">باروری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل طبقه‏بندی چندگانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سمنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">متولدان هم‏دوره (کوهورت تولد)</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_52357_3991a8d20aa651a8aa29be41f20d2e9c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
