<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2005</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Women in First Centuries of Islamic Society</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>زنان در نخستین سده های اسلامی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19197</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>صادق  آئینه</FirstName>
					<LastName>وند</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد تاریخ اسلام دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>: In this article the presence of women in Islamic society has been addressed. Women has been discussed in three social, economic, and scientific areas. The relation between the Islamic jurisdiction and social presence of women has been studied based on the act and tradition of the Prophet and Imams. Moreover, this article examines how much the Islamic rulers adhere to the Islamic acts and traditions. The author tried to make distinction between what has been resulted from the rulers&#039; acts and what is related to the essence of Islam.
The findings show that there is no band on women&#039;s presence based on Islamic tradition. So it can be concluded that Islam has emphasized on women&#039;s social participation in Islamic society.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">موضوع این مقاله، حضور زن در جامعه اسلامی است. زن در سه حوزة علمی، اجتماعی و اقتصادی مورد بحث قرار گرفته و رابطة بین نگاه حاکمیت اسلامی بر مبنای عمل به سیرة نبوی و علوی و حضور اجتماعی زن و برعکس فاصلة حاکمان از عمل به سیره مورد توجه این مقاله بوده است. نویسنده سعی داشته که بین آنچه در میراث و تمدّن اسلامی که حاصل عملکرد حاکمان است، با آنچه اصل اسلام و بر مبنای عمل به سیرة نبوی و علوی است، فرق نهد. در نتیجه، حاصل پژوهش مُبیّن عدم منع برای حضور اجتماعی زنان است و با استناد به سیره، می‌توان گفت، حضور زن در جامعة اسلامی مورد تأیید و تأکید بوده است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جامعه اسلامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عصر نبوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عصر علوی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیره</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_19197_1820eee4f9240ab2c2033777d23c6a49.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
