<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2008</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Study on Social and Cultural Factors Related to the Participation Level of Rural Women</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>عوامل فرهنگی و اجتماعی مرتبط با میزان مشارکت زنان روستایی در امور و مسائل خانوادگی و اجتماعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">27307</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا  صفری</FirstName>
					<LastName>شالی</LastName>
<Affiliation>? مدرس جهاد دانشگاهی، کارشناس ارشد در دو رشته توسعه روستایی و برنامه¬ریزی رفاه اجتماعی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The general purpose of the present study is to investigate the social and cultural factors related to the participation level of rural women in familial and meta-familial (social, political, economic and cultural) issues. The study is carried out using documental and fieldwork (questionnaire) methods. The theoretical framework of the study is based on pattern variables of Parsons and gender stratification theories of Randal Collins and Janet Chaftz. 
The total population of the present study consists of women aged between 15 to 65 years old in rural regions of Zanjan province. Based on Cochran sampling formula, 500 of total population are selected as the sample size. Results show that about 21% of women have low participation in familial and meta-familial issues; whereas about 25% of women have a high level of participation, and only 35% of women have a medium level of participation. Results of path-analysis reveal that women&#039;s social and economic status is among the key variables that can influence their participation; (considering two dimensions of participation including culture and behavior). In other words, as the social and economic status of women ascends, their participation level rises considerably.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف کلی تحقیق حاضر، بررسی عوامل فرهنگی و اجتماعی مرتبط با میزان مشارکت زنان روستایی در مسائل و امور خانوادگی و فرا خانوادگی (اجتماعی، سیاسی، اقتصادی و فرهنگی)  می‌باشد. مبنای نظری بر اساس متغیرهای الگویی «تالکوت پارسونز» و نظریات قشربندی جنسیتی «راندال کالینز و جانت چفز» قرار گرفته‌است. برای اجرای پژوهش حاضر از دو روش اسنادی و میدانی (پرسشنامه) استفاده شد. جامعه آماری این تحقیق شامل زنان بین 15 تا 65 سال مناطق روستایی استان زنجان بوده که با استفاده از فرمول نمونه‌گیری کوکران، تعداد 500 نفر از زنان مذکور به عنوان حجم نمونه انتخاب شدند. یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد که در حدود 21 درصد از زنان، میزان مشارکت کم یا پایین در مسائل و امور خانوادگی و فرا خانوادگی (عرصه اجتماع) داشته و در مقابل حدود 25 درصد میزان مشارکت بالایی داشته‌اند و در این میان حدود 53 درصد از زنان از سطح مشارکت متوسط برخوردار بوده‌اند. نتایج تحلیل مسیر نشان می‌د‌هد که پایگاه اقتصادی و اجتماعی زنان از جمله متغیرهای کلیدی است که می‌تواند بر میزان مشارکت آنها (در دو بُعد فرهنگ مشارکتی و رفتار مشارکتی)  تأثیر قابل ملاحظه‌ای داشته باشد، یعنی با بالا رفتن پایگاه اقتصادی و اجتماعی زنان روستایی میزان مشارکت آنها به‌طور فزاینده‌ای بالا می‌رود.</OtherAbstract>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_27307_b840e0d52f7f1e27a312bee51482fe34.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
