<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Status and Role-Relaxed models Consumption Patterns among Students of University of Isfahan</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی الگوهای مصرفی دانشجویان دختر دانشگاه اصفهان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>155</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>180</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22991</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بهرام</FirstName>
					<LastName>رنجبریان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مدیریت دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کاظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>ذبیح زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مجتبی</FirstName>
					<LastName>براری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مدیریت بازرگانی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today consumption has turned to be one of the most important concepts in our modern world. Although it used to be a way to satisfy basic needs of humans in the past, it can be regarded as a social phenomenon in which individuals are trying satisfy their multiple needs. Despite the importance of women’s consumption patterns there is no precise information in this regard. Thus the main purpose of this study is to investigate the parameters of status consumption and role-relaxed consumption as well as to study the effect of personal and social factors, inclination to be unique, to be impressed by others, and to notice the social comparison information on status oriented consumption and role-relaxed consumption. 
This is a descriptive study conducted through a survey. The statistical population of the study is girl students of university of Isfahan. The sample size was estimated to be 369 and data gathering has been done by classified random sampling. The data gathering instrument was questionnaire. Results indicate that respondents’ consumption pattern complies with the status consumption, also personal factors (tendency to uniqueness) have positive effect on status consumption and social factors (consumers’ susceptibility to interpersonal influence and attention to social comparison information) have negative effect on role-relaxed consumption.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه مصرف به یکی از اساسی ترین مفاهیم جامعه مدرن تبدیل شده است، به گونه ای که می توان آن را پدیده ای اجتماعی تلقی نمود که نیازهای چندگانه افراد را برآورده می سازد. با وجود چنین  اهمیتی، در مورد الگوهای مصرفی زنان در ایران به وی‍ژه دانشجویان دختر،اطلاعات دقیقی در این زمینه وجود ندارد. لذا هدف اصلی تحقیق حاضر بررسی الگوی مصرف منزلت گرا و مصرف بی توجه به نقش در بین دانشجویان دختر دانشگاه اصفهان است،همچنین این نوشتار درصدد است تا تاثیر عوامل فردی( تمایل به منحصر به فرد بودن) و عوامل اجتماعی( تاثیرپذیری از دیگران و توجه به اطلاعات مقایسه اجتماعی)را برالگوهای مصرفی دانشجویان دختر بسنجد. تحقیق حاضر با روش پیمایشی انجام شده و ابزار جمع‌آوری داده‌ها ،پرسشنامه است. نمونه آماری این پژوهش 369 دانشجوی دختر مشغول به تحصیل در دانشگاه اصفهان بوده و نمونه‌گیری به شیوه تصادفی طبقه‌ بندی انجام شده است. یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد که الگوی مصرفی افراد نمونه ، در انتخاب و مصرف محصولات، متمایل به الگوی مصرف منزلت‌گرا بوده است. همچنین عوامل فردی (تمایل به منحصر به فرد بودن) و اجتماعی (توجه به اطلاعات مقایسه اجتماعی) تأثیر مثبتی بر مصرف منزلت‌گرا دارند، در زمینه مصرف بی‌توجه به نقش نیز عوامل فردی (تمایل به منحصر به فرد بودن) و عوامل اجتماعی (تأثیرپذیری از دیگران و توجه به اطلاعات مقایسه اجتماعی) تأثیر منفی بر این الگوی مصرفی داشته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوهای مصرفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشجویان دختر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار مصرف کننده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مصرف بی توجه به نقش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مصرف منزلت‌گرا</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_22991_246b026f692b655e49d346faceaeb564.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
