<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2004</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>عوامل مؤثر بر مشارکت اقتصادی زنان ایران
با استفاده از مدل رگراسیونی داده های پانلی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">13275</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرزایی</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Women&#039;s social and economic participation is considered to be an important development indicator. In developing countries, however, social and cultural factors have limited the opportunity for women&#039;s participation in social and economic structures. This paper examines the factors which promote the rate of participation by women in the labor market within the provinces of Iran. The methodology applied is a regression model utilizing panel data. The results indicate; factors influencing the women&#039;s participation in the labor market include level of education, the incentive to gain income, and the rate of male unemployment. Negative factors include rural-urban migration (the rate of urbanization), rate of women&#039;s unemployment, and the birthrate. The trend of women&#039;s participation in the labor market of Iran is V-shaped in which has experienced an upward turn in recent years.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از معیارهای ارزیابی کشور ها از نظر توسعه، میزان حضور و مشارکت زنان در فعالیت های اجتماعی و اقتصادی است. در کشورهای در حال توسعه ، به دلایل مختلف فرهنگی و اجتماعی، زمینه های مشارکت زنان در ساختارهای اجتماعی و اقتصادی محدود شده است. در این پژوهش سعی بر آن است تا عوامل مؤثر در نرخ مشارکت زنان ایران در بازار کار به صورت تاریخی و در بین استان های کشور مورد بررسی همه جانبه قرار گیرد. کاربرد مدل رگرسیونی داده های پانلی نشان می دهد که مهم ترین عوامل مؤثر در حضور زنان در بازار کار سطح آموزش ،انگیزه کسب درآمد مالی و نرخ بیکاری مردان با اثر مثبت؛ و پدیده مهاجرت از روستا به شهر(درجه شهری شدن)، نرخ بیکاری زنان و نرخ زاد و ولد با اثر منفی است که هریک با ضرایب ویژه ای در نرخ مشارکت زنان تأثیر می گذارند.روند مشارکت زنان در بازار کار ایران به صورت یک منحنی سهمی شکل است که در سال های اخیر سیر صعودی به خود گرفته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آموزش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">باروری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بیکاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دستمزد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_13275_10823427b472fc3b6efe021eded4b866.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
