<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Study of Cultural Conceptualization of Marriage and Childbearing among Women in Tehran: with a Cognitive Sociolinguistics Approach</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی مفهوم‌سازی فرهنگی ازدواج و فرزندآوری در میان زنان شهر تهران: با رویکرد جامعه شناسی زبانی-شناختی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>359</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>377</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68853</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2018.247109.1007322</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیلیا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نرسسیانس</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مردم‏ شناسی، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابراهیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>فیاض</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه مردم‏ شناسی، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>لیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>اردبیلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مردم ‏شناسی، دانشکدة علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>02</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Recent studies in the field of cognitive science on conceptual metaphor indicated that metaphor is not merely a linguistic phenomenon but it is essentially a conceptual-experimental process that constructs our mental world and is a means that reflects the origin of the cognitive structures of human thought. By examining the metaphorical conceptualization of marriage and childbearing widely used in Persian everyday language, the present study seeks to demonstrate how the study of conceptual metaphors, within the framework of sociolinguistics, can help us get a better understanding of collective representations and cultural cognition. To achieve this goal, the present study is to utilize ethnographic strategy and semi-structured interview from twenty married women between the ages of 50-70 in Tehran, has gained some common metaphors in the conceptualization of marriage and childbearing. Subsequently, based on the premises of Conceptual Metaphor Theory, these metaphors are analyzed qualitatively. The results show that such conceptual mappings bear theoretical significance for the study of metaphor in identifying collective representation and cultural cognition and help us to get a deeper understanding of cultural understanding of the concepts in a community.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تحقیقات اخیر در حوزة علوم‏شناختی دربارة استعارۀ مفهومی نشان داده‏اند که استعاره صرفاً یک پدیدة زبانی نیست، بلکه اساساً فرایندی مفهومی‏ـ تجربی است که جهان ذهنی ما را ساخت‌مند می‏کند و ابزاری است که منعکس‏کنندة منشأ ساختارهای شناختی تفکر انسان است. پژوهش حاضر بر آن است با بررسی مفهوم‏سازی‏های استعاری ازدواج و فرزند،که در کاربردهای زبان فارسی روزمره به‏وفور دیده می‏شوند، نشان دهد که چگونه بررسی استعاره‏های مفهومی در چارچوب زبان‏شناسی اجتماعی‏ـ شناختی می‏تواند ما را در درک بهتر بازنمایی‏های جمعی و شناخت فرهنگی ازدواج و فرزندآوری یاری رساند. برای رسیدن به این هدف، پژوهش حاضر با استفاده از راهبرد قوم‏نگاری و فن مصاحبه‏‏های نیمه‏ساخت‏یافته از زنان متأهل دارای فرزند، بین سنین 50 تا 70 سالِ ساکن شهر تهران، استعاره‏های رایج در مفهوم‏سازی ازدواج و فرزند را به‏دست آورده و در ادامه با تکیه بر نظریة استعاره‏های مفهومی، آن‌ها را مورد تحلیل کیفی قرار داده است. نتایج نشان می‏دهند که استعاره‏های به‏دست‏آمده در بررسی بازنمایی جمعی و شناخت فرهنگی مفهوم ازدواج و فرزند معنادارند و به ما کمک می‏کنند به درک عمیقی از فهم فرهنگی این مفاهیم در جامعه دست یابیم.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ازدواج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استعارة مفهومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان‏شناسی اجتماعی‏ـ شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شناخت فرهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرزندآوری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_68853_0865de638989c482d48801548be06ea4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
