<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>17</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Challenges for Remarriage of Women with Children: A Qualitative Study</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>چالش ‏های ازدواج مجدد زنان با حضور فرزند: پژوهشی کیفی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>97</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>119</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">71924</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2019.275723.1007586</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رزگار</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری مشاورة خانواده، دانشگاه شهید چمران اهواز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد مشاورة خانواده، دانشگاه علامه طباطبائی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>08</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Marriage for the second time will be a big challenge if any of the man or woman or both have children. In this case, there will be challenging factors including various cultural, economic, traditions and beliefs and many other problems. Even the existence of a child will be one of the main reasons for preventing them from marriage. Therefore, the purpose of this study is to examine the experience of the challenges of re-marriage with the presence of children and to identify its final structure in the participants who had experienced that. In this research, a qualitative descriptive phenomenological research has been directed to collect and evaluate information about the challenges of re-marriage with the presence of the children. Fourteen subjects who experienced remarriage in their married life were selected through targeted sampling and data collection was conducted through semi-structured interviews. Data analysis has revealed 4 main themes (themes) and 10 sub-themes (categories). These are including: &quot;Perceiving the problems of having a child&quot; with categories of, behavioral problems and children&#039;s adaptation, the presence of the child as an obstacle, the acceptance or rejection of the child of the remarriage; economic and financial dimension with the categories of the importance of economic dimension and the necessity of financial management; social and cultural dimensions with categories of social and cultural inefficiencies, interference of those around them, social facilitation or inhibition; and requirements for re-marriage with the categories of facilitators and importance of proper behaviors and understanding of the spouse. The results of this research have indicated that this is a multidimensional phenomenon with individual, economic, social, cultural and family dimensions. The findings of this study expanded the limited literature on the experience of re-marriage with the presence of the child. Also, the structure of the challenges posed by this study in the field of paternity treatment and premarital counseling has many implications for preventing marital dissatisfaction and increasing marital and family success. </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">ازدواج دوباره چالش بزرگی خواهد بود؛ زمانی که یکی از طرفین یا هردو دارای فرزند باشند. در این صورت، عوامل مختلف فرهنگی، اقتصادی، سنت و عقاید و بسیاری عوامل دیگر چالش‌زا می‌شود و حتی وجود فرزند یکی از دلایل اصلی بر جلوگیری از آن خواهد بود. از‌این‏‌رو، هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی تجربة چالش‏های ازدواج مجدد با حضور فرزندان و مشخص‌کردن ساختار نهایی آن در مشارکت‏کنندگانی بود که تجربة این پدیده را داشتند. در این پژوهش، برای جمع‏آوری و ارزیابی اطلاعات دربارة چالش‏های ازدواج مجدد با حضور فرزند از پژوهش کیفی پدیدارشناسی توصیفی استفاده ‏شده است. چهارده مشارکت‏کننده، که ازدواج مجدد را در زندگی زناشویی خود تجربه کرده بودند، به روش نمونه‏گیری هدفمند انتخاب شدند و جمع‏آوری داده‏ها از طریق مصاحبة نیمه‌ساختاریافته با آن‏ها تا رسیدن داده‏ها به اشباع ادامه یافت. تحلیل داده‏ها به ۴ درون‏مایة اصلی (تم) و ۱۰ درون‏مایة فرعی (مقوله) منتهی شد. این درون‏مایه‏ها عبارت‌اند از: «ادراک مشکلات حضور فرزند» با درون‏مایه‏های فرعی: مشکلات رفتاری و سازگاری فرزندان، حضور فرزند به‏عنوان مانع، پذیرفتن یا نپذیرفتن ازدواج مجدد از جانب فرزند؛ حضور بعد اقتصادی و مالی با درون‏مایه‏های فرعی: اهمیت بعد اقتصادی و لزوم مدیریت مالی؛ حضور ابعاد اجتماعی و فرهنگی با درون‏مایه‏های فرعی: باورهای کارآمد و ناکارآمد اجتماعی و فرهنگی، دخالت اطرافیان، تسهیل‌گری یا بازداری اجتماعی و ملزومات ازدواج مجدد با درون‏مایه‏های فرعی: همبسته‏های تسهیل‏کننده و اهمیت رفتارهای مناسب و درک همسر. نتایج این پژوهش نشان می‏دهد ازدواج مجدد پدیدة چندبعدی با ابعاد فردی، اقتصادی، اجتماعی، فرهنگی و خانوادگی با چالش‏های گوناگون است. یافته‏های این پژوهش ادبیات محدود گذشته درزمینة تجربة ازدواج مجدد با حضور فرزند را گسترش می‏دهد. همچنین ساختار چالش‏های استخراج‏شدة این مطالعه در زمینة زوج‏درمانی و مشاورة پیش از ازدواج این شکل از ازدواج دارای تلویحات کاربردی فراوان برای پیشگیری از ناخشنودی زناشویی و افزایش موفقیت زناشویی و خانوادگی آن‏هاست.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ازدواج مجدد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پدیدارشناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">چالش‏های ازدواج مجدد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حضور فرزند</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_71924_bd809322194c86a85f6a81d75265968a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
