<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Self-control, Gender, and the Impacts on the Deviant Behaviors]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Aliverdinia, Akbar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Saleh nejad, Saleh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crime.]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[deviant behaviors]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Diversion opportunity]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Gender]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Self-Control]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Crime patterns and styles show that crime is a gendered phenomenon. This study seeks to explain the gender gaps in deviant behaviors, using the general theory of crime and analyses the role of self-control in deviant behaviors of boys and girls. The present research was carried out through survey method and a statistical sample of 420 students of Orumieh University in the academic year of 2010- 2011 was included in this study. The results of the mean difference test show that access to diversion opportunities and participation in deviant behaviors of the two genders are significantly different and the self-control mean of the two genders has been different, though not significantly. Moreover, the results of multivariate regression show that three variations of self-control, diversion opportunity, and the gender of respondents have significant impacts on their participation in deviant behaviors. Self-control variation, among three other main variables in this research, stands as the strongest predictor of boys’ and girls’ deviant behaviors.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24416_c5d85a711839200ff1dde74de8af7be2.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Gender Equality in Iris Marion Young’s Theory of Differentiated Citizenship]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Tavana, Mohammad ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[communicative-participatory democracy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Difference]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Differentiated Citizenship]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Equality]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Women]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Women’s issues are among basic issues of contemporary society which have been offered different solutions. While the first- wave feminists would insist on the gender equality, the second wave would emphasize that women differ from men. The third wave tried to hold on to both sides of the conundrum: equality and difference. Iris Marion Young is one of the theorists of the third wave of feminism who presented the theory of Differentiated Citizenship. Through Consultative Democracy theory of Habermas and Foucault’s theory of Marginalized and Oppressed Groups she tried to plan a type of communicative-participatory democracy in order for women and other oppressed and deprived groups to fully and equally participate with others while maintaining their differences in public areas. On this very basis, the present research analyses Young’s Theory of Differentiated Citizenship to show the extent of success of the theory in offering an alternative solution to the issues of women and deprived social groups.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24417_e42f5f7401395ffb98a9d6342cdbe9c1.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Audience and television programs: women readings of television commercials]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bahar, Mehri]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[haji mohammadi, Ali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[cultural studies]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[gender roles]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[reading]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Representation]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[television]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[television commercials]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[woman]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Portraying women in the media is one of the main social and cultural issues especially on television.  Television commercials as a genre have ideas about goods and services, but it constructs a secondary discourse about society, culture and gender roles along the way. The main goal of this paper is to examine women’s readings of gender roles representation in Iranian television commercials from the cultural studies perspective. To achieve this objective, focus group interviews were used to study women readings and then their readings was analyzed. The results showed that television commercials are heedless of socio-cultural developments and the gender roles changes in different aspects in the society, but it represents dominant ideology in media and minimal status group of woman in Iranian society. 
 Currently, different groups of women are engaged in different discourses and they will gradually engage in other discourses. If this trend continues by different groups of women and the misrepresentation or exclusion of women doesn’t stop in the media, the audiences with different readings will become the most rethinking groups.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24418_305893b62d3f78f41800f32d522c8a2c.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Leisure, Cultural capital, and Women (Case Study of Juybar Town)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ebrahimi, Ghorbanali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[moslemi petroodi, roghayeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cultural Capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[leisure]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[leisure activities.]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Social capital]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Women]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The way people spend their leisure is a reflection of social, economic, and cultural capital in any given society. The present research studies the influence of cultural capital on leisure using survey method. Instrument used to collect data has been: questionnaire. The statistical population constitutes all women living in the city of Juybar  aged 15-64. Based on the results of the latest census of Statistical Center of Iran, 1385, total women’s population in Juybar was 25325. Using multistage cluster sampling, a sample size of 378 was chosen based on the formula of Cochran. The results show that the average women’s participation in active leisure (1.91 out of 4) is more than women’s participation in passive leisure (1.3 out of 4). Women's participation in leisure activities in this study’s population is lower than average. Multivariate linear regression results show that out of the three dimensions of cultural capital, two dimensions (objective structured and institutionalized cultural capital) have a significant effect on leisure.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24419_d92fc5d365571751fefe2424a48e4996.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Comparative Effectiveness of Group Consultation of Reality Therapy and Feminism on Identity of Women Headed Families]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[shafi abady, Abdollah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[gholamhosein ghashghaei, fahimeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Group feminist therapy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Group reality therapy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Householder women.]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Identity]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The present research aims to compare the impact of group consultation on the basis of two approaches of reality therapy and feminism over the identity changes of householder women. Statistical society has been the whole community of householder women who receive support from Imam Khomeini Relief Committee in fifth District of Tehran, which was randomly selected. Research tool has been Indigenous Crisis Questionnaire (ICQ). 42 women out of 80 householder ones were selected randomly through matching up their identity and were divided into three groups. 14 women were placed in experiment group with reality therapy approach. 14 ones in experiment group with feminist approach (1 loss was witnessed) and 14 of them were placed in control group. 9 consultation meetings were held for reality therapy group, and 10 for feminist group. The data of both groups were collected and Sceffe post hoc analysis of variance test was performed to evaluate the impact of group consultation on both groups and the result was analyzed. As a result both consultation meetings- reality therapy and feminist- had impacts on alteration of householder women’s identity without any significant differences between impacts on the two groups.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24420_0a93a3472619c4e782383018e30df777.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Women's Indigenous Knowledge in Process of Sustainable Development of Farming]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Afshar zade, Nashmil]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[pap zan, Abdolhamid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[farming]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Indigenous Knowledge]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Kalhor tribe]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Kermanshah.]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[nomad woman]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Qualitative research]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sustainable Development]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In recent years sustainable development has been one of the concerns of man. To address this concern farming sustainable development will be one of the most important issues which must be dealt with. It seems that one of the necessary elements to further this goal is to have a serious look at indigenous knowledge of farming and particularly women’s knowledge. Women and above all nomad women have admirable indigenous knowledge of farming: dairy farming, and dairy products which is worth of being registered and preserved because it can be practiced to provide food and sustainable development as humanitarian development.  
This qualitative study was conducted to detect and document the indigenous knowledge of migrant women of Kalhor tribe about dairy farming. Geographical area was Gilan-e-Gharb Township, Kermanshah province. Focus Groups technique was employed to collect data. Purposive sampling was used and the collected data was analyzed through content analysis.   The results show that nomad women have impressive knowledge of farm animal nourishment, veterinary, producing dairy and non dairy products returnable to the nature and by learning this knowledge we can have a step forward to sustainable farming.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24421_7eea202a517f907c194711a688fed1e3.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[The Relationship between Self-Confidence and Performance of Amateur and Professional Woman Footballers on their Anxiety of Competition]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Esfahani, Nooshin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[ghezel Sefloo, Hamid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Competitive Anxiety]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Futsal player]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[performance]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Self-confidence]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Women.]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Anxiety of sports is one of the variables which is closely related to sports performance and happens in sports competitions. Considering the negative effects of competitive anxiety on performance of athletes this study tries to compare competitive anxiety of amateur or professional female futsal players and its connection with self confidence and sports performance. The statistical population of this study was 77 university students who were futsal players participating in academic tournaments. 56 of them were randomly placed in amateur group and 21 students were purposively placed in professional group. To assess the level of competitive anxiety of samples, a questionnaire of competitive-state anxiety (CSAI-2) was used. Three subscales of the questionnaire, subjective anxiety, somatic anxiety and self-confidence are assessed by a Likert scale value. In order to analyze the data after Calmograph Smirnoff test, a “t” test and Pearson correlation coefficient were used. The results of the study showed that there are significant differences between competitive anxiety (physical and mental symptoms, and self-confidence) of academic and club futsal players. A direct relationship was also found between competitive anxiety and performance in female futsal players.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24422_599be9c08ee7053e1fe512794d8842cf.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>