<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The effective determinants in willingness to cesarean section (The case of pregnant women in Tehran)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تعیین‌کننده‌های موثر بر تمایل به سزارین (مطالعۀ موردی: زنان باردار شهر تهران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>357</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>376</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56336</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2015.56336</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خلیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>علی محمدزاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار رشتة مدیریت خدمات بهداشتی و درمانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران شمال، رئیس مرکز تحقیقات سیاست‌گذاری اقتصاد سلامت</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پریوش</FirstName>
					<LastName>افرادی اسبقرانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت خدمات بهداشتی و درمانی، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تهران شمال</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Based on statistical evidence, rate of cesarean   in Iran is quite high ranking Iran  the second country in the world; in terms of the highest cesarean rates,  various parameters affect  decision of  delivery mode  in pregnant women. One way to reduce caesarean sections is to identify these factors and their impacts. The aim of this study is to identify factors affecting willingness to cesarean section in pregnant women and the correlation between them to reduce the willingness to C-section. This study was examined in a cross-sectional way by means of stochastic and available selection procedure, within the second half of 2014, on pregnant women who live in Tehran. In the semi-structured survey with the answer package (5 point Likert scale), five effective factors to predict   willingness to cesarean were examined  including psychological, environmental and socio-cultural factors, as well as conditions and outcomes of childbirth;  structural equation modeling (SEM) method and Amossoftware were utilized in order to confirm the parameters. Among the 5 factors affecting willingness to cesarean section in pregnant women, &quot;fear of natural childbirth&quot;  related to psychological factors and the component &quot;Not to put pressure on the baby&#039;s head&quot; and &quot;no shoulder dislocation  other physical damages” caused by Caesarean section related to the consequences of childbirth, have the greatest impact. Also the results of this study demonstrated that the highest and lowest correlations are related to conditions and consequences and socio-cultural and psychological factors respectively. Therefore, we can help pregnant women to recognize their capabilities and overcome their fear of pain by improving the level of pregnant women’s awareness and using natural vaginal delivery techniques with lower pain.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">براساس شواهد آماری نرخ سزارین در ایران بسیار بالاست. پارامترهای گوناگون در تصمیم‌گیری زنان باردار دربارۀ انتخاب روش زایمان تأثیر دارند. پژوهش حاضر با هدف شناسایی عوامل تأثیرگذار بر میزان تمایل به سزارین در زنان باردار و میزان همبستگی بین این عوامل به منظور کمک به کاهش تمایل به سزارین انجام شده است. این مطالعه به صورت مقطعی در بین زنان باردار ساکن شهر تهران و به روش انتخاب تصادفی و در دسترس انجام شد. در پرسش‌نامۀ محقق‌ساخته، پنج عامل تأثیرگذار در پیش‌بینی تمایل به سزارین شامل: عوامل روان‌شناختی، محیطی، اجتماعی‌ـ فرهنگی، شرایط و پیامدهای زایمان، بررسی شده و برای تأیید مؤلفه‌ها از روش مدل‌سازی معادلات ساختاری و نرم‌افزار آموس بهره گرفته شده است. در بین 5 مؤلفۀ یادشده، «ترس از زایمان طبیعی» مربوط به عوامل روان‌شناختی و مؤلفۀ «تحت فشار قرار نگرفتن سر نوزاد» و «عدم دررفتگی شانه یا وارد آمدن سایر آسیب‌های جسمی به نوزاد» در روش سزارین مربوط به پیامدهای زایمان، بیشترین تأثیر را داشته‌اند. همچنین، عوامل مربوط به «شرایط زایمان» و «پیامدهای زایمان» بیشترین همبستگی و کمترین همبستگی مربوط به عوامل «روان‌شناختی» و «اجتماعی‌ـ فرهنگی» را داشت. بنابراین، با ارتقای سطح آگاهی زنان باردار از مراحل بارداری و زایمان و استفاده از تکنیک‌های زایمان طبیعی با درد کمتر، می‌توان به بهبود شناخت زنان باردار از توانمندی‌های خود و غلبۀ آن‌ها بر ترس کمک کرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تمایل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زایمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان باردار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سزارین</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_56336_5ab914a3ff83f6fda8ae7ae59d5d5217.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
