<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Relationship between Digital Divide and Empowerment of Shiraz Women</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سنجش رابطۀ شکاف دیجیتالی و توانمندی زنان شهر شیراز</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>21</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>38</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">51345</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2014.51345</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>بیژن</FirstName>
					<LastName>خواجه نوری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار جامعه‌شناسی دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>کریمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد جامعه‌شناسی دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعید</FirstName>
					<LastName>کشاورزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری جامعه‌شناسی دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>13</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Abstract &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Women as half of the population of each society have important role in societies development. Accordingly, many sociologists consider study of women’s empowerment and its influencing factors. Present study is to examine the relationship between digital divide and women empowerment. In addition, women empowerment and its dimensions (access and control of resources, participation, gender awareness, mobility and security) were investigated. Also these independent variables: marital Status, respondents and their families’ Income, social class, Education level of respondents and their spouses, Head of household status, employment status, occupation, age, technology divide, information access divide, information literacy divide were investigated. By virtue of multistage random sampling, 600 ones were selected based on leen formula. Required Datas were collected from Shiraz women aged 15-54 by means of questionnaires based on survey method. The study findings indicated variables: social status, respondent and husband education, technology divide, and information literacy divide and information access had a significant relation with the women empowerment; while marital status had no significant relationship with women empowerment. Multiple regression showed that 27 percent of the variance of women empowerment variable was explained through the independent variables (information literacy divide, respondents under Graduate Diploma).</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">توانمندی راهی برای دیده‌شدن زنان، همچون اعضای برابر جامعه، است که در‌عین‌حال می‌تواند نقش مهمی در توسعۀ جوامع ایفا کند. بر همین اساس، بررسی توانمندی زنان و عوامل مؤثر بر آن مورد توجه بسیاری از جامعه‌شناسان قرار گرفته است. هدف پژوهش حاضر، بررسی رابطة شکاف دیجیتالی و توانمندی زنان شهر شیراز است. توانمندی زنان با مؤلفه‏های دسترسی و کنترل بر منابع، مشارکت در تصمیم‌گیری، آگاهی جنسیتی، تحرک، و امنیت بررسی شد. متغیرهای مستقلی که در این پژوهش بررسی شدند نیز عبارت‌اند از: طبقة اجتماعی، تحصیلات پاسخگو، تحصیلات همسر، شکاف فنّاوری، شکاف سواد اطلاعاتی، و شکاف دسترسی به اطلاعات. برای این پژوهش، نمونه‏ای به حجم 600 نفر با روش نمونه‏گیری لین و با شیوة نمونه‏گیری تصادفی چند‌مرحله‏ای انتخاب شد. اطلاعات مورد نیاز با تکنیک پیمایش و ابزار پرسشنامه، از بین زنان 15ـ54 سالة شهر شیراز جمع‏آوری شد. نتایج پژوهش نشان داد که متغیرهای طبقۀ اجتماعی، تحصیلات پاسخگو و همسر، شکاف فنّاوری، شکاف سواد اطلاعاتی، و دسترسی به اطلاعات با توانمندی زنان رابطة معناداری دارند. نتایج حاصل از رگرسیون چند‌متغیره نشان داد که به ترتیب متغیر‌های شکاف سواد اطلاعاتی و تحصیلات زیر دیپلم حدود 27‌درصد از تغییرات متغیر توانمندی زنان را تبیین کرده‏اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شکاف دیجیتالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شیراز</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_51345_f5398b6d75501dc8b962765d97ff5b23.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
