<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2004</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطه کار / خانواده: تفاوت های جنسیتی در برخورداری از حمایت اجتماعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">13262</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیر رستگار</FirstName>
					<LastName>خالد</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The emergence of families with two income sources (employment of husband and wife) is one of the important social changes in Iran. This type of family, despite benefiting from a blending of roles, is faced with certain pressures, which stem from traditional division of labor within the family and new responsibilities of its members. If the conflict is not properly managed, have a negative impact on the social unity and functions of the family as well as the emotional and social health of the members. This paper identifies the impact of social support as one of the resources for addressing the conflict of work/family and gender-based expectations in two income families. The findings of a surrey conducted in Tehran demonstrate that the strategies chosen for addressing the conflict of work and family tend to be influenced by traditional gender roles. Additionally, the study indicates; women prefer to receive family support in addressing the
pressures, while men choose professional support systems as a means of addressing the conflict.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پیدایش و افزایش خانواده های دو شغله که در آن زن و شوهر هر دو شاغل و دارای درآمد هستند، از تحولات اجتماعی کشور است. این سبک از زندگی خانوادگی به رغم بهره مندی از فواید ترکیب نقش، به دلیل نادیده گرقتن تقسیم سنتی کار در خانواده و نیز پذیرش و ایفای تعهدات بیشتر و جدیدتر، با فشارهایی مواجه است. یکی از این فشارها، تعارض کار / خانواده است که چنانچه مدیریت نشود، می تواند پیامدهای ناخواسته بر انسجام اجتماعی و کارکردهای خانواده و نیز سلامت روانی و اجتماعی اعضای آن داشته باشد. این مقاله ضمن شناسایی تأثیر حمایت اجتماعی به نوان یک منبع مقابله با فشار و سازو کارهای آن، بع انتظارات ناشی از نقش های جنسیتی می پردازد. به همین منظور پژوهشی به روش پیمایشی، با انتخاب نمونه های تصادفی از خانواده دو شغله شهر تهران انجام شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان می دهد که دلایل بروز تعارض کار / خانواده و انتخاب راه های مقابله با آن، متأثر از الگوی سنتی تقسیم کار جنسیتی است. زنان به برخورداری از حمایت خانوادگی تمایل دارند و مردان حمایت شغلی را برای مقابله با فشار بر می گزینند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتغال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حمایت اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خانواده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شغل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کار</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_13262_578113f131fac0d15ec8d4f50b7d2d5d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
