<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>6</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2003</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>گروه های زنان در حرکت تواناسازی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">11359</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName></FirstName>
					<LastName>Unknown</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This article considers women’s struggle as a part of the social movement emphasizing classical and modern perspectives. It also attempts to examine the factors which are inhibiting women, forcing them to call for change of their conditions. In the 90s, social movement thinkers emphasized the interaction process in social movements and social structures. In this view, instead of emphasizing strategies, they examined rehabilitation and changes of social identities of group members. Based on the feminist definition of the women’s movement, the need for change is common among all women and emphasis could be made on the demand for change in a framework that creates social sensitivity about women’s issues and their hidden needs. The activist groups of women can be categorized under four groups: 1. Women who are on the fringes of power. 2. Women in mass media. 3. Women at the universities. 4. Women in general. The author considers the basic challenges of Iranian women’s social movement to be: A pretentious backing of women, misconception about feminism, irrelevant support of women, lack of common language and interaction among activists in modern NGOs and traditional groups.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این مقاله به موضوع جنبش زنان بعنوان جنبشی اجتماعی پرداخته و دیدگاه های کلاسیک و مدرن جنبش اجتماعی را بیان کرده است همچنین این پرسش اصلی مطرح شده است که خواست تغییر و نارضایتی زنان ایران از وضع خویش پیرامون چه محدودیت هایی شکل گرفته است نظریه پردازان جنبش اجتماعی در آغاز دهه 90 به فرایند کنش متقابل میان اعضای درگیر در جنبش اجتماعی و سازه های اجتماعی توجه نشان دادند از دیدگاه آنها این جنبش ها به جای تاکید براستراتژی به بازسازی و تغییر هویت اجتماعی اعضای خود تاکید دارند بنا بر تعاریف فمینیستی از جنبش زنان خواست تغییر در دهه زنان مشترک است و برای تغییر می توان به خواسته های آشکار و خواسته های پنهان اشاره کرد گروه های زنان درگیر با مسائل زنان در ایرن عبارتند از گروه زنان در حاشیه قدرت گروه زنان در رسانه های جمعی گروه زنان در سطح دانشگاهی و گروه زنان در سطح عامه طرفداری نمایش از زنان کج فهمی از فمینیسم و طرفداری نادرست از زنان نبود زبان مشترک و تعامل پویا میان فعالان سازمان های غیردولتی مدرن و تشکل های سنتی زنان چالش های پیش روی جنبش زنان در ایرن را تکشیل می دهند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنبش های اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فمینیسم</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_11359_6cedfc8f1df97a36ec5614afee877232.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
