<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Sociological study of the concept of money for women in the family (Case study: Tabriz married women)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی جامعه‌شناختی مفهوم پول برای زنان در خانواده (مطالعة موردی: زنان متأهل شهر تبریز)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>325</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>344</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53686</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2014.53686</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جهانگیر</FirstName>
					<LastName>جهانگیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار بخش جامعه‌شناسی دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>وحید</FirstName>
					<LastName>کشافی نیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد جامعه‌شناسی دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>10</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The main purpose of this research is to study the concept of money for women in the family, in sociological prespective. The case sudy of the research was Tabriz married women. In doing so, we have used Viviena Zelizer’s Special monies approach as theoritical framework. In order to ghather data we have used the survey technique. This study has been done upon 400 married women in the Tabriz city, Iran. The findings of research show that the concept of money for 61.8 percent of women is family-oriented, for 31.5 percent is self-family-oriented, and for 6.7 percent of women is self-oriented. Also, results show that variables edjucation, employment status, income, social and economic status, money allocation system in family have a significant relationship with concept of money for women in the family, but there is no relationship between variable age and independent variable. The result of stepwise regression showed that three factors explain the variance of the total by 36.4 percent, respectively.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مطالعة حاضر با هدف بررسی جامعه‌شناختی مفهوم پول برای زنان در خانواده با تمرکز بر زنان متأهل شهر تبریز انجام گرفته است. برای این منظور، از رهیافت پول‌های خاص زلیزر به‌منزلۀ چارچوب نظری استفاده شده است. این تحقیق با تکنیک پیمایشی انجام گرفته و حجم نمونه شامل 400 نفر از زنان متأهل شهر تبریز است. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد که برای 8&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;61درصد از زنان مطالعه‌شده مفهوم پول خانواده‌محور، 5&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;31درصد خودمحور/خانواده‌محور و 7&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;6درصد خودمحور است. بین متغیرهای میزان تحصیلات، وضعیت اشتغال، میزان درآمد، پایگاه اقتصادی و اجتماعی، و الگوهای تخصیص پول در خانواده با مفهوم پول برای زنان در خانواده رابطة معناداری وجود دارد، اما بین متغیر سن و مفهوم پول برای زنان در خانواده رابطة معناداری مشاهده نشد. نتایج حاصل از رگرسیون گام‌به‌گام نشان داد که از بین متغیرهای وارد‌شده در رگرسیون چندمتغیره به ترتیب متغیرهای میزان درآمد زن، پایگاه اقتصادی و اجتماعی، و وضعیت اشتغال باقی ماندند که در مجموع 4&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;36درصد از تغییرات واریانس متغیر وابسته را تبیین کردند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جامعه‌شناسی پول</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهیافت پول‌های خاص</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان متأهل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شهر تبریز</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مفهوم پول</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_53686_9563ad84c9d4aa087718425111bf71cd.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
