<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Rating Micro Credit Funds Based on Rural Women’s Ability in Kermanshah</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رتبه بندی صندوق های اعتبارات خرد بر اساس توانمندسازی زنان روستایی استان کرمانشاه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>105</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>124</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24771</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2012.24771</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کیومرث</FirstName>
					<LastName>زرافشانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیرحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>علی بیگی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مژگان</FirstName>
					<LastName>فقیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه رازی-کارشناس ارشد ترویج و آموزش</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Empowering rural women is one of the third millennium goals. To this end it was proposed to allot micro credits to rural women in order to provide the required capital to launch productive careers. Now after a decade from the establishment of micro credit funds in Iran, only few researches have been done to give a rank to them. The present research is conducted through survey method to rank micro credit funds based on empowering rural women of Kermanshah using Bartlett table and systematic random sampling for which 183 women members of this fund were selected. The ranking results show that from economic aspect: Fash (Kangavar), Tamarg, Pariveh (Mersin) have achieved the places first to third, in terms of empowering women goals. From social aspect: Fash, Pariveh and Gheitas Abad were placed first to third. From family aspect: members of Fash Fund, Pariveh, and Kooseh vand were ranked first to third. According to the results, since the authorities of the funds can play a key role in the success of funds it is recommended to the Office for Rural Women’s Affairs that the authorities of funds are selected based on the votes of the members and criteria like: education, age, etc.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">توانمندسازی زنان روستایی یکی از اهداف توسعه‌ هزاره ‌سوم است. در همین راستا طرح اعطای اعتبارات‌ خرد به زنان روستایی با هدف فراهم ساختن سرمایه لازم برای راه‌اندازی مشاغل تولیدی به‌منظور توانمندسازی آنان مطرح گردید. اکنون با وجود گذشت حدود یک دهه از عمر صندوق اعتبارات‌ خرد در ایران، مطالعات اندکی در زمینه رتبه‌بندی این صندوق‌ها انجام شده‌است. این پژوهش از نوع پیمایشی بوده که برای رتبه‌بندی صندوق‌های اعتبارات‌خرد بر اساس توانمندسازی زنان روستایی استان کرمانشاه، با استفاده از جدول بارتلت و روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی سیستماتیک، 183 نفر از زنان عضو این صندوق ها انتخاب گردیدند. رتبه‌بندی صندوق‌ها بر اساس توانمندسازی زنان از ابعاد مختلف ، بر اساس آماره تحلیل عامل تاییدی نشان می دهد که در بعد اقتصادی: فش (کنگاور)، تمرگ و پریوه (هرسین) رتبه‌های اول تا سوم را کسب نمودند. در بعد اجتماعی: فش، پریوه و قیطاس‌آباد (صحنه) رتبه‌ی اول تا سوم را به خود اختصاص دادند. در بعد خانوادگی اعضای صندوق‌های فش، پریوه و کوسه‌وند (کرمانشاه) به ترتیب در جایگاه‌های اول تا سوم قرار گرفتند. با توجه به نتایج به‌دست آمده، از ‌آنجایی‌که مسئولین صندوق‌ها می‌توانند نقش قابل توجهی را در موفقیت صندوق‌ها ایفا نمایند، توصیه می‌گردد انتخاب مسئولین صندوق بر اساس رأی‌ اعضا و تعیین معیارهایی همچون تحصیلات، سن و ... از سوی دفتر امورزنان روستایی باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل عاملی تأئیدی.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندسازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رتبه بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان روستایی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24771_b4f4e618fdd994afdf64f0bdfe515ac5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
