<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2002</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Girls’ Academic Achievements;</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>موفقیت تحصیلی دختران : مطالعه عوامل غیرشناختی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">26995</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یاسمین</FirstName>
					<LastName>عابدینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری روانشناسی تربیتی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This article presents the findings of a research on the relations between coping styles of crisis and socio-economic status of the family, as two important non-cognitive factors, and academic achievements of young female students. 328 third grade students were selected through multi-stage random sampling from junior schools of Tehran. Data on coping with crisis test (CISS) and grade point average are statistically analyzed. Results indicate a positive relation between &quot;problem-oriented coping style&quot; and academic achievement. Also socio-economic status of the family and academic achievement are related. There is no significant relation between &quot;coping style with stress” and academic achievement. It seems young girls with higher achievements apply more problem -oriented coping style while students with lower academic achievement have a stress coping mechanism.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به منظور بررسی رابطه راه های مقابله تنیدگی با پیشرفت تحصیلی و جایگاه اجتماعی - اقتصادی نوجوانان دختربه عنوان متغیر مهم غیرشناختی ، تعداد 328 دانش آموز دختر پایه سوم راهنمایی با روش نمونه گیری تصادفی مرحله ای از مدارس راهنمایی جنوب، مرکز و شمال شهر تهران انتخاب شدند. داده ها با استفاده از آزمون مقابله با بحران و معدل آزمودنی ها گرد آوری شد و با روش واریانس چند متغیری و تک متغیری به درآمدند. نتایج، نشان دهنده وجود رابطة مثبت بین پیشرفت تحصیلی و مقابله  ”مسئله مدار“  از یکسو و رابطة مثبت بین جایگاه اجتماعی – اقتصادی و پیشرفت تحصیلی از دیگر سو بود. بین راه های مقابله با تنیدگی وجایگاه اجتماعی- اقتصادی رابطه ای معناداری مشاهده نشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دختران نوجوان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مقابله با تنیدگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">موفقیت تحصیلی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_26995_2aa77da0622d2220856d7e80d0a4a80f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
