<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Viewpoints of Rural Women on Effect of Social Capital Components on their Empowerment (Case study: Hassan- Khan Village, Ghorveh Township)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی دیدگاه زنان روستایی در مورد تأثیر مؤلفه‌های سرمایه اجتماعی بر توانمندسازی آنان (مورد مطالعه: روستای حسن‌خان، شهرستان قروه)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>287</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>304</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">52360</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2014.52360</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>روح اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده کشاورزی دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شیما</FirstName>
					<LastName>زارعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد، دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>16</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Regarding the undeniable role of women in the process of rural development on the one hand and their inappropriate situation in terms of the most indices of rural development on the other hands, rural women’s empowerment is essential. Meanwhile, many researchers and scholars believe that social capital and its components play a key role. Thus, the main purpose of this descriptive- correlative research was to study of the viewpoints of rural women on effect of social capital components on their empowerment in Hassan- Khan village in Ghorveh Township.The statistical population of the research consisted of all women in Hassan- Khan village ranged from 15 to 64 years old (N= 213). According to the Krejcie and Morgan table, a sample size of 165 was selected using random sampling technique. The questionnaire were used to collect data. The content validity of the questionnaire was confirmed by a panel of experts. The construct validity and the composite reliability of the research instrument were tested by estimating the measurement model and they were satisfied after making necessary corrections. The results showed that the main hypotheses of the research have verified and three components of social capital including social cohesion, participation and trust had a positive and significant effect on dependent variable. The components totally explained about 43 percent of variances of women&#039;s empowerment in Hassan- Khan village. Based on the findings, it can be concluded that increasing social capital of rural women directly results in their empowerment.   </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">با در نظر گرفتن نقش انکارناپذیر زنان در فرایند توسعه روستایی از یک سوی و وضعیت نامطلوب آنان از نظر بیشتر شاخص­های توسعه از سوی دیگر، توانمندسازی آنان امری ضروری به نظر می­رسد که در این خصوص، بنا بر نظر بیشتر محققان و صاحبنظران، سرمایه اجتماعی و مولفه­های آن می­تواند نقش کلیدی داشته باشد. بر این اساس، تحقیق توصیفی- همبستگی حاضر با هدف اصلی بررسی دیدگاه زنان روستایی در مورد تأثیر مؤلفه­های سرمایه اجتماعی بر توانمندسازی آنان در روستای حسن­خان در شهرستان قروه انجام گرفت. جامعه آماری این پژوهش، تمامی زنان 15 تا 64 سال، ساکن در روستای حسن­خان بودند (213=N) که با توجه به جدول کرجسی- مورگان، تعداد 165 نفر از آنان از طریق روش نمونه­گیری تصادفی ساده برای انجام تحقیق انتخاب شدند. برای گردآوری داده‌ها از پرسشنامه استفاده گردید. روایی محتوایی پرسشنامه با نظر پانلی از متخصصان مورد تایید قرار گرفت و روایی سازه و پایایی ترکیبی ابزار تحقیق نیز از طریق برآورد مدل اندازه­گیری و پس از انجام اصلاحات لازم به دست آمد. برای تجزیه و تحلیل داده­ها از تکنیک چند متغیره مدل­سازی معادلات ساختاری استفاده شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد که هر سه فرضیه اصلی تحقیق مورد تایید قرار گرفته و از دیدگاه زنان مورد مطالعه هر یک از مؤلفه­های سرمایه اجتماعی شامل انسجام، مشارکت و اعتماد اجتماعی از اثر مثبت و معنی­داری بر متغیر وابسته برخوردار بوده و در مجموع 43 درصد از واریانس توانمندسازی زنان در روستای حسن­خان را تبیین نمودند. با توجه به یافته­های پژوهش، می­توان نتیجه گرفت افزایش میزان سرمایه اجتماعی زنان روستایی به طور مستقیم منجر به توانمندسازی آنان می­شود. </OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندسازی اقتصادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سیاسی و اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتماد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشارکت و انسجام اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان روستایی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_52360_d5c153c1576f3639854c7b319c553514.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
