<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2008</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Study on Work Ethic</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مطالعة تجربی اخلاق کار با تأکید بر جنسیت</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">27415</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامعباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>توسلی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه جامعه¬شناسی دانشکده علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم  نجار</FirstName>
					<LastName>نهاوندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی گروه برنامه¬ریزی اجتماعی دانشکده علوم¬اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Theoreticians of development believe that among the 3 types of capital; physical, technological and human capital; the main important one is human capital and its appropriate utilization. Economical development will not occur unless environmental factors of work and work organization develop culturally. Thus work ethic in the work culture of society will become important and warrant development and improvement. Presence of women in the work market is one of the effective variables on work culture and work ethic. 
This research has a gendered view of work ethic in Iranian society. The question raised in this article tackles the following issues: 
What similarities and differences are observed in men’s and women’s work ethic? If they are different, which factors interfere? 
This research is conducted through a survey using a questionnaire. The sample population consists of 356 faculty staff of Tehran University including 148 females and 208 males. The sampling method used is stratified sampling. The results of research show that the variable of gender does not influence work ethic directly but it is influential through other variables. The most effective variables are mediating variables such as inner organizational and cultural variables. The causal model is distinctive both in men and women. While the work ethic model is very complicated for men, it is very simple for women. The reason for this refers to the fact that women want to maintain their jobs and keep it as long as they can. Therefore, in order to reach a desirable and effective work for all individuals based on universal standards, it is important to consider gender differences.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه، محققان توسعه بر این باورند که از میان سرمایه‌های فیزیکی، تکنولوژیک و انسانی؛‌ متغیر اصلی و با اهمیت، سرمایه انسانی و بهره‌وری صحیح از آن است. توسعه و تکامل اقتصادی، جز از طریق رشد فرهنگی عوامل کار در محیط و سازمان‌های کار محقق نمی‌گردد. این‌چنین است که اخلاق کار در فرهنگ کار جامعه اهمیت یافته و متضمن توسعه و پیشرفت می‌شود. در این میان ورود زنان به بازار کار یکی از متغیرهای مؤثر بر فرهنگ و اخلاق کار در جامعه بوده است. این تحقیق با رویکردی جنسیتی به اخلاق کار در جامعة ایرانی، درصدد پاسخ به این نکته است که با توجه به خصوصیات محیط کار در ایران، چه تفاوت‌ها و شباهت‌هایی بین اخلاق کار زنان و مردان قابل مشاهده است و اینکه در صورت وجود تفاوت، چه عواملی در آن دخالت دارند. در این تحقیق از روش پیمایشی استفاده شده و ابزار تحقیق پرسشنامه بوده است.جامعه آماری، اعضای هیئت علمی و کارمندان دانشگاه تهران بوده‌اند که از میان آنان به صورت نمونه‌گیری طبقه‌بندی شده، جمعیت نمونه انتخاب شده‌است. پس از تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها و تحلیل مسیر، این نتایج بدست آمد: آنچه که در محیط کار دانشگاه بر اخلاق کار افراد مؤثر است، متغیرهای اقتصادی و پایگاهی کارکنان آن نیست، بلکه آنچه اهمیت دارد، متغیرهای فرهنگی و روابط درون سازمانی است و در دانشگاه به عنوان یک محیط فرهنگی بیشتر متغیرهای منزلتی، اجتماعی و ساختاری هستند که بر رفتار و اخلاق کارکنان تأثیرگذارند و زنان هم از این قاعده مستثنی نیستند. متغیر«جنسیت» به عنوان یک عامل مهم و مشخص در اخلاق کار(متغیر وابسته) خود را نشان نداده ولی توسط متغیرهای درون سازمانی (متغیرهای فرهنگی)، خود را بازنمایی و بازشناسی می‏کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اخلاق کار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">وضع اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرایط کار</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_27415_7787c530731ef32543172a764f69ab0e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
