<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Women and Beauty Project (Subjective meanings of cosmetic surgery)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amir</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rastegar Khaled</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Sociology, Shahed University, Iran (corresponding author)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kaveh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Master Science in Sociology, University of Shiraz, Shiraz, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Physical attractiveness has set new standards, so that the management body in general and cosmetic surgery in particular become increasingly important; such as a range of different behaviors, health, body building, diet, and different types of surgery include. This study examined the meanings of mental patients for cosmetic surgery in Tehran. Participants in this study comprised 26 female patients. The grounded theory is a qualitative research approach and data collection techniques are made use of in-depth interviews. The data suggest a model paradigm made to promote itself as causal conditions, context and enhance the socialization process as involving mental space as conditions are influenced. Participants included in the above circumstances, the decision to reflective strategy, which thus arises as a result of its social acceptance.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>453</start>
					<end>478</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_50282_a21c30edb6fc6faef9bac6aa62eb051b.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.50282</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Study of the Impacts of Social Learning in Family on the Premarital Skills</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">mohammad Esmaeil</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Riahi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, University of Mazandaran, Mazandaran, Iran (corresponding author)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Tohid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Alizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A in Sociology, University of Mazandaran, Mazandaran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The present study aims to describe the rate of premarital skills among daughters of Martyrs and Veterans in Mazandaran Province, as well as to identify the impact of parents’ marital skills on their girls’ skills. The universe of the study is all of single, older than 15 years old girls whose fathers were martyr or veteran. 366 young girls have been selected as a sample of the study via two-steps proportional random sampling method. Descriptive results indicate that rate of premarital skills is less than expected level (9.4 out of 20 score). However, these girls were more skilled in communication and anger control skills, as well as problem solving than marriage expectation and fertility skills. On the basis of regression analysis, rate of premarital skills among young girls can be predicted significantly (R2= 0.45), by independent variables, such as receiving direct education on marital life from parents, being younger girl, having higher education level, having richer fathers financially, and observing less negative behaviors of their fathers at home. These findings imply on necessity of invest on the teaching of premarital skills to young girls, especially in order to regulating their marriage expectation and increasing fertility knowledge.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>479</start>
					<end>508</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_50283_bc25ac4309a831f7142f0139982948e9.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.50283</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An Intergenerational Comparison of Women’s Cultural, Social and Economic Capital in Shiraz</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Taghi Iman</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor in Sociology, University of Shiraz, Shiraz, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">soroush</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor in Sociology, Academic Center for Education, Culture &amp; Research (ACECR), Fars Branch, Iran (correspondence author)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract> Various forms of capital provide sources in social structure that facilitate social action. The aim of this study was to compare available capitals in different generations of women. Questionnaire was completed by 386 women and their mothers (a total of 772 questionnaires). The results indicate that cultural capital of the present generation has increased compared to past generation. Social capital has lowered and economic capital has not changed. The results indicate that structural variables have a significant relationship with all types of capital. Controlling these variables we conclude that cultural capital is increased between generations, social capital has not changed with the reference of generation and economic capital well distributed along class and generational dynamics have not significant relationship. Results are discussed in relation with theory and previous researches.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>509</start>
					<end>530</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_50284_d0455be18e644f2956fd62761753405e.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.50284</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Comparative study of psychological well-being of female heads of house hold &amp; women in male headed households in Tehran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahmood</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Jamali</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Psychology, Islamic Azad Uuniversity, Central Brach, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mojgan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sepah Mansor</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Psychology, Islamic Azad Uuniversity, Central Brach, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">masomeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">fallahian</namePart>
				<affiliation>Md. Educational Psychology, PhD, Psychology, Islamic Azad University (corresponding author)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This research compares the psychological well-being of female heads of household and woman in male-headed in city of Tehran. It was a descriptive\ cross-sectional study. Statistical population was consisted of female heads of family under coverage of Imam Khomeini aid committee and woman in male-headed households in city of Tehran in 2012. The sample consisted of 280 subjects including 140 female heads of household and 140 women in male-headed households, who were selected randomly among statistical population. The research instrument was Ryff’s Psychological Well-being Scale (1995). Data were analyzed using multivariable analysis of variances (MANOVA), by SPSS-18 software. The results showed that average scores of psychological well-being, and subscales of self-acceptance, positive relations with other people، and purposeful life in male-headed households were higher than female heads of households and difference between two average scores was significant. Mean scores of female heads of households in scales of autonomy, control over environment and personal development, were higher than women in male-headed households, but difference between two groups was significant only in terms of autonomy. The results indicated that the female heads of family were more prone to risk taking behavior, then conducting workshops on communicational skills and problem solving can be efficient to improve the psychological well- being of them.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>531</start>
					<end>542</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_50285_ae1bdd696a9f0fae657f025eb384ff39.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.50285</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Health Promoting Life Style among Women of Reproductive Age (Case Study of Shiraz City)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Aliyar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ahmadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Demographics, University of Shiraz, Shiraz, Iran (corresponding author)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rosta</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA in Demographics, University of Shiraz, Shiraz, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Health promoting lifestyle is a valuable source for reducing the incidence and impact of health problems and improving the quality of life. The purpose of this study is investigating the health-oriented lifestyle of women of reproductive ages. The statistical population of study is women of reproductive age living in Shiraz city. A sample of 392 person was selected thorough multiple stage cluster sampling. The study is based on Pender&#039;s health promotion model, although with some revisions. The result of Cronbach’s Alpha for the test of reliability for the lifestyle index is 0.87. The findings reveals that there is a significant relationship between the education of women, the study in areas of health, the use of communication media, social identity, social support, self-efficacy of health, self-reported general health, and awareness of health behavior with the dependent variable; health oriented life style. The study indicates that age of respondents, the marital status, employment status, household income and experience of some particular diseases do not have any significant relationship with the dependent variable. The results of regression models shows that four variables including self-efficacy of health, self-reported general health, the study in areas of health, and awareness of health behavior explain 51 percent of changes in variance of health oriented lifestyle. Among them, self-efficacy of health is the most influential one.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>543</start>
					<end>558</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_50287_dbd96a5ff66b753f22ad68e3eb026d44.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.50287</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identifying Inhibitions of Rural Women’s Trend to Home Businesses (Case Study: Sardrod district, Razan county)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Yaghoubi Farani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Agricultural Extension and Education, College of Agriculture, Bu-Ali Sina University, Hamedan, Iran (corresponding author)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hajar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Vahdat Moaddab</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc. Student of Rural Development , College of Agriculture, Bu-Ali Sina University, Hamedan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Somayeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Latifi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph. D. Student of Agricultural Development, College of Agriculture, Tabriz University, Tabriz, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Home business is one of the best fields of women&#039;s economic activity and considered as an important strategy for job creation, particularly for rural women. Nonetheless many barriers avoid addressing rural women to these businesses. The main purpose of this study was to analyze the most important barriers for trends of rural women and girls to home businesses. The statistical population of this study was rural women that are over 18 years in Sardrod district in Razan county, Hamedan province. 187 people were studied randomly according to Cochran formula. The most important data collection tool was a questionnaire that its validity was confirmed by panel of experts and Its reliability was tested by Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient. According to results of factor analysis, barriers to rural women trend to establish home businesses were classified in six factors that were: social and cultural, infrastructure and finance, personality, support, domestic and training. Social and cultural factors as the most important factor was introduced.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>559</start>
					<end>574</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_50289_2276cba09ad2f93a26529d2ebefe4765.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.50289</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Comparative Study on the Presence of Women in the Legislature Branch: Developments and Changes before and after Iran’s Islamic Revolution</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hosseion</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Masudnia</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Political Science, University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran.</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mina</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Nazari</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A. student of political science, University of Isfahan, Isfhan, Iran (corresponding author)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Nejat</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mohammadifar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.D student, Political Science, University of Isfahan, Isfhan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Changes in the rate of women socio-political participation and presence are among the changes and developments occurred in socio-political sphere in Iran in the recent decades. It is expected that as women capabilities and education rate and international interactions increase, their socio-political participation and presence especially in Legislature Branch increase dramatically as well. This study is to evaluate women participation and presence in Legislature Branch before and after Islamic Revolution through comparative-analytic approach by stressing the importance of political participation of women in the development of the country.Findings of this article indicate thatwomen political participation has undergone striking fluctuation from Pahlavi period to Islamic Revolution. Although women have fulfilled scientific and socio-political accomplishments hence there is a long way to go in order to utilize their abilities in the management structure of the country pertinently. It seems that their participation in this level demands motivation and eliminating existing obstacles.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>575</start>
					<end>594</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_50290_2a87e75ba1c7d178f19bec3024265417.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.50290</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Representation of the Women’s Social - Political Roles in Elementary and Middle School Textbooks</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fahimeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Farahmand Pour</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Faculty of Theology and Islamic Studies, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">elham</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">bahranifard</namePart>
				<affiliation>Student in MA, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran (corresponding author)</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Besides textbooks teach students, prepare them to accept their roles in accordance with their gender characteristics, as it is considered by the authors. This study is intended to represent how women’s social – political roles in both elementary and middle high school textbooks, academic year deal 1391-92. Research method is quantitative content analysis based on gender in education between images and text. The results indicate the defining social roles for women new look requires a lot of activities , such as care for the environment, charitable activities and public works, aid workers, and the presence of important social practice such as enjoining good and forbid the evil taking place in the new definition. Also, the categories and content analysis, descriptive and normative statements indicate that further descriptive statements and images in textbooks. But describing the role of women in social and political issues in most cases is not consistent with reality.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>11</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>4</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>595</start>
					<end>610</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_50291_856e675eaffb3da1c2fcd1d099240213.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.50291</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>