<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل رابطه سطوح توسعه  انسانی و جنسیتی با شاخص های محرومیت و بهره مندی باروری</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19510</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم (آزاده)</FirstName>
					<LastName>مردانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مطالعات زنان دانشگاه الزهرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فضیله</FirstName>
					<LastName>خانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه جغرافیا و برنامه¬ریزی روستایی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present study tries to investigate the dissimilarities among women in therural areas of different counties in terms of fertility, possible access (accessibility) to health, hygiene and medical attention during fertility, taking into account the difference in human and gender development index of the counties. Since the ertility variables express the condition and circumstances of a woman and types and causes of deprivations as well as uncommon needs prevent them to be in a same group, therefore it is important to have access to the divisive information about various or different groups of women. In this study it is argued that being in the same rural area does not necessarily mean that these areas are similar. Unbalanced levels of human and gender development indices, geographical isolation and different climates of rural areas causes different status in the level of fertility  and the index of possible accessibility to hygiene and health during pregnancy and after pregnancy. Therefore to have access to this information in planning and programming of the rural areas is vital. The theories onsidered in this research include the theory of economical fertility, theory of proximate determination and the theory of cultural fertility. This research has utilized documental-statistical of survey method.Factorial, experimental and Pearson&#039;s correlation coefficient, regression multiple experimental ,cluster analysis and software of&#039; spss&#039; has also been used. The outcome and results of this research show that there is a positive and significant relationship between levels of gender and human development and level of fertility benefits, contrary there is a negative relationship between the levels of human and gender development and the level of fertility deprivation. Although the intensity of this relationship has reduced in the year 1385 as compared to the year 1375 ,but still the relationship is
significant and continuous. The relationship between deprivation and the level of benefit or returns or quotient reveals that one of the causes of a decline in
fertility specially during 1385 can be the level of benefit or quotient because anywhere that women have possible access to health and
hygiene during pregnancy and after pregnancy, they have shown lower tendency to the fertility</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در مطالعه  حاضر تلاش می کنیم تا تفاوت زنان در مناطق روستایی استان های مختلف کشور را در سطح باروری و نیز امکانات بهداشتی و پزشکی در حین باروری با توجه به رتبه  متفاوت این مناطق در شاخص توسعه  انسانی و جنسیتی در سال های عنوان شده را مطالعه کنیم. از آنجا که متغیرهای باروری بیانگر وضعیت خاص زنان است و اَشکال  و علل محرومیت‌ها و نیازهای غیرمشترک زنان مانع قرارگیری آن ها در یک گروه همگن با نیازهای یکسان می شود، دست یابی به اطلاعات تفکیکی در مورد گروه‌های مختلف زنان در درون هر یک از مناطق  خیلی اهمیت دارد. در این مطالعه استدلال می کنیم که قرار گرفتن یک منطقه در گروه مناطق روستایی نمیتواند دلیلی بر همگونی و تشابه  این مناطق باشد. نامتوازن بودن سطوح توسعه  انسانی و جنسیتی در مناطق روستایی، انزوای جغرافیایی برخی از مناطق روستایی و شرایط متفاوت اقلیمی، جایگاه متفاوتِ آنها را در سطح باروری (محرومیت باروری) و شاخص میزان دسترسی به امکانات بهداشتی در حین حاملگی و پس از آن (بهره مندی باروری) را به دنبال دارد. تئوری های مورد توجه در این پژوهش شامل؛ تئوری های اقتصادی باروری، تئوری تعیین کننده های بلافصل و تئوری  فرهنگی باروری است. در این پژوهش از روش اسنادی-آماری و به منظور تحلیل اطلاعات و روابط علّیِ بین متغیرها از آزمون‌های آماری و ضرایب همبستگی پیرسون، آزمون رگرسیونِ چندگانه و تحلیل خوشه ای و برای شاخص سازی از تحلیل عاملی استفاده میکنیم. نتایج این مطالعه نشان میدهد که بین سطوح توسعه  انسانی و جنسیتی با سطح محرومیت باروری رابطه‌ا‌ی منفی و با سطح بهره‌مندی باروری رابطه ای مثبت و معنادار وجود دارد. گرچه از شدت رابطه در سال 1385 در مقایسه با 1375 کاسته شده، اما رابطه همچنان معنادار است. رابطه بین محرومیت و سطح بهره‌مندی باروری  بیان‌گر آن است که یکی از دلایل کاهش سطح باروری در برخی مناطق، به خصوص در سال 1385، میتواند سطح بهره مندی باروری باشد؛ چون در هر کجا که زنان بیشتر به امکانات بهداشتی در حین حاملگی و پس از آن دسترسی دارند، تمایل به سطح باروری پایینتری را نشان میدهند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بهره‌مندی باروری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توسعه  انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توسعه  جنسیتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محرومیت باروری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مناطق روستایی.</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_19510_1ca221cacecd5e0f4daa3603ea601f1f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
