<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Consequences of Divorce A Systematic Review of Current Literature with an Emphasis on Gender-Related Issues (1997-2011)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آثار و پیامدهای طلاق مرور نظام مند تحقیقات انجام شده در ایران با تأکید بر ملاحظات جنسیتی(1390 – 1376)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>111</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>131</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">23652</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>کلانتری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار جامعه شناسی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پیام</FirstName>
					<LastName>روشن فکر</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد رفاه و برنامه‌ریزی اجتماعی دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی(ره)</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جلوه</FirstName>
					<LastName>جواهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مطالعات زنان دانشگاه الزهرا(س)</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Consequences of divorce, specially the negative ones, affect different sectors of society generally and become specifically important in gender development analysis and social policy, because of their especial influence on women’s lives. This article reviews the previous studies and published literature on after-effects of divorce in Iran in a period between 1997 and 2011. Based on an initial search, 197 texts were gathered and after preliminary evaluation and screening, the content of 23 of them were extracted and analyzed. Finally the analysis was organized and evaluated in the following levels: 1- general features, 2- aims and queries of the research, 3- methodology of the research, 4- types of variables and 5- findings as well as outcomes of the research.
Findings of this study show that in general, divorce not only damages human and economic resources, but a gender-sensitive analysis also shows that it could be an obstacle in women’s participation in development and finally leads to their marginalization and exploitation. This study also demonstrates that female researchers pay more attention to psychological and economic impacts of divorce rather than social problems and drug addiction.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پیامدهای طلاق به ویژه وجوه منفی آن، هم به صورت عمومی بر ارکان مختلف جامعه تأثیر می گذارد و هم به واسطه تأثیرات ویژه ای که بر زنان دارد، در تحلیل های جنسیتی توسعه و سیاستگذاری های اجتماعی اهمیت می یابد، این مقاله مروری خواهد داشت بر پژوهش های صورت گرفته در حوزه پیامدها و آثار طلاق در ایران در بازه زمانی 1376 الی 1390. بر اساس نتایج جستجوی اولیه، 197 سند به دست آمد که پس از بررسی و غربال‌گری اولیه، محتوای 23 تحقیق استخراج گردید. سپس، یافته های به دست آمده از این تحقیقات در سطوح 1- مشخصات عمومی 2- اهداف و سؤالات تحقیق، 3- متدولوژی تحقیقات، 4- انواع متغیرهای مورد بررسی و 5- یافته‌ها و نتایج تحقیقات، طبقه‌بندی و ارزیابی گردیدند.یافته های این پژوهش نشان می دهد که نه تنها طلاق به‌طور کلی می تواند باعث صدمه به سرمایه انسانی و اقتصادی جامعه شود، بلکه در تحلیلی حساس به جنسیت، می تواند مانع نقش آفرینی زنان در فرایند توسعه و در نتیجه به حاشیه راندن و استثمار زنان شود. به علاوه، این تحقیق نشان می دهد که محققان زن بیشتر از محققان مرد به مسائل روانشناختی و اقتصادی پیامدهای طلاق توجه داشته و کمتر به مسائلی نظیر آسیب های اجتماعی و سوءمصرف مواد مخدر توجه داشته اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آثار طلاق.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیامدهای طلاق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل جنسیتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طلاق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مرور نظام مند</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_23652_49a03e828ced21b6682de41eff6291c7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
