<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluating Attachment of Children to their Parents and their Separation Considering the Role of Gender Differences</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سنجش رابطه دلبستگی به والدین و جدایی- تفرد با توجه به نقش تفاوت های جنسیتی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>31</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>50</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">29481</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2012.29481</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمیدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>عریضی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترای روانشناسی صنعتی-سازمانی، دانشیار گروه روانشناسی دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شبنم</FirstName>
					<LastName>جوانمرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد روانشناسی صنعتی-سازمانی، دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Attachment of children to their parents and their separation are two important growth processes which are summoned up in teens again and become more important. The present research tends to find out either the processes of attachment and separation among girls and boys take place in different ways or gender can affect the relationship between these two processes. To this end 300 students of the University of Isfahan were randomly selected and divided into two groups of 150 who answered the questionnaire of teen separation and attachment to their parents and peers. The results of independent “t” analysis show that two groups of boys and girls are different in terms of their attachment to their parents and their separation. Also a significant relationship between attachment of children to the parents and their separation in both groups was confirmed. The results of the analysis of subgroup (Z Ficsher) didn’t certify the regulating role of gender between attachment and separation. The above results made it clear that the process of separation for boys and girls is different. It was also revealed that girls are less confident of their parents support and availability. This may lead in formation of unsafe attachment styles and then block the successful process of separation and individualization among girls.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">دلبستگی و جدایی- تفرد دو فرایند مهم رشدی هستند که در نوجوانی مجدداً فراخوانده شده و اهمیت فراوانی می یابند. پژوهش حاضر درصدد پاسخ‌گویی به این سؤالات است که آیا فرایند دلبستگی و جدایی- تفرد در دختران و پسران به شیوه های متفاوتی طی می شوند و آیا جنسیت می تواند بر روابط این دو فرایند بر یکدیگر تأثیرگذار باشد. بدین منظور 300 نفر از دانشجویان دانشگاه اصفهان به صورت تصادفی و بر اساس جنسیت به دو گروه 150 نفری تقسیم شدند و به پرسشنامه های جدایی- تفرد نوجوانی و دلبستگی به والدین و همتاها پاسخ دادند. نتایج حاصل از تحلیل t مستقل نشان داد که دو گروه دختران و پسران از لحاظ دلبستگی به والدین و جدایی- تفرد متفاوتند. همچنین رابطه ی معنادار بین دلبستگی به والدین و جدایی تفرد در هر دو گروه مورد تأیید قرار گرفت. اما نتایج حاصل از تحلیل زیرگروه (Z فیشر) نقش تعدیلی جنسیت را در رابطه بین دلبستگی به والدین و جدایی- تفرد تأیید نکرد. تبیین یافته های فوق نشان داد که فرایند جدایی- تفرد در دختران و پسران به صورت متفاوتی طی می شود. همچنین بر اساس نتایج پژوهش حاضر دختران نسبت به حمایت والدین و دسترس پذیری آنها در مواقع نیاز اطمینان کمتری دارند، این مسئله می تواند به شکل گیری سبک های دلبستگی ناایمن منجر شده و به دنبال آن مانع از طی شدن موفقیت آمیز روند جدایی و فردیت یابی در دختران شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جدایی- تفرد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دلبستگی پدری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دلبستگی مادری.</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_29481_0cff41cb5d350e24abc67fb9effe6198.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
