<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Archaeology of Bi-Hijābi (Unveiling) in Iran
Qasem Zaeri</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>دیرینه شناسی بی حجابی در ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>153</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>186</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">52354</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2014.52354</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>قاسم</FirstName>
					<LastName>زائری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار جامعه شناسی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>27</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This article investigates the possibility context of the unveiling genesis (taking off the Hijab, i. e. the Islamic veil) in Iran and elucidates the dynamics possibility of the first attempt to unveil. An archaeological method of Foucaultian approach is adopted to reach this goal. The article demonstrates that “unveiling” is one of the implications of modernity and should be considered in light of the distinction between “Native Modernity” and “Western Modernity”. Therefore, despite the common narrative, we cannot think of the time when Ghorrat-alein bābi attended Badasht meeting with her veil taken off in 1852 the starting point of the unveiling in Iran while the native modernity with its arrangements was in an outstanding stage of its authority. Moreover, Ghorrat-alein’s style of argumentation entirely belongs to traditional texture. the unveility developed only in an advanced stage of western modernity with its consolidated arrangements and lively dynamics in Iran. Historically, it occurred in 1927 when Sediqeh Dowlat-abādi took her veil off roaming in the streets. Dowlat-abādi’s maneuver lay in a sequence of internal and international relations supported and empowered by the “modern state” of Rezakhan namely the influence of modernization in Afghanistan and Turkey, inclination to gain international prestige in the end of the World War I and the nationalistic strategy of education of women. Although Dowlat-abādi herself was initially under the influence of modern relations that emerged in the realm of education within the “underdevelopment discourse” since the time of Sepah-salār and especially the Constitutional Revolution, later she turned to be a proponent of a new discourse for promoting unveiling and defining women’s rights and tended toward some type of “maternal feminism” derived from common arguments of religious modernism under the influence of the feministic trends between the two World Wars.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این مقاله به بررسی شرایط امکانی پیدایی بی‏حجابی در ایران اختصاص دارد و درصدد است نشان دهد که در برآیند چه نیروها و مناسباتی، نخستین اقدام به بی‏حجابی در ایران ممکن شده است. برای رسیدن به این هدف، از جهت‏گیری فوکویی متکی بر روش دیرینه‏شناسی استفاده شده است. مقاله نشان می‏دهد که «بی‏حجابی» حکمی از احکام تجدد است که باید در مناقشة «تجدد بومی» و «تجدد غربی» در ایران فهمیده شود. از‌این‌رو، برخلاف تصور رایج، حضورِ بدون حجابِ قرةالعین بابی در اجتماع بدشت در 1231 ش.، در‌حالی‏که «تجدد بومی» و نظامات آن در مرحلة مهمی از اقتدار خود است، نمی‏تواند نقطة صفر بی‏حجابی در ایران باشد. به‏علاوه، شیوة استدلال و اسلوب بیانی قرةالعین نیز به تمامی در متن سنت است. مقاله نشان می‏دهد که بی‏حجابی فقط در مرحلة پیشرفته‏ای از «تجدد غربی»، و با پیدایی نظامات و نیروهای آن، در ایران می‏توانسته ممکن شود و از حیث تاریخی، این امر در 1306 ش. و با حضورِ بدون حجابِ صدیقه دولت‏آبادی در خیابان‏ها محقق شد. اقدام دولت‏آبادی در برآیند مجموعه‏ای از روابط و مناسبات داخلی و بین‏المللی مورد حمایت «دولت جدید» رضاخان قرار گرفت: تأثیر الگوهای نوسازی در ترکیه و افغانستان، و میل به شناساییِ بین‏المللی در پایان جنگ جهانی اول، و نیز راهبرد ملت‏گرایانة تربیت زنان از این جمله‏اند. خود دولت‏آبادی نیز، هرچند بدواً تحت‌تأثیر مناسبات جدیدی قرار داشت، که از زمان سپهسالار و خصوصاً از انقلاب مشروطه ذیلِ «گفتمان عقب‏ماندگی» در حیطة آموزش جدید پدید آمده بود، بعدها خود به مبلغ گفتار جدیدی برای ترویج بی‏حجابی و تعریف حقوق زنان بدل شد که تحت‌تأثیر روندهای فمنیستی بین دو جنگ جهانی، از استدلال‏های رایج مبتنی بر نوگرایی دینی به نوعی «فمنیسم مادرانه» تمایل پیدا کرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انقلاب مشروطه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بی‏حجابی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دیرینه‏شناسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رضاخان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صدیقه دولت‏آبادی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فمنیسم مادرانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">‌ قرةالعین بابی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_52354_c5361f36cacb14b8b2f53f0fc6e7cefc.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
