<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>&quot;Woman from&quot; Rassafi&#039;s Point of View</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>زن در نگاه معروف رصافی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">28286</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عزت</FirstName>
					<LastName>ملاابراهیمی</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نوید</FirstName>
					<LastName>پیری</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Many poets have somewhat dealt with the concept of feminity in their poems, and some only have alluded to it. Their attitude and their viewpoint towards woman is influenced by the popular viewpoint dominating their society as well as their own personal experiences. Marouf Abdolqani Rasafi discussed nearly all aspects of women&#039;s social problems. He was aware of such problems and tried his best to liberate the female gender from the dominant restrictions, but the restrictions hindered him in moving away from society&#039;s discourse. In his poems lies a great soul which is reinforced by Islam.  This type of poem is mainly based on the feelings and sympathy that are bestowed upon the poet&#039;s soul. According to Rasafi poems, he is a Muslim who under the influence of western culture deviates from Islamic culture but ultimately returns to the dominant and deeply rooted Islamic culture. This reminds the famous proverb: Such is the tree, such is the fruit.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">چکیده: بسیاری از شاعران در اشعار خود به‌نوعی به مقوله‌ی زن پرداخته یا به آن اشاره‏ای داشته‏اند. طرز تلقی و نوع دیدگاه آنان به زن متأثر از دیدگاه عام حاکم بر جامعه و نیز تجربه‌های شخصیِ شاعر است. معروف عبدالغنی رصافی تقریباً تمام جوانب مشکلات اجتماعی زن را مطالعه کرده است. هرچند او به این مشکلات واقف بوده و تلاشی فراوان داشته تا زن را از قید و بندهای حاکم برهاند، اما محدودیت‏ها مانع می‏شد تا پا را از حصار گفتمان جامعه فراتر نهد. در ورای اشعار او روحی بزرگ قرار دارد که مقوی آن اسلام است. این دسته اشعار به‌طور عمده از احساسات و عواطف شاعر نسبت به زنان سرچشمه می‌گیرد. طبق اشعار، رصافی مسلمانی است که گاهی تحت تأثیر فرهنگ ساختگی غرب دست‌خوش انحرافاتی جزیی می‌شود اما در نهایت به فرهنگ غالب و ریشه‏دار اسلامی برمی‏گردد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رصافی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تعلیم و تربیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حجاب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ازدواج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اسلام.</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_28286_22837180ac5fb543b77a32d4255e56ec.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
