<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>15</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Comparative study of the women’s status in the Islamic countries of the Middle East and North Africa</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تطبیقی وضعیت زنان در کشورهای اسلامی خاورمیانه و شمال آفریقا</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>123</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>147</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">61990</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2017.61990</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یعقوب</FirstName>
					<LastName>فروتن</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار جمعیت شناسی گروه علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه مازندران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مینا</FirstName>
					<LastName>شجاعی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری جامعه‌شناسی – مسائل اجتماعی ایران، دانشگاه مازندران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>12</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Women&#039;s status has experienced significant progress in most parts of the world in recent decades. However, the gender gap still exists in many countries. This study investigates the status of women in the Islamic countries of the Middle East and North Africa (MENA) region from a comparative perspective. It uses such international indices as Gender Development Index, Gender Inequality Index, and Gender Gap Index. The methodology of the study is a secondary analysis using descriptive exploratory analysis and cluster analysis techniques on international data. Generally speaking, the results of this analysis highlight two key patterns. First, while all the MENA women are considered within one single category, they tend to hold a relatively lower level of gender outcomes and represent more visible gender gap in global comparison. Second, more detailed analysis emphasizes the substantial heterogeneity of the MENA women, suggesting that there is a significantly wide range of socio-economic patterns associated with women’s status by individual country in the region. This diversity needs to be carefully considered in order to provide an appropriate explanation on patterns and determinants associated with the MENA women’s status.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">وضعیت زنان در چند دهۀ اخیر در بیشتر نقاط دنیا پیشرفت‌های چشمگیری داشته است. بااین‌حال، شکاف جنسیتی هنوز در بسیاری از جوامع وجود دارد. این پژوهش، با استفاده از شاخص‌های بین‌المللی سنجش وضعیت زنان، به بررسی تطبیقی کشورهای اسلامی خاورمیانه و شمال افریقا از حیث توسعۀ جنسیتی، نابرابری و شکاف جنسیتی می‌پردازد. روش این پژوهش تحلیل ثانویۀ داده‌های بین‌المللی است که به دو روش تحلیل توصیفی اکتشافی و تحلیل خوشه‌ای انجام ‌گرفته است. تجزیه و تحلیل‌های این تحقیق در‌خصوص وضعیت این کشورهای اسلامی بر دو الگوی اصلی تأکید دارد: اول آنکه، چنانچه مجموعۀ این کشورها را به‌عنوان یک کل در نظر بگیریم، شکاف‌ جنسیتی میان آن‌ها به‌مراتب بیشتر و برجسته‌تر از سایر نقاط جهان است. دوم آنکه، تحلیل‌های تفصیلی این پژوهش نیز نشان‌دهندۀ تنوع و تفاوت‌های قابل ملاحظه بین این کشورهاست؛ به‌طوری‌که می‌توان آن‌ها را بر‌اساس وضعیت زنان در سه شاخص بین‌المللی به پنج گروه مجزا تقسیم کرد. در این گروه‌بندی، کشورهای قطر و کویت در دستۀ یک، کشورهای امارات متحدۀ عربی، تونس، بحرین، عمان، عربستان سعودی و لیبی در گروه دوم، کشورهای لبنان، ترکیه و الجزایر در گروه سوم، کشورهای ایران، سوریه، اردن، مصر، مراکش، پاکستان و عراق در گروه چهارم و یمن و افغانستان در گروه پنجم قرار می‌گیرند. بر این اساس، به نظر می‌رسد برای تبیین و شناخت دقیق وضعیت زنان در این کشورها، توجه به تفاوت‌های متعدد و ناهمسانی آن‌ها، هم در وضعیت کنونی و هم در روند تحولات وضعیت زنان در سه دهۀ گذشته، ضروری است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خاورمیانه و شمال افریقا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شکاف جنسیتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کشورهای اسلامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشخصه‌های اقتصادی‌ـ اجتماعی. وضعیت زنان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_61990_854f6e9ea2c14cabeddf316a90c6f361.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
