<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Comparative-Historical Study of the Position of ‘Family’ in Feminist Thought and Islamic Viewpoint; with Emphasis on ‘Rules’</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی مقایسه ای-تاریخی جایگاه «خانواده» در فکر فمینیستی و دیدگاه اسلام با تأکید بر مسالة «قواعد»</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>5</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>36</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">30573</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2013.30573</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>قاسم</FirstName>
					<LastName>زائری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار جامعه شناسی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Feminist thought has always challenged the Islamic viewpoint. A majority of feminists believe that ‘family,’ is a source of oppression against women, and is essentially, the main way of reproducing male dominance. Part of the feminist argumentation, highlights itself through the form of criticism of Western political customs, especially in the liberal debate of ‘public order’.  In this debate, liberal theorists treat the ‘family’ as a part of a ‘personal sphere’ or a ‘strictly private area,’ and thus, by taking this stance, drive it out from the attention of public debate and legislation; the result of which, being that it leads to the perfect breeding ground for male dominance and for the fostering of unfair relations.This paper, reviewing the aforementioned standpoint, illustrates that ‘family’, has been subject to legislation in Muslim society since the emergence of Islam, and an abundance of rules and laws have been created in order to establish healthy and just relations and protect women&#039;s rights. Indeed, from the viewpoint of Islam, the family structure has been created on the basis of affection, and specific rules have been formed for regulating this important establishment.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">فکر فمینیستی، همواره دیدگاه اسلام در مورد خانواده را به چالش کشیده و می کشد. باورِ بخش عمده ای از فمینیست ها این است که خانواده منشأ ستمگری علیه زنان و راه اصلیِ اعمال و بازتولیدِ سلطة مردان است. بخشی از استدلال فمینیست ها خود را در نقد سنت سیاسی در غرب، خصوصاً مبحث لیبرالیِ «امر عمومی» نشان می دهد که بر مبنای آن، نظریه پردازان لیبرال، با قلمداد کردنِ خانواده به عنوان بخشی از حیطة خصوصی» یا «حریم شخصی»، آن را از شمول مباحثة عمومی و قانون گذاری خارج کرده و به جایگاه مناسبی برای اعمال سلطة مردان بر زنان و نیز تقویت مناسبات ناعادلانه تبدیل کرده اند. مقاله ضمن تشریح این دیدگاه، نشان می دهد که از دیدگاه اسلام، اساساً خانواده نمی تواند چنین خصیصه ای داشته باشد، زیرا از همان ابتدای ظهور اسلام، خانواده به موضوعی برای قاعده گذاری شارع بدل شده و انبوهی از قواعد برای تنظیم مناسبات عادلانه در خانواده و دفاع از حقوق زنان تنظیم و تعریف شده است. در واقع، چارچوب خانواده از دیدگاه اسلام، ترکیبی از عواطف و قواعد است.</OtherAbstract>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_30573_1b29042c891126a0a20a42fc9ef0b427.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
