<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>17</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Meta-analysis of Divorce Researches in Iran in the Last Two Decades (1377-1397) and Suggesting Solutions to Reduce Divorce and Its Negative Consequences</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>فراتحلیل پژوهش های طلاق در ایران در دو دهه اخیر (1377-1397) و ارائه راهکارهای کاهش طلاق و پیامدهای منفی آن برای زنان و فرزندان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>653</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>674</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">76907</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2020.287279.1007699</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>روشنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار مطالعات زنان دانشگاه الزهرا(س)</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>تافته</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد جامعه‏ شناسی دانشگاه الزهرا(س)</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>خسروی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد روان‌شناسی دانشگاه الزهرا(س)</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>13</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The growth of divorce in Iranian society and its negative consequences have made it necessary to pay attention to this social problem. The purpose of this study was to present strategies to reduce divorce and its negative consequences. For this purpose, using qualitative meta-analysis method, by examining 70 selected divorce studies in the last two decades (1377-97), it has classified the factors of divorce and its negative consequences and then presented strategies for reducing the divorce and its negative consequences. Based on the findings, the factors of divorce can be classified into four categories of Incorrect spouse choice, Lack of knowledge and skills of spouses and maladaptation, Bad performance of spouses, and adverse economic conditions. accordingly, we can propose solutions based on training courses and consulting services by the Responsible entities, and Oblige spouses to participate. Researches has also studied the negative consequences of divorce for women and children. To reduce these consequences, Solutions included Eliminate legal challenges, Teaching parents to minimize divorce harm for children, providing counseling services, culturalization for family support for divorced women, and Reforming society&#039;s attitude to divorced women and children of divorce are proposed.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">رشد طلاق در جامعة ایران و تبعات منفی آن توجه به این مسئلة اجتماعی را ضروری ساخته است. در این زمینه، هدف پژوهش حاضر ارائة راهکارهایی برای کاهش طلاق و پیامدهای منفی آن بوده است. به این منظور، با استفاده از روش فراتحلیل کیفی، با بررسی 70 پژوهش منتخب حوزة طلاق در دو دهة اخیر (1377ـ1397)، به دسته‏بندی عوامل طلاق و پیامدهای منفی آن و سپس ارائة راهکارهایی برای کاهش طلاق و پیامدهای منفی آن پرداخته است. طبق یافته‏ها، عوامل طلاق را براساس منشأ عوامل می‏توان در چهار دستۀ همسرگزینی نادرست، نقص دانش و مهارت همسران، عملکرد نامطلوب همسران و شرایط اقتصادی نامطلوب قرار داد. بر این اساس، برای کاهش طلاق، راهکارهایی بر پایة اجرای دوره‏های آموزشی و مشاوره‏ای از سوی نهادهای مسئول و الزام همسران به شرکت در آن با در نظر گرفتن ضمانت اجرای قانونی مناسب پیشنهاد می‏شود. پژوهش‏ها همچنین به پیامدهای منفی طلاق برای زنان و فرزندان پرداخته‏اند که برای کاهش این پیامدها می‏توان راهکارهایی بر محور رفع چالش‏های حقوقی و خلأهای قانونی، آموزش والدین برای به حداقل رساندن آسیب‏های طلاق برای فرزندان، ‏ارائة خدمات مشاوره‏ای، فرهنگ‏سازی برای حمایت خانواده از زنان مطلقه و اصلاح نگرش جامعه به زنان مطلقه و فرزندان طلاق ارائه کرد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیامدها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">راهکارها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طلاق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فراتحلیل</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_76907_00ec7284d775cb55f6f7560e1c483ea9.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
