<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>7</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2003</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نحوه وقت زنان روستایی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">11367</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName></FirstName>
					<LastName>Unknown</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Rural women spend a considerable portion of their time and energy performing activities that are not calculated in production and the national product. Women’s increasing inequality and decreasing resource benefits are glaring reflections of this condition. This study aims to identify women’s activities in the village of Dona, in Mazandaran province, and the time they allocate to each activity. It applied qualitative research over a period of four seasons in 2002. Women spent two-thirds of their waking hours in productive activities, corresponding to an average work time of 10 hours and 26 minutes per day. On average, they spent 17 minutes a day on personal hygiene, health, and leisure-time. No time was spent on education and reading.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">زنان روستایی بخش قابل توجهی از وقت و انرژی خود را صرف فعالیت هایی می کنند که غالباً در محاسبات تولید و درآمد ملی نادیده گرفته می شود . انعکاس نادیده گرفته می شود . انعکاس نادیده انگاری در افزایش نا برابری و کاهش بهره مندی آنها از منابع و فرصت هاست . هدف این بررسی شناخت انواع فعالیت های زنان در روستای دونا – از توابع استان مازندران – و ترسیم الگوی صرف وقت به هر یک از این فعالیت هاست . مطالعه حاضر با بهره گیری از روش پژوهش کیفی در مدت چهار فصل از سال 1381 صورت گرفته است . نتایج پژوهش نشان می دهد زنان مورد مطالعه بیش از دو سوم اوقات بیداری خود را صرف فعالیت های تولیدی می کنند . این رقم به طور متوسط برابر 10 ساعت و 26 دقیقه در شبانه روز است . همچنین این زنان به طور متوسط در شبانه روز حدود 17 دقیقه وقت به نظافت – درمان و اوقات فراغت خود اختصاص می دهند و آموزش و مطاله در الگوی صرف وقت آنها جایی ندارد .</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اوقات فراغت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان روستایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فعالیت های اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نیروی انسانی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_11367_359e8e013e0706e4feb170ee82884068.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
