<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[First Pages]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_65003_f91c4fa71dd57b6cfe118da6b8e7dd09.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2017.65003]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[One-child living experience: A study of girls over 18 years]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Shojaei, Javad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Yazdkhasti, Bahjat]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[phenomenology]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lived Experience]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[one-child]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tehran]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Statistics indicates that fertility is falling below the level of replacement. In parallel to this declining trend, we see an increase in the proportion of one-child families. This change in the family structure affects the quality of one-child life and, due to role limitation, the one-child socialization process has different conditions. Therefore, one-child as a social phenomenon must be studied precisely. The existing studies focus on quantitative explanations of the change in fertility behavior, and the meaning of these behaviors is less well-known. Also, few studies that have been performed on one-child, have "why" assumptions; it is important to identify the "Quiddity" of one-child. The current research, by adopting a phenomenological approach, describes the experience of one-child living in Tehran. The data were collected through a deep interview with twenty girls over the age of 18 years using with purposive sampling, analyzed by smith's six-step technique. Twelve themes were extracted from data analysis. The themes are: " reign in family, in regret of other positions, extreme expectations, loneliness: Just yourself and yourself, need for family support, in search of compensation, credit link, weakness in emotional relationships, destructive worries, parent's educative encounter, self-adjustment, and confrontation with stereotypes". The findings of this study could provide a clear picture of one-child lived experience. In a general conclusion, the lived experiences of subjects show that those who are the only child are usually different in terms of life skills and individual capabilities, and this difference often shows itself in extremity. It should also be noted that one-child, because of lack of conflict of interests, usually has more facilities and welfare leading to emergence of some specific themes listed above.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_64642_0880414beff8a36cd5e35edc98c86423.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2017.238489.1007242]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A Study of the role of women in decision-making for family migration to Tehran province]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mahmoudian, Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mahmoudiani, Serajeddin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Family migration]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[migration decision-making]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[women’s status]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[power in the family]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[internal migration]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[migration network]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tehran Province]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[A majority of women in family migration flow are considered as tied migrants and their role in migration decision-making has generally been neglected. The current study aims to explain the role of women in decision-making for family migration to Tehran province. The target population includes women who have migrated to Tehran province during 2007-2017. Conducting a sample survey, a total of 500 migrant women were interviewed in the cities of Tehran and Mallard. The findings indicate that women’s participation in the decision-making process has significant positive relationships with their dissatisfaction with the origin place, and power in the family. The participation in female-oriented migrations is stronger compared to those in child-oriented and husband-oriented migrations. Women with pre-migration familiarity and contacts with the destination have shown to be more active in migration decision-making process than their other counterparts. Migrant women have utilized family migration as a strategy to eliminate the social constraints in the origin, to improve the family economic situation, and to enhance their children’s future security. In view of further improvement of women’s status in the country, women’s role in migration is expected to increase.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_64643_315243a1822efe0799bc9a967dcac3d7.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2017.233975.1007204]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Semantic reconstruction role of women in family enterprises (Case study of small and medium family businesses in Tehran Province)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Bani Fatemeh, Hossein]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohammadi Talvar, Sattar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Nozari, Hamza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Family economic enterprise]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[the role of women in enterprise]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[the challenges of women's presence]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[outcomes]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This paper studies family businesses in the province of Tehran, by adopting a cultural approach in the context of economic sociology. It takes a qualitative approach. The data were collected using semi-structured interviews with 25 CEOs of family firms. In order to analyze the findings coding method was used. The current study aims to provide a review of the role and status of women in this type of business from the perspective of the respondents. The results show that the role and position of women in the eyes of managers who are all men can be classified under three categories:  the role of women in enterprises (including formalism - immaterialness – controversy- invisibility- and lack of promotion);  challenges for the presence of women in enterprises (including relationships- jealousy- and familial distrust); and consequences (including family collapse and enterprise collapse). In general, the attitude and management of patriarchy as the most important family value system and culture dominates the role of women in the family business to a large extent. In addition, the presence of women in family-owned businesses is fraught with challenges that ultimately lead to consequences (for example, the weakening of family ties and the collapse of business) for both the family and the family business.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_64645_f2ca36d616c5cc8a13d7862076d07e33.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2017.239415.1007250]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A sociological study of body industry: Qualitative study of the causes and consequences of cosmetic surgery of women living in Tehran 1395]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mahmoodi, Yosra]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohadessi Ghilovaei, Hasan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Body industry]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[cosmetic surgery]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[body economy]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Women]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The current research aims at sociological investigation and understanding of body industry and cosmetic surgeries of women. This research is conducted using qualitative approach and grounded theory method. The tool used to collect data was a semi-structured interview. Targeted sampling was used to select the interviewees and theoretical sampling was used to identify the number of people. The population under study is women living in Tehran who have experienced cosmetic surgery. The number of examined sample is 27 women aged 20-60 who have experienced cosmetic surgery. Based on the findings, the causal of the research were the fear of being rejected and a negative mental picture of oneself. The desire for beauty and physical expressiveness is the pivotal cause of  surgery, which has happened in the context of social values and family conditions. Social constraints, sense of conflict, intervening conditions, promotions and encouragement by others for surgery are the facilitating reasons of this phenomenon. The implications and effects of the body industry, found in this study, are increasing confidence, saving time and economic savings.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_64651_bf9385d82350ec1c9bd8a496d70385b2.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2017.238833.1007247]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[Feminine money and sustaining family life: A study on families in Tehran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Alirezanejad, Soheila]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khakpour Marvasti, Elahe]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[family]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Women]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[the dual function of money]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[separation]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This research aims to analyze the effect of money and its dual function on the continuity of a family. In this regard, mixed method (field research and survey) is designed. The data were collected through semi-structured interview and questionnaire. The findings reveal that based on a traditional role men are bread winners of the family. Women’s ability of making money may bring a new financial challenge for men’s traditional role as breadwinners of family; which can create sort of new marital economic relations in the family. However, when this role is disturbed by women, some serious challenges happen in family’s life. This condition, particularly in the early years of marriage when the wife is young, results in emergence of the idea of separation. However, feminine money creates some experience of co-breadwinning for family which may create a new balance between spouses. As the age of marriage increases, this balance may prevent marital separation. Then, as sort of catalyst, feminine money plays a dual role in separation between spouses.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_64648_ed318eae8ff5cec32fb56c39cbcfd30f.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2017.248309.1007334]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[An analysis of the impact of tourism expansion on subjective well-being of rural women (Case study: tourist targeted villages of Awraman Region of Sarvaabad)]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohammadi, Saadi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Talati, Marzieh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Mohammadi, Arkan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Subjective Well-Being]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tourism]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[rural women]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Awraman region]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Nowadays, in order to build a jolly environment in the villages and achieve the subjective well-being of rural women who are isolated for social and economic reasons, given the great poverty and unemployment and the necessity to overcome these issues, the use of rural areas potentials for realization of economic growth and the presence of women in them are emphasized. Rural tourism due to its nature and related job opportunities income is welcomed and accepted by women. In this applied research, which is conducted  by descriptive-analytical method, the effects of women's presence in the rural tourism sector of the Awraman region were examined on their mental well-being. Accordingly, a questionnaire was distributed among 90 rural women in tourism destination villages, selected by targeted sampling, and analysis of the obtained data was done using one-sample inferential T, Xi-two, Friedman and Qi-two consonants. It was found that spread of tourism and the presence of women in related activities at a significant level of 0.001 and an average of 3.47, has increased and improved the mental well-being of rural women. Among the indicators, the cognitive indices of subjective well-being with an average of 3.55, and among the studied variables,  the satisfaction of the rural environment and dependence on it, the decrease of feeling of poverty and life satisfaction, respectively, have the highest degree of improvement of the situation and the effectiveness of women's presence in tourism activities. The findings also showed that there is a significant, positive and direct relationship between the level of satisfaction with development and income dependence on tourism activities and the level of vitality of rural women.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_64649_9f334edd49662b569d94a311f9b913f2.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2017.239962.1007256]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[A study of social vulnerability among female-headed households and headed women in Soltan-Abad District, Tehran]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khani, Saeed]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Khezri, Farsheed]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Yari, Katayoon]]></ags:creatorPersonal>

			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[Female-headed households]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[social vulnerability]]></dc:subject>
				<dc:subject><![CDATA[economic poverty]]></dc:subject>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The number of female-headed households has increased with extensive growth rate in recent decades. This group in line with the population growth rate, has experienced another qualitative changes such as age composition and education, income distribution and economic poverty changing issues relating to them as a relatively normal social condition to a social problem associated with damage over time. The current article aims to study and analyze social vulnerability among female-headed households and their children in comparison with  married women. The theoretical framework of the problem is derived from strain, social attachments and feminization of poverty theories. This study is a quasi-experimental research based on  survey technique. The investigation consists of two statistical populations. First, it consists of female-headed households who have been active in Setayesh-e-Mehr's Social Work Clinic in Soltan-Abad district-Tehran since 2015. The sampling method in the first population was enumeration. The second statistical population consisted of male-headed households in the same area selected with multi-stage cluster sampling to  be compared with the first group. The result showed that there is a significant difference among female-headed households and male-headed households regarding social isolation, tendency to addiction, children's delinquency and economic poverty. This evidence in conjunction with the theoretical framework, shows the position of  female-headed households in the socio-economic structure of society. Poverty and lack of social bound, and as a result, their experience of strain and lack of appropriate support, in  both formal and informal forms, make these women and their children vulnerable to harm.]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_64650_3ca913fb09626962c519612e2408e220.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2017.233709.1007203]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>
<ags:resource>
					<dc:title><![CDATA[English Abstracts]]></dc:title>
					<dc:creator>
					
			</dc:creator>
			<dc:publisher>
				<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[University of Tehran]]></ags:publisherName>
			</dc:publisher>
			<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2017]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
			<dc:description>
				<ags:descriptionNotes><![CDATA[Includes references]]></ags:descriptionNotes>
				<dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[]]></dcterms:abstract>
			</dc:description>
            <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_64991_410db200009f0ad5eac45674811ca740.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:identifier scheme="ags:DOI"><![CDATA[10.22059/jwdp.2017.64991]]></dc:identifier>
			<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
			<dc:format><dcterms:medium><![CDATA[text]]></dcterms:medium></dc:format>
			<dc:language><![CDATA[Persian]]></dc:language>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/]]></dc:source>
			<dc:source><![CDATA[Women in Development & Politics]]></dc:source>
		</ags:resource>

</ags:resources>