<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2002</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Social Participation of Women</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مشارکت اجتماعی زنان (1 )</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">26989</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ژاله  شادی</FirstName>
					<LastName>طلب</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>افسانه</FirstName>
					<LastName>کمالی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دوره دکتری جامعه شناسی ، دانشکده علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>There is no single sociological theory which can explain the full extent of women&#039;s social participation in the developing countries. An analytical framework is developed to serve the objectives of the research. This article presents a summary of most important findings on the types and intensity of women&#039;s social participation in the city of Tehran. Factors related to their social participation are divided into four groups: values- culture, family, personality and socio-economic characteristics of the individual and her family..
Religious and charity organizations have the highest rate of participation (over the group mean) and the levels of other types of social participations are much lower. Based on the intensity of social participations women are grouped into four categories: (1) Absolutely non-participants 38%, (2) Isolationists 31%, (3) Cultural participants 14% and (4) Social Participants 16%.  Structural and family norms are among the most important factors related to low levels of participation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">درجامعه شناسی نظریه واحدی که بتواند در توضیح وتبیین مشارکت اجتماعی زنان بویژه در کشورهای درحال توسعه بکار گزفته شود کمتر یافت می شود . بنابراین چارچوب مفهومی خاصی برای این پژوهش طراحی شد . این مقاله بخشی از یافته های پژوهشی  را ارئه می کند که  با هدف بررسی میزان و عوامل موثر بر مشارکت اجتماعی زنان در سطح شهر تهران انجام گرفته است .
متغیر های پژوهشی شامل ویژگی های فرهنگی- ارزشی- خانوادگی و اقتصادی- اجتماعی است. یافته ها حاکی از سطح مشارکت مذهبی- خیریه ای بالاتر از متوسط و گرایش اندک به سایر انواع مشارکت های اجتماعی در میان زنان است.
زنان بر اساس میزان مشارکت اجتماعی به چهار گروه تفکیک شده اند : منفعل ترین گروه زنان 38 درصد، انزواجویان 31 درصد، فعالان فرهنگی 14 درصد و مشارکت جوترین زنان که 16 درصد از کل جامعه مورد بررسی را تشکیل می دهند. محدودیت های ساختاری و خانوادگی از بارزترین موانع مشارکت اجتماعی زنان گزارش شده است .</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشارکت اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_26989_2885636737a89558482c60ace5156bc2.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
