<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>First Pages</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>16</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>2</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_67031_e73e9ff50a91ff7b542d284fe1242d50.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2018.67031</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Fields and Domains of Decision-Making by Housewives; a Semantic Reconstruction of the Experiences and Understanding of Women In Sanandaj</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Omid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Qaderzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Sociology,Kurdistan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parivash</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Hoseini</namePart>
				<affiliation>Postgraduate Alumnus of Sociology,Kurdistan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The scope of power of housewives is subject to limitations due to their fragile and vulnerable position in the economic and social structures. One of the areas on the basis of which women’s empowerment could be assessed is the decision-making process in everyday life. The purpose of this research is to reconstruct the lived experience of married women in decision-making and explore the fields, consequences and the ways of women’s exposure to the phenomenon of decision-making through the perception and mental conceptualization of the actions that they exploit in their everyday life as a source of power to enhance their agency in the environment. The present study was carried out with a qualitative approach in the grounded theory. Target sampling with maximum diversity was used to select the samples; and semi-structured interview was used to collect the data. The results of interview with 28 samples of Sanandaj women indicate that self-esteem, re-conceptualization and risk-taking, family support, gender stereotypes, experience (of decision making), and resources available to women constitute the grounds for decision making of women. The semantic reconstruction of the experience and understanding of women of decision making shows the women appeal to such strategies as logical dialogue, due and timely fulfillment of responsibilities, financial independence and support, raising the expectations, and strike. The decision-making experience for women contributes to their sense of value, collective belonging, self-reliance, empowerment and self-esteem.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>16</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>25</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_66215_b394a27a65d456ef425170900c3b54f3.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2018.249993.1007357</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The role of charities in the production and continuation of women's poverty</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehri</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Bahar</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Tehran University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Foroughi</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA in Tehran University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The purpose of this present study is to analyze subjective meaning of Isfahanian Philanthropists on their indifferences toward health centers for women. These centers have been recently founded by legislation of the council of ministers to investigate the women prone to drug abuse and prostitution (direct or indirect). While these centers demand financial resources, they are rejected or ignored by the philanthropists. Many researchers and officials on this domain believe that financial needs is one important reason that people in need move toward deviations. For this purpose, through qualitative approach and phenomenal methodology the present study is analyzed to gain an emphatic understanding on the participants` attitude taking part in this study. Data have been collected through 10 profound interviews within a seven-level method named Colaizzi. The findings of this research have revealed that not only Isfahanian Philanthropists completely disagreed with the think to help the women dealing with drug and prostitution, but they also attempted to enforce  the violence to prevent them from taking responsibility. It can be claimed that they are faced with the thoughts “not having trust to people and officials” and “assigning the responsibility of organizing them to that government” codes. In this approach, “patriarchal attitudes toward hurt women and women in charge of them” is highly obvious. About hostile disagreement, not only we are faced with divesting their responsibilities but also we witnessed violent opinions and ask for enforcing punishment for these women.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>16</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>27</start>
					<end>49</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_66218_80c7f0ef1b0af897d7197a36071c9423.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2018.240650.1007268</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Identifying the Context of Designing a Model for Successful Social Integration of Offender Women: A Grounded Theory Approach</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Zahra</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mirhosseini</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Alzahra University, Department of women and family studies</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mahsa</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Larijani</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of police university</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The present study attempts to investigate the social integration of prisoners via a grounded theory approach. It is aimed to explain a model for successful social integration of female offenders. In this qualitative study, the data were collected through in-depth semi-structured interviews with 21 women who had a record in the Welfare Services Organization, and all of whom have had previous experience of being in jail. Then, using a grounded theory approach, the data were analyzed and coded. The exploratory findings of the study show that various factors contribute to the formation of the core category, that is, “social integration as a move towards the normalization of life and social adaptation” of women. Other contextual factors such as personal characteristics is supported and not rejected by the family and access to capitals are significant too. Moreover, interventional factors such as maternal motivation, empowerment and rehabilitation of women, and not using drugs influence the process of social integration. Analytical findings indicate that the strategies and solutions for social integration of women have two categories of environmental appropriateness and sanitation, and the development of social networks. Ultimately, all these factors and strategies contribute to satisfaction from life, adaptability and social organization, or in other words, social integration of women.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>16</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>51</start>
					<end>78</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_66219_d01ee06789009b7cc65fc2ef66473952.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2018.246504.1007316</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Editing the Strategies for Psychological Empowerment of Women in Rural Areas using Strategic Management Tools (SWOT-QSPM)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghasemi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof. of Geography and Rural Planning, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Lida</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Alizadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Ph.d Student of Geography and Rural Planning, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Elham</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghandehari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Masters student of Geography and Rural Planning, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Empowerment is the linking point between development and women which is closely connected to continuous improvement, competency enhancement, behavioral changes, and development of women’s performance. It is considered as a part of establishing the concept of development. As the focal point in the area of empowerment lies within women’s ability to control their future (psychological empowerment), the present study seeks to identify and prioritize various approaches for psychological empowerment of women in rural areas. The descriptive-analytical method was used in this applied-developmental study. Data have been collected using documents and field studies. The data were then analyzed using SWOT-QSPM by strategic management tools. In this study, 142 women from the rural areas of Torghabeh and Binaloud County voluntarily participated to fill out the questionnaires. Given the final scores of IFE=1.79 and EFE=2.60 in SWOT matrix, defensive strategies (minimum-minimum) were identified as optimal for psychological empowerment of women in rural areas. Among the ten strategies outlined using the QAPM (Quantitative Strategic Planning Matrix), the most important strategy was “the identification of restrictive and facilitative factors for psychological empowerment of women in rural areas. The strategy attempts to mitigate the following obstacles”, with a score of 1.176; the second and third strategies with scores of 0.256 and 0.219 were “holding various educational workshops in line with psychological empowerment of women in rural areas”, and “encouraging women in rural areas to form cooperatives as well as various NGOs for women and supporting them”, respectively.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>16</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>79</start>
					<end>109</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_66221_a6b05cbb93cc17abc44c75d9c96b9566.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2018.245090.1007300</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Qualitative investigation about the drug trafficking from the perspective of women smugglers in the central prison of Kerman</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amir</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Soltani Nejad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Sociology Ph.D, Khaje nasiradin toosi Farhangian University, Kerman, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Adibeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Barshan</namePart>
				<affiliation>Educational Measurement PhD candidate, Tehran University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amirsadra</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Asadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA in Educational Administration, Islamic Azad University, Kerman</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Balvardi</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA in anthropology, expert staff counternarcotics Kerman</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Sadei</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Department of Social Sciences, Farhangian University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Drug trafficking is one of the complex social problems of the present time. This is the cause of many social injuries and deviations. This phenomenon targets not only individual security but also national security of the community. In this research, the qualitative method has been used to recreate life experience of women to identify the causes and areas of their exposure to narcotics trafficking. The research data were obtained from a deep interview with 18 trafficked women in the central prison of Kerman. The subjects were selected through purposeful sampling. The results were analyzed using thematic analysis approach. According to the results, the causes of drug trafficking by women can be found in eight main themes: women&#039;s situations, economic system problems, weaknesses in coping systems, ecological platforms of the region, family problems, cultural poverty, inferior friends and class contradictions. Therefore, the smuggling of drugs by women is a phenomenon of several causes. The causes and areas of its formation should not be sought only in a person or a particular entity; it is also always a set of cultural, social and environmental factors, family, judicial, law enforcement, and individual causes were the basis of smuggling.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>16</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>111</start>
					<end>129</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_66224_a53e53c1f99dea89c0651dcbe3fdeac1.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2018.239629.1007252</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Social Factors Affecting Spouse Abuse in the Family with Emphasis on the Role of Patriarchy System of the Family</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Manijeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Navidnia</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Sociology of Islamic Azad University of Garmsar Branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ebrahim</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shamloo</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA in Sociology, Islamic Azad University of  garmsar Branch</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>One of the social harms that threatens the community is a spouse who presents himself in different ways in the institution of the family. The purpose of the present study is to identify the relationship between social factors affecting wives abusers in 2017. The relationship has been analyzed by using a descriptive-analytical approach and using a questionnaire tool and using SPSS software. The statistical population is consisted of 120 married women who were selected by random sampling method. The results show that male-dominated attitudes have a significant and meaningful relationship with the wife abuse. There is also a significant difference between spouses of different ages. The final results of the study indicated that  as the patriarchal system, the unequal power, male dominance over women, the patriarchal domination system, the superiority of the male class on women, and the oppression of women in society are increased, and the violation against women in society is also increased. This can, itself, intensify the role of the patriarchal system and its prevalence.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>16</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>131</start>
					<end>147</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_66225_65615b3286aa2c24efe1fff5f268fce8.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2018.238552.1007244</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Rural Women’s Cooperatives as a Potential for Social Entrepreneurship (Case Study: Mehr Afarin e Eram as a Rural Women's Cooperative)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Seyed Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Firouzabadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associated Professor of Sociology, in the field of social development, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Imani Jajarmi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associated Professor of Sociology, in the field of social development, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hamideh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Dabbaghi</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD of sociology, in the field of social development, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Nowadays, social entrepreneurship in the form of different organizational structures (profit, non-profit, or combination, charities, cooperatives, joint-stock companies, businesses, unions) creates social value. The  cooperatives play an expanding role in the society and the number of women as their member is increasing.  This research is to investigate whether rural women&#039;s cooperatives in Iran, considering they are a combination of both private and public sectors, can be a platform for social entrepreneurship. We have analyzed eight interviews rural women as members of a rural women&#039;s cooperative and the text of law about cooperative companies. Moreover, we have applied grounded theory as our method and the MAX QDA as a software to analyze qualitative data. The results of this research show that 438 semantic terms were extracted and categorized into 5 categories of clusters, 16 main themes, and 42 sub-themes. During the establishment of a cooperative in 2011, there have been two kinds of capital-financial facilities, human capital and knowledge. The nature of the created business in the cooperative has addressed rural women as the community and their problems as social problems. Analysis of the social problems shows that this cooperative has initially intended to create job for the entrepreneurs and secondly to solve the local economic problems of women, especially those as the head of the household. The Entrepreneurship Environment in the rural women&#039;s cooperatives (Mehr Afarin Eram) consists of four main factors: entrepreneurs, rural women as local community, special aspects in social, cultural, economic and legal contexts, as well as the obstacles against the cooperatives. Strategies of these cooperatives are formed via current strategies like training part, human resource management, financial, production and sales as well as development strategies in the future. Additionally, the achievements and outcomes of the cooperatives shows that Mehr Afarin Eram can empower women, create objective and subjective values, and achieve financial success.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>16</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>149</start>
					<end>173</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_66227_226e21e5d967b28c72a6271fda80f93a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2018.238461.1007241</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>English Abstracts</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2018</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>16</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>1</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2018</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>7</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_67029_7ce4bcc8f1b88159eb3aac065a9b3cca.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2018.67029</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>