<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Survey on the Factors Affecting Women’s Political Participation (Case Study: Women in Booshehr City)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر مشارکت سیاسی زنان مطالعۀ موردی زنان شهر بوشهر</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>265</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>286</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">52359</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2014.52359</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>اطهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار علوم سیاسی دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ابوالقاسم</FirstName>
					<LastName>شهریاری</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد علوم سیاسی دانشگاه فرودسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Political participation is an indication of democracy and political development and legitimacy in different societies. The more participation in a society occurs, the more legitimacy a political system will have. So, the efforts of Iranian political system are toward increasing people’s political participation rate. Since half of the Iranian world consists of women, a survey on the factors affecting their political participation can make us understand how and why the political participation is done and reveal the solutions to increase women’s participation. The purpose of this paper which has been done through survey-research method is to consider the factors that affect the political participation of women in Booshehr. The sample size is comprised of 350 persons who have been selected by cluster sampling (urban areas) and random sampling. The obtained results show that women in Booshehr have either mass or observational participation. The equation obtained by regression shows that the variable of political awareness has the most effect on increasing women’s political participation. After that, variables of being religious, educational level, feeling of powerlessness, social rank, feeling of political efficacy, and membership in communities have the most effect on women’s political participation. Among these variables, the variable of political powerlessness has negative effects on political participation.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مشارکت سیاسی از نشانه‌های دموکراسی و توسعه و مشروعیت سیاسی در جوامع مختلف است. هر اندازه میزان مشارکت در جامعه افزایش یابد، مشروعیت نظام سیاسی هم افزایش خواهد یافت. به همین دلیل نیز، تلاش نظام سیاسی ایران در جهت افزایش هرچه بیشتر میزان مشارکت سیاسی مردم است. از آنجاکه نیمی از زیست جهان ایرانی متشکل از زنان است، بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر مشارکت سیاسی آنان می‌تواند فهم ما از علل و چگونگی مشارکت سیاسی را مشخص سازد و راهکارهای بهبود مشارکت زنان را نمایان کند. هدف از این تحقیق، که به روش پیمایش صورت گرفته است، بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر مشارکت سیاسی زنان در شهر بوشهر است. حجم نمونه 350 نفر بوده که به روش خوشه‌ای (مناطق شهری) و تصادفی انتخاب شده‌اند. نتایج حاصل نشان می‌دهد که کیفیت مشارکت زنان بوشهری از نوع توده‌ای یا تماشاگرانه است. معادلۀ حاصل از رگرسیون، متغیر آگاهی سیاسی را دارای بیشترین تأثیر بر افزایش مشارکت سیاسی زنان نشان داده و پس‌ از آن، متغیرهای مذهبی‌بودن، تحصیلات، احساس بی‌قدرتی، طبقۀ اجتماعی، احساس اثربخشی سیاسی و عضویت در انجمن‌ها بیشترین اثر را بر مشارکت سیاسی زنان دارند که در این میان متغیر بی‌قدرتی سیاسی اثر منفی بر مشارکت سیاسی دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بوشهر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشارکت سیاسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_52359_a14a236ced01a815d5a956051722113c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
