<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>7</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2009</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Reproduction of Gender Roles in Farsi Textbooks of Iranian Primary Schools</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بازتولید نقش‌های جنسیتی در کتاب‌های فارسی مقطع ابتدایی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">28288</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی¬رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>افشانی</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>عسکری¬ندوشن</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سمیه     فاضل</FirstName>
					<LastName>¬نجف¬آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The purpose of this article is to investigate the differences between men and women’s painting regardless of being limited to presuppositions about masculine and feminine art. Therefore, first the appearance of differences between men and women art during the eighteenth and nineteenth century is considered. Having done that, various types of women’s painting, Feminine painting and feminism painting are compared. Finally, by presenting a theoretical model, the article delineates the differences between visual technique, artistic style, and coloration in men’s and women’s painting. The statistic universe contains 2525 painting and the sample universe contains 370 painting which are presented in 60active gallery in Tehran in the first quarter of 1387. It is concluded that regarding visual technique, women’s painting is brighter, more ordered, clearer and more decorative than that of the men’s painting. They are also more symbolic and decorative from the point of style.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">چکیده: در سالیان اخیر، تغییراتی مهم در تدوین کتاب‏ها‏ی درسی صورت پذیرفته و محتوای آن‌ها بازنگری شده است. تحقیق حاضر، شیوه‌ی بازتولید نقش‌های جنسیتی در محتوای کتاب‏های فارسی دوره‌ی دبستان را مطالعه می‌کند. به همین منظور، محتوای کتاب‏ها‏ در چهار مؤلفه‌ی تصاویر، خویشاوندان، والدین و نقش‌های شغلی با استفاده از تکنیک تحلیل محتوا مطالعه شده است. یافته‌ها نشان می‏دهد که تصاویر جنس مذکر به‌وضوح بیشتر از تصاویر جنس مؤنث است. زنان بیشتر در نقش‏های کودکی و نوجوانی و مردان عمدتاً در نقش‏های بزرگ‌سالی به تصویر کشیده شده‌اند. هم‌چنین، خویشاوندان مذکر به‌نحوی چشم‌گیر بیش از خویشاوندان مؤنث منعکس شده‌اند. اگرچه در سالیان اخیر تعداد و تنوع مشاغل معرفی‌شده بیشتر شده، ولی نسبتِ مشاغل زنانه کمتر و نسبتِ مشاغل مردانه بیشتر شده است. بر اساس نتایج، انتساب نقش خانه‏داری به زنان کاهش و ترسیم زنان در نقش‏های حرفه‏ای و تخصصی افزایش یافته است. بر خلاف سایر موارد، در معرفی والدین، انعکاس نقش‌های جنسیتی زنان بیش از مردان بود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هویت جنسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازتولید ارزش‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کتاب فارسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل محتوا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نقش شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_28288_277b217bc51771976d2f2ea556fcaff6.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
