<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>11</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The impact of the Gender Gap on the Electoral Behavior of Women in Isfahan</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر شکاف جنسیتی بر رفتار انتخاباتی زنان در شهر اصفهان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>65</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>82</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">35480</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2013.35480</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاتمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم سیاسی دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهه</FirstName>
					<LastName>امامی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد علوم سیاسی دانشگاه اصفهان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The impact of gender gap on voting behavior generally is categorized into the traditional gap, convergence and Revisionist patterns. This paper, Firstly By using survey research method and data were collected from 230 eligible male and female voters in Isfahan, makes clear that the first pattern or the traditional gender gap is dominated in this electorate, which denotes that women are more conservative than men. Secondly, it suggests that the effect of traditional gender gap on the population of women is not homogeneous and factors such as the level of education and age of women reduce or increase the level of their conservatism. Thirdly, by showing a relation between gender gap and subordinate behavior explains a relation between women’s conservatism and their subordinate behavior. Then makes clear that the factors reduce women’s conservatism and women&#039;s subordinate behavior are the same. Ultimately, the key idea underlying this paper is that the impact of gender or the gender gap on the electoral behavior of women do not simply biologically or predetermined, but somewhat this behavior is multi-layer and is constructed in the context of community and by the non-gender factors. In the latter instance, the construction of women&#039;s political behavior shows the extent to which attention to the mechanism for political empowerment of women is necessary.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تأثیر شکاف‌های جنسیتی بر رفتار انتخاباتی عموماً در قالب سه الگوی شکاف سنتی، همگرایی و تجدید نظرطلبانه صورتبندی شده اند. این مقاله با استفاده از روش پیمایشی و جمع‌آوری داده از بین 230 نفر زن و مرد در شرایط رأی‌دهی در شهر اصفهان، نشان داد که اولاً الگوی شکاف جنسیتی سنتی یا محافظه کارتر بودن زنان نسبت به مردان در این جامعه آماری تفوق داشته است. ثانیاً تأثیر این شکاف جنسیتی سنتی در جامعه آماری زنان یکدست نبوده و عواملی مانند تحصیلات و سن باعث کاهش یا افزایش میزان محافظه کاری زنان شده است. ثالثاً با تایید رابطه معنادار میان جنسیت و رفتار تبعی زنان مشخص گردید عواملی که باعث کاهش میزان محافظه کاری زنان شده اند میزان رفتار تبعی زنان را نیز کاهش داده اند. نهایتاً مقاله متضمن این ایده کلیدی است که تأثیر عامل جنسیت بر رفتار انتخاباتی زنان را نباید صرفاً تاثیری از پیش تعیین شده، بیولوژیک و مبتنی بر هویت‌های پایدار جنسیتی آنها دانست بلکه رفتار انتخاباتی زنان رفتاری چندلایه است که تا حدی در متن اجتماع و از طریق عوامل غیر جنسیتی نیز برساخته می شود. همین برساخته شدن نسبی رفتار سیاسی زنان مشخص می سازد تا چه حد توجه به شیوه‌های توانمند سازی سیاسی زنان ضروری به نظر می رسد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شکاف جنسیتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار انتخاباتی  زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رفتار تبعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محافظه کاری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_35480_017211faffb4f5ab8917146802f318b0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
