<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>6</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2003</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>جنبش اجتماعی زنان ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">11360</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName></FirstName>
					<LastName>Unknown</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Common futures in the definitions of new social movements, allow us to call the ongoing process among Iranian women a “social movement”. This movement is distinguished by women challenging legal inequality among men and women and other deficiencies in different aspects of their life. To understand the goals and principals of the movement, a survey on the attitudes of activists in Iranian women social movement is carried out. The samples are selected from women NGOs. The research findings show an organized move among Iranian women with the goal of improvement in their life. The main futures of the movement are: efforts to decline legal inequalities, fact based evaluation, and concerns on sex differences, without any prejudice. The most and basic problem of Iranian women is legal inequality between men and women which is rooted in cultural values, biased and inferior attitudes of society towards women.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در میان زنان ایران معاصر پویشی در جریان است که با توجه به عناصر مشترکی که در تعاریف جنبش های اجتماعی جدید وجود دارد می توان آن را یک جنبش نامید جنبشی که با چالش های زنان نسبت به نابرابری های قانونی حقوقی میان زنان و مردان و سایر مسائل آنان درحوزه های گوناگون زندگی مشخص می شود این مقاله با استفاده از یافته های پژوهشی میدانی با هدف درک ویژگیها اصول و اهداف جتنبش اجتماعی زنان ایران نگرش فعالان جنبش زنان ایران را که درتشکل های زنان فعالیت می کنند مورد کند وکاو قرار داده است این پژوهش سعی بر این دارد نشان دهد بین زنان ایران حرکت سازمان یافته ای با هدف بهبود وضعیت زندگی شکل گرفته است تلاش برای کاهش نابرابری حقوقی زن و مرد ارزیابی واقع گرایانه از ماهیت دو جنس( بدون جهت گیری فمینیستی ) از ویژگی های این حرکت سازمان یافته می باشد یافته های این پژوهش نشان می دهد مساله اولیه زنان ایران نابرابری حقوقی بین زنان و مردان است که ریشه در ارزش های فرهنگی و نگرش سوگیرانه و فرودستانه جامعه نسبت به زن دارد .</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">برابری حقوقی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنبش های اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فمینیسم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نگرش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_11360_5adb84ef9bb42334a76de7b7af7a482e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
