<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>7</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2003</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نوگرایی زنان فعال در حوزه فرهنگی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">11372</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName></FirstName>
					<LastName>Unknown</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Rapid technological and cultural changes of the past two centuries in developed countries and their effects on modernization in other societies, including Iran, have preoccupied many social scientists. This study aims to measure the level of modernity among women who are active in the cultural realm (teaching profession). Modernization theories confirm that conditions such as urban dwelling, industrialization, level of education, communication, social participation, socialization patterns, and socio-economic status accelerate modernization. The modem individual believes in science, adapts to new experiences, seeks equality and independence, is achievement-oriented, civil-minded, global and democratic, and takes risks. The study applied secondary data and surveyed women teachers in the city of Tehran. The findings reveal that 72.3% of the instructors are modern-oriented and that education length and social status has a significant relationship with levels of modernity.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تحولات سریع تکنولوژیکی و فرهنگی دو سده اخیر کشورهای توسعه یافته و تاثیر آن در نوسازی سایر جوامع از جمله جامعه ایران توجه پژوهشگران بسیاری را به خود جلب کرده است . نظریه های نوسازی تاکید دارند که عواملی همچون میزان شهرنشینی – صنعتی شدن – سطح تحصیلات – ارتباطات – مشارکت اجتماعی – چگونگی اجتماعی شدن و پایگاه اجتماعی – اقتصاد فرد نوگرایی در جوامع را تسریع می کنند . فرد نوع گرا نیز دارای ویژگی هایی مانند علم گرایی – پذیرش تجربیات جدید – پیشرفت گرایی – نگرش های مدنی و جهانی و دموکراتیک – تساوی طلبی – استقلال طلبی و خطر پذیری است . هدف این پژوهش سنجش میزان نوگرایی زنان فعال در حوزه فرهنگی ( دبیران ) و عوامل موثر بر آن است که با روش پژوهش کتابخانه ای و پیمایشی انجام شده است و جامعه آماری آن زنان دبیر شهر تهران هستند . یافته های پژوهش نشان می دهد که 3/72 در صد زنان دبیر مطالعه نوگرا هستند و دو عامل طول مدت تحصیل و پایگاه اقتصادی – اجتماعی با میزان نوگرایی رابطه معانادار دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آموزش</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پیشرفت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زبان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرهنگ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">معلمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نگرش</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_11372_689964d86a9d2d1ccf976ec7736a29ae.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
