<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>First Pages</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>2</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_63335_b5c7a59617bee45c998da65566e41e6c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Social exclusion of poor women in urban life (Case study: urban poor women supported by relief Committee of Imam Khomeini in Urmia)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zahedi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Payam-e- Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Parvaneh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Danesh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Payam-e- Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Firouz</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Payam-e- Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Reza</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mojarab Qushchi</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student in Sociology, Payam-e- Noor University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Existing evidence shows that poor women who live in urban areas face different kinds of social exclusion. The present study investigates the roots of social exclusion in small scale and everyday life of these people aiming to clarify some dimensions of this problem. Qualitative method has been used in this study, and research data were collected through interviewing 32 poor women supported by Relief Committee of Imam Khomeini in Urmia. The results obtained from this study were analyzed by grounded theory approach. The obtained results showed that five factors including poor cultural capital, financial limitations, negative approach to the poor, being single and negative life events give rise to social exclusion in these women’s life. Avoiding social unification and negative attitudes are two major consequences of this issue which strengthen this phenomenon. The final and central aspect which encompasses the entire process of social exclusion has been presented as norm-bonded failure. In terms of ways by which social exclusion happens, there are delicate forms of disgrace and deprivation in poor women&#039;s life which are not identifiable through quantitative or economical approaches.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>291</start>
					<end>310</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_63326_770fec6ff9366d70d6f02b14b0f05f78.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.219352.1007081</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>An analysis of the relationship between women’s employment and fertility rate in Iran</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Hassan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Fotros</namePart>
				<affiliation>Professor in Economics, Bu Ali Sina University, Hamedan</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Maryam</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Najmi</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA in Economics, Islamic Azad University, Arak</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abbas</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Memarzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor in Economics, Vali’ Asr University, Rafsanjan</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>One of the biggest developments of the recent decades has been dramatic women’s participation in social and economic fields, and in this regard, the relationship between women’s participation in the labor market as one of the important and influential factors in economic growth, and fertility rate as one of the effective factors in population growth, has been taken into account. Many empirical studies have shown the  relationship between women’s employment and fertility rate to be negative. On the one hand, many researchers found that in the European countries, there was a negative correlation between these two variables in the labor market before the 1980s, while the correlation became positive afterwards. Therefore, in this study, using 1360-1392 annual data, extracted from central bank and statistical center of Iran, and ARDL BOUND TESTING approach, we investigate the relationship between employment rate and fertility. The findings indicate that the impact of marriage age, urbanization rate, and per capita income on fertility rate is negative while the effect of women’s employment rate on fertility rate is positive. This indicates that, increased employment rate and thereby creation of financial security give rise to an increase in the tendency for fertility among women; therefore,  the negative relationship shown in previous studies is not confirmed.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>311</start>
					<end>325</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_63327_bac886f97de95398f402521288eca191.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.230655.1007176</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Imam Khomeini and the construction of a female identity in the Islamic Revolution</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Masoud</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Kosari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Social Communication Sciences, Faculty of Social Sciences, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Amirali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tafreshi</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student, Social Communication Sciences, Faculty of Social Sciences, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Masoumeh Sadat</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Alavi Nekoo</namePart>
				<affiliation>. MA, Social Communication Sciences, Faculty of Social Sciences, Allameh Tabataba&amp;#039;i University, Tehran, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The Islamic Revolution of Iran can be identified as the emergence of a discursive transformation in Iranian society. This revolution, not only was indicative of a discursive and semantic transformation in the context of the Iranian society, but also it was able to create a new sign and a new meaning within the context of global discourses; thus, Foucault also mentioned this revolution as &quot;the soul of a world repulsions.&quot; The present study for understanding the characteristics of this discursive evolution, aimed to study its most influential theorist, Imam Khomeini, the founder of the Islamic Revolution. Given the necessity of creating boundaries for the study of discourse analysis, one of the most controversial discourse disciplines, that is, the discursive order of female identity, was chosen for study in this discourse. At the next phase, according to the macro view and the abstract mapping of discursive articulation, using Laclau and Mouffe&#039;s approach, this theory and method was chosen for analyzing the discourse of Imam Khomeini&#039;s speeches. According to the findings, the central sign of this discourse is &quot;preservation of chastity and religiosity&quot; and despite the conformity of some of the signs of this discourse with hegemonic discourses in the Western world, such as &quot;social activity&quot; and &quot;freedom,&quot; all this is defined around &quot;The preservation of chastity and religiosity&quot; in this discourse, and a meaning different from other discourses is created. This discourse, which emerges in the apparent controversy with the second Pahlavi’s discourse, is also seriously deconstructing its hostile discourse-especially in the case of removing the shame from society- and attempts to marginalize it. Among epistemes that these two conflicting discourses have used to marginalize their rival discourse, are &quot; being foreign&quot;, &quot;seeing women as objects&quot;, &quot;ignorance&quot;, &quot; negligence&quot; and &quot; &quot;approval of prostitution.&quot;  On the contrary, the well-known fundamental epistemes that these two discourses have used for their hegemony in the Discursive Order of feminine identity include: &quot;belief in progress&quot;, &quot;support of freedom&quot;, &quot;respect for women&quot;, &quot;belief in equality of women and men&quot; and &quot;being civilized&quot;.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>327</start>
					<end>357</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_63329_f575d980c27a27955871e31550889f00.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.219672.1007085</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Investigating the role of employment and education of women on economic growth in Iran: Gravitational search algorithm and Firefly algorithm approach</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ahmad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Asadzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor, Tabriz University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Nina</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mirani</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student in Economy, Tabriz University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Forough</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghazi khani</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA in Economy, Bu Ali Sina University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Najmaeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Esmail Darjani</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student in Economy, Tabriz University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Atieh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Honardoust</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Student in Economy, Isfahan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>To enrich the complex process of development and the role of human resources as one of its main factors, it is essential to review the role of the human resources, especially the role of women, who constitute half of the world population. In recent years, the new socio-economic phenomenon of the female participation in the labor market has emerged. Empowering women and removing the obstacles improve the political, social and economic conditions of the society, as it brings about the sustainable growth and development. The present paper gives an analysis on the relationship between the variables affecting economic growth during the period 1380- 1393, with emphasis on the role of employment and education of women. Then, by using the Gravitational Search Algorithm (GSA) and Firefly Algorithm (FA), the economic development of the country is estimated in the form of non-linear equations with emphasis on the rate of the economic participation of women and their education. The findings indicate that increasing rate of women&#039;s economic participation in the labor market has a positive and significant impact on the country&#039;s GDP as the growth of the literacy level in form of an intersection variable has a positive impact on the rate of the women&#039;s economic participation and as a whole on GDP.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>359</start>
					<end>381</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_63330_bb8de5e8eb9e3cee5f4c84257821cf7c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.225995.1007138</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A study of population dynamics on gender equality in Iran (An emphasis on population composition)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Tavakkol</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Aghayari Hir</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD in Demography, Assistant Professor in Department of Social Sciences, University of Tabriz</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Golabi</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD in Sociology, Associate Professor in Department of Social Sciences, University of Tabriz</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mehdi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shafeiy Zazali</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA in Sociology, University of Tabriz</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Demographic changes can affect all facets of development, including gender equality, as one of the main components of development. This study aimed at investigating the relationship between changes in population composition and gender equality in Iran during 1956-2011. The relationship is studied with a descriptive-analytical approach using secondary data and time-series models at national level. The data was obtained from Statistical Center of Iran’s population time series and various censuses’ data. Findings suggest that Composite Gender Equality Index improved considerably during the study period, and urbanization, age structure of the population, as well as women’s average age at marriage, significantly affected the composite index of gender equality. Besides, AR (1) and MA (2) components of the fitted Arima model have expectedly shown significant effect on the gender equality’s variations. Three independent variables, aggregately accounted for 33 percent of gender equality’s variance during the study period.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>383</start>
					<end>401</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_63331_2e7c48846a0762fa113c53f05c044234.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.232086.1007190</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Semantic reconstruction of girls’ lived experience of singleness</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Omid</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Qaderzadeh</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Sociology, Kurdistan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Gholami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Postgraduate Alumnus of Sociology, Kurdistan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Elahe</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Gholami</namePart>
				<affiliation>Postgraduate Alumnus of Sociology, Kurdistan University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Single girls are among the groups that are subject to rejection because of their fragile and vulnerable situation in social and economic structures. The current study aims to reconstruct the meaning of singleness experience and find the backgrounds and the way single girls encounter singleness through perception and subjective meaning of the girls who are involved in this process. The current paper was conducted by applying qualitative approach and the grounded theory among single girls of Ivan County. In order to choose the samples, we used purposive sampling and also we used maximum diversity for collecting data from Semi-structured interviews.  In this case study, 28 single girls participated. They were different in terms of using economic, social and cultural capitals.  The findings suggest that women are subject to singleness because of war trauma and education. In between , stabilization of accepted reasons, the need for commitment, gender-based nature of public space, and accepted restrictions are shown to be the facilitator reason, and dependency depiction in media is represented as confounding condition. Reconstructing the meaning of girls’ experience and understanding singleness imply the camouflage obligation, religious places as a friendly place, politics of presence, tendency to female occupations, rethinking and virtualization of relationships. Based on the current study, girls’ lived experience of singleness results in psychological violence, double isolation, ambiguous future and feeling of being a burden. Also, the core category implies the unavailability of situations.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>403</start>
					<end>426</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_63332_cb5a6f5de40a35fdd7f10230d8751df4.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.223685.1007116</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Suicidal behavior among women of Abdanan: motivations and conditions</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Akbar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zare Shahabadi</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Professor of Sociology, Department of Social Sciences, Yazd University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mojtaba</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shafiee Nejad</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA in Sociology, Yazd University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Javad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Madahi</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA in Sociology, Yazd University</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Suicidal behavior is defined as a non-fatal act wherein the person consciously and purposefully and without the interference of others, in order to achieve the desired changes, does self-painful and self-harmful acts, which is understood and interpreted in various ways by different people. The purpose of this research, Background discovery and has been involved in Suicide emprise Through perception and the intrinsic meaning women who have been involved in this process. Study with qualitative methods and deep interview among women was Abdanan city. The sample consisted of 23 women who participated have experienced suicide That in terms of age, education, place of residence, marital status were different. A sample of purposive sampling was used to collect data from interview. Data were analyzed with no coding style. According to the findings, women collaborator perceive Suicide is a way to express and achieve the desired In order to try to hegemonic behavior, restrictions, slander and selfishness, react and manage it. In the end, improve supporting role in suicide prevention as a strategy is very important.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>427</start>
					<end>446</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_63333_4be82cbb5e57f13832b42a10a0e60d8a.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2017.229631.1007164</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>English Abstracts</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2017</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract></abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>15</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>3</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2017</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>1</start>
					<end>7</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_63334_46319d8f7bb4d85364b01a469b70bfc9.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi"></identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>