<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Gender representation in the course books of Middle School and High School (Case Study Farsi Course book of 2009-10)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>باز نمایی جنسیت در کتب فارسی مقاطع تحصیلی راهنمایی و دبیرستان در سال تحصیلی 89- 1388</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>75</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>96</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">29483</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2012.29483</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاضری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکترای جامعه‌شناسی و عضو هیأت علمی گروه جامعه‌شناسی دانشگاه تربیت مدرس</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>احمدپور خرّمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مطالعات فرهنگی دانشگاه علم و فرهنگ تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Course books do not only educate students but also prepare them to take responsibilities proportional to their gender as planned by the author. This research is trying to examine the way that gender is represented in Farsi books of middle school and the first three grades of high school in non-human science fields in the academic year 2009-10. Research method was through analyzing the quantity content for indicators like images, names, authors of books, course book writers, and characters presented in set texts. Content quality analysis was used to analyze the quality of representations of images and content of set texts. On the basis of Altosser and Bourdieu theories, this research tries to find out the way the gender is represented in books. The results show that more attention has been paid to men in terms of quantity and women- according to the criteria- have no significant presence. In terms of quality women in their few cases of presence are represented as weak, emotional, needy, and obedient to men creatures. On the opposite side in many cases men are represented as sociable, powerful, knowledgeable and wise, administrator, brave and fighter. According to this research gender clichés which are common in the society are reflected in these books.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کتاب‌های درسی در کنار آموزشِ دانش‌آموزان، آنها را برای پذیرش نقش‌های متناسب با ویژگی‌های جنسیتی‌شان، آن گونه که مدنظر مؤلفین این کتب می‌باشد، آماده می‌کنند. پژوهش حاضر درصدد است به چگونگی بازنمایی جنسیت در کتاب‌های فارسی دوره‌ی راهنمایی و پایه‌های اول، دوم و سوم دبیرستان در رشته‌های غیر انسانی در سال تحصیلی 89- 1388 بپردازد. روش تحقیق، تحلیل محتوای کمی بر اساس شاخص‌ جنسیت در بین تصاویر، اسامی، مؤلفان کتاب‌ها، نویسندگان متون درسی و شخصیت‌های حاضر در متن دروس می‌باشد. همچنین از روش تحلیل محتوای کیفی برای تحلیل کیفیت بازنمایی‌ها در تصاویر و متون درسی استفاده شده است. این تحقیق با مبنا قرار دادن نظریه‌های آلتوسر و بوردیو در این زمینه، سعی در کشف چگونگی بازنمایی‌های جنسیتی در این کتاب‌ها نموده است. نتایج به دست آمده نشان می‌دهد در بخش کمّی، به مردان، بسیار بیش از زنان پرداخته شده است و زنان با معیار این شاخص‌ها حضور چندانی در کتاب‌های مورد بررسی ندارند. از نظر کیفی زنان در اندک موارد حضور، موجوداتی ضعیف، عاطفی، نیازمند کمک و مطیع مردان بازنمایی می‌شوند. در مقابل، مردان در موارد بسیاری، حاضر در اجتماع، صاحب قدرت، دانا و عاقل، مدیر و کاردان، شجاع و جنگنده تصویر شده‌اند. به نظر می‌رسد کلیشه‌های جنسیتی رایج در اجتماع، در کتاب‌های مورد بررسی نیز بازتولید شده‌اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازنمایی جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل محتوای کیفی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصاویر کتاب‌ها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کتب آموزشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کلیشه‌های جنسیتی.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">متون درسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_29483_022a0a78984e360d9229ee70c983fd98.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
