<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>17</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analysis of Effective Barriers on Women&#039;s Entrepreneurship Development in Rural Tourism (Case Study: Oraman Region, Sarvabad County)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر موانع گرایش زنان روستایی به کارآفرینی گردشگری (مطالعة موردی: بخش اورامان شهرستان سروآباد)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>439</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>468</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">75183</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2020.275033.1007581</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سعدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی روستایی دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ژاله</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمد شریفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد جغرافیا و برنامه‌ریزی روستایی، دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>29</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present paper seeks to identify the obstacles and problems that women&#039;s rural entrepreneurs faced in the Oraman region of Sarvaba county, which is considered as one of the important hubs of rural tourism in the country. The aim is to remove the barriers to create an appropriate entrepreneurship environment for rural women to be employed in the field of tourism. Data gathering in the theoretical part was done by using documentary resources and in the practical section with survey method and based on distribution of questionnaire among 97 employed rural women in the tourism sector of the villages of Oraman section and 50 knowledgeable and specialized developers in rural issues who were chosen by using Snowy bullet method. Data analysis was performed by inferential statistics (factor analysis and path analysis) and indicates that in total, there are five factors including; weakness in planning, executive performance of public institutions and financial resources constraints, weaknesses in marketing and infrastructure service failures, social and cultural barriers of rural environment, individual weaknesses and educational constraints, and technical and practical barriers are the main obstacles that employed rural women entrepreneurs are facing in the rural tourism sector. Among them, the weakness of planning, the executive function of state institutions and financial constraints have the greatest impact on the inclination of employed rural women in the area of tourism to entrepreneurial.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر در پی شناسایی موانع و مشکلات پیش‏روی ایجاد محیط مناسب و گرایش زنان روستایی شاغل در عرصة گردشگری منطقة اورامان شهرستان سروآباد به کارآفرینی است. جمع‏آوری داده‏ها در بخش نظری با استفاده از منابع اسنادی و در بخش عملی با روش پیمایشی و مبتنی بر توزیع پرسش‌نامه در میان 97 زن روستایی شاغل در عرصة گردشگری روستاهای بخش اورامان و 50 نفر از آگاهان و مختصصان توسعة روستایی است که به روش هدفمند انتخاب شدند. تجزیه و تحلیل داده‏های گردآوری‌شده با آزمون‏های آمار استنباطی (تحلیل عاملی و تحلیل مسیر) نشان دادند که در‌مجموع پنج عامل ضعف در برنامه‏ریزی، عملکرد اجرایی نهادهای دولتی و محدودیت‏های منابع مالی؛ ضعف در بازاریابی و نارسایی‏های خدماتی‌ـ زیرساختی؛ موانع اجتماعی و فرهنگی محیط روستایی؛ ضعف‎های فردی و محدودیت‏های آموزشی و موانع فنی و عملی از موانع مهم پیش‌روی کارآفرینی زنان روستایی شاغل در عرصة گردشگری روستاهای منطقه هستند که در این میان، عامل ضعف در برنامه‎ریزی، عملکرد اجرایی نهادهای دولتی و محدودیت‏های مالی بیشترین تأثیر را در تمایل زنان روستایی شاغل در عرصة گردشگری روستایی منطقة مطالعه‌شده به کارآفرینی داشت.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روستاهای بخش اورامان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان روستایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی گردشگری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_75183_ccb5c2a3eb0557aa4f66cac0a1b0800e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
