<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>4</Volume>
				<Issue>1-2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2006</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Gender in Iranian Cinema</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نمایش جنسیت در سینمای ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19208</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی سلطانی</FirstName>
					<LastName>گردفرامرزی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد جامعه‌شناسی، پژوهشگر جهاد دانشگاهی، دانشکده علوم اجتماعی، دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Sociological analysis of gender relations in films has always been important to sociologists due to monitoring social relations and structures. In this research, the researcher tries to investigate quality of gender relations in Iranian films after the revolution. The fundamental question of the research is how gender inequality is represented and constructed in interaction of men and women in Iranian films. The theoretical framework in the research is social constructionist approach of Erving Goffman based on which concepts, variables and hypothesis of research have been defined and constructed. The Method of research is content analysis, by which 62 Iranian films are analyzed. In This article, it is tried to introduce brilliant thinking of Goffman and analyze gender displays in Iranian films by using Goffman’s visual analysis model.
 The findings of research approve the presence of significant gender displays in Iranian films within the framework of Goffman’s visual analysis model, while expressing the reconstruction and reproduction of gender values and norms in Iranian cinema after revolution.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA"></OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سینما</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عقب ‌نشینی روانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرامناسکی شدن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مناسکی شدن فرمانبری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نمایش جنسیت.</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_19208_0be12cb9bfe34a2af5dd774fc18700f7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
