<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Entrepreneurial self-efficacy and entrepreneurial intention: moderating role of gender</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطۀ بین خودکارآمدی کارآفرینانه با قصد کارآفرینانه: نقش تعدیلگری جنسیت</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>387</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>404</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">53690</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2014.53690</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>روح اله</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکدۀ کشاورزی دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>28</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The main purpose of this survey was to study of relationship between entrepreneurial intention and entrepreneurial self-efficacy of agricultural students and test of moderating effect of gender in this relationship. The statistical population of the study contained all M.Sc. students in Agriculture Faculty of Zanjan University (N=469). A sample size of 285 was selected using a stratified random sampling method (n=285). The standard questionnaires were used to collect the data. A panel of experts confirmed the content validity of the questionnaires. A pilot study was conducted to establish the reliability of the instrument. Cronbach’s alpha coefficients for the main scales of questionnaire were at appropriate level (ranged from 0.792 to 0.887). The data were analyzed using SPSS&lt;sub&gt;win20&lt;/sub&gt; and AMOS&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; softwares. The results showed that entrepreneurial self-efficacy had a positive and significant effect on dependent variable of entrepreneurial intention explaining about 40 percent of its variances. Also, the results indicated that gender had a moderating effect on the relationship between entrepreneurial intention and entrepreneurial self-efficacy; so that the relationship was non-significant for female students, whereas it was positive and significant for male students.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف اصلی این تحقیق بررسی رابطۀ بین قصد کارآفرینانه و خودکارآمدی کارآفرینانه دانشجویان رشته‏های کشاورزی و آزمون اثر تعدیلگری متغیر جنسیت در این رابطه بود. جامعۀ آماری تحقیق شامل 469 نفر از دانشجویان کارشناسی ارشد دانشکدۀ کشاورزی دانشگاه زنجان بود که تعداد 285 تن از آن‌ها از طریق روش نمونه‏گیری طبقه‏ای با انتساب متناسب انتخاب شدند. برای گردآوری داده‏ها از پرسشنامه‏های استاندارد استفاده شد. روایی محتوایی پرسشنامه با نظر کارشناسان و متخصصان تأیید شد. به منظور تعیین قابلیت اعتماد ابزار تحقیق پیش‏آزمون انجام شد که مقدار آلفای کرونباخ محاسبه‌شده برای مقیاس‏های اصلی پرسشنامه در حد مناسب (در دامنۀ بین 792&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 تا 887&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0) بود. داده‏های گردآوری‌شده با نرم‏افزارهای SPSS&lt;sub&gt;win20&lt;/sub&gt; و AMOS&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; تجزیه و تحلیل شد. نتایج تحقیق نشان داد که خودکارآمدی کارآفرینانه اثر مثبت و معناداری بر قصد کارآفرینانه داشت و در حدود 40‌درصد از واریانس آن را تبیین کرد. همچنین، بر‌اساس نتایج تحقیق مشخص شد که متغیر جنسیت از اثر تعدیلگری در رابطۀ بین قصد کارآفرینانه و خودکارآمدی کارآفرینانه برخوردار بود؛ به‌نحوی‌که این رابطه برای دانشجویان دختر غیرمعنادار، ولی برای دانشجویان پسر مثبت و معنادار بود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خودکارآمدی کارآفرینانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشجویان کشاورزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قصد کارآفرینانه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_53690_c6bb8d8702dbe954dd969d5d66cf2903.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
