<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Surplus Value of Homemaking and the Influential Factors</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارزش افزوده کار خانه‌داری زنان و عوامل مؤثر بر آن</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>89</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>109</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">23651</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شهلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>باقری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار و عضو هیئت علمی‌دانشگاه تربیت معلم</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Women’s homemaking activities involve a variety of jobs including taking care of children and family. Despite the fact that these activities encompass economic, social and cultural values, they are not generally considered and the economic place of homemaking activities in the society has been ignored. In other words, a major part of women? s activities in areas of upbringing children and homemaking that take place at home are not counted.
The main aim of this research is to calculate the surplus value of the  activities of  homemaking  and  to study  the effective social factors  on  added  values of  women’s  indoor activities. Accordingly the weekly calculation of the surplus value of Tehran women’s homemaking activities estimates at 1600000 Rials.
Questionnaire and a random multi-stage sampling were the tools used in this survey. After filing the final questionnaires by 2000 homemaker women of Tehran, the gathered related data were coded and analyzed by means of SPSS software. The result of research show that three variables including &quot;woman’s age&quot;, &quot;woman’s education&quot; and &quot;family size&quot; have meaningful impacts on explaining the surplus value of women&#039;s indoor activities. Among the mentioned variables the “family size” or the number of family members had the most impact on the changes in surplus value of homemaking activities.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کار خانه‌داری زنان در محیط خانه، دارای ارزش اجتماعی، فرهنگی و اقتصادی است و مشتمل بر انجام فعالیت‌های متنوع زنان در خانه است که عمدتاً، پنهان و نامحسوس بوده و به‌علاوه نقش آن در اقتصاد و اجتماع تبیین نشده است. به عبارت دیگر، بخش اعظم فعالیت‌هایی که زنان در زمینه نگهداری و تداوم منابع انسانی و مراقبت از کیان خانواده انجام می‌دهند و محل اجرای آن در منزل است، در حسابرسی‌ها و آمارگیری‌های ملی به حساب نمی‌آید. هدف این مقاله، محاسبه ارزش افزوده کار خانه‌داری زنان و بررسی برخی عوامل مؤثر بر آن است. بر اساس محاسبات، ارزش افزوده هفتگی کار خانه‌داری زنان معادل مبلغ 1600000 ریال برآورد گردید. روش مورد نظر در این پژوهش، روش پیمایشی و ابزار مورد استفاده در این روش، پرسشنامه بوده و از شیوه نمونه‌گیری چند مرحله‌ای تصادفی استفاده شده است. پس از تکمیل پرسشنامه نهایی از 2000 زن خانه دار، داده‌های مربوط جمع آوری و توسط نرم افزارspss مورد تحلیل قرار گرفته است. نتایج تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که سه متغیر «سن زن»، «تحصیلات زن» و «تعداد اعضای خانواده» اثر معناداری در تبیین متغیر ارزش افزوده کار خانه‌داری داشته و در معادله نهایی رگرسیون باقی ماندند. در بین متغیرهای مستقل، متغیر «تعداد اعضای خانوار» بیشترین سهم را در تبیین تغییرات ارزش افزوده کار خانه‌داری داشته است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ارزش افزوده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهیافت ستانده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رهیافت نهاده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان خانه‌دار.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کار خانه‌داری</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_23651_acc0b6f937f469832bb9f1ae691f3833.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
