<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
		<modsCollection
		    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
		    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		    xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
		    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Archaeology of Bi-Hijābi (Unveiling) in Iran
Qasem Zaeri</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ghasem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zaeri</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Dep. of Sociology, University of Tehran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This article investigates the possibility context of the unveiling genesis (taking off the Hijab, i. e. the Islamic veil) in Iran and elucidates the dynamics possibility of the first attempt to unveil. An archaeological method of Foucaultian approach is adopted to reach this goal. The article demonstrates that “unveiling” is one of the implications of modernity and should be considered in light of the distinction between “Native Modernity” and “Western Modernity”. Therefore, despite the common narrative, we cannot think of the time when Ghorrat-alein bābi attended Badasht meeting with her veil taken off in 1852 the starting point of the unveiling in Iran while the native modernity with its arrangements was in an outstanding stage of its authority. Moreover, Ghorrat-alein’s style of argumentation entirely belongs to traditional texture. the unveility developed only in an advanced stage of western modernity with its consolidated arrangements and lively dynamics in Iran. Historically, it occurred in 1927 when Sediqeh Dowlat-abādi took her veil off roaming in the streets. Dowlat-abādi’s maneuver lay in a sequence of internal and international relations supported and empowered by the “modern state” of Rezakhan namely the influence of modernization in Afghanistan and Turkey, inclination to gain international prestige in the end of the World War I and the nationalistic strategy of education of women. Although Dowlat-abādi herself was initially under the influence of modern relations that emerged in the realm of education within the “underdevelopment discourse” since the time of Sepah-salār and especially the Constitutional Revolution, later she turned to be a proponent of a new discourse for promoting unveiling and defining women’s rights and tended toward some type of “maternal feminism” derived from common arguments of religious modernism under the influence of the feministic trends between the two World Wars.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>153</start>
					<end>186</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_52354_c5361f36cacb14b8b2f53f0fc6e7cefc.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.52354</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Subjectivity of Women &amp; Release in Kristeva’s Thought: The Idea for Participation of Matter Semiotic of Genius in Public Sphere of Symbolic</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Mohammad Ali</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Tavana</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor of Political Science, University of Yazd</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Farzad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azarkamand</namePart>
				<affiliation>Masters student of political science, University of Yazd</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>In the contemporary political philosophy was presented the various resolutions for release of female from repression and inequality. For example, the feminists of the post-structuralisms Foucault speak about the permanent refusal of female in opposition. The feminists of the post-modernists Baudrillard defend from the acute of male matter for depletion of the central cause. The feminists of post-colonialists such as Spivak support from Deconsturction of Logoscenterism that is govern on mail discourse. The feminist of contemporarys libral such as Suzan Okin also defend based on the principle of its fundamental of the female’s rights. The Jolia Kristeva thinker moving in the border between modernism and postmodernism, presented the particularly solution for female subjectivity which consists of formative suggestions for our society in modern era. According to this article, two main questions were discussed: 1. What is the resolution of Kristeva for releasing the female subject from the repression and inequality? 2. What is the practical and theoretical results for our society in modern era? It is supposed that the idea of feminine genius can be a good solution for suppression and removing the female subject in public sphere. Since, the idea open a way entrance of Semiotic matter of female to symbolic matter of male. It means that genius caused that the subject of female talker can participate in the logical social political of male actively and disorder that from heart. One of the possible resolutions for battle to in inequality is the activity participation of women in cultural weave of society. The social-political participation of Iranian women is not ignoring the family and maternal role and women values. The women identity could perform balance in Iranian society. In this research grounded hermeneutics method and framework of inner logic were used.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>187</start>
					<end>206</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_52355_f76ba4028be56a6ba50eddf5b904b522.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.52355</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Lived Experience of Social Relations in Women Living with HIV</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sattar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Parvin</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Professor, Alameh Tabatabayi University, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Ayoub</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Eslamian</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA student, Alameh Tabatabayi University, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>This paper studies the experience of social exclusion in women with HIV. The method research is qualitative research and the technique used to collect data is interview. Also, the population is women with HIV in Clinique of behavioral sickness counseling in Tehran. The sample size is 30 people. Research findings indicate that these women have experienced exclusion. Also, the results show that social exclusion occurs in women with AIDS in the seven fields as Aids panic, exclusion in social relation, economic exclusion, exclusion of support network, symbolic exclusion, exclusion from the health and spatial exclusion.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>207</start>
					<end>228</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_52356_5e42eb8977ba4ae4bee10f1bc78e3489.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.52356</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Cohort Analysis of Women's Attitude towards Value of Children  in Semnan Province</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hajiieh Bibi</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Razeghi Nasrabad</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof., Demography, National Population Studies and Comprehensive Management Institute, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hasan</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Saraei</namePart>
				<affiliation>Prof., Allameh Tabatabaei University, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The purpose of this paper is to investigate the differences in value of children between the 1960s, 1970s, after 1980 birth cohort, and identifying the factors affecting. The data for this study are drawn from a survey in Semnan province in 2012. Information is related to 405 married women aged 15-49 years. The result shows that the highest score of the children value belonged to the 1960 birth cohort. Protect, emotional and family continuity value in childbearing are characteristics of this cohort. In contrast, emphasis on the economic costs and lost opportunity costs, emotional and psychological benefits to children are characteristics of the 1980 birth cohorts. Based on this study, in line with the socio- economical changes, significant changes in childbearing attitude have emerged in three cohorts. Nevertheless, the 1960 birth cohort more than any other generation produces modern childbearing values and behaviors gives great importance to childbearing and because of the emotional value of children, one of the goals of younger cohort is childbearing. Multiple classification analysis showed that by controlling the effect of factors related to modernization and individual characteristics of respondents, the mean score of value of children within cohort changes. A more percent of the differences between the cohorts are affected by education variable. After entering these variables are considerably reduced the intensity of relationship between value of children and birth cohort. But, the differences in the value of children in three cohorts are still significant.
 </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>229</start>
					<end>250</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_52357_3991a8d20aa651a8aa29be41f20d2e9c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.52357</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Assessing the Relation of Body Image Dissatisfaction and Social Anxiety by the using of Cosmetics</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sajjad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Basharpoor</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof., Psychology, University of Mohaghegh Ardabili, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Azadeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Abasi</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A. Students of Psychology, University of Mohaghegh Ardabili, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Fatemeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Ghorbani</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A. Students of Psychology, University of Mohaghegh Ardabili, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Akbar</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Atadokht</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assistant Prof., Psychology, University of Mohaghegh Ardabili, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sajjad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Almardi Someh</namePart>
				<affiliation>M.A. Students, Psychology, University of Mohaghegh Ardabili, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>The aim of current study was assessing the relation of body image dissatisfaction and social anxiety with using of cosmetics in female college students.The method of this research was descriptive-analytical. The whole female students of Mohaghegh Ardabili University in second half of 2013 comprised statistical population of this study. One hundred and ten female students selected from this society by multistage randomly sampling. They were asked to respond questionnaires of social anxiety, body image dissatisfaction and researcher made questionnaire of using of cosmetics. Gathered data were analyzed by Pearson correlation and multivariate regression tests. The correlation results showed that the using ratio of cosmetics are related positively to body image dissatisfaction (r=0.44, P&lt;0.001). Social anxiety (r=0.26, P&lt;0.001) and its components as fear (r=0.28, P&lt;0.004), physiological symptoms (r=0.22, P&lt;0.02) and avoidance (r=0.21, P&lt;0.03). The results of regression analysis also showed that 19% of variance of the using of cosmetics was explained by body image dissatisfaction and social anxiety disorder gender attitudes. Results of this study demonstrated that body image dissatisfaction and social anxiety disorder play role in the using of cosmetics. </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>251</start>
					<end>264</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_52358_de1effc5f53999ec22770f0b4ac64963.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.52358</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>A Survey on the Factors Affecting Women’s Political Participation (Case Study: Women in Booshehr City)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Hossein</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Athari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof., Politics, Ferdousi University of Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Abolghasem</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Shahriyari</namePart>
				<affiliation>Student in MA., Politics, Ferdousi University of Mashhad, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Political participation is an indication of democracy and political development and legitimacy in different societies. The more participation in a society occurs, the more legitimacy a political system will have. So, the efforts of Iranian political system are toward increasing people’s political participation rate. Since half of the Iranian world consists of women, a survey on the factors affecting their political participation can make us understand how and why the political participation is done and reveal the solutions to increase women’s participation. The purpose of this paper which has been done through survey-research method is to consider the factors that affect the political participation of women in Booshehr. The sample size is comprised of 350 persons who have been selected by cluster sampling (urban areas) and random sampling. The obtained results show that women in Booshehr have either mass or observational participation. The equation obtained by regression shows that the variable of political awareness has the most effect on increasing women’s political participation. After that, variables of being religious, educational level, feeling of powerlessness, social rank, feeling of political efficacy, and membership in communities have the most effect on women’s political participation. Among these variables, the variable of political powerlessness has negative effects on political participation.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>265</start>
					<end>286</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_52359_a14a236ced01a815d5a956051722113c.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.52359</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>Viewpoints of Rural Women on Effect of Social Capital Components on their Empowerment (Case study: Hassan- Khan Village, Ghorveh Township)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Rohollah</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Rezaei</namePart>
				<affiliation>Associate Prof., University of Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Shima</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Zareei</namePart>
				<affiliation>MSc, University of Zanjan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Regarding the undeniable role of women in the process of rural development on the one hand and their inappropriate situation in terms of the most indices of rural development on the other hands, rural women’s empowerment is essential. Meanwhile, many researchers and scholars believe that social capital and its components play a key role. Thus, the main purpose of this descriptive- correlative research was to study of the viewpoints of rural women on effect of social capital components on their empowerment in Hassan- Khan village in Ghorveh Township.The statistical population of the research consisted of all women in Hassan- Khan village ranged from 15 to 64 years old (N= 213). According to the Krejcie and Morgan table, a sample size of 165 was selected using random sampling technique. The questionnaire were used to collect data. The content validity of the questionnaire was confirmed by a panel of experts. The construct validity and the composite reliability of the research instrument were tested by estimating the measurement model and they were satisfied after making necessary corrections. The results showed that the main hypotheses of the research have verified and three components of social capital including social cohesion, participation and trust had a positive and significant effect on dependent variable. The components totally explained about 43 percent of variances of women&#039;s empowerment in Hassan- Khan village. Based on the findings, it can be concluded that increasing social capital of rural women directly results in their empowerment.   </abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>287</start>
					<end>304</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_52360_d5c153c1576f3639854c7b319c553514.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.52360</identifier>
			</mods>
		<mods version="3.5">
		    <titleInfo>
				<title>The Relationship between Gender and Organizational Culture (Case Study: National Library of the Islamic Republic)</title>
			</titleInfo>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Behjat</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Yazdkhasti</namePart>
				<affiliation>Assosiat Prof., University of Esfahan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Sayed Ali mohammad</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Azarbakhsh</namePart>
				<affiliation>PhD Candidate, Information Science and Knowledge Studies, University of Esfahan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
				<name type="personal">
				<namePart type="family">Raziyeh</namePart>
				<namePart type="given">Mortazavi Ab Alvan</namePart>
				<affiliation>MA., Information Science and Knowledge Studies, University of Esfahan, Iran</affiliation>
				<role>
				<roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
				</role>
			</name>
			<typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
			<genre>article</genre>
			<originInfo>
				<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="w3cdtf">2014</dateIssued>
			</originInfo>
			<language>
				<languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">per</languageTerm>
			</language>
			<abstract>Gender factor can have a significant impact on the organization or even an individual with certain gender characteristics can be different from organization to organization, the degree of acceptance of the models and assumptions underlying the organization. The purpose of this study was to investigate the relationship between gender and culture at the National Library of the Islamic Republic. This study applied a descriptive- survey. For collecting the survey data, standard questionnaire used. Denison with 60 questions and four sections were collected. Statistical analysis, both descriptive and inferential statistics using SPSS 20 software has been made. The results showed that the average overall score of &quot;corporate culture based on the National Library of Dennison&quot; Less than average level is. Most points after engaging in work (participatory) (mean 01.3) and lowest points in the mission rocker (Mission) (mean 83.2) have been obtained in the field theory has been achieved. The results showed that among the four dimensions of organizational culture that includes gender and conflict at work (participatory), adaptability (stability and integrity), adaptability (flexibility) and taking the mission (mission) are not statistically significant and researcher&#039;s claim was not confirmed and the observed difference between the mean scores based on gender, according to the twelve indicators of organizational culture, empowerment, team building, development potential, intrinsic value, consistency and coherence, flexibility, customer orientation, organizational learning and landscape variables, gender was not significant, but Indicators such agreements, strategic direction and goals and this difference was significant.</abstract>
			<relatedItem type="host">
			<titleInfo>
				<title>Women in Development &amp; Politics</title>
			</titleInfo>
			<originInfo>
				<publisher>University of Tehran</publisher>
			</originInfo>
			<identifier type="issn">2538-3132</identifier>
			<part>
				<detail type="volume">
					<number>12</number>
					<caption>v.</caption>
				</detail>
				<detail type="issue">
				<number>2</number>
				<caption>no.</caption>
				</detail>
				<text type="year">2014</text>
				<extent unit="pages">
					<start>305</start>
					<end>323</end>
				</extent>
			</part>
			</relatedItem>
			<identifier type="uri">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_52361_41ce7fabcc6fed2d53807c70b8189db8.pdf</identifier>
			<identifier type="doi">dx.doi.org/10.22059/jwdp.2014.52361</identifier>
			</mods>
		</modsCollection>