<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>14</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Assessing different aspects and barriers of self-employment among agricultural female students (Case study: Zanjan University)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی ابعاد مختلف خوداشتغالی و موانع آن در میان دانشجویان دختر دانشکدۀ کشاورزی (مطالعۀ موردی: دانشگاه زنجان)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>343</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>360</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">60055</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2016.60055</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>جعفر</FirstName>
					<LastName>یعقوبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پریسا</FirstName>
					<LastName>نجفلو</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهه</FirstName>
					<LastName>حق وردی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد توسعۀ روستایی دانشگاه زنجان</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>26</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The main purpose of this research was to study different aspects of self-employment among the agricultural female students in University of Zanjan. The statistical population of the study consisted of senior female students in agriculture faculty of Zanjan University in 2014-2015 academic year (N= 135). According to Cochran&#039;s formula, 63 students were selected using a stratified random sampling method. The research tool was a questionnaire. Validity of the instrument was confirmed by a panel of faculty members and experts of the field. The reliability was determined by pilot test and calculating Cronbach&#039;s alpha coefficient (0.71-0.88). The results of this study showed that the most important priority for employment was cooperative work, self-employment and recruitment. The most important motivation for self-employment was greater prosperity, freedom and flexibility to work and use all the knowledge, skills and their ideas. Most students tend to agricultural employment in the service section. The self-employment requirements included: need of financial capital, benefiting from specialized training and experience in the field to set up business on one’s own way. Using exploratory factor analysis, barriers to female students self-employment in agriculture were summarized into seven factors including: supporting law and gender barriers, agricultural risks and weaknesses in communication skills, physical weakness and knowledge, attitude and security, tendency to indolence and failure to taking risk in employment, lack of technical and management skills and lack of facilities. These factors explained 74.34% of barriers to female students&#039; self-employment in agriculture.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف کلی این تحقیق، بررسی ابعاد مختلف و موانع خوداشتغالی در میان دانشجویان دختر دانشکدۀ کشاورزی است. این پژوهش توصیفی‌ـ همبستگی به روش پیمایشی انجام شد. جامعۀ مطالعه‌شده دانشجویان دختر سال آخر مقطع کارشناسی دانشکدۀ کشاورزی دانشگاه زنجان در سال تحصیلی 1394ـ1395 بودند (135N=). حجم نمونه با استفاده از فرمول کوکران برآورد شد (63=N). نمونه‏ها با روش نمونه‏گیری طبقه‏ای تصادفی انتخاب شدند. پرسش‌نامۀ محقق‌ساخته ابزار جمع‏آوری داده‏ها بود که روایی آن از طریق آرای اعضای هیئت‏علمی دانشگاه زنجان و پایایی آن از طریق پایلوت تست و اندازه‏گیری ضریب آلفای‏ کرونباخ، به میزان 71&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0- 89&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;0 برآورد شد. نتایج حاصل از این تحقیق نشان داد اولویت‏های مهم اشتغال به ترتیب کار تعاونی، خوداشتغالی و استخدام است. از انگیزه‌های مهم خوداشتغالی دستیابی به رفاه بیشتر، آزادی و انعطاف‏پذیری در کار و استفاده از همۀ دانش، مهارت‏ و ایده‏های خود بود&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; دانشجویان تمایل بیشتری به اشتغال در بخش خدمات‏رسانی کشاورزی داشتند و مهم‏ترین ملزومات خوداشتغالی از نظر آن‌ها به ترتیب سرمایۀ مالی‏، برخورداری از آموزش تخصصی جهت راه‏اندازی کسب‏وکار و تجربه‌های کاری در زمینۀ مربوطه بیان شد. نتایج تحلیل عاملی نشان داد که هفت عامل حمایتی، قانونی و موانع جنسیتی، خطر‏پذیری کشاورزی و ضعف مهارت‏های ارتباطی، ضعف مادی و دانشی، نگرشی و امنیتی، گرایش به راحت‏طلبی و عدم ریسک‏پذیری در اشتغال، ضعف مهارت مدیریتی و فنی و کمبود تسهیلات توانستند 34&lt;sub&gt;/&lt;/sub&gt;74‌درصد از کل واریانس موانع خوداشتغالی دانشجویان دختر در بخش کشاورزی را تبیین کنند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتغال زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انگیزۀ اشتغال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دانشجویان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خوداشتغالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کشاورزی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_60055_bbfdca5718897b88a06bf22b7ff360f3.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
