<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Image of Unveiling and Forced Unveiling, the Status of the Picture of Unveiling in the Second Pahlavi Era</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>عصر تصویر بی حجابی و بی حجابی اجباری بررسی وضعیت تصویر بی حجابی در دورۀ پهلوی دوم</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>339</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>358</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68852</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2018.262289.1007458</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>قائمی نیک</LastName>
<Affiliation>دکتری جامعه‌شناسی نظری‌ـ فرهنگی از دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طیبه</FirstName>
					<LastName>نجفی</LastName>
<Affiliation>پژوهشگر مرکز مطالعات زنان دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>There are two different viewpoints on the approach of the Iranian society to the phenomena of veiling, especially female veiling. The first is the resistance of Muslim Iranians to the forced unveiling (kashf-e hejab) in Reza Pahlavi`s monarchy and the second, according to some opinions, is reaction Iranian people to the forced veiling or law of veiling in the Islamic Republic era. In the first era, under the influence of Reza Pahlavi’s Western Modernization, unveiling is considered to be imposed, and in the second era, veiling. However, between the two periods, there is a 37 years period of Mohammad Reza Pahlavi. Despite of continuity of the forced unveiling policies, this era has been less analyzed. Unlike Reza Pahlavi`s period, forced unveiling not only was not directly in the real social scene, but also, it was disseminated through media and to influence the unconscious mind of social actors. Furthermore, since the 1960s, these policies have been linked to the plan for development of capitalism. In the present study, &quot;the image of unveiling&quot; has been used to express the pictorial feature of unveiling. In the West, the unveiling picture of men or women`s organs was expanded under the development of music and cinema industry, after World War II. Before that time, revealing of the images of feminine or masculine bodies was limited, or at least, wasn’t the symbol of modernity, progress and personality. In the present research, the Critical Theory of Frankfort School and methodological of Culture Industry which was formulated in the second half of the twentieth century, has been employed to investigate the status of the picture of unveiling and the influence of the policies of the second Pahlavi on that. It can be concluded that, the attention to the pictorial feature of unveiling that began from the second Pahlavi`s era can explain superficial contradiction of the two opinions on Iranian reaction to veiling. With the continuation of media images during the Islamic Republic era, it seems necessary to make further researches on the contrast of veiling picture-unveiling picture.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">دربارۀ مواجهۀ جامعۀ ایران با پدیدۀ حجاب (به‌خصوص حجاب زنانه)، دو دیدگاه به‌ظاهر متفاوت وجود دارد؛ اول مقاومت مردم در برابر بی‏حجابی اجباری (کشف حجاب) در دورۀ رضاخان پهلوی و دوم مطابق با برخی از دیدگاه‌ها، واکنش به حجاب اجباری یا قانون حجاب در دورۀ جمهوری اسلامی. در دورۀ اول، در ذیل سیاست‏های «تجدد آمرانۀ» غربی، بی‏حجابی و در دورۀ دوم حجاب امری تحمیلی محسوب می‏شود. بین این دو دوره، حکومت 37 سالۀ پهلوی دوم قرار دارد که به‏رغم استمرار سیاست‏های تحمیل بی‏حجابی، کمتر مورد تحلیل قرار گرفته است. تحمیل بی‏حجابی در این دوره، برخلاف دورۀ پهلوی اول، مستقیماً در صحنۀ واقعی اجتماعی نبود، بلکه از طریق گسترش تصاویر رسانه‏ای و تبلیغاتی و تأثیر بر ناخودآگاه ذهن کنشگران اجتماعی صورت گرفت. به‏علاوه، این سیاست‏ها از دهۀ 1340 با طرح توسعۀ سرمایه‏داری پیوند ‏خورد. در این مقاله، برای بیان ویژگی تصویری بی‏حجابی، از تعبیر «تصویر بی‏حجابی» استفاده شده است. این تصویر از اندام زنانه یا مردانه عمدتاً تحت تأثیر صنایع سینما و موسیقی پس از جنگ جهانی دوم گسترش یافت. پیش از آن، آشکار‌شدنِ تصاویر بی‏حجاب از اندام زنانه یا مردانه چندان رایج نبود  یا حداقل نشانۀ تجدد، ترقی و شخصیت تلقی نمی‏شد. در مقالۀ حاضر، با استفاده از نظریۀ انتقادی مکتب فرانکفورت و چارچوب روشی صنعت فرهنگ، که در نیمۀ دوم قرن بیستم صورت‏بندی شد، به بررسی وضعیت تصویر بی‏حجابی و تأثیر سیاست‏های پهلوی دوم بر آن خواهیم پرداخت. در نتیجه‏گیری، اولاً اشاره خواهیم کرد که توجه به ویژگی تصویری تحمیل بی‏حجابی، که از دورۀ پهلوی دوم شروع شد، می‏تواند دو دیدگاه به‌ظاهر متضاد دربارۀ واکنش جامعۀ ایران به حجاب را توضیح دهد. ثانیاً، با توجه به استمرار تصاویر رسانه‏ا‏ی در دورۀ جمهوری اسلامی، پژوهش دربارۀ منازعۀ تصویر باحجاب‌ـ تصویر بی‏حجاب ضرورت دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بی‏حجابی اجباری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پهلوی دوم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تصویر بی‏حجابی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حجاب</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">صنعت فرهنگ</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_68852_4fb01c7d0397a7d4e2ebb61742e97e5a.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
