<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>12</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2014</Year>
					<Month>12</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Measuring factors affecting Female entrepreneur&#039;s business performance in rural areas of Mianeh County</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سنجش عوامل موثر بر عملکرد کسب و کارهای زنان کارآفرین در روستاهای شهرستان میانه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>545</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>558</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">54534</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2014.54534</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>غلامحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسینی نیا</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکدۀ کارآفرینی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>احمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>یعقوبی فرانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکدۀ کشاورزی دانشگاه بوعلی‌سینا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>سیدین</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مدیریت کارآفرینی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The main purpose of this applied research is to investigate the factors affecting rural female entrepreneur’s business performance. Based on theoretical literature, business performance is affected by several factors such as demographic characteristics, environmental factors, motives, social networks, skills, human capital and social learning. This research has been conducted applying a surveying technique by using questionnaire as the main tool. The population consists of 111 rural women who owned business in Mianeh County. The analysis and structural equation modeling showed the significant relationship between independent variables such as rural women’s goals, motives, planning skill, business skills and their business performance. Based on the research results, straightening these variables can enhance rural women entrepreneurship development.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">برنامه‌ریزی برای توسعة کسب‌وکارهای زنان روستایی در گام نخست نیازمند شناسایی عوامل بهبود‌دهندۀ عملکرد این‌گونه کسب‌وکارهاست. بر همین اساس، در پژوهشی پیمایشی به بررسی ماهیت و کیفیت اثر‌گذاری هر‌یک از عوامل مؤثر بر ارتقای عملکرد کسب‌وکارهای زنان کارآفرین در روستاهای شهرستان میانه پرداخته شده است. جامعۀ آماری تحقیق را زنان روستایی دارای کسب‌وکار در روستاهای شهرستان میانه تشکیل دادند که از بین آن‌ها 111 نفر برای‌ حجم نمونه انتخاب شدند. داده‌های مورد نیاز تحقیق از طریق پرسشنامه به‌منزلۀ ابزار اصلی تحقیق جمع‌آوری شد. تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها و مدل‌یابی معادلات ساختاری نشان داد که ارتباط بین متغیرهایی نظیر اهداف، انگیزه‌ها، داشتن مهارت برنامه‌ریزی، مهارت‌های مختلف کسب‌وکار و در‌نهایت برخورداری زنان از برخی نقاط قوت در کسب‌وکار با عملکرد کسب‌وکار آن‌ها معنادار است و این متغیرها می‌توانند عملکرد کسب‌وکارهای کارآفرینانۀ زنان روستایی را تبیین کنند. بر مبنای نتایج تحقیق می‌توان گفت تقویت متغیرهای مذکور می‌تواند روند توسعة کارآفرینی زنان روستایی را در این مناطق سرعت بخشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان روستایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارآفرینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کسب‌وکار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عملکرد</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_54534_a14d20768de7c38db1baf3998a436bca.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
