<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2008</Year>
					<Month>07</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Occupational Problems Facing Female University Faculty Members</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مشکلات شغلی زنان عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">27410</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>جواهری</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه جامعه¬شناسی دانشگاه تربیت¬معلم</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>داریاپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه جامعه¬شناسی دانشگاه شاهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Women&#039;s strong will to obtain higher education degrees and to work as faculty member of universities is an undeniable fact in Iranian current society. Nevertheless, female faculty members just like many other women encounter some career problems which can affect their emotions, attitudes and behaviors. This article aims at answering the three following questions:  
- What are the career problems of female university faculty members? 
-Is there any significant relationship between individual characteristics of female faculty members and their problems?
- Is there any significant relationship between the problems and job tendencies of female faculty members? 
 The surveys are obtained through interviewing 290 female members of non-medical faculties of state universities. The survey shows that a noticeable number of female faculty members face two major problems. The first problem is inconsistency between family-job role expectations while the second problem consists of discrimination against women
Among demographic variables only age, ethnicity and scientific position are statistically related to the so-called problems but only in a limited way. In addition, interaction of family-job roles and gender discrimination has a significant negative relationship with job satisfaction and sense of fulfillment from their affiliated organization.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">علاقه‌مندی زنان به کسب مدارج تحصیلی بالا و اشتیاق آنها به فعالیت آموزشی در دانشگاه واقعیت انکارناپذیر جامعه ایران در دوران کنونی است. با این وجود زنان عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه مانند بسیاری دیگر از زنان غیر دانشگاهی با مشکلاتی مواجه هستند که می‌تواند بر سطوح عاطفی، نگرش و عملکرد آنها تأثیر بگذارد. این مقاله درصدد پاسخگویی به پرسش‌های زیر تنظیم شده است: 
ـ زنان هیئت علمی دانشگاه در محیط کار خود با چه مشکلاتی مواجه هستند؟  
ـ آیا بین ویژگی‌های فردی زنان هیئت علمی دانشگاه و مشکلات آنها رابطه‌ای وجود دارد؟ 
- آیا بین مشکلات شغلی زنان هیئت علمی دانشگاه با گرایش آنها نسبت به کارشان رابطه‌ای وجود دارد؟
اطلاعات این مقاله از یک تحقیق پیمایشی که در آن با 290 نفر از زنان عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه‌های دولتی (غیرپزشکی) مصاحبه شده، بدست آمده  است. یافته‌های تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که تعداد قابل ملاحظه‌ای از زنان دانشگاهی با دو مشکل ناهماهنگی انتظارات نقش‌های خانوادگی و شغلی و تبعیض جنسیتی مواجه هستند. از بین متغیرهای جمعیتی فقط سن، قومیت و مرتبه دانشگاهی در مواردی محدود با مشکلات زنان ارتباط دارد. افزون بر این، تداخل نقش‌ها و تبعیض جنسیتی با رضایت از کار و رضایت از سازمان رابطه‌ای معنادار و منفی دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان شاغل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انتظارات نقشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تبعیض جنسیتی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رضایت شغلی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_27410_3ca5dc8f20b8ade7444396fe8bac49b0.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
