<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Women entering  male jobs: causes and consequences Qualitative exploration of experts’ views</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ورود زنان به مشاغل مردانه: دلایل و پیامدها واکاوی کیفی آرای کارشناسان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>399</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>424</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">56338</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2015.56338</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اسماعیل</FirstName>
					<LastName>بلالی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه جامعه‌شناسی، دانشگاه بوعلی سینای همدان</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مونس</FirstName>
					<LastName>سیاح</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشگاه صنعتی شریف</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سیده فاطمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>محبی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری مسائل اجتماعی ایران دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد تهران مرکز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Gender as one of the social and cultural determinant factors, affects many dimensions of women including their occupation and can affect  the types of male and female jobs. Nowadays, gender segregation of jobs in Iran is gradually being removed. Nevertheless, social policy making in this subject needs scientific studies. It seems necessary to take advantage of qualitative methods. In this qualitative study using focus group discussions, views of  19 women and family experts  about the phenomenon of women presence in occupations and its reasons were questioned and discussed. The findings and thematic analysis showed three types of views including: supporters,  opponents and intermediate. Individual and communicative capability elevation, economic and social justice realization are mensioned as positive implications of women entering  male jobs. In some experts’ views, seperation of women jobs prevents their talent development, strengthens gender beliefs in society and economic-gender imbalance. But opponents of women entering  male jobs see this entrance as equivalent to women distancing from women world, identity and personality imbalance, physical and mental exhaustion, reduction of marriage opportunity, sexual and ethical insecurity and male social reactions.   </Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">جنسیت، به‌منزلة یکی از عناصر تعیین‌کنندة فرهنگی و اجتماعی، بسیاری از ابعاد حیات جمعی زنان همچون اشتغال آنان را تحت‌تأثیر قرار می‌دهد و می‌تواند بر نوع مشاغل زنان و مردان در جامعه تأثیر‌گذار باشد. امروزه، جداسازی جنسیتی مشاغل در ایران به‌تدریج در حال برداشته شدن است، اما سیاست‌گذاری اجتماعی در مورد این موضوع نیازمند مطالعات علمی است. از‌این‌رو، در این مطالعه با استفاده از روش کیفی و بحث گروهی متمرکز، دیدگاه‌های 19 نفر از کارشناسان مسائل زنان و خانواده دربارة پدیدة «ورود زنان به مشاغل مردانه» و دلایل آن، مورد پرسش و بحث قرار گرفته است. یافته‌های حاصل از تجزیه و تحلیل داده‌ها به روش تحلیل تماتیک نشان داد مشارکت‌کنندگان در مورد این پدیده دیدگاه‌های پیامدگرای مثبت‌گرا، پیامدگرای منفی‌گرا و تلفیقی داشتند. تعالی توانایی‌های فردی و ارتباطی زنان و تحقق عدالت اقتصادی و اجتماعی از دلالت‌های مثبت ورود زنان به مشاغل مردانه ذکر شده‌اند. همچنین، جداسازی مشاغل زنان مانع پرورش استعدادهای آن‌ها، تقویت باورهای جنسیتی در جامعه و عدم تعادل اقتصادی‌ـ جنسیتی قلمداد شده است. اما پیامدگرایان منفی‌گرا ورود زنان به مشاغل مردانه را مترادف فاصله‌گیری زنان از دنیای زنانه، عدم تعادل هویتی و شخصیتی، فرسودگی جسمی و روانی، کاهش فرصت ازدواج، ناامنی اخلاقی و جنسی برای زنان درگیر در این مشاغل و بازخوردهای اجتماعی مردانه دانسته‌اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتغال زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جداسازی جنسیتی مشاغل</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشاغل زنانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشاغل مردانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مطالعة کیفی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_56338_152e76f751566ddecf08cd2acb84e523.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
