<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2004</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آثار جهانی شدن بر زنان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">13274</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>طاهرخانی</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>It is apparent that globalization has created both a sense of promise and fear in the world community. This phenomenon has created both opportunities and threats for developing countries. Developed nations and developing, urban and rural areas, men and women, are affected differently by globalization. The depth and complexity of the outcome of globalization for women is more severe. As such, while globalization can have a positive impact on women, such as increases in income, employment, social capital, efficiency, choices, knowledge and information, and a decline in the birth rate, it also has an equally negative impact on women, such as growth of the employment in informal sector, low wages, reduced food safety, increased migration, disintegration of traditional values, lack of job security, and increases in consumerism. Globalization, because of social, economic, political and cultural limitations of women, has impacted them more severely, bringing greater challenges and threats as compared with the opportunities.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">به نظر می رسد که جهانی شدن برای مردم جهان بیم و امید به رمغان آورده است. این پدیده دو رویه دارد. از یک سو ، تهدید است که کشورهای در حال توسعه با آن روبرو هستند و ، از سوی دیگر، فرصت هایی برای این کشورهای به وجود آورده است. ساز و کارهای مورد استفاده در فرآیند جهانی شدن مشابهت دارند، ولی آثار و پیامد های آن در جوامع مختلف – کشورهای توسعه یافته و در حال توسعه، شهرها و روستاها – و زنان و مردان کاملاً متفاوت است. در این بین، آثار جهانی شدن بر زنان عمق و پیچیدگی بیشتری دارد. بدین ترتیب ، اگرچه جهانی شدن آثار مثبتی همچون افزایش درآمد، رشد اشتغال، توسعه سرمایه اجتماعی،افزایش بهره وری، افزایش حق انتخاب، افزایش سطح آگاهی ها، و کاهش موالید را برای زنان به همراه داشته، به همان نسبت نیز آثار منفی نظیر رشد اشتغال غیر رسمی، پرداخت دستمزدهای اندک، کاهش امنیت غذایی، افزایش مهاجرت، فروپاشی ارزش های سنتی ، عدم امنیت شغلی، و گسترش فرهنگ مصرف را به زیان زنان تشدید کرده است. ویژگی های کارکردی زنان ایران نشان می دهد که به دلیل محدودیت های اجتماعی، اقتصادی، سیاسی و فرهنگی حاکم بر جامعه زنان و تجربیات جهانی حاصل از جهانی شدن، تهدید های فراروی زنان کشور بیشتر از فرصت های پیش روی آنان است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تهدیدها</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جهانی شدن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فرصت ها</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_13274_189653e825254c8e9b28c7ba6051b91d.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
