<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Examining Educational Needs of Rural Women in Ghomum Village of Songhor Township Using Borich Model and Quadrant Analysis</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نیازسنجی آموزشی زنان روستای قمام شهرستان سنقر
(بر مبنای مدل بوریچ و تحلیل کوادرانت)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>165</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>183</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22497</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کیومرث</FirstName>
					<LastName>زر افشانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده کشاورزی و عضو پژوهشکده اقتصادی اجتماعی دانشگاه رازی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>آگهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده کشاورزی، دانشگاه رازی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خوشقدم</FirstName>
					<LastName>خالدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه رازی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Needs assessment is “gaps between current conditions and desired conditions”. Most educational programs in extension education pay little attention to clients’ needs. This devalues the assessment as a policy making tool. However, this study will approach both rural women and extension agents’ perception, supposing rural women’s needs are considered to find areas of match or mismatch among stakeholders. Therefore, the survey aimed at inspecting educational needs of rural women in Ghomum Village using Borich needs assessment model and quadrant analysis. 
Through survey methodology, Borich (1980) obtained some data that could be ranked in order of priority. He believed that through needs assessment model rural women should judge about their own needs. Other researchers have also defined approaches to assessing educational needs. Through quadrant analysis, Witkin (1984) used importance as a qualifying factor in deriving priorities without fallacy of basing priority decisions on simple discrepancies. 
The population consisted of rural women and community extension agents in Gomum village. 100 women were selected and 35 of them were brought in to the study. Through Borich needs assessment model the questionnaires revealed that home economics, child care and methods of cooking were their top three needs. And quadrant analysis showed that educational needs were also ranked high. As a result both techniques should be used.  Specifically, issues such as home economics, child care, and method of cooking should be more emphasized when planning extension classes for women residing in Gomum village.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">در بسیاری از برنامه‌های آموزشی ترویجی توجه اندکی به نیازهای آموزشی از دیدگاه مخاطبین و کارشناسان ترویج می‌گردد و درنتیجه اثربخشی فعالیت‌های ترویجی تحت شعاع قرار می‌گیرد. لذا هدف از این پ‍‍ژوهش توصیفی- پیمایشی بررسی نیازهای آموزشی زنان روستای قمام شهرستان سنقر با استفاده از دو مدل نیازسنجی بوریچ و کوادرانت بود. جامعه‌ی آماری این مطالعه را زنان روستای قمام در شهرستان سنقر و کارشناسان ترویج تشکیل دادند. با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی ساده و بهره‌گیری از جدول کرجسی و مورگان تعداد 100 نفر از زنان روستایی انتخاب شدند. با توجه به محدودیت تعداد کارشناسان ترویج اقدام به سرشماری نموده و تعداد 35 نفر از آنان در این مطالعه شرکت نمودند. این پژوهش در دو مرحله انجام گردید؛ نخست نیازهای آموزشی زنان روستایی از دیدگاه خودشان با استفاده از پرسشنامه مبتنی بر مدل بوریچ مشخص گردید. نتایج این بخش نشان داد که 12 نیازآموزشی، دارای بالاترین اولویت می‌باشند که 3 اولویت اول به ترتیب شامل اقتصاد خانه‌داری، آموزش تغذیه‌ی کودکان و مهارت‌های طبخ غذا بود. در مرحله دوم با استفاده از مدل کوادرانت نیازها از دیدگاه زنان و کارشناسان تطبیق داده شد، نتایج نشان داد که اکثر نیازهای آموزشی از دید گاه زنان وکارشناسان با یکدیگر تطابق دارد. به منظور اثربخشی برنامه‌های ترویجی، توجه به دیدگاه زنان روستایی و کارشناسان ترویج امری ضروری بوده و این مسئله با استفاده از مدل نیازسنجی بوریچ و کوادرانت امکان پذیر است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان روستایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل بوریچ</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل کوادرانت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نیازسنجی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نیازهای آموزشی.</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_22497_ab8349a31b8ec7e9a39f4ec4478a3603.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
