<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>14</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The relationship between self-objectification with resilience and self-compassion of female students (Case study: Islamic Azad University of Sabzevar)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رابطه خودشیءانگاری با تاب‌آوری و خوددلسوزی دانشجویان دختر (مطالعۀ موردی: دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی سبزوار)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>125</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>139</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">58665</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2016.58665</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>ناعمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم تربیتی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی واحد سبزوار، سبزوار، ایران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today, self-objectification is defined by evaluating the others based on physical appearance, beauty and sexual attractiveness; it is a major source of women suffering especially for female students and reduces their resilience and self-compassion thereby endangering mental health. The current study aims to investigate the relationship between self-objectification with resilience and self-compassion of female students of Islamic Azad university of Sabzevar. The present research was descriptive and correlative. The population of this study included all incoming female students of Islamic Azad University of Sabzevar in 2014 that were totally 647 individuals. Using accessible sampling method and with help of Cochran’s formula for sample size, 242 subjects were selected through Stratified random sampling method. The data was collected using McKinley &amp; Hyde self-objectification scale, Conner-Davidson Resilience Scale, and Neff self -compassion Scale. Pearson correlation and stepwise regression were used for analyzing data with SPSS18. The results showed that there were significant and negative correlation between self-objectification with resilience and self-compassion. In addition, it was found that component of self-objectification (body shame, body surveillance, appearance control) could respectively explain 31 Percent of variance of resilience and 18 Percent of self-compassion among students. Therefore, decreasing self-objectification can increase resilience and self-compassion among female students.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه، پدیدة خودشیءانگاری به مفهوم ارزیابی دیگران براساس ظاهر فیزیکی، زیبایی و جذابیت جنسی، پدیده‏ای است که منبع عمدة درد و رنج زنان، به‌ویژه دانشجویان دختر، به‌شمار می‏آید و موجب کاهش تاب‏آوری و خوددلسوزی و تهدید سلامت روانی آن‏ها می‏شود. پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی رابطۀ خودشیءانگاری با تاب‏آوری و خوددلسوزی دانشجویان دختر دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی سبزوار انجام شد. این پژوهش از نوع توصیفی همبستگی بود. جامعة آماری این پژوهش شامل همۀ دانشجویان دختر دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی سبزوار ورودی 1393 به تعداد 647 نفر بود. حجم نمونه با استفاده از فرمول کوکران 242 نفر تعیین شد که با روش نمونه‏گیری تصادفی طبقه‏ای انتخاب شدند. برای گردآوری داده‏ها از پرسش‌نامه‏های استاندارد خودشیءانگاری مک‏کینلی و هاید، تاب‏آوری کونور و دیویدسون و خوددلسوزی نف استفاده شد. یافته‏های پژوهش نشان داد که بین متغیرهای خودشیءانگاری با تاب‏آوری و خوددلسوزی رابطة منفی و معناداری وجود دارد. همچنین، براساس نتایج تحقیق مشخص شد که مؤلفه‏های خودشیءانگاری (شرم بدنی، نظارت بدنی و کنترل ظاهر) توانستند حدود 31‌درصد واریانس تاب‏آوری و 18‌درصد واریانس خوددلسوزی را تبیین کنند. بنابراین، کاهش خودشیءانگاری می‏تواند سبب افزایش تاب‏آوری و خوددلسوزی دانشجویان دختر شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تاب‏آوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خوددلسوزی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خودشیءانگاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شرم بدنی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کنترل ظاهر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نظارت بدنی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_58665_98985aad0c3017c4412121420aad6178.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
