<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2004</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اختیار زوجه و ابهام در مفهوم عسر و حرج</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">13269</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی حاجی</FirstName>
					<LastName>پور</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of the present article is to report the findings of a study on the condition of divorce that is Osre-o-Hara}. Woman can request divorce for the hardships in her married life (Osre-o-Hara}). When the life is impossible to continue and women can not tolerate anymore, she has the right to ask for divorce. The article of 1130 of Civil Code emphasizes; when the hardship is proved in the court, the husband has to divorce his wife. If he resists, the judge can divorce her. Considering the importance of Osr-o¬Hara}, few questions should be raised:
1. What is the status of Osre-o-Hara} in the Iranian legal system? What are the conditions for its implementation? In what circumstances women can file a request for divorce?
2. What types of problems and deficiencies are raised due to the generality of the concept? Is it a good solution to the problem? Is it able to provide judicial security in the family relations?
The available information demonstrates women&#039;s difficulties in proving hardship. Also Judges issue different verdicts based on their interpretation of the concept.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این مقاله مطالعه عسر و حرج به عنوان یکی از مواردی است که بر مبنای آن زنان می توانند از دادگاه درخواست طلاق نمایند. به بیان دیگر، در صورتی که ادامه زندگی زناشویی به دلایل مختلف برای زوجه غیر قابل تحمل شود، وی مجاز است از دادگاه رفع پیوند زناشویی را خاستار شود. این امر به صراحت در ماده 1130 قانون مدنی پیش بینی شده است:« در صورتی که دوام زوجیت موجب عسر و حرج زوجه باشد وی می تواند به حاکم شرع مراجعه و تقاضای طلاق کند. چنانچه عسر و حرج مذکور در محکمه ثابت شود دادگاه می تواند زوج را اجبار به طلاق نماید و درصورتی که اجبار ممکن نباشد زوجه به اذن حاکم شرع طلاق داده می شود». با توجه به اهمیت عسر و حرج می توان این این پرسش ها را مطرح و مطالعه را بر آن مبتنی ساخت: عسر و حرج درحکم یکی از موجبات طلاق چه جایگاهی در حقوق اران دارد و شرایط اعمال و اجرای آن به چه نحو است؟ به عبارت دیگر ، زنان در چه شرایطی می توانند به «عسر و حرج» به عنوان یکی از موجبات طلاق استناد نمایند؟ عسر و حرج با کلیت خود چه مشکلاتی را در عمل به وجود می آورد؟ آیا وضع قاعده عام می تواند پاسخگوی مشکلات باشد یا اینکه مصادیق عسر  حرج را باید به طور حصری مورد اشاره قرار داد؟ امری که ضرورت وجود امنیت قضایی در روابط خانوادگی آن را ایجاب می کند. اطلاعات قابل دسترس حاکی از مشکل اثبات عسر و حرج برای زنان و تفسیرهای متفاوت قضاوت از این مفهوم و در نتیجه صدور احکام متفاوت است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پدرسالاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جهانی شدن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حرج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خانواده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زناشویی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زوجه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طلاق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عسر</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فمینیسم</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_13269_7325d1059d4a32cae740ef7cef3a111f.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
