<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Study On Factors Affecting Victimization of Woman Living in Tehran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی عوامل مؤثر بر بزه دیدگی زنان شهر تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>35</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>62</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22492</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>سهیلا</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی فسائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار دانشکده علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>میرحسینی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد پژوهش علوم اجتماعی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Nowadays, new developments in the realm of criminological studies have considerably aroused social science criminal researcher’s attention toward the other involved side, which are the very victims of such crimes. Considering this, researchers have attempted to investigate, through victim-oriented approaches, the ruling condition of crime creation so that they might take sufficient measures to prevent the crimes or reduce and alleviate their consequences.
This paper which is based on qualitative research aims to analyze the grounds for crimes committed against women according to their accounts.
This is done by means of qualitative reasearch methods and performed interviews with 65 women with the age ranging from 19 to 60.
The findings of this paper suggest that the interviewed women consider the following factors as the reasons underlying the crimes committed against them which include women’s carelessness, type of daily activities, behavior and dress code, violence in the private and public environments, familial disorder and lack of sociability, inconsistent self-defense trainings, urban environment disfiguration, existence of hidden crime-causing locations such as under passes and dark places, social and economical issues like unemployment and poverty along with women’s physiological features.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه تحولات نوین در حوزه مطالعات جرم شناسی سبب شده است که توجه محققین علوم اجتماعی و جرم شناسی به آن سوی عمل مجرمانه، یعنی قربانیان جرایم معطوف شود. بر اساس رویکردهای قربانی محور، شرایط حاکم بر تکوین جرم و وقوع بزه دیدگی مورد بررسی و کنکاش قرار می‌‌گیرد تا بتوان جهت پیشگیری از جرم و کاهش تبعات آن گام برداشت. مقاله حاضر که مبتنی بر پژوهشی کیفی است، با استفاده از روش تحقیق کیفی و انجام مصاحبه‌های عمیق با 65 زن 19 تا 60 ساله تهرانی، علل بزه دیدگی زنان را  بر اساس روایت خود آنان مورد بررسی و تجزیه تحلیل قرار دهد. یافته‌های این تحقیق حاکی از آن است که زنان مصاحبه شونده عواملی نظیر: بی‌احتیاطی زنان، نوع فعالیت‌های روزمره، نوع رفتار و پوشش، خشونت درحوزه خصوصی و عمومی، نابسامانی خانوادگی و ضعف در جامعه پذیری‌، ناکارآمدی یا نبود قوانین حمایتی و اجتماعی، عدم آموزش روش‌های دفاع از خود، درهم ریختگی فضای شهری، وجود مکان‌های جرم خیز و مخفی نظیر زیرگذرها و معابر تاریک، وجود نابسامانی‌های اجتماعی و اقتصادی نظیر بیکاری و فقر را در کنار ویژگی‌های فیزیولوژیک و زیستی، از جمله مهم‌ترین دلایل بزه دیدگی می‌دانند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بزه دیدگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ترس از جرم</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خشونت‌</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان‌</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عدم ادغام اجتماعی.</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_22492_ca76c832fd626f494d4e23fbe342ad10.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
