<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Evaluating the Factors Affecting the Distribution of Power in Family</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سنجش عوامل مؤثر بر توزیع قدرت در خانواده  (با تأکید بر نظریه سرمایه اجتماعی)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>23</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>40</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24765</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2012.24765</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حلیمه</FirstName>
					<LastName>عنایت</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>طاهره</FirstName>
					<LastName>رئیسی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>One of recent developments in modern societies is the evolution in the structure of power division in the family and changes in reciprocal actions between wife and husband. This research aims to study the factors affecting distribution of power in the family by using the theories of: social capital, valuable resources, and sociability of gender. The data has been collected through survey method and questionnaire among 400 married women of Jiroft by multi-stage cluster sampling. The results show that the variables: social capital, income, awareness of the respondent of women’s rights respectively describe 43.1 percent of changes related to the variable of power division in families.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">یکی از تحولات اخیر در جوامع امروزی، دگرگونی در ساخت توزیع قدرت در خانواده و تغییر در کنش متقابل بین زن و شوهر است. هدف پژوهش حاضر بررسی عوامل جامعه شناختی مؤثر بر توزیع قدرت در خانواده با استفاده از نظریه‌های سرمایه‌ی اجتماعی، منابع ارزشمند و جامعه‌پذیری جنسیت است. اطلاعات این تحقیق با روش پیمایشی و توزیع پرسشنامه در بین 400 نفر از زنان متأهل شهر جیرفت و با شیوه نمونه‌گیری خوشه‌ای مرحله‌ای گردآوری شده است. نتایج تحقیق نشان می‌دهد که به ترتیب متغیرهای سرمایه اجتماعی، میزان درآمد، میزان آگاهی پاسخ‌گو از حقوق زن و وابستگی عاطفی پاسخ‌گو به همسرش به طور کلی 1/43 درصد از تغییرات متغیر وابسته‌ی توزیع قدرت در خانواده را تبیین می‌کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توزیع قدرت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جامعه‌پذیری جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خانواده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه اجتماعی.</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24765_878403a2e16d4e747d802eb2aeab0166.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Social and Cultural Factors Affecting Women&#039;s Nutritional Disorders</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تأثیر عوامل اجتماعی و فرهنگی مؤثر بر اختلالات تغذیه‌ای زنان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>41</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>60</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24766</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2012.24766</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>عباس زاده</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>استاد رحیمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تبریز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فریبا</FirstName>
					<LastName>غنی افشرد</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناسی ارشد جامعه شناسی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پروین</FirstName>
					<LastName>علیپور</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد پژوهش موسسه مطالعات و تحقیقات اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Food safety is among the important and remarkable subjects which is considered fundamental and a basic need of individuals and society so that lack of food or nutritional disorders has serious consequences and worrying reflections. This paper aims to measure nutritional disorders among female citizens of Tabriz and Intends to identify social and cultural factors affecting it. Survey method was applied and measuring instrument was localized Standard questionnaire. The study sample included 400 women and girls aged 15-49 in the year 1389 in Tabriz who were selected by stratified random sampling based on Census 1385 and the among 432 127 individuals.  The results indicate the independent variables (influence of family, peers, media, religion and the impact of social comparisons), social comparison variable has the highest influence on respondents&#039; level of nutritional disorders and mentioned variables explain 34% of the variable changes dependant variable (eating disorder).</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">سلامت غذایی، از جمله پدیده‌های مهم و شایان توجهی است که از نیازها و ضرورت‌های اساسی و پایه‌ای فرد و جامعه به شمار می‌رود، به طوری که فقدان یا اختلالات غذایی نیز پیامدها و بازتاب‌های نگران کننده و خطرناکی به دنبال دارد. بر‌ این اساس، مقاله حاضر با هدف اندازه‌گیری میزان اختلالات تغذیه‌ای در بین شهروندان زن شهر تبریز نگاشته شده و در نظر دارد عوامل اجتماعی و فرهنگی مؤثر بر آن را شناسایی نماید. روش تحقیق، پیمایشی بوده و ابزار اندازه‌گیری، پرسشنامه استاندارد بومی شده می‌باشد. حجم نمونه  این پژوهش400 نفر  از زنان و دختران 49- 15 ساله شهر تبریز در سال 89 می‌باشند که بر اساس سرشماری سال 1385 و  از بین تعداد 432127 نفر، به روش نمونه‌گیری طبقه‌ای تصادفی انتخاب شده‌اند. نتایج تحقیق نشان می‌دهد، از بین متغیرهای مستقل (تأثیر خانواده، همسالان، رسانه‌ها، میزان دینداری و تأثیر مقایسه‌های اجتماعی)، متغیر مقایسه اجتماعی بالاترین تأثیر را بر میزان اختلالات تغذیه‌ای پاسخ‌گویان داشته است و متغیرهای مذکور 34 درصد تغییرات متغیر وابسته (اختلال تغذیه‌ای) را تبیین می‌نماید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اختلالات تغذیه‌ای</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خانواده</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">دینداری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رسانه</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مقایسه اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24766_18bdf94f965b704224269ccfd2cc391b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Sociological Analysis of Women’s Urbanization Trend in Tehran</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>تحلیل جامعه‌شناختی رفتار شهرگرایی زنان شهر تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>61</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>82</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24767</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2012.24767</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یعقوب</FirstName>
					<LastName>موسوی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه الزهرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>اعظم</FirstName>
					<LastName>پاک خصال</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه الزهرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Urbanization with all its semblances, complexities, and problems has been able to have profound effects on the behavior and action of citizens. This study intends to examine the issue of urbanization trends growth sociologically through survey method among women. It seems that in terms of acceptance, internalization, and representing parts of cultural situation, values and urbanization norms, women have peculiar conditions which need to be studied. This article is an attempt at analyzing the research findings, patterns and basic indicators of urban women in connection with Urbanization. The level of the research is micro and the unit of analysis is individual.  Sample size was 400 individuals of 20-50 year old women living in three districts of Tehran, selected randomly by cluster sampling. Findings revealed a significant relationship among Urbanization and self-estrangement, rationalization of individual action, declination of social cohesion and escalation of individualism and loss of bond between women.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">شهرگرایی با همه مظاهر، پیچیدگی‌ها و مسائل مختلف خود توانسته است آثار عمیق بر رفتار و کنش شهروندان ایجاد کند. این بررسی در نظر دارد تا مسئله‌ی رشد فرهنگ شهرگرایی را در مطالعه‌ای جامعه‌شناختی و با روش پیمایشی در بین گروه زنان بررسی نماید. به نظر می‌رسد زنان از لحاظ پذیرش، درونی کردن و بازنمایی بخشی از ایستارهای فرهنگی، ارزش‌ها و هنجارهای شهرگرایی، شرایط خاص و قابل مطالعه‌ای دارند. در این نوشتار تلاش می‌شود با تحلیل یافته‌های تحقیق، الگوها و شاخص‌های اساسی زنان شهرنشین در ارتباط با شهرگرایی مورد بررسی قرار گیرد. سطح تحلیل در این پژوهش، خرد و واحد تحلیل، فرد است. حجم نمونه تحقیق 400 نفر از زنان 50-20 ساله‌ی ساکن در سه منطقه‌ی شهر تهران است که به صورت تصادفی و با روش نمونه‌گیری خوشه‌ای انتخاب شده‌اند. یافته‌های پژوهش مبیّن وجود رابطه‌ی معنادار بین شهرگرایی و از خودبیگانگی فردی، عقلانی شدن کنش فردی، کاهش انسجام اجتماعی و افزایش فردگرایی و کاهش پیوند عاطفی در بین زنان است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ازخودبیگانگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ایستار فرهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انسجام اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شهرگرایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فردگرایی.</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24767_2d60db189207e5332e45967f63ce1f03.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Reviewing the Mechanism of Information Technology on Rural Women&#039;s Empowerment Based on Model DEA (case study: the village of Gharn Abad)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی سازوکار تأثیر فناوری اطلاعات بر توانمندی زنان روستایی بر مبنای مدلDEA (مطالعه موردی: روستای قرن آباد)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>125</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>138</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24768</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2012.24768</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسنعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>فرجی سبکبار</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرتضی</FirstName>
					<LastName>نعمتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>افشین</FirstName>
					<LastName>خاکی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This study has investigated the effects of ICT to increase efficiency and empowerment of rural women using data envelopment analysis (DEA) to investigate the mechanism of effectiveness of information technology (ICT) on the efficiency and empowerment of rural women in the village of Gharn Abad, Golestan province. In this study, using survey methods, 38 users and 25 non-users of technology (control group) were selected by stratified random sampling. Female users of technology were classified into seven levels, with level 1 the least and level 7 the most users. Based on the results, the performance of rural women in basic levels of IT users is better than their performance in higher levels. The study also confirmed the theory of digital gap, and the positive effects of information technologies and communication on empowering women in the economic, social, political, and psychological, dimensions and shows an increase in rural women&#039;s performance.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این پژوهش با هدف بررسی تأثیرات فناوری اطلاعات و ارتباطات بر افزایش کارایی و توانمندی زنان روستایی انجام شده است و با استفاده از مدل تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها (DEA) به بررسی سازوکار تأثیرگذاری فناوری اطلاعات(ICT) بر کارایی و توانمندسازی زنان روستایی در روستای قرن آباد استان گلستان می‌پردازد. در این مطالعه با استفاده از روش پیمایشی ، تعداد 38 نفرکاربر فناوری و 25 نفر غیر کاربر (گروه شاهد) به صورت نمونه‌گیری تصادفی طبقه‌ای انتخاب شدند. زنان کاربر فناوری اطلاعات از نظر سطح کاربری به هفت سطح طبقه‌بندی شدند، به نحوی که میزان استفاده از فناوری به ترتیب از سطح یک تا هفت افزایش می‌یافت. بر اساس نتایج به دست آمده میزان شاخص کارایی زنان روستایی در سطوح ابتدایی کاربری فناوری، دارای وضعیت بهتری نسبت به سطوح بالاتر است. نتایج این پژوهش همچنین ضمن تأیید نظریه شکاف دیجیتالی، تأثیرات مثبت فناوری‌های نوین اطلاعاتی و ارتباطی را بر توانمندسازی در ابعاد اقتصادی، اجتماعی، سیاسی و روانی و افزایش کارایی زنان روستایی نشان می‌دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان روستایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فناوری‌ اطلاعات</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">کارایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدل تحلیل پوششی داده‌ها.</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24768_5951cd7f35dc077194f6dcc6cb147390.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Power Resources and Ideological Interpretation of Women’s Sports Rules</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>منابع قدرت و تفسیر ایدئولوژیک قواعد ورزش بانوان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>5</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>22</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24769</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2012.24769</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمدحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>پناهی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد دانشگاه علامه طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شهناز</FirstName>
					<LastName>صداقت زادگان اصفهانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار، گروه علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه پیام نور</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Sociologists including structuralists and trans-structuralists emphatically believe in interpreting sports rules ideologically and also believe that a number of factors such as power of personality, organization and economic situation are involved. This research studies the relationship between personality power, economic, social and organizational resources with ideologically interpreting the sports rules of women. Through survey method the data collected from 30 federations which had women’s sports. The statistical population included all managers of the federations at different levels and the athletes, totally 650 people. Out of 6 hypotheses based on research theories, the ones which were orderly connected organizationally, economically, socially and gender specifically to interpreting sports rules ideologically were approved. The 3 other hypothesis did not get the approval.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">جامعه‌شناسان اعم از ساختارگرا و فراساختارگرا بر تفسیر ایدئولوژیک قواعد ورزشی تأکیده کرده و عواملی مانند سازمان و وضعیت اقتصادی را در آن موثر می‌دانند. در این تحقیق رابطه منابع قدرت اقتصادی- اجتماعی و سازمانی با نوع تفسیر ایدئولوژیک قواعد ورزشی بانوان مطالعه شده است. با استفاده از روش پیمایشی، داده‌های تحقیق از 30 فدراسیون ورزشی که دارای ورزش بانوان بودند به طور تمام شماری جمع‌آوری شد. جامعه آماری پژوهش شامل همه مدیران سطوح مختلف این فدراسیون‌ها و ورزشکاران آنها بود که در زمان تحقیق جمعاً 650 نفر بودند. از 4 فرضیه مطرح شده بر اساس مبانی نظری تحقیق، فرضیه‌های رابطه مرتبه سازمانی، پاداش‌های مالی و جنس با نوع تفسیر ایدئولوژیک قواعد ورزشی تأیید شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تفسیر ایدئولوژیک</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فدراسیون‌های ورزشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قواعد ورزشی.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">منابع قدرت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ورزش بانوان</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24769_a9f83ef520fa97b3e6e15133fd776b05.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Demographic and Social Factors Affecting Women&#039;s Employment of Higher Education Graduates (case study: Tehran)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>اشتغال زنان فارغ التحصیل آموزش عالی و عوامل جمعیتی و اجتماعی مؤثر بر آن
(مطالعه موردی شهر تهران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>83</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>104</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24770</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2012.24770</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>محمودیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار گروه جمعیت شناسی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مرجان</FirstName>
					<LastName>رشوند</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد جمعیت شناسی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>In recent years despite the rise in the number of women who have graduated from universities women’s participation in the labor market has not been increased proportionally. The present study tries to examine the employment status of women graduates of higher education as well as of social and demographic factors affecting it. In this study, secondary analysis of data from 2% sample of Census 1385 is used. The statistical population was female higher education graduates of over 20 residing in Tehran. The findings show that women have mostly graduated in social sciences, business and law. Over 90 percent of employed women are salaried by public or private section and less than 8 percent of them own managerial positions. They are mostly active in educational, health care, and assistance areas. The results of double variable analysis show that except recent immigration variable there is significant relationship among independent variables (age, education, marital status, having children, number of children, field of study, and permanent migration) and the rate of employed women who are higher education graduates. The results of multi-variable studies show that female university graduates of 35 to 49 have more opportunity to hold a job. Also women who have not migrated to Tehran in the last 10 years (1375-1385) have had more luck to have a job. In therms of fields of study, humanities females graduated in educational fields compared to humanities and arts have a greater rate of employment.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">پژوهش حاضر با هدف بررسی وضعیت اشتغال زنان فارغ التحصیل آموزش عالی و عوامل جمعیتی اجتماعی مؤثر بر آن صورت گرفته است. در این مطالعه از روش تحلیل ثانویه داده‏های نمونه 2 درصدی سرشماری 1385 استفاده شده است. جامعه آماری، کلیه فارغ التحصیلان (آموزش عالی) زن و فعال 20 سال و بیش‏تر شهر تهران می‌باشد. یافته‌های تحقیق حاکی از آن است که زنان بیش تر در رشته علوم اجتماعی، بازرگانی و حقوق فارغ التحصیل شده‌اند. بیش از 90 درصد زنان شاغل، مزد و حقوق بگیر بخش عمومی و خصوصی هستند و کم‌تر از 10 درصد زنان فارغ التحصیل صاحب پست‌های مدیریتی می‌باشند. زنان بیش تر در بخش آموزش و بعد از آن در بخش بهداشت و مددکاری اجتماعی حضور دارند. نتایج تحلیل دو متغیره نشان داد که به جز متغیر مهاجرت اخیر، بین تمامی متغیرهای مستقل (سن، وضعیت تأهل، داشتن فرزند، تعداد فرزندان، سطح تحصیلات، رشته تحصیلی و مهاجرت طول عمر) و میزان اشتغال زنان فارغ التحصیل آموزش عالی رابطه معنی‏دار وجود دارد. نتایج تحلیل چند متغیره نشان داد که احتمال اشتغال برای زنان فارغ التحصیل 49-35 ساله بیش از سایر گروه‌های سنی است. هم چنین زنان فارغ التحصیلی که طی ده سال گذشته (85-1375) مهاجرت به شهر تهران نداشته‌اند، از اشتغال بیشتری برخودار هستند. از نظر رشته تحصیلی، زنان فارغ التحصیل رشته علوم تربیتی در مقایسه با زنان فارغ التحصیل رشته‏های علوم انسانی و هنر اشتغال بالاتری دارند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتغال زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتغال زنان فارغ التحصیل آموزش عالی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شهر تهران.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">عوامل جمعیتی و اجتماعی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24770_cefdd7134b64c3647dba53cb9de3e956.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>

<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Rating Micro Credit Funds Based on Rural Women’s Ability in Kermanshah</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رتبه بندی صندوق های اعتبارات خرد بر اساس توانمندسازی زنان روستایی استان کرمانشاه</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>105</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>124</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24771</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2012.24771</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کیومرث</FirstName>
					<LastName>زرافشانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیرحسین</FirstName>
					<LastName>علی بیگی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه رازی کرمانشاه</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مژگان</FirstName>
					<LastName>فقیری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشگاه رازی-کارشناس ارشد ترویج و آموزش</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Empowering rural women is one of the third millennium goals. To this end it was proposed to allot micro credits to rural women in order to provide the required capital to launch productive careers. Now after a decade from the establishment of micro credit funds in Iran, only few researches have been done to give a rank to them. The present research is conducted through survey method to rank micro credit funds based on empowering rural women of Kermanshah using Bartlett table and systematic random sampling for which 183 women members of this fund were selected. The ranking results show that from economic aspect: Fash (Kangavar), Tamarg, Pariveh (Mersin) have achieved the places first to third, in terms of empowering women goals. From social aspect: Fash, Pariveh and Gheitas Abad were placed first to third. From family aspect: members of Fash Fund, Pariveh, and Kooseh vand were ranked first to third. According to the results, since the authorities of the funds can play a key role in the success of funds it is recommended to the Office for Rural Women’s Affairs that the authorities of funds are selected based on the votes of the members and criteria like: education, age, etc.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">توانمندسازی زنان روستایی یکی از اهداف توسعه‌ هزاره ‌سوم است. در همین راستا طرح اعطای اعتبارات‌ خرد به زنان روستایی با هدف فراهم ساختن سرمایه لازم برای راه‌اندازی مشاغل تولیدی به‌منظور توانمندسازی آنان مطرح گردید. اکنون با وجود گذشت حدود یک دهه از عمر صندوق اعتبارات‌ خرد در ایران، مطالعات اندکی در زمینه رتبه‌بندی این صندوق‌ها انجام شده‌است. این پژوهش از نوع پیمایشی بوده که برای رتبه‌بندی صندوق‌های اعتبارات‌خرد بر اساس توانمندسازی زنان روستایی استان کرمانشاه، با استفاده از جدول بارتلت و روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی سیستماتیک، 183 نفر از زنان عضو این صندوق ها انتخاب گردیدند. رتبه‌بندی صندوق‌ها بر اساس توانمندسازی زنان از ابعاد مختلف ، بر اساس آماره تحلیل عامل تاییدی نشان می دهد که در بعد اقتصادی: فش (کنگاور)، تمرگ و پریوه (هرسین) رتبه‌های اول تا سوم را کسب نمودند. در بعد اجتماعی: فش، پریوه و قیطاس‌آباد (صحنه) رتبه‌ی اول تا سوم را به خود اختصاص دادند. در بعد خانوادگی اعضای صندوق‌های فش، پریوه و کوسه‌وند (کرمانشاه) به ترتیب در جایگاه‌های اول تا سوم قرار گرفتند. با توجه به نتایج به‌دست آمده، از ‌آنجایی‌که مسئولین صندوق‌ها می‌توانند نقش قابل توجهی را در موفقیت صندوق‌ها ایفا نمایند، توصیه می‌گردد انتخاب مسئولین صندوق بر اساس رأی‌ اعضا و تعیین معیارهایی همچون تحصیلات، سن و ... از سوی دفتر امورزنان روستایی باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل عاملی تأئیدی.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندسازی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">رتبه بندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان روستایی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24771_b4f4e618fdd994afdf64f0bdfe515ac5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
