<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>10</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2013</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Investigation of Empowerment Levels and Rate among Members of the Women’s Rural Association (A Case Study of the Tafihan Women’s Association, Shiraz County)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی سطوح و میزان توانمندی در بین اعضای تعاونی زنان روستایی (مورد مطالعه: تعاونی زنان تفیهان شهرستان شیراز)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>153</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>172</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">30579</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2013.30579</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ناصر</FirstName>
					<LastName>زمانی میاندشتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار بخش ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>پوریا</FirstName>
					<LastName>عطائی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نسیم</FirstName>
					<LastName>ایزدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانش آموخته کارشناسی ارشد ترویج و آموزش کشاورزی دانشگاه شیراز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The empowerment of women has been widely acknowledged as an important goal in international development. The main aim of this study was to investigate empowerment levels and rate among the members of Tafihan Rural Women’s Association.Those who were subject to research consisted of all members of the Tafihan Women’s Association (418 members), out of which, a total number of 200 members were selected through a stratified random sampling method. The data was obtained through means of a questionnaire. Face validity of the questionnaire was obtained through an experts’ panel, and reliability was acquired through pilot testing. The Cronbach&#039;s alpha was .94. Results revealed that empowerment dimensions of the association members can be categorized in four sectors: psychological, familial, economic and socio-cultural dimensions. Results also showed that psychological and socio-cultural dimensions ranked highest, and were followed by familial and economic dimensions.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">توانمندسازی زنان به طور گسترده‌ای به عنوان یک هدف مهم در توسعه بین‌المللی شناخته شده است. هدف اصلی این پژوهش، بررسی سطوح و میزان توانمندی اعضای تعاونی زنان روستایی تفیهان بود. جمعیت این مطالعه تمام اعضای تعاونی تفیهان 418 نفر بودند که تعداد 200 نفر از اعضا با استفاده از روش نمونه‌گیری طبقه بندی تصادفی انتخاب و مورد مطالعه قرار گرفتند. ابزار مورد استفاده برای جمع‌آوری داده‌ها پرسشنامه بود که روایی صوری آن به‌وسیله پانلی از متخصصین تأیید گردید و برای بررسی پایایی آن نیز آزمون راهنما اجرا شد که آلفای کرونباخ 94/0 برای گویه‌های توانمندی به‌ دست آمد. نتایج نشان داد که ابعاد توانمندی اعضای تعاونی در چهار بعد توانمندی روانی، خانوادگی، اقتصادی و اجتماعی ـ فرهنگی قابل تقسیم بندی است. همچنین، نتایج نشان داد که رقم ابعاد روانی و اجتماعی ـ فرهنگی توانمندی از سایر ابعاد توانمندی بیش‌تر بوده و توانمندی خانوادگی و اقتصادی در رتبه‌های بعدی قرار دارد.</OtherAbstract>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_30579_5da8c28ea0a2af1c51ffee07b0b025dc.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
