<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>15</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2017</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Imam Khomeini and the construction of a female identity in the Islamic Revolution</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>امام خمینی(ره) و برساخت هویت زنانه در انقلاب اسلامی چگونگی واسازی گفتمان پهلوی دوم و هژمونی معنایی امام خمینی(ره)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>327</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>357</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">63329</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2017.219672.1007085</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مسعود</FirstName>
					<LastName>کوثری</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشیار ارتباطات اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>امیرعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>تفرشی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری تخصصی علوم ارتباطات اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>معصومه سادات</FirstName>
					<LastName>علوی نکو</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد علوم ارتباطات اجتماعی دانشگاه علامه‌ طباطبایی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2016</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>07</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The Islamic Revolution of Iran can be identified as the emergence of a discursive transformation in Iranian society. This revolution, not only was indicative of a discursive and semantic transformation in the context of the Iranian society, but also it was able to create a new sign and a new meaning within the context of global discourses; thus, Foucault also mentioned this revolution as &quot;the soul of a world repulsions.&quot; The present study for understanding the characteristics of this discursive evolution, aimed to study its most influential theorist, Imam Khomeini, the founder of the Islamic Revolution. Given the necessity of creating boundaries for the study of discourse analysis, one of the most controversial discourse disciplines, that is, the discursive order of female identity, was chosen for study in this discourse. At the next phase, according to the macro view and the abstract mapping of discursive articulation, using Laclau and Mouffe&#039;s approach, this theory and method was chosen for analyzing the discourse of Imam Khomeini&#039;s speeches. According to the findings, the central sign of this discourse is &quot;preservation of chastity and religiosity&quot; and despite the conformity of some of the signs of this discourse with hegemonic discourses in the Western world, such as &quot;social activity&quot; and &quot;freedom,&quot; all this is defined around &quot;The preservation of chastity and religiosity&quot; in this discourse, and a meaning different from other discourses is created. This discourse, which emerges in the apparent controversy with the second Pahlavi’s discourse, is also seriously deconstructing its hostile discourse-especially in the case of removing the shame from society- and attempts to marginalize it. Among epistemes that these two conflicting discourses have used to marginalize their rival discourse, are &quot; being foreign&quot;, &quot;seeing women as objects&quot;, &quot;ignorance&quot;, &quot; negligence&quot; and &quot; &quot;approval of prostitution.&quot;  On the contrary, the well-known fundamental epistemes that these two discourses have used for their hegemony in the Discursive Order of feminine identity include: &quot;belief in progress&quot;, &quot;support of freedom&quot;, &quot;respect for women&quot;, &quot;belief in equality of women and men&quot; and &quot;being civilized&quot;.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">انقلاب اسلامی ایران به‌عنوان ظهور و بروز یک تحول گفتمانی در جامعۀ ایران قابل شناسایی ا‌ست. این انقلاب نه‌تنها در وضعیت جامعۀ ایران بیان‌گر تحولی گفتمانی و معنایی بود، بلکه در چارچوب گفتمان‌های جهانی نیز توانست ایجاد یک پیوند نشانه و معنای جدیدی را به منصۀ ظهور گذارد؛ بدین‌گونه است که فوکو نیز از این انقلاب به‌‌منزلۀ «روح یک جهان بی‌روح» نام می‌برد. پژوهش حاضر در راستای شناخت مشخصه‌های این تحول گفتمانی، به مطالعۀ مؤثرترین نظریه‌پرداز آن، یعنی امام خمینی(ره)، بنیان‌گذار انقلاب اسلامی، اقدام کرده است. با توجه به لزوم ایجاد حدود و ثغور برای مطالعۀ تحلیل گفتمان، یکی از نظم‌های پر‌مناقشۀ گفتمانی، یعنی نظم گفتمانی هویت زنانه، برای مطالعه در این گفتمان انتخاب شد. در ادامه، با توجه به دید کلان‌نگر و ایجاد نقشه‌های انتزاعی از مفصل‌بندی‌های گفتمانی، توسط رویکرد لاکلا و موف، این نظریه و روش برای تحلیل گفتمان سخنان امام خمینی(ره) انتخاب شد. طبق یافته‌های به‌دست‌آمده، دال مرکزی این گفتمان «حفظ عفت و دینداری» ا‌ست و با وجود همسانیِ نشانه‌ایِ بعضی از دال‌های این گفتمان با گفتمان‌های هژمونیک‌شده در دنیای غرب، مانند «فعالیت اجتماعی» و «آزادی»، اما همین دال‌ها نیز در حول محوریت «حفظ عفت و دینداری» در این گفتمان تعریف می‌شود و معنایی دیگر و متفاوت با گفتمان‌های رقیب از آن‌ها خلق می‌شود. این گفتمان، که در نزاعی آشکار با گفتمان پهلوی دوم ظهور پیدا می‌کند، به‌ شکل جدی به واسازی گفتمان متخاصم خود می‌پردازد. گفتمانِ امام خمینی(ره)، گفتمان پهلوی را با «خارجی‌بودن»، «قائل به شیء بودن زنان»، «موافقت با فحشا» و بالاخص به‌عنوان گفتمانی که «عفت و دینداری زن را در حاشیه قرار داده»، معرفی می‌کند و معتقد است گفتمان پهلوی با طرح شعارهایی چون «حرکت به سوی ترقی و پیشرفت»، «طرفداری از آزادی زنان»، «احترام برای زنان»، «برابری زنان و مردان» و «تمدن‌مدار بودن» تلاش دارد زنان را سوژۀ گفتمان خود کند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">امام خمینی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">انقلاب اسلامی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحلیل گفتمان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">لاکلا و موف</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هویت زنانه</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_63329_f575d980c27a27955871e31550889f00.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
