<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>17</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Analysis of short-term and long-term economic variables on marriage and divorce trend with an emphasis on sexual and educational control channels</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی تأثیر کوتاه‌مدت و بلندمدت متغیرهای اقتصادی بر روند ازدواج و طلاق در ایران با تأکید بر کانال‌های کنترلی جنسی و آموزشی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>487</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>511</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">75185</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2020.289345.1007715</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>قائمی اصل</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار دانشکدة اقتصاد دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>نصر اصفهانی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت‌علمی دانشکدة اقتصاد، دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>الهه</FirstName>
					<LastName>شاه پرست</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد اقتصاد انرژی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>نیره</FirstName>
					<LastName>توسلی عبدل‌آبادی</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد اقتصاد انرژی، دانشگاه فردوسی مشهد</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2019</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Marriage and divorce can be related to economic, sexual and institutional issues that make it easier or more difficult to create or maintain a new married life. In this study, the impact of economic variables on smooth and stochastic trends of marriage and divorce, with emphasis on sexual ratio and literacy rate control channels has been analyzed during 1969-2016 in Iran, using Autoregressive Distributed Lag model and Kalman filter. The results show that there is a significant and positive relationship between smooth divorce process and economic variables. Importantly, sexual ratio and literacy rate control channels are the channels that allow for accurate interpretations of unemployment and inflation on the smooth divorce process. In addition, sexual ratio and literacy rate have a positive and significant effect on the smooth marriage process. Therefore, the emphasis on gender-based alerting mechanism and literacy rate planning can have a double and synergic effect on improving the marriage process in Iran. Therefore, family formation in Iran is particularly influenced by gender control channels (especially sexual ratio) and institutional control channels (especially literacy rates) but the decision to divorce can be influenced by inflation and unemployment in addition to gender and institutional variables.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">تحولات ازدواج و وقوع طلاق می‏تواند با مسائل جنسی، نهادی و اقتصادی‌ـ که امکان تشکیل یا ادامة زندگی مشترک را تسهیل یا دشوار می‏کنند‌ـ ارتباط داشته باشد. در این پژوهش، تأثیر متغیرهای اقتصادی بر روند ساختاری (پایدار) و روند تصادفی ازدواج و طلاق با بهره‏گیری از فیلتر کالمن (KF)، با تأکید بر کانال‏های کنترلی نسبت جنسیتی و نرخ باسوادی در ایران طی دورة 1348ـ1395 در دو الگوی کوتاه‏مدت و بلندمدت مبتنی بر مدل خودرگرسیون با وقفه‏های توزیعی (ARDL) بررسی شده است. نتایج نشان می‏دهد میان روند ساختاری (پایدار) متغیر طلاق و متغیرهای اقتصادی رابطة معنا‏دار و مثبتی وجود دارد. نکتة حائز اهمیت این است که کانال‏های کنترلیِ نسبت جنسی و نرخ باسوادی هستند که امکان تأثیرگذاری و تفسیر دقیق و معنا‏دار بیکاری و تورم بر روند ساختاری (پایدار) طلاق را فراهم می‏آورند. به‌علاوه، نسبت جنسی و نرخ باسوادی خود نیز تأثیر مثبت و معنا‏داری بر روند ساختاری (پایدار) ازدواج دارند. از‌این‌رو، تأکید و توجه ویژه به مکانیسمِ هشدار نسبت جنسی و برنامه‏ریزی در‌خصوص نرخ باسوادی می‏تواند تأثیری مضاعف و هم‏افزا بر بهبود روند ازدواج در ایران داشته باشد. بنابراین، تشکیل خانواده در ایران به‌طور ویژه تحت‌تأثیر زمینه‏های جنسی (به‌ویژه نسبت جنسی) و زمینه‏های آموزشی (به‌ویژه نرخ باسوادی) است، ولی تصمیم به طلاق می‏تواند علاوه بر متغیرهای جنسی و آموزشی، تحت‌تأثیر تورم و بیکاری نیز باشد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ازدواج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بیکاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">طلاق</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فلیتر کالمن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نسبت جنسی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_75185_e7fd1eeec02423b36efed7f15fdd751b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
