<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2005</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>قومیت و الگوهای ازدواج در ایران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">13238</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد جلال عباسی</FirstName>
					<LastName>شوازی</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رسول</FirstName>
					<LastName>صادقی</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>: Marriage patterns are different between countries and even among different ethnic groups within countries. Such differences are determined by both ethnic-cultural factors as well as socio-economic ones. The present paper uses the data from the 1991 Household Socioeconomic Characteristics to examine marriage patterns among ethnic groups in Iran, to identify the impact of ethnicity on these patterns. The results indicate that there are distinct marriage patterns among
ethnic groups in Iran.	Various analyses also show that after
controlling socio-economic and demographic factors, ethnic differences in marriage patterns remain in the model. In other words, ethnicity has an independent role in the explanation of ethnic differentials in marriage patterns. The result of research shows that though ethnic norms and values are important and influensive in patterns of marriage but some other factors such as modernization and socio-economic determinants have also been important, too. Anthropological-demographic studies using qualitative methods can provide a deeper understanding on the impacts of ethnic norms, values and practices on marriage patterns and family in Iran.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">الگوهای ازدواج در بین کشورها و حتی در درون یک کشور در میان گروه های قومی گوناگون، متفاوت است. چنین نوسانی می تواند هم ناشی از عوامل قومی – فرهنگی ،و هم متأثر از عوامل اقصادی – اجتماعی باشد. مقاله حاضر با استفاده از داده های طرح ملی&quot;بررسی ویژگی های اقتصادی اجتماعی خانوار 1380 &quot; به بررسی الگوهای ازدواج در میان گروه های قومی در ایران پرداخته و تأثیر مستقل قومیت بر این الگوها را بررسی می نماید. یافته ها نشان دهنده الگوهای متمایز ازدواج در میان گروه های قومی در ایران است. نتایج تحلیل چند متغیره نیز بیانگر این است که بعد از کنترل مشصه های اقتصادی، اجتماعی و جمعیتی، تفاوتهای قومی در الگوهای ازدواج باقی می ماند و به عبارتی قومیت نقش مستقلی در تبیین الگوهای ازدواج در ایران است. هرچند هنجارها و ارزش های قومی فرهنگی در ورای نوسازی اقتصادی اجتماعی اثر خود را اعمال نموده و به تفاوت درالگوهای ازدواج منجر شده است، با اینحال عوامل اقتصادی اجتماعی نیز در تعدیل و کاهش اثر قومیت نقش داشته است. مطالعات جمعیت شناسی – مردم شناسانه با بکارگیری روش های کیفی می تواند شناخت عمیق تری نسبت به تأثیر هنجارها ،ارزشها و اعمال قومی بر الگوهای ازدواج و خانواده در ایران ارائه نماید.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اثر ناهنجاری – فرهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ازدواج بین قومی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">الگوهای ازدواج</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قومیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همانندی مشخصه ها</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_13238_05ccf3606d9a78a61e44784a0fd6790c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
