<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Vulnerability of Women to Natural Disasters: A Social Construct</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>آسیب‌پذیری زنان در سوانح طبیعی: یک برساختۀ اجتماعی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>457</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>481</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68858</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2018.251698.1007376</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>کرم</FirstName>
					<LastName>حبیب‌پور گتابی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار جامعه‏ شناسی دانشگاه خوارزمی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>03</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The present study uses feminist and critical theories to study the vulnerability of women in natural disasters in order to optimize the management of natural disaster risk with the aim of reducing their vulnerability. This research has a quantitative methodology using survey. Among 384 men and women aged 15-65 in Gorgan and Kerman provinces, we selected some people based on cluster and proportional stratification sampling methods. The results showed that the most important areas of vulnerability of women in natural disasters were lack of security, lack of employment, lack or weakness of education in the field of natural disasters, cultural problems or the traditional thinking patterns of men about women, no belief in women&#039;s participation in disasters. Meanwhile, the most important contexts of women&#039;s vulnerability to natural disasters were, as compared to men, the potential and background of women emotional and psychological vulnerability.  The social conditions are defined for women in the society and the lack of respect for women&#039;s rights by the society and authorities; the physical vulnerability of women; and the preservation of Hijab at the time of the disaster. The findings imply that the natural disasters are intrinsically social phenomena rooted from a social structure or system. Hence, vulnerability of women to natural disasters can be traced back to a construction and the consequence of social structures and semantic systems, which makes the division in the roles of men and women that, produces and reproduces this vulnerability.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقالة حاضر با تلفیقی از نظریه‏های برساخت‏گرایی اجتماعی و فمنیستی به بررسی کمّ‏وکیف آسیب‏پذیری زنان در سوانح طبیعی به منظور مدیریت بهینة ریسک سوانح طبیعی با هدف کاهش میزان آسیب‏پذیری آنان می‏پردازد. روش‏شناسی تحقیق کمی و روش آن پیمایشی بوده است که بین 768 نفر از زنان و مردان 15 تا 65 سالة دو شهر گرگان و کرمان براساس شیوه‏های نمونه‏گیری خوشه‏ای، طبقه‏بندی متناسب و تصادفی نظام‏مند انجام شده است. نتایج نشان داد که حوزه‏های مهم آسیب‏پذیری زنان در سوانح طبیعی عبارت بودند از: فقدان امنیت، فقدان اشتغال، فقدان یا ضعف آموزش در زمینة سوانح طبیعی و مشکلات فرهنگی یا انگاره‏های تفکر سنتی مردان درخصوص زنان و باورنداشتن به مشارکت زنان در سوانح. همچنین، دلایل مهم آسیب‏پذیری زنان در سوانح طبیعی، در مقایسه با مردان، عبارت بودند از: پتانسیل و زمینة آسیب‏پذیری بیشتر روحی و روانی زنان (به دلیل عاطفی‏بودن، داشتن ترس و اضطراب و...)، شرایط اجتماعی تعریف‏شده برای زنان در جامعه و رعایت‌نکردن حقوق زنان از طرف جامعه و مسئولان، آسیب‏پذیری جسمانی و فیزیکی زنان و حفظ حجاب در زمان وقوع سوانح و... . دلالت یافته‏ها بر آن است که سوانح طبیعی ذاتاً پدیده‏های اجتماعی‏اند و در ساختار یا نظام اجتماعی ریشه دارند. از‌این‌رو، آسیب‏پذیری زنان در سوانح طبیعی را می‏توان به‌منزلة امری برساختی و نتیجة ساختارهای اجتماعی و نظام‏های معنایی آن دانست که تفکیک نقشی زن و مرد موجب تولید و بازتولید این آسیب‏پذیری می‏شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آسیب‏ پذیری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سوانح طبیعی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت ریسک</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_68858_2975a61d548464be20da02cbdf2ae4b7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
