<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>3</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2005</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Critical Review on Mernissi idea of Hejab</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>نقد آراء فاطمه مرنیسی در خصوص حجاب</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">19204</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>زهرا</FirstName>
					<LastName>فهرستی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیأت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی ـ واحد تهران مرکز</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This article is an analytical review of the book &quot;The veil and the male elites&quot; written by Fatima Mernissi.  The author of the book justifies her elaboration based on two historical references namely Tabari History and Traditions of Ibn Husham. The limitation of references utilized by the author as well as neglecting research standards in analysis and critical review of the issues has made her book unreliable from so many aspects. But the author&#039;s failure is more significant on various issues such as instruction of veiling for women according to verse 53 from Ahzab, in Koran. The wrong approach which is applied by Mernissi led her to depict a voyeuristic picture of great prophet.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مقالة حاضر تلاشی است در جهت نقد و تحلیل کتاب زنان پرده‌نشین و نخبگان جوشن‏پوش نوشته فاطمه مرنیسی. نویسندة کتاب با تکیه بر دو منبع تاریخی؛ تاریخ طبری و سیرة ابن هشام تحلیل‏های خود را ارائه کرده است.
محدودیت منابع مورد استفاده نویسنده و عدم اتقان علمی آنها، همچنین عدم رعایت شاخصه‏های پژوهش در تحلیل و نقد مطالب، کتاب حاضر را از جهات بی‏شماری قابل تأمل ساخته است. اما لغزش نویسنده در چند جا نمود بیشتری دارد که می‏توان به موارد زیر اشاره کرد: استنباط اشتباه از آیه 53 سورة احزاب، روش نادرست نویسنده در نقد احادیث مذمت زنان و سرانجام ترسیم چهره‌ای نادرست از پیامبر اسلام (ص).</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مرنیسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حجاب و روایت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_19204_4806a147b847ca223691e7b63a643575.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
