<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>16</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Relationship between Board Gender Diversity and Internal Control Weaknesses</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>بررسی ارتباط بین حضور زنان در هیئت‌مدیره و ضعف کنترل داخلی، شواهدی از شرکت‌های پذیرفته شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>439</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>456</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">68857</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2018.259908.1007441</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>یاسر</FirstName>
					<LastName>رضائی پیته‌نوئی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار حسابداری، دانشکدۀ ادبیات و علوم انسانی، دانشگاه گیلان</Affiliation>
<Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8025-3555</Identifier>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>خدیجه</FirstName>
					<LastName>محسنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد حسابداری، واحد بندر گز، دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2018</Year>
					<Month>06</Month>
					<Day>10</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Today, sustainable development relies on empowerment of women, as social scientists have always emphasized on the elimination of gender barriers as a prerequisite for the realization of economic and social development. Accordingly, the main purpose of this research is to investigate the relationship between Board Gender Diversity and Internal Control Weaknesses in companies admitted to the Tehran Stock Exchange. To test the research hypotheses, financial information of the companies listed in Tehran Stock Exchange was used between 2012 and 2016. Thus, after applying the limitations in this study, a final sample of 87 companies was selected. In this study, the Board Gender Diversity as independent variable and Internal Control Weaknesses are dependent variables of the research. After measuring the variables of the research, multivariate linear regression analysis was used to test the research hypotheses. Statistical tests were performed using the Eviews econometric software and the statistical data compilation technique. The results obtained from the test indicate that there is a significant relationship between Board Gender Diversity and Internal Control Weaknesses. In other words, the presence of women on the board reduces the company&#039;s internal control weaknesses.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">امروزه، توسعة پایدار بر توانمندسازی زنان تکیه دارد؛ به‌طوری‌که اندیشمندان اجتماعی همواره بر رفع موانع جنسیتی به‌منزلة لازمة تحقق توسعة اقتصادی و اجتماعی تأکید کرده‌اند. بر این اساس، هدف اصلی تحقیق حاضر بررسی ارتباط بین جنسیت هیئت‌مدیره و ضعف کنترل داخلی در شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران است. در این مطالعه، جنسیت هیئت‌مدیره به‌منزلة متغیر مستقل و ضعف کنترل داخلی متغیر وابسته پژوهش است. برای آزمون فرضیه‌های تحقیق از اطلاعات مالی شرکت‌های پذیرفته‌شده در بورس اوراق بهادار تهران در فاصلة زمانی بین سال‌های 1391 تا 1395 استفاده شده است. به‌طوری‌که پس از اعمال محدودیت‌های مورد نظر در این تحقیق، نمونة نهایی متشکل از 87 شرکت انتخاب شدند. پس از اندازه‌گیری متغیرهای تحقیق از تجزیه و تحلیل رگرسیون خطی چند‌متغیره و تکنیک آماری داده‌های ترکیبی برای آزمون فرضیة‌ تحقیق استفاده شد. نتایج به‌دست‌آمده از آزمون فرضیه‌ حاکی از آن است که بین جنسیت هیئت‌مدیره و ضعف کنترل داخلی شرکت‌ها رابطة منفی معناداری وجود دارد. به ‌عبارت دیگر، حضور زنان در هیئت‌مدیره ضعف کنترل داخلی شرکت را کاهش می‌دهد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جنسیت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">ضعف کنترل داخلی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">گزارش حسابرسی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">هیئت‌مدیره</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_68857_2d214e9d751d3d58bd932e81f740cad5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
