<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>2</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2011</Year>
					<Month>08</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Qualitative Study of Social Factors of Spousal Homicide</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مطالعه کیفی عوامل اجتماعی همسرکشی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>77</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>110</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">22988</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>قاضی نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیات علمی گروه جامعه شناسی دانشگاه الزهراء</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>ماریا</FirstName>
					<LastName>عباسیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد جامعه‌شناسی دانشگاه الزهرا</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Spousal homicide is a personal, domestic and social problem which has mortal and morbid effects on public safety. Domestic homicide, especially spousal homicide, is typically unlike stranger murder, not a crime of sudden, unanticipated violence. Rather, these murders hide the tragic story of escalated domestic violence, strain and personal and social harmful consequences in them that require serious study. 
So the aim of this research is to identify social-cultural factors leading to spousal homicide which has been increased considerably in last years and involve many men and women as a &quot;murder&quot; or &quot;victim&quot;. By applying qualitative method of research, we try to achieve this aim. For this reason, through random sampling, we select 34 files of spousal homicide incidents that occurred in Tehran between 1380 and 1387. Half of these files belong to spousal homicide of men and the rest half belong to spousal homicide of women. By applying content analysis technique, we have analyzed and examined all of these files. 
The result of this research show that the presence of social-psychological strain on men and women in the family, in the absence of social and personal support system and association with delinquent peers and blockage of legal coping ways, lead couples to commit spousal homicide. Results also show different patterns of killing and factors between men and women.
Moreover demographic variables such as social-economical status of couples and their families, couple&#039;s age and age disparity, age and the number of children also affecting spousal homicide.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">همسرکشی مسئله‌ای فردی، خانوادگی و اجتماعی است که تأثیر مخرب و نابودکنند‌ای بر امنیت و سلامت عمومی جامعه به جای می‌گذارد. قتل‌های خانوادگی، به خصوص همسرکشی، برخلاف قتل‌های دیگر، خشونتی تصادفی و نامحتمل نیست، بلکه ماجرای غم انگیزی از انواع خشونت خانوادگی، فشارها و پیامدهای زیان‌بار فردی و اجتماعی را در خود پنهان دارد. از این رو هدف مقاله حاضر، کشف علل و عوامل اجتماعی و فرهنگی مؤثر بر پدیده همسرکشی است که در سال‌های اخیر در جامعه ما افزایش داشته و زنان و مردان بسیاری را در جایگاه قاتل یا مقتول درگیر ساخته است. بدین منظور، با روش کیفی از میان پرونده‌های جنایی همسرکشی مربوط به قتل‌هایی که در خلال سال‌های 1380 تا 1387 در استان تهران رخ داده است، 34 پرونده، 17 مورد مربوط به زن‌کشی مردان و 17 مورد مربوط به شوهرکشی زنان، به طور تصادفی انتخاب شده‌اند و با استفاده از تکنیک تحلیل محتوا بررسی و تجزیه و تحلیل شدند. نتایج نشان می‌دهد که وجود فشارهای روانی ـ اجتماعی بر زنان و مردان در خانواده، در غیاب یا ضعف شبکه‌های حمایت اجتماعی و فردی، همچنین معاشرت با دوستان بزهکار و انسداد راه‌های قانونی مواجهه با این فشارها، همسران را به قتل شریک زندگی سوق داده است. یافته‌ها همچنین تفاوت‌هایی را در الگوی ارتکاب قتل زنان و مردان و عوامل دخیل در ارتکاب قتل توسط آنان نشان داده‌اند. علاوه بر این، متغیرهای جمعیت شناختی و اجتماعی چون پایگاه اقتصادی ـ اجتماعی زن و شوهر و خانواده منشأ، سن زن و شوهر و تعداد و سن فرزندان نیز بر ارتکاب همسرکشی تأثیر داشته‌اند.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">پرونده جنایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خشونت</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">‌ زن‌کشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شوهرکشی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">فشارهای روانی ـ اجتماعی.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">قتل‌</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">همسرکشی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_22988_1dd00b26c5d5c3541ed12b5e75143051.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
