<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>13</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>An assessment of the effect of citizenship education on empowering women (Case study: Tehran 6th district)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سنجش تأثیر آموزش‌ شهروندی بر توانمندسازی زنان (مطالعۀ موردی: منطقۀ 6 شهرداری تهران)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>131</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>149</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">55210</ELocationID>
			
<ELocationID EIdType="doi">10.22059/jwdp.2015.55210</ELocationID>
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مریم</FirstName>
					<LastName>نجار نهاوندی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه برنامه‌ریزی اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>معصومه</FirstName>
					<LastName>آبخوش</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد مطالعات زنان دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>2015</Year>
					<Month>04</Month>
					<Day>19</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Following a neighborhood-oriented approach, Tehran municipality provided citizenship education with the purpose of empowering women. In spite of the large coverage of the project and its high costs, comprehensive studies haven’t been conducted in this area yet. Thus, the present study primarily tries to examine the relationship between provided education and the level of empowerment. The research methodology is survey. Research population consists of 700 female inhabitants of Jihad neighborhood in 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; municipality district. The study sample, randomly selected, includes 384 females (divided in two equal groups of educated and uneducated women). Information was collected through a questionnaire which had already been shown to have an acceptable alpha coefficient. Results from independent T test suggest that there&#039;s a significant relation between educated and uneducated women in terms of participation, hygiene awareness, citizenship rights and duties and life skills, i.e. educated women have higher scores. However, no significant relation was found between educated and uneducated women in terms of health and social harms. Results from correlation test indicated that education is strongly and positively related to women&#039;s empowerment. Additionally, test results revealed that marital status and employment status are not related to the extent of the influence of education on empowering women.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">شهرداری تهران براساس رویکرد محله‌محوری به ارائۀ آموزش‌های شهروندی جهت توانمندی زنان پرداخته است. با وجود گستردگی و هزینۀ زیاد این آموزش‌ها، تحقیقات منسجمی در این خصوص صورت نگرفته است. از‌این‌رو، بررسی رابطۀ آموزش‌های ارائه‌شده بر سطح توانمندی زنان هدف اصلی این تحقیق است. روش تحقیق پیمایشی و جامعۀ آماری 7000 نفر از زنان محلۀ جهاد شهرداری منطقۀ 6 هستند. حجم نمونه 384 نفر (192 نفر از زنان آموزش‌دیده و 192 نفر از زنان آموزش‌ندیده) است که با روش نمونه‌گیری تصادفی و سهمیه‌ای انتخاب شده‌اند. تکنیک جمع‌آوری اطلاعات پرسش‌نامه است که ضریب آلفای قابل ‌قبولی دارد. نتایج آزمون تی‌ مستقل نشان داد بین مشارکت، آگاهی از مسائل بهداشتی، حقوق و وظایف شهروندی، و میزان مهارت زندگی زنان آموزش‌دیده‌ و آموزش‌ندیده تفاوت معناداری وجود دارد و زنان آموزش‌دیده وضعیت مطلوب‌تری دارند؛ اما درخصوص رابطۀ بین آموزش‌های ارائه‌شده در حوزۀ سلامت و آسیب‌های اجتماعی تفاوتی بین زنان مشاهده نشد. نتایج آزمون همبستگی نشان داد رابطۀ مثبت و قوی بین میزان تحصیلات و میزان توانمندسازی زنان برقرار است. نتایج آزمون خی‌دو نیز نشان داد بین وضعیت تأهل و وضعیت شغلی با میزان تأثیر آموزش بر توانمندسازی زنان رابطه وجود ندارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آموزش شهروندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">توانمندی زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">حقوق و وظایف شهروندی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محلۀ جهاد</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">محله‌محوری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مشارکت</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_55210_fb035f667522d512271838ce713f1e3e.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
