<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2002</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Rationality and Reasoning: Dialogue among Generations and Gender</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>عقلانیت و استدلال ؛ گفتگو میان نسل‏ها و زنان و مردان</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">26922</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>حمید</FirstName>
					<LastName>عبداللهیان</LastName>
<Affiliation>? دارای دکترای جامعه شناسی از دانشگاه کارلتون، کانادا، استادیار دانشکده علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This paper is an attempt to criticize “universalism” and “rationality” that is engraved in the epistemological foundations of the social sciences in the modernity era. This attempt will help to reconstruct these foundations provide a better understanding of the processes of reasoning and production of knowledge by generations and gender.
The concept of rationality with a universalistic approach and in its positivist meaning has resulted in neglecting rational specifies of women, which has led to a crisis in social sciences.
Changes in the university and positivist meaning of rationality and replacing it with a more flexible content which assumes plurality in the process of reasoning will provide a ground for post modernists efforts in current decades.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این مقاله کوششی است برای نقد عام گرایی در مبانی معرفت شناختی علوم اجتماعی و کاربرد مفهوم عقلانیت در دوران مدرنیته، به گونه‏ای که این نقد به بازسازی این مبانی در فرآیند فهم استدلال و تولید دانش توسط نسل‏ها، جنسیت ها و ... کمک کند.
کاربرد مفهوم عقلانیت به معنای پوزیتیویستی و عام گرایانه‏اش موجب نادیده انگاشتن خصلت‏های عقلانی و منحصر به فرد گروههای اجتماعی متفاوت بویژه زنان شده است و همین غفلت امروز به بن بستهای علم اجتماعی دامن زده است. تغییر معنای عام گرایانه عقلانیت و جایگزینی آن با مفهومی که تکثرگرایی را محور قرار می‏دهد ، این امکان را فراهم می‏کند که تلاش‏های پست مدرنیست‏ها در متکثر دانستن فهم نسلها و زنان و مردان تلاشی مشروع قلمداد شود.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">استدلال / زنان / عقلانیت / نسل</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_26922_d7767b1faeab97f7590227f8b5b27669.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
