<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2002</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Provision of Finantial Services for women: World&#039;s Experiances</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>ارائه خدمات مالی به زنان : مروری بر تجربیات جهانی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">26920</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد مهدی</FirstName>
					<LastName>رحمتی</LastName>
<Affiliation>عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه گیلان ودانشجوی دوره دکتری جامعه شناسی دانشکده علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>محمد</FirstName>
					<LastName>سزاوار</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی کارشناسی ارشد دانشکده اقتصاد دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This article reviews world’s experiences in providing financial services for women. Countries under study include some of the developing countries Islamic and Non- Islamic), as well as development, in which governmental or non-governmental organizations have been established to provide financial help, credits, saving and other services. Their objectives, methods, activities, and programs are reported.
Also, the most important non-financial services and projects of these organizations are presented, such as social welfare, training courses in management skills, activities and supports for economic independence, consultative services and research projects.
The key finding of the article is the difference in approaches and thereby in types of services, objectives and functions of the financial organizations in the developed countries in comparison with developing countries. The first group of countries has taken more supportive actions for women as vulnerable groups, while the latter is pursuing women’s entrepreneurship.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">این مقاله نگاهی اجمالی به تجربه کشورهای جهان در زمینه ارائه خدمات مالی به زنان دارد. کشورهای مورد بررسی شامل کشورهای در حال توسعه اسلامی و غیراسلامی و توسعه یافته می‏باشد  در این کشورها سازمانهای دولتی یا غیردولتی برای ارائه خدمات مالی به زنان تاسیس شده‏اند. اهداف تاسیس، روش کار، حوزه فعالیت وچارچوب عملکردی این سازمانها بصورت خلاصه بحث شده است.
برخی از مهمترین خدمات و طرحهای غیراعتباری ارائه شده به زنان توسط این سازمانها معرفی می‏گردد. از آن جمله خدمات رفاه اجتماعی، آموزشی در زمینه‏های فنی ومدیریتی برای کسب مهارتهای لازم، فعالیت‏هایی در زمینه کسب استقلال اقتصادی، خدمات مشاوره‏ای و فرهنگی و انجام پروژه‏های پژوهشی.
نکته قابل توجه در این مطالعه تفاوت میان رهیافت‏ها، نوع خدمات، اهداف و عملکرد سازمانها در کشورهای توسعه یافته در مقایسه با کشورهای در حال توسعه است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اعتبار /  خدمات مالی / زنان / سیستم بانکی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_26920_f396c95dcf595471bcef5a8881ee14b7.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
