<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>1</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2002</Year>
					<Month>05</Month>
					<Day>22</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>MethodRural Women&#039;s Studies with Qualitative Research</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>شناخت زنان روستایی با کاربرد روش تحقیق کیفی</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">26919</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عبدالرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>اسدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>? دارای کارشناسی ارشد رشته جامعه شناسی – کارشناس مسؤل برنامه همیاران سلامت روان، معاونت امور فرهنگی و پیشگیری سازمان بهزیستی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The application of qualitative and participatory research methods in rural development studies shows similarities in findings with quantitative methods, as well as possibilities of more depth data analysis.
This article is based on research carried out with rural appraisal method and participatory technique. The objective is to gather information on four major issues in Women’s studies. The research is conducted in Garmsar region in the time period of 1999 and 2000.
Based on research findings rural women’s activities is extensive, their knowledge on environmental conditions and degradation factors is good but their participation in group decision making in rural society is low. Therefore with qualitative research methods we can have information on: (1) rural women’s knowledge of their environment, (2) their activities, (3) their participation in the process of decision making and (4) their needs, problems and priorities.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">کاربرد روش‏های کیفی و مشارکتی در مسائل توسعه روستایی نشان می‏دهد با این روش‏ها نیز می‏توان به نتایجی مشابه روش‏های کمی با ژرفانگری بیشتری دست یافت. مقاله حاضر براساس یافته‏های پژوهشی که با استفاده از روش ارزیابی به شیوه مشارکتی انجام شده، تنظیم گردیده است. این پژوهش با هدف شناخت و دستیابی به اطلاعات در چهار محور اساسی در حوزه مطالعات زنان در منطقه گرمسار در طی سالهای 1378 و 1379 انجام شده است. یافته‏های تحقیق نشان دهنده گستردگی کار و فعالیت زنان روستایی، شناخت قابل تحسین آنها از شرایط محیطی و عوامل تخریب کننده محیط زیست و مشارکت اندک آنها در تصمیم‏گیری‏های جمعی جامعه روستایی است. بدین ترتیب با روش‏های کیفی نیز می‏توان در موارد زیر اطلاعات لازم را بدست آورد : (1) شناخت زنان روستایی از محیط پیرامونی خود، (2) شناخت فعالیت‏های آنان، (3) چگونگی مشارکت زنان در فرایند تصمیم‏گیری و (4) شناخت نیازها، مشکلات و اولویت‏بندی آنها.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تحقیق کیفی / روش / شناخت / مشارکتی/ مطالعات زنان روستایی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_26919_5ea898c83bd029c5cd787a1bdf04b8e4.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
