<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>2</Volume>
				<Issue>1</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2004</Year>
					<Month>03</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>-</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>رویکرد جنسیتی به عدم تعادل های بازار کار</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">13276</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علیرضا</FirstName>
					<LastName>امینی</LastName>
<Affiliation></Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The aim of this paper is to identify indicators that demonstrate the lack of gender balance in the Iranian labor market. Based on a review of the theories on the dual labor market and the distinctions between available
employment options in the first and second sectors, the emergence of
employment opportunities and their implications for women will be examined. The indicators have been identified based on data and official national reports. The findings point to the low level of women&#039;s participation, despite the increase in their presence as compared with the past decade, as well as the concentration of women in relatively few economic activities. The results also point to the relatively higher level of unemployment among women, especially young women in urban areas, as compared with men&#039;s unemployment level. The gender-based employment indicators in different parts of the country speak of alarming gender imbalances. For example, in Lorestan Province, the rate of women&#039;s unemployment in urban areas is 53% and 64.6% in rural areas. In urban areas, the problems of women&#039;s unemployment and in rural areas the high rate of male unemployment exist at alarming levels.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">هدف این مقاله ارائه شاخص هایی است که عدم تعادل های جنسیتی در بازار کار ایران را نشان می دهد. با مروری بر نظریه های بازار کار دو گانه و موضوع تمایز شغل های بخش اول و دوم، پیدایش شغل های پرتراکم و پیامدهای آن برای زنان بررسی می شود. شاخص های مورد نیاز با استفاده از اطلاعات و آمار موجود در گزارش های رسمی کشور محاسبه شده است. یافته ها حاکی از نرخ پایین مشارکت زنان به رغم افزایش آن نسبت به دهه گذشته، تمرکز اشتغال زنان در معدودی از فعالیت های اقتصادی، و سطح بالاتر نرخ بیکاری زنان به ویژه جوانان در مناطق شهری نسبت به نرخ بیکاری مردان است. شاخص های جنسیتی بازارکار در مناطق مختلف کشور نشان دهنده عدم تعادل های نگران کننده ای است. برای مثاال، در استان لرستان، نرخ بیکاری زنان در مناطق شهری و روستایی بسیار زیاد است. در مناطق شهری کشور ، مشکل بیکاری زنان و در مناطق روستایی ، مشکل بیکاری زیاد مردان به شکل نگران کننده ای وجود دارد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">اشتغال</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازارکار</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بیکاری</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">روستا</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">شهر</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_13276_c884882fca0aa13ba5191244b1e27204.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
