<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>9</Volume>
				<Issue>4</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2012</Year>
					<Month>02</Month>
					<Day>20</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>Audience and television programs: women readings of television commercials</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مخاطبان و برنامه‌های تلویزیون: قرائت زنان از آگهی‌های بازرگانی تلویزیون</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage>43</FirstPage>
			<LastPage>72</LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">24418</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>مهری</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهار</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه ارتباطات دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>علی</FirstName>
					<LastName>حاجی محمدی</LastName>
<Affiliation>دانشجوی دکتری علوم ارتباطات دانشگاه تهران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>Portraying women in the media is one of the main social and cultural issues especially on television.  Television commercials as a genre have ideas about goods and services, but it constructs a secondary discourse about society, culture and gender roles along the way. The main goal of this paper is to examine women’s readings of gender roles representation in Iranian television commercials from the cultural studies perspective. To achieve this objective, focus group interviews were used to study women readings and then their readings was analyzed. The results showed that television commercials are heedless of socio-cultural developments and the gender roles changes in different aspects in the society, but it represents dominant ideology in media and minimal status group of woman in Iranian society. 
 Currently, different groups of women are engaged in different discourses and they will gradually engage in other discourses. If this trend continues by different groups of women and the misrepresentation or exclusion of women doesn’t stop in the media, the audiences with different readings will become the most rethinking groups.</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">بازنمایی زنان در رسانه‌ها، یکی از مسائل مهم اجتماعی و فرهنگی به ویژه در رسانه ملی صداوسیما است. آگهی-های بازرگانی در این رسانه به عنوان ژانر تلویزیونی، علاوه بر پیامی درباره کالا و خدمات، گفتمان ثانویه‌ای را درباره جامعه، فرهنگ و نقش‌های جنسیتی برمی‌سازد. هدف اصلی این مقاله بررسی قرائت‌ها و خوانش‌های زنان از آگهی‌های بازرگانی تلویزیون پیرامون بازنمایی نقش‌های جنسیتی از منظر مطالعات فرهنگی است. برای دست-یابی به این هدف، از روش کیفی مصاحبه گروهی متمرکز، استفاده شده و سپس برداشت‌های مصاحبه شوندگان تحلیل گردید. نتایج پژوهش نشان می‌دهد که آگهی‌های بازرگانی توجهی به تحولات فرهنگی- اجتماعی و تغییر نقش‌های جنسیتی در جامعه در جنبه‌های مختلف نداشته، بلکه بیانگر بازنمایی از وضعیت گروه حداقلی از زنان می‌باشد. در حال حاضر، گروه‌های مختلف زنان وارد گفتمان‌های مختلف شده‌اند و به تدریج وارد گفتمان‌های دیگر نیز خواهند شد. در صورت ادامه این روند از سوی گروه‌های مختلف زنان و عدم بازنمایی یا سوءبازنمایی از آنها در رسانه، مخاطبانی که خوانشی معارض با برنامه‌ها دارند، به بازاندیش‌ترین گروه‌ها تبدیل خواهند شد.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">آگهی‌های بازرگانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">بازنمایی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">تلویزیون</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">خوانش.</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زنان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مخاطبان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مطالعات فرهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">نقش‌های جنسیتی</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_24418_305893b62d3f78f41800f32d522c8a2c.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
