<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>8</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2010</Year>
					<Month>09</Month>
					<Day>23</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>The Youth, Cultural Capital and appearance management  (case study: Boys and Girls of Babolsar City)</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>سرمایه‌ی فرهنگی، مدیریت ظاهر و جوانان (مطالعه‌ی دختران و پسران شهر بابلسر)</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">21273</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>قربانعلی</FirstName>
					<LastName>ابراهیمی</LastName>
<Affiliation>استادیار گروه علوم اجتماعی دانشگاه مازندران</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>عباس</FirstName>
					<LastName>بهنوئی‌گدنه</LastName>
<Affiliation>کارشناس ارشد جامعه¬شناسی از دانشگاه مازندران</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>The appearance of body, which is considered as people’s physical capital, is influenced by cultural position of individuals. People have different attitude towards their body and appearance depending on their cultural capital. In addition, in today’s world visible characteristics and features of individuals are ever more important than they used to be in the past. Thus, as appropriate and desired appearance is gaining importance in different social groups, particularly youngsters, this study investigates the relationship between cultural capital and appearance management among the youth. In order to investigate this relationship, the theory of Anthony Giddens and Pierre Bourdieu are used. Data collection is conducted through a questionnaire. The sample population consists of youngsters between 15 to 25 years old residing in Babolsar city. Through proportional multi-step cluster stratified sampling and Cochran formula 380 cases are chosen as the statistical sample of the study. The results of descriptive findings show that nowadays young people control their weight in order to look physically attractive and young in front of others, thus more youngsters are inclined to join a bodybuilding and fitness club. Based on gender analysis, a greater number of girls resort to dieting to keep their bodies fit (40 percent) while higher number of boys choose sports clubs (58/15 percent). The findings show that among the many criteria, hair and face makeup along with using perfume are more important than other items of appearance management. Age and native language had no significant relationship with body management. In addition, there is  a positive and significant relationship between cultural capital and appearance management. In general, the results of descriptive statistics show that girls and boys use a variety of mechanisms for appearance management to a degree that these mechanisms put their health at risk. As modernisms, culture of media, commercialization, fashion and beauty industry, have put great importance on attractive bodies, a situation referred to as Physical Culture which is prevalent among boys and girls</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">مدیریتِ ظاهر و بدن که در دنیای امروزی آن‌را سرمایه‌ی جسمانی افراد می‌دانند، بر حسب این‌که افراد بیشتر از چه محصولات فرهنگی استفاده می‌کنند به‌نوعی از جایگاه فرهنگی آن‌ها متأثر است زیرا افراد بر حسب این‌که دارای چه میزان سرمایه‌ی فرهنگی می‌باشند، دارای نگرش‌های خاصی نسبت به بدن و چگونگی ظاهر شدن‌شان در اجتماع هستند. از این رو، تحقیق حاضر در صدد مطالعه‌ی رابطه‌ی بین سرمایه‌ی فرهنگی و مدیریت ظاهر جوانان است. به‌منظور سنجش این رابطه، از نظریه‌ی پیر بوردیو و آنتونی گیدنز استفاده می‌کنیم. به اعتقاد بوردیو، سرمایه‌ی فرهنگی از طریق قریحه و سلیقه‌ی افراد بر مدیریت ظاطر و بدن آنان تأثیر می‌گذارد. در نظریه‌ی گیدنز، مدیریت بدن نشانه‌ی دخالتِ آگاهانه‌ی کنش‌گر در شکل دادن به خود در متن اجتماعی است.  این تحقیق به روش پیمایشی و با ابزار پرسش‌نامه در میان جوانان 25- 15 ساله‌ی شهر بابلسر در سال 1386 انجام می‌شود. روش نمونه‌گیری، طبقه‌ای خوشه‌ایِ چندمرحله‌ایِ متناسب و حجم نمونه بر اساس فرمول کوکران 380 نفر انتخاب می‌شود. نتایج به‌دست‌آمده بیان‌گر آن است که مدیریت ظاهر در میان جوانان از اهمیتی ویژه برخوردار است. هم‌چنین نتایج حاصل از آزمون فرضیات حاکی از آن است که هرچه میزان سرمایه‌ی فرهنگی افراد بیشتر باشد، نحوه‌ی مدیریت ظاهر نیز در میان دختران و پسران جوان اهمیت ییشتری پیدا می‌کند. از سوی دیگر، نتایج حاصل از جداول توصیفی بیان‌گر آن است که الگوی رایجِ مدیریت ظاهر در میان جوانان، متأثر از نوگرایی و مؤلفه-های مرتبط با دنیای مدرن است.</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جامعه‌شناسی بدن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">جوانان</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه‌ی جسمانی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">سرمایه‌ی فرهنگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت بدن</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">مدیریت ظاهر</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_21273_77012dbb824a59412d07ec267fc939c5.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
