<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMed 2.7//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/in/PubMed.dtd">
<ArticleSet>
<Article>
<Journal>
				<PublisherName>دانشگاه تهران</PublisherName>
				<JournalTitle>زن در توسعه و سیاست</JournalTitle>
				<Issn>2538-3132</Issn>
				<Volume>6</Volume>
				<Issue>3</Issue>
				<PubDate PubStatus="epublish">
					<Year>2008</Year>
					<Month>11</Month>
					<Day>21</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</Journal>
<ArticleTitle>A Comparison of Effectiveness of Two Couple Therapies, CBCT and EFT, on Depression in Infertile Male-factor Pairs</ArticleTitle>
<VernacularTitle>مقایسه اثر بخشی زوج درمانی رفتاری- شناختی و هیجان‌محور</VernacularTitle>
			<FirstPage></FirstPage>
			<LastPage></LastPage>
			<ELocationID EIdType="pii">27416</ELocationID>
			
			
			<Language>FA</Language>
<AuthorList>
<Author>
					<FirstName>فریبا</FirstName>
					<LastName>حسنی</LastName>
<Affiliation>?  دانش¬آموخته دکتری مشاوره، عضو هیئت علمی دانشگاه آزاد اسلامی، واحد تهران مرکز</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>شکوه</FirstName>
					<LastName>نوابی¬نژاد</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مشاوره، دانشگاه تربیت معلم</Affiliation>

</Author>
<Author>
					<FirstName>رحمت¬الله</FirstName>
					<LastName>نورانی¬پور</LastName>
<Affiliation>استاد گروه مشاوره، دانشگاه شهید بهشتی</Affiliation>

</Author>
</AuthorList>
				<PublicationType>Journal Article</PublicationType>
			<History>
				<PubDate PubStatus="received">
					<Year>1970</Year>
					<Month>01</Month>
					<Day>01</Day>
				</PubDate>
			</History>
		<Abstract>This current research is a quasi experimental design which is aimed to study the effectiveness of two couple therapies, Cognitive Behavioral Couple Therapy (CBCT) and Emotional Focused Couple Therapy (EFT), on depression and some other variables in infertile male factor pairs. 
The sample includes 30 infertile volunteer pairs from Kosar Infertility Clinic which are placed in an experimental and a control group by applying Beck Depression Inventory (BDI-II) and U-man vitney test. 
The results show that depression in CBCT group has a significant difference in comparison with control group (p&lt;%1), while the EFT approach has no significant effect on it (p&gt;%5). The results also reveal that the effect of two approaches on men and women are the same and there is no difference between them in affecting the depression (p&gt;%5).</Abstract>
			<OtherAbstract Language="FA">: مقاله حاضر برگرفته از یک پژوهش شبه آزمایشی است که با هدف بررسی تأثیر دو روش زوج‌درمانی رفتاری-شناختی و هیجان‌محور بر کاهش افسردگی زوجِ مرد نابارور شکل گرفته‌است. نمونه آماری شامل 30 زوج مرد نابارور از بین مراجعین کلینیک ناباروری کوثر بود که با روش نمونه‌گیری داوطلبانه در دو گروه آزمایشی و یک گروه گواه جایگزین شده و با استفاده از آزمون افسردگی بک-II مورد سنجش قرار گرفتند و داده‌های بدست آمده با استفاده از روش‌های آمار توصیفی و استنباطی مورد تجزیه و تحلیل قرار گرفت. یافته‌های استنباطی حاصل از آزمون غیر پارامتریک یومان ویتنی حاکی از این است که زوج‌درمانی رفتاری-شناختی با اطمینان 99 درصد بر کاهش افسردگی زوج مرد نابارور مؤثر است ( ) اما روش زوج‌درمانی هیجان محور در تغییر میزان افسردگی معنادار نبوده است ( ). همچنین یافته‌ها نشان می‌دهد که جنسیت تأثیر معناداری در میزان کارآیی دو روش زوج درمانی رفتاری-شناختی و هیجان محور بر کاهش افسردگی نداشته است و هر دو رویکرد بر زنان و مردان به‌گونه‌ای یکسان تأثیر می‌گذارد( ).</OtherAbstract>
		<ObjectList>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زوج درمانی رفتاری شناختی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زوج درمانی هیجان محور</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">افسردگی</Param>
			</Object>
			<Object Type="keyword">
			<Param Name="value">زوج مرد نابارور</Param>
			</Object>
		</ObjectList>
<ArchiveCopySource DocType="pdf">https://jwdp.ut.ac.ir/article_27416_e931f2006e70865b6581e614234cca7b.pdf</ArchiveCopySource>
</Article>
</ArticleSet>
